<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 01:24:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Bonding of Lattice N Activates Metal Ni to Achieve Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411526</link>
      <description>Nian-Dan Zhao, Wei Luo, Sijun Li, Hua Wang, Yini Mao, Yimin Jiang, Wenbin Wang, Ming Li, Wei&#8208;Fang Su, Rongxing He, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404611968

                Abstract Developing efficient and robust free&#8208;standing electrocatalysts for overall water splitting is a promising but challenging task. Herein, the N&#8208;incorporated Ni nanosheets non&#8208;fully encapsulated by N&#8208;doped carbon (NC) layer are fabricated (N&#9472;Ni&#169;NC). The introduction of N not only regulates the size of nanosheets in N&#9472;Ni&#169;NC but also promotes the electrochemical activity of metal Ni. Experimental and theoretical results reveal that strong bonding of the lattice N activates the inert metal Ni by promoting charge transfer between Ni and N. In addition, the upward shift of the d&#8208;band center induced by lattice N enhances the adsorption of intermediates, thereby making Ni as a new OER active site together with C. This strategy of generating Ni and C dual active sites by introducing lattice N greatly accelerates oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics, resulting in excellent electrocatalytic performance of N&#9472;Ni&#169;NC. At the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , the overpotentials of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and OER are 27 and 206 mV, respectively, and the cell voltage for overall water splitting only needs 1.47 V. This work offers a unique heteroatom activation approach for designing free&#8208;standing electrodes with high activity.</description>
      <author>Nian-Dan Zhao, Wei Luo, Sijun Li, Hua Wang, Yini Mao, Yimin Jiang, Wenbin Wang, Ming Li, Wei&#8208;Fang Su, Rongxing He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Excess Hydrogen Output via Concurrent Electrochemical and Chemical Redox Reactions on P&#8208;Doped Co&#8208;Based Catalysts with Electron Manipulation and Kinetic Regulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406288</link>
      <description>Yue Yao, Menghui Qi, Liang Chen, Enlai Hu, Haotian Cai, Defa Gu, Li Wang, Yuanjing Cui, Guodong Qian, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404617882

                Abstract Electrolytic hydrogen production is of great significance in energy conversion and sustainable development. Traditional electrolytic water splitting confronts high anode voltage with oxygen generation and the amount of hydrogen produced at cathode depends entirely on the quantity of electric charge input. Herein, excess hydrogen output can be achieved by constructing a spontaneous hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR) coupled hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) system. For the hydrazine oxidation&#8208;assisted electrolyzer in this work, both the external input electrons and the electrons produced by spontaneous chemical redox reaction can reduce water, producing more hydrogen than traditional electrolytic water splitting system. The ultrafast kinetics of bifunctional P&#8208;doped Co&#8208;based catalysts plays a key role in the spontaneous feature of HzOR/HER redox reaction and low working voltage of hydrazine oxidation&#8208;assisted electrolyzer (12 mV@100 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Theoretical calculation results and ex situ/in situ spectra demonstrate that doped P could optimize electronic structure, regulate adsorption energy of intermediates, and thus endows catalysts with ultrafast kinetics. This work provides a new pathway for the development of spontaneous oxidation&#8208;assisted hydrogen production, to achieve excess hydrogen output via concurrent electrochemical and chemical redox reactions.</description>
      <author>Yue Yao, Menghui Qi, Liang Chen, Enlai Hu, Haotian Cai, Defa Gu, Li Wang, Yuanjing Cui, Guodong Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Perovskite Oxides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Structures, Mechanisms, and Strategies for Performance Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416705</link>
      <description>Xiong Sun, Ying Yuan, Shuzhi Liu, Hongqing Zhao, Suqiang Yao, Sun Yuying, Shouxin Zhang, Yijiang Liu, Zhiqun Lin, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404618145

                Abstract Perovskite&#8208;type oxides are widely employed as oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts due to their tunable composition, diverse structure, abundant natural reserves, remarkable stability, and low cost. The intrinsic OER electrocatalytic activity of these perovskite oxides is generally enhanced by improving conductivity, increasing specific surface area, and optimizing the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates. This is achieved through rationally designed strategies, including compositional engineering, defect engineering, hybridization, and surface regulation. In this review, recent advances in perovskite oxides for OER are summarized, with a focus on exploring structure&#8208;performance relationships. This review provides a brief introduction to the application of perovskite oxides in OER, followed by the classification and characteristics of these perovskite oxides. The primary OER catalytic mechanisms, and well&#8208;established activity descriptors are discussed. The key strategies are concentrated for enhancing OER activity, including composition engineering, defect engineering, hybridization, and surface reconstruction. Finally, the challenges and opportunities in developing high&#8208;performance perovskite oxides as OER electrocatalysts are presented.</description>
      <author>Xiong Sun, Ying Yuan, Shuzhi Liu, Hongqing Zhao, Suqiang Yao, Sun Yuying, Shouxin Zhang, Yijiang Liu, Zhiqun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering for Improved Large&#8208;Current Oxygen Evolution via Partial Phosphorization of Ce&#8208;MOF/NiCo&#8208;MOF Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408897</link>
      <description>Dan Li&#365;, Xuewen Xia, Xue&#8208;Qiang Zhang, Fei Wang, Tao Li, Ya Gao, Shujuan Wang, Zhongya Pang, Yu Xing, Guangshi Li, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Shen Hu, Ji Li, Xionggang Lu, Xingli Zou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404618356

                Interface engineering for electrocatalysts has proven to be an effective method for modulating electrocatalytic properties, yet a more efficient and straightforward strategy to construct a valid heterointerface for further enhancing interface effects is urgently needed for boosting oxygen evolution reactions (OER) at large current. Herein, a closely compacted heterostructure combining NiCo-metal-organic framework (MOF) and Ce-MOF is in situ formed through a one-step hydrothermal treatment, and partial phosphorization is employed to further enhance the interface effect between the newly formed urchin-shaped NiCoP shells and hexagonal rod-like Ce-MOF cores on nickel foam (NiCoP/Ce-MOF@NF). Experimental and theoretical results indicate that the heterogeneous NiCoP/Ce-MOF@NF, characterized by a more intensive interface rather than a simple physical mixture, generates an OER-beneficial electronic structure, significantly facilitates charge transfer and reaction kinetics, and creates a synergistically stable structure. The optimal NiCoP/Ce-MOF@NF exhibits remarkable electrocatalytic activity for OER, achieving an ultralow overpotential of 268 mV at a current density of 500 mA cm</description>
      <author>Dan Li&#365;, Xuewen Xia, Xue&#8208;Qiang Zhang, Fei Wang, Tao Li, Ya Gao, Shujuan Wang, Zhongya Pang, Yu Xing, Guangshi Li, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Shen Hu, Ji Li, Xionggang Lu, Xingli Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-Earth Elements Doped NiFe-MOFs as Efficient and Robust Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Both Alkaline Freshwater and Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06574c</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Jing Wang, Jiahui Xian, Runan Xiang, Guangqin Li, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404619733

                Based on the target of carbon neutrality, it is very important to explore highly active and durable electrocatalysts for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here,...</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Jing Wang, Jiahui Xian, Runan Xiang, Guangqin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06574c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Chalcogenide&#8208;Derived NiFe2O4 as Highly Efficient and Stable Anode for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403198</link>
      <description>Husileng Lee, Guoheng Ding, Linqin Wang, Licheng Sun, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404619914

                Developing low&#8208;cost, highly active, and durable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrodes is one of the critical scientific issues for anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEM&#8208;WE). Herein, we report a vacancy&#8208;rich and alkali&#8208;stable NiFe2O4&#8208;type electrode (named as NiFeOx&#8208;350&#8208;Ov), derived from the chemical&#8208;vapor deposited precursor NiFeSexSy&#8208;350, as an efficient and robust anode material. The obtained electrode affords current densities of 100 and 500 mA cm&#8722;2 at overpotentials of 245 and 270 mV, respectively, and displays excellent long&#8208;term durability sustaining 1.0 A cm&#8722;2 at least for 1000 h. When coupled with Ni4Mo/MoO2/NF as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst, the resulting platinum group metal (PGM)&#8208;free single&#8208;cell AEM&#8208;WE exhibits a cell voltage of 1.71 V at the current density of 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 at 80 &#176;C and long&#8208;term durability during a current&#8208;cycling test between 0.5 and 1.0 A cm&#8722;2 over 150 h at 60 &#176;C. This work highlights a unique reconstruction strategy for preparing highly active and durable OER catalysts used in PGM&#8208;free AEM&#8208;WE.</description>
      <author>Husileng Lee, Guoheng Ding, Linqin Wang, Licheng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Zhang, Xuanyu Zhou, Kongliang Luo, Yaning Fan, Chuandong He, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404620648

                Developing efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts was urgent for producing clean hydrogen energy. High-entropy oxides (HEOs) have become a focus of interest, were widely used for OER. HEOs would...</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Zhang, Xuanyu Zhou, Kongliang Luo, Yaning Fan, Chuandong He, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological&#8203; Evolution and Crystal Plane Effects of Spinel Nico2o4 Catalyst on Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030028</link>
      <description>Qimei Liang, Yihui Liu, Yan Dong, Liuyang Bai, Hui Kang, Chao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404621038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qimei Liang, Yihui Liu, Yan Dong, Liuyang Bai, Hui Kang, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameterization and quantification of two key operando physio-chemical descriptors for water-assisted electro-catalytic organic oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54318-7</link>
      <description>Bailin Tian, Fangyuan Wang, Pan Ran, Luhan Dai, Jing Wang, Yuxia Sun, Zhangyan Mu, Yamei Sun, Lingyu Tang, William A. Goddard, Mengning Ding, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404623942

                Electro-selective-oxidation using water as a green oxygen source demonstrates promising potential towards efficient and sustainable chemical upgrading. However, surface micro-kinetics regarding co-adsorption and reaction between organic and oxygen intermediates remain unclear. Here we systematically study the electro-oxidation of aldehydes, alcohols, and amines on Co/Ni-oxyhydroxides with multiple characterizations. Utilizing Fourier transformed alternating current voltammetry (FTacV) measurements, we show the identification and quantification of two key operando parameters (&#916;Iharmonics/IOER and &#916;Vharmonics) that can be fundamentally linked to the altered surface coverage ( $$\Delta {\theta }_{{{{{\rm{OH}}}}}^{*}}/{\theta }_{{{{{\rm{OH}}}}}^{*}}^{{{{\rm{OER}}}}}$$ ) and the changes in adsorption energy of vital oxygenated intermediates ( $${\Delta G}_{{{{\rm{OH}}}}*}^{{{{\rm{EOOR}}}}}-{\Delta G}_{{{{\rm{OH}}}}*}^{{{{\rm{OER}}}}}$$ ), under the influence of organic adsorption/oxidation. Mechanistic analysis based on these descriptors reveals distinct optimal oxyhydroxide surface states for each organics, and elucidates the critical catalyst design principles: balancing organic and M3+&#948;&#8722;OH* coverages and fine-tuning &#916;G for key elementary steps, e.g., via precise modulation of chemical compositions, crystallinity, defects, electronic structures, and/or surface bimolecular interactions. Water-assisted electro-catalytic selective oxidation is promising for sustainable production of value-added chemicals. Here the authors quantify two key physio-chemical parameters for efficient mechanistic investigation and rational catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Bailin Tian, Fangyuan Wang, Pan Ran, Luhan Dai, Jing Wang, Yuxia Sun, Zhangyan Mu, Yamei Sun, Lingyu Tang, William A. Goddard, Mengning Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54318-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A dual-phase PtNiCuMnMo high-entropy alloy as high-performance electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161865</link>
      <description>Fang Miao, Tongheng Wang, Zhiyuan Jing, Bin Zhang, Jun Wang, Tao Gu, Zhijie Yan, Xiubing Liang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404626182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fang Miao, Tongheng Wang, Zhiyuan Jing, Bin Zhang, Jun Wang, Tao Gu, Zhijie Yan, Xiubing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Cationic Vacancy Defects to Switch Oxygen Evolution Mechanisms on Atomically Dispersed Ru for Enhanced Acidic Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124845</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Deshuai Yang, Zhen Yang, Lili Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404628614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Deshuai Yang, Zhen Yang, Lili Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous amorphous high entropy oxide coated dimensionally stable anode for oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161882</link>
      <description>Wushuai Dai, Lei Wang, Keyi Li, Wei Wang, Yunlong Bai, Feng Xie, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wushuai Dai, Lei Wang, Keyi Li, Wei Wang, Yunlong Bai, Feng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in advanced design of iridium&#8208;based and ruthenium&#8208;based perovskite catalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.79</link>
      <description>Yuqing Cheng, Yibo Wang, Zhaoping Shi, Hongxiang Wu, Jiahao Yang, Jing Ni, Ming Yang, Ziang Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631203

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is of great importance for the production of green hydrogen. The large&#8208;scale implementation of PEMWE, however, is seriously impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode, which results in considerable overpotential and thus the decreased energy conversion efficiency. To overcome this problem, researchers have extensively explored efficient anode catalysts that possess high activity and prolonged stability. Up to now, Ir&#8208;based and Ru&#8208;based catalysts are considered to be the most efficient candidates. Especially perovskite&#8208;based catalysts have received intensive attention due to their distinctive structures and exceptional OER catalytic performance. To further promote their practical application, considerable research efforts are devoted to structural engineering toward enhanced activity and stability. In this paper, a review of the research progress on the advanced design of Ir&#8208; and Ru&#8208;based perovskite catalysts is presented, with a focus on phase engineering, doping/substitution, morphology control, and compositing with other materials for perovskite catalysts as well as some preparation methods commonly used. It also summarizes the challenges and opportunities concerning perovskite&#8208;based catalysts in current research, yielding further comprehension of the pertinent preparation and scrutiny of perovskite catalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Cheng, Yibo Wang, Zhaoping Shi, Hongxiang Wu, Jiahao Yang, Jing Ni, Ming Yang, Ziang Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.79</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of electrochromic band-shifts in the Soret region induced by the formation of TyrD, TyrZ, and QA- in Photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.21.624785</link>
      <description>Alain Boussac, Takumi Noguchi, A. William Rutherford, Julien Sell&#233;s, Miwa Sugiura, Stefania Viola, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631459

                The effects of TyrD, TyrZ, and QA- radical formation on the absorption spectrum in the Soret region were studied in Mn-depleted Photosystem II at pH 8.6 (in order to be in the TyrD state after the dark adaptation). Flash-induced difference spectra were recorded in several PSII samples from i) Thermosynechococcus vestitus (formerly T. elongatus), ii) Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803, iii) Chroococcidiopsis thermalis PCC7203 grown under far-red light, and iv) Acaryochloris marina. In the case of T. vestitus, mutants D1/H198Q, D1/T1789H, D2/I178H and D2/Y160F, with PsbA1/Q130 instead of PsbA3/E130, were also studied for possible contributions from PD1, ChlD1, ChlD2 and PheD1, respectively. For a possible contribution from PD2, the D2/H197A mutant was studied in S. 6803. While PD1 is clearly the species whose spectrum is blue shifted by ~ 3 nm in the presence of QA-, as already well documented in the literature, the species whose spectra are shifted upon the formation of TyrD, and TyrZ remain to be clearly identified as they appear different from PD1, PD2, PheD1, ChlD1 and ChlD2 as concluded by the lack of different light-induced difference spectra in the mutants listed above. Although we cannot rule out too weak effect taking into account the accuracy of the experiments, it is proposed that other pigments are involved as antenna Chl and/or Car near the reaction center. Additionally, it is shown that, i) there is no proton release into the bulk upon the oxidation of TyrD at pH 8.6, and ii) the rearrangement of the electrostatic environment of the pigments involved in the light-induced different spectra in the samples studied upon the formation TyrD, TyrZ, and QA- likely occur differently on a kinetic and structural point of views.</description>
      <author>Alain Boussac, Takumi Noguchi, A. William Rutherford, Julien Sell&#233;s, Miwa Sugiura, Stefania Viola</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.21.624785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Electronic Correlations in Ruthenium Oxides for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00068</link>
      <description>Xianbing Miao, Jingda Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Shiming Zhou, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404632938

                Elucidating the electronic factors dominating the adsorption properties of transition-metal oxides is essential to construct highly efficient oxygen-evolving catalysts for hydrogen production by water splitting but remains a great challenge. Electron correlation from on-site Coulomb repulsion (U) among d-electrons is generally believed to significantly affect the electronic structure of these materials; however, it has long been neglected in studying their adsorption properties. Here, by choosing ruthenium oxide as a model system, we demonstrate the role of electron correlation on the electrocatalytic activity toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Our density functional theory plus U calculations on rutile RuO2 reveal that the electron correlation can tune the adsorption energies for oxygenated intermediate and optimize them after the metallic oxide being a Mott insulator upon increasing U. By regulating the RuO6 octahedral network, we constructed and synthesized a series of strongly correlated ruthenium oxides, where the Mott insulating ones indeed exhibit a superior OER performance to the metallic RuO2. Our work builds a bridge between the electrochemistry and Mott physics for transition-metal oxides, opening a new avenue for designing advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xianbing Miao, Jingda Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Shiming Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Ru nanoclusters in tandem with single atoms on oxygen-vacancy regulated CeO2 for anion exchange membrane seawater-splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.017</link>
      <description>Yan Wang, Jing Li, Pengfei Yang, Hongdong Li, Guangrui Xu, Yunmei Du, Caixia Li, Wei Jin, Tianyi Ma, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404633981

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Wang, Jing Li, Pengfei Yang, Hongdong Li, Guangrui Xu, Yunmei Du, Caixia Li, Wei Jin, Tianyi Ma, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and application of a liquid metal ball-supported layered double hydroxide core&#8211;shell structure as highly efficient catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction in rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157924</link>
      <description>Liqing Qiao, Wenwei Liu, Na Du, Ying Wang, Yankun Li, Haijun Wu, Zhonghua Bao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404634694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liqing Qiao, Wenwei Liu, Na Du, Ying Wang, Yankun Li, Haijun Wu, Zhonghua Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Donation from Carbon Support Enhances the Activity and Stability of Ultrasmall Ruo2 Nanoparticles in Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030506</link>
      <description>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic modulation of CoFe sites for advanced bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100470</link>
      <description>Ju-Hong Zhou, Hui Zhao, Ping Han, Ruizi Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Xiaoxia Mao, Konglin Wu, Shengjue Deng, Wenxiang He, Binbin Jiang, Chinese Journal of Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635846

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ju-Hong Zhou, Hui Zhao, Ping Han, Ruizi Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Xiaoxia Mao, Konglin Wu, Shengjue Deng, Wenxiang He, Binbin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An oxycarbide-derived-carbon supported nickel ferrite/copper tungstate ternary composite for enhanced electrocatalytic activity towards the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02688h</link>
      <description>Kumar Sanket, Uttam Kumar, Indrajit Sinha, Shantanu K. Behera, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404637944

                This work integrates a unique porous carbon with a binary heterostructured NiFe 2 O 4 /CuWO 4 composite to enhance electrocatalytic activity towards the oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Kumar Sanket, Uttam Kumar, Indrajit Sinha, Shantanu K. Behera</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02688h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution on Flexible Catalysts Based on Nickel&#8211;Iron Coatings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120843</link>
      <description>Dmytro Shyshkin, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Dijana &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Zita Sukackien&#279;, J&#363;rat&#279; Vai&#269;i&#363;nien&#279;, Birut&#279; &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;-Stanynien&#279;, Antanas Nacys, Eugenijus Norkus, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404639176

                The electrolysis of water is one of low-cost green hydrogen production technologies. The main challenge regarding this technology is designing and developing low-cost and high-activity catalysts. Herein, we present a strategy to fabricate flexible electrocatalysts based on nickel&#8211;iron (NiFe) alloy coatings. NiFe coatings were plated on the flexible copper-coated polyimide surface (Cu/PI) using the low-cost and straightforward electroless metal-plating method, with morpholine borane as a reducing agent. It was found that Ni90Fe10, Ni80Fe20, Ni60Fe40, and Ni30Fe70 coatings were deposited on the Cu/PI surface; then, the concentration of Fe2+ in the plating solution was 0.5, 1, 5, and 10 mM, respectively. The morphology, structure, and composition of NixFey/Cu/PI catalysts have been examined using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and inductively coupled plasma&#8211;optical emission spectroscopy (ICP-OES), whereas their activity has been investigated for hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions in 1 M KOH using linear sweep voltammetry (LSVs). It was found that the Ni80Fe20/Cu/PI catalyst exhibited the lowest overpotential value of &#8722;202.7 mV for the HER, obtaining a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 compared to Ni90Fe10/Cu/PI (&#8722;211.9 mV), Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI (&#8722;276.3 mV), Ni30Fe70/Cu/PI (&#8722;278.4 mV), and Ni (&#8722;303.4 mV). On the other hand, the lowest OER overpotential (344.7 mV) was observed for the Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI catalyst, obtaining a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 compared to the Ni35Fe65 (369.9 mV), Ni80Fe20 (450.2 mV), and Ni90Fe10 (454.2 mV) coatings, and Ni (532.1 mV). The developed Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI catalyst exhibit a cell potential of 1.85 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The obtained catalysts seem to be suitable flexible catalysts for HER and OER in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Dmytro Shyshkin, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Dijana &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Zita Sukackien&#279;, J&#363;rat&#279; Vai&#269;i&#363;nien&#279;, Birut&#279; &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;-Stanynien&#279;, Antanas Nacys, Eugenijus Norkus</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bismuth sensitized iron oxide on exfoliated graphene oxide (Bi&#8211;Fe2O3@GO) for oxygen evaluation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s11671-024-04146-x</link>
      <description>Akhtar Munir, Shaheer Jamal, Humaira Yasmeen Gondal, Javed Iqbal, Aamir Hussain, Alex Aziz, Muhammad Shahid Nisar, Muhammad Zubair, Abdul Momin, Ali Haider, Discover Nano. 19(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404643210

                Electrochemical water splitting is a promising approach towards a sustainable and renewable energy source. However, the demand for high anodic potential and sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) restrict the efficiency and feasibility of the water-splitting process. In this quest, transition metal oxides and alloys are considered potential candidates owing to their natural occurrence and high redox potential for OER. However, many associated challenges in their use are still there to be addressed. Here, we designed a new class of bismuth-doped iron oxide on exfoliated graphene oxide by optimizing the metal loading on the conductive support to facilitate the flow of charge during catalysis. The catalytic ability of the synthesized Bi-doped nanocomposites was evaluated in activating the OER under extreme alkaline conditions (1 MKOH). On screening different combinations, 20Bi&#8211;Fe2O3@GO was identified as the most efficient and sustainable electrocatalyst even under harsh operating conditions, with an onset potential of 1.48 V and a Tafel slope of 65 mV/dec. The current study offers a new class of Bi-doped electrocatalysts, where the precise doping of Bi and the optimized loading of metal was found the key to achieving low onset potential and high current density to initiate OER.</description>
      <author>Akhtar Munir, Shaheer Jamal, Humaira Yasmeen Gondal, Javed Iqbal, Aamir Hussain, Alex Aziz, Muhammad Shahid Nisar, Muhammad Zubair, Abdul Momin, Ali Haider</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s11671-024-04146-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404647545

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404647569

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O&#9472;O Radical Coupling in Ultrathin Reconstructed Co6.8Se8 Nanosheets for Effective Oxygen Evolution and Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419083</link>
      <description>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Chengyuan Dong, Xiaohui Peng, Yousef Ibraheem, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Laura Simonelli, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Yizhong Lu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404651304

                Designing ultrathin transition metal electrocatalysts with optimal surface chemistry state is crucial for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the structure&#8208;dependent electrochemical performance and the underlying catalytic mechanisms are still not clearly distinguished. Herein, we synthesize ultrathin Co6.8Se8 nanosheets (NSs) with subnanometer thickness by incorporating catalytically inactive selenium (Se) into ultrathin Co(OH)2, thereby switching the OER reaction pathway from adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) to oxide path mechanism (OPM). The prepared ultrathin Co6.8Se8 NSs exhibit an overpotential of 253 mV at 10 mA/cm2, outperforming the mostly reported Co&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Advanced operando synchrotron spectroscopies and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy reveal the ultrathin Co6.8Se8 NSs, whose surface is reconstructed into Se&#8208;doped Co(OH)2 during the OER process, could trigger direct O*&#8208;O* radical coupling rather than OOH* intermediates within AEM pathway thus lowering the energy input. Density functional theory calculations confirm that Co6.8Se8 NSs with shorter Co&#8208;Co bond length and stable Co&#8208;Se bond could optimize the rate&#8208;determining step barrier via OPM pathway. Besides, rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries based on Co6.8Se8 NSs exhibit excellent stability for more than 500 h of continuous charge&#8208;discharge cycles at 4 mA/cm2. The present study highlights the structural&#8208;dependent switch of OER pathways and provides valuable insights for further development of ultrathin OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Chengyuan Dong, Xiaohui Peng, Yousef Ibraheem, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Laura Simonelli, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Yizhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O&#9472;O Radical Coupling in Ultrathin Reconstructed Co6.8Se8 Nanosheets for Effective Oxygen Evolution and Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419083</link>
      <description>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Chengyuan Dong, Xiaohui Peng, Yousef Ibraheem, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Laura Simonelli, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Yizhong Lu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404651398

                Designing ultrathin transition metal electrocatalysts with optimal surface chemistry state is crucial for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the structure&#8208;dependent electrochemical performance and the underlying catalytic mechanisms are still not clearly distinguished. Herein, we synthesize ultrathin Co6.8Se8 nanosheets (NSs) with subnanometer thickness by incorporating catalytically inactive selenium (Se) into ultrathin Co(OH)2, thereby switching the OER reaction pathway from adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) to oxide path mechanism (OPM). The prepared ultrathin Co6.8Se8 NSs exhibit an overpotential of 253 mV at 10 mA/cm2, outperforming the mostly reported Co&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Advanced operando synchrotron spectroscopies and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy reveal the ultrathin Co6.8Se8 NSs, whose surface is reconstructed into Se&#8208;doped Co(OH)2 during the OER process, could trigger direct O*&#8208;O* radical coupling rather than OOH* intermediates within AEM pathway thus lowering the energy input. Density functional theory calculations confirm that Co6.8Se8 NSs with shorter Co&#8208;Co bond length and stable Co&#8208;Se bond could optimize the rate&#8208;determining step barrier via OPM pathway. Besides, rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries based on Co6.8Se8 NSs exhibit excellent stability for more than 500 h of continuous charge&#8208;discharge cycles at 4 mA/cm2. The present study highlights the structural&#8208;dependent switch of OER pathways and provides valuable insights for further development of ultrathin OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Chengyuan Dong, Xiaohui Peng, Yousef Ibraheem, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Laura Simonelli, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Yizhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRADA: Development and Commercialization of a Nanosegrated Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2478157</link>
      <description>Xiong Peng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404652091

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiong Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2478157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404653580

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404653843

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404653928

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy Enriched and Cu Single-Atom Contained Covalent Organic Frameworks: A Competitive Photocatalyst to Promote Hydrogen Evolution under Visible Light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101750</link>
      <description>Zhishi Qiu, Zhongge Luo, Tong Zhou, Baoye Zi, Mingpeng Chen, Rui Hu, Tianping Lv, Tianwei He, Yu&#8208;Xiang Ma, Jin Zhang, Hao Cui, Jianhong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Qingju Liu, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404655150

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhishi Qiu, Zhongge Luo, Tong Zhou, Baoye Zi, Mingpeng Chen, Rui Hu, Tianping Lv, Tianwei He, Yu&#8208;Xiang Ma, Jin Zhang, Hao Cui, Jianhong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101750</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the properties of perovskite oxide based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06616-1</link>
      <description>Areej S. Alqarni, Arooj Fatima, Abhinav Kumar, A. Dahshan, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404656161

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Areej S. Alqarni, Arooj Fatima, Abhinav Kumar, A. Dahshan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06616-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamically Reconstructed Fe&#8208;CoOOH Semi&#8208;Crystalline Electrocatalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408854</link>
      <description>Abdul Qayum, Karim Harrath, Rui Li, Abebe Reda Woldu, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Fushen Lu, Xiangdong Yao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657010

                Abstract The development of robust and efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been the main focus of water electrolysis but remains a great challenge. Here, the synthesis of a highly active and ultra&#8208;stable Fe&#8208;CoOOH electrocatalyst is reported by steering raw cobalt foam via an in situ solution combustion method assisted by a galvanic replacement reaction and subsequent electrochemical reconstruction of the CoFeO x pre&#8208;catalyst. In/ ex situ electrochemical analysis and physicochemical characterizations show that the CoFeO x undergoes quick chemical and slow morphological reconstruction to Fe&#8208;CoOOH nanosheets. The Fe&#8208;CoOOH possesses a semi&#8208;crystalline nature with distinct short&#8208;range ordering and outstanding OER activity with overpotentials as low as 271 and 291 mV at current densities of 500 and 1,000 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The remarkable stability under 1,000 mA cm &#8722;2 for at least 700 h is achieved. Theoretical calculations confirm the crucial role of Fe doping in facilitating surface reconstruction, enhancing OER activity, and improving the stability of the Fe&#8208;CoOOH. Comparative analysis with other transition metals doping reveals the unique ability of Fe to adsorb onto the CoOOH surface, thereby modulating the electronic density and facilitating faster adsorption of reaction intermediates. This work represents valuable insights into the surface reconstruction and doping processes.</description>
      <author>Abdul Qayum, Karim Harrath, Rui Li, Abebe Reda Woldu, Paul K. Chu, Liangsheng Hu, Fushen Lu, Xiangdong Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interplay Between Calcination Temperature and Alkaline Oxygen Evolution of Electrospun High&#8208;Entropy (Cr&lt;sub&gt;1/5&lt;/sub&gt;Mn&lt;sub&gt;1/5&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;1/5&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;1/5&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;1/5&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanofibers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408319</link>
      <description>Keti Vezz&#249;, Claudia Triolo, Kaveh Moulaee, Gioele Pagot, Alessandro Ponti, Nicola Pinna, G. Neri, S. Santangelo, Vito Di Noto, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657044

                Abstract Spinel&#8208;structured transition metal (TM) oxides have shown great potential as a sustainable alternative to platinum group metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Among them, high&#8208;entropy oxides (HEOs) with multiple TM&#8208;cation sites are suitable for engineering octahedral redox&#8208;active centers to enhance the catalyst reactivity. This paper reports on the preparation of electrospun (Cr 1/5 Mn 1/5 Fe 1/5 Co 1/5 Ni 1/5 ) 3 O 4 nanofibers (NFs) and their evaluation as electrocatalysts. Its main aim is to unveil the nanostructural features that play a key role in the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction. Differing calcination temperature (300&#8722;800 &#176;C) and duration (2 or 4 h) leads to different morphology of the NFs, crystallinity of the oxide, density of defects, and cation distribution in the lattice, which reflect in different electrocatalytic behaviors. The best performance (overpotential and Tafel slope at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 : 325 mV and 40 mV dec &#8722;1 , respectively) pertains to the NFs calcined at 400 &#176;C for 2 h. To gain a deeper understanding of their electrocatalytic properties, the pristine NFs are investigated by a combination of analytical techniques. In particular, broadband electric spectroscopy reveals that the mobility of oxygen vacancies in the best electrocatalyst is associated to very fast local dielectric relaxations of metal coordination octahedral geometries and experimentally demonstrates the key role of O&#8208;deficient octahedra.</description>
      <author>Keti Vezz&#249;, Claudia Triolo, Kaveh Moulaee, Gioele Pagot, Alessandro Ponti, Nicola Pinna, G. Neri, S. Santangelo, Vito Di Noto</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain-limited surface oxygen vacancy in rutile TiO2 for enhancing photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.338</link>
      <description>Huazhang Feng, Zhaohui Chen, Cheng Lin, Yan&#8208;Ping Chen, Jingyun Su, Enna Ha, Kan Zhang, Luyang Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 96(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657741

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huazhang Feng, Zhaohui Chen, Cheng Lin, Yan&#8208;Ping Chen, Jingyun Su, Enna Ha, Kan Zhang, Luyang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Ni-coordinated MOF on stainless steel via electrodeposition as efficient and stable oxygen evolution electrode for alkaline water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145416</link>
      <description>Valentina Maria Volanti, Andrea Zaffora, Leonardo Iannucci, Sabrina Grassini, Elisabetta Inico, Clara Saetta, Giovanni Di Liberto, Monica Santamaria, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657854

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Valentina Maria Volanti, Andrea Zaffora, Leonardo Iannucci, Sabrina Grassini, Elisabetta Inico, Clara Saetta, Giovanni Di Liberto, Monica Santamaria</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru0.1Mn0.9Ox Electrocatalyst for Durable Oxygen Evolution in Acid Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420615</link>
      <description>Jun Xu, Chun&#8208;Chuan Kao, Haifeng Shen, Hao Liu, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404665200

                Currently, direct electrolysis of seawater for green hydrogen production is primarily focused on neutral and alkaline systems. However, the precipitation of calcium and magnesium ions restricts the advancement of this technology. An acidic system can effectively address this issue. Given that Ru/Ir&#8208;based catalysts with high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity also exhibit high chlorine evolution reaction (CER) activity, acid seawater splitting requires anodes with higher selectivity and stability compared to the other two systems. In this study, we propose a non&#8208;precious Ru0.1Mn0.9Ox as the active anode for direct acid seawater electrolysis, which exhibits a high OER selectivity and remarkable stability for more than 1200 hours. Different from the Cl&#8208;&#8208;free system, *Cl occupied on Ru sites could shift the OER active center to Mn on Ru0.1Mn0.9Ox, which prevents the lattice oxygen consumed on Ru and hinders the metal site dissolution. As the CER&#8208;insensitive catalytic center, Mn activated by the introduction of Ru can adsorb a substantial amount of *OH, creating an OER&#8208;favored local environment that inhibits CER. We introduce Cl&#8208;&#8208;assisted transfer of OER active sites to CER&#8208;insensitive Mn as a fundamental strategy for achieving highly selective and durable oxygen evolution in acidic seawater.</description>
      <author>Jun Xu, Chun&#8208;Chuan Kao, Haifeng Shen, Hao Liu, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420615</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalysts of Mn-doped Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6023/a24050152</link>
      <description>Ziyi Shui, Sile Yu, Wei Lu, Liuyun Xu, Qingye Liu, Wei Zhao, Yilun Liu, Acta Chimica Sinica. 82(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404665261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyi Shui, Sile Yu, Wei Lu, Liuyun Xu, Qingye Liu, Wei Zhao, Yilun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6023/a24050152</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru0.1Mn0.9Ox Electrocatalyst for Durable Oxygen Evolution in Acid Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420615</link>
      <description>Jun Xu, Chun&#8208;Chuan Kao, Haifeng Shen, Hao Liu, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404665286

                Currently, direct electrolysis of seawater for green hydrogen production is primarily focused on neutral and alkaline systems. However, the precipitation of calcium and magnesium ions restricts the advancement of this technology. An acidic system can effectively address this issue. Given that Ru/Ir&#8208;based catalysts with high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity also exhibit high chlorine evolution reaction (CER) activity, acid seawater splitting requires anodes with higher selectivity and stability compared to the other two systems. In this study, we propose a non&#8208;precious Ru0.1Mn0.9Ox as the active anode for direct acid seawater electrolysis, which exhibits a high OER selectivity and remarkable stability for more than 1200 hours. Different from the Cl&#8208;&#8208;free system, *Cl occupied on Ru sites could shift the OER active center to Mn on Ru0.1Mn0.9Ox, which prevents the lattice oxygen consumed on Ru and hinders the metal site dissolution. As the CER&#8208;insensitive catalytic center, Mn activated by the introduction of Ru can adsorb a substantial amount of *OH, creating an OER&#8208;favored local environment that inhibits CER. We introduce Cl&#8208;&#8208;assisted transfer of OER active sites to CER&#8208;insensitive Mn as a fundamental strategy for achieving highly selective and durable oxygen evolution in acidic seawater.</description>
      <author>Jun Xu, Chun&#8208;Chuan Kao, Haifeng Shen, Hao Liu, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420615</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand&#8208;Tuning Metallic Sites in Molecular Complexes for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415755</link>
      <description>Yun Gao, Chengdong Yang, Fenglei Sun, Daping He, Xinqiang Wang, Jian Chen, Xiaobo Zheng, Runcong Liu, Hongge Pan, Dingsheng Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404665300

                Metal&#8208;organic hybrid catalysts with highly tunable single&#8208;sites are promising for oxygen&#8208;evolution reaction (OER), but molecular&#8208;scale understanding of underlying reaction mechanisms still remain elusive on these bulk materials. Herein, we report a direct construction of heterogenized molecular complexes stabilized on carbon substrates via coordinating Fe&#8208;Ni sites with four aromatic carboxylate ligands (FeNi&#8208;Lx). The ligands&#8208;tuning &#960;&#8208;&#960; stacking interaction between aromatic carboxylate ligands and carbon supports promote the oxidative charge accumulation on Fe&#8208;Ni sites via fast electron transferring, thus the optimized FeNi&#8208;Lx rendering a mass activity of 6680 A gFe/Ni&#8208;1 at 0.3 V overpotential. In situ characteristics and theoretical analysis demonstrate that the OH&#8208; nucleophilic attack on hypervalent iron sites induce the reconstruction of active Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Ni species, accompanying with fast valence increasing. Whereas, during OER, the unexpected valence reduction of Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Ni sites would be attributed to the oxygen&#8208;generating from OOH* intermediates. These findings would establish an essential understanding of the origin of active centers in molecular complexes catalysts for oxygen&#8208;evolution.</description>
      <author>Yun Gao, Chengdong Yang, Fenglei Sun, Daping He, Xinqiang Wang, Jian Chen, Xiaobo Zheng, Runcong Liu, Hongge Pan, Dingsheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-Co Doped M-type Strontium Hexaferrite as Electrode Material for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00913-7</link>
      <description>Rajeshree J. Bani, Krishnendu TV, Sachin Kumar Godara, Jayesh C. Chaudhari, Divesh N. Srivastava, Gopala Ram Bhadu, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404666465

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rajeshree J. Bani, Krishnendu TV, Sachin Kumar Godara, Jayesh C. Chaudhari, Divesh N. Srivastava, Gopala Ram Bhadu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00913-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Fabrication of Mn-Doped FeTiO3 Nanostructure via Hydrothermal Route for Robust Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-06991-8</link>
      <description>Khansa Ashfaq, Gaber A.M. Mersal, Ahmed M. Fallatah, Mohamed M. Ibrahim, Abhinav Kumar, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, JOM. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404673625

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Khansa Ashfaq, Gaber A.M. Mersal, Ahmed M. Fallatah, Mohamed M. Ibrahim, Abhinav Kumar, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-06991-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High stability cubic perovskite Sr0.9Y0.1Co1-Fe O3- oxygen evolution by phase control and electrochemical reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177709</link>
      <description>Hongyuan Song, Yijia Pang, Linjie Dong, Kun Dong, Haorong Wu, Liang-Wei Chen, Bin Liu, Zhen&#8208;Hua Ge, Lan Yu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1010(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404678888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongyuan Song, Yijia Pang, Linjie Dong, Kun Dong, Haorong Wu, Liang-Wei Chen, Bin Liu, Zhen&#8208;Hua Ge, Lan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Iridium Aerogel-Like Structures for Efficient and Stable Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4404681212</link>
      <description>Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Maillard, Delphine Clauss, Vincent Martin, Marta Mirolo, Jakub Drnec, Rapha&#235;l Chattot, La&#235;titia Dubau, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404681212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Maillard, Delphine Clauss, Vincent Martin, Marta Mirolo, Jakub Drnec, Rapha&#235;l Chattot, La&#235;titia Dubau</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4404681212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complex Oxide Containing Inherent Peroxide Ions for Catalyzing Oxygen Evolution Reactions in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11477</link>
      <description>Jie Dai, Zihan Shen, Yu Chen, Mengran Li, Vanessa K. Peterson, Jiayi Tang, Xixi Wang, Yu Li, Daqin Guan, Chuan Zhou, Hainan Sun, Zhiwei Hu, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Guangming Chen, Yinlong Zhu, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404690511

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers powered by sustainable energy represent a cutting-edge technology for renewable hydrogen generation, while slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics still remains a formidable obstacle that necessitates basic comprehension for facilitating electrocatalysts' design. Here, we report a low-iridium complex oxide La</description>
      <author>Jie Dai, Zihan Shen, Yu Chen, Mengran Li, Vanessa K. Peterson, Jiayi Tang, Xixi Wang, Yu Li, Daqin Guan, Chuan Zhou, Hainan Sun, Zhiwei Hu, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Guangming Chen, Yinlong Zhu, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymorph &#947;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Optimal Phase Composition for Stable Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06977</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Shuang Kong, Yimeng Sun, Qinqin Hu, Pengfei Zhang, Ailong Li, Kiyohiro Adachi, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura, Taifeng Liu, Can Li, Hongxian Han, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404691832

                The development of non-noble-metal oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts stable in acid to replace rare and expensive iridium catalysts is crucial yet challenging for the large-scale application of proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis technology. Here, we show that increasing the Pr (pyrolusite ratio) in &#947;-MnO2 from 73% to 84% results in about 10 times longer durability at a high working current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1 M H2SO4 for more than 1000 h. Dramatic stability enhancement is due to the inhibition of lattice Mn or O dissolution by leveraging the formation of more stable corner-shared pyrolusite MnO6 octahedra with a higher oxidation state of Mn, fewer defects, a shorter Mn&#8211;O bond distance, an increase in stable mono-oxo-bridged Mn&#8211;O&#8211;Mn pyrolusite MnO6 octahedra, and a decrease in di-oxo-bridged Mn&#8211;O2&#8211;Mn ramsdellite MnO6 octahedra with more Mn&#8211;Mn tension. Because polymorph materials like &#947;-MnO2 are quite common in nature, phase composition turning may serve as an effective strategy for the development of stable OER catalysts in acidic environments.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Shuang Kong, Yimeng Sun, Qinqin Hu, Pengfei Zhang, Ailong Li, Kiyohiro Adachi, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura, Taifeng Liu, Can Li, Hongxian Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction: Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi90086c</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhou, Xuan Hao, Jiexin Guan, Yilin Deng, Wei Zi, Yashu Liu, Guoxing Zhu, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404694208

                Correction for &#8216;Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution&#8217; by Hongbo Zhou et al. , Inorg. Chem. Front. , 2024, 11 , 8110&#8211;8122, https://doi.org/10.1039/D4QI01934B.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhou, Xuan Hao, Jiexin Guan, Yilin Deng, Wei Zi, Yashu Liu, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi90086c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological semimetals with intrinsic chirality as spin-controlling electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01674-9</link>
      <description>Xia Wang, Qun Yang, Sukriti Singh, Horst Borrmann, Vicky Hasse, Changjiang Yi, Yongkang Li, Marcus Schmidt, Xiaodong Li, Gerhard H. Fecher, Dong Zhou, Binghai Yan, Claudia Felser, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404699558

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting is a promising approach for clean hydrogen production, but the process is hindered by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) owing to the spin-dependent electron transfer process. Efforts to control spin through chirality and magnetization have shown potential in enhancing OER performance. Here we harnessed the potential of topological chiral semimetals (RhSi, RhSn and RhBiS) and their spin-polarized Fermi surfaces to promote the spin-dependent electron transfer in the OER, addressing the traditional volcano-plot limitations. We show that OER activities follow the trend RhSi &lt; RhSn &lt; RhBiS, corresponding to the increasing extent of spin&#8211;orbit coupling (SOC). The chiral single crystals outperform achiral counterparts (RhTe 2 , RhTe and RuO 2 ) in alkaline electrolyte, with RhBiS exhibiting a specific activity two orders of magnitude higher than RuO 2 . Our work reveals the pivotal roles of chirality and SOC in spin-dependent catalysis, facilitating the design of ultra-efficient chiral catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xia Wang, Qun Yang, Sukriti Singh, Horst Borrmann, Vicky Hasse, Changjiang Yi, Yongkang Li, Marcus Schmidt, Xiaodong Li, Gerhard H. Fecher, Dong Zhou, Binghai Yan, Claudia Felser</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01674-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate regulation of carbon skeletons bonded to Fe-N4 single atom nanozymes for efficient generation of reactive oxygen species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2268-7</link>
      <description>Fuchun Nan, Qilin Wei, Tongtong Kou, Yuxuan Zhao, Lanbo Shen, Dawei Li, Tong Chang, Li Wang, Fangfang Lang, William W. Yu, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404700779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuchun Nan, Qilin Wei, Tongtong Kou, Yuxuan Zhao, Lanbo Shen, Dawei Li, Tong Chang, Li Wang, Fangfang Lang, William W. Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2268-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered Nickel&#8211;Iron Nitride Electrocatalyst for Industrial&#8208;Scale Seawater Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202415421</link>
      <description>Huashuai Hu, Xunlu Wang, Zhaorui Zhang, Jiahao Liu, Xiaohui Yan, Xiaoli Wang, Jiacheng Wang, J. Paul Attfield, Minghui Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404700885

                Abstract Seawater electrolysis under alkaline conditions is a crucial technology for sustainable hydrogen production. However, achieving the long&#8208;term stability of the electrocatalyst remains a significant challenge. In this study, it is demonstrated that surface reconstruction of a transition metal nitride (TMN) can be used to develop a highly stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalyst. Rapid introduction of phosphate groups (PO 4 3&#8722; ) accelerates the in situ surface reconstruction of Ni 3 FeN, generating a catalyst, with a conductive nitride core and Cl &#8722; &#8208;resistant hydroxide shell that demonstrates outstanding performance, maintaining stability for over 2500 h at 1 A cm &#8722;2 current density in alkaline seawater. In situ characterization and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal the dynamic evolution of active sites, providing insights into the mechanisms driving long&#8208;term stability. This work not only introduces an efficient approach to TMN&#8208;based catalyst design but also advances the development of durable electrocatalysts for industrial&#8208;scale seawater hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Huashuai Hu, Xunlu Wang, Zhaorui Zhang, Jiahao Liu, Xiaohui Yan, Xiaoli Wang, Jiacheng Wang, J. Paul Attfield, Minghui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202415421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bead-Structured Triple-Doped Carbon Nanocage/Carbon Nanofiber Composite as a Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05385</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Yige Zhao, Bo Zhang, Yukun Li, Xiang Li, Guosheng Shao, Peng Zhang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404702649

                Zeolitic imidazolate framework (ZIF)-derived metal&#8211;nitrogen carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) materials are considered as promising electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) applied in rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). However, due to their unsatisfied conductivity and aggregation, appropriate regulations about structure and components are still necessary to achieve superior bifunctional performance. Herein, by simple ion exchange and one-step electrospinning method, a beaded composite electrocatalyst (Fe, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C/CNF) with Fe, Co, N codoped carbon nanocages uniformly embedded in the carbon nanofibers one by one was synthesized, achieving simultaneous structural and compositional regulation. Benefiting from the beaded-like structure and dual sites, the Fe, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C/CNF exhibits outstanding bifunctional catalytic performance for the ORR and the OER. Ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) reveals that Fe, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C/CNF has a low electron transfer barrier between active centers and the ORR (OER) intermediates, ultimately accelerating the reaction kinetics. In addition, the Fe, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C/CNF-based ZAB also demonstrates superior charge&#8211;discharge performance compared to the Pt/C-RuO2-based ZAB. This study not only offers an effective structural design strategy but also provides a component regulation method for ZIF-derived materials as bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Yige Zhao, Bo Zhang, Yukun Li, Xiang Li, Guosheng Shao, Peng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable and Energy-Saving Hydrogen Production via Binder-free and In-situ Electrodeposited Ni-Mn-S Nanowires on Ni-Cu 3-D Substrate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03486d</link>
      <description>Ghasem Barati Darband, Danial Iravani, Meiling Zhang, Meysam Maleki, Shun Huang, Seyyed Mehdi Khoshfetrat, Reza Andaveh, Jinyang Li, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404704477

                Electrochemical water splitting, with its oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), is undoubtedly the most eco-friendly and sustainable method to produce hydrogen. However, water splitting still requires...</description>
      <author>Ghasem Barati Darband, Danial Iravani, Meiling Zhang, Meysam Maleki, Shun Huang, Seyyed Mehdi Khoshfetrat, Reza Andaveh, Jinyang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03486d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe Dimers Incorporated within Ni(OH)2 Nanosheets to Enable Rapid Oxygen Radical Coupling and Exceptional Durability in Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124861</link>
      <description>Huanli Jia, Haiyan Wang, Fangfang Yan, Ze Li, Ruijian Li, Shenshen Li, Jianji Wang, Hucheng Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404704730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huanli Jia, Haiyan Wang, Fangfang Yan, Ze Li, Ruijian Li, Shenshen Li, Jianji Wang, Hucheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economical iron-based catalyst electrode for highly stable catalytic industrial-scale overall seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43979-024-00112-9</link>
      <description>Weiju Hao, Guoqing Huang, Xunwei Ma, Fengjing Lei, Shouxin Zhang, Jiacheng Zhang, Y. P. Guo, Guisheng Li, Carbon Neutrality. 3(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404704869

                Abstract The development of economical and stable catalyst electrodes for industrial-scale seawater splitting is one of the current challenges in hydrogen production. The economical transition metals possess high electrical conductivity and offer the potential for designing electrodes with high intrinsic activity through appropriate modifications, thus holding promising applications in industrial contexts. Herein, a durable and economical self-supported bifunctional electrode (Fe@Ni) with high efficiency and large area is successfully constructed by one step in-situ deposition of iron on the porous structure of nickel foam (NF) via mild (298 K) electroplating method. Transition metals like iron and nickel offer high electrical conductivity and can be properly modified to achieve electrodes with high intrinsic activity. Due to the in-situ growth of cost-effective iron on the NF surface, the electrode surface morphology and electronic structure are reconstructed, which significantly improves the electrochemical activity surface area and electron transfer capability of the electrode. The hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction (HER/OER) in simulated seawater (1 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl) require only 129 mV and 323 mV overpotentials to achieve a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Overall seawater splitting (OWS) achieves 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at a low voltage of 1.49 V and with a faradaic efficiency of nearly 100%. More importantly, the bifunctional electrodes remain stable at industrial-level current density (1.0 A cm &#8722;2 ) for more than 50 days. More attractively, this work realizes the universal construction of large-area electrode for multiple metals (e.g., Fe, Cu, Al, etc . ) with mild and simple process, which provides a new strategy for the current research of energy and materials.</description>
      <author>Weiju Hao, Guoqing Huang, Xunwei Ma, Fengjing Lei, Shouxin Zhang, Jiacheng Zhang, Y. P. Guo, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43979-024-00112-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pr&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;11&lt;/sub&gt; clusters anchored CoFe-LDH on vertical graphene nanosheets as oxygen evolution electrocatalyst for long-term high-current-density seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07515c</link>
      <description>Quan Wu, Xiaoyu Dong, Kefeng Ouyang, Youfa Liu, Hao Lei, Jie Yu, Yan Huang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404708300

                The severe catalyst corrosion caused by chlorides as well as industry-scale high current density are two critical issues for seawater electrolysis that need to be solved. Herein, due to the...</description>
      <author>Quan Wu, Xiaoyu Dong, Kefeng Ouyang, Youfa Liu, Hao Lei, Jie Yu, Yan Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07515c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core-shell cobalt-iron silicide electrocatalysts with enhanced bifunctional performance in hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.195</link>
      <description>Zhixuan Han, Yifu Zhang, Tianming Lv, Xianfang Tan, Qiushi Wang, Sheng Wang, Changgong Meng, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404710333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhixuan Han, Yifu Zhang, Tianming Lv, Xianfang Tan, Qiushi Wang, Sheng Wang, Changgong Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monolithic medium-entropy alloy electrode enables efficient and stable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110535</link>
      <description>Xiaoke Xi, Xinpeng Li, Yang Liu, Yucheng Zhang, Linmei Li, Jianming Li, Jin Xu, Shuhong Jiao, Zhanwu Lei, Ruiguo Cao, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404710412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoke Xi, Xinpeng Li, Yang Liu, Yucheng Zhang, Linmei Li, Jianming Li, Jin Xu, Shuhong Jiao, Zhanwu Lei, Ruiguo Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Surface and In-Depth Operational Performances of Oxygen-Evolving Anode Coatings: A Guideline for the Synthesis of Inert Durable Anodes in Metal Electrowinning from Acid Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14121339</link>
      <description>Jovana Bo&#353;njakovi&#263;, Vladimir Pani&#263;, Maja Stevanovi&#263;, Sre&#267;ko Stopi&#263;, Jasmina Stevanovi&#263;, Branimir Grgur, Gavrilo &#352;ekularac, Metals. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404711836

                The electrochemical performances of an oxygen-evolving anode produced by the reactivation of waste Ti substrate by a typical IrO2-Ta2O5 coating are correlated to the textural (non)uniformities of the coating and its exhaustion state. Coating degradation is considered operational loss of the activity in a metal electrowinning process. It was found that (pseudo)capacitive performances can vary over the coating surface by 20&#8211;30% and depend on the type of dynamics of the input perturbation: constant through cyclic voltammetry (CV) or discontinuous time-dependent through electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). CV-EIS data correlation enabled profiling of the capacitive properties through the depth of a coating and over its surface. The correlation was confirmed by the findings for the analysis of coating activity for an oxygen evolution reaction, finally resulting in the reliable proposition of a mechanism for the operational loss of the anode. It was found that the less compact and thicker coating parts performed better and operated more efficiently, especially at lower operational current densities.</description>
      <author>Jovana Bo&#353;njakovi&#263;, Vladimir Pani&#263;, Maja Stevanovi&#263;, Sre&#267;ko Stopi&#263;, Jasmina Stevanovi&#263;, Branimir Grgur, Gavrilo &#352;ekularac</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14121339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Dense CoRu&#8208;CoMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Heterointerfaces with Electron Redistribution for Synergistically Boosted Alkaline Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409159</link>
      <description>Huamei Tong, Shengjie Xu, Xinyu Zheng, Mengyue Qi, Jianjun Zhu, Di Li, Deli Jiang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718235

                Abstract Constructing metal alloys/metal oxides heterostructured electrocatalysts with abundant and strongly coupling interfaces is vital yet challenging for practical electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, CoRu nanoalloys uniformly anchored on CoMoO 4 nanosheet heterostructured electrocatalyst (CoRu&#8208;CoMoO 4 /NF) are synthesized via a self&#8208;templated strategy by simply annealing of Ru&#8208;etched CoMoO 4 /NF precursor in a reduction atmosphere. The dense and robustly coupled interface not only provides abundant active sites for water splitting but also strengthens the charge transfer efficiency. Furthermore, the theoretical calculations unveil that the strong electronic interaction at CoRu&#8208;CoMoO 4 interface can induce an interfacial electron redistribution and reduce the energetic barriers for the hydrogen and oxygen intermediates, thereby accelerating the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics. The resultant catalyst only requires the overpotentials of 49 mV for HER and 209 mV for OER at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Moreover, the constructed CoRu&#8208;CoMoO 4 ||CoRu&#8208;CoMoO 4 two&#8208;electrode cell achieves a cell voltage of 1.54 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , outperforming the benchmark Pt/C||IrO 2 . This work explores an avenue for the rational design of heterostructured electrocatalysts with abundant interfaces for practical water&#8208;splitting electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Huamei Tong, Shengjie Xu, Xinyu Zheng, Mengyue Qi, Jianjun Zhu, Di Li, Deli Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Nitride Controlled Atomic Doping of Mo&lt;sup&gt;x+&lt;/sup&gt; in NiFe (Oxy)Hydroxide to Trigger Lattice Oxygen&#8208;Mediated Mechanism for Superior Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418439</link>
      <description>J.G. Wang, Zhenyu Xing, Ran Kang, Yijuan Zheng, Zhen Zhang, Tian Ma, Yi Wang, Bo Yin, Yaozu Liao, Liang Li, Chong Cheng, Shuang Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718250

                Abstract The covalency of the metal&#9472;oxygen (M&#9472;O) bond is significantly amplified in the transition metal sites with elevated oxidation states, thereby enabling the lattice oxygen&#8208;mediated mechanism (LOM) to transcend the traditional linear scaling limitations of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, an innovative surface atom release speed&#8208;mediated doping of Mo atoms in NiFe (oxy)hydroxides by controlled dissolution of Mo atoms from the Mo 2 N surface, which resulted in the formation of NiFeMo(OH) 2 with high valence Ni species for OER. Structural characterizations, coupled with in situ Raman and theoretical calculations, elucidate that the incorporation of Mo in NiFeMo(OH) 2 modulates the electronic configuration of the metal centers, thereby diminishing the formation energy of Ni 3+/4+ species. This modulation augments the M&#9472;O bond covalency, facilitating a shift in the OER pathway from the conventional absorbate evolution mechanism to the more efficient LOM. Consequently, the NiFeMo(OH) 2 displays a low overpotential of 236 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , along with long stability (&gt;500 h) at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . Furthermore, when integrated into an anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer, it achieves a current density of 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at a cell voltage of merely 2.27 V, underscoring its potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>J.G. Wang, Zhenyu Xing, Ran Kang, Yijuan Zheng, Zhen Zhang, Tian Ma, Yi Wang, Bo Yin, Yaozu Liao, Liang Li, Chong Cheng, Shuang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shedding Light on the Active Species in a Cobalt&#8208;Based Covalent Organic Framework for the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202413555</link>
      <description>Pouya Hosseini, Andr&#233;s Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Camargo, Yiqun Jiang, Shouxin Zhang, Christina Scheu, Liang Yao, Bettina V. Lotsch, Kristina Tschulik, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404723714

                Abstract While considerable efforts have been devoted to developing functionalized covalent organic frameworks (COFs) as oxygen evolution electrocatalysts in recent years, studies related to the investigation of the true catalytically active species for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remain lacking in the field. In this work, the active species of a cobalt&#8208;functionalized COF (TpBpy&#8208;Co) is studied as electrochemical OER catalyst through a series of electrochemical measurements and post&#8208;electrolysis characterizations. These results suggest that cobalt oxide&#8208;based nanoparticles are formed in TpBpy&#8208;Co from Co(II) ions coordinated to the COF backbone when exposing TpBpy&#8208;Co to alkaline media, and these newly formed nanoparticles serve as the primary active species for oxygen evolution. The study thus emphasizes that caution is warranted when assessing the catalytic activity of COF electrocatalysts, as the pristine COF may act as the pre&#8208;catalyst, with the active species forming only under catalyst operating conditions. Specifically, strong coordination between COFs and metal centers under electrochemical operation conditions is crucial to avoid unintended transformation of COF electrocatalysts. This work thus contributes to the rational development of earth&#8208;abundant COF OER catalysts for the production of green hydrogen from renewable resources.</description>
      <author>Pouya Hosseini, Andr&#233;s Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Camargo, Yiqun Jiang, Shouxin Zhang, Christina Scheu, Liang Yao, Bettina V. Lotsch, Kristina Tschulik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202413555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering of bifunctional nanocomposite with enhanced redox-type energy storage and oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158014</link>
      <description>Samikannu Prabu, Goli Nagaraju, Sivaprakash Sengodan, Kung&#8208;Yuh Chiang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404726700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samikannu Prabu, Goli Nagaraju, Sivaprakash Sengodan, Kung&#8208;Yuh Chiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-dimensional multilevel stalactite-like Ni3S2-Fe(Mo2S4) bifunctional electrocatalyst with excellent oxygen evolution reaction and overall water splitting performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.193</link>
      <description>Ning Zhao, Lan Mu, Wenbo Liao, Gang Zhao, Mei Xue, Meng Ding, Yuxiang Dai, Xijin Xu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404728328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Zhao, Lan Mu, Wenbo Liao, Gang Zhao, Mei Xue, Meng Ding, Yuxiang Dai, Xijin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Organized Integrated Electrocatalyst on Oxygen Conversion for Highly Durable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416664</link>
      <description>Qian Chang, Feng He, Zhihui Zhang, Xinlong Fu, Wei Wang, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730109

                Efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are key for clean energy applications such as rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries. Highly efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts have been the focus of great attention by scientists. Here, an innovative and continuous growth method is established to fabricate integrated Janus structure Co3O4/CoNGDY catalyst, which can work for bifunctional oxygen catalytic conversion, achieving highly durable zinc&#8208;air batteries. Embedded in the hydrangea&#8208;shaped N&#8208;doped graphdiyne (NGDY), the Co3O4/CoNGDY is self&#8208;organized by CoNGDY at the NGDY contact sites and Co3O4 at the upper part, in which Co3O4 works as OER catalyst and CoNGDY acts as ORR catalyst. Due to the incomplete charge transfer within integrated structure, NGDY reduces the d&#8208;band center of the Co sites, so the adsorption strength of intermediates is balanced, and the catalytic activity for ORR/OER is increased. The Co3O4/CoNGDY can serve as an efficient air electrode of rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries. The rechargeable Co3O4/CoNGDY&#8208;based aqueous zinc&#8208;air batteries demonstrate excellent performance with a high specific capacity of 746.8 mAh g&#8722;1 and an extremely long lifetime of more than 5000 hours. The recoverable modularized cylindrical Co3O4/CoNGDY&#8208;based solid&#8208;state zinc&#8208;air batteries with a power density of up to 167.6 mW cm&#8722;2 can be achieved.</description>
      <author>Qian Chang, Feng He, Zhihui Zhang, Xinlong Fu, Wei Wang, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Organized Integrated Electrocatalyst on Oxygen Conversion for Highly Durable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416664</link>
      <description>Qian Chang, Feng He, Zhihui Zhang, Xinlong Fu, Li Wang, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730180

                Efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are key for clean energy applications such as rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries. Highly efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts have been the focus of great attention by scientists. Here, an innovative and continuous growth method is established to fabricate integrated Janus structure Co3O4/CoNGDY catalyst, which can work for bifunctional oxygen catalytic conversion, achieving highly durable zinc&#8208;air batteries. Embedded in the hydrangea&#8208;shaped N&#8208;doped graphdiyne (NGDY), the Co3O4/CoNGDY is self&#8208;organized by CoNGDY at the NGDY contact sites and Co3O4 at the upper part, in which Co3O4 works as OER catalyst and CoNGDY acts as ORR catalyst. Due to the incomplete charge transfer within integrated structure, NGDY reduces the d&#8208;band center of the Co sites, so the adsorption strength of intermediates is balanced, and the catalytic activity for ORR/OER is increased. The Co3O4/CoNGDY can serve as an efficient air electrode of rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries. The rechargeable Co3O4/CoNGDY&#8208;based aqueous zinc&#8208;air batteries demonstrate excellent performance with a high specific capacity of 746.8 mAh g&#8722;1 and an extremely long lifetime of more than 5000 hours. The recoverable modularized cylindrical Co3O4/CoNGDY&#8208;based solid&#8208;state zinc&#8208;air batteries with a power density of up to 167.6 mW cm&#8722;2 can be achieved.</description>
      <author>Qian Chang, Feng He, Zhihui Zhang, Xinlong Fu, Li Wang, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution kinetics, supercapacitor and display applications of Europium doped ZnSnO3 nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.140801</link>
      <description>Vishwalinga Prasad B., C. Ningappa, H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, R. Sahana, K.N. Sridhar, K. Manjunatha, Sheng Yun Wu, Journal of Molecular Structure. 1324(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404738480

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vishwalinga Prasad B., C. Ningappa, H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, R. Sahana, K.N. Sridhar, K. Manjunatha, Sheng Yun Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.140801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alternating current and electrolyte engineering-promoted surface reconstruction of NiFeOxHy catalysts for amper-level oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.192</link>
      <description>Chenyang Cai, Zhilin Zhang, Yutao Hua, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Xinchuan Du, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Jinhui Hao, Weidong Shi, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404739506

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenyang Cai, Zhilin Zhang, Yutao Hua, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Xinchuan Du, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Jinhui Hao, Weidong Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Water Splitting in Isoindigo&#8208;based Covalent Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419836</link>
      <description>Ali Trabolsi, Gobinda Das, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Fayrouz Abou Ibrahim, Areej Merhi, Huda N. Dirawi, Farah Benyettou, Akshaya Kumar Das, Thirumurugan Prakasam, Sabu Varghese, Sudhir Kumar Sharma, Serdal K&#305;rm&#305;z&#305;alt&#305;n, Ramesh Jagannathan, Felipe G&#225;ndara, Samer Aouad, Mark A. Olson, Subrata Kumar Kundu, Bilal R. Kaafarani, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404739567

                Developing a low&#8208;cost, robust, and high&#8208;performance electrocatalyst capable of efficiently performing both the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under both basic and acidic conditions is a major challenge. This area of research has attracted much attention in recent decades due to its importance in energy storage and conversion. Herein, we report the synthesis of two imine&#8208;linked isoindigo&#8208;based covalent organic networks. The combination of isoindigo dialdehyde with a planar triazine core, leads to the formation of thin, highly crystalline, planar 2D&#8208;nanosheets covalent organic framework (I&#8208;TTA COF), whereas its combination with ionic non&#8208;planar guanidinium core leads to an amorphous covalent organic polymer (I&#8208;TG COP) with a fibrous morphology. The sheet&#8208;like crystalline I&#8208;TTA COF shows better electrocatalytic activity compared to the amorphous fibrous I&#8208;TG COP. I&#8208;TTA exhibits a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at an overpotential of ~134 mV for HER (in 0.5 M H2SO4) and ~283 mV for OER (in 1 M KOH). The electrocatalytic activity of the I&#8208;TTA COF in the OER exceeds that of other metal&#8208;free COFs. The catalytic activity is maintained even after 24 hours of chronoamperometry and 500 cycles of cyclic voltammetry (CV) at high scan rates.</description>
      <author>Ali Trabolsi, Gobinda Das, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Fayrouz Abou Ibrahim, Areej Merhi, Huda N. Dirawi, Farah Benyettou, Akshaya Kumar Das, Thirumurugan Prakasam, Sabu Varghese, Sudhir Kumar Sharma, Serdal K&#305;rm&#305;z&#305;alt&#305;n, Ramesh Jagannathan, Felipe G&#225;ndara, Samer Aouad, Mark A. Olson, Subrata Kumar Kundu, Bilal R. Kaafarani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Screening of Multifunctional Single-Atom Catalysts Supported by Vs2 Monolayer for the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution, Oxygen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5034793</link>
      <description>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404749614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5034793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsymmetric Protonation Driven Highly Efficient H2O2 Photosynthesis in Supramolecular Photocatalysts via One&#8208;Step Two&#8208;Electron Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421356</link>
      <description>Wenting Li, Bing Han, Yuhan Liu, Jingyi Xu, Huarui He, Gege Wang, Junshan Li, Yaxin Zhai, Xiaolin Zhu, Yongfa Zhu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404755108

                Photocatalytic hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) production has emerged as an attractive alternative to the traditional anthraquinone process. However, its performance is often hindered by low selectivity and sluggish kinetics of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Herein, we report an anthrazoline&#8208;based supramolecular photocatalyst, SA&#8208;SADF&#8208;H+, featuring an unsymmetric protonation structure for H2O2 photosynthesis from water and air. The introduction of unsymmetric protonation disrupts the initial mirror symmetry of SADF, significantly enhancing the molecular dipole and facilitating efficient charge separation and electron transfer. Additionally, this modification increases the hydrophilicity of SA&#8208;SADF&#8208;H+, enabling the interaction of water and dissolved oxygen with the catalytic sites. The altered electron density distribution creates numerous dual active sites for Yeager&#8208;type O2 adsorption, facilitating an efficient ORR towards H2O2 via a direct one&#8208;step two&#8208;electron pathway. Notably, SA&#8208;SADF&#8208;H+ achieves an outstanding photocatalytic H2O2 production at a rate of 4667 &#956;mol L&#8208;1 h&#8208;1, with a remarkable solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion (SCC) of 1.35%, surpassing most organic photocatalytic systems. Furthermore, SA&#8208;SADF&#8208;H+ demonstrates remarkable photocatalytic antibacterial activity, achieving 100% antibacterial efficiency against Staphylococcus aureus within 60 min.</description>
      <author>Wenting Li, Bing Han, Yuhan Liu, Jingyi Xu, Huarui He, Gege Wang, Junshan Li, Yaxin Zhai, Xiaolin Zhu, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeNi/Ni2P nanoparticles encapsulated in nitrogen-doped porous carbon: efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-10433-w</link>
      <description>Tianrui Yu, Yuhong Zhang, Jinzhou Chen, Mingxin Feng, Zewu Zhang, Yuming Zhou, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404757609

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianrui Yu, Yuhong Zhang, Jinzhou Chen, Mingxin Feng, Zewu Zhang, Yuming Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-10433-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing In2S3/FeVO4/CNT Photoelectrode for Enhanced Visible Light Driven Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401192</link>
      <description>Nitika Garg, Sandeep Kumar, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404763487

                The development of efficient and stable photoelectrodes is essential for the advancement of photoelectrochemical (PEC) water&#8208;splitting technologies, which hold promise for efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER), necessary for sustainable hydrogen production. In this study, the synthesis of a ternary composite, In2S3/FeVO4/CNT has been reported, designed for highly efficient PEC oxygen evolution. The formation of In2S3/FeVO4 heterostructure enhances PEC performance significantly due to the type&#8208;II band alignment, which minimizes electron&#8208;hole recombination and improves charge separation The addition of CNTs further enhances performance by providing conductive pathways that improve electron transport and reduce charge transfer resistance. The resulting In2S3/FeVO4/CNT ternary composite achieves a current density of 14.70 mAcm&#8722;2 at 1.8 V vs. RHE, representing a notable increase in performance. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) shows that the ternary composite has the lowest charge transfer resistance, while Bode phase analysis indicates a longer carrier lifetime, emphasizing the synergistic effect of heterostructure formation and CNT inclusion. The ternary composite also demonstrates excellent stability and responsiveness during transient photocurrent cycling, maintaining performance under repeated illumination, making it a strong candidate for water&#8208;splitting applications driven by visible light.</description>
      <author>Nitika Garg, Sandeep Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Doping of 2D Nickel-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks Enhances the Lattice Heterogeneous Interface Coupling Effect for Improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04507</link>
      <description>T. C. Huang, Ya&#8208;Ling Wu, Zhaopeng Sun, Yingying Chen, Shuangying Lei, Yangdan Pan, Lian&#8208;Wen Zhu, Dan Li&#365;, Xuebo Cao, Yan Zheng, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404765783

                The coupling of lattice and heterostructure interfaces represents an effective strategy for disrupting the so-called scalar relationship and accelerating reactions involving multiple intermediates. In view of this, a lattice-heterostructure interfacial catalyst consisting of a crystalline Fe/Ni bimetallic MOF and amorphous Fe-MOF was designed in this paper for high-performance alkaline oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysis. The strongly coupled lattice-heterostructure interface induces a unique synergistic effect that promotes electron transfer of the catalyst. The resulting catalyst exhibits exceptionally high catalytic activity for the oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media, the</description>
      <author>T. C. Huang, Ya&#8208;Ling Wu, Zhaopeng Sun, Yingying Chen, Shuangying Lei, Yangdan Pan, Lian&#8208;Wen Zhu, Dan Li&#365;, Xuebo Cao, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04507</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical NiFe-Layered Double Hydroxide Coupled with Bimetallic NiFe-MOF Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04815</link>
      <description>Weipeng Wang, Chunbo Liu, Jihui Lang, Tianyu Zhou, Feifan Guo, Wei Jiang, Jingdong Feng, Xiaotian Yang, Guangbo Che, Yuanyuan Wu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404767492

                It is crucial to utilize extremely efficient and economical catalysts for the energy-intensive and kinetically slow oxygen evolution process. Here, we fabricated a NiFeLDH coupled with the NiFe-MOF catalyst with a unique hierarchical structure using a facile and rapid electrodeposition and electrochemical activation strategy. With a low overpotential of about 187 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, the NiFeLDH/NiFe-MOF/NF demonstrates exceptional stability for more than 1000 h. Additionally, the produced NiFeLDH/NiFe-MOF/NF could provide high current densities of 500 and 1000 mA cm&#8211;2 in 6 M KOH at relatively low overpotentials of 293 and 353 mV, respectively. The construction of heterojunctions provides abundant interfacial active sites and optimizes catalytic activity by adjusting the surface electronic structure and energy levels. This serves to enhance the intrinsic activity of the catalyst. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations further prove that the construction of NiFeLDH regulates the band structure of metal sites, enhances the catalytic performance for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and lowers the intermediate medium's adsorption free energy.</description>
      <author>Weipeng Wang, Chunbo Liu, Jihui Lang, Tianyu Zhou, Feifan Guo, Wei Jiang, Jingdong Feng, Xiaotian Yang, Guangbo Che, Yuanyuan Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04815</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in electric field guides oxygen evolution electrocatalysts reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04740k</link>
      <description>Chunmei Ni, Kun Wang, LJ Jin, Yan Liu, Jie Chen, Lida Yang, Chang&#8208;Hyeon Ji, Hui Xu, Li Zhao, Lin Tian, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404767653

                Creating built-in electric field (BIEF) in catalysts represents an effective strategy to promote electron transfer and induce asymmetric charge distribution, thereby facilitating surface dynamic reconstruction under oxygen evolution reaction (OER)...</description>
      <author>Chunmei Ni, Kun Wang, LJ Jin, Yan Liu, Jie Chen, Lida Yang, Chang&#8208;Hyeon Ji, Hui Xu, Li Zhao, Lin Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04740k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Engineering of B/N-Doped Graphene with Phosphorus-Transition Metal Diatomic Catalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Bifunctionality Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105532</link>
      <description>Bo Yang, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Liang Tian, Xuefei Liu, Mingqiang Liu, Wenjun Xiao, Xiangyu Wu, Jiajin Ge, Yanchun Li, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Zhen Wang, Wu Yan, Wei Deng, Changsong Gao, Jinshun Bi, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404768559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Yang, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Liang Tian, Xuefei Liu, Mingqiang Liu, Wenjun Xiao, Xiangyu Wu, Jiajin Ge, Yanchun Li, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Zhen Wang, Wu Yan, Wei Deng, Changsong Gao, Jinshun Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cef3-Accelerated Surface Reconstruction of Moo2 Nanosheets into 3d Coral-Like Cef3/Moo2 Composites Enhances the Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5036853</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Chenglin Liu, Xianglin Qiu, Tianshuo Zhang, Shanshan Gao, Fushan Chen, Xiaoming Song, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Chenglin Liu, Xianglin Qiu, Tianshuo Zhang, Shanshan Gao, Fushan Chen, Xiaoming Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5036853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Oxygen Vacancy in SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles to Achieve Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Performance in Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05558</link>
      <description>Xiaoli Ran, Yang Bai, Hao Zeng, Junhao Zhang, Haitao Fu, Xizhong An, Xiaohong Yang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404773317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoli Ran, Yang Bai, Hao Zeng, Junhao Zhang, Haitao Fu, Xizhong An, Xiaohong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05558</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni/Fe Fluorides (Hydroxide) Nanocomposite as Efficient OER Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400701</link>
      <description>Yanli Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Liangliang Dong, Li Wang, Xiangming He, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404773412

                The synthesis of efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts that markedly reduce the overpotential over an extended period is crucial for electrolytic water splitting toward hydrogen production. A kind of Ni/Fe fluoride (hydroxide) nanocomposite OER catalyst is designed and prepared by a two&#8208;step method for the first time. The nanocomposite with the optimal OER performance (Ni:Fe precursor ratio of 9:1) is observed to possess a nanoparticle morphology with size of about 100 nm. Each nanoparticle hosts extensive nanoregions of Ni4OHF7, NiFeF5&#8729;2H2O and Fe1.9F4.75&#8729;0.95H2O phases. The optimal nanocomposite (Ni:Fe precursor ratio of 9:1) exhibits OER overpotential of merely 208 mV and 349 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and 100 mA cm&#8208;2 respectively, tafel slope of 53.1, and outstanding stability for 10 h duration at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. The superior OER catalytic performance of the optimal nanocomposite after CV activation is mainly ascribed to the comprehensive catalytic effect of multiple Ni, Fe active sites from three phases, the smaller charge transfer resistance achieved at this particular Ni:Fe precursor ratio. The abundant resources of Ni, Fe, F elements and the superior OER properties of the Ni/Fe fluorides (hydroxide) nanocomposite, makes it a good OER catalyst candidate for electrolytic water splitting toward hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Yanli Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Liangliang Dong, Li Wang, Xiangming He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation&#8208;Modified Co&#8208;Based Borophosphates for Efficient and Robust Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202404089</link>
      <description>Meng Yan, Dong&#8208;Sheng Pan, Ao Wang, Jun&#8208;Ling Song, ChemistrySelect. 9(45)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404780805

                Abstract The development of cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical and challenging in the field of electrocatalytic water splitting for industrial applications. Herein, a series of cations (Fe, Ni, and Zn)&#8208;doped Co&#8208;based borophosphates with an anion skeleton (Na 2 CoB 3 P 2 O 11 (OH)&#183; n H 2 O are prepared by a simple hydrothermal method, in which the cation dopants could be easily achieved via a simple cation exchange during the hydrothermal reaction process. Especially, the Fe dopant increases active sites, improves charge&#8208;mass transfer, and tunes the electronic structures of the Co&#8208;based borophosphate electrode. The optimal Fe&#8208;doped NaCBPO (NaC 3 FBPO), with the cobalt to iron molar ratio of 3, shows a low overpotential of 289 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and it can be stable for 16 h at this current density. Above all, it has a fast reaction rate with a low Tafel slope of 84.25 mV&#183;dec &#8722;1 . This work provides a promising transition metal&#8208;based borophosphates materials with high efficiency and durability toward water splitting.</description>
      <author>Meng Yan, Dong&#8208;Sheng Pan, Ao Wang, Jun&#8208;Ling Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202404089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trisodium Citrate&#8208;Assisted Synthesis of Edge&#8208;Abundant Nickel&#8208;iron Layered Double Hydroxides for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401667</link>
      <description>Jiang Qu, Xiao Hu, Marielle Deconinck, Lixiang Liu, Yapeng Cheng, Ruyan Zhao, Mingchao Wang, Haining Zhang, Yana Vaynzof, J&#246;rg Schuster, Andreu Cabot, Karin Leistner, Fei Li, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404787231

                The edges of layered double hydroxides (LDHs) display an exceptionally efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity than the (001) basal plane as demonstrated by both theoretical calculations and experimental studies. However, a controllable synthesis method of LDHs with abundant edges has yet to be described. Herein, we report a strategy enabling the synthesis of nickel&#8208;iron LDHs with abundant edges (NiFe LDHs&#8208;E) based on the use of citrate anions as the structure&#8208;directing agent. The edge density is characterized using spectroscopy techniques and its OER performance is compared with that of nickel&#8208;iron LDHs with abundant basal planes (NiFe LDHs&#8208;B). In alkaline electrolyte (1M KOH), NiFe LDHs&#8208;E exhibits excellent OER activity with very low overpotential (235 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2) and current densities up to sixfold (at &#951; = 320 mV) higher than those of NiFe LDHs&#8208;B. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations confirm the high OER activities ascribed to the abundant side&#8208;plane edges with optimal strength of binding of OER intermediates. Overall, a comprehensive investigation, employing both experimental and computational methodologies, yields new insights to fabricate superior catalysts meticulously designed with specific crystal planes and unveils the crucial structural attributes, thus unleashing the limitless potential of the catalytic domain.</description>
      <author>Jiang Qu, Xiao Hu, Marielle Deconinck, Lixiang Liu, Yapeng Cheng, Ruyan Zhao, Mingchao Wang, Haining Zhang, Yana Vaynzof, J&#246;rg Schuster, Andreu Cabot, Karin Leistner, Fei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implications for Oxygen Evolution Spinel-based Electrocatalyst in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyser: A Review from Structural Engineering perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177819</link>
      <description>Iswary Letchumanan, Wei Shi Ng, Mohd Shahbudin Masdar, Azim Fitri Zainul Abidin, Nurul Akidah Baharuddin, Rozan Mohamad Yunus, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404794496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Iswary Letchumanan, Wei Shi Ng, Mohd Shahbudin Masdar, Azim Fitri Zainul Abidin, Nurul Akidah Baharuddin, Rozan Mohamad Yunus</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nanotubes cross-linked Fe/Fe3C Nanoparticles and Fe Single Atoms as High-efficiency Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145427</link>
      <description>Zhiwen Xu, Lanlu Lu, Weiwei Chen, Fei Yang, Guimei Liu, Yan Sun, Xiaoyi Qiu, Meng Gu, Ping Gao, Dong Su, Minhua Shao, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404797231

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiwen Xu, Lanlu Lu, Weiwei Chen, Fei Yang, Guimei Liu, Yan Sun, Xiaoyi Qiu, Meng Gu, Ping Gao, Dong Su, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium-based electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.033</link>
      <description>Yanhui Yu, Gai Li, Yutong Xiao, Chi Chen, Yuhang Bai, Wei Wang, Jing Li, Yingjie Hua, Daoxiong Wu, Peng Rao, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Y. Yuan, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404801259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanhui Yu, Gai Li, Yutong Xiao, Chi Chen, Yuhang Bai, Wei Wang, Jing Li, Yingjie Hua, Daoxiong Wu, Peng Rao, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Y. Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Electrochemical Performance of Co3O4/ZnO Composite Nanostructures through Interface Engineering for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135858</link>
      <description>K. Mallikarjuna, Kiran Kumar Ganta, Tarun Kumar, Nadavala Siva Kumar, Mohammad Asif, S.V. Prabhakar Vattikuti, Jaesool Shim, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404814566

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Mallikarjuna, Kiran Kumar Ganta, Tarun Kumar, Nadavala Siva Kumar, Mohammad Asif, S.V. Prabhakar Vattikuti, Jaesool Shim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancy mediated TiO2-x-MoS2/FTO heterostructure as an efficient photoanode for photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.11.043</link>
      <description>Mahdieh Rezaei, Ali A. Ensafi, Esmaeil Heydari&#8208;Bafrooei, Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404814699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mahdieh Rezaei, Ali A. Ensafi, Esmaeil Heydari&#8208;Bafrooei</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.11.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic MIL&#8208;88/Polyaniline Hybrid Hollow Structure: In&#8208;situ Synthesis and Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction at High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403141</link>
      <description>Ying Liu, Hong&#8208;Yan Lin, Congcong Wang, Kai Zhang, Bai Yang, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404817862

                Abstract Developing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts in an efficient strategy, while maintaining high catalytic activity and stability under high current densities, remains a crucial problem. In this study, a bimetallic iron&#8208;cobalt phytic acid complex loaded with polyaniline hollow structure (FCP@PAn) was successfully constructed, via a progress of selective etching and surface modification in one step without high&#8208;temperature phosphating or carbonization. The as&#8208;obtained FCP@PAn required only 329 and 385 mV overpotentials at high current densities of 500 and 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively, due to phytic acid and polyaniline incorporation and the coordinated effect of each component. Additionally, the FCP@PAn exhibited the lowest Tafel slope values of 44.6 mV dec &#8722;1 and was able to continuously operate for 120 h at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 , displaying high catalytic activity and stability. Hence, the hollow structure of the conductive polymer and MOFs composites provided a new surface modification strategy for transition metal&#8208;based catalysts that are prone to dissolution or corrosion during the OER process, as well as for high current density applications.</description>
      <author>Ying Liu, Hong&#8208;Yan Lin, Congcong Wang, Kai Zhang, Bai Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distorted MO6 octahedral unit on the activity and stability for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04992f</link>
      <description>Huaixin Yang, Xin Ning, W. B. Yan, Hua Gui Yang, Haiyang Yuan, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635654

                Metal oxides have garnered significant attention in oxygen evolution reaction (OER), where the distorted MO6 octahedral unit has a marked impact on their performance. This study introduces the distortion coefficient...</description>
      <author>Huaixin Yang, Xin Ning, W. B. Yan, Hua Gui Yang, Haiyang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04992f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-step Preparation of Amorphous Citrate-Chelated CoNiFe Trimetallic Hydroxides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04240a</link>
      <description>Jin Zhou, Yuhong Zhang, Tianrui Yu, Mingxin Feng, Tong Wang, Chaobo Tong, Zewu Zhang, Jiehua Bao, Yuming Zhou, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404668004

                Reasonable morphology regulation and electronic structure modulation enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of the catalyst. In this study, amorphous citrate-chelated CoNiFe trimetallic hydroxide nanoparticles were synthesized in one...</description>
      <author>Jin Zhou, Yuhong Zhang, Tianrui Yu, Mingxin Feng, Tong Wang, Chaobo Tong, Zewu Zhang, Jiehua Bao, Yuming Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04240a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe/Co bimetallic borides with modified electronic structure for Efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161893</link>
      <description>Shuai Wan, Lihong Bao, Yuyang Zong, Jiayu Xiao, Jiaru He, Xinyu Gao, Sheng Wang, Ruguang Ma, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631327

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Wan, Lihong Bao, Yuyang Zong, Jiayu Xiao, Jiaru He, Xinyu Gao, Sheng Wang, Ruguang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161893</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and kinetic analysis of the oxygen evolution reaction on TiO2 (100) and (101) surfaces: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122654</link>
      <description>Felipe Marinho Fernandes, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, M&#225;rcio Soares Pereira, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404642081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Felipe Marinho Fernandes, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, M&#225;rcio Soares Pereira, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Zhang, Xuanyu Zhou, Kongliang Luo, Yaning Fan, Chuandong He, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404647510

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Zhang, Xuanyu Zhou, Kongliang Luo, Yaning Fan, Chuandong He, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Similarity between oxygen evolution in photosystem II and oxygen reduction in cytochrome c oxidase via proton coupled electron transfers. A unified view of the oxygenic life from four electron oxidation&#8211;reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43630-024-00648-w</link>
      <description>K. Yamaguchi, Koichi Miyagawa, Mitsuo Shoji, Hiroshi Isobe, Takashi Kawakami, Photochemical &amp; Photobiological Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404611030

                Abstract Basic concepts and theoretical foundations of broken symmetry (BS) and post BS methods for strongly correlated electron systems (SCES) such as electron-transfer (ET) diradical, multi-center polyradicals with spin frustration are described systematically to elucidate structures, bonding and reactivity of the high-valent transition metal oxo bonds in metalloenzymes: photosystem II (PSII) and cytochrome c oxidase (C c O). BS hybrid DFT (HDFT) and DLPNO coupled-cluster (CC) SD(T 0 ) computations are performed to elucidate electronic and spin states of CaMn 4 O x cluster in the key step for oxygen evolution, namely S 4 [S 3 with Mn(IV) = O + Tyr161-O radical] state of PSII and P M [Fe(IV) = O + HO-Cu(II) + Tyr161-O radical] step for oxygen reduction in C c O. The cycle of water oxidation catalyzed by the CaMn 4 O x cluster in PSII and the cycle of oxygen reduction catalyzed by the Cu A -Fe a -Fe a3 -Cu B cluster in C c O are examined on the theoretical grounds, elucidating similar concerted and/or stepwise proton transfer coupled electron transfer (PT-ET) processes for the four-electron oxidation in PSII and four-electron reduction in C c O. Interplay between theory and experiments have revealed that three electrons in the metal sites and one electron in tyrosine radical site are characteristic for PT-ET in these biological redox reaction systems, indicating no necessity of harmful Mn(V) = O and Fe(V) = O bonds with strong oxyl-radical character. Implications of the computational results are discussed in relation to design of artificial systems consisted of earth abundant transition metals for water oxidation. Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>K. Yamaguchi, Koichi Miyagawa, Mitsuo Shoji, Hiroshi Isobe, Takashi Kawakami</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43630-024-00648-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing the carbon nano-belt (8-CNB) loaded late second-row transition metal (TM) single-atom catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution during water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109139</link>
      <description>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Shimna Biju, Remabai Balachandran, Khurshid Ayub, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 187(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404670172

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulrahman Allangawi, Shimna Biju, Remabai Balachandran, Khurshid Ayub, Mazhar Amjad Gilani, Muhammad Imran, Tariq Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.109139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal synthesis of tungsten oxide photo/electrocatalysts: precursor-driven morphological tailoring and electrochemical performance for hydrogen evolution and oxygen reduction reaction application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-35607-6</link>
      <description>Rahul Sarma, Biraj Kumar Kakati, Environmental Science and Pollution Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404734191

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahul Sarma, Biraj Kumar Kakati</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-35607-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction Really Need To Be Suppressed in O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Tolerant CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Catalyzed by DAE-BPy-CoPor and Co-TAPP?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02957</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404771815

                This letter chooses DAE-BPy-CoPor [DAE, 1,2-bis(5'-formyl-2'-methylthien-3'-yl)cyclopentene; BPy, 2,2'-bipyridine-5,5'-dicarbaldehyde; and CoPor, two-dimensional cobalt porphyrin-based covalent organic framework] and Co-TAPP [10,15,20-tetrakis(4-aminophenyl)porphinatocobalt] as two model catalysts to investigate the effect of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in the O</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand&#8208;Tuning Metallic Sites in Molecular Complexes for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415755</link>
      <description>Yun Gao, Chengdong Yang, Fenglei Sun, Daping He, Xinqiang Wang, Jian Chen, Xiaobo Zheng, Runcong Liu, Hongge Pan, Dingsheng Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404665301

                Metal&#8208;organic hybrid catalysts with highly tunable single&#8208;sites are promising for oxygen&#8208;evolution reaction (OER), but molecular&#8208;scale understanding of underlying reaction mechanisms still remain elusive on these bulk materials. Herein, we report a direct construction of heterogenized molecular complexes stabilized on carbon substrates via coordinating Fe&#8208;Ni sites with four aromatic carboxylate ligands (FeNi&#8208;Lx). The ligands&#8208;tuning &#960;&#8208;&#960; stacking interaction between aromatic carboxylate ligands and carbon supports promote the oxidative charge accumulation on Fe&#8208;Ni sites via fast electron transferring, thus the optimized FeNi&#8208;Lx rendering a mass activity of 6680 A gFe/Ni&#8208;1 at 0.3 V overpotential. In situ characteristics and theoretical analysis demonstrate that the OH&#8208; nucleophilic attack on hypervalent iron sites induce the reconstruction of active Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Ni species, accompanying with fast valence increasing. Whereas, during OER, the unexpected valence reduction of Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Ni sites would be attributed to the oxygen&#8208;generating from OOH* intermediates. These findings would establish an essential understanding of the origin of active centers in molecular complexes catalysts for oxygen&#8208;evolution.</description>
      <author>Yun Gao, Chengdong Yang, Fenglei Sun, Daping He, Xinqiang Wang, Jian Chen, Xiaobo Zheng, Runcong Liu, Hongge Pan, Dingsheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Water Oxidation Catalysts: The Dominant Role of Surface Chemistry over Reconstruction Degree in Activity Promotion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01562-7</link>
      <description>Li An, Jianyi Li, Yuanmiao Sun, Jiamin Zhu, Justin Zhu Yeow Seow, Hong Zhang, Nan Zhang, Pinxian Xi, Zhichuan J. Xu, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Nano-Micro Letters. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404725533

                Water splitting hinges crucially on the availability of electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction. The surface reconstruction has been widely observed in perovskite catalysts, and the reconstruction degree has been often correlated with the activity enhancement. Here, a systematic study on the roles of Fe substitution in activation of perovskite LaNiO</description>
      <author>Li An, Jianyi Li, Yuanmiao Sun, Jiamin Zhu, Justin Zhu Yeow Seow, Hong Zhang, Nan Zhang, Pinxian Xi, Zhichuan J. Xu, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01562-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocomposites - Electrochemical Oxidation of Organic Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47392/irjash.2024.047</link>
      <description>Sakshi Mokashi, A&#241;il Sharma, International Research Journal on Advanced Science Hub. 6(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404764652

                Electrochemical regeneration is very suitable approach for industrial effluents, but it suffers from low regeneration efficiency due to side reactions like oxygen evolution, as well as oxidation of the adsorbent. Utilizing PVA films through a solution casting method, incorporating varying concentrations of Cr&#8322;O&#8323; nanoparticles to evaluate their effects on the material properties .The measurement of the viscosity of the PVA- nanoparticle solution shows that the viscosity increases with the addition of Cr&#8322;O&#8323;, indicating that the viscosity is related to the interaction between the nanoparticles and PVA chains.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Mokashi, A&#241;il Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47392/irjash.2024.047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Nanocomposites in Covalent Organic Framework-Based Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14231907</link>
      <description>Haiping Zhou, Kechang Li, Qingqing Pan, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Rui Wang, Nanomaterials. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404756219

                In recent years, the development of high-performance electrocatalysts for energy conversion and environmental remediation has become a topic of great interest. Covalent organic frameworks (COFs), linked by covalent bonds, have emerged as promising materials in the field of electrocatalysis due to their well-defined structures, high specific surface areas, tunable pore structures, and excellent acid&#8211;base stability. However, the low conductivity of COF materials often limits their intrinsic electrocatalytic activity. To enhance the catalytic performance of COF-based catalysts, various nanomaterials are integrated into COFs to form composite catalysts. The stable and tunable porous structure of COFs provides an ideal platform for these nanomaterials, leading to improved electrocatalytic activity. Through rational design, COF-based composite electrocatalysts can achieve synergistic effects between nanomaterials and the COF carrier, enabling efficient targeted electrocatalysis. This review summarizes the applications of nanomaterial-incorporated COF-based catalysts in hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, oxygen reduction, carbon dioxide reduction, and nitrogen reduction. Additionally, it outlines design principles for COF-based composite electrocatalysis, focusing on structure&#8211;activity relationships and synergistic effects in COF composite nanomaterial electrocatalysts, as well as challenges and future perspectives for next-generation composite electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Haiping Zhou, Kechang Li, Qingqing Pan, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Rui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14231907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic metal-support interactions break the activity-stability dilemma in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5208867/v1</link>
      <description>Ruitao Lv, Lingxi Zhou, Menghao Yang, Yihong Liu, Feiyu Kang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404776253

                Abstract Electrocatalysis plays a central role in clean energy conversion and sustainable technologies. However, the trade-off between activity and stability of electrocatalysts significantly hinders their practical applications, notably in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for producing hydrogen and solar fuels. Here we report a steam-assisted synthesis armed with machine learning screening of an integrated ruthenium-titanium-manganese electrode, featuring intrinsic metal-support interactions. These atomic-scale interactions with self-healing capabilities radically address the activity-stability dilemma across all pH levels. Consequently, our electrode achieved high mass activities, 48.5, 112.8 and 74.6 times those of benchmark ruthenium oxides in acidic, neutral and alkaline conditions, respectively; and stable operation for up to 3,000 hours, a multi-fold improvement in stability over the reported advanced catalysts. The breakthrough in activity-stability limitations highlights the potential of intrinsic metal-support interactions for enhancing electrolysis and other heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Ruitao Lv, Lingxi Zhou, Menghao Yang, Yihong Liu, Feiyu Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5208867/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress on layered double hydroxides-based electrocatalysts for electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837676408-00282</link>
      <description>Mohamed H. Elbakkay, S.I. El&#8208;Dek, Ahmed A. Farghali, Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404756818

                Replacing global depleting fossil fuels with sustainable energy sources that are affordable and environmentally-benign, is from the most pressing challenges for the future socio-economic developments. To that goal, electrochemical water splitting would provide green hydrogen fuel which is considered one of the most promising energy carriers. However, the viability of the process still hinges on the availability of robust earth-abundant electrocatalysts that catalyze the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In recent years, transition metal based layered double hydroxides (LDHs) electrocatalysts, with advantageous physio-chemical properties, can represent a promising outstanding research approaches to accelerate the sluggish electrochemical kinetics of these two half-reactions. Herein, we present brief explanations of the reaction mechanisms and the important parameters relating to the electrochemical water splitting along with the recent developments of different LDHs derived electrocatalysts towards the HER/OER performances. Furthermore, the innovative fabrication strategies of the LDHs systems and the subsequent evolution of the LDHs classes, including adopted modification strategies including cation/anion doping, defect engineering, exchanging interlayer anions, nanostructured morphology, designing hierarchical heterostructures or nanocomposites, etc. Finally, the current perspectives and challenges of some critical issues as well as the future opportunities for the developments of outstanding LDHs-based electrocatalysts for electrochemical water electrolysis are also provided.</description>
      <author>Mohamed H. Elbakkay, S.I. El&#8208;Dek, Ahmed A. Farghali</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837676408-00282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lateral size dependence of photoconductivity in TMD networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-648x/ad965a</link>
      <description>Daniel Olaya-Cortes, Liliana Ramos-Moreno, Tomas Rubio Cruz, Juan Pablo Pablo Pab&#243;n Londo&#241;o, Yenny Hern&#225;ndez, Journal of Physics Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404623680

                Abstract Photoconductivity is an important feature of semiconductors that finds major attention in the fields of solar cells, hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions, and photodetectors. This feature involves a change of density of charge carriers induced by light, which is dependent on the generation of light-induced carriers and the recombination of excitons. This phenomenon has been observed in transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) since 2010; however, when printing such materials on flexible substrates, they form networks that would exhibit distinct transport characteristics compared to isolated TMDs crystals. In this work, TMD nanosheets are printed by vacuum filtering and their photoconductivity was measured by using a xenon lamp inside an obscure chamber. Molybdenum disulfide-based devices show higher responsivity as compared with tungsten disulfide devices, which is attributed to an increased light absorption and hydroxyl groups attached to the surface of the MoS$_2$ networks that enhance the photoconductivity by increasing the carrier lifetimes. Furthermore, the responsivity of the devices behaves similarly to the conductivity, which is modeled as networks of pairs of nanosheets and junctions through percolative paths. Finally, this is the first report that shows that the response time of the devices increases with lateral size.</description>
      <author>Daniel Olaya-Cortes, Liliana Ramos-Moreno, Tomas Rubio Cruz, Juan Pablo Pablo Pab&#243;n Londo&#241;o, Yenny Hern&#225;ndez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-648x/ad965a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic mechanism for overall water splitting to produce sustainable hydrogen by 2D Janus MoSH monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-024-00516-2</link>
      <description>Deobrat Singh, Nisha Singh, Yogesh Sonvane, npj 2D Materials and Applications. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404761563

                Abstract In the present work, we investigates the potential of two dimensional (2D) Janus MoSH monolayer as an electrocatalyst for overall water splitting using first-principles calculations. Our results shows that 2D Janus MoSH monolayer exhibits excellent structural stability and electronic properties, which are essential for efficient electrocatalysis. We find that the charge transfer mechanism between Mo and S atoms plays a crucial role in the electrocatalytic activity of 2D Janus MoSH monolayer. Due to the asymmetric structure of MoSH monolayer, it has intrinsic electric field with dipole moment of 0.24 D. Moreover, we demonstrate that 2D Janus MoSH monolayer exhibits high catalytic activity for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with overpotential 0.04 V and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with overpotential 0.11 V, making it a promising candidate for overall water splitting. Our findings have significant implications for the design and optimization of 2D monolayered materials for renewable energy production. By providing insights into the underlying mechanisms of HER and OER on 2D Janus MoSH monolayer, our study paves the way for the development of efficient and sustainable electrocatalysts for water splitting. We hope that current work will be helpful in understanding the electrocatalytic mechanism of 2D Janus MoSH monolayer and its potential applications in renewable energy production.</description>
      <author>Deobrat Singh, Nisha Singh, Yogesh Sonvane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-024-00516-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Water Splitting in Isoindigo&#8208;based Covalent Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419836</link>
      <description>Ali Trabolsi, Gobinda Das, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Fayrouz Abou Ibrahim, Areej Merhi, Huda N. Dirawi, Farah Benyettou, Akshaya Kumar Das, Thirumurugan Prakasam, Sabu Varghese, Sudhir Kumar Sharma, Serdal K&#305;rm&#305;z&#305;alt&#305;n, Ramesh Jagannathan, Felipe G&#225;ndara, Samer Aouad, Mark A. Olson, Subrata Kumar Kundu, Bilal R. Kaafarani, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404739555

                Developing a low&#8208;cost, robust, and high&#8208;performance electrocatalyst capable of efficiently performing both the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under both basic and acidic conditions is a major challenge. This area of research has attracted much attention in recent decades due to its importance in energy storage and conversion. Herein, we report the synthesis of two imine&#8208;linked isoindigo&#8208;based covalent organic networks. The combination of isoindigo dialdehyde with a planar triazine core, leads to the formation of thin, highly crystalline, planar 2D&#8208;nanosheets covalent organic framework (I&#8208;TTA COF), whereas its combination with ionic non&#8208;planar guanidinium core leads to an amorphous covalent organic polymer (I&#8208;TG COP) with a fibrous morphology. The sheet&#8208;like crystalline I&#8208;TTA COF shows better electrocatalytic activity compared to the amorphous fibrous I&#8208;TG COP. I&#8208;TTA exhibits a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at an overpotential of ~134 mV for HER (in 0.5 M H2SO4) and ~283 mV for OER (in 1 M KOH). The electrocatalytic activity of the I&#8208;TTA COF in the OER exceeds that of other metal&#8208;free COFs. The catalytic activity is maintained even after 24 hours of chronoamperometry and 500 cycles of cyclic voltammetry (CV) at high scan rates.</description>
      <author>Ali Trabolsi, Gobinda Das, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Fayrouz Abou Ibrahim, Areej Merhi, Huda N. Dirawi, Farah Benyettou, Akshaya Kumar Das, Thirumurugan Prakasam, Sabu Varghese, Sudhir Kumar Sharma, Serdal K&#305;rm&#305;z&#305;alt&#305;n, Ramesh Jagannathan, Felipe G&#225;ndara, Samer Aouad, Mark A. Olson, Subrata Kumar Kundu, Bilal R. Kaafarani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Delocalized Ni Active Sites in Spinel Catalysts Enable Efficient Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421027</link>
      <description>Hui-Jian Zhang, Zi-Qiang Chen, Xiaotong Ye, Kang Xiao, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772457

                The urea oxidation reaction (UOR) has attracted much attention as an efficient alternative reaction to oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to its low required overpotential. Despite significant progress in efficient nickel&#8208;based catalysts, the fundamental issues regarding product selectivity control and dissociation mechanism during the UOR process have not been clarified. Here, we report that tuning the electron delocalization strength of Ni sites significantly affects the OH&#8208; binding sites, altering urea molecule dissociation patterns in alkaline systems. Using spinel NiCo2O4 as a model catalyst, the charge delocalization strength of nickel active centers is influenced by the degree of phosphorus&#8208;substituted anions. Specifically, complete phosphorus&#8208;substituted spinel enhances N2 selectivity to over 26.8% with a peak current density of 300 mA&#183;cm&#8208;2, while partial phosphorus&#8208;substituted spinel achieves a Faraday efficiency of 78.1% for liquid products (NOx&#8208;). Experiments and theory reveal that strong charge delocalization at Ni sites favors remote&#8208;site attack on urea molecules by hydroxide ions, whereas weak delocalization prefers nearby&#8208;site attack, enhancing UOR efficiency and suppressing OER in both pathways.</description>
      <author>Hui-Jian Zhang, Zi-Qiang Chen, Xiaotong Ye, Kang Xiao, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Delocalized Ni Active Sites in Spinel Catalysts Enable Efficient Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421027</link>
      <description>Hui-Jian Zhang, Zi-Qiang Chen, Xiaotong Ye, Kang Xiao, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772608

                The urea oxidation reaction (UOR) has attracted much attention as an efficient alternative reaction to oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to its low required overpotential. Despite significant progress in efficient nickel&#8208;based catalysts, the fundamental issues regarding product selectivity control and dissociation mechanism during the UOR process have not been clarified. Here, we report that tuning the electron delocalization strength of Ni sites significantly affects the OH&#8208; binding sites, altering urea molecule dissociation patterns in alkaline systems. Using spinel NiCo2O4 as a model catalyst, the charge delocalization strength of nickel active centers is influenced by the degree of phosphorus&#8208;substituted anions. Specifically, complete phosphorus&#8208;substituted spinel enhances N2 selectivity to over 26.8% with a peak current density of 300 mA&#183;cm&#8208;2, while partial phosphorus&#8208;substituted spinel achieves a Faraday efficiency of 78.1% for liquid products (NOx&#8208;). Experiments and theory reveal that strong charge delocalization at Ni sites favors remote&#8208;site attack on urea molecules by hydroxide ions, whereas weak delocalization prefers nearby&#8208;site attack, enhancing UOR efficiency and suppressing OER in both pathways.</description>
      <author>Hui-Jian Zhang, Zi-Qiang Chen, Xiaotong Ye, Kang Xiao, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material sustainability evaluation of electrocatalysts in early-stage development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ft8zt</link>
      <description>Lisa Heymann, Andrea Schreiber, Christian Pithan, Christoph Baeumer, Felix Gunkel, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404729679

                Sustainable energy materials for energy storage applications are crucial for a reliable energy transition. However, evaluating material sustainability in early stages of energy material research is a big challenge, as it is difficult to predict the final industrial process and supply chain of the investigated material. In this work we showcase that a sustainability evaluation can already be conducted in the early stage of electrocatalyst research. We provide a case study of two highly active alkaline oxygen evolution catalysts La0.6Sr0.4CoO3-&#948; and La0.6Ca0.4FeO3-&#948; with a thin film model catalyst approach. For the sustainability evaluation, we consider the material criticality, compare precursor prices, conduct an environmental impact analysis of the precursors based on life cycle assessment and provide a qualitative discourse for social impacts of raw material extraction. We find that La0.6Ca0.4FeO3-&#948; has a reduced environmental footprint, smaller precursor supply risk and 10 times lower precursor price compared to La0.6Sr0.4CoO3-&#948;. However, for both perovskites the high environmental impact and high supply risk of lanthanum is of immediate concern towards larger scale application purposes. Sustainability evaluation in the early stages of energy material research can be a great chance to develop new material selection strategies leveraging sustainability in later stages of materials research for the energy transition.</description>
      <author>Lisa Heymann, Andrea Schreiber, Christian Pithan, Christoph Baeumer, Felix Gunkel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ft8zt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Ni&#8208;Doping on the Optical, Structural, and Electrochemical Properties of Ag&lt;sub&gt;29&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408096</link>
      <description>Abdullah Ahmed Ali Ahmed, Shana Havenridge, Koustav Sahoo, Loknath Thapa, Ananya Baksi, Guido H. Clever, Heshmat Noei, Mona Kohantorabi, Andreas Stierle, C. Retna Raj, Wolfgang J. Parak, Christine M. Aikens, Indranath Chakraborty, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404657011

                Abstract Atomically precise metal nanoclusters (NCs) can be compositionally controlled at the single&#8208;atom level, but understanding structure&#8208;property correlations is required for tailoring specific optical properties. Here, the impact of Ni atom doping on the optical, structural, and electrochemical properties of atomically precise 1,3&#8208;benzene dithiol (BDT) protected Ag 29 NCs is studied. The Ni&#8208;doped Ag 29 (NiAg 28 (BDT) 12 ) NCs, are synthesized using a co&#8208;reduction method and characterized using electrospray ionization mass spectrometry (ESI MS), ion mobility spectrometry (IMS), and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). Only a single Ni atom doping can be achieved despite changing the precursor concentration. Ni doping in Ag 29 NCs exhibits enhanced thermal stability, and electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) compared to the parent NCs. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations predict the geometry and optical properties of the parent and NiAg 28 (BDT) 12 NCs. DFT is also used to study the systematic single&#8208;atom doping effect of metals such as Au, Cu, and Pt into Ag 29 NCs and suggests that with Ni and Pt, the d atomic orbitals contribute to creating superatomic orbitals, which is not seen with other dopants or the parent cluster. The emission mechanism is dominated by a charge transfer from the ligands into the Ag core cluster regardless of the dopant.</description>
      <author>Abdullah Ahmed Ali Ahmed, Shana Havenridge, Koustav Sahoo, Loknath Thapa, Ananya Baksi, Guido H. Clever, Heshmat Noei, Mona Kohantorabi, Andreas Stierle, C. Retna Raj, Wolfgang J. Parak, Christine M. Aikens, Indranath Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408096</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Magnetic Heterostructures with Synergistic Regulation of Charge&#8208;Transfer and Spin&#8208;Ordering for Enhanced Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409842</link>
      <description>Chongyan Hao, Yang Wu, Xiaobo Zheng, Yumeng Du, Yameng Fan, Wei Kong Pang, Anton Tadich, Shujun Zhang, Thomas Frauenheim, Tianyi Ma, Xiaoning Li, Zhenxiang Cheng, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404722349

                Abstract The design of heterojunctions offers a crucial solution for energy conversion and storage challenges, but current research predominantly focuses on charge transfer benefits, often neglecting spin attribute regulation despite the increasing recognition of spin&#8208;sensitivity in many chemical reactions. In this study, a novel magnetic heterostructure, CoFe 2 O 4 @CoFeMo 3 O 8 , is designed to simultaneously modulate charge and spin characteristics, and systematically elucidated their synergistic impact on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Experimental results and density functional theory calculations confirmed that the magnetic heterostructure exhibits both charge transfer and spin polarization. It is found that the charge&#8208;transfer behavior enhances conductivity and adsorption ability through band structure regulation. Meanwhile, magnetically polarized electrons promote triplet O 2 generation and accelerate electron transport via spin&#8208;selective pathways. Moreover, the heterostructure's effective response to external alternating magnetic fields further amplifies the spin&#8208;dependent effect and introduces a magnetothermal effect, locally heating the active sites through spin flip, thereby boosting catalytic activity. Consequently, the OER activity of the magnetic heterostructure is improved by 83.8 times at 1.5 V compared to its individual components. This magnetic heterojunction strategy presents a promising avenue for advanced catalysis through synergistic regulating of charge&#8208;transfer and spin&#8208;ordering.</description>
      <author>Chongyan Hao, Yang Wu, Xiaobo Zheng, Yumeng Du, Yameng Fan, Wei Kong Pang, Anton Tadich, Shujun Zhang, Thomas Frauenheim, Tianyi Ma, Xiaoning Li, Zhenxiang Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteroatom-Doped Carbon Allotropes in Water-Splitting Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/bk-2024-1491.ch007</link>
      <description>Abhisek Majumdar, Tran Khoa Dang, Deepanshu Malhotra, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, ACS symposium series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404751796

                Water-splitting technology is crucial for generating green hydrogen energy, a sustainable and clean fuel source that can significantly decrease reliance on fossil fuels and reduce greenhouse gas emissions, thereby helping to mitigate the global energy crisis. Renewable energy sources are expected to significantly replace fossil fuels, contributing to lowering greenhouse gas releases and helping to mitigate the energy crisis. The water-splitting process for generating green hydrogen energy is acknowledged as a promising approach toward achieving carbon neutrality. In this context, the attributes and features of electrocatalysts have a crucial part in shaping the reaction activity and selectivity of both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) processes involved in the water-splitting process. In addition to traditional noble-metal-based catalysts, carbon-based materials like carbon nanotubes (CNTs), graphene, and porous carbons have proven effective for catalyzing these reactions. A highly effective strategy to enhance their electrical, physical, and chemical characteristics involves doping them with heteroatoms like nitrogen (N), sulfur (S), phosphorus (P), boron (B), and transition metals. These materials, renowned for their exceptional characteristics, have been extensively researched in both the academic and industrial sectors for diverse applications, like energy conversion and storage technologies. This chapter comprehensively reviews notable advancements in the progress of heteroatom-doped carbon allotropes materials and their utilization in overall water splitting, highlighting different synthesis methods and strategies like templating strategy, hydrothermal/solvothermal synthesis, chemical vapour deposition (CVD), and high-temperature annealing aimed at achieving heteroatom-doped carbon allotrope materials with diverse types and quantities of dopants (both metallic and non-metallic), as well as multi-atoms. Additionally, the discussion underlines the structural and morphological characteristics that elucidate the structure-property relationship and improvements in the physicochemical features of heteroatom-doped carbon allotropes. It explores how heteroatom doping enhances different properties, such as conductivity, and optimizes surface adsorption for various reaction intermediates, as evidenced by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Finally, the chapter explores recent promising studies of heteroatom-doped carbon allotropes with excellent catalytic performance and reveals their future prospects for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Abhisek Majumdar, Tran Khoa Dang, Deepanshu Malhotra, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/bk-2024-1491.ch007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The changes of oxygen extraction fraction in different types of lesions in multiple sclerosis: A cross-sectional and follow-up study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/1051</link>
      <description>Yan Xie, Wenzhen Zhu, Proceedings on CD-ROM - International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine. Scientific Meeting and Exhibition/Proceedings of the International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, Scientific Meeting and Exhibition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404748184

                Motivation: Multiple sclerosis (MS) lesions with different pathologic conditions could be distinguished by MRI. There may be differences in oxygen metabolism in different types of lesions. Goal(s): To explore the oxygen metabolism of different types of lesions in MS patients by oxygen extraction fraction (OEF) both cross-sectionally and longitudinally. Approach: The OEF map was reconstructed from a 3D multi-echo gradient echo scan. White matter lesions were classified into four types based on contrast-enhanced T1WI and quantitative susceptibility mapping. Results: There were differences in OEF among different types of MS lesions. The OEF in the lesion and the lesion type may change as time progresses. Impact: This study revealed tissue damage and oxygen metabolism level in different types of MS lesions. The OEF may contribute to further understanding of the pathological mechanisms in MS lesion evolution.</description>
      <author>Yan Xie, Wenzhen Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/1051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co nanoparticles encapsulated in N-doped carbon nanotube materials derived from new metal-organic frameworks for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07187e</link>
      <description>Jieling Zhang, Weiran Suo, Yu Han, Yiwen Cao, Yi Xu, Mengying Wang, Zuozhong Liang, Yuan Wang, Haoquan Zheng, Rui Cao, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404731116

                Bifunctional electrocatalysts used for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER) are of great significance for metal-air batteries. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs), after undergoing a high-temperature calcination process, emerge as promising precursors...</description>
      <author>Jieling Zhang, Weiran Suo, Yu Han, Yiwen Cao, Yi Xu, Mengying Wang, Zuozhong Liang, Yuan Wang, Haoquan Zheng, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07187e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen&#8208;blocking properties of HfB&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;MoSi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;SiC coating by CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20266</link>
      <description>Sheng Zhang, Ji Xiang, Yuexing Chen, Peipei Wang, Ph. V. Kiryukhantsev&#8208;Korneev, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;&#1096;&#1086;&#1074;, Ji Shi, Xuanru Ren, Xueqin Kang, Baojing Zhang, Ping Zhang, Leihua Xu, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404691021

                Abstract To alleviate the destructive alteration of the glass layer surface caused by gas evolution during the oxygen&#8208;blocking process of the HfB 2 &#8208;MoSi 2 &#8208;SiC coating, CeO 2 was incorporated to modify HfB 2 &#8208;MoSi 2 &#8208;SiC coating, and the anti&#8208;oxidation mechanism at 1700&#176;C in air was investigated. Compared with the unmodified HfB 2 &#8208;MoSi 2 &#8208;SiC coating, the addition of the refractory CeO 2 to the Hf&#8208;B&#8208;Si&#8208;O system leads to the formation of a stable Hf&#8208;Ce&#8208;B&#8208;Si&#8208;O complex phase glass, which substantially enhances the viscosity, stability, and self&#8208;healing sealing properties of the glass layer. The introduction of 0.75 vol.% CeO 2 significantly lowers the oxidative activity of the HfB 2 &#8208;MoSi 2 &#8208;SiC coating, boosting its average protective efficiency to 99.96% and reducing the maximal oxygen permeability by 43.48%, thus exhibiting superior oxygen&#8208;blocking performance. However, excessive addition of CeO 2 leads to an overabundance of oxygen release through its distinctive oxygen vacancy mechanism, which accelerates the formation of Hf&#8208;oxides, resulting in excessive viscosity on the coating surface and leaving oxidation defects unrepaired.</description>
      <author>Sheng Zhang, Ji Xiang, Yuexing Chen, Peipei Wang, Ph. V. Kiryukhantsev&#8208;Korneev, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;&#1096;&#1086;&#1074;, Ji Shi, Xuanru Ren, Xueqin Kang, Baojing Zhang, Ping Zhang, Leihua Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Microstructural Evolution and Mechanical Properties of Boron-Doped Ti35Zr30V10Nb25 Refractory High-Entropy Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14121029</link>
      <description>Xinggang Wang, Meng Sun, Jiaxin Liu, Xueqing Liu, Weibin Jiang, Xianping Wang, Q.F. Fang, Crystals. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404755203

                The addition of oxygen or nitrogen in refractory high-entropy alloys (HEAs) has been widely reported, but studies on boron-doped HEAs have mainly focused on the segregation of boron elements at grain boundaries. The changes in the microstructure and mechanical properties in TiZrNb-based HEAs remain enigmatic. In this work, boron-doped Ti35Zr30V10Nb25 (Ti35-xB) refractory HEAs were designed to elucidate their microstructural evolution and mechanical properties. Unlike oxygen and nitrogen, trace amounts of boron addition result in the formation of borides, and boron exhibits a strong repulsion towards Zr, leading to Zr-depleted borides. Borides distributed along the grain boundaries refine the grain size and dendritic structure. The borides and structural refinement effect enhance the strain-hardening capacity and uniform elongation, resulting in an over 15% uniform elongation for Ti35-0.25B.</description>
      <author>Xinggang Wang, Meng Sun, Jiaxin Liu, Xueqing Liu, Weibin Jiang, Xianping Wang, Q.F. Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14121029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving coupled non-linear schr&#246;dinger equations via quantum imaginary time evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1140/epjs/s11734-024-01384-z</link>
      <description>Yang Hong Li, Jim Al-Khalili, P. D. Stevenson, The European Physical Journal Special Topics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404681499

                Abstract Coupled non-linear Schr&#246;dinger equations are crucial in describing dynamics of many-particle systems. We present a quantum imaginary time evolution (ITE) algorithm as a solution to such equations in the case of nuclear Hartree-Fock approach. Under a simplified Skyrme interaction model, we calculate the ground state energy of an oxygen-16 nucleus and demonstrate that the result is in agreement with the classical ITE algorithm. We examine bottlenecks and deficiencies in the quantum algorithm and suggest possible improvements.</description>
      <author>Yang Hong Li, Jim Al-Khalili, P. D. Stevenson</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1140/epjs/s11734-024-01384-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation of High-Altitude Plants to Harsh Environments: Application of Phenotypic-Variation-Related Methods and Multi-Omics Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252312666</link>
      <description>Kai&#8208;Lu Zhang, Ya-Nan Leng, Ruirui Hao, Wenyao Zhang, Hongfei Li, Mo&#8208;Xian Chen, Fu&#8208;Yuan Zhu, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 25(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404724114

                High-altitude plants face extreme environments such as low temperature, low oxygen, low nutrient levels, and strong ultraviolet radiation, causing them to adopt complex adaptation mechanisms. Phenotypic variation is the core manifestation of ecological adaptation and evolution. Many plants have developed a series of adaptive strategies through long-term natural selection and evolution, enabling them to survive and reproduce under such harsh conditions. This article reviews the techniques and methods used in recent years to study the adaptive evolution of high-altitude plants, including transplantation techniques, genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and metabolomics techniques, and their applications in high-altitude plant adaptive evolution. Transplantation technology focuses on phenotypic variation, which refers to natural variations in morphological, physiological, and biochemical characteristics, exploring their key roles in nutrient utilization, photosynthesis optimization, and stress-resistance protection. Multiple omics technologies, including genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and metabolomics, have revealed genes, regulatory pathways, and metabolic networks associated with phenotypic variations at the genetic and molecular levels. At the same time, the limitations and deficiencies of current technologies used to study plant adaptation to high-altitude environments were discussed. In addition, we propose future improvements to existing technologies and advocate for the integration of different technologies at multiple levels to study the molecular mechanisms of plant adaptation to high-altitude environments, thus providing insights for future research in this field.</description>
      <author>Kai&#8208;Lu Zhang, Ya-Nan Leng, Ruirui Hao, Wenyao Zhang, Hongfei Li, Mo&#8208;Xian Chen, Fu&#8208;Yuan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252312666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of the biodrying and biostabilization efficiency of a continuous flow full-scale facility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5276/jswtm/iswmaw/50s1/2024.755</link>
      <description>Francesco Di Maria, Somnath Ghosh, The Journal of Solid Waste Technology and Management. 50(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404652164

                The technological solution adopted for aerobic treatment of Waste Organic Fraction (WOF) can influence the evolution of the physical parameters of the process making the facility acting as a biostabilization or a biodrying system. In the present study, the continuous flow biological section of the full-scale mechanical biological treatment plant was experimentally investigated by means of evolution, during treatment period (day), of temperature (T) (&#176; C), volatile solids (VS) (%TS) and oxygen uptake of the WOF under treatment. Oxygen uptake was measured by the Dynamic Respirometer Index Potential (DRIP) (mgO2/kgVSh). Main findings were that T (&#176; C) and VS %TS remained quite constant among inlets and outlets of the biological treatment sections, about 70&#176; C and 50 (%TS), respectively. DRIP (mgO2/kgVSh) values measured by several samples withdrawn along the basin width increased significantly in the first half portion of the basin of the aerobic section, remaining quite constant in the second half. This was mainly caused by the strong moisture reduction that rapidly achieved values lower than 40% causing inhibition to microbial activity. The simulation model developed in this work showed that the mean retention time (day) of the WOF inside the aerobic basin was about 14-16 days, this parameter being strongly influenced by the WOF inlet rate (tonnes/day). Finally, experimental evidence pointed out that the reduction of WOF DRIP (mgO2/kgVSh) stopped after the first days of treatment indicating that the facility operates mainly as biodrying system. Based on simulations, biostabilization can also be pursued by maintaining the moisture of WOF to proper values not lower than 40 (% w/w).</description>
      <author>Francesco Di Maria, Somnath Ghosh</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5276/jswtm/iswmaw/50s1/2024.755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multinonmetal-Doped V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocomposites for Lithium-Ion Battery Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02043</link>
      <description>Yikang Yu, Guangqi Zhu, Yuanfeng Qi, Mohammad Behzadnia, Zhenzhen Yang, Yuzi Liu, Fan Yang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404677000

                Lithium-ion batteries (LIBs) are critical for portable electronics and electric vehicles, demanding higher energy density to meet increasing energy storage needs. Current commercial cathode materials, such as LiFePO4 and LiCoO2, are limited by a single electron transfer, restricting their energy density. Vanadium pentoxide (V2O5) emerges as a promising high-capacity cathode due to its high theoretical capacity of 443 mA h g&#8211;1 with three Li storage capacities, significantly surpassing conventional materials. However, the practical application of V2O5 is hindered by a large structural evolution and rapid capacity fading during full lithium intercalation. This study introduces a multinonmetal doping (MNM) strategy to enhance V2O5 cathodes by incorporating all-nonmetal dopants (B, P, and Si) and graphene (G). MNM-V2O5-G exhibits increased surface oxygen defects, improving charge transfer kinetics and thus enhancing the rate performance and cycling stability. Our results provide valuable insights into the role of surface oxygen defects in stabilizing V2O5 with element doping. This research highlights the potential of multinonmetal doping to improve LIB cathode materials, offering a promising pathway for design of high-energy-density V2O5 cathodes and advancing the development of next-generation energy storage solutions.</description>
      <author>Yikang Yu, Guangqi Zhu, Yuanfeng Qi, Mohammad Behzadnia, Zhenzhen Yang, Yuzi Liu, Fan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pore Types and Dolomite Reservoir Genesis of the Fifth Member of the Ordovician Majiagou Formation in the Central and Eastern Ordos Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app142310976</link>
      <description>Shilei Chen, Rongji Dai, Shunshe Luo, Applied Sciences. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404715881

                The Ordovician dolomite in the Ordos Basin is an important natural gas reservoir. Exploring dolomite genesis and the factors influencing reservoir characteristics is essential for deep carbonate rock exploration. This study offers a comprehensive analysis of dolomite evolution using methods such as thin-section petrography, isotope analysis, and trace and rare earth elements. The analysis shows that: Based on petrographic observations of the Majiagou Formation in the study area, the dolomite in the study area can be divided into residual oolitic dolomite of synsedimentary or metasomatic origin, micritic dolomite of secondary metasomatism or recrystallization origin, powder crystal dolomite, and fine crystal dolomite. Reservoir pores mainly develop intergranular pores, mold pores, dissolved pores, and fractures. Combined with the characteristics of major elements, trace elements, carbon and oxygen isotopes, rare earth elements, and inclusions in the study area, it can be concluded that the fifth member dolomite of the Majiagou Formation is of shallow&#8211;medium burial origin. The diagenetic evolution sequence from the penecontemporaneous period to the middle&#8211;deep burial period in the study area is penecontemporaneous dolomite, anhydrite dissolution &#8594; seepage silt filling, freshwater dolomite, calcite, and gypsum filling, pressure solution compaction, calcite partial dissolution &#8594; gypsum filling, karst cave, buried hydrothermal dolomite, dolomite partial dissolution &#8594; calcite complete dissolution, pore dissolution expansion, and quartz pyrite filling. In the early stage of compaction and pressure solution, the primary pores are rapidly reduced, and in the later stage, sutures are generated to provide channels for reservoir fluid migration. The recrystallization reduces the porosity during the middle&#8211;deep burial period.</description>
      <author>Shilei Chen, Rongji Dai, Shunshe Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app142310976</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observations of Molecular CN toward S-type Asymptotic Giant Branch Stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ad8ba6</link>
      <description>Yanan Feng, Xiaohu Li, Xiaofeng Yang, T. J. Millar, R. Szczerba, Sheng&#8208;Li Qin, Xue-Jian Jiang, Donghui Quan, Juan Tuo, Zhenzhen Miao, Sheng&#8208;Yuan Liu, Xiang Liu, The Astronomical Journal. 168(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404696113

                Abstract S-type asymptotic giant branch (AGB) stars are defined by their carbon-to-oxygen (C/O) ratio approaching unity. However, observations of circumstellar molecules in these stars are limited and challenging. In this study, we used the James Clerk Maxwell Telescope to search for cyanide (CN) in 12 selected S-type AGB stars, with only 4 of these stars displaying CN spectral line signals. The column density and fractional abundance of CN were calculated assuming local thermodynamic equilibrium, and the average CN-to-hydrogen-cyanide (HCN) abundance ratio of the four sources is about 0.036. We investigate, for the first time, the relationship between CN and HCN fractional abundances in all types of AGB stars, finding that the ratio is similar in O-rich and S-type stars, while those in C-rich stars are quite different. This result supports the idea that the level of HCN photodissociation plays a crucial role in determining the CN abundance in the circumstellar envelopes of AGB stars at various stages of their evolution.</description>
      <author>Yanan Feng, Xiaohu Li, Xiaofeng Yang, T. J. Millar, R. Szczerba, Sheng&#8208;Li Qin, Xue-Jian Jiang, Donghui Quan, Juan Tuo, Zhenzhen Miao, Sheng&#8208;Yuan Liu, Xiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ad8ba6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MULTI-ECHO FUNCTIONAL IMAGING ON AN ULTRA HIGH-PERFORMANCE HEAD-ONLY GRADIENT SYSTEM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/5122</link>
      <description>Gail Kohls, Nastaren Abad, Heidi Morris, Mauren Hood, J. Kevin DeMarco, Thomas Foo, Proceedings on CD-ROM - International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine. Scientific Meeting and Exhibition/Proceedings of the International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, Scientific Meeting and Exhibition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404743435

                Motivation: This abstract focuses on educating on how high-gradient MRI systems can utilize the multi-echo functional MRI (ME-fMRI) techniques. Goal(s): We explain the blood-oxygen-level-dependent (BOLD) signal technique and how additional echoes can improve the signal fidelity. Approach: The ME-fMRI, using three or more echoes allow for the pixelwise T2* decay to be modeled, and as BOLD contrast is a function of T2* evolution over time, an experiment sampling the voxel-wise T2* signal decay can be used to separate BOLD from artifact signal constituents. Results: Gradient systems with ultra-rapid slew rates (&amp;gt; 400 T/m/s) allow ME-fMRI to reduce artefacts from flow, motion, and susceptibility effects. Impact: MRI systems with ultra-high gradient systems can reduce artefacts from flow, motion, and susceptibility effects in the BOLD contrast technique using an ME-fMRI technique with three or more echoes to improve fidelity of fMRI.</description>
      <author>Gail Kohls, Nastaren Abad, Heidi Morris, Mauren Hood, J. Kevin DeMarco, Thomas Foo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/5122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental understanding of voltage decay in Li-rich Mn-based layered oxides cathode materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43673-024-00138-2</link>
      <description>Huixian Xie, Jia&#8208;Cheng Xiao, Hongyi Chen, Boyang Zhang, Kwun Nam Hui, Shanqing Zhang, C.S. Liu, Dong Luo, Zhan Lin, AAPPS bulletin. 34(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404703159

                Abstract To satisfy the needs of modern intelligent society for power supplies with long-endurance ability, Li-rich Mn-based layered oxides (LRMOs) are receiving much attention because of their ultrahigh capacity. However, their real-world implementation is hindered by the serious voltage decay, which results in a continuous decrease in energy density. The understanding on voltage decay still remains a mystery due to the complicated hybrid cationic-anionic redox and the serious surface-interface reactions in LRMOs. Moreover, some of the mechanisms are occasionally contradictory, indicating that the origin of voltage decay is still unclear. As a result, none of the innovative strategies proposed on the basis of mechanisms has effectively alleviated the problem of voltage decay, and voltage decay becomes a long-term distress of LRMOs. Therefore, it is particularly crucial to sort out the mutual relation of various mechanisms, which helps to go back to the source of voltage decay. In this review, we summarize the current mechanisms of voltage decay as structural evolution and oxygen chemistry, and attempt to trace the origin of voltage decay for LRMOs. In addition, we discuss how current researches address the issue with generalized guidance in designing appropriate strategies based on mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Huixian Xie, Jia&#8208;Cheng Xiao, Hongyi Chen, Boyang Zhang, Kwun Nam Hui, Shanqing Zhang, C.S. Liu, Dong Luo, Zhan Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43673-024-00138-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distinct immune responses to HIV and CMV in Hofbauer cells across gestation highlight evolving placental immune dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.21.624730</link>
      <description>Viviane Schuch, Daniel J. Hossack, Tiffany Hailstorks, Rana Chakraborty, Erica L. Johnson, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404629620

                Placental immune responses to Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) and Human Cytomegalovirus (CMV) vary across gestational stages and may influence postnatal outcomes. This study investigates the innate immunity of Hofbauer cells from placentae obtained at early/mid-gestation (18-21.6 weeks) and term (&gt;37 weeks). RNA sequencing and cytokine profiling reveal that early/mid-gestation HCs exhibit heightened differential gene expression responses compared to term HCs, indicating a distinct transcriptional activity in early pregnancy. Significant overlap in gene expression profiles of early/mid-gestation cells in response to CMV and HIV suggest similar innate immune responses, while term cells exhibit distinct patterns, reflecting the temporal evolution of placental immunity. Integration with the Human Protein Atlas database reveals more placental-specific differentially expressed genes in early/mid-gestation HCs exposed to HIV and CMV compared to term cells. Functional analysis reveals downregulation of pathways related to oxygen stress, estrogen response, and KRAS signalling pathway in early/mid-gestation HCs, with HIV uniquely upregulating reactive oxygen species and CMV uniquely disrupting WNT &#946;-Catenin signalling. In term HCs, CMV exposure upregulates antiviral interferon (IFN) signaling and inflammatory pathways. Co-expression analysis highlights distinct molecular pathway enrichments across gestation, particularly with upregulation of IFN signalling and disruption of lipid metabolism in term CMV-exposed HCs. Cytokine profiling shows enhanced expression of GM-CSF, IFN-&#947;, and Th2-associated cytokines in early/mid-gestation HCs, indicating heightened immune responsiveness. These findings reveal the dynamic nature of placental immunity and underscore the need for targeted interventions to address unique immune and metabolic disruptions caused by viral infections at distinct stages of pregnancy to improve fetal and infant health outcomes.</description>
      <author>Viviane Schuch, Daniel J. Hossack, Tiffany Hailstorks, Rana Chakraborty, Erica L. Johnson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.21.624730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New-to-nature CO2-dependent acetyl-CoA assimilation enabled by an engineered B12-dependent acyl-CoA mutase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53762-9</link>
      <description>Helena Schulz-Mirbach, Philipp Wichmann, Ari Satanowski, H. Meusel, Tong Wu, Maren Nattermann, Simon Burgener, Nicole Paczia, Arren Bar&#8208;Even, Tobias J. Erb, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404716791

                Abstract Acetyl-CoA is a key metabolic intermediate and the product of various natural and synthetic one-carbon (C1) assimilation pathways. While an efficient conversion of acetyl-CoA into other central metabolites, such as pyruvate, is imperative for high biomass yields, available aerobic pathways typically release previously fixed carbon in the form of CO 2 . To overcome this loss of carbon, we develop a new-to-nature pathway, the Lcm module, in this study. The Lcm module provides a direct link between acetyl-CoA and pyruvate, is shorter than any other oxygen-tolerant route and notably fixes CO 2 , instead of releasing it. The Lcm module relies on the new-to-nature activity of a coenzyme B 12 -dependent mutase for the conversion of 3-hydroxypropionyl-CoA into lactyl-CoA. We demonstrate Lcm activity of the scaffold enzyme 2-hydroxyisobutyryl-CoA mutase from Bacillus massiliosenegalensis , and further improve catalytic efficiency 10-fold by combining in vivo targeted hypermutation and adaptive evolution in an engineered Escherichia coli selection strain. Finally, in a proof-of-principle, we demonstrate the complete Lcm module in vitro. Overall, our work demonstrates a synthetic CO 2 -incorporating acetyl-CoA assimilation route that expands the metabolic solution space of central carbon metabolism, providing options for synthetic biology and metabolic engineering.</description>
      <author>Helena Schulz-Mirbach, Philipp Wichmann, Ari Satanowski, H. Meusel, Tong Wu, Maren Nattermann, Simon Burgener, Nicole Paczia, Arren Bar&#8208;Even, Tobias J. Erb</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53762-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Oxygen Redox Activity by Local Chemical Disorder toward Robust Co&#8208;Free Li&#8208;Rich Cathode with High Voltage Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414443</link>
      <description>Hongfei Zheng, Mengjian Fan, Chenying Zhang, Wei He, Guiyang Gao, Yuanyuan Liu, Laisen Wang, Qingshui Xie, Dong&#8208;Liang Peng, Jun L&#252;, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404774764

                Abstract Despite extensive investigation on the lattice oxygen redox (LOR) in Li&#8208;rich cathodes, significant challenges remain in utilizing LOR activity without compromising structural and electrochemical stability. Related breakthroughs are hindered by the lack of understanding regarding how different LOR activity influences the structural evolution and electrochemical stability, and what is the optimal LOR activity. Herein, the degree of LOR activity is successfully regulated from 22% to 92% in Co&#8208;free Li&#8208;rich cathodes (Li 1+x Mn 0.62 Ni 0.18 O 2 ) by controlling local chemical disorder, and the relationship between LOR activity and cycling stability is revealed. Conventional consensus is challenged by new findings that the over&#8208;suppressive LOR activity also undermines electrochemical/structural stability, and even causes more severe voltage fading compared to cases with excessive LOR. However, their failure mechanisms related to lattice strain present different characteristics. Based on the established understanding, the appropriate LOR activation is necessary to balance the maximum reversible LOR activity and good stability, and the optimal degree is identified as 86% in Li 1.18 Mn 0.62 Ni 0.18 O 2 (LR&#8208;78). LR&#8208;78 exhibits remarkable voltage retention of 96% after 400 cycles at 1 C, and superior high&#8208;rate cyclability without capacity decay within 600 cycles at 5 C. These findings significantly broaden the understanding of LOR mechanisms and provide critical guidance for designing durable LOR&#8208;based cathodes.</description>
      <author>Hongfei Zheng, Mengjian Fan, Chenying Zhang, Wei He, Guiyang Gao, Yuanyuan Liu, Laisen Wang, Qingshui Xie, Dong&#8208;Liang Peng, Jun L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative/Nitrosative Stress and Brain Involvement in Sepsis: A Relationship Supported by Immunohistochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina60121949</link>
      <description>Giuseppe Bertozzi, Michela Ferrara, Mariagrazia Calvano, Natascha Pascale, Aldo Di Fazio, Medicina. 60(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718285

                Background and Objectives: A large amount of recent evidence suggests that cellular inability to consume oxygen could play a notable part in promoting sepsis as a consequence of mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress. The latter could, in fact, represent a fundamental stage in the evolution of the &#8220;natural history&#8221; of sepsis. Following a study previously conducted by the same working group on heart samples, the present research project aims to evaluate, through an immunohistochemical study, the existence and/or extent of oxidative stress in the brains of subjects who died due to sepsis and define, after reviewing the literature, its contribution to the septic process to support the use of medications aimed at correcting redox anomalies in the management of septic patients. Materials and Methods: 10 cases of subjects who died in healthcare facilities with ante-mortem clinical-laboratory signs that allowed the diagnosis of septic shock were selected as case studies, and 1 case of a subject who died immediately following a road traffic accident was used as a negative control. Samples of the cerebral cortex were then taken, fixed in formalin, and subjected to sections on which an immunohistochemical study was performed using anti-NOX-2, NT, iNOS, and 8-OHdG antibodies. Results: The results emerging from the present study demonstrate that despite a variable expressivity for the NT, iNOS, and NOX2 markers, the brain samples demonstrated univocal and high positivity for the 8-OHdG marker. Conclusions: This would allow us to hypothesize how, regardless of the mechanism of production of ROS and NOS (iNOS or NOX2 mediated) and the pathophysiological mechanisms that are triggered during sepsis, oxidative damage to DNA represents the event to which this whole process leads and, in fact, in the literature, is directly correlated to sepsis-dependent mortality. Neurons, conversely, appear to be more sensitive to oxidative stress because of a low number of protective or scavenger molecules (catalase, glutathione peroxidase, GSH, or vitamin E). Therefore, despite reduced production, the manifestation of the damage remains high. This evidence, together with that of the previous study, can only support the introduction of substances with an antioxidant function in the guidelines for the treatment of sepsis.</description>
      <author>Giuseppe Bertozzi, Michela Ferrara, Mariagrazia Calvano, Natascha Pascale, Aldo Di Fazio</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina60121949</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metagenomic analysis sheds light on the mixotrophic lifestyle of bacterial phylum &lt;i&gt;Zhuqueibacterota&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/imt2.249</link>
      <description>Zheng&#8208;Han Lian, Nimaichand Salam, Sha Tan, Yang Yuan, Meng&#8208;Meng Li, Yu&#8208;Xian Li, Ze&#8208;Tao Liu, Chao&#8208;Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yu&#8208;Ting OuYang, Caiyu Lu, Jingyi Zhang, Ying Chen, Le&#8208;Bin Chen, Zhen&#8208;Hao Luo, Bin Ma, Zheng&#8208;Shuang Hua, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Wen&#8208;Jun Li, Lan Liu, iMeta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404650498

                Zhuqueibacterota is a novel bacterial phylum proposed based on hot spring metagenomes and public metagenome-assembled genomes, classified within the Fibrobacterota-Chlorobiota-Bacteroidota superphylum. This globally distributed phylum consists of one class and five orders, with the majority of its members being facultative anaerobes. Notably, the order Zhuqueibacterales utilizes hydrogen as an electron donor for carbon fixation through the Calvin Benson Bassham cycle. Phylogenetic and metabolic analyses reveal the phylum's key role in the carbon cycle, with frequent horizontal gene transfer events influencing its evolutionary trajectory. To the editor, The candidate phylum KSB1 has been identified as anaerobic heterotrophic bacterium and detected in various environments. However, little known about its diversity, ecology, and evolutionary history. In this study, we analyzed 30 new metagenome-assembled genomes (MAGs) from the Tengchong hot spring and 45 public MAGs. Phylogenetic analyses based on the draft genome and 16S rRNA gene indicate they form a distinct group within the Fibrobacterota-Chlorobiota-Bacteroidota (FCB) superphylum, and thus we propose their classification as a new phylum, herein Zhuqueibacterota, which contain five orders and one class. Members of Zhuqueibacterota are globally distributed and likely facultative anaerobes, with one order exhibiting autotrophy via the Calvin Benson Bassham (CBB) cycle by using hydrogen as an electron donor. Metabolic predictions at the community level suggest that Zhuqueibacterota play a significant role in the carbon fixation of hot spring. Ancestral state reconstruction points to frequent horizontal gene transfer (HGT) events throughout Zhuqueibacterota evolution. Facultative anaerobic traits appear to be ancestral, with some lineage losing hydrogen oxidation capabilities while acquiring carbon fixation capabilities through HGT in Zhuqueibacterales. These results shed light on diversity, ecological roles, and evolutionary history of Zhuqueibacterota, highlighting their significance in the carbon cycle. The earth harbors a huge biodiversity of eukaryotic and prokaryotic microorganisms. However, only a small portion of bacteria is culturable under laboratory conditions and most bacterial phyla have no cultured members. The candidate bacterial phylum KSB1, as one of the uncultured phyla, was first identified in sulfur-rich marine sediments, and now was recognized for its broad ecological adaptability [1]. In estuary sediments, genome studies revealed its capacity for carbohydrate metabolism and &#946;-oxidation [2]. KSB1 members from hydrothermal sediment possess genes encoding benzylsuccinate synthase and alkylsuccinate synthase, suggesting a role in anaerobic hydrocarbon degradation [3]. In wetland sediments, KSB1 MAGs encode enzymes such as isopropanol dehydrogenase, phosphotransbutyrylase, and butyrate kinase, further highlighting their ecological versatility. Notably, KSB1 was also recovered from metagenomic data of hot spring, indicating KSB1 may harbor new functional niches that allow it to grow in the extreme environment. In addition, although nearly 100 MAGs of KSB1 have been reconstructed from various environments, the limited number of high-quality genomes hinders the ability to understand the ecological roles and metabolism of KSB1. Thus, more comprehensive research is needed to explore their metabolic pathways and evolutionary history. To address this, we collected available KSB1 genomes from public database and extracted new MAGs from hot spring samples. Our study significantly expands the genomic diversity of KSB1, clarify the phylogenetic relationships, and revealing its facultative anaerobic lifestyle and carbon fixation potential via the CBB cycle. We hereby designate this phylum as Zhuqueibacterota. Continuous sampling of hot springs in Tengchong County, Yunnan province, China, has been conducted for metagenomic studies since 2016, and 30 high-quality MAGs (Table S1) assigned to KSB1 were reconstructed from 16 metagenomes of hot springs. In total, 75 high-quality KSB1 MAGs were used to construct phylogenetic trees, including 45 genomes (Table S2) downloaded from GenBank. A maximum-likelihood tree, employing Bac120 marker sets from genome taxonomy database (GTDB), revealed that KSB1 forms a monophyletic clade within the FCB superphylum [4], and clearly separated from other phyla (Figure S1A). Phylogenetic tree based on 16S rRNA gene further supports the classification of KSB1 as a distinct phylum taxon in the domain Bacteria under the kingdom Psuedomonadati [5] (Figure S1B). To resolve the phylogenetic affiliations within phylum Zhuqueibacterota, we constructed a maximum likelihood tree with a concatenated set of single-copy marker genes. Previous analyses identified four clades within KSB1 [1]; however, our phylogenetic analysis revealed five distinct groups, corresponding to five orders of the undescribed phylum KSB1 in GTDB r214 (Figure 1A) and clarified that clade II (GTDB taxonomy: p__JdFR-76) is not part of KSB1 but a sister phylum. Average amino acid identity (AAI, 95%&#8211;100% for same species) [6], and average nucleotide identity (ANI, 95%&#8211;100% for same species) (Table S3, Figure S2) were used to classify the novel lineage on the species, which were consistent with the GTDB classification. In addition, phylogenomic tree and GTDB toolkit (GTDB-Tk) (Tables S1 and S2) based analyses were performed to classify the novel lineage on genus levels and higher taxonomic ranks. Finally, we identified 1 class, 5 orders, 14 families, 27 genera, and 40 species from the 75 MAGs (Table S4), including 9 novel species from our own 30 MAGs. Following the recommendations for defining species and higher ranks of not-yet-cultured bacteria using MAGs as type material [6, 7], we proposed the name Zhuqueibacterota phyl. nov. for the KSB1 with five orders: Zhuqueibacterales (O1), Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), Thermofontimicrobiales (O4), and Oceanimicrobiales (O5). Using 16S rRNA gene sequences as queries in the IMNGS platform, Zhuqueibacterota was detected across six biotopes: aquatic, sediment, soil, hydrothermal vents, animal- and plant-associated environments (Figure 1B). The phylum is particularly prevalent in soil and biofilm samples, where it constitutes 3%&#8211;10% of biofilm-associated communities (Table S5), suggesting that biofilms may serve as a protective niche for these bacteria. Zhuqueibacterales (O1), the most widely distributed order (Figure 1C), was found in diverse environments. Residuimicrobiales (O2) and Oleimicrobiales (O3) were predominantly detected in hydrothermal vents and sediment, and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4) was enriched in marine environments. Despite limited data for Oceanimicrobiales (O5), Zhuqueibacterota's broad ecological presence (Figure 1C) highlights its adaptability across various habitats, emphasizing its ecological significance. Previous studies suggested that Zhuqueibacterota is enriched in anoxic environments [1], leading to the hypothesis of an anaerobic lifestyle. In our study, genes associated with anaerobic metabolism, such as acetyl-CoA synthetase (acs), phosphate acetyltransferase (pta), acetate kinase (ack), aldehyde dehydrogenase (aldh), and alcohol dehydrogenase (adh), were detected across all clades of Zhuqueibacterota (Table S6), suggesting they may have the ability to produce ethanol through fermentation [8]. Additionally, we identified the Rnf complexes [9] were widely distributed among Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Phylogenetic analysis of the rnfABCDEG operon indicated that they clustered with anaerobic microorganisms (Figure S3), further suggesting the potential anaerobic lifestyle of Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Remarkably, Zhuqueibacterota harbored cydAB genes, encoding the cytochrome bd ubiquinol oxidase, which provides an O2-directed respiratory chain under low-oxygen conditions. The coxABC genes [10] were identified in all MAGs of the Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5), as well as in three MAGs of the Residuimicrobiales (O2) and two MAGs of the Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Additionally, we observed that several MAGs from Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) encoded the aerobic aa3-type cytochrome c oxidase [10]. However, the genes of complete pathways for oxidative phosphorylation were just widely distributed in Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5). These findings suggest that members of Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) may have the ability to utilize oxygen as a terminal electron acceptor. Considering these observations, we propose that members of Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) are more likely facultative anaerobes, rather than being obligate anaerobes. Through metabolic reconstruction, all Zhuqueibacterota orders contain complete genes for glycolysis, gluconeogenesis, and pentose phosphate pathways (Figure 1D). MAGs assigned to the Zhuqueibacterales (O1), Thermofontimicrobiales (O4), and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) harbor the complete gene sets for the TCA cycle. We also identified a diverse array of carbohydrate-active enzymes (CAZymes) among the 75 MAGs, including 79 glycoside hydrolases (GHs), 10 glycosyl transferases (GTs), 10 carbohydrate esterases (CEs), 8 polysaccharide lyases (PLs), and 10 carbohydrate-binding modules (CBMs) (Table S7). Interestingly, the gene encoding the large subunit of ribulose-1,5-bisphosphate carboxylase/oxygenase (RuBisCO) was identified in 35 MAGs of Zhuqueibacterales (O1). Phylogenetic analysis revealed that the RuBisCO large subunit (rbcL) gene belongs to form I group (Figure 2A), which plays a crucial role in carbon fixation via the CBB cycle [11]. Moreover, genes encoding RuBisCO small subunit (rbcS), phosphoribulokinase (PRK), transketolase (TKT), fructose-1,6-bisphosphate aldolase (FBPA), fructose-1,6-bisphosphatase (FBPase), and ribulose-5-phosphate 3-epimerase (RuPE) were found near the rbcL gene cluster (Figure 2B). Based on these observations, we hypothesize that members of Zhuqueibacterota possess the capability for carbon fixation via the CBB cycle. Notably, the absence of sedoheptulose-1,7-bisphosphatase (SBPase) and the presence of transaldolase (TAL) suggest that Zhuqueibacterota uses the transaldolase-variant of the CBB cycle [12, 13]. Carbon fixation via the CBB cycle requires significant energy and reducing equivalents, and hydrogen is a critical energy source in terrestrial hot springs [14] and hydrothermal vents [15]. Numerous prokaryotes can utilize H2 and CO2 as their energy and carbon source [16]. In our study, genes annotated to encode hydrogenases were present in Zhuqueibacterota, and the phylogenetic analyses of hydrogenases revealed five different clades ([Ni&#8211;Fe] group 1d, 3b-3d, and [Fe&#8211;Fe] group) (Figure S4). In Zhuqueibacterales (O1) MAGs, especially those containing CBB gene cluster, we identified two types of hydrogenases (Figure 2C). The [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1d hydrogenase, a membrane-bound hydrogenase, transfers electrons from H2 to the respiratory chain via membrane-connected cytochromes [17] (Figure S4). Additionally, the cytosolic [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 3b hydrogenase transfers electrons generated by H2 oxidation to NAD+ [18], which serves as a reducing equivalent, for carbon fixation or for ATP production through the respiratory chain [17]. The biosynthesis and maturation of [Ni&#8211;Fe] hydrogenase are catalyzed by six Hyp proteins (hypABCDEF) [19]. The co-localization of hydrogenase maturation proteins, [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1 d and 3b hydrogenases (Figure 2C) indicate that Zhuqueibacterales (O1) likely utilizes hydrogen as an energy source for carbon fixation. The CBB cycle operates aerobically [20], and both the [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1d and 3b hydrogenases exhibit O2 tolerance, maintaining hydrogen oxidation even in the presence of oxygen. This further supports the hypothesis that Zhuqueibacterota is facultative anaerobic mixotrophy. Utilizing METABOLIC v4.0, we constructed a community metabolic network comprising with 186 medium/high-quality MAGs (completeness &gt;50% and contamination &lt;6%) derived from JZ2 hot spring (JZ2_202007). Despite being represented by only two MAGs, Zhuqueibacterota exhibited the highest relative abundance (15.48%). It contributed to 24 metabolic processes, with a relative contribution exceeding 25% (Figure S5, Table S8). Notably, Zhuqueibacterota dominated carbon fixation via the CBB cycle, with the highest contribution (57.9%) among all microbial taxa (Table S8). These findings suggest that Zhuqueibacterota, with its chemolithoautotrophic capabilities, plays a vital role in this ecosystem. To decipher the evolutionary histories of the Zhuqueibacterota, we predicted gene gain and loss events mapping onto a Bayesian tree showed that contemporary Zhuqueibacterota harbor more gene families over time (Figure 2D, Figure S6), with 71% of HGT events occurred within Zhuqueibacterales (O1), mostly from hot spring-associated MAGs. HGT played a major role in genome diversity, despite the common trend of genome reduction in hot spring environments. The ancestral Zhuqueibacterota likely possessed hydrogenase, with later loss events leading to the loss of this hydrogen utilization capability in some lineages. The cydAB gene (Figure 2E, Table S9) for high oxygen stress response was acquired early, while the coxABC gene was independently acquired by different lineages (Figure 2E, Table S9). Anaerobic fermentation-related genes were lost at multiple evolutionary nodes, potentially contributing to metabolic diversity, indicating that the ancestors of Zhuqueibacterota were facultative anaerobic bacteria. Genes related to the CBB cycle, such as rbcL, rbcS, and PRK, were acquired gradually. Over time, Zhuqueibacterota inhabiting thermal environments gained the ability for carbon fixation via the CBB cycle. In this study, we have expanded our understanding of the uncultured phylum KSB1, herein Zhuqueibacterota, by utilizing high-quality genomes to explore its diversity and function. Our analysis indicated that Zhuqueibacterota has clear functional differentiation, and distinct environmental preferences among its clades. Notably, this phylum represents a group of facultative anaerobic chemoautotrophs, which play a pivotal role in sustaining microbial communities in hot springs. Ancestral state reconstructions suggest the facultative anaerobic lifestyle of their ancestor, while carbon fixation capabilities probably evolved through HGT. Overall, this study provides new insights into the ecological functions of Zhuqueibacterota and open avenues for further research. Moreover, the findings indicate the possibility of isolating and purifying members of this phylum using the hydrogen-oxidizing autotrophic enrichment system. Zheng-Han Lian: Writing&#8212;review and editing; writing&#8212;original draft; software. Nimaichand Salam: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis; data curation; investigation. Sha Tan: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; visualization. Yang Yuan: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; visualization. Meng-Meng Li: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; resources. Yu-Xian Li: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software. Ze-Tao Liu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; data curation. Chao-Jian Hu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; methodology. Ai-Ping Lv: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis. Yu-Ting OuYang: Writing&#8212;review and editing; validation. Cai-Yu Lu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis. Jing-Yi Zhang: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization. Ying Chen: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; data curation. Le-Bin Chen: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; resources. Zhen-Hao Luo: Writing&#8212;review and editing; resources; validation. Bin Ma: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software. Zheng-Shuang Hua: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software. Jian-Yu Jiao: Supervision; writing&#8212;review and editing; writing&#8212;original draft; software; funding acquisition. Wen-Jun Li: Supervision; writing&#8212;review and editing; funding acquisition; project administration; resources. Lan Liu: Supervision; writing&#8212;original draft; writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software; validation; funding acquisition; project administration; data curation; resources. This research received financial support from the Key R&amp;D Program of Zhejiang Province (2023C02004, 2023C020015), the Key-Area Research and Development Program of Guangdong Province (2022B0202110001), the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grants No. 92251302, 32200010, 32300001, 32200007, and 32370011), the National Science and Technology Fundamental Resources Investigation Program of China (2021FY100900), and the Fundamental Research Funds for the Universities (Nos. 23ptpy11, 23ptpy136, and 23ptpy137). We extend our sincere appreciation to the staff at Yunnan Tengchong Volcano for their invaluable assistance and gracious permission granted for sample collection. Special thanks are due to Dr. Chih-Min Chang from Guangdong Magigene Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China, for his expert guidance and support throughout the data analysis process. The authors declare no conflicts of interest. No animals or humans were involved in this study. The MAGs discussed in this research have been archived in the GenBank database under the BioProject ID PRJNA895542 (https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/bioproject/PRJNA895542/). Accession numbers for each individual MAG are detailed in Table S1. The data and scripts used are saved in GitHub https://github.com/lianzhh-pub/Code_for_iMeta2024. Supplementary materials (methods, figures, tables, graphical abstract, slides, videos, Chinese translated version, and updated materials) may be found in the online DOI or iMeta Science http://www.imeta.science/. The data that supports the findings of this study are available in the supplementary material of this article. Figure S1. Phylogeny of Zhuqueibacterota. Figure S2. The ANI/AAI heatmap of all pairwise comparisons. Figure S3. The phylogenetic tree based on concatenated alignment of Rnf complex genes. Figure S4. Phylogenetic trees and classification of hydrogenases and metabolic model of hydrogen-oxidizing bacteria. Figure S5. Microbial contribution to carbon, nitrogen, and sulfur cycling in hot spring. Figure S6. Ancestral genome content reconstruction using COUNT software. Figure S7. Phylogenetic tree of nosZ gene. Figure S8. Variation and correlation of genome size and GC content across orders of Zhuqueibacterota. Figure S9. Plot of Principal Coordinates Analysis (PCoA) based on functional traits of Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S1. General genomic features of Candidate Division KSB1 genomes from hot spring. Table S2. Genomic overview of Candidate Division KSB1 reference genome. Table S3. ANI/AAI values for each genome pair. Table S4. Brief nomenclature of Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S5. Global distribution and relative abundances of the Zhuqueibacterota. Table S6. List of genes in the metabolic model of Zhuqueibacterota. Table S7. CAZyme statistics for Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S8. The MW-score for JZ2 hot spring metagenomic dataset. Table S9. Gene gain and loss events detected at key nodes. Please note: The publisher is not responsible for the content or functionality of any supporting information supplied by the authors. Any queries (other than missing content) should be directed to the corresponding author for the article.</description>
      <author>Zheng&#8208;Han Lian, Nimaichand Salam, Sha Tan, Yang Yuan, Meng&#8208;Meng Li, Yu&#8208;Xian Li, Ze&#8208;Tao Liu, Chao&#8208;Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yu&#8208;Ting OuYang, Caiyu Lu, Jingyi Zhang, Ying Chen, Le&#8208;Bin Chen, Zhen&#8208;Hao Luo, Bin Ma, Zheng&#8208;Shuang Hua, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Wen&#8208;Jun Li, Lan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/imt2.249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eLife Assessment: Spatial and temporal coordination of Duox/TrpA1/Dh31 and IMD pathways is required for the efficient elimination of pathogenic bacteria in the intestine of Drosophila larvae</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.98716.3.sa0</link>
      <description>Bruno Lemaitre, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631782

                Full text Figures and data Peer review Side by side eLife Assessment This article describes a novel mechanism allows Drosophila to combat enteric pathogens while also preserving the beneficial indigenous microbiota. The authors provide compelling evidence that oral infection of Drosophila larvae by pathogenic bacteria activate a valve that traps the intruders in the anterior midgut, allowing them to be killed by antimicrobial peptides. This is an important finding revealing a new mechanism of host defense in the gut of insects. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.98716.3.sa0 Significance of the findings: Important: Findings that have theoretical or practical implications beyond a single subfield Landmark Fundamental Important Valuable Useful Strength of evidence: Compelling: Evidence that features methods, data and analyses more rigorous than the current state-of-the-art Exceptional Compelling Convincing Solid Incomplete Inadequate During the peer-review process the editor and reviewers write an eLife Assessment that summarises the significance of the findings reported in the article (on a scale ranging from landmark to useful) and the strength of the evidence (on a scale ranging from exceptional to inadequate). Learn more about eLife Assessments Abstract Introduction Results Discussion Materials and methods Data availability References Article and author information Metrics Abstract Multiple gut antimicrobial mechanisms are coordinated in space and time to efficiently fight foodborne pathogens. In Drosophila melanogaster, production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and antimicrobial peptides (AMPs) together with intestinal cell renewal play a key role in eliminating gut microbes. A complementary mechanism would be to isolate and treat pathogenic bacteria while allowing colonization by commensals. Using real-time imaging to follow the fate of ingested bacteria, we demonstrate that while commensal Lactiplantibacillus plantarum freely circulate within the intestinal lumen, pathogenic strains such as Erwinia carotovora or Bacillus thuringiensis, are blocked in the anterior midgut where they are rapidly eliminated by antimicrobial peptides. This sequestration of pathogenic bacteria in the anterior midgut requires the Duox enzyme in enterocytes, and both TrpA1 and Dh31 in enteroendocrine cells. Supplementing larval food with hCGRP, the human homolog of Dh31, is sufficient to block the bacteria, suggesting the existence of a conserved mechanism. While the immune deficiency (IMD) pathway is essential for eliminating the trapped bacteria, it is dispensable for the blockage. Genetic manipulations impairing bacterial compartmentalization result in abnormal colonization of posterior midgut regions by pathogenic bacteria. Despite a functional IMD pathway, this ectopic colonization leads to bacterial proliferation and larval death, demonstrating the critical role of bacteria anterior sequestration in larval defense. Our study reveals a temporal orchestration during which pathogenic bacteria, but not innocuous, are confined in the anterior part of the midgut in which they are eliminated in an IMD-pathway-dependent manner. Introduction One of the key avenues by which bacterial pathogens infiltrate a host is through the ingestion of contaminated food. Following the entry of bacteria in the intestine, the host defense mechanisms will operate in a temporal manner, with mechanical and constitutive chemical barriers serving as the first line of defense, followed by inducible mechanisms involving the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS), the transcription, translation, and secretion of antimicrobial peptides (AMPs) as well as inter-organ signaling to cope with possible upcoming stages of infection. This temporality is evident between innate and adaptive immunity, with the former considered the primary defense line that contains and combats the threat while preparing the more subtle adaptive response. To focus on deciphering innate immune processes, the insect Drosophila melanogaster has been widely and successfully used (Neyen et al., 2014; Younes et al., 2020). This model has made it possible to establish the chronology of the events involved in the defense against pathogenic bacteria. In Drosophila, as in all metazoans, a layer made of mucus, completed with a peritrophic membrane in insect midguts, protects the intestine lining from direct contact with pathogens (Hegedus et al., 2009; Lemaitre and Miguel-Aliaga, 2013; Pelaseyed et al., 2014). In adult Drosophila, a conserved immune response involving the production of ROS by Duox (dual oxidase) enzyme in enterocytes (ECs) is triggered in the intestine as early as 30 min after ingesting pathogenic bacteria. ROS directly damage bacterial membranes (Benguettat et al., 2018; Ha et al., 2009; Ha et al., 2005; Lee et al., 2013) but also exert an indirect effect in adults by triggering visceral spasms through the host detection of ROS mediated by the TrpA1 nociceptor and subsequent secretion of diuretic hormone 31 (Dh31) by enteroendocrine cells (EECs; Benguettat et al., 2018; Du et al., 2016a). Dh31 then binds its receptor on visceral muscles, triggering contractions that expedite bacterial elimination (Benguettat et al., 2018). This pathway seems to be conserved during evolution as TrpA1 is a Drosophila homolog of TRP receptors that respond to noxious conditions (Ogawa et al., 2016) and Dh31 is the Drosophila homolog of the mammalian CGRP (Guo et al., 2022; N&#228;ssel and Zandawala, 2019). In parallel, the immune deficiency (IMD) innate immune pathway is activated following bacterial peptidoglycan detection, leading to the transcription of AMP encoding genes and to the subsequent secretion of the peptides that kill bacteria (Capo et al., 2019). Previous study has explored the dynamics of food transit involving intestinal valves and Dh31 in the context of Drosophila larvae (LaJeunesse et al., 2010). Additionally, the perturbed circulation of bacteria within the intestine has not been documented in the literature though some specific localization of commensal and pathogenic bacteria along the intestine have been observed in insects (Basset et al., 2000; Bosco-Drayon et al., 2012; Lanan et al., 2016; Nardi et al., 2016; Ramond et al., 2021; Yao et al., 2022). However, the intricate interplay between the sequestration of bacteria in specific gut regions and their subsequent elimination has remained unexplored. In our study, we leveraged a novel real-time experimental system designed specifically for Drosophila larvae, enabling us to meticulously trace the journey and ultimate fate of pathogenic bacteria ingested alongside food. This approach has allowed us to shed light on the complex mechanisms underpinning bacterial management within the larval gut, contributing a significant advancement to our understanding of host-pathogen interactions at the intestinal level. We characterized a new mechanism implicated in the blockage and elimination of pathogenic bacteria in the anterior part of the midgut. We demonstrated that this confinement is regulated by the ROS/TrpA1/Dh31 axis. Our results delineate a model in which bacterial trapping arises from ROS production in the intestinal lumen in response to pathogenic bacteria. These ROS compounds interact with TrpA1 in Dh31-expressing EECs located between the anterior and middle midgut, leading to Dh31 secretion and subsequent bacterial compartmentalization, suggesting the closure of a valve, a midgut junction structure proposed by LaJeunesse et al., 2010. Interestingly, we found that we can ectopically induce the trapping of fluorescent particles or innocuous bacteria using human CGRP that replaces Dh31. Our findings also highlight the central role of this blockage, which acts first allowing sufficient time for the subsequent eradication of blocked pathogens by the IMD pathway and its downstream effectors. Collectively, our data unravel a finely tuned coordination between the ROS/TrpA1/Dh31 axis and the IMD pathway, enabling an effective bactericidal action of AMPs. Results Bacterial confinement in the anterior part of larval intestine The translucency of Drosophila larvae allows for live studies of immune defense components and their coordination in eradicating pathogenic bacteria. In our prior work, we revealed a modified food transit in larvae exposed to the Gram-negative opportunistic bacterium Erwinia carotovora carotovora (Ecc15), a process that involved TrpA1 (Keita et al., 2017). Using blue food dye, we tracked the presence of food in the intestinal lumen and observed that larval guts were blue without bacterial contaminants, while in the presence of Ecc15, they appeared clearer (Keita et al., 2017). Such a strategy was already used to delineate whether oral infection by Pseudomonas entomophila could modulate food transit (Liehl et al., 2006). However, our previous assay with Ecc15 was limited to 1 hr post-ingestion and using a food dye, not directly moenitoring the fate of the ingested bacteria over the time. We therefore designed a new protocol allowing to film the fate of fluorescent bacteria once ingested by the larvae. Animals are fed for 1 hr with food contaminated with fluorescent bacteria to investigate the localization of these pathogens within the intestinal tract. Following this feeding period, the animals were transferred to a wet chamber devoid of food. This setup allowed us to monitor the positional dynamics of the bacteria within the intestine over time, without further food intake influencing the observations. We principally tested three different fluorescent bacteria: Ecc15-GFP (Ecc, an opportunistic Gram-negative bacterium), Bacillus thuringiensis-GFP (Bt, an opportunistic Gram-positive bacterium), and Lactiplantibacillus plantarum-GFP (Lp, a commensal Gram-positive bacterium). After 1 hr of feeding on contaminated media, Ecc and Bt were concentrated in the anterior midgut (Videos 1 and 2). The location of the bacteria specifically in the anterior part of the intestine following 1 hr exposure was confirmed when individuals from populations were imaged and counted (Figure 1A). The consistently defined limits of the area containing bacteria in the anterior part of the gut across our observations strongly indicate the presence of a physical boundary. This reproducibility contrasts with what would be expected if the cessation of food intake was responsible for halting bacterial progression, which would likely result in more variable bacterial distributions within the intestine among individual subjects (Figure 1A). Remarkably, with animals fed 1 hr with Ecc or Bt and transferred in a wet chamber, tracking the GFP signal over time revealed that it remained in the anterior part of the larva and began to fade 6 hr after ingestion (Videos 1 and 2; Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 1A and B). This fading suggests the elimination of the bacteria, while the larva continued to exhibit active movements. This pattern was observed for both Ecc and Bt. Interestingly, the blockage is reversible and may depend upon the presence or status of the trapped bacteria. Indeed, if fluorescent dextran polymers are co incubated with Ecc, both bacteria and dextran are blocked in the anterior part of the intestine and following bacteria-associated fluorescence disappearance, the dextran is released in the posterior part (Video 3). However, unlike the opportunistic bacteria Ecc and Bt, a food mixture contaminated with Lp led to the bacteria being present in the posterior compartment of the larval midgut after 1 hr of feeding and remained there throughout the 16 hr duration of our observation (Video 4, Figure 1A and Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 1C; Storelli et al., 2018). To better characterize the blockage phenomenon, we counted the ratio of larvae with trapped GFP-bacteria 1 hr post feeding. Importantly, in all our experiments, approximately 20% of larvae displayed an absence of fluorescent bacteria within the intestinal lumen. Notably, this proportion remained consistent across different bacterial strains used to contaminate the food, indicating that the specific compartmentalization of pathogenic bacteria we observed is not related to a global food-intake cessation. Instead, these findings suggest the deployment of a targeted sequestration mechanism. Focusing on animals containing fluorescent bacteria, we found that while less than 10% of the larvae had Lp blocked in the anterior part of the intestine, more than 80% of the larvae had Ecc and Bt bacteria localized in the anterior part of the midgut (Figure 1A and B). We completed our observation of the posterior location of non-pathogenic bacteria with another harmless species, the OP50 strain of Escherichia coli (Eco). Less than 20% of the animals fed a mixture containing Eco showed a blocking phenotype. The portion of the intestine containing the fluorescent bacteria is delimited posteriorly by an extensive turn, a region that was suggested to act like a valve (LaJeunesse et al., 2010). Importantly, the blockage of pathogenic bacteria (Ecc and Bt) in the anterior part of the intestine was confirmed using D. melanogaster larvae with different genetic backgrounds (Figure 1C). To confirm our findings, we dissected the intestines of larvae that had ingested the bacteria. Our analysis confirmed that Ecc and Bt were predominantly located in the anterior part of the intestines, whereas Lp was not, supporting our initial observations (Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 2). Our data collectively indicate that pathogenic bacteria, such as Ecc and Bt, are spatially confined to the anterior part of the larval midgut before their disappearance. In contrast, the commensal bacterium Lp or the innocuous Eco line we used are distributed throughout the midgut, persisting principally in the posterior part. Figure 1 with 2 supplements see all Download asset Open asset Contrary to Lp or Eco, Ecc or Bt bacteria are found exclusively in the anterior part of the gut. (A) Pictures to illustrate the position of the green fluorescence of control (CantonS) L3 stage larvae as a group (upper panel) or individual (lower panel) after having been fed 1 hr with a media containing yeast and GFP-producing bacteria (Ecc or Bt or Lp). The white asterisk indicates the anterior part of the animal. The white arrow indicates the posterior limit of the area containing the fluorescent bacteria. Below the pictures are schematics representing larvae, their gut, and the relative position of the GFP-producing bacteria in green. Scale bar is 1 mm. (B) Graphic representing the blockage ratio for CantonS (ctrl) L3 larvae exposed during 1 hr to a mixture composed of yeast and fluorescent bacteria: Lp or Escherichia coli (Eco) or Ecc or Bt. The ratio of control larvae with a distinguishable green fluorescence only in the upper part of the intestine, considered as blocked bacteria, is represented. The ratio is calculated as: x larvae with bacteria exclusively in the anterior part of the gut / (x larvae with bacteria exclusively in the anterior part of the gut +y larvae with bacteria all along the gut). Larvae with no distinguishable fluorescence were considered as non-eaters and discarded from the quantifications. The ratio of larvae with no distinguishable fluorescence was not influenced by the different conditions we tested. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 30 animals per condition and trial. **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. (C) Blockage ratio for L3 larvae of w1, Oregon or w1118 isogenized genotypes fed during various times with a mixture combining yeast with Lp, Ecc, or Bt. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 100 animals in total. The 0 symbol indicates an absence of blockage, **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. Video 1 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Ecc is blocked in the anterior part of the larval intestine then vanishes. Live imaging during 12 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Ecc fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018385.v2. Video 2 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Bt is blocked in the anterior part of the larval intestine then vanishes. Live imaging during 12 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Bt fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018427.v2. Video 3 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Dextran-TexasRed is concomitantly blocked Fluorescent Bt in the anterior part of the larval intestine then released posteriorly following bacterial clearance. Live imaging during 6 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Bt fluorescent bacteria and Dextran-Texas-Red then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. The anterior part of the larvae is at the bottom right. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.26355076.v1. Video 4 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Lp is not blocked in the anterior part of the larval intestine and persists in the posterior midgut. Live imaging during 10 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Lp fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018442.v2. The anterior intestinal confinement of pathogenic bacteria is dose-specific and occurs rapidly We hypothesized that the bacterial localization specifically in the anterior part of the larval intestine was an active host response and might be dependent on the bacterial dose. To test this, we exposed larvae to varying concentrations of Ecc and Bt and measured the blockage ratio. We found that a concentration of 2.109 Ecc bacteria per ml was sufficient to induce the bacterial compartmentalization, whereas for Bt, a concentration of 4.1010 Bt bacteria per ml was required (Figure 2A). Interestingly, following over time the intoxication of control larvae with a Bt concentration of 1.1010 bacteria per ml instead of 4.1010 Bt bacteria per ml revealed that bacteria were not sequestered in the anterior part of the intestine but reached the posterior part (Video 5). Nonetheless, the fluorescence remained weak likely due to the low amount of bacteria and we could even observed an excretion of bacteria. For all subsequent experiments, we used 4.1010 bacteria per ml. Figure 2 with 1 supplement see all Download asset Open asset Bacterial blockage is dose-dependent, occurs in less than 30 min, and does not involve a group effect. (A) Blockage ratio for control L3 larvae fed 1 hr with a mixture combining yeast with different concentrations of fluorescent Ecc or Bt, concentrations are in number of bacteria per ml. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 18 animals per condition and trial. **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. (B) Representative images of control larvae fed during 30 min. with Bt. Scale bar is 1 mm. (C) Blockage ratio for control L3 larvae fed during various times with a mixture combining yeast with Ecc or Bt. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 20 animals per condition and trial. ns indicates values with differences not statistically significant, **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. (D) Blockage ratio for control L3 larvae fed 1 hr as individual animals or as groups of 10 or &gt;40 with a mixture combining yeast with a constant concentration of Ecc or Bt (4.1010 bacteria per ml). Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with the exact number of animals indicated per condition and trial. ns indicates values with differences not statistically significant, Fischer exact t-test. See the source data file for details. Video 5 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Bt at a low concentration is not blocked in the anterior part of the larval intestine, persists in the posterior midgut and the larva does not die. Live imaging during 10 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Bt fluorescent bacteria (1.1010 bacteria per ml instead of 4.1010) then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.26355196.v1. In previous contamination assays, we arbitrary used a 1 hr time point to assess the phenotype. However, observations of bacterial blockage occurring within minutes suggested that this response does not require de novo protein synthesis by the host. Shorter exposure times revealed that Ecc was blocked in the anterior part of the intestine within 15 min, while Bt showed a similar pattern beginning at 15 min and completing by 30 min (Figure 2B and C). Based on these results, we defined 1 hr as our standard exposure time of larvae with bacterial contaminated food. In addition, we performed longer continuous feeding with Ecc (20 hr) to assay whether the blockage would still be present. We observed that while most of the larvae continuously exposed to the contaminated mixture tend to flee and do not contain fluorescent bacteria in their intestine, the ones with detectable fluorescence were blocking the bacteria (Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 1). Our assays typically involved groups of approximately 50 larvae to observe population-level phenomena. Recent studies have suggested that larval behavior can be influenced by group dynamics (Dombrovski et al., 2019; Dombrovski et al., 2017; Louis and de Polavieja, 2017; Mast et al., 2014). To determine whether group size affects the bacterial confinement, we exposed groups of varying sizes to Bt or Ecc and measured the blockage ratio. The phenomenon proved robust even with a single larva exposed to contaminated food, indicating that the response was not influenced by group size under our experimental conditions (Figure 2D). Based on these findings, for all subsequent experiments, we standardized the conditions using 4.1010 bacteria per ml, a 1 hr exposure time, and groups of at least 20 larvae. Host TrpA1 and Dh31 are crucial for the blockage phenotype In our previous study reporting an altered food transit for larvae exposed to a food contaminated with Ecc (Keita et al., 2017), we identified the gene TrpA1 as essential for the host response. The TrpA1 protein, a member of the TRP channel family, facilitates Ca2 +entry into cells at temperatures over 25 &#176;C or upon exposure to chemicals such as ROS (Du et al., 2016b; Gu et al., 2019; Guntur et al., 2015). This channel, involved in nociception (Lapointe and Altier, 2011), has been linked to intestinal muscle activity in adult Drosophila following Ecc exposure (Du et al., 2016a) and in response to ROS production by the host (Benguettat et al., 2018). We examined the role of TrpA1 during the larval response to contaminated food using TrpA11 homozygous viable mutant in the experimental setup with fluorescent Lp, Ecc, or Bt bacteria. In these mutant larvae, while the localization of Lp in the posterior midgut remained unchanged, Ecc and Bt were found in the posterior midgut following a 1 hr intoxication and the fluorescence does not fade (Figure 3A and B, Video 6 and Figure 3&#8212;figure supplement 1A). This observation underscores that TrpA1 is necessary for the blockage of pathogenic bacteria in the anterior midgut and suggests that the disappearance of the fluorescence observed for pathogenic bacteria within the intestine of control animals may be due to bacteria being killed rather than fading of GFP or plasmid loss. Considering previous reports on visceral contraction in adult Drosophila linked to ROS production, detection by TrpA1, and Dh31 secretion to expel bacteria (Benguettat et al., 2018; Du et al., 2016a), we wondered whether a similar ROS/TrpA1/Dh31 signaling axis is necessary in larvae to block pathogenic bacteria in the anterior midgut. Indeed, the bacterial blockage we observed might involve muscle contractions related to food contamination. Thus, we tested the blockage ratio of Dh31KG09001 homozygous viable mutants exposed to Lp, Bt, or Ecc bacteria. In contrast to control animals, where fewer than 20% of larvae exhibited Ecc or Bt in the posterior section of the intestine, for more than 60% of Dh31KG09001 mutant larvae, the pathogenic bacteria Bt or Ecc were localized in the posterior midgut confirming Dh31's crucial role in this mechanism (Figure 3A and B, Video 7 and Figure 3&#8212;figure supplement 1B). The localization of Lp was not affected (Figure 3B). Figure 3 with 2 supplements see all Download asset Open asset The bacterial blockage necessitates Duox in enterocytes, the TrpA1 channel and Dh31 in Pros + cells. (A) Pictures to illustrate the localization of the fluorescent bacteria within the intestine of control (ctrl), TrpA11 or Dh31KG09001 L3 larvae after having been fed 1 hr with a mixture of yeast and Ecc. Scale bar is 1 mm. (B) Blockage ratio for control (ctrl) L3 larvae or mutants for TrpA11 or Dh31KG09001 fed 1 hr with a mixture combining yeast and Lp or Ecc or Bt or fluorescent Dextran with or without hCGRP hormone. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 30 animals per condition and trial. 0 indicates an absence of blockage. **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. (C) Pictures to illustrate the localization of the fluorescence within the intestine of control L3 larvae after having been fed 1 hr with a mixture of yeast and fluorescent Dextran with or without hCGRP hormone. Below the pictures are schematics representing larvae, their gut, and the relative position of the fluorescence in green. Scale bar is 1 mm. (D) Blockage ratio for animals expressing RNA interference constructions directed against Duox mRNA or Dh31 mRNA, ubiquitously (Da-Gal4), in enterocytes (Mex-Gal4) or in enteroendocrine cells (Pros-Gal4) and then fed 1 hr with a mixture combining yeast and Ecc or Bt. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 30 animals per condition and trial. ns indicates values with differences not statistically significant, **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. Video 6 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Ecc is not blocked in the anterior part of the TrpA1 mutant larval intestine and persists in the posterior midgut. Live imaging during 10 hr of a L3 TrpA1 mutant larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Ecc fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018463.v1. Video 7 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Ecc is not blocked in the anterior part of the Dh31 mutant larval intestine and persists in the posterior midgut. Live imaging during 10 hr of a L3 Dh31 mutant larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Ecc fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber.https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018472.v1. Given the possibility that the compartmentalization of pathogens we observed might be driven by bacterial virulence factors, we aimed to further investigate the underlying mechanism. To discern whether this phenomenon was specific to pathogenic bacteria or could extend to non-pathogenic entities, we conducted experiments to determine if abiotic particles or non-virulent bacteria could also be ectopically sequestered within the gut. The human Calcitonin Gene-Related Peptide (hCGRP) is the functional homolog of Dh31. Indeed, hCGRP has been shown to promote visceral muscle contractions in adult flies (Benguettat et al., 2018). To investigate whether the bacterial confinement could be triggered without pathogenic bacteria in response to a hormone, we exposed larvae to either Lp or Dextran-FITC in the presence of hCGRP. While Lp and Dextran-FITC were normally distributed throughout the midgut, adding hCGRP to the food induced a significant blockage (Figure 3</description>
      <author>Bruno Lemaitre</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.98716.3.sa0</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
