<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 01:11:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Inactive Ag Modification and Defect Engineering Optimization on Three-Dimensional Coral-Like High-Entropy Oxides to Trigger Effective Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4896977</link>
      <description>Bing Zhang, Mengzhao Liu, Meiqin Cui, Weiming L&#252;, Ping Geng, Weiming Yi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400673542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Zhang, Mengzhao Liu, Meiqin Cui, Weiming L&#252;, Ping Geng, Weiming Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4896977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of nickel-cobalt-zinc oxide/manganese-nickel hydroxide/reduced graphene oxide on nickel foam for efficient supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.07.193</link>
      <description>Shangru Zhou, Hanwei Zhao, E. Fan, Zhuanfang Zhang, Guohua Dong, Wenzhi Zhang, Yu Zang, Ming Zhao, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Xiaoming Huang, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400676349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shangru Zhou, Hanwei Zhao, E. Fan, Zhuanfang Zhang, Guohua Dong, Wenzhi Zhang, Yu Zang, Ming Zhao, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Xiaoming Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.07.193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atom Catalysts for Electrochemical Water Splitting: A Critical Review of Recent Advancements in Single-Site, Dual-Site, and Alloy Configurations for Enhanced Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/au.172115273.30149968/v1</link>
      <description>Maheswari Arunachalm, Kwang&#8208;Soon Ahn, Soon Hyung Kang, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400678453

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maheswari Arunachalm, Kwang&#8208;Soon Ahn, Soon Hyung Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/au.172115273.30149968/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Hydrothermal Synthesis of NiMn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/C Nanosheets for Solid-State Asymmetric Supercapacitor and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02216</link>
      <description>Pragati N. Thonge, Suprimkumar D. Dhas, Shivaji D. Waghmare, Aravind H. Patil, Teja M. Patil, Manesh A. Yewale, Avinash C. Mendhe, Daewon Kim, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400681305

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pragati N. Thonge, Suprimkumar D. Dhas, Shivaji D. Waghmare, Aravind H. Patil, Teja M. Patil, Manesh A. Yewale, Avinash C. Mendhe, Daewon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoS2@MWCNTs Core&#8211;shell Heterostructure for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/au.172114242.28442487/v1</link>
      <description>Huy Du Nguyen, Kyu Yeon Jang, Hye Bin Jung, MinJoong Kim, Chang&#8208;Soo Lee, Young&#8208;Woo Lee, Kyu&#8208;Nam Jung, Seung Woo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Hana Yoon, Younghyun Cho, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400684062

                This work reports the development of a MoS2@MWCNTs core&#8211;shell heterostructure synthesized through an optimized hydrothermal process, designed to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) efficiency in alkaline water electrolysis. By employing continuous tumbling during synthesis, a uniform and precise thickness of MoS2 was grown on the MWCNTs, striking a balance between maximal catalytic activity at the MoS2 edges, and leveraging the high electrical conductivity of the MWCNTs. The resulting MoS2@MWCNTs catalyst exhibited outstanding electrocatalytic performance for OER, with low overpotential of 285 mV at current density of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2, Tafel slope of 42 mV&#183;dec&#8722;1, and exceptional durability, maintaining stable operation over 900 hours. Furthermore, the catalyst demonstrated robust performance under dynamic and unstable operating conditions, highlighting its potential for real-world applications in green hydrogen production. This study showcases the successful application of a core&#8211;shell structure for OER catalysis, while contributing to the advancement of sustainable energy technologies by providing a cost-effective and efficient solution for hydrogen production through water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Huy Du Nguyen, Kyu Yeon Jang, Hye Bin Jung, MinJoong Kim, Chang&#8208;Soo Lee, Young&#8208;Woo Lee, Kyu&#8208;Nam Jung, Seung Woo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Hana Yoon, Younghyun Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/au.172114242.28442487/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerosol Assisted Synthesis of Iron Oxide@High Entropy Alloy Core-Shell Nanospheres as Superior Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/au.172114236.61135092/v1</link>
      <description>Burak K&#252;&#231;&#252;kelyas, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Zhipeng Yu, Duygu Ye&#351;iltepe &#214;z&#231;elik, Francis Leonard Deepak, Deniz Uzunsoy, Sebahattin G&#252;rmen, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400684242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Burak K&#252;&#231;&#252;kelyas, &#304;hsan &#199;aha, Zhipeng Yu, Duygu Ye&#351;iltepe &#214;z&#231;elik, Francis Leonard Deepak, Deniz Uzunsoy, Sebahattin G&#252;rmen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/au.172114236.61135092/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchoring Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;CeO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure on FeOOH&#8208;Modified Nickel&#8208;Mesh for Efficient Alkaline Water&#8208;Splitting Performance with Improved Stability under Quasi&#8208;Industrial Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403971</link>
      <description>Waleed Yaseen, Yuanguo Xu, Bashir Adegbemiga Yusuf, Suci Meng, Iltaf Khan, Jimin Xie, Yuanguo Xu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400686614

                Abstract Developing low&#8208;cost and industrially viable electrode materials for efficient water&#8208;splitting performance and constructing intrinsically active materials with abundant active sites is still challenging. In this study, a self&#8208;supported porous network Ni(OH) 2 &#8208;CeO x heterostructure layer on a FeOOH&#8208;modified Ni&#8208;mesh (NiCe/Fe@NM) electrode is successfully prepared by a facile, scalable two&#8208;electrode electrodeposition strategy for overall alkaline water splitting. The optimized NiCe 0.05 /Fe@NM catalyst reaches a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at an overpotential of 163 and 262 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively, in 1.0 m KOH with excellent stability. Additionally, NiCe 0.05 /Fe@NM demonstrates exceptional HER performance in alkaline seawater, requiring only 148 mV overpotential at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Under real water splitting conditions, NiCe 0.05 /Fe@NM requires only 1.701 V to achieve 100 mA cm &#8722;2 with robust stability over 1000 h in an alkaline medium. The remarkable water&#8208;splitting performance and stability of the NiCe 0.05 /Fe@NM catalyst result from a synergistic combination of factors, including well&#8208;optimized surface and electronic structures facilitated by an optimal Ce ratio, rapid reaction kinetics, a superhydrophilic/superaerophobic interface, and enhanced intrinsic catalytic activity. This study presents a simple two&#8208;electrode electrodeposition method for the scalable production of self&#8208;supported electrocatalysts, paving the way for their practical application in industrial water&#8208;splitting processes.</description>
      <author>Waleed Yaseen, Yuanguo Xu, Bashir Adegbemiga Yusuf, Suci Meng, Iltaf Khan, Jimin Xie, Yuanguo Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ion- and surface-sensitive interactions during oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1755-1315/1372/1/012101</link>
      <description>P D Angeles, Author Bustamante, H A S Sasil, D E D Loresca, Julie Anne D. del Rosario, IOP conference series. Earth and environmental science. 1372(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400686653

                Abstract Clean and sustainable energy has turned towards electrochemical water splitting as a viable solution in minimizing carbon emissions. Electrolysis of water converts electrical energy to chemical energy, through the production of hydrogen and oxygen gases, which can be harnessed for potential applications without contributing to greenhouse emissions. While this energy storage process shows great potential, its efficiency is hindered by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As a result, its widespread application in green electrolytic technologies is limited hence investigations on improving OER kinetics are of utmost importance. Recent research breakthroughs indicate that alkali metal cations are more than passive observers. They play complex roles in the electric double layer (EDL), which positively influences the OER kinetics. The presence of numerous ions and their combinations presents a challenge of complexity. This study aims to delve into the impact of alkali metal cations on OER activity due to the variance in their hydration energies. Specific investigations focusing on different alkali metal cations in solution, such as Li + , Na + , and K + , was conducted on RuO 2 to gain a deeper understanding of how these ions interact with both reactants and intermediate species in the reaction kinetics. Traditional electrochemical tests, including cyclic voltammetry (CV), linear sweep voltammetry (LSV), electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), and accelerated degradation test (ADT) measurements were employed to elucidate critical aspects such as surface activation, electric double layer interactions, catalytic activity and stability, ohmic resistance, and mass and charge transport.</description>
      <author>P D Angeles, Author Bustamante, H A S Sasil, D E D Loresca, Julie Anne D. del Rosario</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1755-1315/1372/1/012101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-Mediated Promotion of Cobalt-Based Oxygen Evolution Catalyst for Practical Anion-Exchange Membrane Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05983</link>
      <description>Pengcheng Yu, Xiaolong Zhang, Tian-Yun Zhang, Xuyingnan Tao, Yang Yu, Ye-Hua Wang, Sichao Zhang, Fei&#8208;Yue Gao, Zhuang&#8208;Zhuang Niu, Minghui Fan, Min&#8208;Rui Gao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400688461

                Scarce and expensive iridium oxide is still the cornerstone catalyst of polymer-electrolyte membrane electrolyzers for green hydrogen production because of its exceptional stability under industrially relevant oxygen evolution reaction (OER) conditions. Earth-abundant transition metal oxides used for this task, however, show poor long-term stability. We demonstrate here the use of nitrogen-doped cobalt oxide as an effective iridium substitute. The catalyst exhibits a low overpotential of 240 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Pengcheng Yu, Xiaolong Zhang, Tian-Yun Zhang, Xuyingnan Tao, Yang Yu, Ye-Hua Wang, Sichao Zhang, Fei&#8208;Yue Gao, Zhuang&#8208;Zhuang Niu, Minghui Fan, Min&#8208;Rui Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unbiased photoelectrochemical H2O2 coupled to H2 production via dual Sb2S3&#8208;based photoelectrodes with ultralow onset potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411305</link>
      <description>Lei Wang, Fei Guo, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400697173

                The productions of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) and hydrogen (H2) in a photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting cell suffer from an onset potential that limits solar conversion efficiencies. The formation of H2O2 through two&#8208;electron PEC water oxidation reaction competes with four&#8208;electron oxidation evolution reaction. Herein, we developed the surface selenium doped antimony trisulfide photoelectrode with the integrated ruthenium cocatalyst (Ru/Sb2(S,Se)3) to achieve the low onset potential and high Faraday efficiency (FE) for selective H2O2 production. The photoanode exhibits an average FE of 85% in the potential range of 0.4&#8208;1.6 VRHE and the H2O2 yield of 1.01 &#956;mol cm&#8208;2 min&#8208;1 at 1.6 VRHE, especially at low potentials of 0.1&#8208;0.55 VRHE with 80.4% FE. Impressively, an unassisted PEC system that employs light and electrolyte was constructed to simultaneously produce H2O2 and H2 production on both Ru/Sb2(S,Se)3 photoanode and the Pt/TiO2/Sb2S3 photocathode. The integrated system enables the average PEC H2O2 production rate of 0.637 &#956;mol cm&#8208;2 min&#8208;1 without applying any addition bias. This is the first demonstration that Sb2S3&#8208;based photoelectrodes exhibit H2O2/H2 two&#8208;side production with a strict key factor of the system, which represents its powerful platform to achieve high efficiency and productivity and the feasibility to facilitate value&#8208;added products in neutral conditions.</description>
      <author>Lei Wang, Fei Guo, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic&#8208;Level Observation of Potential&#8208;Dependent Variations at the Surface of an Oxide Catalyst during Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403392</link>
      <description>Chang Hyun Park, Hyungdoh Lee, Jin&#8208;Seok Choi, Tae Gyu Yun, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400699451

                Understanding the intricate details of the surface atomic structure and composition of catalysts during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for developing catalysts with high stability in water electrolyzers. While many notable studies highlight surface amorphization and reconstruction, systematic analytical tracing of the catalyst surface as a function of overpotential remains elusive. Heteroepitaxial (001) films of chemically stable and lattice-oxygen-inactive LaCoO</description>
      <author>Chang Hyun Park, Hyungdoh Lee, Jin&#8208;Seok Choi, Tae Gyu Yun, Young-Hwan Lim, Hyung Bin Bae, Sung&#8208;Yoon Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermocatalytic Epoxidation by Cobalt Sulfide Inspired by the Material&#8217;s Electrocatalytic Activity for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00518j</link>
      <description>Vanessa Wyss, Ionel Adrian Dinu, L. Marot, Cornelia G. Palivan, Murielle F. Delley, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400701558

                New discoveries in catalysis by earth-abundant materials can be guided by leveraging knowledge across two sub-disciplines of heterogeneous catalysis: electrocatalysis and thermocatalysis. Cobalt sulfide has been reported to be a...</description>
      <author>Vanessa Wyss, Ionel Adrian Dinu, L. Marot, Cornelia G. Palivan, Murielle F. Delley</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00518j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of MXene-based vacancy-confined single-atom catalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.014</link>
      <description>Zhongheng Fu, Guangtong Hai, Xia&#8208;Xia Ma, Dominik Legut, Yongchao Zheng, Xiang Chen, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400721513

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongheng Fu, Guangtong Hai, Xia&#8208;Xia Ma, Dominik Legut, Yongchao Zheng, Xiang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.07.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin high-entropy layered double hydroxide electrocatalysts for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175584</link>
      <description>Xianxu Chu, Ting Wang, Haoyuan Wang, Bingbing Du, Guanqun Guo, Yanli Zhou, Xuelin Dong, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400721805

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianxu Chu, Ting Wang, Haoyuan Wang, Bingbing Du, Guanqun Guo, Yanli Zhou, Xuelin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring of bulk oxygen vacancies in BiVO4 photoanodes via crystallization dynamics engineering for boosted photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154064</link>
      <description>Shiyuan Wang, Jie Jian, Fan Li, Ziying Zhang, Xiao&#8208;Long Feng, Yazhou Shuang, Yang Zhang, Yong Wang, Jiulong Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Lichao Jia, Hongqiang Wang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400722422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiyuan Wang, Jie Jian, Fan Li, Ziying Zhang, Xiao&#8208;Long Feng, Yazhou Shuang, Yang Zhang, Yong Wang, Jiulong Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Lichao Jia, Hongqiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic NiCo-MOF engineering on foam nickel for efficient oxygen evolution reaction in wide-pH-value water and seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154093</link>
      <description>Shuangyan Shang, Weichang Li, Lixin Zhang, Suyi Liu, Qinyu Tang, Chuanqi Feng, Chunsheng Li, Yanzhi Sun, Huimin Wu, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400722642

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuangyan Shang, Weichang Li, Lixin Zhang, Suyi Liu, Qinyu Tang, Chuanqi Feng, Chunsheng Li, Yanzhi Sun, Huimin Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactive oxygen species generation for catalysis and biotherapeutic applications based on crystalline porous materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216068</link>
      <description>Yunyang Qian, Bo Li, Muhammad Irfan, Dandan Li, Hai&#8208;Long Jiang, Coordination chemistry reviews. 518(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400726429

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunyang Qian, Bo Li, Muhammad Irfan, Dandan Li, Hai&#8208;Long Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.216068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe2O4 supported on g-CN nanosheet for oxygen evolution reaction in basic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.133</link>
      <description>K. M. Ashfaq, Muhammad Imran Saleem, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Arslan Aslam, A.M.A. Henaish, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Khurshid Ahmad, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400728693

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. M. Ashfaq, Muhammad Imran Saleem, Ahmed A. Ibrahim, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Arslan Aslam, A.M.A. Henaish, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Khurshid Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Bi2O3)0.705(Er2O3)0.245(WO3)0.05&#8211;Co3O4: A new oxygen electrode material with high oxygen reduction and evolution reaction catalytic activity for low-temperature solid oxide electrochemical cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235052</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Jiaqi Tang, Chengxin Li, Shan-Lin Zhang, Journal of power sources. 614(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400731103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Jiaqi Tang, Chengxin Li, Shan-Lin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalytic Properties of Novel Nanowire Structures from FeCo&#8208;MOFs/GO via Low&#8208;Temperature Annealing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400058</link>
      <description>Hao Liang, Yujie Lv, Kui Tang, Yuxin Chai, Jing Wang, Jing Wang, Yuyang Liu, Jianping Sun, Energy technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400734512

                Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) often suffer from poor stability, making them suitable precursors for metal oxides/porous carbon catalysts in the oxygen evolution reaction via pyrolysis. High&#8208;temperature treatment, however, leads to significant loss of active sites. To address this, Fe&#8208;MOFs, FeCo&#8208;MOFs, and FeCo&#8208;MOFs/graphene oxide (GO) composites using a one&#8208;pot hydrothermal method are synthesized and annealed at a low temperature of 300 &#176;C. Characterization reveals that FeCo&#8208;MOFs/GO composites possess unique nanowire structures mixed with a small amount of nanoflakes. It is believed that introducing graphene oxide plays a critical role in forming this structure, because the defects in GO provide numerous nucleation sites for nanowire growth. With high specific surface area and good stability, these nanostructures show a low overpotential of 261.5 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722; 2 and a Tafel slope of 20.47 mV dec &#8722;1 in 1 mol L &#8722;1 KOH alkaline water electrolysis. Density functional theory calculations further indicate that the synergistic effect of Fe and Co atoms enhances the catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Hao Liang, Yujie Lv, Kui Tang, Yuxin Chai, Jing Wang, Jing Wang, Yuyang Liu, Jianping Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Construction of a 3D Self-Supported Electrode Based on ZIF-67 and Amorphous NiCoP for an Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01863</link>
      <description>Mengya Cao, Yanrong Li, Yijia Cao, Yusong Wen, Li Bao, Qing Shen, Wen Gu, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741414

                The development of efficient and Earth-abundant electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an urgent requirement in the field of electrochemical water splitting. The electrocatalytic performance of the OER can be greatly enhanced by the synergistic combination of zeolite imidazolate frameworks (ZIFs) and transition-metal phosphides, both of which individually exhibit promising capabilities in this regard. In this study, a novel amorphous NiCoP deposited on ZIF-67 sheets supported on Ni foam (labeled as NiCoP/ZIF-67/NF) as an OER electrocatalytic material was successfully synthesized using a simple, secure, and time-efficient two-step strategy. The experimental results demonstrate that NiCoP/ZIF-67/NF possesses a large active surface area with abundant active sites. Also, the synergistic effect and interaction between NiCoP and ZIF-67, as well as between Ni and Co within NiCoP, effectively enhance its electrochemical performance under alkaline conditions. Consequently, NiCoP/ZIF-67/NF exhibits outstanding catalytic activity for OER with an overpotential (&#951;) of 175 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Mengya Cao, Yanrong Li, Yijia Cao, Yusong Wen, Li Bao, Qing Shen, Wen Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Role of Particle Size and Nanostructuring on the Oxygen Evolution Activity of Fe-Doped NiO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02329</link>
      <description>Reshma R. Rao, Alberto Bucci, Sacha Corby, Benjamin Moss, Caiwu Liang, Aswin Gopakumar, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Julio Lloret&#8208;Fillol, James R. Durrant, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400741431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Reshma R. Rao, Alberto Bucci, Sacha Corby, Benjamin Moss, Caiwu Liang, Aswin Gopakumar, Ifan E. L. Stephens, Julio Lloret&#8208;Fillol, James R. Durrant</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting the bifunctional oxygen catalytic activity of the perovskite and Co3O4 heterostructure by introducing oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.193</link>
      <description>Bingen Yuan, Jiaqun Zou, Jian Jia, Jiatang Wang, Heng Xu, Jia Li, Chunfei Zhang, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400762167

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bingen Yuan, Jiaqun Zou, Jian Jia, Jiatang Wang, Heng Xu, Jia Li, Chunfei Zhang, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ fabrication of low-crystallinity (Ni,Fe)xSy nanosheet arrays via room-temperature corrosion engineering toward efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124415</link>
      <description>Mingyue Chen, Wenhui Li, Y. Lu, Pengcheng Qi, Hao Wu, Kunyu Hao, Yiwen Tang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. 358(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400762733

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingyue Chen, Wenhui Li, Y. Lu, Pengcheng Qi, Hao Wu, Kunyu Hao, Yiwen Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Oxides as Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Mini Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02061</link>
      <description>Yueqi Huang, Dan Wang, Yihang Yu, Zenghui Li, Xiaojing Wen, Zhiyuan Wang, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400763937

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yueqi Huang, Dan Wang, Yihang Yu, Zenghui Li, Xiaojing Wen, Zhiyuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>p-Block Anion Compressed d/p Band Center of Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Durable Aqueous Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103654</link>
      <description>Kejian Ding, Yi Yang, Jiugang Hu, Liming Zhao, Huanan Yu, Zejie Zhu, Yunpeng Liu, Shan Cai, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Xiaobo Ji, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400767685

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kejian Ding, Yi Yang, Jiugang Hu, Liming Zhao, Huanan Yu, Zejie Zhu, Yunpeng Liu, Shan Cai, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Xiaobo Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the cationic vacancy structure of NiO to optimize its d band center and accelerate oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.194</link>
      <description>Wen-Zhuo Zhang, Xiang Li, Guangyi Chen, Junyuan Xu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400767816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wen-Zhuo Zhang, Xiang Li, Guangyi Chen, Junyuan Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese Doped Tailored Cobalt Sulfide as an Accelerated Catalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898894</link>
      <description>Junbai Li, Hafiz Muhammad Naeem Ullah, Nouraiz Mushtaq, Sajid ur Rehman, Zeeshan Tariq, Shafaqat Ali, Muhammad Tahir, Chuanbo Li, Xiaoming Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400769895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junbai Li, Hafiz Muhammad Naeem Ullah, Nouraiz Mushtaq, Sajid ur Rehman, Zeeshan Tariq, Shafaqat Ali, Muhammad Tahir, Chuanbo Li, Xiaoming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B&#8208;site Doping Boosts the OER and ORR Performance of Double Perovskite Oxide as Air Cathode for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400531</link>
      <description>Cagla Ozgur, Tuncay Erdil, Uygar Geyikci, &#304;lker Y&#305;ld&#305;z, Ersu LOKCU, &#199;i&#287;dem Toparl&#305;, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400769965

                Double perovskite oxides are key players as electrocatalytic oxygen catalysts in alkaline media. In this study, we synthesized B&#8208;site doped NdBaCoaFe2&#8208;aO5+&#948; (a= 1.0, 1.4, 1.6, 1.8) electrocatalysts, systematically to probe their bifunctionality and assess their performance in zinc&#8208;air batteries as air cathodes. X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy analysis reveals a correlation between iron reduction and increased oxygen vacancy content, influencing electrocatalyst bifunctionality by lowering the work function. The electrocatalyst with highest cobalt content, NdBaCo1.8Fe0.2O5+&#948; exhibited a bifunctional index of 0.95 V, outperforming other synthesized electrocatalysts. Remarkably, NdBaCo1.8Fe0.2O5+&#948;, demonstrated facilitated charge transfer rate in oxygen evolution reaction with four&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction process. As an air cathode in a zinc&#8208;air battery, NdBaCo1.8Fe0.2O5+&#948; demonstrated superior performance characteristics, including maximum capacity of 428.27 mA h at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 discharge current density, highest peak power density of 64 mW cm&#8208;2, with an outstanding durability and stability. It exhibits lowest voltage gap change between charge and discharge even after 350 hours of cyclic operation with a rate capability of 87.14%.</description>
      <author>Cagla Ozgur, Tuncay Erdil, Uygar Geyikci, &#304;lker Y&#305;ld&#305;z, Ersu LOKCU, &#199;i&#287;dem Toparl&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-bridging Fe, Co dual-metal dimers boost reversible oxygen electrocatalysis for rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2404013121</link>
      <description>Qixing Zhou, Wendan Xue, Xun Cui, Pengfei Wang, Sijin Zuo, Fan Mo, Chengzhi Li, G. Liu, Shaohu Ouyang, Sihui Zhan, Juan Chen, Chao Wang, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400772891

                Rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) are regarded as a remarkably promising alternative to current lithium-ion batteries, addressing the requirements for large-scale high-energy storage. Nevertheless, the sluggish kinetics involving oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) hamper the widespread application of ZABs, necessitating the development of high-efficiency and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts. Here, we report oxygen atom&#8211;bridged Fe, Co dual-metal dimers (FeOCo-SAD), in which the active site Fe&#8211;O&#8211;Co&#8211;N 6 moiety boosts exceptional reversible activity toward ORR and OER in alkaline electrolytes. Specifically, FeOCo-SAD achieves a half-wave potential ( E 1/2 ) of 0.87 V for ORR and an overpotential of 310 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8211;2 for OER, with a potential gap (&#916; E ) of only 0.67 V. Meanwhile, FeOCo-SAD manifests high performance with a peak power density of 241.24 mW cm &#8722;2 in realistic rechargeable ZABs. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that the introduction of an oxygen bridge in the Fe, Co dimer induced charge spatial redistribution around Fe and Co atoms. This enhances the activation of oxygen and optimizes the adsorption/desorption dynamics of reaction intermediates. Consequently, energy barriers are effectively reduced, leading to a strong promotion of intrinsic activity toward ORR and OER. This work suggests that oxygen-bridging dual-metal dimers offer promising prospects for significantly enhancing the performance of reversible oxygen electrocatalysis and for creating innovative catalysts that exhibit synergistic effects and electronic states.</description>
      <author>Qixing Zhou, Wendan Xue, Xun Cui, Pengfei Wang, Sijin Zuo, Fan Mo, Chengzhi Li, G. Liu, Shaohu Ouyang, Sihui Zhan, Juan Chen, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2404013121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural, Magnetic and Electrocatalytic Properties of Rock Salt Oxide Nanofibers (Ni0.2mg0.2zn0.2cu0.2-Xco0.2+X)O Produced by Air-Heated Solution Blow Spinning (A-Hsbs) for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898639</link>
      <description>Rubens Maciel Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Medeiros, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400776985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rubens Maciel Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Medeiros, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4898639</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the oxygen evolution activity of biomass-derived porous carbon plate as self-supported metal-free electrocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.07.007</link>
      <description>Xinghe Zhang, Yujie Wang, Jin Zou, Shichao Zhao, Hongbo Hou, Fengmei Zhang, Huaipeng Wang, Progress in Natural Science/Progress in natural science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400780005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinghe Zhang, Yujie Wang, Jin Zou, Shichao Zhao, Hongbo Hou, Fengmei Zhang, Huaipeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.07.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts: Efficient and Ultrastable Interstitial W&#8208;Doped NiFe&#8208;LDHs/MOFs through Controlled Topological Conversion of Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401909</link>
      <description>Y. W. Bao, Xiongyi Liang, Hao Zhang, Xiuming Bu, Ziyan Cai, Yikai Yang, Di Yin, Yuxuan Zhang, L Chen, Yang Cheng, Xiulan Hu, Xiao Cheng Zeng, Johnny C. Ho, Ding Wang, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400782710

                Abstract Although metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) show promise as electrocatalysts due to their unique intrinsic features, their activity and stability often fall short. Herein, NiFe&#8208;MOFs is used as a model to introduce group VIB metalates (Na 2 WO 4 , Na 2 CrO 4 , and Na 2 MoO 4 ) into the topological conversion process of layer double hydroxide (LDHs)/MOFs, creating a series of interstitial VIB element&#8208;doped LDHs/MOFs catalysts. The metalates engage in the alkaline hydrolysis process of MOF, generating LDHs on the MOF surface. Furthermore, altering the pH value in the reaction environment can modify the catalysts' morphology, dopant/LDHs content, and electronic structure. Consequently, the prepared interstitial W&#8208;doped NiFe&#8208;LDHs/MOFs catalyst displays superior catalytic performance, with overpotentials of only 250 mV at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . Moreover, a homemade anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) system featuring the fabricated electrocatalyst as the anode can operate stably for 500 hours at 1 A cm &#8722;2 . The exceptional catalytic activity and stability stem from optimized intermediate adsorption/desorption behavior and the unique LDHs/MOFs nanostructure. This work not only highlights the potential of the catalysts for practical applications but also offers a new design approach for modulating MOFs using an alkaline hydrolysis strategy.</description>
      <author>Y. W. Bao, Xiongyi Liang, Hao Zhang, Xiuming Bu, Ziyan Cai, Yikai Yang, Di Yin, Yuxuan Zhang, L Chen, Yang Cheng, Xiulan Hu, Xiao Cheng Zeng, Johnny C. Ho, Ding Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401909</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineering and Carbon Supporting to Achieve Ni-Doped CoP3 with High Catalytic Activities for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01471-9</link>
      <description>Daowei Zha, Ruoxing Wang, Shijun Tian, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Zejun Xu, Chu Qin, Xiaoning Tian, Lin Zhao, Nano-micro letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400784939

                Abstract This work reports the use of defect engineering and carbon supporting to achieve metal-doped phosphides with high activities and stabilities for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. Specifically, the nitrogen-doped carbon nanofiber-supported Ni-doped CoP 3 with rich P defects (Pv&#183;) on the carbon cloth (p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC) is synthesized through a plasma-assisted phosphorization method. The p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC is an efficient and stable catalyst for the HER and the OER. It only needs overpotentials of 107 and 306 mV to drive 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for the HER and the OER, respectively. Its catalytic activities are higher than those of other catalysts reported recently. The high activities of the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC mainly arise from its peculiar structural features. The density functional theory calculation indicates that the Pv&#183; richness, the Ni doping, and the carbon supporting can optimize the adsorption of the H atoms at the catalyst surface and promote the strong electronic couplings between the carbon nanofiber-supported p-NiCoP with the surface oxide layer formed during the OER process. This gives the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC with the high activities for the HER and the OER. When used in alkaline water electrolyzers, the p-NiCoP/NCFs@CC shows the superior activity and excellent stability for overall water splitting. Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Daowei Zha, Ruoxing Wang, Shijun Tian, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Zejun Xu, Chu Qin, Xiaoning Tian, Lin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01471-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic NiFe MOF with ultra-thin two-dimensional nanosheet structure effectively accelerates oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01656d</link>
      <description>Jiaqi He, Xin Deng, Wenting Sun, Wenjing Shang, Yongbing Lou, Jinxi Chen, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400787777

                To address the shortage of fossil energy, the development of affordable and efficient non-precious metal catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) from electrocatalytic water splitting is still a crucial challenge....</description>
      <author>Jiaqi He, Xin Deng, Wenting Sun, Wenjing Shang, Yongbing Lou, Jinxi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01656d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Complementary Multisite Turnover Catalysis toward Superefficient Bifunctional Seawater Splitting at Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405852</link>
      <description>Liling Liao, Dongyang Li, Yan Zhang, Yong Zhang, Fang Yu, Lun Yang, Xiuzhang Wang, Dongsheng Tang, Haiqing Zhou, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400789454

                Abstract The utilization of seawater for hydrogen production via water splitting is increasingly recognized as a promising avenue for the future. The key dilemma for seawater electrolysis is the incompatibility of superior hydrogen&#8208; and oxygen&#8208;evolving activities at ampere&#8208;scale current densities for both cathodic and anodic catalysts, thus leading to large electric power consumption of overall seawater splitting. Here, in situ construction of Fe 4 N/Co 3 N/MoO 2 heterostructure arrays anchoring on metallic nickel nitride surface with multilevel collaborative catalytic interfaces and abundant multifunctional metal sites is reported, which serves as a robust bifunctional catalyst for alkaline freshwater/seawater splitting at ampere&#8208;level current density. Operando Raman and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopic studies combined with density functional theory calculations corroborate that Mo and Co/Fe sites situated on the Fe 4 N/Co 3 N/MoO 2 multilevel interfaces optimize the reaction pathway and coordination environment to enhance water adsorption/dissociation, hydrogen adsorption, and oxygen&#8208;containing intermediate adsorption, thus cooperatively expediting hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions in base. Inspiringly, this electrocatalyst can substantially ameliorate overall freshwater/seawater splitting at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 with low cell voltages of 1.65/1.69 V, along with superb long&#8208;term stability at 500&#8211;1500 mA cm &#8722;2 for over 200 h, outperforming nearly all the ever&#8208;reported non&#8208;noble electrocatalysts for freshwater/seawater electrolysis. This work offers a viable approach to design high&#8208;performance bifunctional catalysts for seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>Liling Liao, Dongyang Li, Yan Zhang, Yong Zhang, Fang Yu, Lun Yang, Xiuzhang Wang, Dongsheng Tang, Haiqing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La-induced nanosheet intercalated spheroid hierarchical structure with abundant oxygen vacancy promotes electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00653d</link>
      <description>Di Wang, Jianguo Tang, Wenguang Cui, Chaozheng He, Zhongkui Zhao, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400798723

                The electron coupling effect at the interface, as well as the introduction of oxygen vacancy (Ov), play critical roles in the electrocatalytic activity. The key to lowering the energy barrier...</description>
      <author>Di Wang, Jianguo Tang, Wenguang Cui, Chaozheng He, Zhongkui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00653d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce- and La-doped polymetallic layered double hydroxides for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction performance at high current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-1952-9</link>
      <description>Mukesh Ratnaparkhi, Ping Wang, Miao He, Senyao Meng, Jiasai Yao, Huawei Li, Cuicui Yang, Zhenxing Li, Science China. Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400800404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukesh Ratnaparkhi, Ping Wang, Miao He, Senyao Meng, Jiasai Yao, Huawei Li, Cuicui Yang, Zhenxing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-1952-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering assisted La1-xSrxCoO3/FeOOH heterostructure as a high-performance electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.201</link>
      <description>Juan Yu, Shuai Zhao, Bing Li, Chunyu Zhu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400800503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juan Yu, Shuai Zhao, Bing Li, Chunyu Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and solvation of Key Intermediates of Oxygen Evolution on TiO2, RuO2, IrO2 (110) Surfaces: A Comparative DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400813</link>
      <description>Giovanni Di Liberto, Giovanni Di Liberto, Livia Giordano, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400802784

                Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) is a fundamental process, with gold standards like RuO2 and IrO2. Recently, it was suggested that OER could go through unconventional intermediates, &#8208;O&#8208;H, &#8208;OO&#8208;H. &#8208;O&#8208;H is formed by the direct interaction of an adsorbed O species to a metal surface atom and a proton bound to a surface oxygen. Similarly, in &#8208;OO&#8208;H, an adsorbed &#8208;OO adduct interacts with a proton bound to a surface oxygen. This work compares the nature of key intermediates of OER on TiO2, RuO2, and IrO2(110) surfaces by Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations and Ab&#8208;Initio Molecular Dynamics (AIMD). We rationalized the nature, the relative stability trends in vacuum, the effect of water solvation of the species. &#8208;OO&#8208;H is preferred than &#8208;OOH. &#8208;OH is preferred than &#8208;O&#8208;H except for RuO2. We investigated the nature of the catalyst/water interfaces and the interaction of intermediates with water based on AIMD. On RuO2, &#8208;OH and &#8208;O&#8208;H display a different interaction with water. &#8208;OO&#8208;H is quite rigid on RuO2, while it is dynamic on IrO2 as the proton is shared between &#8208;OO and a surface oxygen atom. This study provides insights on the role of solvation to the nature of OER intermediates, that may help future studies.</description>
      <author>Giovanni Di Liberto, Giovanni Di Liberto, Livia Giordano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large-current polarization-engineered FeOOH@NiOOH electrocatalyst with stable Fe sites for large-current oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60062-8</link>
      <description>Qingyun Lv, Weiwei Zhang, Zhipeng Long, Jiantao Wang, Xingli Zou, Wei Ren, Long Hou, Xionggang Lu, Yufeng Zhao, Yu Xing, Xi Li, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400807136

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingyun Lv, Weiwei Zhang, Zhipeng Long, Jiantao Wang, Xingli Zou, Wei Ren, Long Hou, Xionggang Lu, Yufeng Zhao, Yu Xing, Xi Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60062-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Immiscible Ruthenium&#8211;Cadmium Alloy for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01412</link>
      <description>Tiantian Yang, Min Wang, Fei-Fei Zhang, Cong Xi, Liyang Xiao, Xueru Zhao, Jiaqi Wang, Weibo Hua, Cunku Dong, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400807961

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tiantian Yang, Min Wang, Fei-Fei Zhang, Cong Xi, Liyang Xiao, Xueru Zhao, Jiaqi Wang, Weibo Hua, Cunku Dong, Hui Liu, Xi&#8208;Wen Du</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ fabrication of oxygen deficient Bi2MoO6/InVO4/CeVO4 dual S-scheme ternary heterostructure for robust photocatalytic H2 and H2O2 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104824</link>
      <description>Sibun Kumar Pradhan, Ranjit Bariki, Adarsh Kumar, Swagat Kumar Nayak, Saumyaranjan Panda, Nikhil Kumar Das, Braja Gopal Mishra, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400839387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sibun Kumar Pradhan, Ranjit Bariki, Adarsh Kumar, Swagat Kumar Nayak, Saumyaranjan Panda, Nikhil Kumar Das, Braja Gopal Mishra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase Engineering and Surface Reconstruction of FeNiMo Alloys as High Efficient Electrode for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.07.109</link>
      <description>Si-Cheng Zhong, Jia Li, Zhe Cui, GY Tian, F Zhao, Zhong-Hong Zhou, Hongfei Jiao, Danyang Liu, Jiefu Xiong, Li&#8208;Chen Wang, Jun Xiang, Fufa Wu, Rongda Zhao, Journal of materials research and technology/Journal of Materials Research and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400839752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Si-Cheng Zhong, Jia Li, Zhe Cui, GY Tian, F Zhao, Zhong-Hong Zhou, Hongfei Jiao, Danyang Liu, Jiefu Xiong, Li&#8208;Chen Wang, Jun Xiang, Fufa Wu, Rongda Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.07.109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrocatalytic performance of CoFe hydroxide catalyst by P-doping for oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105664</link>
      <description>Guanming Huang, Yufei Wang, Xiaofeng Ma, Yanpeng Cao, Baogang Wei, Jian He, Wenbo Chen, Feng Ye, Chao Xu, Xiaoze Du, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 163(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400842033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guanming Huang, Yufei Wang, Xiaofeng Ma, Yanpeng Cao, Baogang Wei, Jian He, Wenbo Chen, Feng Ye, Chao Xu, Xiaoze Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction over IrO2: Essential Role of Hydronium Cation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409526</link>
      <description>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jingguang G. Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400842354

                The development of active, stable, and more affordable electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is of great importance for the practical application of electrolyzers and the advancement of renewable energy conversion technologies. Currently, IrO2 is the only catalyst with high stability and activity, but a high cost. Further optimization of the catalyst is limited by the lack of understanding of catalytic behaviors at the acid-IrO2 interface. Here, in strong interaction with the experiment, we develop an explicit model based on grand-canonical density function theory (GC-DFT) calculations to describe acidic OER over IrO2. Compared to the explicit models reported previously, hydronium cations (H3O+) are introduced at the electrochemical interface in the current model. As a result, a variation in stable IrO2 surface configuration under the OER operating condition from previously proposed complete *O-coverage to a mixture coverage of *OH and *O is revealed, which is well supported by in situ Raman measurements. In addition, the accuracy of predicted overpotential is increased in comparison with the experimentally measured. More importantly, an alteration of the potential limiting step from previously identified *O &#8594; *OOH to *OH &#8594; *O is observed, which opens new opportunities to advance the IrO2-based catalysts for acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jingguang G. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Dual Gain Strategy of Introducing Nickel Doping and Anchoring Amorphous Iron Oxyhydroxide Nanosheets on Zif-67 Achieves an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4900554</link>
      <description>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Gao Y, Shigang Shen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400844039

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Gao Y, Shigang Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4900554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalyst Spinel Oxide Co2GeO4 and Ni2GeO4 with High Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11320-5</link>
      <description>Yanjie Wang, Yumin Guo, Jingjing Wu, H. Y. Liu, Xin Tang, Journal of electronic materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400851289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanjie Wang, Yumin Guo, Jingjing Wu, H. Y. Liu, Xin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11320-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction over IrO2: Essential Role of Hydronium Cation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409526</link>
      <description>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jingguang G. Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400852162

                The development of active, stable, and more affordable electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is of great importance for the practical application of electrolyzers and the advancement of renewable energy conversion technologies. Currently, IrO2 is the only catalyst with high stability and activity, but a high cost. Further optimization of the catalyst is limited by the lack of understanding of catalytic behaviors at the acid&#8208;IrO2 interface. Here, in strong interaction with the experiment, we develop an explicit model based on grand&#8208;canonical density function theory (GC&#8208;DFT) calculations to describe acidic OER over IrO2. Compared to the explicit models reported previously, hydronium cations (H3O+) are introduced at the electrochemical interface in the current model. As a result, a variation in stable IrO2 surface configuration under the OER operating condition from previously proposed complete *O&#8208;coverage to a mixture coverage of *OH and *O is revealed, which is well supported by in situ Raman measurements. In addition, the accuracy of predicted overpotential is increased in comparison with the experimentally measured. More importantly, an alteration of the potential limiting step from previously identified *O &#8594; *OOH to *OH &#8594; *O is observed, which opens new opportunities to advance the IrO2&#8208;based catalysts for acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Seong&#8208;Min Bak, Jingguang G. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed Ru doped on IrOx sub-nano clusters for the enhanced oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01998a</link>
      <description>Yan Dong, Yanle Li, Yichao Lin, Anyang Chen, Mengting Deng, Linjuan Zhang, Zhiyi Lu, Ziqi Tian, Liang Chen, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400854602

                High-performance anodic electrocatalysts are urgently required for proton exchange membrane (PEM)-based water electrolysis. Here, a simple one-step approach is introduced to produce atomically dispersed Ru on iridium oxide (Ru-IrOx) sub-nano...</description>
      <author>Yan Dong, Yanle Li, Yichao Lin, Anyang Chen, Mengting Deng, Linjuan Zhang, Zhiyi Lu, Ziqi Tian, Liang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01998a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photosynthetic performance of the red algae &lt;i&gt;Gracilariopsis lemaneiformis&lt;/i&gt; under high seawater &lt;scp&gt;pH&lt;/scp&gt;: Excess reactive oxygen production due to carbon limitation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/php.13968</link>
      <description>Hongjun Xu, Tong Pang, Litao Zhang, Jianguo Liu, Photochemistry and photobiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400856154

                Abstract The red algae Gracilariopsis lemaneiformis is extensively cultivated at high densities, leading to significant increases in regional seawater pH due to its photosynthetic removal of inorganic carbon. We conducted a study on G. lemaneiformis cultured under various pH conditions (normal pH, pH 9.3, and pH 9.6) and light levels (dark and 100 &#956;mol photons m &#8722;2 s &#8722;1 ) to investigate how high pH seawater environments affect the metabolic processes of G. lemaneiformis . The high pH did not directly damage the photosynthetic light reactions or the Calvin cycle. Instead, the observed reduction in photosynthetic rates was primarily due to CO 2 limitation. However, under illuminated conditions, a high pH environment leads to a decrease in electron transport efficiency (ETo/RC) and reaction center density (RC/CSo), while simultaneously increasing the levels of hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ), malondialdehyde (MDA), and the activity of antioxidant enzymes. Under illuminated conditions, the limitation of inhibit the photosynthetic electron transport process, leading to energy imbalance and excessive production of reactive oxygen species, which in turn resulted in lipid peroxidation of the cell membrane. This might be one of the inducing factors responsible for the bleaching in sea&#8208;farmed G. lemaneiformis plants.</description>
      <author>Hongjun Xu, Tong Pang, Litao Zhang, Jianguo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/php.13968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &amp;lt;&#8217;Facile synthesis of CuZrO3@PPY nanohybrid balls embedded 3-dimensional network with synergistic effect for efficient oxygen evolution reaction&#8217;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;[Surfaces and Interfaces Volume 36, February 2023, 102607]&amp;gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104827</link>
      <description>Salma Aman, Soumaya Gouadria, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Abdullah, Rabia Yasmin Khosa, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Mohd Zahid Ansari, Akram Alfantazi, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400858551

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Salma Aman, Soumaya Gouadria, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Abdullah, Rabia Yasmin Khosa, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Mohd Zahid Ansari, Akram Alfantazi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood derived carbon embedded with shell-core CoP@CoFe for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118514</link>
      <description>Kai Li, Ya-Ping Sun, Xiaoguang Zhang, Linzheng Ma, Jinxue Guo, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400858930

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Li, Ya-Ping Sun, Xiaoguang Zhang, Linzheng Ma, Jinxue Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118514</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles Anchored in Cation-Vacancies NiFe-LDH toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reactions in Green Sustainable Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c02912</link>
      <description>Zhaokun Wang, Li Wang, Liang Chu, Mu Yang, Ge Wang, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400863995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaokun Wang, Li Wang, Liang Chu, Mu Yang, Ge Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c02912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Engineered P-doped MoO3/Ce2Mo4O15 Bimetallic Heterojunction Nanosheet Array for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144747</link>
      <description>Peng Chen, Hengfu Shui, Sheng Wang, Feng&#8208;Cui Shen, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400865829

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Chen, Hengfu Shui, Sheng Wang, Feng&#8208;Cui Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Oxygen Vacancies to tune Cobalt Oxide by Mn doped for High-effective Overall Water-Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109887</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, Fenghua Wei, Yukui Zhang, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400867149

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, Fenghua Wei, Yukui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extremely Active and Robust Ir&#8208;Mn Dual&#8208;Atom Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Oxygen&#8208;Oxygen Radical Coupling Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411014</link>
      <description>Wenbo Liu, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400869068

                A novel Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom electrocatalyst is synthesized by a facile ion&#8208;exchange method by incorporating Ir in SrMnO3, which yields an extremely high activity and stability for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The ion exchange process occurs in a self&#8208;limitation way, which favors the formation of Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom in the IrMnO9 unit. The incorporation of Ir modulates the electronic structure of both Ir and Mn, thereby resulting in a shorter distance of the Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom (2.41 &#197;) than the Mn&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom (2.49 &#197;). The modulated Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom enables the same spin direction O (&#8593;) of the adsorbed *O intermediates, thus facilitating the direct coupling of the two adsorbed *O intermediates to release O2 via the oxygen&#8208;oxygen radical coupling mechanism. Electrochemical tests reveal that the Ir&#8208;SrMnO3 exhibits a superior OER's activity with a low overpotential of 207 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and achieves a mass specific activity of 1100 A gIr&#8208;1 at 1.5 V. The proton&#8208;exchange&#8208;membrane water electrolyzer with the Ir&#8208;SrMnO3 catalyst exhibits a low electrolysis voltage of 1.63 V at 1.0 A cm&#8208;2 and a stable 2000&#8208;h operation with a decay of only 15 &#956;V h&#8208;1 at 0.5 A cm&#8208;2.</description>
      <author>Wenbo Liu, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances of the catalysts for photoelectrocatalytic oxygen evolution and CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60053-7</link>
      <description>Hongrui Zhu, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Zhijie Zhang, Qi&#8208;Ni Zhan, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Gao&#8208;Ren Li, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 62(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806504

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongrui Zhu, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Zhijie Zhang, Qi&#8208;Ni Zhan, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Gao&#8208;Ren Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60053-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extremely Active and Robust Ir&#8208;Mn Dual&#8208;Atom Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Oxygen&#8208;Oxygen Radical Coupling Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411014</link>
      <description>Wenbo Liu, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400869196

                A novel Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom electrocatalyst is synthesized by a facile ion&#8208;exchange method by incorporating Ir in SrMnO3, which yields an extremely high activity and stability for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The ion exchange process occurs in a self&#8208;limitation way, which favors the formation of Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom in the IrMnO9 unit. The incorporation of Ir modulates the electronic structure of both Ir and Mn, thereby resulting in a shorter distance of the Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom (2.41 &#197;) than the Mn&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom (2.49 &#197;). The modulated Ir&#8208;Mn dual&#8208;atom enables the same spin direction O (&#8593;) of the adsorbed *O intermediates, thus facilitating the direct coupling of the two adsorbed *O intermediates to release O2 via the oxygen&#8208;oxygen radical coupling mechanism. Electrochemical tests reveal that the Ir&#8208;SrMnO3 exhibits a superior OER's activity with a low overpotential of 207 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and achieves a mass specific activity of 1100 A gIr&#8208;1 at 1.5 V. The proton&#8208;exchange&#8208;membrane water electrolyzer with the Ir&#8208;SrMnO3 catalyst exhibits a low electrolysis voltage of 1.63 V at 1.0 A cm&#8208;2 and a stable 2000&#8208;h operation with a decay of only 15 &#956;V h&#8208;1 at 0.5 A cm&#8208;2.</description>
      <author>Wenbo Liu, Guifa Long, Zhipeng Xiang, Jinhua Piao, Kai Wan, Zhiyong Fu, Zhenxing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition Heterogeneity of Metal Ions Bound at the Oxygen-Evolving Center of Photosystem II in Living Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.biochem.4c00261</link>
      <description>Jimin Wang, Biochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400870406

                Recent resolution advancement of</description>
      <author>Jimin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.biochem.4c00261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous carbon modulated-Quantum Dots NiO for Efficient Oxygen Evolution in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124437</link>
      <description>Benjin Jin, Qian Wang, Jani Sainio, Viktoriia A. Saveleva, Hua Jiang, Junjie Shi, Basit Ali, Antti&#8208;Jussi Kallio, Simo Huotari, Dage Sundholm, Nana Han, Tanja Kallio, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400871939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benjin Jin, Qian Wang, Jani Sainio, Viktoriia A. Saveleva, Hua Jiang, Junjie Shi, Basit Ali, Antti&#8208;Jussi Kallio, Simo Huotari, Dage Sundholm, Nana Han, Tanja Kallio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Doped into Layered Double Hydroxide as Efficient Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901876</link>
      <description>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400872888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Fluffy Sphere-Like Nicocu-Carbonate Hydroxide Based Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Ph Neutral Electrolyte Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902010</link>
      <description>Li Yu, Xiaocai Ma, Qin Liang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400872985

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Yu, Xiaocai Ma, Qin Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruo2/Feco2o4 as an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901885</link>
      <description>Jiale Li, Weigang Gu, Dajun Wu, Xuekun Hong, Tao Shi, Bin Qian, Shaohui Xu, Paul K. Chu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400873086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiale Li, Weigang Gu, Dajun Wu, Xuekun Hong, Tao Shi, Bin Qian, Shaohui Xu, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4901885</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Realistic Models of the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00171</link>
      <description>Travis E. Jones, Detre Teschner, Simone Piccinin, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400875520

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Travis E. Jones, Detre Teschner, Simone Piccinin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir-Doped Core&#8211;Shell Hollow Heterogeneous Nanospindles for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02285</link>
      <description>Wanyu Liang, Yanghanqi Li, Nannan Zhang, Jie Li, Shujin Li, Zhengying Wu, Yukou Du, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400876349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wanyu Liang, Yanghanqi Li, Nannan Zhang, Jie Li, Shujin Li, Zhengying Wu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure deformation of Ni&#8211;Fe&#8211;Se enables efficient oxygen evolution via RE atoms doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02900-9</link>
      <description>Hong-Rui Zhao, Cheng&#8208;Zong Yuan, Cong&#8208;Hui Li, Wenkai Zhao, Fuling Wu, Xin Lei, Hong Yin, Shufeng Ye, Xiaomeng Zhang, Yunfa Chen, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400878897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong-Rui Zhao, Cheng&#8208;Zong Yuan, Cong&#8208;Hui Li, Wenkai Zhao, Fuling Wu, Xin Lei, Hong Yin, Shufeng Ye, Xiaomeng Zhang, Yunfa Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02900-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic modulation and dual-defect construction of NiMoP/Ni2P heterointerfaces for sustainable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02784-9</link>
      <description>Qingqing Zhang, Yuehang Xu, Derong Duan, Hongbo Su, Tao Wang, Xiaojun Zeng, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400879075

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingqing Zhang, Yuehang Xu, Derong Duan, Hongbo Su, Tao Wang, Xiaojun Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02784-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring transition metal hydroxides performance in membrane-free electrolyzer based decoupled water splitting for step-wise production of hydrogen and oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154215</link>
      <description>Subramanian Rajalekshmi, Sakkarapalayam Murugesan Senthil Kumar, Alagarsamy Pandikumar, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subramanian Rajalekshmi, Sakkarapalayam Murugesan Senthil Kumar, Alagarsamy Pandikumar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten, copper and cobalt-single metal atom oxides embedded CeO2-MnO2-rGO nanorods as electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105653</link>
      <description>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Tae Hwan Oh, Yueshuai Wang, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, S. Sadhasivam, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, Madhavan Swaminathan, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 163(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Tae Hwan Oh, Yueshuai Wang, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, S. Sadhasivam, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, Madhavan Swaminathan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105653</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrochemical performance of NbSe2/rGO nanocomposite for oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06431-8</link>
      <description>Arooj Fatima, B. M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, A.M.A. Henaish, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885314

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arooj Fatima, B. M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, A.M.A. Henaish</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06431-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bicarbonate is a key regulator but not a substrate for O2 evolution in Photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01111-8</link>
      <description>David J. Vinyard, Govindjee Govindjee, Photosynthesis Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400885384

                Abstract Photosystem II (PSII) uses light energy to oxidize water and to reduce plastoquinone in the photosynthetic electron transport chain. O 2 is produced as a byproduct. While most members of the PSII research community agree that O 2 originates from water molecules, alternative hypotheses involving bicarbonate persist in the literature. In this perspective, we provide an overview of the important roles of bicarbonate in regulating PSII activity and assembly. Further, we emphasize that biochemistry, spectroscopy, and structural biology experiments have all failed to detect bicarbonate near the active site of O 2 evolution. While thermodynamic arguments for oxygen-centered bicarbonate oxidation are valid, the claim that bicarbonate is a substrate for photosynthetic O 2 evolution is challenged.</description>
      <author>David J. Vinyard, Govindjee Govindjee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01111-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Temperature Plasma-Constructed Ni-Doped W&lt;sub&gt;18&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;49&lt;/sub&gt; Nanorod Arrays for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution and Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05120</link>
      <description>Qingdong Ruan, Jin&#8208;Yuan Liu, Dan Li, Xiaolin Zhang, Liangliang Liu, Chao Huang, Bin Wang, Paul K. Chu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400886716

                Surface engineering by doping and amorphization is receiving widespread attention from the perspective of the regulation of the electrocatalytic activities of electrocatalysts. However, the effective modulation of active sites on catalysts is still challenging. Herein, a straightforward and efficient method combining hydrothermal treatment with low-temperature plasma processing is presented to synthesize Ni-doped W</description>
      <author>Qingdong Ruan, Jin&#8208;Yuan Liu, Dan Li, Xiaolin Zhang, Liangliang Liu, Chao Huang, Bin Wang, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Superior Bifunctional Electrocatalyst in Which Directional Electron Transfer Occurs Between a Co/Ni Alloy and Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401730</link>
      <description>Ziyi Xu, Shihao Wang, Wenmao Tu, Ling Shen, Wu Lu, Shilong Xu, Yong Qiu, Hongfei Pan, Xiaoyu Yang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400891163

                Abstract Stable, efficient, and economical bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are needed for rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries. In this study, a directional electron transfer pathway is exploited in a spatial heterojunction of Co y Ni x @Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C heterogeneous catalyst for effective bifunctional electrolysis (OER/ORR). Thereinto, the Co/Ni alloy is strongly coupled to the Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C support through Co/Ni&#9472;N bonds. DFT calculations and experimental findings confirm that Co/Ni&#9472;N bonds play a bridging role in the directional electron transfer from Co/Ni alloy to the Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C support, increasing the content of pyridinic nitrogen in the ORR&#8208;active support. In addition, the discovered directional electron transfer mechanism enhances both the ORR/OER activity and the durability of the catalyst. The Co 0.66 Ni 0.34 @Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C with the optimal Ni/Co ratio exhibits satisfying bifunctional electrocatalytic performance, requiring an ORR half&#8208;wave potential of 0.90 V and an OER overpotential of 317 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline electrolytes. The assembled rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) incorporating Co 0.66 Ni 0.34 @Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C cathode exhibits a charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap comparable to the Pt/C||IrO 2 assembly and high robustness for over 60 h at 20 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Ziyi Xu, Shihao Wang, Wenmao Tu, Ling Shen, Wu Lu, Shilong Xu, Yong Qiu, Hongfei Pan, Xiaoyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Evolution Reaction Promoted by Iron and Brass Under Alkaline Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01262</link>
      <description>Meysam Maazallahi, Subhajit Nandy, P. Aleshkevych, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400891252

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meysam Maazallahi, Subhajit Nandy, P. Aleshkevych, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating &lt;sup&gt;*&lt;/sup&gt;OOH Adsorption on RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Efficient and Durable Acidic Water Oxidation Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404092</link>
      <description>Tingting Yin, Mengying Yang, Meng Tian, Wei Wang, Guigao Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400891281

                Abstract Acidic water electrolysis is of considerable interest due to its higher current density operation and energy conversion efficiency, but its real industrial application is highly limited by the shortage of efficient, stable, and cost&#8208;effective acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. Here, an electrocatalyst consisting of Ni&#8208;implanted RuO 2 supported is reported on &#945;&#8208;MnO 2 (MnO 2 /RuO 2 &#8208;Ni) that shows high activity and remarkable durability in acidic OER. Precisely, the MnO 2 /RuO 2 &#8208;Ni catalyst shows an overpotential of 198 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and can operate continuously and stably for 400 h (j = 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) without any obvious attenuation of activity, making it one of the best&#8208;performing acid&#8208;stable OER catalysts. Experimental results, in conjunction with density functional theory calculations, demonstrate that the interface electron transfer effect from RuO 2 to MnO 2 , further enhanced by Ni incorporation, effectively modulates the adsorption of OOH * and significantly reduces the overpotential, thereby enhancing catalytic activity and durability.</description>
      <author>Tingting Yin, Mengying Yang, Meng Tian, Wei Wang, Guigao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonized Wood Plate Decorated with a N-Doped Carbon Nanomushroom Encapsulating FeNiS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/(Co, Ni, Fe)&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; Heteroparticle for Efficiently Catalyzing Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01295</link>
      <description>Yuntang Zhuang, Sheng Wang, Guihua Yang, Zhengjun Shi, Shouxin Zhang, Ming He, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400891365

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuntang Zhuang, Sheng Wang, Guihua Yang, Zhengjun Shi, Shouxin Zhang, Ming He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Reconstruction of a Cobalt- and Ferrocene-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework during the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03262</link>
      <description>Thomas Doughty, Andrea Zingl, Maximilian W&#252;nschek, Christian M. Pichler, Matthew B. Watkins, Souvik Roy, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400899320

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thomas Doughty, Andrea Zingl, Maximilian W&#252;nschek, Christian M. Pichler, Matthew B. Watkins, Souvik Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting oxygen evolution with amine-induced reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132545</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhou, Wei Zi, Ziliang Kang, Hina Naz, Yashu Liu, Zhenyuan Ji, Guoxing Zhu, Fuel. 374(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400849006

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhou, Wei Zi, Ziliang Kang, Hina Naz, Yashu Liu, Zhenyuan Ji, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/crystalline AgS@CoS core@shell catalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110275</link>
      <description>Yangping Zhang, Tianpeng Liu, Jun Yu, Zhengying Wu, Dongqiong Wang, Yukou Du, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400843962

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yangping Zhang, Tianpeng Liu, Jun Yu, Zhengying Wu, Dongqiong Wang, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quenching controlled spin exchange interactions and spin selective electron transfer for oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154216</link>
      <description>Zhihan Gao, Jinhua Liu, Shuaijie Wang, Wen-Cai Lu, Wenyue Wang, Lingyun Li, Hui Guo, Jie Zheng, Seeram Ramakrishna, Shouxin Zhang, Jing Wang, Yun&#8208;Ze Long, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhihan Gao, Jinhua Liu, Shuaijie Wang, Wen-Cai Lu, Wenyue Wang, Lingyun Li, Hui Guo, Jie Zheng, Seeram Ramakrishna, Shouxin Zhang, Jing Wang, Yun&#8208;Ze Long</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the oxygen evolution reaction activity of lanthanide-doped NiFe-LDHs through lanthanide contraction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154059</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Kai-Sheng Chen, ZihaoYan, Yongjun Chen, Hongtao Liu, Pengfei Yin, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400673171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Kai-Sheng Chen, ZihaoYan, Yongjun Chen, Hongtao Liu, Pengfei Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Step-by-step enhancing oxygen evolution ability of CoFe2O4 by hybrid structure engineering and fluorine doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154211</link>
      <description>Yi&#8208;Gang Ji, Jiawei Wu, Huan Wen, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881404

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi&#8208;Gang Ji, Jiawei Wu, Huan Wen, Shuli Wang, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Mof-Based Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Microenvironment Regulated by Organic Ligands, Metals and Carbonization Synergistically</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4896757</link>
      <description>Chenchen Ding, Wenge Zhong, Yuqi Cao, Tingting Ma, Huimin Ye, Zheng Fang, Yirong Feng, Shuangfei Zhao, Jiming Yang, Yuguang Li, L. Shen, Wei He, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400672123

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenchen Ding, Wenge Zhong, Yuqi Cao, Tingting Ma, Huimin Ye, Zheng Fang, Yirong Feng, Shuangfei Zhao, Jiming Yang, Yuguang Li, L. Shen, Wei He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4896757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zipper&#8208;Like Interlocked Heterostructure of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide&#8208;WN for Super&#8208;Stable Oxygen Evolution over 4500 h</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409559</link>
      <description>Minghui Xing, Zelong Qiao, Shaoke Zhu, Gaohong Xu, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881423

                Abstract The nickel&#8208;iron based materials are widely studied as excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. However, its relatively poor OER stability limits its practical applications. Herein, a zipper&#8208;like interlocked heterostructure of NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH)&#8208;WN is constructed. The NiFe LDH&#8208;WN exhibits not only ultrahigh OER activity of 228 mV overpotential at a current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 , but also extremely long&#8208;term stability over 4500 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 and over 550 h at an industrial current density &#8776;350 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is ascribed to its special zipper&#8208;like interlocked structure. Moreover, in situ Raman confirms that the presence of WN can efficiently achieve NiFe LDH reconstruction to slower the metal dissolution during OER, and therefore boosts its stability. DFT calculations reveal that WN not only can increase the *O adsorption capability and conductivity of NiFe LDH layer, but also can anchor the metal atoms of NiFe LDH layer to improve the dissolution energy barrier. In short, this work presents a new method of constructing the interlocked heterostructure to improve the OER stability of Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;based catalysts, which would accelerate its practical application.</description>
      <author>Minghui Xing, Zelong Qiao, Shaoke Zhu, Gaohong Xu, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of 3d-Network Structure Based on Sepiolite Loaded Mn2coo4 Aerogel Powder and its Oxygen Evolution Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902235</link>
      <description>Rui Xu, Tianlei Wang, Xiudang Jing, Y Chen, Lei Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400898278

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rui Xu, Tianlei Wang, Xiudang Jing, Y Chen, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Heteroatom Doping in Enhancing the Catalytic Activities and Stability of Atomically Dispersed Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02747</link>
      <description>Xueqi Cheng, Dengfeng Wu, Hui Xu, Wei Zhang, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400692872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xueqi Cheng, Dengfeng Wu, Hui Xu, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Fe&#8211;Zr, Co&#8211;Zr, and Ni&#8211;Zr Catalysts to Boost CNTs Synthesis from Plastic Wastes and the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01357</link>
      <description>Xinyao Sun, Xu Hou, Dong Ao, Changchang Tian, Li Yin, Jing Huang, Tingting Cui, Enxian Yuan, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400725437

                The efficient conversion of plastic wastes to high-value carbon materials like carbon nanotubes (CNTs) is one important issue about the rational recycling, reduction, and reuse of solid wastes. Herein, Fe-, Co-, and Ni-Zr catalysts were prepared and used for CNTs synthesis from polyethylene (PE) waste via a two-stage reaction system. At the same time, the effects of the PE/catalyst ratio and reaction temperature on CNTs synthesis have been studied. Compared with Co-Zr and Ni-Zr, Fe-Zr exhibited the best activity in CNTs synthesis from PE, and it achieved the highest CNTs yield of 806.3 mg/g (per gram of Fe-Zr) at 800 &#176;C with a PE/catalyst ratio of 4. Furthermore, the obtained Fe-Zr/CNTs composite exhibited a low overpotential of 267 mV for the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at 20 mA/cm</description>
      <author>Xinyao Sun, Xu Hou, Dong Ao, Changchang Tian, Li Yin, Jing Huang, Tingting Cui, Enxian Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonized wood fiber-supported S, N-codoped carbon layer-coated multinary metal sulfide nanoarchitecture for efficient oxygen evolution reaction at ampere-level current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.178</link>
      <description>Ying Wu, Hongwei Liao, Sha Chen, Jianjie Cao, Wanjuan Zeng, Yuanyuan Liao, Yan Qing, Han Xu, Yiqiang Wu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400871849

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Wu, Hongwei Liao, Sha Chen, Jianjie Cao, Wanjuan Zeng, Yuanyuan Liao, Yan Qing, Han Xu, Yiqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural evolution and electronic properties of anionic plutonium-doped oxygen clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141484</link>
      <description>Zaifu Jiang, Peixin Fu, Siyu Jin, Panlong Kong, Panlong Kong, Wei Dai, Haiyan Lu, Cheng L&#252;, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400859860

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zaifu Jiang, Peixin Fu, Siyu Jin, Panlong Kong, Panlong Kong, Wei Dai, Haiyan Lu, Cheng L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-organic frameworks-engineered reactive-oxygen catalytic materials: Enzyme-mimicking coordinations, structure evolutions, and biotherapeutic applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.06.017</link>
      <description>Fuzhen Li, Qinlong Wen, Li Wang, Sutong Xiao, Yang Gao, Mao Wang, Xiaohui Xu, Lang Ma, Qian Li, Materials today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400857927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuzhen Li, Qinlong Wen, Li Wang, Sutong Xiao, Yang Gao, Mao Wang, Xiaohui Xu, Lang Ma, Qian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.06.017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT and machine learning studies on a multi-functional single-atom catalyst for enhanced oxygen and hydrogen evolution as well as CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.244</link>
      <description>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi, International journal of hydrogen energy. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400806168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanochemically synthesized RuO2&#8208;doped LaMnO3 perovskites as bifunctional cathodes for rechargeable Zn/air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400341</link>
      <description>Antonio J. Fern&#225;ndez Romero, Katherine Jejen, Florencio Santos Cutillas, J. J. L&#243;pez Cascales, Fran&#231;ois Huet, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400676634

                Herein, we have developed LaMnO3 (LMO) perovskite&#8208;based electrocatalysts of oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions (ORR and OER) in a basic aqueous solution. Mechanochemical grinding and thermal annealing leads to highly&#8208;pure perovskites as shown by X&#8208;ray diffraction. This methodology allows as well for a swift integration of RuO2 additive which improves especially the oxygen evolution reaction. ORR have been analyzed by rotating ring&#8208;disk electrode (RRDE). Eventually, these catalysts are employed in Zn/air batteries resulting in specific capacity values of 12.76 Ahg&#8208;1 at 1 Ag&#8208;1, when LMO&#8208;RuO2 (LMO&#8208;Ru) was used as catalyst in the positive electrodes. Besides, high operational stability of Zn/air batteries for over 100 cycles was obtained, saving 1,46 mWh per cycle when LMO&#8208;Ru was used with respect to pure LMO.</description>
      <author>Antonio J. Fern&#225;ndez Romero, Katherine Jejen, Florencio Santos Cutillas, J. J. L&#243;pez Cascales, Fran&#231;ois Huet</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Cobalt Inverse Spinel Oxides via Fe Substitution for Enhanced Water Splitting Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00468j</link>
      <description>Saraswati Roy, Sounak Roy, Sustainable energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400697118

                Owing to the expeditious kinetics and remarkable catalytic prowess, spinel oxides have garnered significant attention as promising non-precious metal electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Modulating the oxidation state of...</description>
      <author>Saraswati Roy, Sounak Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00468j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zn Leaching Reconstructs High-Entropy Hydroxyl Oxides for Efficient OER at Large Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03296a</link>
      <description>Xiaolong Liang, Kang Xu, Wenqian Gao, Yukui Zhang, Tingting Lv, H. Zhang, Jun Lv, Lie Zou, Jinxuan Liu, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400672638

                The study of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is crucial for the development of hydrogen energy technology. However, industrial water splitting requires high current densities, and monometallic catalysts have poor...</description>
      <author>Xiaolong Liang, Kang Xu, Wenqian Gao, Yukui Zhang, Tingting Lv, H. Zhang, Jun Lv, Lie Zou, Jinxuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03296a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene-supported MN4 single-atom catalysts for multifunctional electrocatalysis enabled by axial Fe tetramer coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.132</link>
      <description>Lulu Gao, Donghai Wu, Silu Li, Haobo Li, Dongwei Ma, Journal of colloid and interface science. 676(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400672156

                Multifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are crucial for development of the key electrochemical energy storage and conversion devices, for which single-atom catalyst (SAC) has present great promises. Very recently, some experimental works showed that structurally well-defined ultra-small transition-metal clusters (such as Fe and Co tetramers, denoted as Fe</description>
      <author>Lulu Gao, Donghai Wu, Silu Li, Haobo Li, Dongwei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical in situ deciphering of the surface reconstruction&#8211;assistant multielectron transfer event of single Co &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; O &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2407146121</link>
      <description>Bo Jiang, Haoran Li, Wei Wang, Hui Wang, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400729762

                Surface reconstruction determines the fate of catalytic sites on the near-surface during the oxygen evolution reaction. However, deciphering the conversion mechanism of various intermediate-states during surface reconstruction remains a challenge. Herein, we employed an optical imaging technique to draw the landscape of dynamic surface reconstruction on individual Co</description>
      <author>Bo Jiang, Haoran Li, Wei Wang, Hui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2407146121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4f&#8211;2p&#8211;3d Orbital Coupling in Ce&#8211;Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Enhancing the Urea Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02111</link>
      <description>Wei Zheng, Niangao Duan, Yang Yang, Peichen Wang, Yafei Qu, Cichang Zong, Qianwang Chen, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400882057

                The electrocatalytic urea oxidation reaction (UOR) provides a promising alternative to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for various renewable energy-related systems owing to its lower thermodynamic barriers. However, its optimization and commercial utilization were hampered due to a lack of mechanistic understanding. Here, we demonstrate a Ce-doped Ni</description>
      <author>Wei Zheng, Niangao Duan, Yang Yang, Peichen Wang, Yafei Qu, Cichang Zong, Qianwang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic-Structure Transformation of Platinum-Rich Nanowires as Efficient Electrocatalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03946</link>
      <description>Bolin Zhao, Chuhao Liu, Azhar Mahmood, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Pengchong Wang, Ying He, Dongyang Qu, Li Niu, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400688649

                Platinum (Pt) has been widely used as cathodic electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) but unfortunately neglected as an anodic electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to excessively strong bonding with oxygen species in water splitting electrolyzers. Herein we report that fine control over the electronic-structure and local-coordination environment of Pt-rich PtPbCu nanowires (NWs) by doping of iridium (Ir) lowers the overpotential of the OER and simultaneously suppresses the overoxidation of Pt in IrPtPbCu NWs during water electrolysis. In light of the one-dimensional morphology featured with atomically dispersed IrO</description>
      <author>Bolin Zhao, Chuhao Liu, Azhar Mahmood, Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Pengchong Wang, Ying He, Dongyang Qu, Li Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Component leaching of water oxidation electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/inf2.12609</link>
      <description>Gao Chen, Yanping Zhu, Sixuan She, Zezhou Lin, Hainan Sun, Haitao Huang, InfoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400746813

                Abstract Most electrocatalysts are known to experience structural change during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process. Considerable endeavors have been dedicated thus far to comprehending the catalytic process and uncovering the underlying mechanism. During the dynamic evolution of catalyst structure, component leaching of electrocatalysts is the most common phenomenon. This article offers a concise overview of recent findings and developments related to the leaching phenomena in the OER process in terms of fundamental understanding of leaching, advanced characterization techniques used to investigate leaching, leaching of inactive components, and leaching of active components. Leaching behaviors and the induced effects in various kinds of OER catalysts are discussed, progress in manipulating leaching amount/degree toward a tunable surface evolution is spotlighted, and finally, three representative types of structure transformations induced by leaching metastable species in OER condition are proposed. By understanding the process of component leaching in the OER, it will provide more guidance for the rational design of superior electrocatalysts. image</description>
      <author>Gao Chen, Yanping Zhu, Sixuan She, Zezhou Lin, Hainan Sun, Haitao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/inf2.12609</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intercalation-Induced Irreversible Lattice Distortion in Layered Double Hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04832</link>
      <description>Deok Ki Cho, Hyun Woo Lim, Andi Haryanto, Bingyi Yan, Chan Woo Lee, Jin Young Kim, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400882007

                Inducing strain in the lattice effectively enhances the intrinsic activity of electrocatalysts by shifting the metal's d-band center and tuning the binding energy of reaction intermediates. NiFe-layered double hydroxides (NiFe LDHs) are promising electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their cost-effectiveness and high catalytic activity. The distorted &#946;-NiOOH phase produced by the Jahn-Teller effect under the oxidation polarization is known to exhibit superior catalytic activity, but it eventually transforms to the undistorted &#947;-NiOOH phase during the OER process. Such a reversible lattice distortion limits the OER activity. In this study, we propose a facile boron tungstate (BWO) anion intercalation method to induce irreversible lattice distortion in NiFe LDHs, leading to significantly enhanced OER activity. Strong interactions with BWO anions induce significant stress on the LDH's metal-hydroxide slab, leading to an expansion of metal-oxygen bonds and subsequent lattice distortion.</description>
      <author>Deok Ki Cho, Hyun Woo Lim, Andi Haryanto, Bingyi Yan, Chan Woo Lee, Jin Young Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NANOCARBONS&#8208;BASED TRIFUNCTIONAL ELECTROCATALYSTS FOR OVERALL WATER SPLITTING AND METAL&#8208;AIR BATTERIES: &#8208; METAL&#8208;FREE AND HYBRID ELECTROCATALYSTS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400712</link>
      <description>Viswanathan S. Saji, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400880734

                Trifunctional electrocatalysts, an exciting class of materials that can simultaneously catalyze hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), can significantly enhance the performance and economic viability of electrochemical energy storage and conversion technologies such as water&#8208;splitting electrolyzers, metal&#8208;air batteries, fuel cells and their integrated devices. Such multifunctional electrocatalysts encompass multiple active sites that can simultaneously catalyze two or more different electrochemical reactions and are feasible routes for addressing global energy and environmental challenges. This review accounts for nanocarbons&#8208;based trifunctional electrocatalysts reported for electrolyzers, metal&#8208;air batteries and integrated electrolyzer&#8208;battery systems, providing a practical perspective. Metal&#8208;free and hybrid (hybrids of nanocarbons and transition metals/compounds) trifunctional electrocatalysts are covered. Given the growing importance of green technologies, we discuss biomass&#8208;derived carbon&#8208;based trifunctional electrocatalysts separately. The collective information provided in the review could help researchers derive more effective and durable trifunctional electrocatalysts suitable for commercial use.</description>
      <author>Viswanathan S. Saji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical study on the carbon nanomaterial&#8208;supported Pt complex electrocatalysts for efficient and selective chlorine evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27466</link>
      <description>Jewel Hossen, Naoki Nakatani, Journal of computational chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400735545

                Chlorine is an important chemical which has long been produced in chlor-alkali process using dimensionally stable anodes (DSA). However, some serious drawbacks of DSA inspire the development of alternative anodes for chlorine evolution reaction (CER). In this study, we focused on the graphene- and carbon nanotube-supported platinum tetra-phenyl porphyrins as electrocatalysts for CER, which have been theoretically investigated based on density functional theory. Our results reveal that the supported substrates possess potential CER electrocatalytic activity with very low thermodynamic overpotentials (0.012-0.028 V) via Cl* pathway instead of ClO*. The electronic structures analyses showed that electron transfer from the support to the adsorbed chlorine via the Pt center leads to strong Pt-Cl interactions. Furthermore, the supported electrocatalysts exhibited excellent selectivity toward CER because of high overpotentials and reaction barriers of oxygen evolution process. Therefore, our results may pave the way for designing CER electrocatalyst utilizing emerging carbon nanomaterials.</description>
      <author>Jewel Hossen, Naoki Nakatani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jcc.27466</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance Enhancement of Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 Anode through Introduction of Tantalum&#8211;Titanium Interlayer via Double-Glow Plasma Surface Alloying Technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14141219</link>
      <description>Mingshuai Guo, Yueren Liu, Yonglei Xin, Likun Xu, Lili Xue, Tigang Duan, Rongrong Zhao, Junji Xuan, Li Li, Nanomaterials. 14(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400772789

                Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 electrodes are extensively utilized in the electrochemical industries such as copper foil production, cathodic protection, and wastewater treatment. However, their performance degrades rapidly under high current densities and severe oxygen evolution conditions. To address this issue, we have developed a composite anode of Ti/Ta-Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 with a Ta-Ti alloy interlayer deposited on a Ti substrate by double-glow plasma surface alloying, and the IrO2-Ta2O5 surface coating prepared by the traditional thermal decomposition method. This investigation indicates that the electrode with Ta-Ti alloy interlayer reduces the agglomerates of precipitated IrO2 nanoparticles and refines the grain size of IrO2, thereby increasing the number of active sites and enhancing the electrocatalytic activity. Accelerated lifetime tests demonstrate that the Ti/Ta-Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 electrode exhibits a much higher stability than the Ti/IrO2-Ta2O5 electrode. The significant improvement in electrochemical stability is attributed to the Ta-Ti interlayer, which offers high corrosion resistance and effective protection for the titanium substrate.</description>
      <author>Mingshuai Guo, Yueren Liu, Yonglei Xin, Likun Xu, Lili Xue, Tigang Duan, Rongrong Zhao, Junji Xuan, Li Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14141219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Enhancement Discharge Performance by Zinc-Coated Aluminum Anode for Aluminum&#8211;Air Battery in Sodium Chloride Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14146263</link>
      <description>Ruly Bayu Sitanggang, Syarifa Nur&#8217;aini, Susanto Susanto, W. Widiyastuti, Heru Setyawan, Applied sciences. 14(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400767124

                The main drawback of seawater batteries that use the aluminum (Al)&#8211;air system is their susceptibility to anode self-corrosion during the oxygen evolution reaction, which, in turn, affects their discharge performance. This study consist of an electrochemical investigation of pure Al, 6061 Al alloy, and both types coated with zinc as an anode in a 3.5% sodium chloride (NaCl) electrolyte. The electrolyte solution used for the deposition of zinc metal contained citrate, with and without EDTA as a complexing agent. Subsequently, the performance of the anode was tested in a seawater battery, using a carbon@MnO2 cathode and a 3.5% NaCl electrolyte. The performance of Al&#8211;air batteries has been significantly enhanced by applying a process of electrodepositing zinc (Zn) with a citrate deposition electrolyte solution in both pure aluminum and alloy 6061. The performance of the battery was further enhanced by adding EDTA as a chelating agent to the citrate-based electrolyte solution. The Al&#8211;air battery with aluminum alloy 6061 with Zn electrodeposition with an additional EDTA as the anode, carbon@MnO2 as the cathode, and NaCl 3.5% solution as the electrolyte has the highest battery performance, with a specific discharge capacity reaching 414.561 mAh.g&#8722;1 and a specific energy density reaching 0.255 mWh.g&#8722;1, with stable voltage at 0.55 V for 207 h.</description>
      <author>Ruly Bayu Sitanggang, Syarifa Nur&#8217;aini, Susanto Susanto, W. Widiyastuti, Heru Setyawan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14146263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nonpyrolytic Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C/Fe2O3 heterostructure with RuO2&#8208;like OER Activity Synthesized via Polyacrylonitrile&#8208;derived Conjugated Pyridinic&#8208;nitrogen&#8208;carbon Sheet</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400786</link>
      <description>Richard Appiah&#8208;Ntiamoah, Hern Kim, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400694809

                Pyrolytic single Fe atom&#8208;nitrogen&#8208;carbon materials (Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C) and their derivatives are excellent catalysts for electrochemical oxygen reduction reactions. However, they exhibit poor oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity due to non&#8208;optimal Fe&#8208;O* bonding. This limitation is overcome via electronic structure modulation (i.e., tuning the heteroatom type, concentration, and location within Fe&#8217;s n &#8805; 1 coordination sphere). However, the methods used are complex and energy&#8208;intensive (i.e., 1000 to 1200&#176;C) raising concerns about reproducibility and cost. This study introduces a method for synthesizing nonpyrolytic Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C/Fe2O3 composites with similar electronic structure modulation as pyrolytic Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C and OER activity akin to commercial RuO2. The methodology involves doping low&#8208;melting hydrated Fe&#8208;salts in electrospun polyacrylonitrile nanofiber to catalyze its transformation into conjugated pyridinic&#8208;N&#8208;rich graphite&#8208;like sheets (i.e., N&#8208;C) at 300&#176;C. N&#8208;C chelate effectively with oxygen&#8208;vacant (Ov)&#8208;rich Fe atoms derived from Fe2O3 NPs resulting in Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C/Fe2O3 heterostructures. The Fe2O3 coupling effectively tunes Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C&#8217;s electronic structure via Ov modulation. Consequently, the Fermi and d&#8208;orbital energy levels are optimized leading to partial filling of the antibonding states, optimal Fe&#8208;O* bonding, high electrochemically active surface area, and OER activity. Because Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C/Fe2O3 is synthesized at 300 oC using well&#8208;established techniques, its complexity and cost are favorable compared to pyrolytic Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C materials.</description>
      <author>Richard Appiah&#8208;Ntiamoah, Hern Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhibiting the Deep Reconstruction of Ni&#8208;Based Interface by Coordination of Chalcogen Anions for Efficient and Stable Glycerol Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404290</link>
      <description>Shuo Wang, Yong Yan, Yongping Du, Yuguo Zhao, Tongxian Li, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400887098

                Abstract Recently, Ni&#8208;based chalcogenides havedemonstrated remarkable activity and selectivity for alcohol electrooxidation, but the mechanisms remain debated. This study synthesizes Ni&#8208;based electrodeswith different chalcogen anion coordination on nickel nanorod arrays (NiO x /Ni,NiS x /Ni, and NiSe x /Ni NRAs). NiSe x /Ni NRAsshowcases superior performance (Faradaic efficiency 92.9%) in glycerolelectrooxidation reaction (GOR). In situ spectroscopy reveals that NiSecoordination inhibits deep oxidative reconstruction of the Ni&#8208;based interface, preventingNiOOH phase formation during GOR, enhancing activity and stability of NiSe x /NiNRAs. Conversely, NiS and NiO coordination lead to deep reconstruction with NiOOHphase formation, limiting GOR performance. Differently, during competingreaction of GOR, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) leads to deepreconstruction of NiSex interface due to the instability of Ni&#8208;Sebonds, inducing performance degradation and dissolution of Se components. Furthermechanism investigation elucidates that the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) ofGOR at the NiSe x interface involves oxidation of *C 2 H 3 O 3 intermediatesthrough H 2 O adsorption, favoring stable formate production.Contrarily, the RDS at the NiS x , NiO x , and NiOOHinterfaces predominantly focus on the decarboxylation of multi&#8208;carbon intermediates, raisingenergy barriers and over&#8208;oxidizing formate to CO 2 . These results providenew insights for designing Ni&#8208;based non&#8208;oxide catalysts forefficient and stable electrocatalytic oxidation.</description>
      <author>Shuo Wang, Yong Yan, Yongping Du, Yuguo Zhao, Tongxian Li, Dong Wang, Peter Schaaf, Xiayan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202404290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on hydrogen generation based on inorganic metal oxide nano-catalyst using water electrolysis approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/revic-2024-0026</link>
      <description>Muhammad Naeem Ayub, Kwang&#8208;Hyun Baek, Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Saad M. Al-Baqami, Khalid Ahmed Alzahrani, Md. Reazuddin Repon, Md. Rezaur Rahman, Mohammad Mizanur Rahman Khan, Muhammad Nadeem Arshad, Reviews in Inorganic Chemistry. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400836369

                Abstract Today world is looking for a cheap, environment friendly and efficient substitute of fossil fuel. Because due to large consumption of the fossil fuels on daily basis in whole world, emission of hazardous gases have produced lethal effects on human being. In this scenario hydrogen energy has emerged in form of clean, renewable and more efficient energy. Now the key challenge is that efficient production of the green hydrogen at commercial scale to meet demand of hydrogen. The electrolysis of water is the best pathway to achieve efficient hydrogen production. For this purpose the synthesis and improvement of low cast, active as well as stable catalysts or electrolysis is prerequisite for hydrogen production by electro-catalytic method for splitting of water. Main focus of this review is that, how we can perform the electrolysis of water by various techniques using novel methods especially electro-catalysts in term of activity, efficiency, large surface area, porosity, and stability. This will be performed by the method of two-half cell reaction one is the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) other one Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), where reaction proceeded in both medium acidic as well as alkaline phases. Particular attention is given to produce green clean hydrogen production from usable water and its physical and chemical storages for further uses for the support of human sustainability. Basically the recent strategy is to prepare, design and development of nanoscale materials/composite with non-noble metals and with also nanostructured with noble-metals will be discussed in this approach. The increased efficiency and utility have been the focal points of the use of diverse materials from different classes. To increase the electro-catalytic efficiency in OER and HER, we will discuss about new analyses methods and insights into studying the chemical compositions, shapes, surface area, porosity, and synergy of catalysts and the active sites of nanostructured electro-catalysts. This review will further provide the picture of current state of developments as well as recent progress for mechanized efficient production of clean hydrogen (i.e., HER) from water by electrocatalytic method using various nanoscale materials in a broad scale.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Naeem Ayub, Kwang&#8208;Hyun Baek, Umer Shahzad, Mohsin Saeed, Saad M. Al-Baqami, Khalid Ahmed Alzahrani, Md. Reazuddin Repon, Md. Rezaur Rahman, Mohammad Mizanur Rahman Khan, Muhammad Nadeem Arshad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/revic-2024-0026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Carbon Catalyst Coatings in the Electrochemical Water Splitting Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4682574/v1</link>
      <description>Graham N. Newton, William J. V. Townsend, Diego L&#243;pez-Alcal&#225;, Matthew A. Bird, Graham A. Rance, Johannes Biskupek, Jos&#233; J. Baldov&#237;, Darren A. Walsh, Lee Johnson, Andrei N. Khlobystov, Ute Kaiser, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400697323

                Abstract The availability of efficient electrocatalysts is key to the development of next-generation electrolyzers for water splitting to produce so-called &#8216;green hydrogen&#8217; for a future hydrogen economy. The oxygen-evolution reaction (OER) is one half of the water-splitting reaction and is slow at most electrocatalysts. Designing inexpensive, sustainable, stable, and high-performance OER electrocatalysts remains the largest obstacle hindering the development of new electrolyzers. Carbon-coated metal/metal oxide (nano)particles have been used in such applications, but the role played by the carbon coatings in electrocatalysis has provoked debate in the field and is poorly understood. We show here that the carbon coating itself acts as the active site in OER, with the underlying material activating the carbon through a charge-transfer mechanism. We demonstrate this phenomenon using model catalysts consisting of &lt; 2 nm metal-oxide electrocatalyst nanoparticles encapsulated within single-walled carbon nanotubes (SWNTs). Access of electrolyte to the encapsulated metal oxides is blocked by plugging the SWNTs with fullerenes, which shuts off redox processes inherent to the metal oxide but does not affect catalytic activity, showing that the carbon surface is the active OER site. This analysis is supported by electrochemical analysis, which shows that the rate-determining step for the OER is the same at SWNT with and without encapsuled metal oxides, but different to that at bare metal oxides. In-situ electrochemical Raman spectroscopy and computational analysis demonstrate that charge transfer from the carbon host to the metal oxide occurs during the OER. This charge transfer results in a decrease in electron density on the carbon surface, which may facilitate binding of &#8211;OH to the carbon surface, the first step in the OER and the RDS (as determined by electrochemical analysis) and may be key to the activity of carbon coated electrocatalysts. This understanding of how carbon coatings play an active role in electrocatalytic reactions is crucial for the development of future low cost, sustainable electrocatalysts for the OER, and the proposed charge transfer-driven mechanism could be tuneable to both oxidative and reductive reactions.</description>
      <author>Graham N. Newton, William J. V. Townsend, Diego L&#243;pez-Alcal&#225;, Matthew A. Bird, Graham A. Rance, Johannes Biskupek, Jos&#233; J. Baldov&#237;, Darren A. Walsh, Lee Johnson, Andrei N. Khlobystov, Ute Kaiser</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4682574/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Modeling of the Local Reaction Environment in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00234</link>
      <description>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling, Accounts of chemical research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400851781

                ConspectusElectrocatalytic reactions, such as oxygen reduction/evolution reactions and CO</description>
      <author>Xinwei Zhu, Jun Huang, Michael Eikerling</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00234</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A phenomenological study of the evolution of shock-induced O I emission
  lines in the spectrum of nova V2891 Cygni</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.09634</link>
      <description>Ruchi Pandey, Mudit Srivastava, Gargi Shaw, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400702705

                The eruption of Nova V2891 Cygni in 2019 offers a rare opportunity to explore the shock-induced processes in novae ejecta. The spectral evolution shows noticeable differences in the evolution of various oxygen emission lines such as O I 7773 {\AA}, O I 8446 {\AA}, O I 1.1286 $\mu$m, O I 1.3164 $\mu$m, etc. Here, we use spectral synthesis code CLOUDY to study the temporal evolution of these oxygen emission lines. Our photoionization model requires the introduction of a component with a very high density ($n ~ 10^{11}$ cm$^{-3}$) and an enhanced oxygen abundance (O/H $\sim$ 28) to produce the O I 7773 {\AA} emission line, suggesting a stratification of material with high oxygen abundance within the ejecta. An important outcome is the behaviour of the O I 1.3164 $\mu$m line, which could only be generated by invoking the collisional ionization models in CLOUDY. Our phenomenological analysis suggests that O I 1.3164 $\mu$m emission originates from a thin, dense shell characterized by a high density of about $10^{12.5} - 10^{12.8}$ cm$^{-3}$, which is most likely formed due to the strong internal collisions. If such is the case, the O I 1.3164 $\mu$m emission presents itself as a tracer of shock-induced dust formation in V2891 Cyg. The collisional ionization models have also been successful in creating the high-temperature conditions ($~ 7.07 - 7.49 \times 10^5$ K) required to reproduce the observed high ionization potential coronal lines, which coincide with the epoch of dust formation and evolution of the O I 1.3164 $\mu$m emission line.</description>
      <author>Ruchi Pandey, Mudit Srivastava, Gargi Shaw</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.09634</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimodal trending in corrosion loss of magnesium alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5006/4548</link>
      <description>Robert E. Melchers, CORROSION. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400896543

                Abstract Data for mass loss of a variety of magnesium alloys as a function of exposure period show that corrosion loss follows bimodal trending with time for different exposure environments, both laboratory and field support these findings. For data sets sufficient to discriminate bimodal behaviour, the instantaneous rate of corrosion at the commencement of the second mode is (close to) 4 times the instantaneous rate of corrosion at the end of the first mode (i.e. through the transition period). This observation is consistent with the theoretical relative diffusivities of oxygen and hydrogen through the corrosion product layer as it exists during the transition period. These findings support the notion that the bimodal model has corrosion in Mode 1 rate-controlled by the cathodic oxygen reduction reaction and the inward diffusion of oxygen while in Mode 2 corrosion is rate-controlled by the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction and the outward diffusion of hydrogen. Similar findings have been made previously for various ferrous and other alloys and thus throws new light on the development of corrosion of magnesium alloys. It also provides reasons for measurements of hydrogen evolution and for electrochemical techniques underestimating magnesium corrosion rates. A new procedure for combining these is proposed.</description>
      <author>Robert E. Melchers</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5006/4548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial community evolution in the biofilm attached to sponge carriers in pulp mill effluent treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17533/udea.redin.20240730</link>
      <description>Emeline Melchiors, Camila Peitz, Jackeline Valendolf, Mac Wendell Barbosa da Silva, Izadora Cervelin-Fl&#244;r, V&#226;nia Aparecida Vicente, Cl&#225;udia Regina Xavier, Revista Facultad de Ingenier&#237;a Universidad de Antioquia. 113(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400876404

                This study investigates the evolution of the biofilm matrix responsible for treating effluent from a pulp mill and identifies the microbial community by 16S rRNA gene sequencing. In addition, a biocarrier promising a functional structure with better specific features for biofilm formation than traditional polyurethane carriers was explored. The average removal efficiencies were 43.7% for chemical oxygen demand (COD) and 62.7% for biochemical oxygen demand (BOD5). The color increased during the treatment, indicating anoxic zones being formed in the inner part of this type of carrier. Periodic micrographs showed the evolution of extracellular polymeric substances and materials like fungi and bacteria adhered to the carriers. Genetic sequencing confirmed the presence of Bacillus sp. and Paenibacillus glucanolyticus, species with the potential to degrade and discolor pulp industrial effluents. Results offer a potential basis to enhance treatment facilities of pulp and paper mills based on microbial activities.</description>
      <author>Emeline Melchiors, Camila Peitz, Jackeline Valendolf, Mac Wendell Barbosa da Silva, Izadora Cervelin-Fl&#244;r, V&#226;nia Aparecida Vicente, Cl&#225;udia Regina Xavier</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17533/udea.redin.20240730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen is Toxic in the Cold in C. elegans.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.17.603990</link>
      <description>Cameron M Suraci, Michael L Morrison, Mark B. Roth, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400881915

                Temperature and oxygen are two factors that profoundly affect survival limits of animals; too much or too little of either is lethal. However, both humans and animals can exhibit exceptional survival when oxygen and temperature are simultaneously low. To better understand this apparent synergistic interaction between oxygen and temperature, we assayed the survival of Caenorhabditis elegans in experimental environments at different temperatures and oxygen concentrations. While nematodes cannot survive a day in room air at 2 degrees C (cold shock), we found that when oxygen is low, 200-fold less than room air, they can survive this temperature for 48 hours. Consistent with this, we found that worms exposed to high oxygen concentrations, 35 times greater than room air, are more sensitive to low temperature than worms in room air. These results show that normal atmospheric levels of oxygen are toxic in the cold. Using these survival assays, we found that cold acclimatization protects worms from lethal effects of high oxygen, mutations in the cold acclimatization pathway affect oxygen tolerance, and that the naturally occurring and physiologically relevant compounds glucose, manganese (II), and ascorbate improve survival limits in both low temperature and high oxygen when supplied early in life. These results show that the interdependence of temperature and oxygen on survival in C. elegans is based in part on shared physiological mechanisms involved in response to these two environmental stressors. The evolution and natural history of stress responses in animals suggest similar phenomena may function in humans.</description>
      <author>Cameron M Suraci, Michael L Morrison, Mark B. Roth</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.17.603990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melting at the base of a terrestrial magma ocean controlled by oxygen fugacity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01495-1</link>
      <description>Yanhao Lin, Takayuki Ishii, W. van Westrenen, Tomoo Katsura, Ho&#8208;kwang Mao, Nature geoscience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400690152

                Abstract Heat delivered from accretionary impacts is thought to have led to extensive melting of early Earth&#8217;s silicate mantle, resulting in a deep magma ocean covering the surface. The mantle&#8217;s oxygen fugacity is thought to have increased over accretion and core formation due to increasingly oxidated impactors and lower mantle self-oxidation, but the influence of this on the solidus of deep primitive mantle materials has not been well constrained. Here we assess the effect of oxygen fugacity on conditions at the bottom of a magma ocean by experimentally determining the solidus of mantle pyrolite at pressures of 16&#8211;26 GPa at high oxygen fugacities. We find that over this pressure range, the solidus in experiments conducted under oxidizing conditions is at least 230&#8211;450 &#176;C lower than in experiments conducted under more reducing conditions. Assuming constant magma ocean temperature, this would imply a magma ocean floor that deepens by about 60 km for each log unit increase in mantle oxygen fugacity. The strong influence of oxygen fugacity on mantle melting suggests that models of early Earth thermal evolution and geochemical models of core formation should be reassessed.</description>
      <author>Yanhao Lin, Takayuki Ishii, W. van Westrenen, Tomoo Katsura, Ho&#8208;kwang Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01495-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selection for Photocatalytic Function through Darwinian Evolution of Synthetic Self-Replicators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x4fdr</link>
      <description>Kai Liu, Omer Markovitch, Chris van Ewijk, Yari Katar Knelissen, Armin Kiani, Marcel J. Eleveld, Wouter H. Roos, Sijbren Otto, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400830447

                The onset of Darwinian evolution represents a key step in the transition of chemical systems into living ones. Here, we show the emergence of Darwinian evolution in two systems of self-replicating molecules, where natural selection favors replicator mutants best capable of catalyzing the production of the precursors required for their own replication. Such selection for protometabolic activity was observed in a system where trimer and hexamer replicators compete for common resources, as well as in a system of different hexamer replicator mutants. An out-of-equilibrium replication-destruction regime was implemented in a flow reactor, where replication from continuously supplied dithiol building blocks needs to keep up with &#8220;destruction&#8221; by outflow. Selection occurred based on the ability of the mutants to activate a cofactor that photocatalytically produces singlet oxygen which, in turn, enhances the rate by which dithiol building blocks are converted into disulfide-based replicator precursors. Selection was based on a functional trait (catalytic activity) opening up Darwinian evolution as a tool for catalyst development. This work functionally integrates self-replication with protometabolism and Darwinian evolution and marks a further advance in the de-novo synthesis of life.</description>
      <author>Kai Liu, Omer Markovitch, Chris van Ewijk, Yari Katar Knelissen, Armin Kiani, Marcel J. Eleveld, Wouter H. Roos, Sijbren Otto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-x4fdr</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The smallest angiosperm genomes may be the price for effective traps of bladderworts.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/aob/mcae107</link>
      <description>Franti&#353;ek Zedek, Jakub &#352;merda, Aneta Halasov&#225;, Lubom&#237;r Adamec, Adam Veleba, Kl&#225;ra Pla&#269;kov&#225;, Petr Bure&#353;, PubMed. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400702093

                Species of the carnivorous family Lentibulariaceae exhibit the smallest genomes in flowering plants. We explored the hypothesis that their minute genomes result from the unique mitochondrial cytochrome c oxidase (COX) mutation. The mutation may boost mitochondrial efficiency, which is especially useful for suction-bladder traps of Utricularia, but also increase DNA-damaging reactive oxygen species, leading to genome shrinkage through deletion-biased DNA repair. We aimed to explore this mutation's impact on genome size, providing insights into genetic mutation roles in plant genome evolution under environmental pressures.</description>
      <author>Franti&#353;ek Zedek, Jakub &#352;merda, Aneta Halasov&#225;, Lubom&#237;r Adamec, Adam Veleba, Kl&#225;ra Pla&#269;kov&#225;, Petr Bure&#353;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/aob/mcae107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ TEM Investigation of the Lithiation and Delithiation Process Between Graphene Sheets in the Presence of Atomic Defects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406034</link>
      <description>Yueliang Li, Felix B&#246;rrnert, Mahdi Ghorbani&#8208;Asl, Johannes Biskupek, Xuemei Zhang, Yongsheng Zhang, Stefano Passerini, Arkady V. Krasheninnikov, Ute Kaiser, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400782612

                Abstract Using advanced in situ transmission electron microscopy, the lithiation and delithiation processes into graphene sheets are studied and significant differences are detected in the structural evolution of the system. Thin fcc lithium crystals with faceted shapes are formed between graphene sheets during lithiation, but are transformed into irregular patches during delithiation. It is found that defects such as vacancies in graphene and impurity atoms play the key role in these processes. Specifically, during intercalation the lithium crystals nucleate at vacancies in graphene, while upon delithiation the impurity oxygen atoms initially embedded at octahedral interstitial positions inside the lithium crystals agglomerate at the edges of the crystals, thus giving rise to the formation of amorphous lithium oxide patches, where lithium ions are trapped.</description>
      <author>Yueliang Li, Felix B&#246;rrnert, Mahdi Ghorbani&#8208;Asl, Johannes Biskupek, Xuemei Zhang, Yongsheng Zhang, Stefano Passerini, Arkady V. Krasheninnikov, Ute Kaiser</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aging properties of spinel&#8208;type high&#8208;entropy oxides (Co&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;Cr&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;Mn&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;Zn&lt;sub&gt;.2&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for thermistors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14866</link>
      <description>Liangchen Fan, Jincheng Yao, Yuling Tuo, Aimin Chang, Zhaoyang Chen, Jingyi Wang, International journal of applied ceramic technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400778934

                Abstract Herein, a spinel&#8208;type high&#8208;entropy ceramics (Co .2 Cr .2 Fe .2 Mn .2 Zn .2 ) 3 O 4 is introduced. The obtained ceramics exhibit superior thermal stability under accelerated aging conditions at 125&#176;C for 500 h, that is, aging drift was less than .35% for all samples sintered at temperatures (1200or&#8211;1275or . The variation of resistance is mainly attributed to the oxidation of grain boundaries and the migration of oxygen vacancies. The relationship between crystal structure evolution and aging properties was investigated using structural analysis and P&#8211;V&#8211;L bonding theory. Theoretically, the Co/Cr/Mn/Fe&#8211;O bonds at the octahedral sites in the spinel structure are more important for controlling structural stability.</description>
      <author>Liangchen Fan, Jincheng Yao, Yuling Tuo, Aimin Chang, Zhaoyang Chen, Jingyi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14866</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elevational constraints on flight efficiency shape global gradients in avian wing morphology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.12.603304</link>
      <description>Jingyi Yang, Chenyue Yang, Hsi&#8211;Hsin Lin, Alexander Charles Lees, Joseph A. Tobias, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400747516

                Wings with elongated shape or larger surface area are associated with increased flight efficiency and dispersal ability in a wide range of animals from insects to birds. Inter- and intraspecific variation in these attributes of wing shape is determined by a range of factors - including foraging ecology, migration and climatic seasonality - all of which may drive latitudinal gradients in wing morphology. A separate hypothesis predicts that wing shape should also follow an elevational gradient because air density and oxygen supply decline with altitude, altering the aerodynamics of flight, and driving the evolution of more efficient wings in high-elevation species to compensate for reduced lift. However, previous analyses have found only mixed support for the 'thin-air' hypothesis, and we currently lack a global synthesis of elevational gradients in wing design for any taxonomic group. In this study, we use phylogenetic comparative models to explore elevational effects on wing morphology in 9986 bird species, while accounting for multiple climatic and ecological attributes, including latitude, temperature seasonality, body mass, aerial lifestyle and migration. We found that relative wing elongation (hand-wing index) and wing area increase with elevation, particularly in the upper montane zone (&gt;4 km above sea level). These results confirm a pervasive elevational gradient in avian wing morphology, highlighting the role of aerodynamic constraints as key mechanisms shaping global patterns of trait evolution in flying animals.</description>
      <author>Jingyi Yang, Chenyue Yang, Hsi&#8211;Hsin Lin, Alexander Charles Lees, Joseph A. Tobias</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.12.603304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Active Heterostructure Design for Enhanced Two Electron Oxygen Reduction via Chemical and Electrochemical Reconstruction of Heterosulfides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408508</link>
      <description>Kai Yu, Hongyuan Yang, Jie Xu, Weijie Yuan, Ruotao Yang, Meiling Hou, Zhenhui Kang, Yang Liu, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400839905

                Transition metal sulfides, particularly heterostructures, represent a promising class of electrocatalysts for two electron oxygen reduction (2e&#8722; ORR), however, understanding the dynamic structural evolution of these catalysts during alkaline ORR remains relatively unexplored. Herein, NiS2/In2.77S4 heterostructure was synthesized as a precatalyst and through a series of comprehensive ex&#8208;situ and in&#8208;situ characterizations, including X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, Raman spectroscopy, transient photo&#8208;induced voltage measurements, electron energy loss spectroscopy, and spherical aberration&#8208;corrected electron microscopy, it was revealed that nickel/indium (oxy)hydroxides (NiOOH/In(OH)3) could be evolved from the initial NiS2/In2.77S4 via both electrochemical and chemical&#8208;driven methods. The electrochemical&#8208;driven phase featured abundant bridging oxygen&#8208;deficient [NiO6]&#8208;[InO6] units at the interfaces of NiOOH/In(OH)3, facilitating a synergistic effect between active Ni and In sites, thus enabling an enhanced alkaline 2e&#8722; ORR capability than that of chemical&#8208;driven process. Remarkably, electrochemically induced NiOOH/In(OH)3 exhibited exceptional performance, achieving H2O2 selectivity of &gt;90% across the wide potential window (up to 0.4 V) with a peak selectivity of &gt;99%. Notably, within the flow cell, a current density exceeding 200 mA cm&#8722;2 was sustained for over 20 h, together with an impressive Faradaic efficiency of approximately 90% and a hydrogen peroxide production rate surpassing 4 mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1.</description>
      <author>Kai Yu, Hongyuan Yang, Jie Xu, Weijie Yuan, Ruotao Yang, Meiling Hou, Zhenhui Kang, Yang Liu, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408508</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High temperature oxidation regime transitions in hafnium carbide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20008</link>
      <description>Jonathan A. Scott, Xiaoqing He, David W. Lipke, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400779416

                Abstract Understanding the oxidation behavior of hafnium carbide is crucial to its application in extreme environments. In this work, the transition in high&#8208;temperature oxidation kinetics regimes in hafnium carbide is explained based on phase equilibria considerations supported by observed changes in oxide scale microstructure evolution associated with different transformation pathways. Below, a composition&#8208;dependent critical temperature and oxygen pressure, hafnium carbide first transforms to an amorphous material with nominal composition HfO 2 C followed by phase separation into carbon and hafnia domains. Subsequently, gaseous transport through a nanometric pore network formed by oxidative removal of phase&#8208;separated carbon becomes rate&#8208;limiting. Above this critical point, the oxidation sequence involves a direct transformation from hafnium carbide to hafnia and gaseous products, leading to dissimilar scale morphologies responsible for the reported transition from gaseous to solid&#8208;state diffusion&#8208;limited oxidation regimes at ultra&#8208;high temperatures.</description>
      <author>Jonathan A. Scott, Xiaoqing He, David W. Lipke</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Active Heterostructure Design for Enhanced Two Electron Oxygen Reduction via Chemical and Electrochemical Reconstruction of Heterosulfides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408508</link>
      <description>Kai Yu, Hongyuan Yang, Jie Xu, Weijie Yuan, Ruotao Yang, Meiling Hou, Zhenhui Kang, Yang Liu, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400800039

                Transition metal sulfides, particularly heterostructures, represent a promising class of electrocatalysts for two electron oxygen reduction (2e&#8722; ORR), however, understanding the dynamic structural evolution of these catalysts during alkaline ORR remains relatively unexplored. Herein, NiS2/In2.77S4 heterostructure was synthesized as a precatalyst and through a series of comprehensive ex&#8208;situ and in&#8208;situ characterizations, including X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, Raman spectroscopy, transient photo&#8208;induced voltage measurements, electron energy loss spectroscopy, and spherical aberration&#8208;corrected electron microscopy, it was revealed that nickel/indium (oxy)hydroxides (NiOOH/In(OH)3) could be evolved from the initial NiS2/In2.77S4 via both electrochemical and chemical&#8208;driven methods. The electrochemical&#8208;driven phase featured abundant bridging oxygen&#8208;deficient [NiO6]&#8208;[InO6] units at the interfaces of NiOOH/In(OH)3, facilitating a synergistic effect between active Ni and In sites, thus enabling an enhanced alkaline 2e&#8722; ORR capability than that of chemical&#8208;driven process. Remarkably, electrochemically induced NiOOH/In(OH)3 exhibited exceptional performance, achieving H2O2 selectivity of &gt;90% across the wide potential window (up to 0.4 V) with a peak selectivity of &gt;99%. Notably, within the flow cell, a current density exceeding 200 mA cm&#8722;2 was sustained for over 20 h, together with an impressive Faradaic efficiency of approximately 90% and a hydrogen peroxide production rate surpassing 4 mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1.</description>
      <author>Kai Yu, Hongyuan Yang, Jie Xu, Weijie Yuan, Ruotao Yang, Meiling Hou, Zhenhui Kang, Yang Liu, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408508</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous CuxO Nano-Skeletons from Waste Electronics for Enhanced Glucose Detection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01467-5</link>
      <description>Yexin Pan, Ruohan Yu, Yalong Jiang, Haosong Zhong, Qiaoyaxiao Yuan, Connie Kong Wai Lee, Rongliang Yang, Siyu Chen, Yi Chen, Wilson C. K. Poon, Guijun Li, Nano-micro letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400785664

                Abstract Electronic waste (e-waste) and diabetes are global challenges to modern societies. However, solving these two challenges together has been challenging until now. Herein, we propose a laser-induced transfer method to fabricate portable glucose sensors by recycling copper from e-waste. We bring up a laser-induced full-automatic fabrication method for synthesizing continuous heterogeneous Cu x O (h-Cu x O) nano-skeletons electrode for glucose sensing, offering rapid (&lt; 1 min), clean, air-compatible, and continuous fabrication, applicable to a wide range of Cu-containing substrates. Leveraging this approach, h-Cu x O nano-skeletons, with an inner core predominantly composed of Cu 2 O with lower oxygen content, juxtaposed with an outer layer rich in amorphous Cu x O (a-Cu x O) with higher oxygen content, are derived from discarded printed circuit boards. When employed in glucose detection, the h-Cu x O nano-skeletons undergo a structural evolution process, transitioning into rigid Cu 2 O@CuO nano-skeletons prompted by electrochemical activation. This transformation yields exceptional glucose-sensing performance (sensitivity: 9.893 mA mM &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 ; detection limit: 0.34 &#956;M), outperforming most previously reported glucose sensors. Density functional theory analysis elucidates that the heterogeneous structure facilitates gluconolactone desorption. This glucose detection device has also been downsized to optimize its scalability and portability for convenient integration into people&#8217;s everyday lives.</description>
      <author>Yexin Pan, Ruohan Yu, Yalong Jiang, Haosong Zhong, Qiaoyaxiao Yuan, Connie Kong Wai Lee, Rongliang Yang, Siyu Chen, Yi Chen, Wilson C. K. Poon, Guijun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01467-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOO&#8226; as the Chain Carrier for the Autocatalytic Photooxidation of Benzylic Alcohols</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29143429</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, H. B. Lao, H. Zhang, Yi Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Jieqing Wu, Yu&#8208;Feng Li, Hongjun Zhu, Jianyou Mao, Yi Pan, Molecules. 29(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400876445

                The oxidation of benzylic alcohols is an important transformation in modern organic synthesis. A plethora of photoredox protocols have been developed to achieve the aerobic oxidation of alcohols into carbonyls. Recently, several groups described that ultraviolet (UV) or purple light can initiate the aerobic oxidation of benzylic alcohols in the absence of an external catalyst, and depicted different mechanisms involving the photoinduction of &#8226;O2&#8722; as a critical reactive oxygen species (ROS). However, based on comprehensive mechanistic investigations, including control experiments, radical quenching experiments, EPR studies, UV&#8211;vis spectroscopy, kinetics studies, and density functional theory calculations (DFT), we elucidate here that HOO&#8226;, which is released via the H2O2 elimination of &#945;-hydroxyl peroxyl radicals [ArCR(OH)OO&#8226;], serves as the real chain carrier for the autocatalytic photooxidation of benzylic alcohols. The mechanistic ambiguities depicted in the precedent literature are clarified, in terms of the crucial ROS and its evolution, the rate-limiting step, and the primary radical cascade. This work highlights the necessity of stricter mechanistic analyses on UV-driven oxidative reactions that involve aldehydes&#8217; (or ketones) generation.</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, H. B. Lao, H. Zhang, Yi Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Jieqing Wu, Yu&#8208;Feng Li, Hongjun Zhu, Jianyou Mao, Yi Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29143429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Engineering of Fluorescent Carbon Dots with Metal Oxides for Real&#8208;Time Visualization of Oxygen Vacancy Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402827</link>
      <description>Lei Jiang, Wanlu Cao, Zijian Li, Chunchang Wang, Hong Bi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400735836

                Oxygen vacancy (Vo), as one of the most common surface defects, significantly influence the physiochemical properties of metal oxides. However, it remains a challenge for existing techniques to visualize the evolution of Vo during redox process due to its heterogeneous distribution, small size, and dynamic nature. Herein, the real-time monitoring of such microscopic interfacial events is reported by advantage of the high-contrast fluorescence response of carbon dots (H-CDs) to Vo. The green emissive H-CDs possess a unique disc-shaped structure and exceptional hydrophilicity, allowing their tight adhesion to the surfaces of Vo-rich MgO by simple mixing. Subsequently, a water involved interfacial reaction occurred between H-CDs and Vo, resulting in gradual quenching of the original green emission and simultaneously emergence of bright red fluorescence. Moreover, the spatiotemporal diffusion dynamics and reaction kinetics are investigated by confocal laser scanning microscopy, revealing the time-dependent reorganization and structural heterogeneity at the interface. The finding provides a new toolbox for in situ imaging of Vo-triggered phenomena at a microscopic level, which will be helpful in promoting the rational design of oxide materials.</description>
      <author>Lei Jiang, Wanlu Cao, Zijian Li, Chunchang Wang, Hong Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New information about the cyclable capacity fading process of a pouch cell with Li-rich layered oxide cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02472a</link>
      <description>Jinhong Luo, Jinghao Liu, Zilong Su, Hongxing Dong, Zhimin Ren, Guohua Li, Xiaopeng Qi, Bo Hu, Wei Quan, Jiantao Wang, RSC advances. 14(31)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400740121

                Most studies investigate the cyclable capacity fading mechanism of Li-rich layered oxides (LLOs) from the microscopic structure level, lacking discussions about how the structure degradation influences the performance of the pouch cell precisely and quantitatively. Based on the analysis of the evolution of key parameters during the whole cycling period, a new transition-type fading mechanism is proposed. From the early-to-middle stage of the cycling period, polarization increases, most of which is interface-related, causing about 67% of the whole capacity loss. From the middle-to-late stage of the cycling period, active material losses turn out to be the dominating factor, inducing about 61% of the total capacity loss. Diffusion-related polarization, replacing the interface type, is responsible for most of the increased overpotential. Relative analysis confirms that during the early stage, the increase of the charge transfer resistance, induced by CEI (cathode electrolyte interface) growth and initial surface layered-structure degradation, is the main source of interface polarization. As the cycling evolves to the late stage, severe bulky structure degradation, including lattice-oxygen release, Li/Ni mixture and generation of a new spinel phase, turns out to be the major factor, causing further capacity fading.</description>
      <author>Jinhong Luo, Jinghao Liu, Zilong Su, Hongxing Dong, Zhimin Ren, Guohua Li, Xiaopeng Qi, Bo Hu, Wei Quan, Jiantao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02472a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in atomic-scale interface engineering for flexible electronics: Enhancing flexibility and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad64db</link>
      <description>Di Wen, Ruige Yuan, Kun Cao, Jing Wang, Rong Chen, Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400763461

                Abstract Flexible electronics, such as wearable displays, implantable electronics, soft robots, and smart skin, have garnered increasing attention. Despite notable advancements in research, a bottleneck remains at the product level due to the prevalent use of polymer-based materials, requiring encapsulation films for lifespan extension and reliable performance. Multilayer composites, incorporating thin inorganic layers to maintain low permeability towards moisture, oxygen, ions, etc., exhibit potential in achieving highly flexible barriers but encounter challenges stemming from interface instability between layers. This perspective offers a succinct review of strategies and provides atomic-scale interface modulation strategy utilizing atomic layer integration technology focused on enhancing the flexibility of high-barrier films. It delves into bendable multilayers with atomic-scale interface modulation strategies, encompassing internal stress and applied stress modulation, as well as stretchable composite structural designs such as gradient/hybrid, wavy, and island. These strategies showcase significant improvements in flexibility from bendable to stretchable while maintaining high barrier properties. Besides, optimized manufacturing methods, materials, and complex structure design based on atomic-scale interface engineering are provided, better aligning with the future development of flexible electronics. By laying the groundwork for these atomic-scale strategies, this perspective contributes to the evolution of flexible electronics, enhancing their flexibility, durability, and functionality.</description>
      <author>Di Wen, Ruige Yuan, Kun Cao, Jing Wang, Rong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad64db</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfide and selenide PGE mineralization in chromitites of the Dunzhugur ophiolite massif (East Sayan, Russia)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0016777024020054</link>
      <description>Olga Kiseleva, E. V. Ayriyants, &#1057;. &#1052;. &#1046;&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1082;, Dmitriy Belyanin, Geologi&#226; rudnyh mestoro&#382;denij. 66(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400852046

                The paper presents the first data on PGE sulfide and selenide mineralization formed in podiform chromitites at different stages of evolution of the Dunzhugur ophiolite massif. The chromite bodies are local-ized in listvenitized aposerpentinites, which are part of the Dunzhugur ophiolite complex. The forms of occurrence, microstructural features and compositions of platinum-group minerals in chromitites were stud-ied by scanning electron microscopy. The enrichment of chromitites with a refractory platinum group-ele-ment (PGE) sulfides and alloys in the Os-Ir-Ru system (IPGE) testify that the for-mation of magmatic platinum-group minerals (PGMs) occurred under mantle conditions. Primary PGMs were replaced by iridium sulfoarsenides and sulfoantimonides due to the interaction of mantle peridotites and chromitites with As&#8211;Sb-bearing fluid generated during dehydration and melting of the subducting slab. Native osmium was formed as a result of desulfurization of magmatic PGE-bearing sulfides with the partic-ipation of reduced fluids at the serpentinization stage. The replacement of Ru&#8211;Os sulfides by selenides of these metals in chromitites could occur at the stages of subduction or obduction at high oxygen fugacity under the influence of acid hydrothermal/metamorphogenic fluids. A qualitative assessment of physicochemical parameters of the formation of ruthenium selenides was carried out. Oxygen fugacity values estimated from the mag-netite&#8211;hematite association are log fO2 (&#8211;30.5) at 300&#1413;C and log fO2 (&#8211;40.5) at 200&#1413;C. The minimum sulfur fugacity value was determined by the stability line of laurite at 300&#1413;C, log fS2 = &#8211;20; the maximum sulfur fugacity values&#8212;by the stability line of iron and nickel sulfides: log fS2 &#8211;4.5 at 300&#1413;C and log fS2 &#8211;10.5 at 200&#1413;C. The selenium fugacity at T = 300&#1413;C is log fSe2 (&#8211;8&#8230;&#8211;13); at T = 200&#1413;C, log fSe2 (&#8211;12&#8230;&#8211;17). Au&#8211;Ag selenides were formed at T = 200&#1413;C, log fS2 (&#8211;9&#8230;&#8211;10.5); log fSe2 is from &#8211;13.5 to &#8211;20.5, log fO2 (&#8211;40). An important factor for the possibility of replacement of Ru&#8211;Os sulfides by selenides is Se occurrence in the ore-forming system. The source of Se may be the substance of the subducting slab&#8212;volcanogenic&#8211;sedimentary rocks containing fragments of Se-rich hydrothermal&#8211;sedimentary sulfide ores. They were involved in the processes of magma genesis and accompanying hydrothermal circulation.</description>
      <author>Olga Kiseleva, E. V. Ayriyants, &#1057;. &#1052;. &#1046;&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1082;, Dmitriy Belyanin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0016777024020054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early combination of sotrovimab with nirmatrelvir/ritonavir or remdesivir is associated with low rate of persisting SARS CoV-2 infection in immunocompromised outpatients with mild-to-moderate COVID-19: a prospective single center study.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.15.24310384</link>
      <description>Ivan Gentile, Giulio Viceconte, F. M. Cuccurullo, Daria Pietroluongo, Alessia D&#8217;Agostino, Maria Silvitelli, Simona Mercinelli, Riccardo Scotto, Francesco Grimaldi, Salvatore Palmieri, Angela Gravetti, Fabio Trastulli, Marcello Moccia, Antonio Riccardo Buonomo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400701323

                Background Immunocompromised patients are at high risk of developing persisting/prolonged COVID-19. Data concerning early combined use of antivirals and monoclonal antibodies in this population are scarce. Research design and methods We performed an observational, prospective study, enrolling immunocompromised outpatient adults with mild-to-moderate COVID-19 treated with a combination of sotrovimab plus one antiviral (remdesivir or nirmatrelvir/ritonavir) within 7 days from symptoms onset. Results We enrolled 52 patients. No patient was hospitalized within 30 days from the disease onset, needed oxygen administration or died within 60 days, or experienced a reinfection or a clinical relapse within 90 days. Clearance rates were 67% and 97% at 14th day after the end of therapy and at the end of follow-up, respectively. Factors associated with longer infection were initiation of therapy after 3 days from symptoms onset, and enrollment more than 180 days from the beginning of the study. However, only the latter factor was independently associated with longer SARS-CoV-2 infection, suggesting a loss of efficacy of this strategy with the evolution of SARS-CoV-2 variants Conclusions Early administration of combination therapy with a direct antiviral and sotrovimab seems to be effective in preventing hospitalization, progression to severe COVID-19 and the development of prolonged/persisting SARS-CoV-2 infection in immunocompromised patients.</description>
      <author>Ivan Gentile, Giulio Viceconte, F. M. Cuccurullo, Daria Pietroluongo, Alessia D&#8217;Agostino, Maria Silvitelli, Simona Mercinelli, Riccardo Scotto, Francesco Grimaldi, Salvatore Palmieri, Angela Gravetti, Fabio Trastulli, Marcello Moccia, Antonio Riccardo Buonomo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.15.24310384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Transient Reoxidation on Inclusions in Rare&#8208;Earth&#8208;Treated Bearing Steel</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400169</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Boting Yan, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang, Xiangpeng Gao, Steel research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400863264

                The impact of transient reoxidation environments on the chemical morphology evolution of nonmetallic oxide inclusions in rare&#8208;earth&#8208;treated bearing steel is investigated using FactSage thermodynamic simulation calculations, vacuum induction furnace experiments, and high&#8208;temperature laser confocal microscopy experiments. Thermodynamic calculations indicate a direct correlation between the initial rare&#8208;earth content and the oxygen required to transform Ce 2 O 2 S to CeAlO 3 during secondary oxidation. Furthermore, a higher initial rare&#8208;earth content leads to a more extensive and complete conversion to CeAlO 3 . Vacuum induction furnace experiments reveal that the inclusions transform from Ce 2 O 2 S to CeAlO 3 and Al 2 O 3 and eventually into composite oxide clusters. This results in a significant increase in inclusions, with near&#8208;spherical Ce 2 O 2 S inclusions transforming into aggregated CeAlO 3 , leading to an increase in the average inclusion size from 2.4 to 4.2 &#956;m. Laser confocal scanning microscopy experiments show that CeAlO 3 exhibits a higher tendency to aggregate than Ce 2 O 2 S inclusions, the primary factor contributing to the observed increase in the average inclusion size after secondary oxidation. The results of this study provide theoretical guidance for mitigating the adverse effects of rare&#8208;earth secondary oxidation on bearing steels, particularly in terms of inclusion control.</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Boting Yan, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang, Xiangpeng Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A record of magmatic differentiation in plutonic xenoliths from Santorini (Greece)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30909/vol.07.02.421446</link>
      <description>Sean Whitley, Ralf Halama, Ralf Gertisser, Thor H. Hansteen, Matthias Frische, Torsten Vennemann, Volcanica. 7(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400701470

                Plutonic xenoliths from volcanic arcs provide unique insights into transcrustal magmatic systems in subduction zone settings. At Santorini volcano in the Central Aegean Volcanic Arc (Greece), plutonic xenoliths occur throughout a sequence of lavas and pyroclastic rocks erupted within the last ~360 ka. They are mineralogically variable, ranging from troctolites to olivine gabbros, gabbros, gabbronorites, and diorites. Thermobarometric calculations based on mineral and melt inclusion compositions indicate equilibration over a range of temperatures (1100 to 750 &#176;C) at shallow to mid-crustal depths (P &lt;400 MPa), but there is no evidence for crystallisation at lower crustal depths. Oxygen isotope data of mineral separates and calculated &#948;18O melt values are in line with extensive closed-system fractional crystallisation at magmatic temperatures, without a requirement for extensive assimilation of the subvolcanic continental basement. The xenolith minerals compositionally overlap with phenocrysts from the volcanic rocks, but they also contain evidence for the presence of highly evolved melt compositions in the form of melt inclusions with extremely silica-rich compositions (up to 82 wt.% SiO2) and high enrichments of incompatible trace elements coupled with increasing negative Eu anomalies in clinopyroxenes. Since these characteristics correlate systematically with differentiation indices and rock type, they are interpreted to reflect melt evolution via fractional crystallisation as the dominant differentiation process with no significant role of reactive porous flow. These observations highlight that trapped melt fractions can influence mineral compositional variations in the plutonic xenoliths, and in turn the mineral compositions demonstrate a melt compositional variability not preserved in the volcanic rock record.</description>
      <author>Sean Whitley, Ralf Halama, Ralf Gertisser, Thor H. Hansteen, Matthias Frische, Torsten Vennemann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30909/vol.07.02.421446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canine glioma stem-like cells demonstrate DNA methylation-dependent enhancement of cellular respiration following low oxygen tension</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4600799/v1</link>
      <description>Ryan G. Toedebusch, Chang&#8208;Il Hwang, Shafee Syed-Quadri, Orwa Aboud, Kevin Woolard, Daniel York, Maciej Parys, Peter J. Dickinson, Frederick J. Meyers, John M. McPherson, Christine M. Toedebusch, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400764115

                Abstract Glioma stem cells (GSCs) have been implicated in radio- and chemotherapeutic resistance of glioblastoma (GBM). Therapeutic targeting of GSCs has shown promise in immunocompromised rodent models but have not been translated into effective therapies for human patients. The limited success of translating therapies from rodent models to GBM patients may be attributed, in part, to the lack of co-evolution between tumors and the tumor microenvironment in immunocompromised rodent models. Thus, spontaneous canine high-grade gliomas (HGGs) may provide a complementary translational model for human therapeutic development. While described in canine HGGs, little is known about canine glioma stem cell biology. In this study, we evaluatedcellular metabolism, DNA methylation, gene expression, and functional tests of malignancy to interrogate differences between canine glioma stem-cell like (GSLC) lines and a traditional serum grown glioma cell line following exposure to hypoxia. Hypoxia increased oxygen consumption rates in GSLCs, which correlated with hypoxia-induced hypomethylation and increased mRNA levels of genes important in cellular metabolism and stemness (e.g., KCNN3, KDM4B, TCF7L2), as well as augmented features of malignancy in GSLCs. Importantly, we were able to demonstrate a positive correlation between up-regulated genes in human GBM GSCs and hypomethylation of orthologous canine genes following hypoxia. Together, these data highlight similarities between canine and human GBM GSC cellular metabolism and their epigenetic regulation.</description>
      <author>Ryan G. Toedebusch, Chang&#8208;Il Hwang, Shafee Syed-Quadri, Orwa Aboud, Kevin Woolard, Daniel York, Maciej Parys, Peter J. Dickinson, Frederick J. Meyers, John M. McPherson, Christine M. Toedebusch</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4600799/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Nonmetallic Inclusion in High&#8208;Mn and High&#8208;Al Steel Caused by the Interfacial Reaction Between Steel and Ladle Filler Sand</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400381</link>
      <description>Shengli Li, Xinliang Zang, Jun&#8208;Kai Zhang, Jie Yang, Ximin Zang, Guocheng Wang, Steel research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400863299

                The influence of chromium&#8208;bearing filler sand on the transformation of inclusions in high&#8208;Mn and high&#8208;Al steel under various reaction times and Mn content levels is studied, and the mechanism of filler sand intrusion into the steel matrix is analyzed. It is demonstrated that an inclusion containing Cr 2 O 3 is discovered. The evolution pathway of oxide inclusions is identified as Al 2 O 3 &#8211;MnO &#8594; Al 2 O 3 &#8211;MnO&#8211;SiO 2 &#8594; Al 2 O 3 &#8211;MnO&#8211;SiO 2 &#8211;Cr 2 O 3 (Cr 2 O 3 + MnO&#8211;SiO 2 ) &#8594; Al 2 O 3 &#8211;MnO&#8211;Cr 2 O 3 &#8211;MgO&#183;Al 2 O 3 . It is noteworthy that Cr 2 O 3 inclusions tend to diffuse from the outside inward, but the internal content remains almost unchanged, which is due to the strong diffusion hindrance of SiO 2 . The formation of a liquid phase in the filler sand is a necessary condition for its infiltration into the steel matrix. The critical liquid&#8208;phase content that results in the formation of Cr 2 O 3 inclusions is 42%, which contains 5&#8211;8% of Cr 2 O 3 . The formation of pore channels provides favorable conditions for sand penetration, with the maximum penetration depth reaching up to 29 mm. Large sand inclusion particles reach millimeter scale in size and are distributed quite randomly. Chemical reactions at the steel/sand interface can lead to an increase in the total oxygen (T.O) content in the steel. The reaction time has little effect on the T.O content, while the Mn content in the steel has a significant impact, with an increase of up to 41 ppm. During the smelting stage, the filler sand can enter the molten steel, thereby affecting the quality of the product.</description>
      <author>Shengli Li, Xinliang Zang, Jun&#8208;Kai Zhang, Jie Yang, Ximin Zang, Guocheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An oxidation flow reactor for simulating and accelerating secondary aerosol formation in aerosol liquid water and cloud droplets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-17-4227-2024</link>
      <description>Ningjin Xu, Le Chen, David R. Cocker, Kunpeng Chen, Ying&#8208;Hsuan Lin, Don Collins, Atmospheric measurement techniques. 17(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400743280

                Abstract. Liquid water in cloud droplets and aqueous aerosols serves as an important reaction medium for the formation of secondary aerosol through aqueous-phase reactions (aqSA). Large uncertainties remain in estimates of the production and chemical evolution of aqSA in the dilute solutions found in cloud droplets and the concentrated solutions found in aerosol liquid water, which is partly due to the lack of available measurement tools and techniques. A new oxidation flow reactor (OFR), the Accelerated Production and Processing of Aerosols (APPA) reactor, was developed to measure secondary aerosol formed through gas- and aqueous-phase reactions, both for laboratory gas mixtures containing one or more precursors and for ambient air. For simulating in-cloud processes, &#8764; 3.3 &#181;m diameter droplets formed on monodisperse seed particles are introduced into the top of the reactor, and the relative humidity (RH) inside it is controlled to 100 %. Similar measurements made with the RH in the reactor &lt; 100 % provide contrasts for aerosol formation with no liquid water and with varying amounts of aerosol liquid water. The reactor was characterized through a series of experiments and used to form secondary aerosol from known concentrations of an organic precursor and from ambient air. The residence time distributions of both gases and particles are narrow relative to other OFRs and lack the tails at long residence time expected with laminar flow. Initial cloud processing experiments focused on the well-studied oxidation of dissolved SO2 by O3, with the observed growth of seed particles resulting from the added sulfuric acid agreeing well with estimates based on the relevant set of aqueous-phase reactions. The OH exposure (OHexp) for low RH, high RH, and in-cloud conditions was determined experimentally from the loss of SO2 and benzene and simulated from the KinSim chemical kinetics solver with inputs of the measured 254 nm UV intensity profile through the reactor and loss of O3 due to photolysis. The aerosol yield for toluene at high OHexp ranged from 21.4 % at low RH with dry seed particles present in the reactor to 78.1 % with cloud droplets present. Measurement of the composition of the secondary aerosol formed from ambient air using an aerosol mass spectrometer showed that the oxygen-to-carbon ratio (O : C) of the organic component increased with increasing RH (and liquid water content).</description>
      <author>Ningjin Xu, Le Chen, David R. Cocker, Kunpeng Chen, Ying&#8208;Hsuan Lin, Don Collins</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/amt-17-4227-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does water transparency control the banding in shallow water iron formations?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25131/sajg.127.0014</link>
      <description>Daniel Herwartz, Sebastian Viehmann, South African journal of geology. 127(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400747134

                Abstract Iron formations (IFs) are marine chemical sediments that are conined to the Precambrian rock record and provide unique insights into the co-evolution of the atmosphere-hydrosphere and biosphere through almost three billion years of Earth&#8217;s history. IFs commonly appear throughout the Archaean until the Palaeoproterozoic ca. 1.8 billion years ago and re-appear during the &#8220;Snowball Earth&#8221; epoch in the Neoproterozoic. The formation and deposition mechanism(s) of IFs are, however, still incompletely understood, hindering unique interpretations of palaeoenvironments. Many IFs are banded iron formations (BIFs) with layer thickness of alternating Fe- and Si-rich layers ranging over several orders of magnitude from the nanometre to the metre scale. A second textural type, so called granular iron formations (GIFs) that form above storm wave base become widespread in the Palaeoproterozoic. Understanding the fundamental mechanisms that are responsible for the textural types and the periodicity of banding in BIFs is crucial to link these features to the environmental and geochemical evolution of the Earth. We here provide a conceptual model that highlights the role of changing light conditions and water transparency for Iron Formation (IF) precipitation. We show that the model is particularly feasible for IFs deposited in shallow waters but may also be applicable for some IFs deposited in deeper water settings. The model builds on other primary Banded Iron Formation (BIF) precipitation models postulating that Fe(III)-(oxyhydr)oxide production can be dominated by anoxygenic photoautotrophic Fe2+-oxidising bacteria. These so called photoferrotrophs are adapted to very low light levels corresponding to about 1% of the light level required by oxygen-producing phototrophs allowing them to thrive deep down in the water column. The depth of Fe(III)-(oxyhydr)oxide production is mainly controlled by water turbidity which controls how deep photosynthetically available radiation (PAR) penetrates the water column. Eutrophic conditions result in relatively shallow Fe(III)-(oxyhydr)oxide production depth due to turbidity either induced by the biomass itself and/or by particles that are actively or passively produced by microorganisms (e.g., Fe(III) and Mn(IV)-(oxyhydr)oxides, sulphides), triggering the formation of Fe-rich bands. During oligotrophic stages, Fe(III)-(oxyhydr)oxides are only produced relatively deep down in the water column, so that only silica-rich bands form in the Fe(III)-(oxyhydr)oxide free upper water column. Reactive transport modelling adopted from Ozaki et al., (2019) shows that besides upwelling and nutrient supply, alternating Fe(III) production depth is mainly associated with changing light conditions as a result of water transparency. Periodicities reflected by alternating Fe- and Si-rich bands in IFs in our model can thus be associated with: (1) nutrient supply patterns; (2) additional sources of turbidity in the water column such as Fe(III) and Mn(IV) oxide particles, sulphides, and wind-blown silicate particles; or (3) formation and clearing of organic haze in the atmosphere. One or all of these reasons for low light conditions seem to become more important in the Palaeoproterozoic (&amp;lt;2.4 Ga) and could be partly responsible for the more widespread occurrences of shallow marine granular IFs relative to former epochs, which is often assigned to the gradual oxidation of the ocean. Our model shows that variable water transparency should be considered as additional factor for IF deposition especially for shallow marine settings. This model also reasonably explains the prominent layering in BIFs as syn-depositional feature.</description>
      <author>Daniel Herwartz, Sebastian Viehmann</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25131/sajg.127.0014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Geology, Fluid Inclusions, and O&#8208;S Isotopes of the Mibei Gold Deposit, Hunan Province, Southern China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1755-6724.15184</link>
      <description>Wenhao Xue, Yayun Liang, Xiaofeng Li, Minyong Li, Wei Xie, Xue Peng, Rui Xia, Honglin He, Jinzhi Xiao, Acta geologica Sinica/Acta geologica sinica. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400697833

                Abstract The Mibei gold deposit, located in the southwestern part of the Xuefengshan uplift zone, the middle section of the Jiangnan orogenic belt in southern China, has estimated gold resources of approximately seven tons. This deposit is primarily a quartz vein&#8208;type gold deposit, with ore bodies occurring mainly within Neoproterozoic metasediments. The main metallic minerals in the ore are pyrite, chalcopyrite, and arsenopyrite. In this study, the petrography and microthermometry of ore&#8208;forming fluid inclusions, oxygen isotopes of gold&#8208;bearing quartz, and sulfur isotopes of gold&#8208;bearing sulfides and arsenopyrite were analyzed. Three types of fluid inclusions were identified: type Ia three&#8208;phase inclusions comprising vapor and two phases of liquids (V CO2 + L CO2 + L H2O ), type Ib two&#8208;phase liquids (L CO2 + L H2O ), type II two&#8208;phase vapor&#8208;rich inclusions (V/V + L &gt; 50%), and type III pure liquid inclusions. Type I inclusions were heated uniformly to the liquid phase, type II inclusions were heated uniformly to the gas phase, and type III inclusions were heated without change. In general, the temperature range of homogenization to liquid phase of fluid inclusions in the Mibei gold deposit is 204&#8211;227&#176;C. The salinity of the inclusion ranges from 4.6 to 12.2 wt% NaCl equiv. The &#948; 18 O SMOW of gold&#8208;bearing quartz varies from 16.9&#8240; to 17.5&#8240;. The &#948; 18 O H2O of gold&#8208;bearing quartz are varied from 6.5&#8240; to 7.5&#8240;. The &#948; 34 S values of gold&#8208;bearing pyrite range from 1.7&#8240; to 6.8&#8240;. The &#948; 34 S values of gold&#8208;bearing arsenopyrite range from 5.6&#8240; to 5.9&#8240;. The &#948; 34 S values of pyrite from wall rocks slate range from 6.4&#8240; to 11.6&#8240;. This evidence implies that the ore&#8208;forming fluids of the Mibei gold deposit originated from magmatic&#8208;hydrothermal processes, mixing with minor S from the surrounding metasediments. Combined with the evolution of the Jiangnan orogenic belt, due to the magmatic and tectonic activities of the Xuefengshan uplift during the Caledonian period, the fault seal mechanism controlled the ore&#8208;forming process. Overall, the Mibei gold deposit is more akin to a magmatic&#8208;hydrothermal gold deposit.</description>
      <author>Wenhao Xue, Yayun Liang, Xiaofeng Li, Minyong Li, Wei Xie, Xue Peng, Rui Xia, Honglin He, Jinzhi Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1755-6724.15184</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
