<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 01:20:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Production of Cost-effective Green Energy using Mn/Gd Co-substituted Cobalt Ferrites Hydroelectric Cells and their Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177419</link>
      <description>Prachi Jain, Rathindranath Biswas, Lakshi Saikia, Arnab Dutta, O. P. Thakur, Shylashri Shankar, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404092151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Prachi Jain, Rathindranath Biswas, Lakshi Saikia, Arnab Dutta, O. P. Thakur, Shylashri Shankar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal synthesis of CeSe anchored on graphitic carbon nitride nanoclusters as an electrocatalyst for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111751</link>
      <description>Mohammad Numair Ansari, Karam Jabbour, Khadija Bibi, Mehar Un Nisa, Muhammad Yousaf Ur Rehman, Alanoud T. Alfagham, Abdallah M. Elgorban, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404092182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammad Numair Ansari, Karam Jabbour, Khadija Bibi, Mehar Un Nisa, Muhammad Yousaf Ur Rehman, Alanoud T. Alfagham, Abdallah M. Elgorban, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Built&#8208;In Electronic Configuration via Variable Al Doping for Robust Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elan.202400314</link>
      <description>Ling Jin, Chunhui Yang, Yonggang Yang, Haiyan Qiao, Jinhui Hao, Weiwei Shi, Zongbao Yu, Lei Yang, Electroanalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404092929

                Transition metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts play a crucial role in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, their heavy reliance on free electrons at the &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;band significantly limits the screening of potentially efficient, earth&#8208;abundant alternatives. Despite extensive exploration of catalyst engineering through multi&#8208;metal cooperation to modulate electron configuration by introducing additional transition metals, practical success remains elusive. Here, we present a straightforward electrodeposition method for preparing amorphous FeCoAl hydroxide catalysts. The introduction of Al contributes external free electrons, enabling a well&#8208;defined electron configuration for intermediate adsorption. Al doping also adjusts the &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;band position of adjacent Co atoms, bringing them closer to the Fermi level and significantly enhancing intrinsic activity at the active sites. Furthermore, Al dopants facilitate rapid mass and charge transfer near the catalyst layer, promoting faster reaction kinetics. Leveraging these properties, the FeCoAl hydroxide catalyst achieves a large current density of 100 mA cm &lt;sup&gt;&#8208;2&lt;/sup&gt; at an overpotential of 340 mV, with a small Tafel slope of 29.1 mV dec &lt;sup&gt;&#8208;1&lt;/sup&gt;. Our work provides valuable insights for designing efficient electrocatalysts by leveraging free electron&#8208;rich metal doping and expanding the parameter space for catalyst engineering.</description>
      <author>Ling Jin, Chunhui Yang, Yonggang Yang, Haiyan Qiao, Jinhui Hao, Weiwei Shi, Zongbao Yu, Lei Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elan.202400314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tantalum-induced reconstruction of nickel sulfide for enhanced bifunctional water splitting: Separate activation of the lattice oxygen oxidation and hydrogen spillover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.022</link>
      <description>Xuanzhi Liu, Meihuan Liu, Hanxiao Liao, Shaohui Zhang, Xiaorong He, Yue Yu, Longquan Li, Pengfei Tan, Feng Liu, Jun Pan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404094264

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuanzhi Liu, Meihuan Liu, Hanxiao Liao, Shaohui Zhang, Xiaorong He, Yue Yu, Longquan Li, Pengfei Tan, Feng Liu, Jun Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modifying d&#8211;p orbital hybridization of Ni/Fe O species by high-valence ruthenium doping to enhance oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.029</link>
      <description>Tianmi Tang, Xue Bai, Xiaoqin Xu, Zhenl&#252; Wang, Jingqi Guan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404094311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianmi Tang, Xue Bai, Xiaoqin Xu, Zhenl&#252; Wang, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron doped Fe3S4/Co3S4 decorated with multi-wall carbon nanotubes as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114709</link>
      <description>Arti Maurya, Narayan Pradhan, Kumari Keshar, XXXXXXX Manisha, M. Yadav, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404094750

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arti Maurya, Narayan Pradhan, Kumari Keshar, XXXXXXX Manisha, M. Yadav</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating charge separation in p-n heterojunction photocathode for photoelectrochemical oxygen reduction and evolution in photo-enhanced zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.024</link>
      <description>Yunong Qin, Chengrun Liu, Xin Peng, Zhixin Ma, Ling Li, Song Chen, Wenming Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404095005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunong Qin, Chengrun Liu, Xin Peng, Zhixin Ma, Ling Li, Song Chen, Wenming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles supported on graphitic carbon nitride as an electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction and evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03407d</link>
      <description>Au&#353;rin&#279; Zabielait&#279;, Virginija Kepenien&#279;, Dijana &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;, Raminta Stagni&#363;nait&#279;, Vitalija Jasulaitien&#235;, Giedrius Stalnionis, J&#363;rat&#279; Vai&#269;i&#363;nien&#279;, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Eugenijus Norkus, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404107963

                The use of g-CN/C as a substrate for MnO 2 has been demonstrated to enhance the electrocatalytic activity of the ORR and OER.</description>
      <author>Au&#353;rin&#279; Zabielait&#279;, Virginija Kepenien&#279;, Dijana &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;, Raminta Stagni&#363;nait&#279;, Vitalija Jasulaitien&#235;, Giedrius Stalnionis, J&#363;rat&#279; Vai&#269;i&#363;nien&#279;, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Eugenijus Norkus</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03407d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combined effect of nitrogen-doped carbon and NiCo2O4 for electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74031-1</link>
      <description>Laura Kubi&#324;ska, Mariusz Szkoda, Ma&#322;gorzata Skorupska, Patrycja Grabowska, Marta Gajewska, Jerzy P. &#321;ukaszewicz, Anna Ilnicka, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404112810

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting for green hydrogen production necessitates effective electrocatalysts. Currently, commercial catalysts are primarily platinum-based. Therefore, finding catalysts with comparable catalytic activity but lower cost is essential. This paper describes spinel-structured catalysts containing nickel cobaltite NiCo 2 O 4 , graphene, and additionally doped with heteroatoms. The structure and elemental composition of the obtained materials were analyzed by research methods such as TEM, SEM-EDX, XRD, XPS, and Raman spectroscopy. The electrochemical measurements showed that hybrid materials containing nickel cobaltite NiCo 2 O 4 doped with graphene are highly active catalysts in the hydrogen evolution reaction (Tafel slopes = 91 mV dec &#8722;1 , overpotential = 468 mV and onset potential = -339 mV), while in the oxygen evolution reaction (Tafel slopes = 51 mV dec &#8722;1 , overpotential = 1752 mV and onset potential = 370 mV), bare NiCo 2 O 4 without the addition of carbon has a worse activity (for HER: Tafel slopes = 120 mV dec &#8722;1 , overpotential - does not achieve and onset potential = -404 mV, for OER: Tafel slopes = 54 mV dec &#8722;1 , overpotential = 1796 mV and onset potential = 410 mV). In terms of stability, comparable results were obtained for each synthesized compound for both the HER and OER reactions.</description>
      <author>Laura Kubi&#324;ska, Mariusz Szkoda, Ma&#322;gorzata Skorupska, Patrycja Grabowska, Marta Gajewska, Jerzy P. &#321;ukaszewicz, Anna Ilnicka</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74031-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vertically Expanded Covalent Organic Frameworks for Photocatalytic Water Oxidation into Oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416771</link>
      <description>Donglin Jiang, Shuailei Xie, Ruoyang Liu, Nengyi Liu, Hetao Xu, Xiong Chen, Li Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404114719

                Covalent organic frameworks with unique &#960; architectures and pores could be developed as photocatalysts for transformations. However, they usually form &#960;&#8208;stacking layers, so that only surface layers function in photocatalysis. Here we report a strategy for developing vertically expanded frameworks to expose originally inaccessible active sites hidden in layers to catalysis. We designed covalently linked two&#8208;dimensional cobalt(II) porphyrin layers and explored coordination bonds to connect the cobalt(II) porphyrin layers with bidentate ligands via a three&#8208;component one&#8208;pot polymerization. The frameworks expand the interlayer space greatly, where both the up and down faces of each cobalt(II) porphyrin layer are exposed to reactants. Unexpectedly, the vertically expanded frameworks increase skeleton oxidation potentials, decrease exciton dissociation energy, improve pore hydrophilicity and affinity to water, and facilitate water delivery. Remarkably, these positive effects work collectively in the photocatalysis of water oxidation into oxygen, with an oxygen production rate of 1155 &#181;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1, a quantum efficiency of 1.24% at 450 nm, and a turnover frequency of 1.39 h&#8722;1, which is even 5.1&#8208;fold as high as that of the &#960;&#8208;stacked frameworks and ranks them the most effective photocatalysts. This strategy offers a new platform for designing layer frameworks to build various catalytic systems for chemical transformations.</description>
      <author>Donglin Jiang, Shuailei Xie, Ruoyang Liu, Nengyi Liu, Hetao Xu, Xiong Chen, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vertically Expanded Covalent Organic Frameworks for Photocatalytic Water Oxidation into Oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416771</link>
      <description>Donglin Jiang, Shuailei Xie, Ruoyang Liu, Nengyi Liu, Hetao Xu, Xiong Chen, Wei Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404114720

                Covalent organic frameworks with unique &#960; architectures and pores could be developed as photocatalysts for transformations. However, they usually form &#960;&#8208;stacking layers, so that only surface layers function in photocatalysis. Here we report a strategy for developing vertically expanded frameworks to expose originally inaccessible active sites hidden in layers to catalysis. We designed covalently linked two&#8208;dimensional cobalt(II) porphyrin layers and explored coordination bonds to connect the cobalt(II) porphyrin layers with bidentate ligands via a three&#8208;component one&#8208;pot polymerization. The frameworks expand the interlayer space greatly, where both the up and down faces of each cobalt(II) porphyrin layer are exposed to reactants. Unexpectedly, the vertically expanded frameworks increase skeleton oxidation potentials, decrease exciton dissociation energy, improve pore hydrophilicity and affinity to water, and facilitate water delivery. Remarkably, these positive effects work collectively in the photocatalysis of water oxidation into oxygen, with an oxygen production rate of 1155 &#181;mol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1, a quantum efficiency of 1.24% at 450 nm, and a turnover frequency of 1.39 h&#8722;1, which is even 5.1&#8208;fold as high as that of the &#960;&#8208;stacked frameworks and ranks them the most effective photocatalysts. This strategy offers a new platform for designing layer frameworks to build various catalytic systems for chemical transformations.</description>
      <author>Donglin Jiang, Shuailei Xie, Ruoyang Liu, Nengyi Liu, Hetao Xu, Xiong Chen, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Effects and Crystalline&#8208;Amorphous Interface of NiFe&#8208;LDH@S&#8208;NiFeO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;/NF with Heterogeneous Structure for Enhancing Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Water&#8208;Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406071</link>
      <description>Huan Xu, Xiao Wei Sun, Lingtong Ding, Jingjing Liu, Dan Zhang, Minmin Liu, Xiao Wang, Qixian Zhang, Jiujun Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404115268

                Abstract Electrochemical water&#8208;electrolysis for hydrogen generation often requires more energy due to the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This work introduces a double&#8208;layered nanoflower catalyst, NiFe&#8208;LDH@S&#8208;NiFeO x /NF, featuring a crystalline NiFe&#8208;LDH coating on amorphous S&#8208;NiFeO x on nickel foam. Strategically integrating a crystalline&#8208;amorphous (c&#8208;a) heterostructure leverages strain engineering to enhance OER activity with low overpotentials ( &#951; 100 = 220 and &#951; 500 = 245 mV) and stability (135 h at &#951; 100 and 80 h at &#951; 500 ). Theoretical density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the compressive strain can optimize the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates to reduce the reaction energy barrier, thus improving the reaction kinetics and performance of OER. Moreover, its phosphated derivative, NiFeP@S&#8208;NiFeO x /NF, exhibits high hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance ( &#951; 10 = 64 mV, &#951; 100 = 187 mV). An alkaline water&#8208;electrolysis cell of NiFeP@S&#8208;NiFeO x /NF(&#8722;)||NiFe&#8208;LDH@S&#8208;NiFeO x /NF(+) requires only a cell voltage of 1.77 V at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , demonstrating excellent stability over 110 h (at both 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ). This work highlights the benefits of integrating crystal&#8208;amorphous interfaces and strain effects, offering insights into the understanding and optimizing catalytic OER mechanism and advancing water&#8208;electrolysis technology.</description>
      <author>Huan Xu, Xiao Wei Sun, Lingtong Ding, Jingjing Liu, Dan Zhang, Minmin Liu, Xiao Wang, Qixian Zhang, Jiujun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Construction and Design of Bimetallic Co-Ni Species by Pulsed Laser Irradiation for Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5011300</link>
      <description>Xiaohui Ren, Wenzhe Cao, Ying Wen, Tian Zhang, W.Y. Chu, Zhaoyang Liu, Haoran Zou, Qianying Guo, Rongsheng Chen, Feng Ma, Hongwei Ni, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404120450

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaohui Ren, Wenzhe Cao, Ying Wen, Tian Zhang, W.Y. Chu, Zhaoyang Liu, Haoran Zou, Qianying Guo, Rongsheng Chen, Feng Ma, Hongwei Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5011300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Co/Ni-MOFs with Mixed Ligands and Their Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.140549</link>
      <description>Xuejiao Sun, Lei Yang, Dongmei Li, Zhongzhen Tian, Journal of Molecular Structure. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404121987

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuejiao Sun, Lei Yang, Dongmei Li, Zhongzhen Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.140549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction in flexoelectric thin-film heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0215284</link>
      <description>Jibo Xu, Xiaoyan Zhang, Lei Zhu, Ming Wu, Junzhe Liu, Z. Liu, Meiyue Li, Yuhao Yue, Yawen Xu, Chenyu Dong, Weijie Zheng, Lin Zhu, Yanqiang Cao, Chunyan Zheng, Jianyi Liu, Aidong Li, Di Wu, Lixue Zhang, Zheng Wen, Applied Physics Reviews. 11(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404123773

                Recently, the flexoelectric effect has triggered considerable interest in energy-related applications, such as flexo-actuation, flexo-photovoltaic, and flexo-catalysis, because of its ubiquitous feature allowing the creation of electric polarity, i.e., the flexoelectric polarization (Pflexo), in non-polar materials by strain gradient. Here, we show a flexoelectric strategy in electrocatalytic water splitting. Remarkably enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) properties are achieved in strain-gradient LaFeO3 (LFO) thin-film heterostructures owing to the promotion of kinetic processes by Pflexo. The improved OER is demonstrated by increased current density of &#8764;300% in linear sweep voltammetry and lowered charge transfer resistance by two orders of magnitude in electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. These are ascribed to the flexoelectric-induced downward bending of the LFO band, as revealed by density functional theory calculations and band structure measurements. With Pflexo in the thin-film heterostructure catalysts, the adsorption of hydroxyl ions is strengthened on the polar LFO surface, and the transfer of electrons is accelerated from the reactants/key intermediates to the catalyst across the band-tilted LFO layer. These findings indicate the significance of flexoelectric effect in OER kinetics and open a new perspective for exploiting catalytic mechanisms and performances in water splitting.</description>
      <author>Jibo Xu, Xiaoyan Zhang, Lei Zhu, Ming Wu, Junzhe Liu, Z. Liu, Meiyue Li, Yuhao Yue, Yawen Xu, Chenyu Dong, Weijie Zheng, Lin Zhu, Yanqiang Cao, Chunyan Zheng, Jianyi Liu, Aidong Li, Di Wu, Lixue Zhang, Zheng Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0215284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycled industrial waste silicon steel as high-performance electrode for oxygen evolution reaction using electroless plating surface modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161747</link>
      <description>Jiawei Xie, Zijian Wang, Xue Bai, Hong Li, Shige Wang, Weiju Hao, Qingyuan Bi, Jinchen Fan, Guisheng Li, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404124182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawei Xie, Zijian Wang, Xue Bai, Hong Li, Shige Wang, Weiju Hao, Qingyuan Bi, Jinchen Fan, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of D-Band Center in Hollow Ceo2/Cofep Heterojunctions for Boosting Bifunctional Oxygen/Hydrogen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5013883</link>
      <description>Jing-Chang Ni, De-Kun Liu, Xue&#8208;Zhi Song, S. Yu, Xiaobing Wang, Yu&#8208;Xin Luan, Xiuming Zhao, Zhenquan Tan, Changzhu Lv, Wang Xiao-feng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404127765

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing-Chang Ni, De-Kun Liu, Xue&#8208;Zhi Song, S. Yu, Xiaobing Wang, Yu&#8208;Xin Luan, Xiuming Zhao, Zhenquan Tan, Changzhu Lv, Wang Xiao-feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5013883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Ultrathin CoFe&#8208;Nanomesh for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: From Slit Pores to Ink&#8208;Bottle Pores</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401156</link>
      <description>Amit Paul, Shashank Sharma, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404136705

                The time&#8208;dependent mechanism underlying the formation of Co0.8Fe0.2(OH)x&#8208;t nanomesh (nanomesh having 80% Co and 20% Fe, &#8220;t&#8221; represents materials synthesis time) has been identified towards the development of a highly effective catalyst for the OER. Utilizing 2&#8208;ethyl imidazole as an etching reagent and the Ostwald ripening process enabled the evolution of nanomesh formation with a precise pore size of inkbottle shape. Material characterization confirmed the evolution of pore structure from layered double hydroxide&#8208;like structure to hierarchical slit&#8208;pores to uniform ink&#8208;bottle pores after 24 h of synthesis with limited pore shrinkage attributable to iron redeposition at the pore entrances. AFM showed a gradual reduction in nanomesh thickness with an increase in synthesis time up to 24 h, indicative of successful exfoliation. The best catalyst (Co0.8Fe0.2(OH)x&#8208;24h) was developed after 24 h of synthesis, having 3.8 nm ink&#8208;bottle&#8208;shaped pores on the basal plane of nanosheets with only 3&#8208;4 layers. Co0.8Fe0.2(OH)x&#8208;24h exhibited the best catalytic performance, characterized by a 330 mV overpotential, a mass activity of 309.1 A/g, and a turnover frequency of 2.28 s&#8208;1. An increased electrochemical surface area (70.74 cm&#178;) and a high roughness factor of approximately 1010 underlined the importance of narrow mesopores in facilitating catalyst&#8208;electrolyte interactions and improving mass transport.</description>
      <author>Amit Paul, Shashank Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Active Mesoporous MgIn2O4/gCN Electrocatalyst Fabricated via Hydrothermal Route for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10904-024-03475-9</link>
      <description>Arooj Fatima, Sarah A. Alsalhi, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Abhinav Kumar, Journal of Inorganic and Organometallic Polymers and Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404139855

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arooj Fatima, Sarah A. Alsalhi, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Abhinav Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10904-024-03475-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Synergistic Effects on the Stability and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Efficiency of the Mesoporous LiMn&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; (M = Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, and Cu) Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03885</link>
      <description>Irmak Karakaya Durukan, &#214;mer Dag, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404147954

                Stable porous manganese oxide-based electrodes are essential for clean energy generation and storage because of their high natural abundance and health safety. This investigation focuses on mesoporous LiMn2&#8211;xMxO4 (where M is Fe, Co, Ni, and Cu and x is 0, 0.1, 0.3, 0.5, and 0.67) electrodes and thin/thick films. The mesoporous electrodes and films are fabricated by coating clear and homogeneous ethanol solutions of the salts (LiNO3, [Mn(OH2)4](NO3)2, and [M(OH2)x](NO3)2) and surfactants (P123 and CTAB) and calcining at elevated temperature (denoted as F-LiMn2&#8211;xMxO4, G-LiMn2&#8211;xMxO4, and meso-LiMn2&#8211;xMxO4, respectively). The electrochemical properties, stability, and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of the F/G-LiMn2&#8211;xMxO4 electrodes are investigated in alkaline media using a three electrode setup. The F-LiMn1.33M0.67O4 electrodes (where M is Mn, Fe, Co, and Ni) exhibit low Tafel slopes of 60, 43, 44, and 32 mV/dec, respectively. While all the Mn-rich and F-LiMn2&#8211;xFexO4 electrodes degrade via Mn(VI) disproportionation reaction, the 33% Co electrode shows high stability during the OER. The nickel-based electrodes are stable with as little as 15% Ni and display excellent OER performance over 25% Ni, albeit undergoing a transformation that accumulates Ni(OH)2 species on the electrode surface. Copper in the F-LiMn2&#8211;xCuxO4 electrodes is homogeneous at low Cu percentages but forms a CuO phase above 15% Cu, undergoes degradation, and displays a weak OER performance. In short, Co and Ni stabilize the F-LiMn1.33Co0.67O4 and F-LiMn1.7Ni0.3O4 electrodes, which display excellent OER performance.</description>
      <author>Irmak Karakaya Durukan, &#214;mer Dag</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03885</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkaline oxygen evolution reaction on activated industrial Ni-Fe alloys</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4404165935</link>
      <description>Lucile Magnier, Garance Cossard, Val&#233;rie Parry, &#201;ric Sibert, Marian Chatenet, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404165935

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lucile Magnier, Garance Cossard, Val&#233;rie Parry, &#201;ric Sibert, Marian Chatenet</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4404165935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-Doped Spinel Nickel-Iron Oxide Nanoflowers for Remarkably Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177292</link>
      <description>Jing Mei, Xiaohong Cheng, Qi Wu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404167826

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Mei, Xiaohong Cheng, Qi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing the oxygen evolution reaction pathway on iron-oxy-hydroxide through electro-kinetic study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115124</link>
      <description>Mrinal Kanti Adak, Hirak Kumar Basak, Biswarup Chakraborty, Catalysis Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404171594

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mrinal Kanti Adak, Hirak Kumar Basak, Biswarup Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.115124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru Doped in Phosphides Derived from Prussian Blue Analogues to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5014675</link>
      <description>Xianxu Chu, Ting Wang, Chuang Shen, Dongbin Yan, Xi Cheng, Yanli Zhou, Wei Ma, Xuelin Dong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404175165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianxu Chu, Ting Wang, Chuang Shen, Dongbin Yan, Xi Cheng, Yanli Zhou, Wei Ma, Xuelin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5014675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of oxygen-rich vacancy Bi3O4Br: Yb3+, Er3+ nanosheet for enhanced Photoreversible color switching and upconversion luminescence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03981e</link>
      <description>Xueting Zhao, Junhao Ma, Jiawei Zha, Kuan&#8208;Chieh Huang, Changchun Chai, Zhaoyi Yin, Zhiguo Song, Jianbei Qiu, Yongjin Li, Journal of Materials Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404187487

                Traditional inorganic photoreversible color-switching materials (PCSMs) usually exhibit slow color switching and single color switching characteristics, which severely restrict their use in information storage, anti-counterfeiting, and other applications. Herein, we...</description>
      <author>Xueting Zhao, Junhao Ma, Jiawei Zha, Kuan&#8208;Chieh Huang, Changchun Chai, Zhaoyi Yin, Zhiguo Song, Jianbei Qiu, Yongjin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03981e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dodecylamine&#8208;assisted hydrothermal synthesis of carbon&#8208;supported ultrafine IrRu Nanoparticles for oxygen evolution electrocatalysis and overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401446</link>
      <description>Lan Huang, Mengyuan Ma, Hui Liu, Dong Chen, Lin Xu, Shaonan Tian, Mei Yan, Jun Yang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404190308

                Ruthenium (Ru)&#8208; and iridium (Ir)&#8208;based nanomaterials have always been regarded as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic electrolytes. Herein, we develop a facile dodecylamine&#8208;assisted hydrothermal synthesis for producing carbon&#8208;supported IrRu alloy nanoparticles with controllable Ir/Ru ratios and ultrafine sizes towards high&#8208;efficiency OER and overall water electrolysis. In this strategy, the dodecylamine that serves as a capping and reducing agent enables the final IrRu alloy nanoparticles to possess average sizes &lt; 3 nm and high degree of dispersion on carbon substrate. By combining high OER activity of Ru with high acidic robustness of Ir, the as&#8208;prepared IrRu/C nanoparticles at a suitable Ir/Ru ratio of 1/3 show good activity and durability for the OER electrocatalysis and overall water splitting. In specific, the Ir1Ru3/C catalyst exhibits the lowest overpotential of 302 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and the highest mass activity of 120.5 mA mg&#8208;1 at 1.532 V for OER in 0.5 M H2SO4 electrolyte. In addition, a two&#8208;electrode acidic electrolyzer assembled with Ir1Ru3/C at anode and commercial Pt/C at cathode (Pt/C|| Ir1Ru3/C) exhibits a low cell voltage of 1.44 V for achieving the current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2, along with a satisfied 20&#8208;h durability.</description>
      <author>Lan Huang, Mengyuan Ma, Hui Liu, Dong Chen, Lin Xu, Shaonan Tian, Mei Yan, Jun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D ordered RuO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/WO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; heterostructure inverse opal arrays for highly-active and stable acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/nre.2024.9120141</link>
      <description>Runlong Jia, Yan Tan, Aoshuang Li, Yijie Wang, Chuanwei Cheng, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404194983

                Development of highly active and stable acidic oxygen evolution reaction catalyst is very important for efficient water splitting while remains challenging. Herein, we report a highly ordered RuO2/WO3 inverse opals (IOs) catalyst to address the bottleneck problem of see-saw relationship between activity and stability, in which the crystalline and corrosionresistant WO3 facilitates electron transport and stabilizes RuO2, whereas the lattice mismatch-induced amorphousdominated RuO2 provides abundant unsaturated coordination sites to enhance the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. Consequently, the RuO2/WO3 IOs demonstrates outstanding acidic OER performance in terms of a low overpotential of 180 mV to reach 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2, and excellent stability for maintaining 100 hours continuous test. Experimental characterizations and density functional theory calculations reveal that interface coupling between WO3 and RuO2 can enhance the spin polarization of electrons and increase the overlaps of the electronic projected density of states between the Ru d orbitals of active metal and the O p orbitals of oxygen intermediates, facilitating OER pathway to switch from lattice oxygen mechanism to adsorbate evolution mechanism, which significantly decreases the reaction energy barrier of OER process. Meanwhile, the rich oxygen vacancies and WO3 supports in the heterostructures could inhibit the over-oxidation of Ru species, so as to enhance the activity and stability simultaneously.</description>
      <author>Runlong Jia, Yan Tan, Aoshuang Li, Yijie Wang, Chuanwei Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/nre.2024.9120141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Co-Ni3B/GDY heterostructured electrocatalyst for boosting oxygen evolution in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177401</link>
      <description>Fuxiang Jing, Shixin Zhang, Honglei Shao, Shusheng Zhang, Pengfei Shi, Zhaomei Sun, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404195796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuxiang Jing, Shixin Zhang, Honglei Shao, Shusheng Zhang, Pengfei Shi, Zhaomei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous electrocatalyst of nanoscale Fe-based medium-entropy alloy and sulfide for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.034</link>
      <description>Yuxuan Shao, Junjie Ni, Jie Yin, Xinqing Liu, Yulai Song, Yue Xu, Shuai Guo, Laima Luo, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404197487

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxuan Shao, Junjie Ni, Jie Yin, Xinqing Liu, Yulai Song, Yue Xu, Shuai Guo, Laima Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on the development of perovskite based bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen electrodes in metal-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113189</link>
      <description>Shahar Yar Khan, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Naseem Iqbal, Zeeshan Ali, Materials Research Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404197542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shahar Yar Khan, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Naseem Iqbal, Zeeshan Ali</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.113189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron&#8208;Penetrating in Heterointerface Engineering for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416551</link>
      <description>Wangyang Li, J. K. Jiao, Jun Wei, Xiaobing Wang, Yong Zhao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404200223

                Abstract The interfacial electric field ( IEF ) between heterogeneous units plays an important role in the electronic modulation of active centers during oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the weak electronic coupling between spatially separated IEF s limits the deep activation of metal sites on the surface of the catalyst. Herein, a proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept strategy is provided that imbed MS 2 (M = Ni 3 Fe) species with high spin Fe orbits into heterogeneous units to promote the electron penetrating between IEF s. By designing a Fe 2 O 3 @MS/MS 2 @MO y model catalyst, the electronic interaction between adjacent IEF s is effectively enhanced for the deep oxidation of bimetals on the surface, breaking the competing relationship between adsorbed evolution mechanism (AEM) and lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) of catalysts during OER. As a result, the onset overpotential of the synthesized electrode is only 171 mV, and it maintains excellent stability for more than 2300 h at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl electrolyte.</description>
      <author>Wangyang Li, J. K. Jiao, Jun Wei, Xiaobing Wang, Yong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416551</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic oxygen evolution reaction activity and stability enhancement of IrOx electrocatalysts by microwave irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161758</link>
      <description>Swapnil S. Karade, Raghunandan Sharma, P. Morgen, Rebecca K. Pittkowski, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Shuang Ma Andersen, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404201291

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Swapnil S. Karade, Raghunandan Sharma, P. Morgen, Rebecca K. Pittkowski, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Shuang Ma Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring of Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of 2D Conductive Co-Catecholate Metal-Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145343</link>
      <description>T Priyadharshini, M. Lakshmi Narayana, N. K. Murugasenapathi, Tamilarasan Palanisamy, A.V. Ravindra, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404201865

                No abstract</description>
      <author>T Priyadharshini, M. Lakshmi Narayana, N. K. Murugasenapathi, Tamilarasan Palanisamy, A.V. Ravindra</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Construction of oxygen-rich vacancy Bi3O4Br: Yb3+, Er3+ nanosheet for enhanced Photoreversible color switching and upconversion luminescence"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03981e/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404203287

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03981e/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Construction of oxygen-rich vacancy Bi3O4Br: Yb3+, Er3+ nanosheet for enhanced Photoreversible color switching and upconversion luminescence"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03981e/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404203455

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03981e/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Construction of oxygen-rich vacancy Bi3O4Br: Yb3+, Er3+ nanosheet for enhanced Photoreversible color switching and upconversion luminescence"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03981e/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404203462

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03981e/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Au decorated Ni(OH)2 nanostructures: the role of alkaline cations solvation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124804</link>
      <description>Lucas D. Germano, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Antonio G. S. de Oliveira&#8208;Filho, Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404205963

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lucas D. Germano, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Antonio G. S. de Oliveira&#8208;Filho, Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Large-scale Integrated Non-Precious Metal Electrodes for Efficient and Stable Oxygen Evolution Reaction at High Current Density in 2.5 kW Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124811</link>
      <description>Yujie Liu, Qi Song, Tongguang Xu, Qian Kong, Gang He, Haixiao Sun, Huatong Li, Zhaoshuo Yuan, X.-T. Ma, Xiangyu Su, Xiangjun Dai, Qiu Gen Zhang, Zhenxing Li, YueChang Wei, Xin Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404210119

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Liu, Qi Song, Tongguang Xu, Qian Kong, Gang He, Haixiao Sun, Huatong Li, Zhaoshuo Yuan, X.-T. Ma, Xiangyu Su, Xiangjun Dai, Qiu Gen Zhang, Zhenxing Li, YueChang Wei, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically assisted preparation of defect-rich Co3O4 electrocatalysts in a water-modified deep eutectic solvent for enhanced oxygen evolution in acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161761</link>
      <description>X. Shi, Rongrong Deng, Qibo Zhang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404211767

                No abstract</description>
      <author>X. Shi, Rongrong Deng, Qibo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic hydrogen bubble template electrodeposition of a self-supported Co-P electrocatalyst for efficient alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118793</link>
      <description>Yunhao Zhang, Yanxin Qiao, Yihui Wu, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404212256

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunhao Zhang, Yanxin Qiao, Yihui Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-selenization formed NiFe MOF@NiSex heterogeneous arrays for enhanced oxygen evolution and methanol electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118789</link>
      <description>Weiguang Hu, Qing Yan, Sainan Ma, Ruiqin Gao, Qin Wang, Weiyong Yuan, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404212281

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiguang Hu, Qing Yan, Sainan Ma, Ruiqin Gao, Qin Wang, Weiyong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3d-orbital overlap modulated d-band center of high-entropy oxyhydroxide for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161760</link>
      <description>Shaobing Tang, Shuang Wei, Yujun Wu, Zhichao Jia, Zhengyu Bai, Lin Yang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404212825

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaobing Tang, Shuang Wei, Yujun Wu, Zhichao Jia, Zhengyu Bai, Lin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution on Flexible Catalysts Based on Nickel-Iron Coatings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202411.0517.v1</link>
      <description>Dmytro Shyshkin, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Dijana &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Zita Sukackien&#279;, J&#363;rat&#279; Vai&#269;i&#363;nien&#279;, Birut&#279; &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;-Stanynien&#279;, Antanas Nacys, Eugenijus Norkus, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404216623

                Electrolysis of water is one of low-cost green hydrogen production technologies. The challenge is designing and developing low-cost and high-activity catalysts. Herein, we present a strategy to fabricate flexible electrocatalysts based on nickel-iron (NiFe) alloy coatings. NiFe coatings were plated on the flexible copper-coated polyimide surface (Cu/PI) using the low-cost and straightforward electroless metal plating method and morpholine borane as a reducing agent. It was found that Ni90Fe10, Ni80Fe20, Ni60Fe40, and Ni30Fe70 coatings were deposited on the Cu/PI surface, then the concentration of Fe2+ in the plating solution was 0.5 mM, 1 mM, 5 mM, and 10 mM, respectively. Morphology, structure, and composition of NixFey/Cu/PI catalysts have been examined using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and inductively coupled plasma optical emission spectroscopy (ICP-OES), whereas their activity has been investigated for hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions in 1 M KOH using linear sweep voltammetry (LSVs). It was found that the Ni80Fe20/Cu/PI catalyst exhibited the lowest overpotential value of &#8211;202.7 mV for the HER to obtain a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 compared to Ni90Fe10/Cu/PI (&#8211;211.9 mV), Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI (&#8211;276.3 mV), Ni30Fe70/Cu/PI (&#8211;278.4 mV), and Ni (&#8722;303.4 mV). On the other hand, the lowest OER overpotential (344.7 mV) was observed for the Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI catalyst to obtain a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 as compared with the Ni30Fe70 (369.9 mV), Ni80Fe20 (450.2 mV), Ni90Fe10 (454.2 mV) coatings, and Ni (532.1 mV). The developed Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI catalyst exhibit a cell potential of 1.85 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The obtained catalysts seem to be suitable flexible catalysts for HER and OER in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Dmytro Shyshkin, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Dijana &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Zita Sukackien&#279;, J&#363;rat&#279; Vai&#269;i&#363;nien&#279;, Birut&#279; &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;-Stanynien&#279;, Antanas Nacys, Eugenijus Norkus</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202411.0517.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Catalyst Performance for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction under a Chiral Bias</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04477</link>
      <description>Aravind Vadakkayil, Wiley A. Dunlap-Shohl, Meera Joy, Brian P. Bloom, David H. Waldeck, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404220015

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aravind Vadakkayil, Wiley A. Dunlap-Shohl, Meera Joy, Brian P. Bloom, David H. Waldeck</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir nanoparticles anchored on nickel metal-organic framework for efficient hydrogen and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.027</link>
      <description>Xiangting Wang, Dan Wu, Hongli L. Zhu, Man Zhang, Jie Yang, Tuoping Hu, Jingjing Jiao, X. Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404221616

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangting Wang, Dan Wu, Hongli L. Zhu, Man Zhang, Jie Yang, Tuoping Hu, Jingjing Jiao, X. Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Bifunctionality for Overall Water Splitting by Integrating H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Spillover and Oxygen Vacancies in CoPBO/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Composite Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400343</link>
      <description>Rinkoo Bhabal, Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, R. Fernandes, N. Patel, Small Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404222028

                In the pursuit of utilizing renewable energy sources for green hydrogen (H 2 ) production, alkaline water electrolysis has emerged as a key technology. To improve the reaction rates of overall water electrolysis and simplify electrode manufacturing, development of bifunctional electrocatalysts is of great relevance. Herein, CoPBO/Co 3 O 4 is reported as a binary composite catalyst comprising amorphous (CoPBO) and crystalline (Co 3 O 4 ) phases as a high&#8208;performing bifunctional electrocatalyst for alkaline water electrolysis. Owing to the peculiar properties of CoPBO and Co 3 O 4 , such as complementing Gibbs free energy values for H&#8208;adsorption (&#916; G H ) and relatively smaller difference in their work functions (&#916;&#934;), the composite exhibits H 2 spillover (HS) mechanism to facilitate the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The outcome is manifested in the form of a low HER overpotential of 65 mV (at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Moreover, an abundant amount of surface oxygen vacancies (O v ) are observed in the same CoPBO/Co 3 O 4 composite that facilitates oxygen evolution reaction (OER) as well, leading to a mere 270 mV OER overpotential (at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ). The present work showcases the possibilities to strategically design non&#8208;noble composite catalysts that combine the advantages of HS phenomenon as well as O v to achieve new record performances in alkaline water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Rinkoo Bhabal, Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, R. Fernandes, N. Patel</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Accelerated Surface Reconstruction of CoSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoneedle Forms Active CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@CoOOH Interface to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403744</link>
      <description>Quanxin Guo, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhengrong Xu, Rui Liu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404222203

                Abstract Interface engineering is an efficient strategy to create high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for water splitting. In the present work, CeO 2 @CoSe 2 nanoneedle on carbon cloth (CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC) demonstrates high efficiency for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and water splitting. CeO 2 with abundant O vacancies facilitates the adsorption of OH &#8722; and boosts the reconstruction of CoSe 2 into CoOOH at lower potentials. The in situ generated active CeO 2 @CoOOH heterointerface upshifts the d&#8208;band center of Co site, thereby decreasing the free energy of rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) ( * O to * OOH) during the OER process. It delivers a low OER overpotential of 245 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC is also found to be active for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER, 138 mV overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), profiting from CeO 2 &#8208;facilitated * H 2 O dissociation and * H adsorption on CoSe 2 . The overall water splitting is achieved over the CeO 2 @CoSe 2 /CC bifunctional electrode with a low electrolysis voltage of 1.54 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work offers valuable insights into CeO 2 &#8208;assisted surface reconstruction as well as provides water electrolysis catalysts through interface engineering.</description>
      <author>Quanxin Guo, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Zhengrong Xu, Rui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafine CoFe Alloy Nanoparticles Confined in Highly Ordered Mesoporous Carbon Films as Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04249</link>
      <description>Yi Hua Zhou, Yanna Guo, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yoshiyuki Sugahara, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404228166

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yi Hua Zhou, Yanna Guo, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yoshiyuki Sugahara</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Interplay between Fe&#8208;based Perovskite Oxides and Co in Electrolyte for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401982</link>
      <description>Yuta Inoue, Yuto Miyahara, Kohei Miyazaki, Changhee Lee, Ryo Sakamoto, Takeshi Abe, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404228579

                Perovskite oxides have been extensively investigated as active electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline solution. While the OER activity of some perovskite oxides is positively influenced by Fe ions in the electrolyte, the impact of other transition metal ions in the electrolyte remains unclear. In this study, we compared the influence of Co ions intentionally added to the electrolyte on the OER activities of two Fe&#8208;based perovskite oxides (Ba0.5Sr0.5FeO3&#8722;&#948; and LaFeO3). While the OER activity of Ba0.5Sr0.5FeO3&#8722;&#948; is significantly enhanced by adding Co ions to the electrolyte, LaFeO3 showed little difference in the OER behavior between the Co&#8208;free and Co&#8208;containing electrolytes. In the case of Ba0.5Sr0.5FeO3&#8722;&#948;, an amorphous layer was formed, and the Co ions from the electrolyte were incorporated on the surface as a result of OER cycling. On the other hand, Co ions were also detected on the surface of LaFeO3, but its crystalline structure remains unchanged during the OER. Our study suggests that synergistic interplay between the perovskite oxides undergoing a structural transformation at the surface and transition metal ions in the electrolyte can improve the OER activity.</description>
      <author>Yuta Inoue, Yuto Miyahara, Kohei Miyazaki, Changhee Lee, Ryo Sakamoto, Takeshi Abe</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401982</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of precatalyst conversion and iron incorporation in nickel-based alkaline oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102284</link>
      <description>Miika Mattinen, Johanna Schr&#246;der, Giulio D&#8217;Acunto, Mikko Ritala, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Michaela Burke Stevens, Stacey F. Bent, Cell Reports Physical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404229159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miika Mattinen, Johanna Schr&#246;der, Giulio D&#8217;Acunto, Mikko Ritala, Thomas F. Jaramillo, Michaela Burke Stevens, Stacey F. Bent</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102284</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tm-N4 Doped in 4,6,8-Biphenylene as an Efficient Trifunctional Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Reduction Reaction, Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5017109</link>
      <description>Feng Chen, Xinhui Zhang, Baonan Jia, Chunling Zhang, Ge Wu, Yazhao Yuan, Yirong Ma, Yuanzi Li, Jinkang Yu, Xiaoning Guan, Jinbo Hao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404231197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Chen, Xinhui Zhang, Baonan Jia, Chunling Zhang, Ge Wu, Yazhao Yuan, Yirong Ma, Yuanzi Li, Jinkang Yu, Xiaoning Guan, Jinbo Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5017109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-optimizing interface engineering with simultaneous activation of surface lattice oxygen for enhanced electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.095</link>
      <description>Taiyi Liu, Rui Xiao, Mengen Wang, Yingwei Li, Kang Wang, Baojun Ma, Wei Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 94(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404231320

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Taiyi Liu, Rui Xiao, Mengen Wang, Yingwei Li, Kang Wang, Baojun Ma, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Recent advance in Mn-based Li-rich cathode materials: Oxygen release mechanism and its solution strategies based on electronic structure perspective, spanning from commercial liquid batteries to all-solid-state batteries&#8221; [Next Mater. 6 (2025) 100408]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100423</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Jiaxuan Yin, Haoran Li, Tiancheng Wang, Shengrui Cui, Wenchao Yan, Wei Ma, Yongcheng Jin, Next Materials. 6(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404231405

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Jiaxuan Yin, Haoran Li, Tiancheng Wang, Shengrui Cui, Wenchao Yan, Wei Ma, Yongcheng Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-defective ruthenium oxide as an efficient and durable electrocatalyst for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06592a</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Lejuan Cai, Zhipeng Yu, Hao Tan, Xinyi Xiang, Kaiyang Xu, Chao Yang, Sitaramanjaneya Mouli Thalluri, Fei Lin, Haoliang Huang, Chenyue Zhang, Yang Zhao, Wenlong Wang, Lifeng Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404233886

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) is considered a promising technology for green hydrogen production in combination with renewable energy. However, the high cost and particularly the scarcity of iridium...</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Lejuan Cai, Zhipeng Yu, Hao Tan, Xinyi Xiang, Kaiyang Xu, Chao Yang, Sitaramanjaneya Mouli Thalluri, Fei Lin, Haoliang Huang, Chenyue Zhang, Yang Zhao, Wenlong Wang, Lifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06592a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal-Induced Cationic Vacancies in NiAl Hydroxide for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Activities through Optimization of e&lt;sub&gt;g&lt;/sub&gt;* Band Broadening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14089</link>
      <description>Haoyan Meng, Junhua Li, Chao Wu, Qi Zhang, Li Wang, Ying Tang, Anqi Zou, Yiming Zhang, Rui Ma, Zhi Gen Yu, Feng Gao, Shibo Xi, Junmin Xue, Xiaopeng Wang, Jiagang Wu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404235787

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haoyan Meng, Junhua Li, Chao Wu, Qi Zhang, Li Wang, Ying Tang, Anqi Zou, Yiming Zhang, Rui Ma, Zhi Gen Yu, Feng Gao, Shibo Xi, Junmin Xue, Xiaopeng Wang, Jiagang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped Ni-Based Catalysts Surpass Ir-Baselines for Oxygen Evolution Due to Optimal Charge-Transfer Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</link>
      <description>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Engineering of Ruo2/Coooh Heterojunction for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5016770</link>
      <description>Ji-Sen Li, Xianjun Niu, Yin-Lei Ma, Jun-Ya Gao, Shumei Sun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404242056

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ji-Sen Li, Xianjun Niu, Yin-Lei Ma, Jun-Ya Gao, Shumei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5016770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactivity and Stability of Reduced Ir-Weight TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Oxygen Evolution Catalysts for Proton Exchange Membrane (PEM) Water Electrolyzer Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07002</link>
      <description>Hoang Phi Tran, Hong Nhan Nong, Matej Zlatar, Aram Yoon, Uta Hejral, Martina R&#252;scher, Janis Timoshenko, S&#246;ren Selve, Dirk Berger, Matthias Kroschel, Malte Klingenhof, Benjamin Paul, Sebastian M&#246;hle, Kerolus Nasser Nagi Nasralla, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Arno Bergmann, Serhiy Cherevko, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Peter Strasser, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404246558

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hoang Phi Tran, Hong Nhan Nong, Matej Zlatar, Aram Yoon, Uta Hejral, Martina R&#252;scher, Janis Timoshenko, S&#246;ren Selve, Dirk Berger, Matthias Kroschel, Malte Klingenhof, Benjamin Paul, Sebastian M&#246;hle, Kerolus Nasser Nagi Nasralla, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Arno Bergmann, Serhiy Cherevko, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Peter Strasser</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-organic framework-based self-supported electrodes for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.26</link>
      <description>Shulin Li, Dai Tang, Xiaofei Jing, Chemical Synthesis. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404249552

                Oxygen evolution reactions (OER), commonly employed in applications such as metal-air batteries, water electrolysis, fuel cells, etc. , often suffer from slow kinetics, thus leading to ultra-high potentials that severely affect device energy efficiency. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have garnered massive attention as electrodes for OER, benefiting from their highly ordered porous frameworks, abundant accessible active metal sites, and adjustable lattice structures. However, using powdered MOFs in OER poses a challenge, limiting the exposure of numerous active sites and resulting in suboptimal efficiency. To address this limitation, the trend towards designing MOF-based self-supported electrodes with enhanced contact between MOFs and the current collector has gained considerable attention for OER applications. This review highlights recent advancements and future prospects in developing MOF-based self-supported electrodes for OER. We delve into various aspects, including preparation methods, optimization strategies, catalytic efficiencies, and OER mechanisms with MOF-based electrocatalysts. Furthermore, we explore the existing challenges associated with MOF-based self-supported electrodes for OER. This comprehensive overview provides valuable insights into the evolving landscape of MOF-based materials in advancing OER.</description>
      <author>Shulin Li, Dai Tang, Xiaofei Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.26</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation Migration&#8208;Induced Lattice Oxygen Oxidation in Spinel Oxide for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416757</link>
      <description>Lydia Helena Wong, Mahmoud G. Ahmed, Ying Fan Tay, Xiao Chi, Ahmed S. Razeen, Yanan Fang, Mengyuan Zhang, Anqi Sng, Sing Yang Chiam, Andrivo Rusydi, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404251421

                Activating the lattice oxygen can significantly improve the kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), however, it often results in reduced stability due to the bulk structure degradation. Here, we develop a spinel Fe0.3Co0.9Cr1.8O4 with active lattice oxygen by high&#8208;throughput methods, achieving high OER activity and stability, superior to the benchmark IrO2. The oxide exhibits an ultralow overpotential (190 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2) with outstanding stability for over 170 h at 100 mA cm&#8211;2. Soft X&#8208;ray absorption&#8208; and Raman&#8208;spectroscopies, combined with 18O isotope&#8208;labelling experiments, reveal that lattice oxygen activation is driven by Cr oxidation, which induces a cation migration from CrO6 octahedrons to CrO4 tetrahedrons. The geometry conversion creates accessible non&#8208;bonding oxygen states, crucial for lattice oxygen oxidation. Upon oxidation, peroxo O&#8211;O bond is formed and further stabilized by Cr6+ (CrO4 tetrahedra) via dimerization. This work establishes a new approach for designing efficient catalysts that feature active and stable lattice oxygen without compromising structural integrity.</description>
      <author>Lydia Helena Wong, Mahmoud G. Ahmed, Ying Fan Tay, Xiao Chi, Ahmed S. Razeen, Yanan Fang, Mengyuan Zhang, Anqi Sng, Sing Yang Chiam, Andrivo Rusydi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation Migration&#8208;Induced Lattice Oxygen Oxidation in Spinel Oxide for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416757</link>
      <description>Lydia Helena Wong, Mahmoud G. Ahmed, Ying Fan Tay, Xiao Chi, Ahmed S. Razeen, Yanan Fang, Mengyuan Zhang, Anqi Sng, Sing Yang Chiam, Andrivo Rusydi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404251472

                Activating the lattice oxygen can significantly improve the kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), however, it often results in reduced stability due to the bulk structure degradation. Here, we develop a spinel Fe0.3Co0.9Cr1.8O4 with active lattice oxygen by high&#8208;throughput methods, achieving high OER activity and stability, superior to the benchmark IrO2. The oxide exhibits an ultralow overpotential (190 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2) with outstanding stability for over 170 h at 100 mA cm&#8211;2. Soft X&#8208;ray absorption&#8208; and Raman&#8208;spectroscopies, combined with 18O isotope&#8208;labelling experiments, reveal that lattice oxygen activation is driven by Cr oxidation, which induces a cation migration from CrO6 octahedrons to CrO4 tetrahedrons. The geometry conversion creates accessible non&#8208;bonding oxygen states, crucial for lattice oxygen oxidation. Upon oxidation, peroxo O&#8211;O bond is formed and further stabilized by Cr6+ (CrO4 tetrahedra) via dimerization. This work establishes a new approach for designing efficient catalysts that feature active and stable lattice oxygen without compromising structural integrity.</description>
      <author>Lydia Helena Wong, Mahmoud G. Ahmed, Ying Fan Tay, Xiao Chi, Ahmed S. Razeen, Yanan Fang, Mengyuan Zhang, Anqi Sng, Sing Yang Chiam, Andrivo Rusydi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cqds Modified Tio2/Sn-Fe2o3-X Heterojunction Photoanode with Abundant Oxygen Vacancies for Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5018120</link>
      <description>Na Dai, Yingjie Zhang, Zhiwei Peng, Ji&#8208;Kai Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404254074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Dai, Yingjie Zhang, Zhiwei Peng, Ji&#8208;Kai Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5018120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Hidden Catalytic Sites in 2D Basal Plane via p&#8211;n Heterojunction Interface Engineering Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403722</link>
      <description>Eugene Kim, Sungsoon Kim, Yong&#8208;Chul Kim, Kiran Hamkins, Jihyun Baek, MinJoong Kim, Tae&#8208;Kyung Liu, Young Moon Choi, Jung Hwan Lee, Gyu Yong Jang, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Geunsik Lee, Xiaolin Zheng, Jong Hyeok Park, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404255224

                Abstract Nonprecious metal&#8208;based 2D materials have shown promising electrocatalytic activity toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the catalytically active sites of 2D materials are mainly presented at the edge, and most of their basal planes are still catalytically inactive, which turns into a significant drawback on the catalytic efficiency. Here, a novel p&#8211;n heterojunction strategy is suggested that generates active sites on the basal plane of 2D NiFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH). The n&#8208;type NiFe&#8208;LDH is first grown on a nickel foam (NF) substrate, and p&#8208;type Co 3 O 4 nanocubes are deposited through a simple dip&#8208;coating method to fabricate a Co 3 O 4 /NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF p&#8211;n heterojunction electrode. As a result, electron transfer is induced at the interface of p&#8208;type Co 3 O 4 and n&#8208;type NiFe&#8208;LDH, which consequently promotes oxidation of the inert Ni 2+ state to a more catalytically active Ni 3+ state on the inert basal plane of NiFe&#8208;LDH. As&#8208;prepared Co 3 O 4 /NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF electrodes obtained enhanced OER performance showing a high current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.48 V (vs RHE) which outperforms that of pristine NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF. The utilization of the p&#8211;n junction concept will disclose a new strategy for modifying the electronic structure of the catalytically inactive basal plane and stimulating its electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Eugene Kim, Sungsoon Kim, Yong&#8208;Chul Kim, Kiran Hamkins, Jihyun Baek, MinJoong Kim, Tae&#8208;Kyung Liu, Young Moon Choi, Jung Hwan Lee, Gyu Yong Jang, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Geunsik Lee, Xiaolin Zheng, Jong Hyeok Park</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution activity by two-dimensional van der Waals AlSb/ZnO heterostructure: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105397</link>
      <description>Aroni Ghosh, Ahmed Zubair, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404258858

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aroni Ghosh, Ahmed Zubair</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directing the Electrode-Electrolyte Interface Towards Active
  Nickel-Based Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.16715</link>
      <description>Ben Wang, Tomohiro Fukushima, Hiro Minamimoto, Andrey Lyalin, Kei Murakoshi, Tetsuya Taketsugu, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404261170

                A comprehensive understanding of the electrode-electrolyte interface in energy conversion systems remains challenging due to the complex and multifaceted nature of interfacial processes. This complexity hinders the development of more efficient electrocatalysts. In this work, we propose a hybrid approach to the theoretical description of the OER process on nickel-iron-based oxyhydroxides ($\gamma$-Ni$_{1-x}$Fe$_x$OOH) electrodes in alkaline media as a model system. Multiple reaction pathways represented by the single- and dual-site mechanisms were investigated by taking into account the realistic structure of the catalyst, the doping, and the solvation effects using a simple and computationally feasible strategy. Accounting for the variable solvation effects considerably affects the predicted overpotential in a roughly linear relationship between overpotential and dielectric constant. By incorporating quantum chemical simulations with kinetic modeling, we demonstrate that tuning the local solvation environment can significantly enhance the OER activity, opening new routine ways for elucidation of the emerging issues of OER processes on transition metal oxide surfaces and design of cost-effective, efficient electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Ben Wang, Tomohiro Fukushima, Hiro Minamimoto, Andrey Lyalin, Kei Murakoshi, Tetsuya Taketsugu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.16715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Front Cover: Graphitic Carbon Nitride Structures on Carbon Cloth Containing Ultra&#8208; and Nano&#8208;Dispersed NiO for Photoactivated Oxygen Evolution (ChemSusChem 21/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202482101</link>
      <description>Enrico Scattolin, Mattia Benedet, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Oleg I. Lebedev, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato, ChemSusChem. 17(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404263367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enrico Scattolin, Mattia Benedet, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Oleg I. Lebedev, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202482101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Dihydroxyacetone Production via Photoelectrochemical Glycerol Oxidation using Oxygen Vacant BiVO4 Photoanode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04085f</link>
      <description>Yeji Lee, Yeseul Jo, Youn Jeong Jang, Journal of Materials Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404271363

                Photoelectrochemical conversion of glycerol into high-value dihydroxyacetone offers a sustainable approach via BiVO4 semiconductor materials, which manifest highly photoactive properties. However, dihydroxyacetone production poses a limitation due to poor charge...</description>
      <author>Yeji Lee, Yeseul Jo, Youn Jeong Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04085f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active Oxygen Evolution Reaction of NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Sub&#8208;1 nm Nanowires Boosts Luminol Electrochemiluminescence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407321</link>
      <description>Hao Zang, Dong Mei Wang, Wen Dai, Lin Chen, Yi&#8208;Ting Wang, Qiang Wang, Li Wang, Gao Chen, Jia Li, Jia Xie, Hong Yan Zou, Cheng Huang, Yuan Fang Li, Shu Jun Zhen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404275027

                Abstract In recent years, there has been an increasing research focus on the luminol&#8211;H 2 O electrochemiluminescence (ECL) system due to its ability to address the instability and toxicity of H 2 O 2 , which are common issues associated with the conventional luminol&#8211;H 2 O 2 ECL system. To enhance the ECL efficiency of the luminol&#8211;H 2 O system, researchers have developed electrocatalytic materials with exceptional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) properties to facilitate water electrolysis into O 2 to produce reactive oxygen species (ROS) and act as co&#8208;reactant promoters. However, most of these materials are characterized by their nanoscale or microscale dimensions, resulting in relatively large sizes and low specific surface areas, which hinder the application of the luminol&#8211;H 2 O system. To address this challenge, nickel molybdate sub&#8208;1 nm nanowires (NiMoO 4 S1 NWs) with a large specific surface area is synthesized that can offer many active sites to enhance the performance of the OER to boost the ECL of luminol. This study demonstrates that the large amount of ROS generated by the OER of NiMoO 4 S1 NWs play a crucial role in enhancing the ECL intensity of luminol. Finally, a NiMoO 4 S1 NWs&#8208;based ECL biosensor for the highly sensitive detection of the nucleocapsid proteins of SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 is successfully constructed.</description>
      <author>Hao Zang, Dong Mei Wang, Wen Dai, Lin Chen, Yi&#8208;Ting Wang, Qiang Wang, Li Wang, Gao Chen, Jia Li, Jia Xie, Hong Yan Zou, Cheng Huang, Yuan Fang Li, Shu Jun Zhen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-Driven Coordinated Oxygen Migration in an Electrocatalyst for Sustainable H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11307</link>
      <description>Zhiping Deng, Song Jin, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Min Ho Seo, Xiaolei Wang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404276344

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiping Deng, Song Jin, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Min Ho Seo, Xiaolei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Scalable Synthesis of N&#8211;Doped Graphene&#8211;Oxide&#8211;Supported FeCo(OH)x Nanosheets for Efficient Co&#8211;Doped Fe3O4 Nanoparticle-Based Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06684g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404286406

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06684g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Scalable Synthesis of N&#8211;Doped Graphene&#8211;Oxide&#8211;Supported FeCo(OH)x Nanosheets for Efficient Co&#8211;Doped Fe3O4 Nanoparticle-Based Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06684g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404286856

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06684g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical behaviour of WO3 and Se-WO3 films modified with cobalt-based oxygen evolving catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2017.28.2.2</link>
      <description>Simona Ostachavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Agn&#279; &#352;ul&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Eugenijus Valatka, Chemija. 28(2)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4404244929

                Thin &#64257;lms of bare and Se-containing tungsten trioxide (WO3) on AISI304 stainless steel were prepared by electrochemical deposition using peroxy-tungstate solutions. Cobalt-phosphate catalyst was photochemically deposited onto the surface of semiconductor particles in order to enhance their activity towards the oxygen evolution reaction. The photoelectrochemical properties of as-prepared electrodes were investigated in neutral 0.1 M phosphate buffer solutions. The voltammetric characteristics revealed that the presence of cobalt-based catalyst effectively changes the photoelectrocatalytic activity of WO3 and Se-WO3 particles.</description>
      <author>Simona Ostachavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Agn&#279; &#352;ul&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Eugenijus Valatka</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2017.28.2.2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy nitrides from dual entropic and enthalpic forces for high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2024.130</link>
      <description>Jingyun Jiang, Yifan Xu, Zheng Wang, Hongbo Zhang, Qun Xu, Yuan&#8208;Jian Li, Energy Materials. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404170823

                The development of high-entropy materials as active and durable catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction is important but challenging for hydrogen production from water electrolysis. In contrast to conventional synthesis strategies that usually involve high-temperature annealing, a novel poly(ethylene glycol)-barbituric acid deep eutectic solvent-assisted strategy was developed in this work to successfully synthesize high-entropy nitrides (HENs) (FeCoNiCuZn)N at a record low temperature of 473 K. Multiple analytical characterizations illustrate that dual entropic and enthalpic forces provided by the poly(ethylene glycol)-barbituric acid deep eutectic solvent play a critical role in the low-temperature synthesis of HENs. The prepared HENs have a microsphere structure consisting of five highly dispersed active metal (Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, and Zn) species, which are conducive to boosting oxygen evolution reaction performance in alkaline media, in terms of a low overpotential of 223 mV at 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; and sustained durability over 30 hours at 400 mA cm&#8315;&#178;. This work paves the way for the fabrication of high-entropy materials with excellent electrocatalytic properties for future energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Jingyun Jiang, Yifan Xu, Zheng Wang, Hongbo Zhang, Qun Xu, Yuan&#8208;Jian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2024.130</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo2B2O2-supported Cu and Ni heterogeneous dual atom catalysts for oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113505</link>
      <description>Erpeng Wang, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun, Computational Materials Science. 247(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404129222

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Erpeng Wang, Jian Zhou, Zhimei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.commatsci.2024.113505</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the superwetting FeOOH-modified NiMoO4 electrodes for efficient alkaline oxygen evolution reaction: An in-situ spectroscopy study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124814</link>
      <description>Hongru Hao, Jiahui Wang, Zhe Wang, Shuo Shen, Lingling Xu, Zhe Lv, Bo Wei, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. 363(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404281349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongru Hao, Jiahui Wang, Zhe Wang, Shuo Shen, Lingling Xu, Zhe Lv, Bo Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A general machine-learning framework for high-throughput screening for stable and efficient RuO2-based acidic oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5347326/v1</link>
      <description>Zhe Shang, Qian Dang, Sheng Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404257326

                Abstract Doping guest elements is an effective way to increase activity and stability of RuO2 catalysts in acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, due to the vastness of doping space, it is challenging for either high-cost experiments or density functional theory (DFT) calculations to screen out the doped structures with the optimized catalytic performance. Herein, we reported a machine-learning (ML) framework that aims to realize high-throughput screening for both stability and activity of doped-RuO2 acidic OER catalysts from mono-doping to triple-doping at a low level of computational cost. Compared to the d-band theory and some other previous models, our ML model was constructed based on more general input features and realized higher prediction accuracy with mean absolute errors (MAEs) of 0.074, 0.142 and 0.082 eV for *OH, *O and *OOH adsorption, respectively. Through the ML models, three doping structures, Ru41Zn7O96, Ru41Zn4Fe3O96, and Ru39Zn4Cu4Co1O96 were found to possess the extraordinarily high stability and comparable or higher activity than the previously reported OER catalysts. This work provided an efficient study paradigm in fields of material screening and a useful guide for experimental synthesis.</description>
      <author>Zhe Shang, Qian Dang, Sheng Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5347326/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox-Mediated Oxygen Evolution Mechanism in Atomically Dispersed Pt-Supported NiO: Defying the Hydroxyl-Mediated Mechanism of NiO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01920</link>
      <description>Jatin Nama, Sudhanshu Sharma, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237909

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jatin Nama, Sudhanshu Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01920</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling Efficient Oxygen Evolution via Anchoring Carbon-Layer-Confined RuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; on a Well-Matched Substrate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03507</link>
      <description>Liming Zeng, Biao Yuan, Qing Zhou, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404099969

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a multistep proton-coupled four-electron process with sluggish kinetics, which seriously limits the hydrogen production efficiency, thus it is of great importance to develop an efficient and stable OER catalyst. In this study, a two-step differential pyrolysis strategy is employed to design a three-dimensional porous microstructured material consisting of RuOx nanoparticles coated by a thin-layer carbon, where the active particles were isolated in separate chambers and the RuOx nanoparticles mainly existed in the form of a heterogeneous interface between RuO2 and partial metallic Ru. The preparation parameters of the catalysts are optimized via combining transient and steady-state polarization properties, and the target catalyst Cat-500&#8211;1.5t shows the best OER catalytic performance after ca. 60 h of a chronopotentiometry test in an acidic medium with a much smaller performance change than other samples. The unique design of adopting a carbon layer to form separate reaction chambers largely mitigates the excessive oxidation loss of the active components under strong oxidation potential. The suitability of the catalyst with the loaded substrate and test media is explored, and in an acidic medium, the carbon paper is much better than the titanium fiber, while in an alkaline medium, the titanium fiber is obviously superior to the carbon paper. On both carbon paper and titanium fiber, the performance in an alkaline medium outperforms that in an acidic medium, and the possible reasons for the performance difference are analyzed. Herein, to obtain the actual electrocatalytic performance, the optimal design of the catalyst structure and matching suitable conductive substrate in a specific medium are quite necessary, which provides a feasible strategy for the acquisition of efficient and stable electrocatalysts and the desirable presentation of performance.</description>
      <author>Liming Zeng, Biao Yuan, Qing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03507</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel CoCuNi-sulfide nanocatalyst derived from trimetallic zeolitic imidazolate framework for boosting oxygen evolution reaction performance: Comparison study of sulfides and oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102398</link>
      <description>Zahra Bairami, Ali Akbar Asgharinezhad, J.M. Courtney, Afsanehsadat Larimi, Farhad Khorasheh, Materials Today Chemistry. 42(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404201952

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahra Bairami, Ali Akbar Asgharinezhad, J.M. Courtney, Afsanehsadat Larimi, Farhad Khorasheh</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bamboo&#8208;Like Carbon Nanotube&#8208;Encapsulated Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C Nanoparticles Activate Confined Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoclusters Via d&#8208;p&#8208;d Orbital Coupling for Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409325</link>
      <description>Zilong Chen, Wenxia Xu, Weizhou Wang, Zhe Wu, Hongdong Li, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404222014

                Abstract The efficient anion exchange membrane water electrolysis is challenging with low cell voltage and long&#8208;term stability at large current density, due to the unstable anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Fe&#8208;based electrocatalysts are potential candidates for the anodic OER. In Fe&#8208;based materials, iron oxides always show better stability in alkaline solution but lower OER activity. However, the catalysts in previous study are difficult to continuously and effectively activate iron oxides supported on carbon during electrocatalysis. Herein, a new class of electrocatalyst: bamboo&#8208;like carbon nanotubes (B&#8208;CNT)&#8208;encapsulated Fe 2 C nanoparticles (NPs) supported Fe 2 O 3 nanoclusters (NCs), named Fe 2 O 3 /B&#8208;CNT@Fe 2 C is reported. Theoretical calculations and experimental results reveal that B&#8208;CNT&#8208;encapsulate Fe 2 C NPs activate Fe 2 O 3 NCs by the d&#8208;p&#8208;d orbital coupling, thereby weakening the adsorption of OOH* intermediate during OER process. The electrolyzer based on the electrocatalyst requires only 1.48 V to reach 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 and shows a long&#8208;term stability at 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 for 1600 h, comparable to the best&#8208;reported values for the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE).</description>
      <author>Zilong Chen, Wenxia Xu, Weizhou Wang, Zhe Wu, Hongdong Li, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of efficient Pb(II) carboxylate catalysts for Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02958e</link>
      <description>Janak, Vijay S. Sapner, Bhaskar R. Sathe, Sadhika Khullar, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404195140

                The development of cost-effective and efficient electrocatalysts can solve the problem in the production of energy via water splitting reactions. In this work, we focused on two lead-based coordination polymers...</description>
      <author>Janak, Vijay S. Sapner, Bhaskar R. Sathe, Sadhika Khullar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02958e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A comparison of the effect of oxygen partial pressure on microstructural evolution of PAN fibers during industrial carbon fiber production line at different altitudes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2024.111082</link>
      <description>Hongqiang Zhu, Qiufei Chen, Hamza Malik, Yuhang Wang, Jian He, Bomou Ma, Xueli Wang, Hui Zhang, Yong Liu, Jianyong Yu, Polymer Degradation and Stability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404197366

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongqiang Zhu, Qiufei Chen, Hamza Malik, Yuhang Wang, Jian He, Bomou Ma, Xueli Wang, Hui Zhang, Yong Liu, Jianyong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.polymdegradstab.2024.111082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Coupling of CuNi Alloy with CoFe LDH Heterostructure on Nickel Foam toward High-Efficiency Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05681g</link>
      <description>Dan Wang, Yuan Chu, Youzheng Wu, Mengkang Zhu, Lin Pan, Ruopeng Li, Yukai Chen, Wenchang Wang, Naotoshi Mitsuzaki, Zhidong Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404122512

                Accelerating the kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is vital for high-efficiency green hydrogen production. However, developing cost-effective and highly active bifunctional catalysts for overall...</description>
      <author>Dan Wang, Yuan Chu, Youzheng Wu, Mengkang Zhu, Lin Pan, Ruopeng Li, Yukai Chen, Wenchang Wang, Naotoshi Mitsuzaki, Zhidong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05681g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incorporation of Graphene Quantum Dots into Magnesium Copper Phosphate (GQDs-MgCuPO4) for Supercapattery and Electrocatalysis Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1402-4896/ad9117</link>
      <description>Sara Albalwi, Ashwaq Al-Ojeery, Haseebul Hassan, Muhammad Waqas Iqbal, Amir Muhammad Afzal, K.A. Aly, Physica Scripta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404232302

                Abstract We efficiently synthesize magnesium copper phosphate nanoparticles (MgCuPO4) doped with graphene quantum dots (GQDs) using a hydrothermal method for supercapattery and oxygen evolution reactions in KOH electrolyte. The GQDs-MgCuPO4 electrode has a high specific capacity (1188 Cg-1 at 1.0 Ag-1) and a high-rate capability (67%). The symmetric supercapattery (GQDs-MgCuPO4/GQDs-MgCuPO4) provides a staggering energy density of 46 Wh-kg-1, as well as a high-power density of 1300 W-kg-1 and a high cyclic stability of 93% after 10,000 cycles. Furthermore, it demonstrates high efficiency in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), with corresponding low overpotentials of 181 mV and 119 mV. The GQDs-MgCuPO4 stands out as a capable solution for various energy storage and conversion difficulties.</description>
      <author>Sara Albalwi, Ashwaq Al-Ojeery, Haseebul Hassan, Muhammad Waqas Iqbal, Amir Muhammad Afzal, K.A. Aly</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1402-4896/ad9117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical FeCo LDH/NiSe heterostructure electrocatalysts with rich heterointerfaces for robust water splitting at industrial-level current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02426e</link>
      <description>Weiwei Han, Wenyi Wang, Jiahong Liao, Yi He, Xingwang Zhang, Chunlin Yu, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404119212

                Sustainable hydrogen production by electrocatalytic water splitting is a promising energy storage technology yet challenging due to the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Rationally designed robust and...</description>
      <author>Weiwei Han, Wenyi Wang, Jiahong Liao, Yi He, Xingwang Zhang, Chunlin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02426e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical ZnCoS@CoFe-layered double hydroxide on Ni foam to enhance the OER performance for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03986f</link>
      <description>Tianyun Li, Zhongxiao Chen, Chunping Dong, Dan Wang, Wenchang Wang, Xueling Shan, Zhidong Chen, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404282029

                For sustainable energy generation technologies, improving the slow kinetics of the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential. In this study, a three-step hydrothermal-sulfidation-electrodeposition method was developed to prepare a...</description>
      <author>Tianyun Li, Zhongxiao Chen, Chunping Dong, Dan Wang, Wenchang Wang, Xueling Shan, Zhidong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03986f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Anodic Transition and Cathodic Contamination Affect the Overall Voltage of Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225298</link>
      <description>Zheng Liu, Z Liu, Lingxing Zan, Yu Sun, Huizhen Han, Yiran Li, Han Wang, Ting Cao, Yao Zhu, Haiyang Lv, Yuxuan Liu, Juzhe Liu, Xin Bo, Molecules. 29(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404229425

                NiFe (oxy)hydroxide has been widely used as a benchmark anodic catalyst for oxygen evolution reactions (OERs) in alkaline water electrolysis devices; however, the energy saving actually takes contributions from both the anodic OER and cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). In this work, we observe the catalytic promotion upon the in situ-derived NiFe (oxy)hydroxide from the NiFe alloy monolithic electrode and also point out that the coupled nickel cathode is contaminated, leading to the loss of HER activity and a reduction in overall efficiency. It is found that Ni2+ and Fe3+ cations are inevitably detached from the anode into the electrolyte and electrodeposited on the nickel cathode after the three-month industrial simulation. This research presents the significant enhancement of the oxygen evolution catalysis using an in situ aging process and emphasizes that the catalytic application should not only be isolated on the half reaction, but a reasonable coupled electrode match to get rid of the contamination from the electrolyte is also of great significance to sufficiently present the intrinsic catalytic yielding for the real application.</description>
      <author>Zheng Liu, Z Liu, Lingxing Zan, Yu Sun, Huizhen Han, Yiran Li, Han Wang, Ting Cao, Yao Zhu, Haiyang Lv, Yuxuan Liu, Juzhe Liu, Xin Bo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Induces Self-Reconstruction for Urea-Assisted Water Electrolysis Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03343</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Yifeng Liu, Qianqiao Chen, Wan-Chin Yu, Qin Zhong, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404109565

                Urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is an attractive alternative anodic reaction to oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for its low thermodynamic potential (0.37 V vs RHE). A major challenge that prohibits its practical application is the six-electron transfer process during UOR, demanding enhancements in the catalytic activity. Herein, a Fe-doped Ni</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Yifeng Liu, Qianqiao Chen, Wan-Chin Yu, Qin Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Single Atom&#8208;Hydroxyl Incorporation in Poly(heptazine imide) to Create Active Sites for Photocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408436</link>
      <description>Wenxuan Hu, Aifeng Li, Haiping Li, Yu Wang, Zhenzhong Fan, Quanhua Deng, Guoan Wang, Yuguo Xia, Wanguo Hou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404273304

                Abstract Poly(heptazine imide) (PHI) salts are extensively researched crystalline carbon nitride photocatalysts, but their photocatalytic water oxidation (PWO) performance is scarcely researched because of the difficulty in creating efficient active sites. Interference of metal ion (e.g., Na + and K + ) loss from the PHI salts in their PWO research has hardly been considered. Herein, metal single atom&#9472;OH (e.g., Co&#9472;OH) groups are incorporated into PHI to create efficient PWO active sites, via simple ion metathesis, hydrolysis, and deprotonation. The Co&#9472;OH modified PHI exhibits 9.3&#8208;fold higher PWO (oxygen evolution) activity than PHI, with an external quantum yield reaching 0.44% even at 600 nm. Excluding interference of the metal ion loss, the function of the Co&#9472;OH incorporation is evidenced mainly to facilitate the oxygen evolution reaction, as well as to promote photogenerated charge separation and raise visible light absorption, with the role of the OH especially revealed. Moreover, it is discovered that Na + loss from sodium PHI will decrease its PWO activity, protonation of PHI has a detrimental effect on its PWO performance, and some other metal single atom&#9472;OH incorporation in PHI can also enhance its PWO activity. Overall, this work provides a general way to create PWO active sites in PHI.</description>
      <author>Wenxuan Hu, Aifeng Li, Haiping Li, Yu Wang, Zhenzhong Fan, Quanhua Deng, Guoan Wang, Yuguo Xia, Wanguo Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XPS investigation of CuxO-functionalized amorphous carbon nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0004078</link>
      <description>Giacomo Marchiori, Mattia Benedet, Angelica Fasan, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Surface Science Spectra. 31(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404243982

                In this work, we report the x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy characterization of a novel nanocomposite (photo)electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction, based on amorphous carbon nitride (aCN) functionalized with CuxO nanoparticles (NPs). The specimen has been fabricated employing two sequential plasma-assisted processes, involving the initial aCN deposition onto conductive glass via magnetron sputtering, followed by carbon nitride functionalization with CuxO (x = 1, 2) NPs by radio frequency-sputtering. The results reported herein include the survey spectrum and the high-resolution C 1s, N 1s, O 1s, Cu 2p, and Cu LMM signals. The most significant spectral features are analyzed and critically discussed.</description>
      <author>Giacomo Marchiori, Mattia Benedet, Angelica Fasan, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0004078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Ru Species Induced by Strong Metal&#8211;Support Interaction for Electrochemical Methane Reforming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c10729</link>
      <description>Yuefeng Song, Tianfu Liu, Weicheng Feng, Rongtan Li, Yige Guo, Mingrun Li, Luozhen Jiang, Hiroaki Matsumoto, Chaobin Zeng, Xiaomin Zhang, Geng Zou, Qingxue Liu, Houfu Lv, Jingcheng Yu, Meilin Liu, Guoxiong Wang, Xinhe Bao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404160270

                During the high-temperature oxygen evolution reaction for CO2 electrolysis in solid oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs), the key elementary process of O2&#8211; transfer is restricted by the high anodic oxygen pressure thermodynamically, thus requiring a high external voltage [open-circuit voltage (OCV)] to drive the electrolysis reaction. Herein, electrochemical CH4 reforming is introduced to the SOEC anode, which remarkably lowers the anodic oxygen pressure and OCV, finally reducing the energy demand from 3.12 to 0.11 kW h per cubic meter of CO. Meanwhile, atomically dispersed Ru species is anchored on the anode surface due to the strong metal&#8211;support interaction, which exhibits superior CH4 reforming activity (90% of CO selectivity) and stability (300 h) to the infiltrated Ru nanoparticles and doped Ru species in the bulk lattice at 600 &#176;C. This work proposes an efficient strategy to boost the SOEC performance thermodynamically and produce value-added chemicals at both the cathode and anode of SOEC simultaneously.</description>
      <author>Yuefeng Song, Tianfu Liu, Weicheng Feng, Rongtan Li, Yige Guo, Mingrun Li, Luozhen Jiang, Hiroaki Matsumoto, Chaobin Zeng, Xiaomin Zhang, Geng Zou, Qingxue Liu, Houfu Lv, Jingcheng Yu, Meilin Liu, Guoxiong Wang, Xinhe Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c10729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lewis acid sites in hollow cobalt phytate micropolyhedra promote the electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401932</link>
      <description>Mingxing Chen, Jing Wang, Qizhen Chen, Ying Gao, Yajing Zhao, Shengbo Gao, Enbo Shangguan, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404145093

                The acid-base microenvironment of the metal center is crucial for constructing advanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. However, the correlation between acidic site and OER performance remains unclear for cobalt-based catalysts. Herein, Lewis acid sites in hollow cobalt phytate micropolyhedra (M-CoPA, M = Cu, Sr) were synthesized by a cation-exchange strategy, and their OER performances were studied systematically. Experimentally, Lewis acid Cu2+ sites with stronger Lewis acidity exhibited superior intrinsic activity and long-term stability in alkaline electrolytes. The spectroscopic and electrochemical studies show Lewis acid sites in hollow cobalt phytate micropolyhedra can modulate the electronic distribution of the adjacent cobalt center and further optimize the adsorption strength of oxygenated species. This study figures out the effect of Lewis acid sites on the OER kinetics and provides an effective way to develop high-efficiency electrocatalysts for energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Mingxing Chen, Jing Wang, Qizhen Chen, Ying Gao, Yajing Zhao, Shengbo Gao, Enbo Shangguan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401932</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Rechargeable Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225313</link>
      <description>Hui Zhao, Molecules. 29(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404241269

                Rechargeable Zn-air batteries are considered to be an effective energy storage device due to their high energy density, environmental friendliness, and long operating life. Further progress on rechargeable Zn-air batteries with high energy density/power density is greatly needed to satisfy the increasing energy conversion and storage demands. This review summarizes the strategies proposed so far to pursue high-efficiency Zn-air batteries, including the aspects of the electrocatalysts (from noble metals to non-noble metals), the electrode chemistry (from the oxygen evolution reaction to the organic oxidation reaction), electrode engineering (from powdery to free-standing), aqueous electrolytes (from alkaline to non-alkaline) and the battery configuration (from liquid to flexible). An essential evaluation of electrochemistry is highlighted to solve the challenges in boosting the efficiency of rechargeable metal-air batteries. In the end, the perspective on current challenges and future research directions to promote the industrial application of rechargeable Zn-air batteries is provided.</description>
      <author>Hui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Investigation of Single-, Double-, and Triple- &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;-block Metals Anchored on g-CN Monolayer for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02399</link>
      <description>Yanan Zhou, Li Sheng, Lanlan Chen, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404133632

                The design and development of highly active non-noble metal electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are crucial for metal-air batteries. In this work, the electrocatalytic performance of different p-block metal (PM = Sn, Sb, Pb and Bi) atoms embedded in the g-CN monolayer (PMx@g-CN, x = 1&#8211;3) for the OER and ORR was systematically investigated by density functional theory (DFT). The strong interaction between PMx atoms and g-CN substrates indicates the good stability of PMx@g-CN catalysts. Among all the designed catalysts, Bi3@g-CN is found to be a promising bifunctional electrocatalyst for both the OER and ORR with the calculated overpotential &#951;OER and &#951;ORR of 0.23 and 0.25 V, respectively. With the atomic active sites of PMx increasing from x = 1 to 3, the OER and ORR catalytic activity is enhanced. The correlations between the overpotentials of the OER/ORR and Bader charge values of the anchored PMx atoms of the catalysts were established. Our findings contribute to searching for noble metal-free bifunctional electrocatalysts and shed light on the rational design of atomic active sites on electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yanan Zhou, Li Sheng, Lanlan Chen, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02399</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Water Dissociation on RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(110) Using Atomic Force Microscopy and First-Principles Simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13164</link>
      <description>Austin Jerad Reese, Simon Gelin, Maria Maalouf, Neha Wadehra, Shouxin Zhang, Geoffroy Hautier, Darrell G. Schlom, Isma&#239;la Dabo, Jin Suntivich, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404163114

                The interaction between interfacial water and transition metal oxides is a primary enabling step for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). RuO2 is a prototypical OER electrocatalyst whose ability to activate interfacial water molecules is essential to its OER activity. We image the dissociation of surface water into OH* and O* on RuO2(110), where * denotes adsorbed species, using atomic force microscopy. Starting from the surface-bound water molecules, which form a one-dimensional network along the rows of Ru surface sites, increasing the oxidative potential strips hydrogen away and transforms the water molecules into OH* and O*. This oxidative step changes the pattern of the adsorbates from one- to two-dimensional. First-principles calculations with interfacial polarization, capacitive charging, and adsorbate interactions attribute this evolution to the cooperative dehydrogenation of adsorbed water and OH* on RuO2. We use these results to map the surface phase diagram of RuO2(110) and provide a quantitative interpretation of its cyclic voltammetry. Our result provides the visualization of the water dissociation on a conductive oxide surface, a critical step in the OER, and demonstrates that the water activation is a collective phenomenon at RuO2(110) electrodes.</description>
      <author>Austin Jerad Reese, Simon Gelin, Maria Maalouf, Neha Wadehra, Shouxin Zhang, Geoffroy Hautier, Darrell G. Schlom, Isma&#239;la Dabo, Jin Suntivich</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the active site in chameleon-like bifunctional catalyst for practical rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54019-1</link>
      <description>Xiongwei Zhong, Xiao Xiao, Qizhen Li, Mengtian Zhang, Zhitong Li, Leyi Gao, Biao Chen, Zhiyang Zheng, Qingjin Fu, Xingzhu Wang, Guangmin Zhou, Baomin Xu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404143912

                The practical application of rechargeable zinc-air batteries faces challenges stemming from inadequate bifunctional catalysts, contradictory gas-liquid-solid three-phase interfaces, and an ambiguous fundamental understanding. Herein, we propose a chameleon-like bifunctional catalyst comprising ruthenium single-atoms grafted onto nickel-iron layer double hydroxide (RuSA-NiFe LDH). The adaptive oxidation of RuSA-NiFe LDH to oxyhydroxide species (RuSA-NiFeOOH) during charging exposes active sites for the oxygen evolution reaction, while reversible reduction to NiFe LDH during discharge exposes active sites for the oxygen reduction reaction. Additionally, a hierarchical air cathode featuring hydrophilic and hydrophobic layers facilitates the reversible conversion between RuSA-NiFe LDH and RuSA-NiFeOOH, expedites oxygen bubble desorption, and suppresses carbon corrosion. Consequently, our zinc-air batteries demonstrate a high charge/discharge capacity of 100 mAh cm&#8722;2 per cycle, a voltage gap of 0.67 V, and an extended cycle life of 2400 h at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. We comprehensively elucidate the catalytic reaction thermodynamics and kinetics for the air cathode through electrode potential decoupling monitoring, oxygen bubble desorption tracking, and carbon content quantification. Rechargeable zinc-air batteries hold great promise for energy storage but face several challenges. In this study, the authors introduce a chameleon-like catalyst and a hierarchical air cathode, achieving a 2400-hour cycle life for these batteries.</description>
      <author>Xiongwei Zhong, Xiao Xiao, Qizhen Li, Mengtian Zhang, Zhitong Li, Leyi Gao, Biao Chen, Zhiyang Zheng, Qingjin Fu, Xingzhu Wang, Guangmin Zhou, Baomin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54019-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targeted Topological Routine Regulation of RuNiOx Precursors for Excellent Alkaline Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401664</link>
      <description>Ziyan Cai, Minghao Yang, Xiaoke Xu, Xiuming Bu, Chuqian Xiao, Yikai Yang, Di Yin, Yuxuan Zhang, Gao Wei, Xianying Wang, Johnny C. Ho, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404205798

                Designing efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER) is crucial for green hydrogen production via the water&#8208;splitting system. The bifunctional electrocatalyst offers a promising strategy due to the simplified preparation process and reduced expenses. However, the single&#8208;component bifunctional catalysts often struggle to match the redox potential of water and to achieve proper adsorption/desorption of Gibbs free energy for both H and O intermediates simultaneously. Herein, through precisely controlling the topological transformation path of the RuNiOx precursor, we successfully prepared high&#8208;performance RuNi/Ni and Ru/NiO heterostructure electrocatalysts for the HER and OER, respectively. The energy level matching between the fabricated electrocatalyst and water oxidation/reduction potential confirms the feasibility of HER and OER. The synergistic effect between the active sites ensures rapid, intermediate adsorption/desorption kinetics. As a result, the assembled alkaline overall water splitting setup achieves a current density of 1 A cm&#8208;2 at 2 V and maintains stable operation at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 for 100 hours.</description>
      <author>Ziyan Cai, Minghao Yang, Xiaoke Xu, Xiuming Bu, Chuqian Xiao, Yikai Yang, Di Yin, Yuxuan Zhang, Gao Wei, Xianying Wang, Johnny C. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalytic Performance of Nickel&#8208;Nitrogen&#8208;Carbon Catalysts through Coordination Environment Engineering&lt;sup&gt;&#8224;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400769</link>
      <description>Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404209081

                Comprehensive Summary Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have attracted significant attention due to their high atomic utilization and tunable coordination environment. However, the catalytic mechanisms related to the active center and coordination environment remain unclear. In this study, we systematically investigated the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalytic activities of NiN 4 , NiN 3 , NiN 3 H 2 , NiN 4 X, NiN 3 X, and NiN 3 H 2 X (X denotes axial ligand) through density functional theory (DFT) calculations. This study unveils two distinct reaction pathways for ORR and OER, involving proton&#8208;electron pairs adsorbed from both the solution and the catalyst surface. The overpotential is the key parameter to evaluate the catalytic performance when proton&#8208;electron pairs are adsorbed from the solution. NiN 3 and NiN 3 H 2 show promise as pH&#8208;universal bifunctional electrocatalysts for both ORR and OER. On the other hand, when proton&#8208;electron pairs are adsorbed from the catalyst surface, the reaction energy barrier becomes the crucial metric for assessing catalytic activity. Our investigation reveals that NiN 3 H 2 consistently exhibits optimal ORR activity across a wide pH range, regardless of the source of proton&#8208;electron pair (solvent or catalyst surface).</description>
      <author>Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Phosphide Decorating Metallic Cobalt With a Nitrogen&#8208;Doped Carbon Nano&#8208;Shell Surpasses Platinum Group Metals for Oxygen Electrocatalysis Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240029</link>
      <description>Muhammad Tahir, Muhammad Asim Farid, Elvin Aliyev, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Shangfeng Du, Battery energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404117598

                ABSTRACT It has been a long&#8208;standing challenge to cultivate capable and resilient oxygen electrocatalysts with higher activity, low price, and long lifetime to replace the commonly used platinum group metals, i.e., Pt for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and RuO 2 /IrO 2 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This work presents a promising approach to address the challenges associated with oxygen electrocatalysis by introducing a cobalt phosphide/metallic cobalt (Co 2 P/Co) core wrapped in a nitrogen&#8208;doped conductive carbon (CN) nano&#8208;shell, demonstrated as Co 2 P/Co@NC. The strong chemical bonding between metallic cobalt and phosphorus, nitrogen and conductive carbon contributes to the enhanced conductivity and stability of the electrocatalyst. The nitrogen doping in the carbon shell provides additional Co&#8211;N active sites, which are crucial for ORR activity. Co 2 P/Co@NC demonstrates promising activity and stability compared to noble metals such as Pt for ORR in an alkaline medium. This suggests its potential as a cost&#8208;effective alternative to Pt&#8208;based catalysts. Further, due to factors such as strong cobalt&#8208;phosphide bonding, high cobalt oxidation states and excellent conductivity of the nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon shell, the Co 2 P/Co@NC outperforms noble metal oxides like iridium dioxide (IrO 2 ) and ruthenium dioxide (RuO 2 ) for OER. Co 2 P/Co@NC exhibits a low potential difference of 0.63 V, which is among the lowest reported for bifunctional electrocatalysts capable of both ORR and OER. Overall, the described strategy offers a promising avenue for developing efficient, low&#8208;cost and stable electrocatalysts for oxygen reactions, which are crucial for various electrochemical energy conversion and storage technologies, such as fuel cells and metal&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Tahir, Muhammad Asim Farid, Elvin Aliyev, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Shangfeng Du</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bte2.20240029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clustered VCoCO&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; Nanosheets Anchored on MXene&#8211;Ti&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@NF as a Superior Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400278</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Yourong Tao, Lulu Xu, Ruilong Ye, Jing Wang, Jun&#8208;Jie Zhu, Liping Jiang, Xingcai Wu, Small Structures. 5(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404113062

                Ti 3 C 2 , one typical MXene, has great potential to be coupled with various transition metals. Herein, a novel and effective catalyst is developed by synergistically loading VCoCO x onto Ti 3 C 2 &#8208;modified nickel foam (VCoCO x &#8211;Ti 3 C 2 @NF). Field emission scanning electron microscope and high&#8208;resolution transmission electron microscopy are employed to characterize the morphology and structure. As expected, the catalyst optimized by response surface methodology attains overpotentials of 290 and 64 mV and Tafel slopes of 82 and 79 mV dec &#8722;1 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), respectively. By using the bifunctional VCoCO x &#8211;Ti 3 C 2 @NF catalyst, the water splitting current density achieves 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1.0 mol L &#8722;1 KOH electrolyte at cell voltage of 1.52 V, comparable with the noble metal electrolyzer Pt@C@NF||RuO 2 @NF (1.57 V). Furthermore, the resulting catalyst exhibits excellent cycling durability after 120 h of continuous catalysis, which retains 103.8% and 105.4% of potential (V vs reversible hydrogen electrode) for OER and HER, respectively. Density functional theory calculation reveals that the Gibbs free energy barriers for the OER and HER intermediates are reduced due to the integration of VCoCO x with Ti 3 C 2 @NF. The fabricated VCoCO x &#8211;Ti 3 C 2 @NF catalyst is a promising electrochemical material for clean energy production.</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Yourong Tao, Lulu Xu, Ruilong Ye, Jing Wang, Jun&#8208;Jie Zhu, Liping Jiang, Xingcai Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reticular One-Pot Synthesis of Synergic 4f(Ln)&#8211;3d(TM) Heterovalence and Heterobimetallic Europium&#8211;Copper MOFs: Emerging Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02257</link>
      <description>Veeramuthu Saravanakumar, Manivannan Mahendran, Aathilingam Vijayaprabhakaran, Ragunath Madhu, Murugavel Kathiresan, Sambandam Anandan, V. Suryanarayanan, Subrata Kundu, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404143514

                A promising potential new electrocatalyst for water splitting could be developed through the meticulous design and synthesis of diverse bimetallic metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs). These MOFs would use different or the same metals from the d and f blocks and could have different oxidation states. This study focuses on developing an efficient bimetallic electrocatalyst, based on the rare-earth lanthanide series element europium (Eu) and transition-metal copper (Cu) as the MOF using a one-pot hydrothermal method. As a result, a significant 4f&#8211;3d heterovalent heterobimetallic MOF was obtained, and its electrocatalytic activity toward water splitting was evaluated. Further, heterobimetallic MOFs with their mixed valence display an improved water-splitting performance through synergistic effects. Linear-sweep voltammetry (LSV) studies reveal that the bimetallic Eu&#8211;Cu-MOF required an overpotential of 133 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 240 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at a current density of 20 mA cm&#8211;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and 1 M KOH, respectively. Moreover, the long-term stability study exhibits a stable nature up to 20 and 16 h in 1 M KOH and 0.5 M H2SO4 solutions, respectively. The incorporation of Eu synergistically increases the adsorption and desorption ability of OH&#8211; and O2 molecules toward OER, respectively. The bimetallic MOF displayed excellent stability under acidic as well as alkaline conditions, indicating an exciting future for Eu&#8211;Cu-MOF in the field of electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Veeramuthu Saravanakumar, Manivannan Mahendran, Aathilingam Vijayaprabhakaran, Ragunath Madhu, Murugavel Kathiresan, Sambandam Anandan, V. Suryanarayanan, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in anion exchange membrane technology for water electrolysis: a review of progress and challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ese3.1938</link>
      <description>Abdul Qayoom, Muhammad Shakeel Ahmad, H. Fayaz, Atika Qazi, Jeyraj Selvaraj, Rahadian Zainul, Krismadinata Krismadinata, Nasrudin Abd Rahim, Farruh Atamurotov, Thien Khanh Tran, Basma Souayeh, Natei Ermias Benti, Energy Science &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404121062

                Abstract Clean energy and environmental pollution are two key concerns of modern society and are pivotal necessities for the economic, social, and sustainable development of the world. Today around 80% of energy is generated using nonrenewable resources and fossil fuels (oil, gas, coal) which ultimately results in hazardous global emissions. As a clean substitute for fossil fuels, hydrogen has emerged as a promising and renewable energy resource. Utilization of this energy resource requires the development of active, stable, low&#8208;cost environmentally friendly techniques. Water splitting electrolysis is a method for producing clean and efficient hydrogen using an environmentally benign technique that is currently at its most mature stage. Electrolysis is attracting ever&#8208;increasing attention, as it is a promising electrochemical device for hydrogen production from water due to the high conversion efficiency and relatively low energy input required when compared to thermochemical and photocatalytic methods. This paper will outline the need, performance, and insight of anion exchange membrane (AEM) electrolyzer. Recent developments in the design and preparation of AEM. New strategies for activity, stability, and efficiency improvement of AEM. Membrane types, and factors affecting AEM performance in an electrolyzer. This review also discusses the effects, operating characteristics, and energy consumption of electrocatalysts in the AEM electrolyzer. Hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) pathways and mechanisms in acidic and alkaline media. This study seeks to provide a detailed overview of recent accomplishments in the field of the hydrogen economy, particularly electrolysis, to inspire further research and development to address the technology's obstacles.</description>
      <author>Abdul Qayoom, Muhammad Shakeel Ahmad, H. Fayaz, Atika Qazi, Jeyraj Selvaraj, Rahadian Zainul, Krismadinata Krismadinata, Nasrudin Abd Rahim, Farruh Atamurotov, Thien Khanh Tran, Basma Souayeh, Natei Ermias Benti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ese3.1938</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Phase Engineering of a Hierarchical 2D&#8211;2D Nickel MOF/Hydroxide&#8208;Derived Ni&lt;sub&gt;0.85&lt;/sub&gt;Se/NiTe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterointerface for Robust HER, OER, and Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406732</link>
      <description>Ishwor Pathak, Sampath Prabhakaran, Debendra Acharya, Kisan Chhetri, Alagan Muthurasu, Yagya Raj Rosyara, Taewoo Kim, Tae Hoon Ko, Do Hwan Kim, Hak Yong Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404222115

                Abstract The development of a nonnoble metal&#8208;based cost&#8208;effective, efficient, and durable bifunctional electrocatalyst is crucial to achieving the goal of carbon neutrality. In this study, a structural and interfacial engineering approach is employed to design a 2D&#8211;2D hierarchical nickel MOF/nickel hydroxide&#8208;derived nickel selenide/nickel telluride dual&#8208;phase material through a single&#8208;step selenotellurization process. The rational design of highly ordered nanoarchitectures provides well&#8208;defined voids and ample pathways for ion diffusion. Furthermore, hierarchical nickel selenide/nickel telluride works synergistically at heterojunctions, providing a local ion enrichment mechanism for the catalytic process. As a result, Ni 0.85 Se/NiTe 2 @Ni&#8208;NH@CC needs an overpotential of 69 and 240 mV to deliver a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively, with an outstanding stability observed for over 100 h. Moreover, the Ni 0.85 Se/NiTe 2 @Ni&#8208;NH@CC (+, &#8722;) device exhibits excellent overall water&#8208;splitting performance with a cell voltage of 1.50 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and can be operated steadily for &gt;100 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate favorable kinetics for H&#8208;adsorption at the selenotelluride heterojunction, thereby promoting the HER. This work highlights a new approach for designing a unique nanoarchitecture of MOF/hydroxide&#8208;derived selenotelluride heterojunctions for high&#8208;efficiency energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Ishwor Pathak, Sampath Prabhakaran, Debendra Acharya, Kisan Chhetri, Alagan Muthurasu, Yagya Raj Rosyara, Taewoo Kim, Tae Hoon Ko, Do Hwan Kim, Hak Yong Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Charge Separation and Transport: Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting in &#945;-Fe2O3/CZTS Nanorod Arrays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110812</link>
      <description>Wen Chen, Ao-Sheng She, Ming-Hao Ji, Hao-Yan Shi, Yang Yang, Yunlong Pu, Rui Chen, Weihua Yang, Yanxin Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu, Catalysts. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404254297

                This study explores the enhancement of &#945;-Fe2O3 (hematite) nanorod arrays for photoelec-trochemical applications by constructing a Cu2ZnSnS4 (CZTS) heterojunction. While &#945;-Fe2O3 offers good stability, a low cost, and environmental benefits, its efficiency is limited by slow oxygen evolution kinetics, high carrier recombination rates, and low conductivity. By introducing CZTS, a material with strong light absorption and charge transport properties, we enhance the separation of photogenerated charge carriers, reduce charge transfer resistance, and increase the carrier concentration, thereby boosting the overall photoelectrochemical performance. The experimental results show that a modified FC-15 photoanode achieves a photocurrent density of 3.40 mA/cm2 at 1.60 V vs. RHE, a substantial increase compared to 0.40 mA/cm2 for unmodified &#945;-Fe2O3. Band gap analysis reveals a reduced band gap in the FC-15 material, enhancing light absorption and boosting the photoelectrocatalytic performance. In photoelectrochemical water-splitting tests, the FC-15 photoanode achieves a hydrogen production rate of 41.6 &#956;mol/cm2/h, which is significantly improved over the unmodified sample at 5.64 &#956;mol/cm2/h. These findings indicate that the CZTS/&#945;-Fe2O3 heterojunction effectively promotes charge separation, enhances charge transport, and improves light absorption, substantially increasing photocatalytic efficiency. This heterojunction approach offers new insights and technical strategies for developing photocatalytic materials with potential applications in renewable energy.</description>
      <author>Wen Chen, Ao-Sheng She, Ming-Hao Ji, Hao-Yan Shi, Yang Yang, Yunlong Pu, Rui Chen, Weihua Yang, Yanxin Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statistical and Electrochemical Insights of Hexagonal NiCoMg-LDH Nanosheets toward Overall Water Splitting and Methanol Oxidation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02144</link>
      <description>Rakesh Kulkarni, Swapnil R. Patil, Lakshmi Prasanna Lingamdinne, Santosh S. Sutar, Chandrika Ashwinikumar Pal, N.S. Reddy, Yoon-Young Chang, Jinho Bae, Janardhan Reddy Koduru, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404199743

                The primary obstacle in electrochemical water splitting for hydrogen (H2) production is the sluggish anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, a promising approach to overcome this barrier involves replacing the OER with the more energetically favorable methanol oxidation reaction (MOR), providing a practical avenue for efficient and energy-saving H2 generation. This paper proposes a bifunctional electrocatalyst, successfully synthesizing a trimetallic hybrid NiCoMg-LDH composite via a one-step hydrothermal method supported on 3-DCF (carbon felt). Additionally, the stability of the electrolyzer was assessed by the statistical modeling and predictive time series analysis (LSTM) technique. The synthesized multimetallic self-supported NiCoMg-LDH composition formed porous hexagonal sheet-like structures, demonstrating outstanding bifunctional activity toward the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and OER, achieving low overpotentials of 0.185 and 0.161 V for HER and OER at an applied current density of 100 mA/cm2, respectively. Additionally, when employed parallel as the anode and cathode for total water splitting, it necessitated only 1.56 V to achieve 100 mA/cm2, surpassing the compared benchmark Pt/C&#8741;RuO2 electrodes. Furthermore, the cell voltage of the NiCoMg-LDH&#8741;NiCoMg-LDH-based methanol&#8211;water electrolyzer at 100 mA/cm2 was notably reduced by 250 mV compared to that of the OER alone at the anode. Therefore, from these results, the superior electroactivity of the trimetallic NiCoMg-LDH catalyst is primarily attributed to its high electrochemical active surface area (ECSA), abundant active sites, and rapid electron transfer from the catalyst surface to the electrolyte. Therefore, this study represents a significant advancement in the design and development of stable, highly active, and economical hybrid catalysts for green energy harvesting applications.</description>
      <author>Rakesh Kulkarni, Swapnil R. Patil, Lakshmi Prasanna Lingamdinne, Santosh S. Sutar, Chandrika Ashwinikumar Pal, N.S. Reddy, Yoon-Young Chang, Jinho Bae, Janardhan Reddy Koduru</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sodium&#8208;Rich, Co&#8208;Ni&#8208;Free P2&#8208;Layered Manganese Oxide Cathodes for Sodium&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404280</link>
      <description>Zulkifli, Balaji Sambandam, Ahmad Nurul Fahri, Kiki Rezki Lestari, Seunggyeong Lee, Jaekook Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404115448

                Abstract The rapid capacity loss attributed to irreversible phase reactions and structural instability has consistently affected the development of P2&#8208;layered cathode materials. Moreover, the introduction of costly elements such as single or multiple dopants has failed to resolve the sustainability challenges in designing an optimal Mn&#8208;based layered oxide cathode. This study proposes a Co&#8208;Ni&#8208;free, poly&#8208;elemental doping strategy (Li, Mg, and Cu) combined with high sodium content for an Mn&#8208;based P2&#8208;layered cathode designed for Na + ion storage. In situ X&#8208;ray diffraction analysis confirms the absence of P2 &#8211; O2 phase transitions during cycling for both NLMMC87 (Na 0.87 Li 0.1 Mg 0.1 Mn 0.7 Cu 0.1 O 2 ) and NLMMC77 (Na 0.77 Li 0.1 Mg 0.1 Mn 0.7 Cu 0.1 O 2 ). This can be attributed to the co&#8208;substitution of the electronegative Cu element and the stabilizing dopants Li and Mg, which suppress oxygen evolution. Simultaneously, the high sodium content within the host structure promotes high reversible capacity, enhances structural stability, and minimizes internal stress due to volume changes. Moreover, NLMMC87 demonstrates a reversible capacity of 167.9 mA h g &#8722;1 at 0.1 C (97% Coulombic efficiency) and maintains excellent stability across various current rates. Further investigations into the practical application of NLMMC87 in a sodium full cell will be a critical step toward realizing an ideal cathode for sodium&#8208;ion batteries.</description>
      <author>Zulkifli, Balaji Sambandam, Ahmad Nurul Fahri, Kiki Rezki Lestari, Seunggyeong Lee, Jaekook Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolated FeN&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; sites anchored hierarchical porous carbon nanoboxes for hydrazine&#8208;assisted rechargeable Zn&#8208;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; batteries with ultralow charge voltage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.637</link>
      <description>Sanshuang Gao, Hongyi Li, Zhansheng Lu, Songjie Meng, Xue Zhao, Xinzhong Wang, X. Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404190332

                Abstract Zn&#8208;CO 2 batteries (ZCBs) are promising for CO 2 conversion and electric energy release. However, the ZCBs couple the electrochemical CO 2 reduction (ECO 2 R) with the oxygen evolution reaction and competitive hydrogen evolution reaction, which normally causes ultrahigh charge voltage and CO 2 conversion efficiency attenuation, thereby resulting in ~90% total power consumption. Herein, isolated FeN 3 sites encapsulated in hierarchical porous carbon nanoboxes (Fe&#8208;HPCN, derived from the thermal activation process of ferrocene and polydopamine&#8208;coated cubic ZIF&#8208;8) were proposed for hydrazine&#8208;assisted rechargeable ZCBs based on ECO 2 R (discharging process: CO 2 + 2H + &#8594; CO + H 2 O) and hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR, charging process: N 2 H 4 + 4OH &#8722; &#8594; N 2 + 4H 2 O + 4e &#8722; ). The isolated FeN 3 endows the HzOR with a lower overpotential and boosts the ECO 2 R with a 96% CO Faraday efficiency (FE CO ). Benefitting from the bifunctional ECO 2 R and HzOR catalytic activities, the homemade hydrazine&#8208;assisted rechargeable ZCBs assembled with the Fe&#8208;HPCN air cathode exhibited an ultralow charge voltage (decreasing by ~1.84 V), excellent CO selectivity (FE CO close to 100%), and high 89% energy efficiency. In situ infrared spectroscopy confirmed that Fe&#8208;HPCN can generate rate&#8208;determining *N 2 and *CO intermediates during HzOR and ECO 2 R. This paper proposes FeN 3 centers for bifunctional ECO 2 R/HzOR performance and further presents the pioneering achievements of ECO 2 R and HzOR for hydrazine&#8208;assisted rechargeable ZCBs.</description>
      <author>Sanshuang Gao, Hongyi Li, Zhansheng Lu, Songjie Meng, Xue Zhao, Xinzhong Wang, X. Liu, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous carbon-nanostructured electrocatalysts for zinc-air batteries: From materials design to applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00847b</link>
      <description>Sanshuang Gao, Maolin Li, Nianpeng Li, Lei Zhang, Qian Liu, Xinzhong Wang, Guangzhi Hu, Nanoscale Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404128443

                Zinc-air batteries (ZABs) are pivotal in the evolution of sustainable energy storage solutions, distinguished by their high energy density and minimal environmental footprint. The oxygen electrode, reliant on sophisticated porous...</description>
      <author>Sanshuang Gao, Maolin Li, Nianpeng Li, Lei Zhang, Qian Liu, Xinzhong Wang, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00847b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPD: Oxygen levels in the cornea with contact lens wear</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12968/opti.2023.268.6911.20</link>
      <description>Douglas Clarkson, Optician. 268(6911)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4404243079

                Dr Douglas Clarkson describes the way a cornea maintains oxygen supply during contact lens wear against the back-drop of contact lens evolution over the last decades (C106006, suitable for logging as one distance learning CPD point for optometrists, contact lens opticians and dispensing opticians)</description>
      <author>Douglas Clarkson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12968/opti.2023.268.6911.20</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CORROS&#195;O LOCALIZADA DO ALUM&#205;NIO EM MEIOS AERADOS E EM MEIOS COM BAIXO TEOR OXIG&#202;NIO: ESTUDO E COMPARA&#199;&#195;O POR MEIO DE CURVAS DE POLARIZA&#199;&#195;O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21577/0100-4042.20250067</link>
      <description>Jo&#227;o Victor de Sousa Araujo, Aline D Gabbardo, S.M.C. Fernandes, Isolda Costa, Qu&#237;mica Nova. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404239881

                LOCALIZED CORROSION OF ALUMINUM IN AERATED ENVIRONMENTS AND IN ENVIRONMENTS WITH LOW OXYGEN CONTENT: STUDY AND COMPARISON THROUGH POLARIZATION CURVES. In this study, the influence of deaeration on the electrochemical behavior of aluminum was studied by polarization techniques. The advantages of deaeration for the evaluation of localized corrosion on aluminum are discussed. The influence of the corrosive environment with low oxygen contents on the electrochemical response of aluminum was evaluated by anodic and cathodic potentiodynamic polarization curves. The polarization tests were carried out in chloride solutions followed by optical and scanning electron microscopy characterization. It was observed that deaeration of the solution significantly influences the electrochemical behavior of aluminum, as predicted by corrosion kinetics theories. For the cathodic curves, a decrease in the limiting current density for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) was observed for low oxygen solutions, while the &#8220;apparent&#8221; initiation of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) was shifted to higher potentials. In the anodic curves, a common passive behavior was not observed in aerated conditions, however, at the corrosion potential, localized pitting was observed indicating that the material was already above the breakdown potential (Ebr). In the low oxygen content solution, however, a passive region with a breakdown potential, was observed on the anodic curves.</description>
      <author>Jo&#227;o Victor de Sousa Araujo, Aline D Gabbardo, S.M.C. Fernandes, Isolda Costa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21577/0100-4042.20250067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geochemical and zircon 18O&#8211;Hf&#8211;U/Pb isotopic study of volcanic rocks from Lutao Island in the northern Luzon magmatic arc</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s40562-024-00363-5</link>
      <description>Nancy Hui-Chun Chen, Geoscience Letters. 11(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404229837

                Abstract Lutao is an islet off the eastern coast of the main island of Taiwan and is composed of pyroclastic agglomerates, volcanic breccias, lava flows, and dykes. There have been no reports of SIMS zircon oxygen isotopic data from Lutao Island so far, which has significantly hampered further understanding of its magmatic processes, such as crystallization, evolution, and generation of magma. In this study, we use zircon U&#8211;Pb dating, Lu&#8211;Hf and O isotopic analysis to constrain the age, origin, and magmatic processes of the volcanic rocks from Lutao Island. Integration of our new U&#8211;Pb and Hf&#8211;O isotope data with available published data allows us to better assess the timing and magmatic processes of Lutao Island in the context of the northern Luzon arc system. This work is the first report of SIMS zircon oxygen isotopic data of volcanic rocks from Lutao island. This study shows that the volcanic rocks from Lutao Island were generated by mantle-derived magma associated with high-T&#176; hydrothermal alteration by seawater-derived fluids.</description>
      <author>Nancy Hui-Chun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s40562-024-00363-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of MoS2/CNT heterostructure with rich S-vacancy for enhanced HER performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237254</link>
      <description>Yuxin Sun, Jinhua Li, Zhiying Wang, Fengxue Tan, Kaixi Shi, Yingjiao Zhai, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404244572

                Molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) is a promising electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to excellent stability and low cost. However, the utilization in electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution is constrained by inherent shortcomings, including fewer edge active sites, poor dispersion, and electrical conductivity. In this work, MoS2 was compounded with carbon nanotubes (CNTs), which are known for their high specific surface area and excellent electrical conductivity. These CNTs, laden with oxygen-containing functional groups, provided nucleation sites that facilitated the rapid assembly of MoS2 nanoflowers under hydrothermal conditions within 3 h. Due to their diminutive size (&#8764;300 nm), these nanoflowers possess a large specific surface area and numerous active sites at their edges. Furthermore, MoS2 nanoflowers exhibited a high concentration of intrinsic S-vacancies. This heterojunction material exhibited superior HER properties. In addition, density functional theory simulation further confirmed that the MoS2 with S vacancy and CNT heterojunction electrocatalysts (VS-M/C) provided a fast charge transfer pathway for water electrolysis, and analysis showed that the conduction band minimum and valence band maximum were mainly contributed by the d orbits of Mo and the p orbits of C. This study proffered a novel approach for the engineering of high-performance MoS2-based HER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuxin Sun, Jinhua Li, Zhiying Wang, Fengxue Tan, Kaixi Shi, Yingjiao Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical Simulation Study on the Mechanism of Plasma Dissociation of Carbon Dioxide in Atmospheric Pressure Packed-Bed Reactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.73.20241241</link>
      <description>Peng Yi, Wang ChunJing, Jing Wang, Gao KaiYue, Xu HanCheng, Chen ChuanJie, Qian Muyang, Dong BinYan, WangDeZhen, Acta Physica Sinica. 73(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404195751

                This article presents a comprehensive study on the streamer propagation and electric field distribution within a two-dimensional fluid model of a packed bed reactor (PBR) filled with carbon dioxide, utilizing the PASSKEy simulation platform. The research delves into the spatiotemporal evolution of electron density, electric fields and key plasma species in the discharge process. The model simulates a PBR with layered dielectric spheres, indicates that the inner sides of the first and second layers of dielectric spheres are not the primary regions for reactions such as CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; dissociation; instead, the main regions are along the streamer propagation path and the outer side of the first layer of dielectric spheres. The study by examining the propagation of streamers in the presence of an electric field, highlighting the influence of anode voltage rise and dielectric polarization on local electric field enhancement. This enhancement leads to increased electron density and temperature, facilitating streamer propagation and the formation of filamentary microdischarges and surface ionization waves. The article provides a detailed analysis of the local electric field evolution at specific points within the PBR. The research further investigates the spatiotemporal dynamics of spatial and surface charges, revealing that negative charges concentrate within the streamer and on the dielectric surface, with densities significantly higher than positive charges. The positive charges' distribution is closely related to the streamer's path, and over time, they come to dominate the charge distribution in the discharge space. The study also explores the surface charge deposition on the dielectric spheres, discusses the evolution trends of the distribution. Additionally, the article discusses the temporal and spatial evolution of key plasma species, including ions and radicals, and their contribution to the overall discharge characteristics. The production mechanisms of carbon monoxide particles, carbon dioxide ions, and oxygen ions are analyzed, with a focus on their spatial distribution and correlation with electron density. The study concludes with an examination of the energy deposition within the PBR, integrating the spatial energy deposition of electrons and major positive ions. The results indicate a total energy deposition value of approximately 1.428 mJ/m, with carbon dioxide ions accounting for 8.8% of this value.</description>
      <author>Peng Yi, Wang ChunJing, Jing Wang, Gao KaiYue, Xu HanCheng, Chen ChuanJie, Qian Muyang, Dong BinYan, WangDeZhen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.73.20241241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MINERALOGICAL, PETROGRAPHIC, AND LITHOCHEMICAL FEATURES OF THE UPPER JURASSIC&#8211;LOWER CRETACEOUS SECTION OF THE NORDVIK PENINSULA (NORTH OF EASTERN SIBERIA)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2113/rgg20244773</link>
      <description>A.Yu. Popov, &#1051;.&#1043;. &#1042;&#1072;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, B.L. Nikitenko, N. A. Palchik, Kirill Melnikov, Russian Geology and Geophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404109968

                Some intervals of the Jurassic&#8211;Cretaceous strata of the Anabar-Lena sedimentary basin have a certain oil and gas production potential, which can be realized in the synchronous offshore horizons of the adjacent territories of the Arctic shelf. Among the most representative objects in this regard are the outcrops of Upper Jurassic and Lower Cretaceous formations of the Nordvik Peninsula. The main data on the composition and structure of this section were obtained mainly at the beginning of the second half of last century. The results of complex mineralogical, petrographic, and lithochemical studies of the Urdyuk-Khaya and Paksa formations of Cape Urdyuk-Khaya of the Nordvik Peninsula presented in here enabled us to identify 10 boundaries for changing of sedimentation regimes of the paleobasin. It was found that the Urdyuk-Khaya Formation was formed mainly in the conditions of the shelf transition zone (moderate deep water) with low rates of terrigenous material intake, some depletion of oxygen in bottom waters, and a trend towards an increase in the depths of the basin. The basal stratum of the Paksa Formation was formed in offshore conditions with periodically occurring dioxic conditions in bottom waters and extremely low rates of terrigenous material intake. The overlying part of the formation was formed in various parts of offshore transition conditions with a gradual decrease in the depths of the basin, an increase in the oxygen content in the bottom layer of water, and the rate of terrigenous material intake. The main provenance area was igneous rocks of mafic, possibly intermediate composition. There was some influence of felsic igneous rocks, or ancient sedimentary rocks rich in quartz. The parent strata were subjected to moderate and severe chemical weathering, in a warm humid climate. The revealed features of the studied strata are similar to the characteristics of the same-age sediments of the lower reaches of the Anabar River, which determines their high correlation potential and allows us to judge the evolution of the western part of the Anabar-Lena basin.</description>
      <author>A.Yu. Popov, &#1051;.&#1043;. &#1042;&#1072;&#1082;&#1091;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, B.L. Nikitenko, N. A. Palchik, Kirill Melnikov</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2113/rgg20244773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Pivotal Role of Acid-Catalyzed Hydration in Electrochemical Carbon Corrosion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05547</link>
      <description>Seunghoon Lee, Haesol Kim, Minho M. Kim, Tae Kyung Ko, Hyung Min, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404172151

                Carbon, with its high electrical conductivity and large surface area, enables the efficient dispersion and utilization of catalytic entities, contributing to the cost-effective development of electrochemical systems for a future energy economy. However, the longevity of these systems is often compromised by carbon corrosion, the fundamental details of which unfortunately remain largely unknown. Here, we elucidate that carbon corrosion is initiated by a covalent addition reaction that chemically breaks the sp2 carbon network, prior to electrochemical oxidation steps. Online differential electrochemical mass spectroscopy and post-mortem X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy unveil the pseudozeroth- and first-order reaction kinetics in the proton concentration and oxygen coverage on the carbon surface, respectively, allowing us to suggest acid-catalyzed hydration with carbocation formation as the initial step in carbon corrosion. The proposed mechanism is further evidenced by the decreased carbon corrosion rate in the presence of the carbocation scavenger, methanol, and by the evolution of the C18O16O product during the corrosion of carbon, pretreated in acid solution prepared with the 18O-isotope of water. Based on these findings, previous empirical understandings, pH-dependent and site-specific (defect, edge, etc.) carbon corrosion characteristics, can be successfully explained, bringing potential avenues for developing rational strategies to mitigate carbon corrosion.</description>
      <author>Seunghoon Lee, Haesol Kim, Minho M. Kim, Tae Kyung Ko, Hyung Min, Hyungjun Kim, Chang Hyuck Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personalized &lt;i&gt;in silico&lt;/i&gt; model for radiation-induced pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2024.0525</link>
      <description>Eleftherios Ioannou, Myrianthi Hadjicharalambous, Anastasia Malai, Elisavet Papageorgiou, Antri Peraticou, Nicos Katodritis, Dimitrios Vomvas, Vasileios Vavourakis, Journal of The Royal Society Interface. 21(220)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404282542

                Radiation-induced pulmonary fibrosis (RIPF) is a severe late-stage complication of radiotherapy (RT) to the chest area, typically used in lung cancer treatment. This condition is characterized by the gradual and irreversible replacement of healthy lung tissue with fibrous scar tissue, leading to decreased lung function, reduced oxygen exchange and critical respiratory deficiencies. Currently, predicting and managing lung fibrosis post-RT remains challenging, with limited preventive and treatment options. Accurate prediction of fibrosis onset and progression is therefore clinically crucial. We present a personalized in silico model for pulmonary fibrosis that encompasses tumour regression, fibrosis development and lung tissue remodelling post-radiation. Our continuum-based model was developed using data from 12 RT-treated lung cancer patients and integrates computed tomography (CT) and dosimetry data to simulate the spatio-temporal evolution of fibrosis. We demonstrate the ability of the in silico model to capture the extent of fibrosis in the entire cohort with a less than 1% deviation from clinical observations, in addition to providing quantitative metrics of spatial similarity. These findings underscore the potential of the model to improve treatment planning and risk assessment, paving the way for more personalized and effective management of RIPF.</description>
      <author>Eleftherios Ioannou, Myrianthi Hadjicharalambous, Anastasia Malai, Elisavet Papageorgiou, Antri Peraticou, Nicos Katodritis, Dimitrios Vomvas, Vasileios Vavourakis</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2024.0525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative genomic characterization of Cellulosimicrobium funkei isolate RVMD1 from Ma&#8217;an desert rock varnish challenges Cellulosimicrobium systematics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2024.1445943</link>
      <description>Sulaiman Alnaimat, Saqr Abushattal, Saif M. Dmour, Frontiers in Microbiology. 15(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404144367

                Desert environments harbor unique microbial communities. This study focuses on Cellulosimicrobium funkei isolate RVMD1, isolated from rock varnish in the Ma&#8217;an Desert. Initial identification was achieved using 16S rRNA gene sequencing, followed by whole-genome sequencing (WGS) for comprehensive characterization. The genome comprises 4,264,015 base pairs (857 contigs) with a high G + C content of 74.59%. A total of 4,449 proteins were predicted. Comparative analysis utilizing OrthoANI, ANI, AAI, and dDDH metrics suggests that RVMD1 belongs to the C. cellulans group, with the highest similarity to C. funkei (97.71% ANI). Phylogenomic analysis of 43 Cellulosimicrobium genomes revealed significant heterogeneity within the genus. Our results challenge current systematics, with C. cellulans potentially representing up to 9 distinct genomospecies. Isolate RVMD1 shows genetic adaptations to its desert environment, including genes for denitrification, oxygen and sulfur cycling, and diverse hydrogen metabolism. Pangenomic analysis uncovered a considerable number of unique genes within RVMD1, highlighting its genetic distinctiveness. Gene family expansions suggest evolution in response to stressors like UV radiation and nutrient limitation. This study represents the first whole-genome analysis of a bacterium isolated from Jordanian rock varnish, emphasizing the value of WGS in understanding microbial diversity and adaptation in extreme environments.</description>
      <author>Sulaiman Alnaimat, Saqr Abushattal, Saif M. Dmour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmicb.2024.1445943</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protracted magma evolution and transcrustal magmatic plumbing system architecture at Erta Ale volcano (Afar, Ethiopia)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/petrology/egae118</link>
      <description>Juliette Pin, Gilles Chazot, Lyd&#233;ric France, B&#233;n&#233;dicte Abily, Andrey Gurenko, Herv&#233; Bertrand, Alexandra Loppin, Journal of Petrology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404246729

                Abstract The Afar region is one of the only places on Earth where magmatic continental rifting and associated ongoing break-up processes are exposed onshore. The several active magmatic segments there are characterized by contrasted morphologies, crustal thicknesses, magma production rates, and magma-tectonic styles. In the Erta Ale Range rift segment, extension is magmatically accommodated, making the range the ideal place to study the magmatic behavior of a mature rift segment. Erta Ale Range comprises sub-segments with magma compositions ranging from basalts to rhyolites, but only the Erta Ale Volcano (EAV) sub-segment is active, where only basaltic compositions have been reported so far. Here, we show for the first time protracted differentiation at EAV that is not expressed volcanically at the surface, but is rather accessible via unique cognate gabbroic and microgabbroic blocks, and recorded by mixing with erupted basaltic magmas. These cognate samples record previously unknown mushy and evolved parts of the EAV plumbing system. To constrain their origin and evolution, we measured the major and trace element compositions of the bulk rocks, interstitial glasses, and melt inclusions. We also measured the oxygen isotopic compositions of olivine crystals, interstitial glasses, and melt inclusions. By combining these results with textural relationships and oxy-thermo-barometry calculations, we discuss magma differentiation and storage conditions, as well as magmatic interactions during transport through the crust. Comparison of our results with rhyolite-MELTS thermodynamic models highlights that protracted fractional crystallization is the main process of magma evolution, and when associated with reactive porous flow is capable of forming the evolved compositions observed (up to 75 wt.% SiO2). We also use the model outputs to quantify distinct steps of igneous differentiation in both shallow and deep crustal reservoirs, and we highlight significant interactions with hydrothermally altered wall rocks. We discuss this model within the geological contexts of the Erta Ale Range rift segment and the larger Afar region, and highlight contrasts with mature oceanic systems to argue that the region is not in the final stages of continental break-up.</description>
      <author>Juliette Pin, Gilles Chazot, Lyd&#233;ric France, B&#233;n&#233;dicte Abily, Andrey Gurenko, Herv&#233; Bertrand, Alexandra Loppin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/petrology/egae118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding cold stress response mechanisms in plants: an overview</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2024.1443317</link>
      <description>Zhenfeng Qian, Lilian He, Fusheng Li, Frontiers in Plant Science. 15(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404121469

                Low-temperature stress significantly impacts plant growth, development, yield, and geographical distribution. However, during the long-term process of evolution, plants have evolved complicated mechanisms to resist low-temperature stress. The cold tolerance trait is regulated by multiple pathways, such as the Ca 2+ signaling cascade, mitogen-activated protein kinase (MAPK) cascade, inducer of CBF expression 1 (ICE1)-C-repeat binding factor (CBF)-cold-reulated gene (COR) transcriptional cascade, reactive oxygen species (ROS) homeostasis regulation, and plant hormone signaling. However, the specific responses of these pathways to cold stress and their interactions are not fully understood. This review summarizes the response mechanisms of plants to cold stress from four aspects, including cold signal perception and transduction, ICE1-CBF-COR transcription cascade regulation, ROS homeostasis regulation and plant hormone signal regulation. It also elucidates the mechanism of cold stress perception and Ca 2+ signal transduction in plants, and proposes the important roles of transcription factors (TFs), post-translational modifications (PTMs), light signals, circadian clock factors, and interaction proteins in the ICE1-CBF-COR transcription cascade. Additionally, we analyze the importance of ROS homeostasis and plant hormone signaling pathways in plant cold stress response, and explore the cross interconnections among the ICE1-CBF-COR cascade, ROS homeostasis, and plant hormone signaling. This comprehensive review enhances our understanding of the mechanism of plant cold tolerance and provides a molecular basis for genetic strategies to improve plant cold tolerance.</description>
      <author>Zhenfeng Qian, Lilian He, Fusheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fpls.2024.1443317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 Pioneers in Energy Research: Haoshen Zhou</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04314</link>
      <description>Ping He, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404134387

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. Energy &amp; FuelsASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialNovember 7, 20242024 Pioneers in Energy Research: Haoshen ZhouClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Ping He*Ping HeDepartment of Energy Science and Engineering, College of Engineering and Applied Sciences, Nanjing University, Nanjing, Jiangsu 210093, People's Republic of China*E-mail: [email protected] and/or [email protected]More by Ping Hehttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-1498-8203Open PDFEnergy &amp; FuelsCite this: Energy Fuels 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04314https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04314Published November 7, 2024 Publication History Received 31 October 2024Published online 7 November 2024editorial&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.BatteriesElectrodesElectrolytesLithiumMaterialsSpecial IssuePublished as part of Energy &amp; Fuels special issue "2024 Pioneers in Energy Research: Haoshen Zhou".Since 2021, Energy &amp; Fuels has established the annual recognition of Pioneers in Energy Research (PIERs) to honor highly influential scientists who have made significant contributions in their respective fields of energy research. (1&#8722;3) Professor Haoshen Zhou from Nanjing University, China, has been selected as the 2024 PIER in the field of batteries and energy storage for his outstanding contribution to the area of high energy density secondary battery materials and systems. (4) We are honored to have the opportunity to celebrate his outstanding contributions in this special issue (SI).Professor Haoshen Zhou received his bachelor's degree in semiconductor physics from the Department of Physics at Nanjing University in 1985, master's degree in 1988 from the Nanjing Institute of Electronic Devices, and Ph.D. in chemical engineering in the School of Engineering at The University of Tokyo, Japan, in 1994. After his Ph.D. study, he pursued a further 3 years of postdoctoral training at RIKEN in Japan. In 1997, Professor Haoshen Zhou joined the Energy Interface Department of the National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology (AIST), Japan, to pursue energy-related scientific research. He was promoted to a professor-level senior researcher in 2004 and became the chief senior researcher in AIST's Energy Department in 2011. During his tenure in Japan, Professor Zhou led numerous projects funded by the Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS), the Japan Science and Technology Agency (JST), the New Energy and Industrial Technology Development Organization (NEDO), and the Precursory Research for Embryonic Science and Technology (PRESTO). In 2012, he joined Nanjing University's College of Engineering and Applied Sciences as a full professor. Professor Zhou established the Department of Energy Science and Engineering and Center of Energy Storage Materials &amp; Technology, where he served as their inaugural chairs. He was also appointed as a Yangtse Distinguished Professor by the Chinese Ministry of Education (2010). He held concurrent appointments as a special professor at The University of Tokyo and University of Tsukuba in Japan. Professor Zhou has served as an associate editor of Science Bulletin and Energy Storage Materials as well as an expert in charge of the National Key R&amp;D Program's "Smart Grid Key Project" in China. During 2014&#8211;2018, he was the chief scientist for China's National Key Research Program in Nanotechnology. Professor Zhou received the "Lihua Yi" Chemical Innovation Award from the Chinese Chemical Society (2023) and the First Prize from the Chinese Materials Research Society (2024). Over his career, Professor Zhou has mentored more than 80 postdoctoral fellows and doctoral students, of which many have grown into emerging leaders in their respective research areas.Professor Haoshen Zhou has long been dedicated to the innovation and engineering of new high-energy-density battery systems and key materials. He established the reaction theory for high-capacity air electrodes, invented solid-state batteries based on sieving electrolytes, and developed and expanded the combined electrolyte battery system. As a corresponding author, he has published over 500 research papers and is a holder of over 80 authorized patents. Professor Zhou is a pioneer in the field of lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries, proposed a comprehensive mechanism for oxygen anion redox energy storage, and designed new high-energy-density lithium batteries. (5&#8722;9) Zhou and his team creatively introduced the "Li2O&#8211;Li2O2" oxygen anion redox process for charge storage, offering advantages such as high coulombic efficiency, good reversibility, and mild stability for the battery system. (6) He also discovered the critical role of trace amounts of H2O in enhancing the catalytic activity of oxygen reduction/evolution reaction (ORR/OER) processes in organic electrolytes, proposing a synergistic catalytic mechanism between H2O molecules and Ru/SP/MnO2 cathodes, leading to breakthrough in lithium&#8211;air batteries. (7) Building upon the oxygen anion redox energy storage mechanism, he designed various highly efficient catalysts (e.g., Ir and Ni) to expand the reversible capacity of the cathode and suppress oxygen evolution. (6,8) Professor Zhou also proposed a concentrated dual-salt LiFSI&#8211;LiNO3/DOL electrolyte to improve the high-rate performance of lithium metal anodes, delivering stable operation for 240 cycles at 8.0 mA cm&#8211;2 and an average coulombic efficiency of 99.14%. (9) He also invented a closed lithium&#8211;oxygen battery with a lithium metal anode and high-capacity Li2O cathode, achieving a practical specific energy of 513 Wh kg&#8211;1 and a charge&#8211;discharge cycle life exceeding 200 cycles. (8) Professor Zhou summarized the essential criteria for redox mediators (RMs) to function as catalysts in lithium&#8211;air batteries and revealed the catalytic mechanism of these soluble catalysts during the charging process: (1) 2RM&#8211; + 2e&#8211; = 2RM+ and (2) 2RM+ + Li2O2 = 2Li+ + O2 + 2RM. (10) This theory led to his pioneering use of trichloroethyl chloroformate (TCCF) as a soluble catalyst for not only significantly reducing the overpotential of the OER but also greatly enhancing the reaction rate of the oxygen electrode. (11) The innovation improved the rate performance of lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries by over 10 times, with the cathode achieving a discharge specific capacity of 2005 mAh g&#8211;1 at a current density of 1 A g&#8211;1.Professor Haoshen Zhou has also made groundbreaking contributions to the study of lithium&#8211;carbon dioxide (Li&#8211;CO2) batteries, high-energy-density batteries without lithium anodes, and development of new battery systems. He introduced in situ surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) to the study of CO2 electrode reactions, proposing the reaction mechanism for the reversible reduction and evolution of CO2 at the air electrode interface: 3CO2 + 4e&#8211; + 4Li+ = 2Li2CO3 + C. (12) He further introduced molten salt electrolytes, which verified the reversible reaction pathway of CO2 at the air electrode, reduced the electrode overpotential, and significantly improved the energy storage efficiency of the battery. (13) Professor Zhou and his team were the first to propose a lithium supplementation mechanism based on the OER of Li2O, successfully addressing the issue of capacity degradation caused by lithium loss during charge and discharge cycles. (14) A prototype anode-free lithium-ion battery with a layered transition metal oxide cathode was designed and operated, achieving a specific energy of 320 Wh kg&#8211;1 and a cycle life of 300 cycles. Professor Zhou also creatively introduced the concept of a combined electrolyte, constructed from "organic electrolytes", "lithium-ion solid electrolytes", and "aqueous electrolytes", integrating the characteristics of two or more electrolytes to design multiple energy conversion systems, leading to the invention of a high-capacity lithium&#8211;air battery and a technology for directly extracting elemental lithium from seawater. (15) The pioneering concept of combined electrolytes further led to the demonstration of an electrolytic cell system that has achieved both lithium extraction from seawater (or brine) and conversion of electrical energy into the chemical energy of lithium as a new energy storage solution. (16)Professor Zhou and his team further expanded the concept of combined electrolytes to integrate molecular sieves or framework compounds with organic electrolytes for successfully mitigating dendrite growth and side reactions on the anode surface, enhancing the stability of high-capacity lithium secondary batteries at high voltages (greater than 5.2 V versus Li/Li+) and elevated temperatures (100 &#176;C). (17) This achievement is significant for expanding the application scenarios of electrolytes in high-output voltage systems and improving the energy density of various battery configurations. Professor Zhou then introduced the Cu3(BTC)2 metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) as a selective electrolyte in lithium&#8211;sulfur battery systems for effectively preventing polysulfide ions from shuttling to the lithium metal side, significantly reducing capacity loss with an average capacity decay of only 0.019% over 1500 cycles. (18) He also invented a polypropylene ultrathin membrane modified with MOFs that greatly enhances the cycle life of lithium metal battery systems while increasing energy density, achieving a specific energy of 354 Wh kg&#8211;1 and 80% retention of its initial capacity after 200 cycles. (19)To celebrate the achievement of Professor Zhou as one of the 2024 PIERs, Energy &amp; Fuels is also pleased to present this SI that includes a collection of 41 invited papers (22 reviews, 18 articles, and 1 communication), contributed by some invited leading as well as early to mid-career authors in the related energy field. As listed in Table 1, these research articles reflect some of the latest developments in the topics of lithium-ion batteries, sodium-ion batteries, zinc-ion batteries, solid-state batteries, high-energy-density Li&#8211;air and Li&#8211;S batteries, and other batteries and energy storage. A concise synopsis of each article, with invited author(s) being explicitly mentioned, is given below.Table 1. List of Papers Published in the "2024 Pioneers in Energy Research: Haoshen Zhou" Special Issuetopicfirst and corresponding author(s)institution of the corresponding authortitle (DOI)article typelithium-ion batteriesBai and Chang (20)Central South UniversityPerspective on Recent Advances of Functional Electrolytes for Lithium Metal Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01525)reviewXu and Liang and Yu (21)Beijing University of TechnologyEthylene Carbonate-Free Electrolytes for High Voltage Lithium-Ion Batteries: Progress and Perspectives (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02728)reviewFeng (22)Changshu Institute of TechnologyRecycling Electrode Materials of Spent Lithium-Ion Batteries for High-Efficiency Catalyst Application: Recent Advances and Perspectives (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02887)reviewLin and Wang (23)Westlake UniversityUnderstanding Lithium Hydride in Lithium Metal Batteries: Advances, Controversies, and Perspectives (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02962)reviewZhu and Peng and Wang (24)Shanghai University of Electric Power and Fudan UniversityRoles of MXene-Based Hybrids in Fabricating Flexible Anodes for Advanced Lithium-Ion Batteries: A Mini Review (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03154)reviewLiu and Liu (25)Tianjin University of TechnologyV2CTx MXene-Encapsulated Liquid Metal Composite as an Anode for Wide-Temperature Li-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02162)articleWang and He (26)Nanjing UniversityElectrochemical Performance and In Situ Phase Transition Analysis of Iron-Doped Lithium Manganese Phosphate (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02173)articleCai and Gan and Song (27)Wuhan UniversityFlavanthrone: From Vat Dye to Organic Cathode Material for Rechargeable Lithium Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02884)articleRen and Li and Chen (28)Hainan University, Nanjing University, and Foshan UniversityThree-Phase Transition of Spinel Li4Ti5O12 with a Dense Single Particle Microelectrode in Li-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02614)articleMcCrystall and Coleman and Konkena (29)Trinity College DublinLiquid Processed Nano As4S4/SWCNTs Composite Electrodes for High-Performance Li-Ion and Na-Ion Battery Anodes (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03525)articleLi and Wei and Bai (30)Fuzhou UniversityPermselective Metal&#8211;Organic Framework-Based Separators via In Situ Self-Assembly for High-Performance Lithium Metal Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02776)articlesodium-ion batteriesZhang and Li (31)Zhengzhou UniversityPerspective on Phase Transition in Layered Oxide Cathodes for Sodium-Ion Batteries: Mechanism, Influenced Factors, and Inhibition Strategies (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02631)reviewGao and Wang (32)Shanghai Jiao Tong UniversityLayered Oxide Cathode Materials for Sodium-Ion Batteries: A Mini Review (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02769)reviewQu and Li (33)Nankai UniversityRecent Advances and Practical Challenges in Organic Electrolytes of Sodium-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01974)reviewFeng and Guo (34)Nanjing UniversityEntropy Strategy for Stabilizing O&#8242;3-NaMnO2-Layered Cathodes for Sodium-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02633)articleLi and Zeng, Wei, and Qian (35)Fujian Normal University and Fuzhou UniversityBiSb Alloy Anchored on Selenium Doped Carbon Nanofibers as Highly Stable Anode Materials for Sodium/Potassium-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02349)articleLi and Zhang, Li, and Chen (36)Hainan University and Foshan UniversityPreparation of Hard&#8211;Soft Carbon via Co-Carbonization for the Enhanced Plateau Capacity of Sodium-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02025)articleZhang and Cao, Sun, and Jiang (37)Nanjing Normal University and Chinese Academy of ForestryUnraveling the Microcrystalline Carbon Evolution Mechanism of Biomass-Derived Hard Carbon for Sodium-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00823)articlezinc-ion batteriesLiu and Liu and Zhang (38)Anhui UniversityMinireview and Perspectives on Functional Electrolyte Additives for Aqueous Zinc-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02552)reviewWang and Wang (39)Qingdao UniversityElectrochemically Active Mn2+ Enabling High-Performance Aqueous Zinc Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02624)articleGuo and Li and Yu (40)China Rare Earth Group Research Institute and East China University of TechnologyPromising Electrolyte Additive-Induced Multifunctional Alloy Interphase Enabling Stable Zinc Anodes for Aqueous Zinc-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01836)articlesolid-state batteriesWang and Wang and Yi (41)Northeastern University at Qinhuangdao and Suzhou University of Science and TechnologyReview on Interface Issues between a Garnet Li7La3Zr2O12 Solid Electrolyte and Li Anode: Advances and Perspectives (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02506)reviewBao and Sun (42)Sun Yat-sen UniversityEnhanced Ionic Conduction in Metal&#8211;Organic-Framework-Based Quasi-Solid-State Electrolytes: Mechanistic Insights (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01821)articleLiu and Li and Zhu and Zhao (43)The Chinese University of Hong KongRoom-Temperature, All-Solid-State Electrolyte Based on a Polymeric Single-Ion Conductor (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02740)communicationhigh-energy-density Li&#8211;air and Li&#8211;S batteriesZhang, Cheng and Mu (44)Jiangsu University, Delft University of Technology, and Nanjing University of Science and TechnologyRecent Advances and Perspectives of High-Entropy Alloys as Electrocatalysts for Metal-Air Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03386)reviewYe and Liao (45)Nanjing Tech UniversityFrom Li&#8211;O2 to Li&#8211;Air Batteries: Challenges and Progress on Oxygen Permeable Membranes (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02606)reviewZeng and Qiao (46)Xiamen UniversityProgress in Sealed Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries Based on the Oxygen Anion Charge Compensation Mechanism (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03663)reviewChen and Zhen and Li (47)Northeastern University and Institute of Metal Research, Chinese Academy of SciencesBoosting Energy Storage in Metal Batteries by Light: Progress, Challenges, and Perspectives (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02588)reviewChi and Wu (48)Tianjin UniversityMinireview: Design of Cathode Structures for Solid-State Lithium&#8211;Air Batteries&#9472;Learning from Solid Oxide Fuel Cells (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02505)reviewGu and Sun and Zhang (49)University of Chinese Academy of SciencesAlloy Drills Regulate MOF-Derived Carbon as a Recyclable Air Cathode (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02610)articleWang and Liu and Yi (50)Shanghai UniversitySuperoxide Radical Capture Agent for a Stable and Efficient Li-CO2 Battery: Experimental and Density Functional Theory Studies (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01730)articleYang and He (51)Northwestern Polytechnical UniversityMultifunction of MXene in Lithium&#8211;Sulfur Batteries: A Review (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02385)reviewShi and Liu, Zheng, and Zhu (52)Osaka University and Harbin Engineering UniversityReview and Perspectives on Preparation Strategies and Applications of Ti3C2 MXene for Li Metal Batteries/Li&#8211;S Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02106)reviewKuroda and Ishikawa (53)Kansai UniversityOptimization of the Chemical Li Predoping Process of S-Confined Microporous Activated Carbon Positive Electrodes for Li&#8211;S Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03554)articleLi and Liu and Li (54)Shaanxi Normal UniversityMono-Element Boron Nanomaterials for Energy Conversion and Storage: Preparation, Recent Progress, and Perspectives (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02646)reviewother batteries and energy storageLiu and Wang (55)Jilin UniversityRecent Research Progress and Perspectives on Porphyrin and Phthalocyanine Analogues for Perovskite Solar Cell Applications (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02136)reviewGong and Zhang (56)Zhengzhou UniversityMetal&#8211;Single Atom Support Interactions for Enhancing Proton-Exchange Membrane Fuel Cell Cathode Stability: A Review (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02727)reviewZhao and Tong (57)Jinhua Advanced Research InstituteRecent Progress and Perspectives on Metal&#8211;Organic Framework-Based Electrode Materials for Metal-Ion Batteries and Supercapacitors (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02337)reviewZheng and Wang and Pang (58)Yangzhou UniversityReview: Synthesis and Catalytic Application of MOF Complexes Containing Noble Metals (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01963)reviewWu and Liao (59)Nanjing Tech UniversityKinetics of Active Seed-Induced Al(OH)3 Precipitation from NaAlO2 Solution for Recycling Aluminum from Spent Lithium-Ion Batteries (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02346)articleZhao, Zhang, and Shu and Yu, Chun, and Shu (60)Nankai University and Ningbo UniversityStabilizing Low-Spin Position by Iron&#8211;Manganese Coexistence in Hexacyanoferrate for Efficient Aqueous Nickel-Ion Storage (10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01001)articleLithium-Ion BatteriesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!A total of 11 papers (5 reviews and 6 articles) are on lithium-ion batteries (LIBs). Electrolytes, a critical component of batteries, play a pivotal role in promoting ionic and charge transport and forming a solid&#8211;electrolyte interphase (SEI). Chang et al. reviewed the characteristics and commonalities of different electrolyte formulations. Inspiring methods to further optimize electrolyte compositions and structures based on novel solvents for practical LIBs are also proposed. (20) Yu et al. reviewed scientific challenges, design strategies, action mechanisms, and latest progresses of ethylene carbonate (EC)-free electrolytes in high-energy-density LIBs. The design principle, advantages, and disadvantages of each electrolyte (carbonate, fluorinate, sulfone, and nitrile based) and their functions are discussed in detail. (21) Feng et al. summarized the available technologies for recycling LIBs and addressed the advantages and disadvantages of different processes. Some scientific challenges and perspectives for recycling and reutilizing spent LIBs as efficient catalysts are also put forward. (22) Wang et al. summarized the latest advancements in lithium hydride dendrite research, discussed the prevailing controversies, and outlined future perspectives in the field. (23) Wang et al. provided a comprehensive overview of recent advances in developing MXenes and their hybrids as flexible electrodes for advanced LIBs; this includes the synthesis, characterization, and structural modification of MXene-based materials and their ability to improve electrochemical performance from the viewpoint of fundamental to various applications. (24) Liu et al. prepared a porous V2CTx-encapsulated liquid GaInSn alloy as an anode for LIBs, which demonstrated excellent electrochemical performance at wide temperatures. Olivine LiMnPO4 cathode materials are favored for their low cost and higher operating voltage compared to those of LiFePO4. (25) He et al. prepared LiMnxFe1&#8211;xPO4/C (x = 0.7, 0.8, and 0.9) cathode materials by solid-state reaction and performed better in cyclic stability, rate capability, and capacity retention. (26) It is a huge challenge to overcome the dissolution problem for cathode materials, especially for small-molecule organic cathode materials (SMOCMs). Song et al. investigated a commercially available vat dye, namely, flavanthrone, directly as a novel SMOCM for rechargeable lithium batteries. It possesses a low solubility benefiting from the extensive aromatic system and a high theoretical capacity based on the four electroactive C&#9552;O/C&#9552;N groups. (27) Chen et al. prepared a dense Li4Ti5O12 single-particle microelectrode, and its electrochemical properties are measured over a wide voltage window in LIBs, which delivered an ultralow-potential discharge plateau. (28) Konkena et al. demonstrated the liquid-phase exfoliation of non-layered, bulk As4S4 material to produce quasi-two-dimensional (2D) platelets. The As4S4 anode with highly disordered, low aspect ratio quasi-2D platelets exhibits commendable performance for both Li-ion and Na-ion storage. (29) Bai et al. demonstrated an in situ self-assembly strategy where metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) grew on a polypropylene separator. This MOF-based separator achieves permselective ion transport and regulation behavior, which effectively suppresses the nucleation and growth of Li dendrites. (30)Sodium-Ion BatteriesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!A total of 7 papers (3 reviews and 4 articles) are on sodium-ion batteries (SIBs). SIBs have great potential for large-scale energy storage devices due to the high abundance, wide distribution, and non-toxicity of the resource. Li et al. reviewed the phase transition in layered oxide cathodes, pointing out the intrinsic causes and degradation mechanisms of phase transition for SIBs. They summarize the mainstream strategies to inhibit the phase transition, such as elemental doping, surface coating, and structural modification as well as the novel strategy of introducing anionic redox, providing new comprehension in understanding the phase transition of layered oxides. (31) Wang et al. presented a thorough discussion of the current research progress on layered transition metal oxides (LTMOs) beginning with an explanation of the structure characteristics of P- and O-phase cathode materials. Three primary modification strategies are outlined to address the challenges faced by LTMOs: element doping, surface coating, and structure design. (32) Li et al. collated recent advances and fundamental design principles of organic electrolytes in terms of sodium salts, solvents, and functional additives. They also discuss the crucial challenges for SIBs, including high operating voltage, wide working temperature range, and fast charge rate. The corresponding solution strategies are introduced for the desired organic electrolytes in high-performance SIBs. (33) Guo et al. employed an entropy strategy for stabilizing O&#8242;3-NaMn0.8Mg0.06Ti0.06Fe0.04Al0.04O2 (NMO-MTFA)-layered cathodes for SIBs, which not only stabilized the crystal structure but also enhanced both the bulk and surface/interface kinetics. (34) Qian et al. developed Se-doped CNFs with rationally integrated BiSb nanocrystals as anode materials for SIBs/potassium-ion batteries (PIBs), presenting a promising pathway for fabricating innovative transition metal dichalcogenide electrode materials. (35) Chen et al. synthesized a composite carbon material with a rich closed-pore structure and a mass of long-range ordered soft carbon phase as a highly efficient anode material for SIBs. This hard&#8211;soft composite carbon material features plenty of closed pores, which facilitates the storage of sodium ions and endows anodes with high-energy and reversible low-potential plateaus (&lt;0.1 V). (36) Cao et al. conducted a systematic study of the evolutionary mechanism of microcrystalline carbon using lignin and cellulose as models, providing theoretical guidance for the design of high-performance biomass-derived hard carbon for SIBs. (37)Zinc-Ion BatteriesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!A total of 3 papers (1 review and 2 articles) are on zinc-ion batteries (ZIBs). ZIBs are viewed as promising grid-level energy storage solutions due to their high theoretical specific capacity (820 Ah kg&#8211;1 and 5855 Ah L&#8211;1), low electrochemical potential, ample geological resources, and compatibility with water. Zhang et al. comprehensively overviewed the functional role of the electrolyte additive in aqueous zinc-ion batteries (AZIBs), including regulating the solvation structure, altering the H-bond network, forming an adsorption layer, generating an electrostatic shielding effect, and constructing a solid electrolyte interphase. The development prospects and existing problems of additives are also presented. (38) Wang et al. introduced certain MnSO4 into the ZnSO4 + K2SO4 hybrid electrolyte (Zn0.5K0.25) to improve the AZIBs. MnSO4 in the hybrid electrolyte facilitates the porous MnO2 electrodeposition on PBAs, resulting in an increased contact area at the electrode/electrolyte interface, thereby accelerating the electrochemical reaction kinetics. (39) Yu et al. introduced a cost-effective copper sulfate additive, enabling the creation of a multifunctional Cu&#8211;Zn alloy solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) layer on the zinc anode. The SEI's superior electrical conductivity, zincophilic sites, ample free space, and elevated surface energy facilitate homogeneous Zn nucleation and deposition, thereby expediting electrochemical kinetics and mitigates dendrite formation. (40)Solid-State BatteriesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!A total of 3 papers (1 review, 1 article, and 1 communication) are on solid-state batteries (SSBs). SSBs, characterized by increasing energy density and enhanced security features, hold the promise of overcoming the constraints faced by traditional liquid lithium-ion batteries. Yi et al. comprehensively examined the mechanistic underpinnings of interface issues arising from the interaction between Li7La3Zr2O12 (LLZO) and a lithium anode. This review surveys the latest advancements and improvement methodologies employed to mitigate these concerns, aiming to propel the advancement of solid-state battery technology. (41) Sun et al. synthesized a series of MOFs to create MOF-based quasi-solid-state electrolytes and explored the structure&#8211;property relationships between tunable MOFs and MOF electrolytes for lithium metal batteries. They systematically investigate the effects of different metal active sites and ligand groups on their electrochemical performance. (42) Zhao et al. reported a solvent-free, free-standing single Li+-ion conductor with an ethylene&#8211;vinyl alcohol main chain and sulfonated poly(ethylene oxide) side chains. The ion transport behavior of this single Li+-ion conductor is investigated with variable ethylene and vinyl alcohol constituents in the main chain and variable chain length and distance in the side chains. (43)High-Energy-Density Li&#8211;Air and Li&#8211;S BatteriesClick to copy section linkSection link copied!A total of 11 papers (8 reviews and 3 articles) are on high-energy-density Li&#8211;air and Li&#8211;S batteries. Li&#8211;air and Li&#8211;S batteries have garnered extensive attention and research efforts due to their high theoretical specific energy, safety, and environmental friendliness. Mu et al. reviewed the reaction mechanism and challenges of the representative metal&#8211;air batteries, including Li&#8211;O2, Li&#8211;CO2, and Zn&#8211;air batteries, and introduced some research progress on high-entropy alloys in these batteries. (44) However, traditional open Li&#8211;O2 battery systems face many significant challenges, such as external moisture infiltration and sluggish electrochemical kinetics within the battery. Liao et al. comprehensively reviewed the five conditions necessary for oxygen-permeable membranes suitable for Li&#8211;air batteries: oxygen permeability, selectivity, waterproof performance, electrolyte resistance, and long-term stability, detailing their importance and influencing factors. (45) Qiao et al. focused on the sealed Li&#8211;O2 battery systems based on the oxide&#8211;peroxide (superoxide) conversion mechanism and p</description>
      <author>Ping He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c04314</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur-bearing molecules in a sample of early star-forming cores</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202452350</link>
      <description>N. C. Martinez, S. Par&#243;n, M. E. Ortega, A. Petriella, A. Guti&#233;rrez del &#193;lamo, Michael A. Brook, C. Carballo, Tamra Heberling, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404174587

                The sulfur content in dense molecular regions is highly depleted in comparison to diffuse clouds. The reason for this phenomenon is unclear, and it is therefore necessary to carry out observational studies of sulfur-bearing species toward dense regions, mainly in early evolution stages. In this context, the analysis of sulfur-bearing molecules in a large sample of dense starless molecular cores is of great importance to help us uncover the early sulfur chemistry in these regions. From the Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA) data archive, we selected a project in Band 7 (275--373 GHz), which contains the emission of several sulfur-bearing species. The observations were performed toward a sample of 37 dense cores that are embedded in the most massive infrared-quiet molecular clumps from the ATLASGAL survey. The lines of 34SO, SO$_ $, NS, SO, SO$^ $, and H$_ $CS were analyzed, and the column densities of each molecular species were obtained. Based on the continuum emission and two CH$_ $OH lines, the 37 cores were characterized in density and temperature, and the corresponding H$_ $ column densities were derived. The abundances of these sulfur-bearing species were derived and studied. We find that the abundances of the analyzed sulfur-bearing species increase with increasing gas temperature. Based on the correlation between abundances and temperature, we suggest that the chemistry involved in the formation of each of the analyzed molecules may similarly depend on T$_ k $ in the range 20 to 100 K. Additionally, we find that the comparisons among abundances are highly correlated in general. Taking into account that this correlation decreases in more evolved sources, we suggest that the sulfur-bearing species we analyzed have a similar chemical origin. Our observational results show that the X(SO$_ $)/X(SO) ratio can be used as a chemical clock of molecular cores. Based on the line widths of the molecular lines, we point out that molecules with an oxygen content (34SO, SO$_ $, SO, and SO$^ $) may be associated with warmer and more turbulent gas than the other molecules. H$_ $CS and NS are associated with more quiescent gas, probably in the external envelopes of the cores, which trace similar physical and chemical conditions. We complement recent similar works done toward more evolved sources with a large sample of sources, but also provide quantitative information about abundances that might be useful in chemical models for explaining the sulfur chemistry in the interstellar medium.</description>
      <author>N. C. Martinez, S. Par&#243;n, M. E. Ortega, A. Petriella, A. Guti&#233;rrez del &#193;lamo, Michael A. Brook, C. Carballo, Tamra Heberling</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202452350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eLife Assessment: Archaic introgression contributed to shape the adaptive modulation of angiogenesis and cardiovascular traits in human high-altitude populations from the Himalayas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.89815.3.sa0</link>
      <description>Emilia Huerta&#8208;S&#225;nchez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404185659

                Full text Figures and data Peer review Side by side eLife Assessment This study presents valuable findings on what networks of genes were impacted by introgression from Denisovans, to identify the biological functions involved in high-altitude adaptation in Tibet. This study applies solid and previously validated methodology to identify genes with signatures of both introgression and positive selection. This paper would be of interest to population geneticists, anthropologists, and scientists studying the genetic basis underlying high-altitude adaptation. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.89815.3.sa0 Significance of the findings: Valuable: Findings that have theoretical or practical implications for a subfield Landmark Fundamental Important Valuable Useful Strength of evidence: Solid: Methods, data and analyses broadly support the claims with only minor weaknesses Exceptional Compelling Convincing Solid Incomplete Inadequate During the peer-review process the editor and reviewers write an eLife Assessment that summarises the significance of the findings reported in the article (on a scale ranging from landmark to useful) and the strength of the evidence (on a scale ranging from exceptional to inadequate). Learn more about eLife Assessments Abstract Introduction Results Discussion Materials and methods Data availability References Article and author information Metrics Abstract It is well established that several Homo sapiens populations experienced admixture with extinct human species during their evolutionary history. Sometimes, such a gene flow could have played a role in modulating their capability to cope with a variety of selective pressures, thus resulting in archaic adaptive introgression events. A paradigmatic example of this evolutionary mechanism is offered by the EPAS1 gene, whose most frequent haplotype in Himalayan highlanders was proved to reduce their susceptibility to chronic mountain sickness and to be introduced in the gene pool of their ancestors by admixture with Denisovans. In this study, we aimed at further expanding the investigation of the impact of archaic introgression on more complex adaptive responses to hypobaric hypoxia evolved by populations of Tibetan/Sherpa ancestry, which have been plausibly mediated by soft selective sweeps and/or polygenic adaptations rather than by hard selective sweeps. For this purpose, we used a combination of composite-likelihood and gene network-based methods to detect adaptive loci in introgressed chromosomal segments from Tibetan WGS data and to shortlist those presenting Denisovan-like derived alleles that participate to the same functional pathways and are absent in populations of African ancestry, which are supposed to do not have experienced Denisovan admixture. According to this approach, we identified multiple genes putatively involved in archaic introgression events and that, especially as regards TBC1D1, RASGRF2, PRKAG2, and KRAS, have plausibly contributed to shape the adaptive modulation of angiogenesis and of certain cardiovascular traits in high-altitude Himalayan peoples. These findings provided unprecedented evidence about the complexity of the adaptive phenotype evolved by these human groups to cope with challenges imposed by hypobaric hypoxia, offering new insights into the tangled interplay of genetic determinants that mediates the physiological adjustments crucial for human adaptation to the high-altitude environment. Introduction The scientific community currently agrees that the Homo sapiens species experienced admixture with extinct Hominins since traces of such inbreeding events are still detectable in the genomes of modern humans (Gouy and Excoffier, 2020). In fact, people belonging to non-African populations show 1&#8211;2% of Neanderthal ancestry (Green et al., 2010; Pr&#252;fer et al., 2014), while Melanesians and East-Asians present 3% and 0.2% of Denisovan ancestry, respectively (Reich et al., 2010; Meyer et al., 2013; Pr&#252;fer et al., 2014; Racimo et al., 2017). Despite evidence supporting selection against introgressed alleles has been collected (Simonti et al., 2016; Racimo et al., 2017; McArthur et al., 2021), some of the genomic segments showing signatures ascribable to archaic introgression were also proved to have been targeted by natural selection in modern human populations, thus providing examples for the occurrence of adaptive introgression (AI) events (Racimo et al., 2017). So far, several studies have indeed identified introgressed archaic alleles at high frequency in human genes involved in metabolism or in the response to environmental conditions, such as temperature, sunlight, and altitude (Pr&#252;fer et al., 2014; Vernot and Akey, 2014; Sankararaman et al., 2014; Huerta-S&#225;nchez et al., 2014; Gittelman et al., 2016; Racimo et al., 2017; Enard and Petrov, 2018; Dannemann and Racimo, 2018). Moreover, some genes that play a role in immune responses to pathogens are found to be characterized by a similar pattern of variability (Laurent et al., 2011; Enard and Petrov, 2018) and certain Neanderthal alleles have been shown to be associated with down-regulation of gene expression in brain and testes (McCoy et al., 2017; Racimo et al., 2017; Dannemann and Racimo, 2018). These works collectively attest how genetic variants introduced in the human gene pool by admixture with archaic species can significantly impact our biology by possibly comporting modifications in the modulation of several functional pathways. In particular, the high frequency of some archaic alleles in protein-coding and/or regulatory genomic regions suggests a possible adaptive role for Neanderthal and/or Denisovan variants, pointing to a further evolutionary mechanism having potentially contributed to the processes of human biological adaptation to different environmental and cultural settings. By introducing new alleles in the gene pool of a given population, admixture in fact provides a very rapid opportunity for natural selection to act on it (Huerta-S&#225;nchez et al., 2014; Jeong et al., 2014; Racimo et al., 2015; Hamid et al., 2021) and this is supposed to have likely occurred during the evolutionary history of H. sapiens, particularly after the last Out of Africa migration in the late Pleistocene (Sugden, 2018; Vahdati et al., 2022). According to this view, gene flow from extinct Hominin species could have facilitated the adaptation of H. sapiens populations to peculiar Eurasian environments. For instance, a Denisovan origin of the adaptive EPAS1 haplotype, which confers reduced susceptibility to chronic mountain sickness to Tibetan and Sherpa highlanders (Beall, 2007; Bigham et al., 2010; Yi et al., 2010; Peng et al., 2011; Xu et al., 2011) is well established (Huerta-S&#225;nchez et al., 2014; Zhang et al., 2021). However, the hard selective sweep experienced in high-altitude Himalayan populations by the EPAS1 introgressed haplotype has been demonstrated to account only for an indirect aspect of their adaptive phenotype, which does not explain most of the physiological adjustments they evolved to cope with hypobaric hypoxia (Gnecchi-Ruscone et al., 2018). Therefore, how far gene flow between Denisovans and the ancestors of Tibetan/Sherpa peoples facilitated the evolution of other key adaptive traits of these populations remains to be elucidated. To fill this gap, and to overcome the main limitation of most approaches currently used to test for AI (i.e., inferring archaic introgression and the action of natural selection separately by means of different algorithms, which increases the risk of obtaining biased results due to confounding variables), we assembled a dataset of whole-genome sequences (WGSs) from 27 individuals of Tibetan ancestry living at high altitude (Cho et al., 2017; Jeong et al., 2018) and we analysed it using a composite-likelihood method specifically developed to detect AI events at once (Setter et al., 2020). Notably, this method was designed to recognize AI mediated by subtle selective events (as those involved in polygenic adaptation) and/or soft selective sweeps, which represent the evolutionary mechanisms that are supposed to have played a more relevant role than hard selective sweeps during the adaptive history of human groups characterized by particularly small effective population size, such as Tibetans and Sherpa (Gnecchi-Ruscone et al., 2018). Coupled with validation of the identified putative adaptive introgressed loci through (1) the assessment of the composition of gene networks made up of functionally related DNA segments presenting archaic derived alleles that are absent in human groups which are supposed to do not have experienced Denisovan admixture, such as African ones, (2) the confirmation that natural selection targeted these genomic regions in populations of Tibetan ancestry, and (3) the quantification of genetic distance between modern and archaic haplotypes, such an approach provided new evidence about the biological functions that have mediated high-altitude adaptation in Himalayan populations and that have been favourably shaped by admixture of their ancestors with Denisovans. Results Spatial distribution of genomic variation and ancestry components of Tibetan samples After quality control (QC) filtering of the available WGS data, we obtained a dataset made up of 27 individuals of Tibetan ancestry characterized for 6,921,628 single-nucleotide variants (SNVs). To assess whether this dataset represents a reliable proxy for the genomic variation observable in high-altitude Himalayan populations, we merged it with genome-wide genotyping data for 1086 individuals of East-Asian ancestry belonging to both low- and high-altitude groups (Gnecchi-Ruscone et al., 2017; Landini et al., 2021). We thus obtained an extended dataset including 231,947 SNVs (Supplementary file 1a), which was used to perform population structure analyses. Results from ADMIXTURE and principal components analysis (PCA) were found to be concordant with those described in previous studies (Jeong et al., 2014; Gnecchi-Ruscone et al., 2017; Gnecchi-Ruscone et al., 2018; Yang et al., 2021). According to the ADMIXTURE model showing the best predictive accuracy (K = 7) (Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 1), the examined WGS exhibited a predominant genetic component that was appreciably represented also in other populations speaking Tibeto-Burman languages, such as Tu, Yizu, Naxi, Lahu, and Sherpa (Figure 1A and Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 2). Such a component reached an average proportion of around 78% in individuals of Tibetan ancestry from Nepal included in the extended dataset, as well as of more than 80% in the subjects under investigation, who live in the Nepalese regions of Mustang and Ghorka (Figure 1A, B). This suggests that after their relatively recent migration in Nepalese high-altitude valleys, these communities might have experienced a higher degree of isolation and genetic drift with respect to populations that are still settled on the Tibetan Plateau, in which the same ancestry fraction did not exceed 64% (Figure 1A, B). Nevertheless, the overall ADMIXTURE profile of the considered WGS appeared to be quite comparable to those inferred according to genome-wide genotyping data for other Tibetan populations (Figure 1A, B, Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 2). Similarly, PCA pointed to the expected divergence of Tibetan and Sherpa high-altitude groups from the cline of genomic variation of East-Asian lowland populations (Abdulla et al., 2009; Jeong et al., 2014; Gnecchi-Ruscone et al., 2017; Zhang et al., 2017; Wang et al., 2022; Figure 1C). Remarkably, the WGS under investigation clustered within the bulk of genome-wide data generated for other groups from the Tibetan Plateau, thus supporting their representativeness as concerns the overall genetic background of high-altitude Himalayan populations. Figure 1 with 2 supplements see all Download asset Open asset Population structure analyses performed on the extended dataset including Tibetan, Sherpa, and lowland East-Asian individuals. (A) Admixture analysis showed the best predictive accuracy when seven (K = 7) population clusters were tested. Populations included in the dataset are labelled according to population names and acronyms reported in Supplementary file 1a. (B) Map showing geographic location and admixture proportions at K = 7 of the high-altitude groups included in the extended dataset. The label Tibetans_WG indicates whole-genome sequence data for individuals of Tibetan ancestry analysed in the present study. Additional information about the considered samples (e.g., number of individuals per group, reference study, and used abbreviations) are reported in Supplementary file 1a. (C) Principal components analysis (PCA) plot considering PC1 vs PC2 and summarizing genomic divergence between high-altitude Tibetan/Sherpa people and the cline of variation observable for lowland East-Asian populations. The enlarged square displays clustering between Tibetan samples sequenced for the whole genome (i.e., blue dots) and Tibetan samples characterized by genome-wide data (i.e., light-blue squares). Detecting putative AI signatures in Tibetan genomes To identify genomic regions showing signatures putatively ascribable to AI events, we scanned Tibetan WGS with the VolcanoFinder algorithm and we computed the composite likelihood ratio (LR) and &#8722;log&#945; statistics for each polymorphic site (Setter et al., 2020). We then considered the most significant results by focusing on loci showing LR values falling in the positive tail (i.e., top 5%) of the obtained distribution (see Materials and methods, Supplementary file 1b). According to such an approach, we were first able to recapitulate the AI event previously described for the EPAS1 gene (Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 1A; Huerta-S&#225;nchez et al., 2014; Hu et al., 2017; Zhang et al., 2021). In fact, this chromosomal interval was found to be characterized by a remarkable number of variants (N = 19) showing significant LR scores, as well as by high overall values of &#8722;log&#945; (Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 1A), suggesting, respectively, the plausible archaic origin of many alleles at this gene and an appreciable action of natural selection on it. Five of these significant SNVs have been already described as Denisovan-like derived alleles at outstanding frequency (i.e., ranging between 0.96 and 1) in Tibetans but not in other modern human populations (Supplementary file 1c; Zhang et al., 2021). On the contrary, at the genomic region encompassing EGLN1 (which we have considered as a negative control for AI, see Materials and methods) we detected high &#8722;log&#945; values coupled with a low number of SNVs (N = 3) showing significant LR scores, with only one being remarkably above the adopted significance threshold (Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 1B and Supplementary file 1d). Overall, these findings are concordant with evidence from literature that suggest adaptive evolution of both EPAS1 and EGLN1 loci in high-altitude Himalayan populations (Yang et al., 2017; Liu et al., 2022), although only the former was proved to have been impacted by archaic introgression (Huerta-S&#225;nchez et al., 2014; Hu et al., 2017; Zhang et al., 2021). Moreover, we were able to confirm other introgression signatures previously inferred from WGS data for populations of Tibetan ancestry, such as those involving the PRKCE gene and the MIRLET7BHG long non-coding region, which are located in the overlapping upstream chromosomal intervals, respectively, of EPAS1 and PPARA (Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 2A, B). In line with what reported for EPAS1, also PPARA has been already proposed to play a role in the modulation of high-altitude adaptation of Himalayan human groups (Simonson et al., 2010; Horscroft et al., 2017; Zhang et al., 2021). Interestingly, AI signatures identified by VolcanoFinder in the MIRLET7BHG locus extended also in the PPARA gene, as well in its downstream region (Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 2A), supporting the findings described by Hu et al., 2017. Finally, we observed patterns comparable to those at EPAS1 and PPARA for 10 additional genomic regions that were differentially pointed out by previous studies as Tibetan and/or Han Chinese DNA segments potentially carrying introgressed Denisovan alleles (Hu et al., 2017; Browning et al., 2018; Zhang et al., 2021; Figure 2A, B, Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 3A, Supplementary file 1e). Figure 2 with 4 supplements see all Download asset Open asset Distribution of VolcanoFinder statistics suggestive of putative adaptive introgrossed loci across the TBC1D1 and PRKAG2 genomic regions. On the x-axis are reported genomic positions of each single-nucleotide variant (SNV), while on the y-axis are displayed the related statistics obtained. Pink background indicates the chromosomal interval occupied by the considered genes, while the grey background identifies those genes (i.e., PGM2 in the TBC1D1 downstream genomic region and the RHEB gene in the upstream PRKAG2 region) possibly involved in regulatory transcription mechanisms. The dashed red line identifies the threshold set to filter for significant likelihood ratio (LR) values (i.e., top 5% of LR values). For both these genomic regions, the distribution of LR and &#8722;log&#945; are concordant with those observed at the EPAS1 positive control for adaptive introgression (AI). (A) A total of 50 significant LR values (red stars) and &#8722;log&#945; (grey diamonds) values resulted collectively elevated in both the TBC1D1 gene and its downstream genomic regions. A remarkable concentration of significant LR values characterizing 19 SNVs was especially observable in the first portion of the gene. (B) The entire PRKAG2 genomic region was found to comprise 46 SNVs showing significant LR values, with the greatest peaks being located in the downstream region associated to such gene. Peaks detected for the LR statistic are accompanied by peaks of &#8722;log&#945; values. Validating genomic regions affected by archaic introgression To validate signatures of archaic introgression at the candidate AI loci identified with VolcanoFinder, we relied on the approach described by Gouy and Excoffier, 2020. In detail, we used the Signet algorithm to identify networks of genes participating to the same functional pathway and presenting archaic-like (i.e., Denisovan) derived alleles observable in the putative admixed group (i.e., Tibetans) but not in an outgroup of African ancestry (i.e., Yoruba, YRI), by assuming that only Eurasian H. sapiens populations experienced Denisovan admixture (see Materials and methods). After having crosschecked results from the VolcanoFinder and Signet analyses, we identified six gene networks that turned out to be consistently significant across all the Signet runs performed and that included a total of 15 genes pointed by VolcanoFinder as candidate AI loci (Supplementary file 1f). Four of these loci composed the gene network overall ascribable to the Pathways in Cancer biological functions, which included also the EPAS1 positive control for AI (Figure 3A). Most of the other genes supported by both the analyses were instead observed in significant networks belonging to the Ras signalling and AMPK signalling pathways (Supplementary file 1f). Figure 3 Download asset Open asset Significant gene networks including Denisovan-like derived alleles according to the Signet analysis. (A) Schematic representation of the activation of the RAS/MAPK(ERK) axis after interaction of the bradykinin receptors with their ligands (e.g., ANG II) within the framework of the Pathways in Cancer network. Genes supported by both Signet (i.e., belonging to the significant network associated to Pathways in cancer) and VolcanoFinder (i.e., including at least a single-nucleotide variant (SNV) showing likelihood ratio (LR) value within top 5% of the obtained results) analyses as potentially introgressed loci, are highlighted in red and present solid outline. Grey circles with dotted-dashed contour instead indicate genes supported only by Signet, while loci marked with stars are those including genomic windows showing LASSI T statistic within top 5% of the related distribution. After the interaction between ANG II (active enzyme angiotensin II) and bradykinin receptors, activation of the Ras protein encoded by KRAS mediated by RAS-GTPases (e.g., RASGRF2) comports a series of phosphorylation reactions that eventually promotes angiogenesis (Kranenburg et al., 2004). In detail, phosphorylation of the MAPK1 protein and prevention of MAPK1-DAPK-1-dependent apoptosis leads to increased MAPK1 activity (Kanehisa and Goto, 2000; Stevens et al., 2007) that causes improved FOS mRNA expression (Monje et al., 2005). FOS together with other proteins (e.g., Jun) forms the AP-1 transcription factor, which bounds to the VEGF promoter region upregulating its expression in endothelial cells (Catar et al., 2013) and sustaining angiogenesis when the hypoxia inducible factor 1 (HIF-1) signalling cascade is inhibited (Lorenzo et al., 2014). (B) Gene network built by setting co-expression as force function and by displaying the entire set of genes identified by the Signet algorithm as belonging to significant pathways including Denisovan-like derived alleles. Genes whose variation pattern was supported by both VolcanoFinder and Signet analyses (e.g., TBC1D1) as shaped by archaic introgression are displayed with a solid black outline. The EPAS1 positive control locus that has been previously proved to have mediated adaptive introgression in Tibetan populations was represented as light-blue octagonal. Genes included in pathways involved in angiogenesis (e.g., RASGRF2) and/or activated in hypoxic conditions (e.g., PRKAG2) are reported as dark red and light-blue circles, respectively, while the remining fraction of significant genes are represented as light-grey circles. The closeness or the distance between all nodes reflects the tendency to be co-expressed with each other and all the connections inferred are characterized by a confident score &#8805;0.7. Interestingly, gene networks belonging to the Pathways in Cancer and Ras signalling pathway appeared to be tightly related from a functional perspective because included oncogenes that promote the initiation and progression of tumour growth by stimulating cell proliferation and angiogenesis (Kranenburg et al., 2004). In particular, according to the Kyoto Encyclopaedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG) database KRAS and RASGRF2 genes from the Ras signalling network were found to contribute also to the Pathways in Cancer functions (Figure 3A), especially by interacting with the identified candidate introgressed loci PLCB1, RASGRP2, DAPK1, MAPK1, FOS, and VEGFA to modulate the VEGF signalling pathway, which is activated in hypoxic conditions and induces the transcription of genes that promote angiogenesis (Figure 3A; Maxwell and Ratcliffe, 2002; Kranenburg et al., 2004). Also, the AMPK signalling pathway is known to be activated in different cell types by stresses such as deprivation of oxygen and/or glucose, leading to the inhibition of energy-consuming biosynthetic pathways (e.g., protein and glycogen synthesis) and to the activation of ATP-producing catabolic pathways, such as fatty acid oxidation and glycolysis (Kanehisa and Goto, 2000; Chen et al., 2018; Dengler, 2020). No significant gene networks involving the EGLN1 genomic region considered as a negative control for AI were instead reconstructed with the Signet approach (Supplementary file 1f), suggesting that the very few variants at this locus that showed VolcanoFinder LR scores above the adopted significant threshold might represent false positive results (Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 1B and Supplementary file 1d). Shortlisting introgressed genomic regions characterized by adaptive evolution To further shortlist the most robust candidate genes involved in AI events, we applied the LASSI algorithm to phased Tibetan WGS data with the aim of searching for genomic signatures ascribable to the action of natural selection (Harris and DeGiorgio, 2020) (see Materials and methods). This enabled us to confirm the strong selective events occurred at the EPAS1 and EGLN1 genes, as previously reported by multiple studies conducted on high-altitude Himalayan populations (Beall et al., 2010; Yi et al., 2010; Simonson et al., 2010; Horscroft et al., 2017; Zhang et al., 2021), as well as to corroborate adaptive evolution of some of the genes pointed out by both VolcanoFinder and Signet analyses. In fact, several chromosomal intervals associated to these loci presented values of the computed T statistic that fall within the top 5% of the related distribution (Figure 4C, D, Figure 4&#8212;figure supplements 1 and 2C, D, Figure 4&#8212;figure supplement 3C, D). Figure 4 with 3 supplements see all Download asset Open asset Representation of genetic distances between modern and archaic haplotypes and barplots showing haplotype frequency spectra for TBC1D1 and RASGRF2 candidate adaptive introgression (AI) genes. Haplotypes are reported in rows, while derived (i.e., black square) and ancestral (i.e., white square) alleles are displayed in columns. Haplotypes are ranked from top to bottom according to their number of pairwise differences with respect to the Denisovan sequence. (A) Heatmap displaying divergence between Tibetan, CHB and YRI TBC1D1 haplotypes with respect to the Denisovan genome. A total of 33 TBC1D1 haplotypes (i.e., 61% of the overall haplotypes inferred for such a region) belonging to individuals with Tibetan ancestry are plotted in the upper part of the heatmap thus presenting the smallest number of pairwise differences with respect to the Denisovan sequence. (B) Heatmap displaying divergence between Tibetan, CHB and YRI RASGRF2 haplotypes with respect to the Denisovan genome. A total of 16 Tibetan haplotypes in the RASGRF2 genomic region present no differences with respect to the Denisovan sequence. As regards barplots, on the x-axis are reported the haplotypes detected in the considered genomic windows, while on the y-axis is indicated the frequency for each haplotype. The black and dark-grey bars indicate the more frequent haplotypes (i.e., the putative adaptive haplotypes inferred by the LASSI method), while red stars mark those haplotypes carrying Denisovan-like derived alleles. (C) TBC1D1 haplotype frequency spectrum. The TBC1D1 gene presents a haplotype pattern qualitatively comparable to that observed at EPAS1 (Figure 4&#8212;figure supplement 3A), with a predominant haplotype carrying archaic derived alleles and reaching elevated frequencies in Tibetan populations. In line with this observation, such a pattern was inferred by LASSI as conformed with a non-neutral evolutionary scenario, even if it seems to be characterized by a soft rather than a hard selective sweep due to the occurrence of three sweeping haplotypes. (D) RASGRF2 haplotype frequency spectrum. A soft selective sweep was inferred also for the considered RASGRF2 genomic window, although frequencies reached by the sweeping haplotypes turned out to be more similar with each other. The second most represented haplotype was that carrying the archaic derived alleles and, reached a frequency of 29% in the Tibetan group. More in detail, in addition to EPAS1, genomic windows associated to the DAPK1, GNG7, AK5, TBC1D1, PLCB1, RASGRF2, and PRKAG2 introgressed loci supported by both VolcanoFinder and Signet approaches were found to present scores within the top 5% of the T distribution, suggesting that their haplotype diversity was appreciably shaped by positive selection. Interestingly, adaptive evolution of the TBC1D1 and RASGRF2 genes has been previously proposed by studies conducted on different populations of Tibetan ancestry (Peng et al., 2011; Zheng et al., 2023). Estimating genetic distance between modern and archaic sequences As a final step for prioritizing the most convincing AI genes supported by VolcanoFinder, Signet, and LASSI approaches, as well as to explicitly test whether the Denisovan human species represented a plausible source of archaic alleles for them, we merged Tibetan WGS data with those from low-altitude Han Chinese (CHB) and YRI populations sequenced by the 1000 Genomes Project (Auton et al., 2015), and with the Denisovan genome. We then used the Haplostrip algorithm (Marnetto and Huerta&#8208;S&#225;nchez, 2017) to estimate genetic distance between modern and archaic haplotypes at the candidate AI genes reported in the previous paragraph. We especially considered genomic windows that included Denisovan-like derived alleles and that presented values of the likelihood T statistic supporting an adaptive evolution (see Materials and methods). Among the tested putative AI loci, TBC1D1, RASGRF2, PRKAG2, and KRAS were found to present substantial proportions of Tibetan haplotypes that cluster close to the Denisovan sequence, thus showing the lowest numbers of pairwise differences with respect to it as compared with CHB or YRI haplotypes (Figure 4A, B, Figure 4&#8212;figure supplement 2A, B). More in detail, 61% of the TBC1D1 Tibetan haplotypes turned out to be the nearest ones to the archaic sequence by entailing only two pairwise differences with respect to it (Figure 4A), while 29% of Tibetan haplotypes inferred for the RASGRF2 gene were even identical to the Denisovan DNA (Figure 4B). Interestingly, both these chromosomal intervals were classified by the LASSI method as regions whose variation pattern was conformed with the soft selective sweep model, presenting three potential adaptive haplotypes (i.e., those haplotypes that plausibly carry putative advantageous alleles and thus increased in frequency due to positive selection). At each gene, one of these haplotypes was found to contain the Denisov</description>
      <author>Emilia Huerta&#8208;S&#225;nchez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.89815.3.sa0</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
