<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 01:09:13 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Accumulation for a Hydrophobic Cathode in Lean-Oxygen Seawater Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07279</link>
      <description>Huaiyuan Wang, Quanjun Tang, Yingxin Liu, Rongwei Meng, Bo Shi, Zhifang Pan, Yiran Jia, Ruotian Zhang, Huan Wang, Chen Zhang, Guowei Ling, Quan&#8208;Hong Yang, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400065427

                The unsatisfactory oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) kinetics caused by the inherent lean-oxygen marine environment brings low power density for metal-dissolved oxygen seawater batteries (SWBs). In this study, we propose a seawater/electrode interfacial engineering strategy by constructing a hydrophobic coating to realize enhanced mass transfer of dissolved oxygen for the fully immersed cathode of SWBs. Accumulation of dissolved oxygen from seawater to the catalyst is particularly beneficial for improving the ORR performance under lean-oxygen conditions. As a result, SWB assembled with a hydrophobic cathode achieved a power density of up to 2.32 mW cm&#8211;2 and sustained discharge at 1.3 V for 250 h. Remarkably, even in environments with an oxygen concentration of 4 mg L&#8211;1, it can operate at a voltage approximately 100 mV higher than that of an unmodified SWB. The introduction of a hydrophobic interface enhances the discharge voltage and power of SWBs by improving interfacial oxygen mass transfer, providing new insights into improving the underwater ORR performance for practical SWBs.</description>
      <author>Huaiyuan Wang, Quanjun Tang, Yingxin Liu, Rongwei Meng, Bo Shi, Zhifang Pan, Yiran Jia, Ruotian Zhang, Huan Wang, Chen Zhang, Guowei Ling, Quan&#8208;Hong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Thickness of Amorphous Carbon Coverage to Enhance the Activity and Stability of Transition Metals in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01913</link>
      <description>Cuimeng Song, Zhaoxi Fang, Yun Li, Fang Wang, Fanbin Meng, Jian Wu, Jian Zhang, Biao Shen, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400067864

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cuimeng Song, Zhaoxi Fang, Yun Li, Fang Wang, Fanbin Meng, Jian Wu, Jian Zhang, Biao Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZIF&#8208;67 Derived Co&#8208;LDH Nanocubes for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202304989</link>
      <description>Ying Chen, Zhaoxu Lv, Jinqiu Yuan, Mingchun Bi, Yue Liang, ChemistrySelect. 9(25)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400075291

                Abstract To address the substantial energy needs of the quickly evolving modern civilization, efforts are still needed to provide sustainable renewable energy sources. The electrocatalytic Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the essential technologies used in the various hydrogen production techniques. ZIF&#8208;67 nanocubes (ZIF&#8208;67 NCs) were synthesized in an aqueous solution and used as sacrificial templates. Cobalt nitrate hexahydrate was added under water bath conditions, resulting in the evolution of numerous small layered layers of cobalt hydroxide. This ultimately led to the formation of multilayered, three&#8208;dimensionally crosslinked Co&#8208;LDH with a porous networked cubic morphology. Hydrolysis of Co 2+ at different concentrations produces different degrees of weak acidic environments, and the loose LDH on the cubic structure of the best catalyst, Co&#8208;LDH&#8208;1, exposes more active cobalt sites for the OER, which results in a high electrochemically active surface area, with an overpotential of 354 mV and a Tafel slope of 79.06 mV dec &#8722;1 at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and good stability and low activation under alkaline condition also has good stability and low activation energy. It provides us an easy and practical plan for logically creating ZIF&#8208;derived hydroxide materials, leading to the development of affordable and effective electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Ying Chen, Zhaoxu Lv, Jinqiu Yuan, Mingchun Bi, Yue Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202304989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of RuO2 composites from hydrogen-bonded organic frameworks for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100892</link>
      <description>Hina Naz, Rai Nauman Ali, Waqar Ahmad Qureshi, Syed Najeeb-Uz-Zaman Haider, Hongbo Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, Materials today sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400077314

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hina Naz, Rai Nauman Ali, Waqar Ahmad Qureshi, Syed Najeeb-Uz-Zaman Haider, Hongbo Zhou, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P&#8208;10.1: Design and Optimization of Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/Alucone Overlapping Film for Improved Water&#8208;Oxygen Barrier Performance of Flexible Displays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sdtp.17329</link>
      <description>Jianjun Zhao, Yuyan Peng, Chunliang Chen, Xiongtu Zhou, Tailiang Guo, Qun Yan, Chaoxing Wu, Yongai Zhang, Digest of technical papers. 55(S1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400078578

                Thin&#8208;film encapsulation plays an essential role in the stability of flexible displays. Although Al 2 O 3 film has good water&#8208;oxygen barrier properties, its bending performance needs to be enhanced. This paper inserts Alucone into Al 2 O 3 film to generate Al 2 O 3 /Alucone overlapping film with good barrier and bending performance to improve the encapsulated devices. The finite element analyzing approach and the calcium dot arrays test are employed to investigate the influence of structural ratio and overlapping density on the water&#8208;oxygen barrier and mechanical properties of the Al 2 O 3 /Alucone overlapping film. The results show that the proportion of Alucone sublayers in the Al 2 O 3 /Alucone overlapping film (with a total thickness of 60 nm) is directly proportional to the overlapping structure's ability to disperse stresses and inversely proportional to the overlapping structure's water&#8208;oxygen barrier property. When the Al 2 O 3 /Alucone overlapping structure ratio is 1:1, the Al 2 O 3 /Alucone overlapping film can balance the bending and barrier properties. The bending property of Al 2 O 3 /Alucone overlapping film (Al 2 O 3 /Alucone ratio is 1:1, total thickness is 60 nm) diminishes with increasing overlapping density, and its water&#8208;oxygen barrier property increases and then drops. Combining the results of the simulation and calcium dot arrays test, it is apparent that when the Al 2 O 3 /Alucone ratio is 1:1 and the overlapping density is 5, the Al 2 O 3 /Alucone overlapping film has good bending and barrier performance. This is expected to promote the development of commercial flexible display technology.</description>
      <author>Jianjun Zhao, Yuyan Peng, Chunliang Chen, Xiongtu Zhou, Tailiang Guo, Qun Yan, Chaoxing Wu, Yongai Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sdtp.17329</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-NiO/MoO2 and In-situ reconstructed Fe, Mo-NiOOH with enhanced negatively charges of oxygen atoms on the surface for salinity tolerance seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109921</link>
      <description>Shiyu Qin, Zhi-Hui Zhan, Jianpeng Sun, Xiangchao Meng, Xiangchao Meng, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400080530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiyu Qin, Zhi-Hui Zhan, Jianpeng Sun, Xiangchao Meng, Xiangchao Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109921</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Synergistic Effect of Co and Fe for Efficient and Durable Oxygen Evolution under Alkaline Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07058</link>
      <description>Sanghwi Han, S. Kim, Tae Hoon Kim, Jang Yong Lee, Jeyong Yoon, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400083261

                Developing robust oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is crucial for advancing anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE). In this study, we present a catalyst optimizing the synergistic effect of Co and Fe by creating a CoFe-based layer on a Fe-based electrode (Fe@CoFe). The Fe@CoFe exhibits an overpotential of 168 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Sanghwi Han, S. Kim, Tae Hoon Kim, Jang Yong Lee, Jeyong Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07058</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ and wavelength-dependent photocatalytic strain evolution of a single Au nanoparticle on a TiO2 film</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49862-1</link>
      <description>S. H. Park, S Kim, Jae Whan Park, Seunghee Kim, Wonsuk Cha, Joon Seok Lee, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400091240

                Abstract Photocatalysis is a promising technique due to its capacity to efficiently harvest solar energy and its potential to address the global energy crisis. However, the structure&#8211;activity relationships of photocatalyst during wavelength-dependent photocatalytic reactions remains largely unexplored because it is difficult to measure under operating conditions. Here we show the photocatalytic strain evolution of a single Au nanoparticle (AuNP) supported on a TiO 2 film by combining three-dimensional (3D) Bragg coherent X-ray diffraction imaging with an external light source. The wavelength-dependent generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) has significant effects on the structural deformation of the AuNP, leading to its strain evolution. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations are employed to rationalize the induced strain caused by the adsorption of ROS on the AuNP surface. These observations provide insights of how the photocatalytic activity impacts on the structural deformation of AuNP, contributing to the general understanding of the atomic-level catalytic adsorption process.</description>
      <author>S. H. Park, S Kim, Jae Whan Park, Seunghee Kim, Wonsuk Cha, Joon Seok Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49862-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineering in Sn-Doped NiS/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanostructures for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02251</link>
      <description>Yunpeng Zhang, Yi Feng, Jiahui Jiang, Jingjing Zhu, Hongyi Gao, Ting Zhao, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Li Zhang, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400093156

                Nickel-based sulfides have been proven to be excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts due to their excellent electrical conductivity, but their poor stability hinders their application in practical applications. To address this issue, defect engineering has been proposed as a viable strategy to enhance the electronic structure of the catalyst and further boost the OER performance. Herein, a MOF-derived Sn-doped NiS/Ni3S2 nanostructure grown in situ on nickel foam (Sn&#8211;NixSy/NF) has been designed as an active OER electrocatalyst. The morphology of the material was significantly impacted by the addition of the Sn elements, nanorods modified with nanoparticles providing more active sites. Moreover, the introduction of Sn elements induced the generation of sulfur vacancies (Vs), enhanced electron transfer, promoted electron redistribution, and increased the charge transfer rate. All of these endow the Sn&#8211;NixSy/NF-T with exceptionally low overpotentials of 104 and 286 mV to achieve a current density of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8211;2 for OER. Moreover, the Sn&#8211;NixSy/NF-T showed long-term stability, maintaining 100 h at current densities of 100 mA cm&#8211;2. In short, this work opened a route for engineering defects to boost the OER.</description>
      <author>Yunpeng Zhang, Yi Feng, Jiahui Jiang, Jingjing Zhu, Hongyi Gao, Ting Zhao, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous flow production of bioactive ceria quantum dots: New paradigms to the effect of process parameters on surface oxygen vacancy tuning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104689</link>
      <description>Sayoni Sarkar, Rohit Srivastava, Ajit R. Kulkarni, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400102272

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sayoni Sarkar, Rohit Srivastava, Ajit R. Kulkarni</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104689</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Kinetics of Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Defect-Engineered B/P-incorporated Cobalt-Oxide Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101638</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Rinkoo Bhabal, Maulik Patel, Mounib Bahri, R. Fernandes, N. Patel, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400105371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Rinkoo Bhabal, Maulik Patel, Mounib Bahri, R. Fernandes, N. Patel</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-step annealing synthesis of MOF-derived Cr-Co-Ru metallic oxides for improving the oxygen evolution reaction in acidic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104695</link>
      <description>Bohan Zhang, Chang Wen, Ming Xu, Qian Liu, Zhi Yong Zhang, Hongbo Huang, Dapeng Wang, Zhengkai Tu, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400109655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bohan Zhang, Chang Wen, Ming Xu, Qian Liu, Zhi Yong Zhang, Hongbo Huang, Dapeng Wang, Zhengkai Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Modified Ruthenium Nanorods for an Ampere-Level Bifunctional Hydrogen Evolution Reaction/Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05286</link>
      <description>Hong Tang, Takeo Kojima, Kenji Kazumi, Kazuhiro Fukami, Hiroshi Sakaguchi, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400110595

                The practical applications of bifunctional ruthenium-based electrocatalysts with two active sites of Ru nanoparticles covered with RuO</description>
      <author>Hong Tang, Takeo Kojima, Kenji Kazumi, Kazuhiro Fukami, Hiroshi Sakaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field-Induced Electron Spin Polarization of Co-Modified Black Phosphorus for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4879661</link>
      <description>Tiekuang Wang, Hui Qiao, Zongyu Huang, Zhaoqi Leng, Ruiyang Yu, Xi Chen, Jun Yang, Xiaohui Ren, Xiang Qi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400112796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tiekuang Wang, Hui Qiao, Zongyu Huang, Zhaoqi Leng, Ruiyang Yu, Xi Chen, Jun Yang, Xiaohui Ren, Xiang Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4879661</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn incorporated RuO2 nanocrystals as an efficient and stable bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction in acid and alkaline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109863</link>
      <description>Jing Cao, Dezheng Zhang, Bianqing Ren, Ping Song, Weilin Xu, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. 35(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400118252

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Cao, Dezheng Zhang, Bianqing Ren, Ping Song, Weilin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-principles and experimental insight of high-entropy materials as electrocatalysts for energy-related applications: Hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, and oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2024.100813</link>
      <description>Jasmin S. Shaikh, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Victor M&#225;rquez, Navajsharif S. Shaikh, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Sumayya C. Pathan, Pongsakorn Kanjanaboos, Toshiaki Taniike, Mohammad Khaja Nazeeruddin, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam, Materials science &amp; engineering. R, Reports. 160(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400120264

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jasmin S. Shaikh, Meena Rittiruam, Tinnakorn Saelee, Victor M&#225;rquez, Navajsharif S. Shaikh, Patcharaporn Khajondetchairit, Sumayya C. Pathan, Pongsakorn Kanjanaboos, Toshiaki Taniike, Mohammad Khaja Nazeeruddin, Piyasan Praserthdam, Supareak Praserthdam</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mser.2024.100813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological Evolution of Carbon Quantum Dots to Carbon Nanoneedles and N/F Codoping as an Efficient Catalyst for Oxygen Electrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00305</link>
      <description>Sumanta Kumar Das, Aiswarya Kesh, D Sujatha, Subhendu K. Panda, A. K. Sahu, ACS applied engineering materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400120401

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sumanta Kumar Das, Aiswarya Kesh, D Sujatha, Subhendu K. Panda, A. K. Sahu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00305</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Research on Iridium&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction from the Origin of Reaction Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403845</link>
      <description>L.-Y. Chen, Wei Zhao, Juntao Zhang, Min Liu, Jun Yin, Ru-Zhi Wang, Maorong Chai, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400122094

                As the anode reaction of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE), the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the main obstacles to the practical application of PEMWE due to its sluggish four-electron transfer process. The development of high-performance acidic OER electrocatalysts has become the key to improving the reaction kinetics. To date, although various excellent acidic OER electrocatalysts have been widely researched, Ir-based nanomaterials are still state-of-the-art electrocatalysts. Hence, a comprehensive and in-depth understanding of the reaction mechanism of Ir-based electrocatalysts is crucial for the precise optimization of catalytic performance. In this review, the origin and nature of the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) and the derived volcanic relationship on Ir-based electrocatalysts for acidic OER processes are summarized and some optimization strategies for Ir-based electrocatalysts based on the AEM are introduced. To further investigate the development strategy of high-performance Ir-based electrocatalysts, several unconventional OER mechanisms including dual-site mechanism and lattice oxygen mediated mechanism, and their applications are introduced in detail. Thereafter, the active species on Ir-based electrocatalysts at acidic OER are summarized and classified into surface Ir species and O species. Finally, the future development direction and prospect of Ir-based electrocatalysts for acidic OER are put forward.</description>
      <author>L.-Y. Chen, Wei Zhao, Juntao Zhang, Min Liu, Jun Yin, Ru-Zhi Wang, Maorong Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorinated Organic Cations Derived Chiral 2D Perovskite Enabling Enhanced Spin&#8208;Dependent Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202403326</link>
      <description>Jaehyun Son, Gyumin Jang, Sunihl Ma, Hyungsoo Lee, Chan Uk Lee, Sejung Yang, Junwoo Lee, Subin Moon, Wooyong Jeong, Jeong Hyun Park, Chul Woo Jung, Jihee Kim, Ji&#8208;Sang Park, Jooho Moon, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400122313

                Chirality-induced spin selectivity observed in chiral 2D organic-inorganic hybrid perovskite holds promise to achieve spin-dependent electrochemistry. However, conventional chiral 2D perovskites suffer from low conductivity and hygroscopicity, limiting electrochemical performance and operational stability. Here, a cutting-edge material design is introduced to develop a stable and efficient chiral perovskite-based spin polarizer by employing fluorinated chiral cation. The fluorination approach effectively promotes the charge carrier transport along the out-of-plane direction by mitigating the dielectric confinement effect within the multi-quantum well-structured 2D perovskite. Integrating the fluorinated cation incorporated spin polarizer with BiVO</description>
      <author>Jaehyun Son, Gyumin Jang, Sunihl Ma, Hyungsoo Lee, Chan Uk Lee, Sejung Yang, Junwoo Lee, Subin Moon, Wooyong Jeong, Jeong Hyun Park, Chul Woo Jung, Jihee Kim, Ji&#8208;Sang Park, Jooho Moon</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202403326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Origin of High Electrochemical Stability of Iridium Oxides for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02494j</link>
      <description>Yuanhua Ding, Wenwen Liu, Zhibin Xu, Zhiyao Duan, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400128654

                Understanding the dissolution mechanisms of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is essential for designing efficient and stable electrolyzers. IrO2, the most stable single oxide OER catalyst, provides a benchmark for...</description>
      <author>Yuanhua Ding, Wenwen Liu, Zhibin Xu, Zhiyao Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02494j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of ultrafine Fe-doped Ni3Se4 nanoparticles on tube-like N-doped carbon as a robust electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175374</link>
      <description>Yasuhiro Kumon, Saikat Bolar, Takeshi Fujita, Ze&#8208;Xing Cai, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400139317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yasuhiro Kumon, Saikat Bolar, Takeshi Fujita, Ze&#8208;Xing Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of FeNi-based nanowire-assembled superstructures with tunable anions for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110184</link>
      <description>Wenzhong Shen, Jie Liu, Gongyu Wen, &#1064;&#1091;&#1072;&#1081; &#1051;&#1080;, B. X. Yu, Shiyan Song, Bin Gong, R.H. Zhang, Shumian Liu, Hongpeng Wang, Yi&#8208;Xin Wang, Yujing Liu, Huadong Yuan, Jie Luo, Shihui Zou, Xinyong Tao, Jianwei Nai, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400139405

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenzhong Shen, Jie Liu, Gongyu Wen, &#1064;&#1091;&#1072;&#1081; &#1051;&#1080;, B. X. Yu, Shiyan Song, Bin Gong, R.H. Zhang, Shumian Liu, Hongpeng Wang, Yi&#8208;Xin Wang, Yujing Liu, Huadong Yuan, Jie Luo, Shihui Zou, Xinyong Tao, Jianwei Nai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Valence Cu Induced by Photoelectric Reconstruction for Dynamically Stable Oxygen Evolution Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04975</link>
      <description>Zhi Cai, Lidong Li, Peijia Ding, Dawei Pang, Mingyuan Xu, Xu Zhang, Jian Kang, Tianqi Guo, Gilberto Teobaldi, Zhongchang Wang, Li-Min Liu, Lin Guo, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400145199

                Oxygen vacancies are generally considered to play a crucial role in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the generation of active sites created by oxygen vacancies is inevitably restricted by their condensation and elimination reactions. To overcome this limitation, here, we demonstrate a novel photoelectric reconstruction strategy to incorporate atomically dispersed Cu into ultrathin (about 2&#8211;3 molecular) amorphous oxyhydroxide (a-CuM, M = Co, Ni, Fe, or Zn), facilitating deprotonation of the reconstructed oxyhydroxide to generate high-valence Cu. The in situ XAFS results and first-principles calculations reveal that Cu atoms are stabilized at high valence during the OER process due to Jahn&#8211;Teller distortion, resulting in para-type double oxygen vacancies as dynamically stable catalytic sites. The optimal a-CuCo catalyst exhibits a record-high mass activity of 3404.7 A g&#8211;1 at an overpotential of 300 mV, superior to the benchmarking hydroxide and oxide catalysts. The developed photoelectric reconstruction strategy opens up a new pathway to construct in situ stable oxygen vacancies by high-valence Cu single sites, which extends the design rules for creating dynamically stable active sites.</description>
      <author>Zhi Cai, Lidong Li, Peijia Ding, Dawei Pang, Mingyuan Xu, Xu Zhang, Jian Kang, Tianqi Guo, Gilberto Teobaldi, Zhongchang Wang, Li-Min Liu, Lin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Electronic Coupling between Ni-Based Mof and Ni2p Enables High-Efficiency Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Various Application Scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4880251</link>
      <description>Yirong Wang, Yi Xuan, Zhonghong Xia, X. Li, Yuliang Gao, Jing Zhang, Wuliang Feng, Xingli Zou, Yufeng Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400148690

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yirong Wang, Yi Xuan, Zhonghong Xia, X. Li, Yuliang Gao, Jing Zhang, Wuliang Feng, Xingli Zou, Yufeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4880251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concurrently boosted oxygen reduction/evolution electrocatalysis over highly loaded CoNi/onion-like carbon hybrid nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.235</link>
      <description>Ai-Hua Yuan, Bo Wang, Minzhe Guo, Yu Fan, Jiang Lan, Weiyou Yang, Guoming Ma, Qiao Liu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400163787

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ai-Hua Yuan, Bo Wang, Minzhe Guo, Yu Fan, Jiang Lan, Weiyou Yang, Guoming Ma, Qiao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Programmable Wet-Interfacial Joule Heating to Rapidly Synthesize Metastable Protohematite Photoanodes: Metal and Lattice Oxygen Dual Sites for Improving Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02690</link>
      <description>Jiujun Deng, Guoqing Li, Dongpeng Yan, Wei Zhang, Kun Feng, Kaiqi Nie, Changhai Liu, Xiaoxin Lv, Jun Zhong, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400166207

                High-temperature sintering is critical for efficient hematite photoanodes in terms of improving the crystallinity and minimizing deficiencies. However, prolonged conventional furnace annealing requires high energy consumption and simultaneously results in serious damage to the transparent conducting oxide (TCO) substrate. This work demonstrates a universal wet-interfacial Joule heating strategy for rapidly synthesizing high-performance metastable protohematite photoanodes, which greatly decreases the power consumption and causes less damage to the TCO substrate by shortening the sintering time to &#8764;90 s. More importantly, the protohematite phase was found to effectively facilitate the charge dynamics in the bulk and surface of the as-resulting photoanode by increasing donor density and lowering the oxygen evolution reaction overpotential via offering dual active sites (lattice oxygen and Fe sites). Moreover, this annealing strategy could be well coupled with commonly used Ti-treatment to achieve a further performance enhancement and also shows high feasibility in rapidly fabricating efficient TiO2 and BiVO4 photoanodes. This study opens a facile, rapid, and reliable approach for fabricating efficient metal oxide photoanodes, contributing to the development of photoelectrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Jiujun Deng, Guoqing Li, Dongpeng Yan, Wei Zhang, Kun Feng, Kaiqi Nie, Changhai Liu, Xiaoxin Lv, Jun Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction performance of nitrogen-doped carbon dots sensitized with rare-earth metal nanorods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111362</link>
      <description>Nithya Selvaraju, Sheethal Sasi, Yuvaraj Sivalingam, Gunasekaran Venugopal, Diamond and related materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400168214

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nithya Selvaraju, Sheethal Sasi, Yuvaraj Sivalingam, Gunasekaran Venugopal</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposition of amorphous CoFe oxide/hydroxide onto nickel mesh as a highly efficient electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112798</link>
      <description>Yujie Hou, Yuli Zhang, Changgan Lai, Donghuai Zhang, Shuai Ji, Zhiliang Guo, Liu Nie, Yifan Zhang, Lixu Lei, Inorganic chemistry communications/Inorganic chemistry communications (Online). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400168229

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Hou, Yuli Zhang, Changgan Lai, Donghuai Zhang, Shuai Ji, Zhiliang Guo, Liu Nie, Yifan Zhang, Lixu Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effect Enables the Dual-Metal Doped Cobalt Telluride Particles as Potential Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution in Alkaline Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00921</link>
      <description>Xuyang Jing, Jinyuan Dong, Yi Mao, Lingyan Zhou, Jiabao Ding, Huilong Dong, Linjuan Zhang, Y. Zhang, Weifeng Zhang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400182573

                Cobalt (Co)-based materials have been widely investigated as hopeful noble-metal-free alternatives for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline electrolytes, which is crucial for generating hydrogen by water electrolysis. Herein, cobalt-based telluride particles with good electronic conductivity as anodic electrocatalysts were prepared under vacuum by the solid-state strategy, which display remarkable activities toward the OER. Nickel (Ni) and iron (Fe) codoped cobalt telluride (NiFe-CoTe) exhibits an overpotential of 321 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Xuyang Jing, Jinyuan Dong, Yi Mao, Lingyan Zhou, Jiabao Ding, Huilong Dong, Linjuan Zhang, Y. Zhang, Weifeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00921</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tip effect-assisted modulation of interfacial charge in FeCoNi LDH/Ni3S2 Mott-Schottky heterojunction for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114335</link>
      <description>Zongheng Zheng, Xue-wei Wang, Yifan Zhang, Jia Li, Liping Xiao, Wenhua Zhang, Hang Qin, Molecular catalysis. 564(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400182702

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongheng Zheng, Xue-wei Wang, Yifan Zhang, Jia Li, Liping Xiao, Wenhua Zhang, Hang Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114335</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedded CoMo-POM@IF nanoflower by facile room temperature etching as an enhanced electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114338</link>
      <description>Bo Li, Xiaolin Zhang, Hong Liang, Chenchen Jing, Huabo Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang, Molecular catalysis. 564(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400183004

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Li, Xiaolin Zhang, Hong Liang, Chenchen Jing, Huabo Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermally fabricated MoTe2/rGO as a proficient electrocatalyst for robust oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111364</link>
      <description>Musarrat Ramzan, Areej S. Alqarni, Khurshid Ahmad, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Muhammad Aslam, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Zubair Ahmad, Diamond and related materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400189670

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Musarrat Ramzan, Areej S. Alqarni, Khurshid Ahmad, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Muhammad Aslam, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Zubair Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon-doped Cobal&#8211;Aluminum Layered Double Hydroxide Electrocatalyst with High Catalytic Activity for Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144649</link>
      <description>Huiping Gao, Ping Fu, Jie Yu, Xiaodong Yang, Ying Tang, Yunxia Zhao, Shuangchun Yang, Gang Wang, Feng Yu, Yongsheng Li, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400191132

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huiping Gao, Ping Fu, Jie Yu, Xiaodong Yang, Ying Tang, Yunxia Zhao, Shuangchun Yang, Gang Wang, Feng Yu, Yongsheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is the &#8727;O vs. &#8727;OH scaling relation intercept more relevant than the &#8727;OOH vs. &#8727;OH intercept to capture trends in the oxygen evolution reaction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101039</link>
      <description>Maksim Sokolov, Kai S. Exner, Chem catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400198183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maksim Sokolov, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetal Oxides Anchored on Carbon Nanotubes/Nanosheets as High&#8208;Efficiency and Durable Bifunctional Oxygen Catalyst for Advanced Zn&#8211;Air Battery: Experiments and DFT Calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402104</link>
      <description>Qi&#8208;Dong Ruan, Yuehong Zhao, Rui Feng, Muhammad Zia Ul Haq, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400201233

                To meet increasing requirement for innovative energy storage and conversion technology, it is urgent to prepare effective, affordable, and long-term stable oxygen electrocatalysts to replace precious metal-based counterparts. Herein, a two-step pyrolysis strategy is developed for controlled synthesis of Fe</description>
      <author>Qi&#8208;Dong Ruan, Yuehong Zhao, Rui Feng, Muhammad Zia Ul Haq, Lu Zhang, Jiu&#8208;Ju Feng, Yijing Gao, Ai&#8208;Jun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Properties of Quasi-2D Oxides LaSrMn0.5M0.5O4 (M = Co, Ni, Cu, and Zn) for Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29133107</link>
      <description>Kinithi M. K. Wickramaratne, Farshid Ramezanipour, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400201508

                Designing cost-effective and highly efficient electrocatalysts for water splitting is a significant challenge. We have systematically investigated a series of quasi-2D oxides, LaSrMn0.5M0.5O4 (M = Co, Ni, Cu, Zn), to enhance the electrocatalytic properties of the two half-reactions of water-splitting, namely oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions (OER and HER). The four materials are isostructural, as confirmed by Rietveld refinements with X-ray diffraction. The oxygen contents and metal valence states were determined by iodometric titrations and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Electrical conductivity measurements in a wide range of temperatures revealed semiconducting behavior for all four materials. Electrocatalytic properties were studied for both half-reactions of water-splitting, namely, oxygen-evolution and hydrogen-evolution reactions (OER and HER). For the four materials, the trends in both OER and HER were the same, which also matched the trend in electrical conductivities. Among them, LaSrMn0.5Co0.5O4 showed the best bifunctional electrocatalytic activity for both OER and HER, which may be attributed to its higher electrical conductivity and favorable electron configuration.</description>
      <author>Kinithi M. K. Wickramaratne, Farshid Ramezanipour</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29133107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Ferric-Oxide-Doped Nickel&#8211;Iron Hydroxide Electrocatalysts by Magnetic-Field-Assisted Chemical Corrosion toward Boosted Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29133127</link>
      <description>Minghan Xu, Lei Ling, Huilin Hu, Yana Chen, Xuchao Yang, Kaiyuan Yu, Bin Cao, Xian&#8208;Zheng Zhang, Xueliang Jiang, Chu Yao, Huan Yang, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400201532

                Transition-metal-based oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts have attracted widespread attention due to their inexpensive prices, unique layered structures, and rich active sites. Currently, designing low-cost, sustainable, and simple synthesis methods is essential for the application of transition-metal-based catalysts. Here, magnetic field (MF)-assisted chemical corrosion, as a novel technology, is adopted to construct superior OER electrocatalysts. The produced Ni(Fe)(OH)2-Fe2O3 electrode exhibits an overpotential of 272 mV at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2, presenting a 64 mV reduction compared to the electrode without an MF. The experimental results indicate that an MF can induce the directional growth of Fe2O3 rods and reduce their accumulation. In addition, an external MF is beneficial for the lattice dislocation of the obtained catalysts, which can increase the surface free energy, thus reducing the activation energy and accelerating the electrochemical reaction kinetics. This work effectively combines a magnetic field with chemical corrosion and electrochemical energy, which offers a novel strategy for the large-scale development of environmentally friendly and superior electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Minghan Xu, Lei Ling, Huilin Hu, Yana Chen, Xuchao Yang, Kaiyuan Yu, Bin Cao, Xian&#8208;Zheng Zhang, Xueliang Jiang, Chu Yao, Huan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29133127</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lignin-assisted electronic modulation on NiSe/FeOx heterointerface for boosting electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.133509</link>
      <description>Xiaowen Zhong, Jianglin Liu, Bowen Liu, Xiaofei Wang, Xuliang Lin, International journal of biological macromolecules. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400201965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaowen Zhong, Jianglin Liu, Bowen Liu, Xiaofei Wang, Xuliang Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.133509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Octahedron Sites of CoV&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; via Cationic Competition for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402402</link>
      <description>Yi Lv, Shuai Wei, Shasha Yi, Yan&#8208;Xin Duan, Rong&#8208;Chao Cui, Guang Yang, Zhongyi Liu, Jing&#8208;Huo Chen, Xinzheng Yue, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400208057

                Abstract Doping transition metal oxide spinels with metal ions represents a significant strategy for optimizing the electronic structure of electrocatalysts. Herein, a bimetallic Fe and Ru doping strategy to fine&#8208;tune the crystal structure of CoV 2 O 4 spinel for highly enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is presented performance. The incorporation of Fe and Ru is observed at octahedral sites within the CoV 2 O 4 structure, effectively modulating the electronic configuration of Co. Density functional theory calculations have confirmed that Fe acts as a novel reactive site, replacing V. Additionally, the synergistic effect of Fe, Co, and Ru effectively optimizes the Gibbs free energy of the intermediate species, reduces the reaction energy barrier, and accelerates the kinetics toward OER. As expected, the best&#8208;performing CoVFe 0.5 Ru 0.5 O 4 displays a low overpotential of 240 mV (@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and a remarkably low Tafel slope of 38.9 mV dec &#8722;1 , surpassing that of commercial RuO 2 . Moreover, it demonstrates outstanding long&#8208;term durability lasting for 72 h. This study provides valuable insights for the design of highly active polymetallic spinel electrocatalysts for energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Yi Lv, Shuai Wei, Shasha Yi, Yan&#8208;Xin Duan, Rong&#8208;Chao Cui, Guang Yang, Zhongyi Liu, Jing&#8208;Huo Chen, Xinzheng Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible Hydrazone&#8208;Linked Metal&#8208;Covalent Organic Frameworks with Copper Clusters for Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403775</link>
      <description>Chao Lin, Huanrong Ma, Jianying He, Qing Xu, Meng Song, Cheng&#8208;Xing Cui, Yong Cui, Chunxiang Li, Mingli Jiao, Lipeng Zhai, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400208113

                Despite the challenges associated with the synthesis of flexible metal-covalent organic frameworks (MCOFs), these offer the unique advantage of maximizing the atomic utilization efficiency. However, the construction of flexible MCOFs with flexible building units or linkages has rarely been reported. In this study, novel flexible MCOFs are constructed using flexible building blocks and copper clusters with hydrazone linkages. The heterometallic frameworks (Cu, Co) are prepared through the hydrazone linkage coordination method and evaluated as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Owing to the spatial separation and functional cooperation of the heterometallic MCOF catalysts, the as-synthesized MCOFs exhibited outstanding catalytic activities with an overpotential of 268.8 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Chao Lin, Huanrong Ma, Jianying He, Qing Xu, Meng Song, Cheng&#8208;Xing Cui, Yong Cui, Chunxiang Li, Mingli Jiao, Lipeng Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the impact of oxygen vacancies in engineered bimetallic oxides for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction: insights from experimental and theoretical approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01180e</link>
      <description>Pratheep Panneerselvam, Chob Singh, J. Santhosh Kumar, Thamarainathan Doulassiramane, R. Padmanaban, Akshaya K. Samal, M. Sakar, Arvind H. Jadhav, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400210206

                In this study, we presented hollow bimetallic mixed oxides of molybdenum and nickel, prepared through a facile polymer-assisted solution process.</description>
      <author>Pratheep Panneerselvam, Chob Singh, J. Santhosh Kumar, Thamarainathan Doulassiramane, R. Padmanaban, Akshaya K. Samal, M. Sakar, Arvind H. Jadhav</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01180e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Assistance of Ir Clusters and NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets Interfaces in Direct O&#8211;O Coupling for High-Efficiency Alkaline Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02837</link>
      <description>Mengqi Yang, Kailing Zhou, Wei Zhao, Changhao Wang, Ge Chen, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400212886

                Adopting noble metals on non-noble metals is an effective strategy to balance the cost and activity of electrocatalysts. Herein, a thorough analysis of the synergistic OER is conducted at the heterogeneous interface formed by Ir clusters and NiCo</description>
      <author>Mengqi Yang, Kailing Zhou, Wei Zhao, Changhao Wang, Ge Chen, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;NdO&#8208;based mixed nanomaterial using green capping agent and its functionalization as electrode material for energy devices: Pseudo capacitors and water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/apj.3119</link>
      <description>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Lin Wang, Ram K. Gupta, Munirah D. Albaqami, S. Noor Mohammad, Mahwash Mahar Gul, Asia-Pacific journal of chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400217828

                Abstract This study investigates the environmentally friendly synthesis of ZrO 2 &#8208;NdO mixed nanomaterial using green reducing and capping agents derived from the plant Amaranthus viridis . X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD) analysis confirmed the successful synthesis of the mixed nanomaterial, revealing an optical band gap of 2.5 eV. The morphology was characterized by spherical&#8208;shaped particles with an average size ranging from 66 to 77 nm. The synthesized ZrO 2 &#8208;NdO mixed nanomaterial was evaluated for its potential application as an electrode material in energy devices, specifically for pseudocapacitors and water splitting studies. Electrochemical performance was assessed using cyclic voltammetry (CV) and galvanostatic charge&#8211;discharge (GCD) techniques. Notably, a specific capacitance of 573.5 F/g was achieved through CV at a scan rate of 2 mV/s. Fabricated electrocatalyst was further analyzed for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and the results showed better over potential value of 164 mV for HER studies. The stability analysis further endorsed the large&#8208;scale commercialization possibility of ZrO&#8208;NdO&#8208;based electrode material.</description>
      <author>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Lin Wang, Ram K. Gupta, Munirah D. Albaqami, S. Noor Mohammad, Mahwash Mahar Gul</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/apj.3119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy sulfurization enables efficient non-noble metal-based NiCoFeCuS electrocatalyst for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.partic.2024.06.014</link>
      <description>Pin Yang, Mingwei Sun, Jingchuan Wang, Jinfeng Li, Ruizhu Yang, Yawei Hao, Lei Qi, Lijian Yang, Xue Li, Particuology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400235886

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pin Yang, Mingwei Sun, Jingchuan Wang, Jinfeng Li, Ruizhu Yang, Yawei Hao, Lei Qi, Lijian Yang, Xue Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.partic.2024.06.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus-doped porous carbon with exceptional electrocatalytic performance for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111373</link>
      <description>Shuhao Chen, Juan Meng, Anzheng Zhang, Rui Xu, Hongyu Zhang, Jie Jiang, Yue Zhou, Zhou Yang, Hengfei Qin, Diamond and related materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400236231

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuhao Chen, Juan Meng, Anzheng Zhang, Rui Xu, Hongyu Zhang, Jie Jiang, Yue Zhou, Zhou Yang, Hengfei Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hf-Doped CoP Hollow Nanocubes as High-Performance Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02212</link>
      <description>Rongmei Zhu, Lipeng Xie, Yi Zhang, Limei Liu, Yuxuan Jiang, Huan Pang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400241637

                Designing and synthesizing hollow frame structures with unique three-dimensional open structures in electrocatalysis remain a challenge. Etching is an effective method to synthesize metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) with a hollow structure and rich function. Herein, we report the design and synthesis of Hf-doped CoP hollow nanocubes by selective etching and ion exchange. Different from the traditional etching method, we used acid xylenol orange solution to etch typically the (211) crystal face of ZIF-67, obtaining the unique bell-like structure, named XO-ZIF-67. Subsequently, Hf-doped CoP hollow nanocubes were formed by Hf</description>
      <author>Rongmei Zhu, Lipeng Xie, Yi Zhang, Limei Liu, Yuxuan Jiang, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction Enabled by Ni Cavity-Arrayed Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-cb2sk</link>
      <description>Daiki Ashizawa, Masaki Itatani, Tomohiro Fukushima, Kei Murakoshi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400245875

                The water electrolysis is mostly limited by the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) including the interfacial electron and mass transfer and autoionization reactions. Especially in the neutral pH condition, slow rate of the autoionization reaction of water molecules also limits the electrolysis. The vibrational strong coupling, where the matter excitation is coupled to the cavity vacuum field mediated by a virtual photon, can be expected to modulate the physicochemical properties of water. Here, we utilized the cavity-arrayed electrode for the promotion of the OER. The OER activities of Ni cavity-array electrodes were evaluated from the oxygen bubble growth behavior. The Tafel slopes from the bubble analyses were modulated from 120 mV per decade to 30 mV per decade and the OER activity was enhanced by the cavity-arrayed electrode. This enhancement was explained with regards to the acceleration of autoionization of water molecules under the vibrational strong coupling. This study demonstrates that the cavity systems modulate the thermodynamic equilibrium of water autoionization under the vibrational strong coupling of liquid water at room temperature, leading to enhanced OER.</description>
      <author>Daiki Ashizawa, Masaki Itatani, Tomohiro Fukushima, Kei Murakoshi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-cb2sk</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Performance Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Flexible and Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Batteries: Recent Advances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402761</link>
      <description>Chengyu Song, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Huimin Xu, Zhijie Zhang, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Qimin Zhan, Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400247901

                Abstract Flexible rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (FZABs) exhibit high energy density, ultra&#8208;thin, lightweight, green, and safe features, and are considered as one of the ideal power sources for flexible wearable electronics. However, the slow and high overpotential oxygen reaction at the air cathode has become one of the key factors restricting the development of FZABs. The improvement of activity and stability of bifunctional catalysts has become a top priority. At the same time, FZABs should maintain the battery performance under different bending and twisting conditions, and the design of the overall structure of FZABs is also important. Based on the understanding of the three typical configurations and working principles of FZABs, this work highlights two common strategies for applying bifunctional catalysts to FZABs: 1) powder&#8208;based flexible air cathode and 2) flexible self&#8208;supported air cathode. It summarizes the recent advances in bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts and explores the various types of catalyst structures as well as the related mechanistic understanding. Based on the latest catalyst research advances, this paper introduces and discusses various structure modulation strategies and expects to guide the synthesis and preparation of efficient bifunctional catalysts. Finally, the current status and challenges of bifunctional catalyst research in FZABs are summarized.</description>
      <author>Chengyu Song, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Huimin Xu, Zhijie Zhang, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Qimin Zhan, Gao&#8208;Ren Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ca3Co4O9-Ba0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3 composite catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05992-6</link>
      <description>Susana Lopes, Thayse R. Silva, Rafael A. Raimundo, Pedro Vieira, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Fausthon F. da Silva, Rosana Cardoso Alves, Fl&#225;via de Medeiros Aquino, Daniel A. Macedo, Journal of solid state electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400248398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Susana Lopes, Thayse R. Silva, Rafael A. Raimundo, Pedro Vieira, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Fausthon F. da Silva, Rosana Cardoso Alves, Fl&#225;via de Medeiros Aquino, Daniel A. Macedo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10008-024-05992-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving high-proportioned 1T-MoS2 within heterostructures derived from polymolybdate-based complex for boosting electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110197</link>
      <description>Zhihan Chang, Yuchen Zhang, Yuan Tian, Xiuli Wang, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400258744

                The fabrication of bifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution in aqueous environment has far-reaching significance. Especially, reasonable interface process regulation toward heterogeneous composites can make full use of the active sites and improve the electrocatalytic activity. In this study, we designed and synthesized NiS2-MoS2-based heterogeneous composites as efficient and stable electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution in alkaline electrolyte. The heterostructure was obtained by one-step hydrothermal ulfurization operation towards polymolybdate-based metal-organic complex. The composition and nanostructures can be tailored by modulating experiment parameter, realizing the phase-controlled synthesis and interface regulation: (1) High-percentage of 1T-MoS2 can be achieved via selecting appropriate vulcanization time and thiourea concentration, benifiting for the higher electroconductivity and more active sites; (2) Regular and orderly vulcanization time promotes the gradual growth and aggregation of nanosheets; (3) The existence of nickel hydroxide improves the electrocatalytic stability for oxygen production performance. The optimized heterogeneous interfaces provide sufficient active sites and accelerate electron transfer. Consequently, the optimal heterogeneous nanosheets present low overpotentials of 33 and 122 mV at the catalytic current densities of 10 mA/cm2 for HER and OER, respectively.</description>
      <author>Zhihan Chang, Yuchen Zhang, Yuan Tian, Xiuli Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in Co&#8211;Fe Hydroxides through Boron Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pssa.202400481</link>
      <description>Peijia Liu, Liang Shan, Zeyi Lu, Min Liu, Physica status solidi. A, Applications and materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400263859

                Among hydrogen production methods, water electrolysis stands out, but its efficiency is hampered by the substantial energy barrier of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). To address this, incorporating electron&#8208;deficient boron (B) into Co&#8211;Fe hydroxide (CoFeO x H y ) promotes higher oxidation states of involved metals, greatly enhancing OER activity and charge transfer capabilities. Herein, the synthesis of a range of amorphous CoFeB nanoparticles with varying Fe to (Co+Fe) atomic ratios achieved through a simple chemical reduction method using CoFe&#8208;Prussian blue analogs as precursors and employing M&#246;ssbauer spectroscopy to observe structural characteristics before and after transformation is reported. Among these nanoparticles, the CoFe 0.25 B variant, exhibiting favorable electrochemical properties, is chosen and subsequently subjected to hydrolysis to yield CoFe 0.25 BOH nanoparticles, serving as an active catalyst for OER. At a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , the overpotentials for CoFe 0.25 O x H y and CoFe 0.25 BOH are 362 and 310 mV, respectively, with Tafel slopes decreasing from 393 to 93 mV dec &#8722;1 . Furthermore, the i &#8211; t test reveals no significant loss of electrochemical performance within 24 h, substantiating the efficacy of enhancing the electrocatalytic performance of CoFeO x H y through the introduction of electron&#8208;deficient elements. This research offers novel insights into the development of efficient and stable water electrolysis catalysts.</description>
      <author>Peijia Liu, Liang Shan, Zeyi Lu, Min Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pssa.202400481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontispiece: Enrooted&#8208;Type Metal&#8208;Support Interaction Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202482861</link>
      <description>Wenjuan Wang, Li Cheng, Chuan Zhou, Xin Xiao, Fayan Li, Ning&#8208;Yu Huang, Lei Li, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu, Angewandte Chemie. 63(28)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400197706

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjuan Wang, Li Cheng, Chuan Zhou, Xin Xiao, Fayan Li, Ning&#8208;Yu Huang, Lei Li, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202482861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontispiz: Enrooted&#8208;Type Metal&#8208;Support Interaction Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202482861</link>
      <description>Wenjuan Wang, Li Cheng, Chuan Zhou, Xin Xiao, Fayan Li, Ning&#8208;Yu Huang, Lei Li, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu, Angewandte Chemie. 136(28)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400197963

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjuan Wang, Li Cheng, Chuan Zhou, Xin Xiao, Fayan Li, Ning&#8208;Yu Huang, Lei Li, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202482861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multimetallic Prussian Blue Analogue Nanoparticles for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Efficient Benzyl Alcohol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02915</link>
      <description>B. N. Singh, Rakesh Kumar, Apparao Draksharapu, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400237352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. N. Singh, Rakesh Kumar, Apparao Draksharapu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood-Derived Continuously Oriented Channels Coupled with Tunable Built-In Electric Fields for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4879384</link>
      <description>Luosong Zheng, Heping Luo, Yisheng Zhong, Wanqian Li, Xu Han, Fuquan Xiong, Jiang Pi, Qing Yan, Yiqiang Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400119239

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luosong Zheng, Heping Luo, Yisheng Zhong, Wanqian Li, Xu Han, Fuquan Xiong, Jiang Pi, Qing Yan, Yiqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4879384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cs-Doped WO3 with Enhanced Conduction Band for Efficient Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Driven by Long-Wavelength Visible Light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29133126</link>
      <description>Dong Liu, Siyu Tian, Qi Qian, Caiyun Gao, Hongfang Shen, Fei Han, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(13)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400201450

                Cesium doped WO3 (Cs-WO3) photocatalyst with high and stable oxidation activity was successfully synthesized by a one-step hydrothermal method using Cs2CO3 as the doped metal ion source and tungstic acid (H2WO4) as the tungsten source. A series of analytical characterization tools and oxygen precipitation activity tests were used to compare the effects of different additions of Cs2CO3 on the crystal structure and microscopic morphologies. The UV&#8211;visible diffuse reflectance spectra (DRS) of Cs-doped material exhibited a significant red shift in the absorption edge with new shoulders appearing at 440&#8211;520 nm. The formation of an oxygen vacancy was confirmed in Cs-WO3 by the EPR signal, which can effectively regulate the electronic structure of the catalyst surface and contribute to improving the activity of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The photocatalytic OER results showed that the Cs-WO3-0.1 exhibited the optimal oxygen precipitation activity, reaching 58.28 &#181;mol at 6 h, which was greater than six times higher than that of WO3-0 (9.76 &#956;mol). It can be attributed to the synergistic effect of the increase in the conduction band position of Cs-WO3-0.1 (0.11 V) and oxygen vacancies compared to WO3-0, which accelerate the electron conduction rate and slow down the rapid compounding of photogenerated electrons&#8211;holes, improving the water-catalytic oxygen precipitation activity of WO3.</description>
      <author>Dong Liu, Siyu Tian, Qi Qian, Caiyun Gao, Hongfang Shen, Fei Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29133126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Eutectic Solvent-Assisted Corrosion Boosting Bulk FeCoNiCrMo High-Entropy Alloys as Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00769</link>
      <description>Yang Xu, Weijia Chen, Jinfeng Zhou, Chao Hu, Shiwei He, Huan Liu, Zhong-sheng Hua, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400183699

                The key to enhancing water electrolysis efficiency lies in selecting highly efficient catalysts. Currently, high-entropy alloys (HEAs) are utilized in electrocatalysis applications owing to their diverse elemental composition, disordered elemental distribution, and the high solubility of each element, endowing them with excellent catalytic performance. The experiments were conducted using isoatomic FeNiCrMo HEA as a precursor, with a high-activity three-dimensional nanoporous structure rapidly synthesized via electrochemical one-step dealloying in a choline chloride-thiourea (ChCl-TU) deep eutectic solvent (DES). The results indicate that the dealloyed Fe</description>
      <author>Yang Xu, Weijia Chen, Jinfeng Zhou, Chao Hu, Shiwei He, Huan Liu, Zhong-sheng Hua</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved hydrogen and oxygen evolution rates in Pt@TiO2@RuO2 hollow nanoshells through dielectric Mie resonance and spatial cocatalyst separation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110192</link>
      <description>Xiaxi Yao, Xiuli Hu, Fangcheng Huang, Xuhong Wang, Xiaodong Hong, Dawei Wang, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400156387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaxi Yao, Xiuli Hu, Fangcheng Huang, Xuhong Wang, Xiaodong Hong, Dawei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the performance of hybrid supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction via temperature-modulated binder-free (zinc strontium phosphate/nitrogen-graphene quantum dots) electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-024-13022-4</link>
      <description>Asma Zaka, Muhammad Waqas Iqbal, Afaf Khadr Alqorashi, Badriah S. Almutairi, Hussei Alrobei, Amir Muhammad Afzal, Haseeb ul Hassan, Journal of materials science. Materials in electronics. 35(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400179113

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asma Zaka, Muhammad Waqas Iqbal, Afaf Khadr Alqorashi, Badriah S. Almutairi, Hussei Alrobei, Amir Muhammad Afzal, Haseeb ul Hassan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-024-13022-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox Promoted Rapid and Deep Reconstruction of Defect&#8208;Rich Nickel Precatalysts for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401384</link>
      <description>Renzheng Jiang, Jinfeng Zhang, Jiajian Gao, Yingpeng Xie, Liyun Wu, Yi Wang, Zichen Xu, Zhong&#8208;Shuai Wu, Shisheng Yuan, Guangwen Xu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400122348

                Understanding the reconstruction mechanism to rationally design cost-effective electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is still challenging. Herein, a defect-rich NiMoO</description>
      <author>Renzheng Jiang, Jinfeng Zhang, Jiajian Gao, Yingpeng Xie, Liyun Wu, Yi Wang, Zichen Xu, Zhong&#8208;Shuai Wu, Shisheng Yuan, Guangwen Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling methanol oxidation with CO2 reduction: A feasible pathway to achieve carbon neutralization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.174288</link>
      <description>Chunyue Zhang, Wei Zhang, Wei Zhang, Wei Zhang, Wei Zhang, Science of the total environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400132985

                The energy consumption of up to 90 % of the total power input in the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) slows down the implementation of electrochemical CO</description>
      <author>Chunyue Zhang, Wei Zhang, Wei Zhang, Wei Zhang, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.174288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unrevealing the Potential of Multicomponent Metal Ion Incorporation and Sulfide Modification in Cobalt Oxide for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00327f</link>
      <description>M. Kashif Masood, Muhammad Aamir, Muhammad Ejaz Khan, Muhammad Sher, Kamran A. Khan, Hafiz Zahid Shafi, Md. Akhtaruzzaman, Hamad AlMohamadi, Md. Shahiduzzaman, Energy advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400188439

                Cobalt oxide is one of the promising materials for oxygen evolution reactions (OER). Customizing the metal oxide by incorporation of metal ions and sulfide modifications are effective but challenging strategy...</description>
      <author>M. Kashif Masood, Muhammad Aamir, Muhammad Ejaz Khan, Muhammad Sher, Kamran A. Khan, Hafiz Zahid Shafi, Md. Akhtaruzzaman, Hamad AlMohamadi, Md. Shahiduzzaman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00327f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetal-doped cobalt oxyhydroxides/hydroxides synthesized by electrochemistry for enhanced OER activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00823e</link>
      <description>Huan Pang, Rui Zhu, Jun Guo, Limei Liu, Gang He, Yong Li, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400223395

                Metal hydroxides and oxyhydroxides are efficient catalysts for electrochemical oxygen evolution reactions. Herein, we employed a Co-MOF with tunable structure, high porosity and easy preparation as a precursor, to synthesize...</description>
      <author>Huan Pang, Rui Zhu, Jun Guo, Limei Liu, Gang He, Yong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00823e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral supramolecular polymer functionalized two-dimensional transition metal-based catalyst for enhancing the electrochemical water splitting via. spin-polarized charge transfer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02665a</link>
      <description>Utkarsh Utkarsh, Sai Rachana Pramatha, Aidin R. Balo, Utpal Kumar Gosh, Venkata Rao Kotagiri, Krishnendu Ghosh, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400132167

                Water-splitting is one of the potential avenues to store electricity produced from renewable energy sources in the form of fuel, though the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limits its extensive application...</description>
      <author>Utkarsh Utkarsh, Sai Rachana Pramatha, Aidin R. Balo, Utpal Kumar Gosh, Venkata Rao Kotagiri, Krishnendu Ghosh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02665a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting OH* adsorption by defect engineering of CuO catalyst for selective electro-oxidation of amines to nitriles coupled with hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01571a</link>
      <description>Youlong Xu, Enhui Wei, Yi Dong, Yuhua Fan, Hongtao Gao, Xiang Liu, Wenlong Yang, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400206326

                Developing a high-efficiency benzylamine oxidation reaction (BOR) to replace sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an attractive pathway to promote H2 production and concurrently realize organic conversion. However, the electrochemical...</description>
      <author>Youlong Xu, Enhui Wei, Yi Dong, Yuhua Fan, Hongtao Gao, Xiang Liu, Wenlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01571a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ electrosynthesis of quinone-based redox-active molecules coupling with high-purity hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03033h</link>
      <description>Hyunjoon Ji, Ziming Zhao, Shun Zhang, Xianfeng Li, Chemical science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400177459

                Clean hydrogen production via conventional water splitting requires sluggish anodic oxygen evolution, which can be replaced with more valuable electrosynthesis reactions. Here, we propose one novel strategy for coupling in-situ...</description>
      <author>Hyunjoon Ji, Ziming Zhao, Shun Zhang, Xianfeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03033h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Field&#8208;Effect Enhancement of Non&#8208;Faradaic Processes at Interfaces Governs Electrocatalytic Water Splitting Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202403206</link>
      <description>Ning Wen, Haihua Wang, Qilu Liu, Kepeng Song, Xiuling Jiao, Yuguo Xia, Dairong Chen, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400134625

                Recognizing the essential factor governing interfacial hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) is central to electrocatalytic water-splitting. Traditional strategies aiming at enhancing electrocatalytic activities have mainly focused on manipulating active site valencies or coordination environments. Herein, the role of interfacial adsorption is probed and modulated by the topological construct of the electrocatalyst, a frequently underestimated non-Faradaic mechanism in the dynamics of electrocatalysis. The engineered Co</description>
      <author>Ning Wen, Haihua Wang, Qilu Liu, Kepeng Song, Xiuling Jiao, Yuguo Xia, Dairong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202403206</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Water Electrolysis by Co&#8211;Cu&#8211;W Mixed Metal Oxides: Insights from X-ray Absorption Spectroelectrochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06365</link>
      <description>Nikita Gupta, Carlo U. Segre, Christean Nickel, Carsten Streb, Dandan Gao, Ksenija D. Glusac, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400205868

                Mixed metal oxides (MMOs) are a promising class of electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Despite their importance for sustainable energy schemes, our understanding of relevant reaction pathways, catalytically active sites, and synergistic effects is rather limited. Here, we applied synchrotron-based X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) to explore the evolution of the amorphous Co-Cu-W MMO electrocatalyst, shown previously to be an efficient bifunctional OER and HER catalyst for water splitting. Ex situ XAS measurements provided structural environments and the oxidation state of the metals involved, revealing Co</description>
      <author>Nikita Gupta, Carlo U. Segre, Christean Nickel, Carsten Streb, Dandan Gao, Ksenija D. Glusac</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Well&#8208;defined nanostructures of high entropy alloys for electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20230036</link>
      <description>Jie Chen, Liping Ren, Xin Chen, Qi Wang, Chunying Chen, Jinpeng Fan, Shuai Wang, Vassili&#959;s Binas, Shaohua Shen, Exploration. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400237940

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy alloys (HEAs) have attracted significant attention for electrocatalytic energy conversion by virtue of their promisingly high efficiency, stability, and low cost. Recently, encouraging progress has been made in tuning the structure and composition of HEAs used in electrolyzers and fuel cells. However, the understanding on the synthetic methods and the structure&#8208;property&#8208;performance relationship of well&#8208;defined HEAs nanostructures is still inadequate. To gain insight into the future research directions on HEAs for electrocatalysis, in this paper, the synthetic methods commonly used to obtain well&#8208;defined HEAs nanostructures (0D nanoparticles, 1D nanowires, 2D nanosheets/nanoplates, 3D nanoporous structures, and other three&#8208;dimensional morphologies) are first summarized. Then, the authors discuss the application of well&#8208;defined HEAs nanostructures in several typical electrocatalytic reactions, including hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, alcohol oxidation reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, nitrogen reduction reaction, and formic acid oxidation reaction. Finally, a practical perspective on the future research directions on well&#8208;defined HEAs nanostructured electrocatalysts is provided.</description>
      <author>Jie Chen, Liping Ren, Xin Chen, Qi Wang, Chunying Chen, Jinpeng Fan, Shuai Wang, Vassili&#959;s Binas, Shaohua Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20230036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Current Pulse Atmospheric Pressure Plasma Jet Treatment on Electrochemically Deposited NiFe/Carbon Paper and Its Potential Application in an Anion-Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01169</link>
      <description>Shuo-En Yu, Yu-Ming Su, I&#8208;Chih Ni, Yi-Cheng Chuang, Cheng&#8208;Che Hsu, Chih&#8208;I Wu, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, I&#8208;Chun Cheng, Jian&#8208;Zhang Chen, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400212785

                An atmospheric pressure plasma jet (APPJ) is used to process electrochemically deposited NiFe on carbon paper (NiFe/CP). The reactive oxygen and nitrogen species (RONs) of the APPJ modify the surface properties, chemical bonding types, and oxidation states of the material at the self-sustained temperature of the APPJ. The APPJ treatment further enhances the hydrophilicity and creates a higher disorder level in the carbon material. Moreover, the metal carbide bonds of NiFe/CP formed in the electrochemical deposition (ED) process are converted to metal oxide bonds after APPJ processing. The potential application of APPJ treatment on NiFe/CP in alkaline water electrolysis is demonstrated. With more oxygen-containing species and better hydrophilicity after APPJ treatment, APPJ-treated NiFe/CP is applied as the electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline water electrolysis. APPJ-treated NiFe/CP is also used in a custom-made anion-exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE); this should contribute toward realizing the practical large-scale application of AEM for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Shuo-En Yu, Yu-Ming Su, I&#8208;Chih Ni, Yi-Cheng Chuang, Cheng&#8208;Che Hsu, Chih&#8208;I Wu, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, I&#8208;Chun Cheng, Jian&#8208;Zhang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dots for Hydrogen Production. How Do They Work?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400757</link>
      <description>Luigi Stagi, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400243856

                Carbon Dots (CDs) have gained significant attention for their fascinating optical properties, potential applications, and puzzling structural challenges. In the last decade, CDs have become the focal point in many photocatalysis studies, either as independent systems or combined with other established photocatalysts. CDs play a crucial role in enhancing the performance of heterostructures for overall water splitting, hydrogen (HER), and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In these "Concepts," we briefly explore the structure of CDs, highlighting their critical aspects, including their role within heterostructures, composition, the presence of fluorophores, and the interaction between the graphitic core and surface functional groups. We will also examine how these factors impact their photocatalytic properties, particularly in the context of future research on H&#8322; production.</description>
      <author>Luigi Stagi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface atomic bidirectional migration modulated electrocatalytic activity in Co2MnO4 nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214408</link>
      <description>Caiyun Qi, Baorui Xia, Xuebing Peng, Xingdong Jiang, Dongning Gao, Applied physics letters. 125(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400246119

                Polymetallic cationic spinel-type oxides are increasingly being used as catalysts for oxygen reduction/oxygen evolution reactions (ORR/OER). Here, we have modified the anti-spinel Co2MnO4 using a quenching strategy (CMO-Q) and demonstrated that the bidirectional migration of Co and Mn cations at the tetrahedral/octahedral positions is the essential reason for enhancing the ORR/OER performance. Electrochemical test results show that CMO-Q is better than Co2MnO4, OER initial potential decreased by 100 mV, and ORR current density increased from 4.2 to 7.3 mA cm&#8722;2 at 1600 rpm, with more stable CMO-Q-based zinc&#8211;air battery performance. Meanwhile, density functional theory calculations confirm that the primary factor contributing to the reduction of distance from the d-band center of Co and Mn to the Fermi level is the conductivity enhancement. This study offers insight into regulating the surface atomic migration and catalytic performance of spinel without compromising its stable structure.</description>
      <author>Caiyun Qi, Baorui Xia, Xuebing Peng, Xingdong Jiang, Dongning Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0214408</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Conductive MoO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Thin Films by Plasma Enhanced Atomic Layer Deposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202301724</link>
      <description>Ling Zhou, Zhuo Guan, Lin Yang, Daying Guo, Leiming Wu, Xi&#8217;an Chen, Yifei Yuan, Advanced engineering materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400137600

                Herein, we construct amorphous molybdenum oxide films by thermal atomic layer deposition (T&#8208;ALD) and plasma enhanced atomic layer deposition (PE&#8208;ALD). The physical and chemical properties of molybdenum oxide films prepared by the two methods were systematically compared by means of film growth law, atomic force microscope and scanning electron microscope etc. The results show that the amorphous molybdenum oxide physical phase prepared by both atomic layer deposition methods is MoO 3 . Compared with T&#8208;ALD MoO 3 , the growth rate of MoO 3 thin films prepared by PE&#8208;ALD is higher. Compared to PE&#8208;ALD MoO 3 , the MoO 3 films prepared by T&#8208;ALD did not have nucleation delayed to a laminar growth mode, resulting in smoother deposited films and contained less impurity carbon. The MoO 3 prepared by PE&#8208;ALD contains 7.4% impurity carbon. This carbon&#8208;doped film significantly improves the conductivity of the MoO 3 film and shows good electrochemical activity. As expected, the MoO 3 films prepared by PE&#8208;ALD show good electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction. The overpotential was only 259 mV at 10 mA cm &#8208;2 and continued to evolution oxygen for 60 h with almost no attenuation, indicating that carbon doping significantly improves the catalytic intrinsic activity and stability of MoO 3 . This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Ling Zhou, Zhuo Guan, Lin Yang, Daying Guo, Leiming Wu, Xi&#8217;an Chen, Yifei Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202301724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Corrosion Resistance in Aluminum-Based Electrolyzer Components via Stoichiometry Tuned Atomic Layer-Deposited TiO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05450</link>
      <description>Kesong Wang, Adam Paxson, Thomas Valdez, Ahmet G&#252;n Erlat, Ping-Che Lee, SeongUk Yun, Pranjali Khajanji, Zichen Zhang, Andrew C. Kummel, Prabhakar R. Bandaru, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400108563

                Titanium (Ti) is widely used as anode current collectors in proton exchange membrane (PEM)-based water electrolyzers due to its self-passivated oxide layer, which protects it from corrosion in acidic solutions. However, the cost of the material and machining process for Ti is high. A wider utilization of water electrolyzers to produce hydrogen could be favored by the use of less expensive coated aluminum (Al) substrates, which could potentially replace high-cost Ti-based components. It is shown here by depositing a pinhole-free oxygen vacancy-rich titanium oxide (TiOx) protection layer by atomic layer deposition (ALD), the corrosion resistance of Al substrates in acidic environments at oxygen evolution potentials can be enhanced. The optimization of the oxygen vacancy concentration is accomplished by tuning the ALD parameters to achieve ideal stoichiometry and conformal coating on rough substrates. The robustness of the coatings was evaluated at high potentials (2.4 V vs NHE = normal hydrogen electrode) in low pH conditions. A low TiOx dissolution rate of the order of &#8764;6 nm year&#8211;1 was observed. By testing under industrially relevant conditions, i.e., high applied voltages (2.4 V) and low pH, an Al loss at around the zero ppb level was achieved using optimized ALD parameters. It is proposed that a 40 nm TiOx coating on Al may be adequate to provide 60,000 h of durability in a PEM water electrolyzer anode current collector.</description>
      <author>Kesong Wang, Adam Paxson, Thomas Valdez, Ahmet G&#252;n Erlat, Ping-Che Lee, SeongUk Yun, Pranjali Khajanji, Zichen Zhang, Andrew C. Kummel, Prabhakar R. Bandaru</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Regulation of MnCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; via Surface&#8208;Phosphorization Coupling to Monolithic Carbon for Oxygen Electrocatalysis in Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400522</link>
      <description>Yanyan Liu, Shilin Liu, Pengxiang Zhang, Jingjing Zhou, Long Huan, Shu&#8208;Qi Li, Li X, Xiaopeng Wang, Han Dong, Yu Chen, Yongfeng Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Baojun Li, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400201031

                Abstract An urgent challenge to the development of rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (RZABs) is the highly active, durable, and low&#8208;cost catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction (ORR and OER). Herein, a carbon&#8208;based monolithic catalyst is designed via anchoring P&#8208;modified MnCo 2 O 4 inverse spinel nanoparticles on biomass&#8208;derived carbon (P&#8208;MnCo 2 O 4 @PWC). The introduction of surface P atoms regulates the electronic structures and valences of metal atoms by adjusting the coordination fields by (P&#8208;O) &#948;&#8211; and Metal&#8208;P. The optimization of the adsorption behavior of key intermediates facilitates the activation and conversion of reaction species. The monolithic structure is beneficial to the construction of a three&#8208;phase interface for efficient mass transfer and high electrical conductivity. The P&#8208;MnCo 2 O 4 @PWC catalyst displays outstanding bifunctional catalytic properties with a thin &#916; E (the difference between the OER potential at 10 mA cm &#8211; 2 and the ORR halfwave potential) of 0.66 V. The RZAB with P&#8208;MnCo 2 O 4 @PWC as cathode delivers an exceptional peak power density (160 mW cm &#8211; 2 ) and remarkable cycle life (over 1200 cycles), overcoming those with noble metal counterparts. This research provides a promising general surface&#8208;phosphorization way to the design of carbon electrocatalysts and the high&#8208;value utilization of biomass.</description>
      <author>Yanyan Liu, Shilin Liu, Pengxiang Zhang, Jingjing Zhou, Long Huan, Shu&#8208;Qi Li, Li X, Xiaopeng Wang, Han Dong, Yu Chen, Yongfeng Wang, Jianchun Jiang, Baojun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directional surface reconstruction of C and S Co-Doped Co2VO4/CoP for the cooperative enhancement of hydrogen production via seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.240</link>
      <description>Haiyang Chang, Kun Lang, Jianping Fan, Jinlong Lei, Baojiang Jiang, Ming Gao, Cheng Wang, Xudong Chen, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400216955

                The endeavor to architect bifunctional electrocatalysts that exhibit both exceptional activity and durability heralds an era of boundless potential for the comprehensive electrolysis of seawater, an aspiration that, nevertheless, poses a substantial challenge. Within this work, we describe the precise engineering of a three-dimensional interconnected nanoparticle system named SCdoped Co2VO4/CoP (SCCo2VO4), achieved through a meticulously arranged hydrothermal treatment sequence followed by gas-phase carbonization and phosphorization. The resulting SCCo2VO4 electrode exhibits outstanding bifunctional electrocatalytic stability, attributed to the strategic anionic doping and abundant heterogeneous interfaces. Doping not only adjusts the electronic structure, enhancing electron transfer efficiency but also optimizes the surface-active sites. This electrode prodigiously necessitated an extraordinarily minimal overpotential of merely 92 and 350 mV to attain current densities of 10 and 50 mA cm&#8722;2 for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively, in 1 M KOH solution. Noteworthily, when integrated into an electrolyzer for the exhaustive splitting of seawater, the SCP-Co2VO4 manifested an exceptionally low cell voltage of 2.08 V@50 mA cm&#8722;2 and showcased a durability that eclipses that of most hitherto documented nickel-based bifunctional materials. Further elucidation through Density Functional Theory (DFT) analyses underscored that anion doping and the inherent heterostructure adeptly optimize the Gibbs free energy of intermediates comprising hydrogen, chlorine, and oxygen (manifested as OH, O, OOH) within the HER and OER paradigms, thus propelling the electrochemical kinetics of seawater splitting to unprecedented velocities. These revelations unfurl a pioneering design philosophy for the creation of cost-effective yet superior catalysts aimed at the holistic division of water molecules, charting a course towards the realization of efficient and sustainable hydrogen production methodologies.</description>
      <author>Haiyang Chang, Kun Lang, Jianping Fan, Jinlong Lei, Baojiang Jiang, Ming Gao, Cheng Wang, Xudong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.240</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A two&#8208;dimensional Cu&#8208;based nanosheet producing formic acid via glycerol electro&#8208;oxidation in alkaline water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400317</link>
      <description>Srewashi Das, Siddarth Jain, Anwesha Banerjee, Arnab Dutta, ChemPlusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400144593

                The sluggishness of the complementary oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is reckoned as one of the major drawbacks in developing an energy-efficient green hydrogen-producing electrolyzer. An array of organic molecule oxidation reactions, operational at a relatively low potential, have been explored as a substitute for the OER. Glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) has emerged as a leading alternative in this context. Additionally, the GOR generates several value-added organic compounds following oxidation that enhance the cost viability of the overall electrolysis reaction. In this study, a low-cost, room temperature operable, and energy-efficient synthetic methodology has been developed to generate unique two-dimensional CuO nanosheets (CuO NS). This CuO NS material was embedded on a carbon paper electrode, which showcased excellent glycerol electro-oxidation performance operational at a moderately low applied potential. Formic acid is the major product of this CuO NS-driven GOR (Faradaic efficiency ~80%), as it is formed primarily via the glyceraldehyde oxidation pathway. This CuO NS material was also active for oxidizing other abundant alcohols like ethylene glycol and diethylene glycol, albeit at a relatively poor efficiency. Therefore, this robust CuO NS material has displayed the potential to be used in large-scale electrolyzers functioning with HER/GOR reactions.</description>
      <author>Srewashi Das, Siddarth Jain, Anwesha Banerjee, Arnab Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus Doping Heterostructure La(OH) 3 @CuO @NF as Advanced Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4568184/v1</link>
      <description>Decui Liang, Weishun Hou, Ying Zhang, Jianhua Shang, Haibo Ren, Yong Sun, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400137499

                Abstract Due to the prevailing energy shortages, the quest for new alternative energy sources is growing increasingly urgent. Hydrogen production through water electrolysis has become a crucial method. However, the slow four-electron reaction in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) becomes the main rate-limiting step. In this study, we propose obtaining heterostructure La(OH)3@CuO-P after composite phosphatisation using nickel foam (NF) as the substrate material. The experimental results demonstrate that the heterostructure La(OH)3@CuO exhibits an overpotential of 365mV at a current density of 10mA/cm2 , and displays a Tafel slope value of 114.02mF/dec, a bilayer capacitance of 1.853mF/cm2 for OER in a 1 M KOH solution. After phosphating, the heterostructure La(OH)3@CuO-P exhibits exceptional catalytic performance with only 215 mV overpotential, a Tafel slope value of 79.36 mV/dec, and a bilayer capacitance of 34.73mF/cm2 at a current density of 10mA/cm2 . Moreover, it also exhibits relatively stable performance during cyclic voltammetry testing for up to1000 cycles. Analyses suggest that the formation of a heterojunction structure in La(OH)3@CuO-P effectively addresses the issues of insufficient conductivity of La(OH)3 and tendency for CuO monomer aggregation while maintaining excellent properties for each component. The substitutional P atom doping not only adjusts the electronic structure and optimizes the adsorption free energy of -OH but also reduces sample size and increases catalytic active sites, thereby further enhancing the OER performance of the material.</description>
      <author>Decui Liang, Weishun Hou, Ying Zhang, Jianhua Shang, Haibo Ren, Yong Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4568184/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser solid-phase synthesis of graphene shell-encapsulated high-entropy alloy nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4471162/v1</link>
      <description>Li Zhu, Yuxiang Liu, Jianghuai Yuan, Jian Zhou, Kewen Pan, Ran Zhang, Rongxia Zhao, Lin Liu, Yihe Huang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400133500

                Abstract Rapid synthesis of high-entropy alloy nanoparticles (HEA NPs) offers new opportunities to develop functional materials in widespread applications. Although some methods have successfully produced HEA NPs, these methods generally require rigorous conditions such as high pressure, high temperature, restricted atmosphere and limited substrates, which impede practical viability. In this work, we report a laser solid-phase synthesis of CrMnFeCoNi nanoparticles by laser irradiation of mixed metal precursors on a laser-induced graphene (LIG) support with a 3D porous structure. The CrMnFeCoNi nanoparticles are embraced by several graphene layers, forming graphene shell-encapsulated HEA nanoparticles. We provide an in-depth understanding of the laser solid-phase synthesis of HEA NPs on LIG supports by simulation and experimental observations, in consideration of mixed metal precursor adsorption, thermal decomposition, reduction through electrons from laser-induced thermionic emission, and liquid beads splitting. The production rate reaches up to 30 g/h under the current laser setup. The laser-synthesized graphene shell-encapsulated CrMnFeCoNi NPs loaded on LIG supports are used directly as 3D binder-free integrated electrodes and exhibited excellent electrocatalytic activity towards oxygen evolution reaction with an overpotential of 293 mV at the current density of 10 mA/cm2 and exceptional stability over 428 hours in alkaline media, outperforming the commercial RuO2 catalyst and the counterpart catalysts reported by other methods. This work also demonstrates the versatility of this technique through the successful synthesis of CrMnFeCoNi oxide, sulfide and phosphide nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>Li Zhu, Yuxiang Liu, Jianghuai Yuan, Jian Zhou, Kewen Pan, Ran Zhang, Rongxia Zhao, Lin Liu, Yihe Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4471162/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of an Ethanol Electroreforming Cell Based on a Pt1Ru1/C Catalyst at the Anode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070415</link>
      <description>Carmelo Lo Vecchio, Enrica Mosca, Stefano Trocino, Vincenzo Baglio, Catalysts. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400196669

                The production of H2 from renewable sources represents a crucial challenge for the planet&#8217;s future to achieve net zero emissions and store renewable energy. A possible alternative to water electrolysis (WE), which requires high potential (E &gt; 1.48 V) to trigger the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), would be alcohol electrochemical reforming (ER), which implies the oxidation of short organic molecules such as methanol or ethanol. In ER, energy must be supplied to the system, but from a thermodynamic point of view, the energy request for the methanol or ethanol oxidation reaction is much lower than that of the OER. To study this process, an in-house 50 wt.% Pt1Ru1/C anodic catalyst was easily synthesized according to the Pt sulphite complex route and the impregnation of a carbon support (Ketjenblack, KB) and a Ru precursor. X-ray diffraction (XRD), X-ray fluorescence (XRF) spectroscopy, and Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) were used to characterize the structure, composition, and morphology of the catalyst. It appears that two distinct crystallographic phases of the Pt and Ru nanoparticles were encountered after the synthesis conducted by Ru impregnation. For the electrochemical measurements, ethanol electrooxidation (2 M CH3CH2OH) was studied first in a half cell with a rotating disc electrode (RDE) configuration under acid conditions and then in a direct ethanol electroreforming (or electrolysis) cell, equipped with a proton exchange membrane (PEM) as the electrolyte. The output current density was 0.93 A cm&#8722;2 at 1 V and 90 &#176;C in 2 M ethanol. The remarkable current densities obtained in the alcohol electrolyzer at a low voltage are better than the actual state of the art for PEM ethanol ER.</description>
      <author>Carmelo Lo Vecchio, Enrica Mosca, Stefano Trocino, Vincenzo Baglio</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical evolution of Complex Organic Molecules in turbulent protoplanetary disks: Effect of stochastic UV irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae1589</link>
      <description>Taiki Suzuki, Kenji Furuya, Yuri Aikawa, Toshikatsu Shibata, Liton Majumdar, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400223606

                Abstract We investigate the chemical evolution of complex organic molecules (COMs) in turbulent disks using gas-ice chemical reaction network simulations. We trace trajectories of dust particles considering advection, turbulent diffusion, gas drag, and vertical settling, for 106 yrs in a protoplanetary disk. Then, we solve a gas-ice chemical reaction network along the trajectories and obtain the temporal evolution of molecular abundances. We find that the COM abundances in particles can differ by more than two orders of magnitude even when the UV fluence (i.e., the time integral of UV flux) received by the particles are similar, suggesting that not only the UV fluence but also the time variation of the UV flux does matter for the evolution of COMs in disks. The impact of UV fluence on molecular abundances differs between oxygen-bearing and nitrogen-bearing COMs. While higher UV fluence results in oxygen being locked into CO2, leading to reduced abundances of oxygen-bearing COMs such as CH3OCH3, mild UV exposure can promote their formation by supplying the precursor radicals. On the other hand, nitrogen is not locked up into specific molecules, allowing the formation of nitrogen-bearing COMs, particularly CH3NH2, even for the particle that receives the higher UV fluence. We also find that the final COM abundances are mostly determined by the inherited abundances from the protostellar core when the UV fluence received by dust particles is less than a critical value, while they are set by both the inherited abundances and the chemistry inside the disk at higher UV fluence.</description>
      <author>Taiki Suzuki, Kenji Furuya, Yuri Aikawa, Toshikatsu Shibata, Liton Majumdar</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae1589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustained increases in atmospheric oxygen and marine productivity in the Neoproterozoic and Palaeozoic eras</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01479-1</link>
      <description>Richard Stockey, Devon B. Cole, &#218;na C. Farrell, Heda Agi&#263;, Thomas H. Boag, Jochen J. Brocks, Donald E. Canfield, Chengsheng Jin, Peter W. Crockford, Huan Cui, Tais W. Dahl, Lucas Del Mouro, Keith Dewing, Stephen Q. Dornbos, Joseph F. Emmings, Robert R. Gaines, Timothy M. Gibson, Benjamin C. Gill, Geoffrey J. Gilleaudeau, Karin Goldberg, Romain Guilbaud, Galen P. Halverson, Emma U. Hammarlund, Kalev Hantsoo, Miles A. Henderson, Charles M. Henderson, Malcolm S.W. Hodgskiss, Amber J. M. Jarrett, David T. Johnston, Pavel Kabanov, Julien Kimmig, Andrew H. Knoll, Marcus Kunzmann, Matthew A. LeRoy, Chao Li, David K. Loydell, Francis A. Macdonald, Joseph M. Magnall, N. Tanner Mills, Lawrence M. Och, Brennan O&#8217;Connell, Ana&#239;s Pag&#232;s, Shanan E. Peters, Susannah M. Porter, Simon W. Poulton, Samantha Ritzer, Alan D. Rooney, Shane D. Schoepfer, Emily F. Smith, Justin V. Strauss, Gabriel Jub&#233; Uhlein, Theresa L. White, Rachel Wood, Christina R. Woltz, Inessa Yurchenko, Noah J. Planavsky, Erik A. Sperling, Nature geoscience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400248620

                Abstract A geologically rapid Neoproterozoic oxygenation event is commonly linked to the appearance of marine animal groups in the fossil record. However, there is still debate about what evidence from the sedimentary geochemical record&#8212;if any&#8212;provides strong support for a persistent shift in surface oxygen immediately preceding the rise of animals. We present statistical learning analyses of a large dataset of geochemical data and associated geological context from the Neoproterozoic and Palaeozoic sedimentary record and then use Earth system modelling to link trends in redox-sensitive trace metal and organic carbon concentrations to the oxygenation of Earth&#8217;s oceans and atmosphere. We do not find evidence for the wholesale oxygenation of Earth&#8217;s oceans in the late Neoproterozoic era. We do, however, reconstruct a moderate long-term increase in atmospheric oxygen and marine productivity. These changes to the Earth system would have increased dissolved oxygen and food supply in shallow-water habitats during the broad interval of geologic time in which the major animal groups first radiated. This approach provides some of the most direct evidence for potential physiological drivers of the Cambrian radiation, while highlighting the importance of later Palaeozoic oxygenation in the evolution of the modern Earth system.</description>
      <author>Richard Stockey, Devon B. Cole, &#218;na C. Farrell, Heda Agi&#263;, Thomas H. Boag, Jochen J. Brocks, Donald E. Canfield, Chengsheng Jin, Peter W. Crockford, Huan Cui, Tais W. Dahl, Lucas Del Mouro, Keith Dewing, Stephen Q. Dornbos, Joseph F. Emmings, Robert R. Gaines, Timothy M. Gibson, Benjamin C. Gill, Geoffrey J. Gilleaudeau, Karin Goldberg, Romain Guilbaud, Galen P. Halverson, Emma U. Hammarlund, Kalev Hantsoo, Miles A. Henderson, Charles M. Henderson, Malcolm S.W. Hodgskiss, Amber J. M. Jarrett, David T. Johnston, Pavel Kabanov, Julien Kimmig, Andrew H. Knoll, Marcus Kunzmann, Matthew A. LeRoy, Chao Li, David K. Loydell, Francis A. Macdonald, Joseph M. Magnall, N. Tanner Mills, Lawrence M. Och, Brennan O&#8217;Connell, Ana&#239;s Pag&#232;s, Shanan E. Peters, Susannah M. Porter, Simon W. Poulton, Samantha Ritzer, Alan D. Rooney, Shane D. Schoepfer, Emily F. Smith, Justin V. Strauss, Gabriel Jub&#233; Uhlein, Theresa L. White, Rachel Wood, Christina R. Woltz, Inessa Yurchenko, Noah J. Planavsky, Erik A. Sperling</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41561-024-01479-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The studies on dehydration reaction mechanism of irradiated solid acid - nanostructured sodium - bentonite clay</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15330/pcss.25.2.362-367</link>
      <description>M.K. Ismayilova, Islam Mustafayev, &#1057;. &#1047;. &#1052;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, F.N. Nurmammadova, M.H. Aliyeva, F&#236;zika &#236; h&#236;m&#236;&#226; tverdogo t&#236;la. 25(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400214185

                Research findings can offer data and a theoretical framework for a quantitative examination of the bentonite dehydration mechanism. The reasons for changes in pore&#8217; water under the influence of gamma rays in vacuum and in the presence of oxygen was discussed using TGA and DTA, FT-IR spectroscopy. It was revealed that dehydration and pore characteristics are mutually dependent. A question about the associated evolution of dehydration pore&#8216;s water in nanostructured sodium &#8211; bentonite clay under the influence of ionizing rays with and without oxygen has been comparatively studied. The article is devoted to a discussion of how ionizing radiation, passing through nanoclays, produces, or rather begins to produce, chemical effects. It was used Infrared spectroscopy as the method for determining structural responses of natural clay from the Alpoid deposit in the Republic of Azerbaijan, to gamma rays exposure. It was found that under influence of ionizing rays in vacuum obtained hydrogen peroxide. It is of great interest for the study of the dehydration reaction mechanism and its role in formation of H2 under gamma irradiation.</description>
      <author>M.K. Ismayilova, Islam Mustafayev, &#1057;. &#1047;. &#1052;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, F.N. Nurmammadova, M.H. Aliyeva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15330/pcss.25.2.362-367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic Character Mapping, Bayesian Model Selection, and Biosynthetic Pathways Shed New Light on the Evolution of Habitat Preference in Cyanobacteria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/sysbio/syae025</link>
      <description>Giorgio Bianchini, Martin Hagemann, Patricia S&#225;nchez&#8208;Baracaldo, Systematic biology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400091897

                Abstract Cyanobacteria are the only prokaryotes to have evolved oxygenic photosynthesis paving the way for complex life. Studying the evolution and ecological niche of cyanobacteria and their ancestors is crucial for understanding the intricate dynamics of biosphere evolution. These organisms frequently deal with environmental stressors such as salinity and drought, and they employ compatible solutes as a mechanism to cope with these challenges. Compatible solutes are small molecules that help maintain cellular osmotic balance in high salinity environments, such as marine waters. Their production plays a crucial role in salt tolerance, which, in turn, influences habitat preference. Among the five known compatible solutes produced by cyanobacteria (sucrose, trehalose, glucosylglycerol, glucosylglycerate, and glycine betaine), their synthesis varies between individual strains. In this study, we work in a Bayesian stochastic mapping framework, integrating multiple sources of information about compatible solute biosynthesis in order to predict the ancestral habitat preference of Cyanobacteria. Through extensive model selection analyses and statistical tests for correlation, we identify glucosylglycerol and glucosylglycerate as the most significantly correlated with habitat preference, while trehalose exhibits the weakest correlation. Additionally, glucosylglycerol, glucosylglycerate, and glycine betaine show high loss/gain rate ratios, indicating their potential role in adaptability, while sucrose and trehalose are less likely to be lost due to their additional cellular functions. Contrary to previous findings, our analyses predict that the last common ancestor of Cyanobacteria (living at around 3180 Ma) had a 97% probability of a high salinity habitat preference and was likely able to synthesise glucosylglycerol and glucosylglycerate. Nevertheless, cyanobacteria likely colonized low-salinity environments shortly after their origin, with an 89% probability of the first cyanobacterium with low-salinity habitat preference arising prior to the Great Oxygenation Event (2460 Ma). Stochastic mapping analyses provide evidence of cyanobacteria inhabiting early marine habitats, aiding in the interpretation of the geological record. Our age estimate of ~2590 Ma for the divergence of two major cyanobacterial clades (Macro- and Microcyanobacteria) suggests that these were likely significant contributors to primary productivity in marine habitats in the lead-up to the Great Oxygenation Event, and thus played a pivotal role in triggering the sudden increase in atmospheric oxygen.</description>
      <author>Giorgio Bianchini, Martin Hagemann, Patricia S&#225;nchez&#8208;Baracaldo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/sysbio/syae025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagnostics of 3D explosion asymmetries of stripped-envelope supernovae by nebular line profiles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae1603</link>
      <description>Bart F A van Baal, A. Jerkstrand, Annop Wongwathanarat, Hans-Thomas Janka, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400163514

                Abstract Understanding the explosion mechanism and hydrodynamic evolution of core-collapse supernovae is a long-standing quest in astronomy. The asymmetries caused by the explosion are encoded into the line profiles which appear in the nebular phase of the SN evolution &#8211; with particularly clean imprints in He star explosions. Here, we carry out nine different supernova simulations of He-core progenitors, exploding them in 3D with parametrically varied neutrino luminosities using the Prometheus-HotB code, hydrodynamically evolving the models to the homologeous phase. We then compute nebular phase spectra with the 3D NLTE spectral synthesis code ExTraSS (EXplosive TRAnsient Spectral Simulator). We study how line widths and shifts depend on progenitor mass, explosion energy, and viewing angle. We compare the predicted line profile properties against a large set of Type Ib observations, and discuss the degree to which current neutrino-driven explosions can match observationally inferred asymmetries. With self-consistent 3D modelling &#8211; circumventing the difficulties of representing 56Ni mixing and clumping accurately in 1D models &#8211; we find that neither low-mass He cores exploding with high energies nor high-mass cores exploding with low energies contribute to the Type Ib SN population. Models which have line profile widths in agreement with this population give sufficiently large centroid shifts for calcium emission lines. Calcium is more strongly affected by explosion asymmetries connected to the neutron star kicks than oxygen and magnesium. Lastly, we turn to the NIR spectra from our models to investigate the potential of using this regime to look for the presence of He in the nebular phase.</description>
      <author>Bart F A van Baal, A. Jerkstrand, Annop Wongwathanarat, Hans-Thomas Janka</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae1603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eReaxFF force field development for BaZr0.8Y0.2O3-&#948; solid oxide electrolysis cells applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01268-9</link>
      <description>Md Jamil Hossain, Prashik Gaikwad, Yun Kyung Shin, Jessica A. Schulze, Katheryn A. Penrod, Meng Li, Yuxiao Lin, Gorakh Pawar, Adri C. T. van Duin, npj computational materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400126208

                Abstract The use of solid-oxide materials in electrocatalysis applications, especially in hydrogen-evolution reactions, is promising. However, further improvements are warranted to overcome the fundamental bottlenecks to enhancing the performance of solid-oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs), which is directly linked to the more-refined fundamental understanding of complex physical and chemical phenomena and mass exchanges that take place at the surfaces and in the bulk of electrocatalysis materials. Here, we developed an eReaxFF force field for barium zirconate doped with 20 mol% of yttrium, BaZr 0.8 Y 0.2 O 3-&#948; (BZY20) to enable a systematic, large-length-scale, and longer-timescale atomistic simulation of solid-oxide electrocatalysis for hydrogen generation. All parameters for the eReaxFF were optimized to reproduce quantum-mechanical (QM) calculations on relevant condensed phase and cluster systems describing oxygen vacancies, vacancy migrations, electron localization, water adsorption, water splitting, and hydrogen generation on the surfaces of the BZY20 solid oxide. Using the developed force field, we performed both zero-voltage (excess electrons absent) and non-zero-voltage (excess electrons present) molecular dynamics simulations to observe water adsorption, water splitting, proton migration, oxygen-vacancy migrations, and eventual hydrogen-production reactions. Based on investigations offered in the present study, we conclude that the eReaxFF force field-based approach can enable computationally efficient simulations for electron conductivity, electron leakage, and other non-zero-voltage effects on the solid oxide materials using the explicit-electron concept. Moreover, we demonstrate how the eReaxFF force field-based atomistic-simulation approach can enhance our understanding of processes in SOEC applications and potentially other renewable-energy applications.</description>
      <author>Md Jamil Hossain, Prashik Gaikwad, Yun Kyung Shin, Jessica A. Schulze, Katheryn A. Penrod, Meng Li, Yuxiao Lin, Gorakh Pawar, Adri C. T. van Duin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01268-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eco-evolutionary Guided Pathomic Analysis to Predict DCIS Upstaging</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.06.23.600274</link>
      <description>Y. Xiao, Manal Elmasry, Ji-Dong Karen Bai, Andrew Chen, Y. Chen, B. D. Jackson, Joseph Johnson, Robert J. Gillies, Prateek Prasanna, Chao Chen, Mehdi Damaghi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400105508

                Cancers evolve in a dynamic ecosystem. Thus, characterizing cancer's ecological dynamics is crucial to understanding cancer evolution and can lead to discovering novel biomarkers to predict disease progression. Ductal carcinoma in situ (DCIS) is an early-stage breast cancer characterized by abnormal epithelial cell growth confined within the milk ducts. Although there has been extensive research on genetic and epigenetic causes of breast carcinogenesis, none of these studies have successfully identified a biomarker for the progression and/or upstaging of DCIS. In this study, we show that ecological habitat analysis of hypoxia and acidosis biomarkers can significantly improve prediction of DCIS upstaging. First, we developed a novel eco-evolutionary designed approach to define habitats in the tumor intra-ductal microenvironment based on oxygen diffusion distance in our DCIS cohort of 84 patients. Then, we identify cancer cells with metabolic phenotypes attributed to their habitat conditions, such as the expression of CA9 indicating hypoxia responding phenotype, and LAMP2b indicating a hypoxia-induced acid adaptation. Traditionally these markers have shown limited predictive capabilities for DCIS upstaging, if any. However, when analyzed from an ecological perspective, their power to differentiate between indolent and upstaged DCIS increased significantly. Second, using eco-evolutionary guided computational and digital pathology techniques, we discovered distinct spatial patterns of these biomarkers and used the distribution of such patterns to predict patient upstaging. The patterns were characterized by both cellular features and spatial features. With a 5-fold validation on the biopsy cohort, we trained a random forest classifier to achieve the area under curve(AUC) of 0.74. Our results affirm the importance of using eco-evolutionary-designed approaches in biomarkers discovery studies in the era of digital pathology by demonstrating the role of eco-evolution dynamics in predicting cancer progression.</description>
      <author>Y. Xiao, Manal Elmasry, Ji-Dong Karen Bai, Andrew Chen, Y. Chen, B. D. Jackson, Joseph Johnson, Robert J. Gillies, Prateek Prasanna, Chao Chen, Mehdi Damaghi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.06.23.600274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Primary Ciliary Dyskinesia Associated with Rheumatoid Lung at The Koulikoro Reference Health Center, Mali</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.36348/sjmps.2024.v10i06.008</link>
      <description>F. Sidib&#233;, R.G. Bopaka, D Sogoba, K. S Demb&#233;l&#233;, Seydou Diallo, Saudi journal of medical and pharmaceutical sciences. 10(06)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400259034

                Primary ciliary dyskinesia is a cause of bronchial dilatation, associated with rheumatoid lung is rare. This is why we report a case with the aim of discussing the clinical, diagnostic characteristics and therapeutic possibilities of ciliary pathology and showing the link between it and rheumatoid arthritis. Observation: This is a 40-year-old African patient, married without children, from a consanguineous couple, with a family history of a brother who died in adulthood in a picture of respiratory failure and productive cough. She presented with recurrent rhinorrhea since childhood and bronchorrhea in a picture of progressively worsening dyspnea and clubbing. During the evolution of the disease, inflammatory polyarthralgia was associated. The ultrastructural ciliary study by electron microscopy and the measurement of nasal nitrogen oxide are the confirmatory examinations of primary ciliary dyskinesia. They are not achievable in our practice. However, based on the history and clinical findings, the patient presented several elements in favor of this pathology. additional investigations, notably the rheumatoid factor and the chest CT scan, allowed us to suggest rheumatoid lung. Our therapeutic conduct was the administration of antibiotic therapy, oxygen therapy, immunosuppressant, anti-inflammatory and the practice of respiratory physiotherapy. Conclusion: Primary ciliary dyskinesia associated with pulmonary involvement in rheumatoid arthritis increases the risk of developing respiratory failure.</description>
      <author>F. Sidib&#233;, R.G. Bopaka, D Sogoba, K. S Demb&#233;l&#233;, Seydou Diallo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.36348/sjmps.2024.v10i06.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra&#8208;Small High&#8208;Entropy Alloy as Multi&#8208;Functional Catalyst for Ammonia Based Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400892</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Zhang, Zumin Wang, Lei Wang, Lingbo Zong, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400247465

                Abstract Ammonia fuel cells using carbon&#8208;neutral ammonia as fuel are regarded as a fast, furious, and flexible next&#8208;generation carbon&#8208;free energy conversion technology, but it is limited by the kinetically sluggish ammonia oxidation reaction (AOR), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Platinum can efficiently drive these three types of reactions, but its scale&#8208;up application is limited by its susceptibility to poisoning and high cost. In order to reduce the cost and alleviate poisoning, incorporating Pt with various metals proves to be an efficient and feasible strategy. Herein, PtFeCoNiIr/C trifunctional high&#8208;entropy alloy (HEA) catalysts are prepared with uniform mixing and ultra&#8208;small size of 2 &#177; 0.5 nm by Joule heating method. PtFeCoNiIr/C exhibits efficient performance in AOR ( J peak = 139.8 A g &#8722;1 PGM ), ORR ( E 1/2 = 0.87 V), and HER ( E 10 = 20.3 mV), outperforming the benchmark Pt/C, and no loss in HER performance at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for 200 h. The almost unchanged E 1/2 in the anti&#8208;poisoning test indicates its promising application in real fuel cells powered by ammonia. This work opens up a new path for the development of multi&#8208;functional electrocatalysts and also makes a big leap toward the exploration of cost&#8208;effective device configurations for novel fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Zhang, Zumin Wang, Lei Wang, Lingbo Zong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A NIR&#8208;II&#8208;Emissive Organic Nanomedicine with Biomimetic Engineering for High&#8208;Contrast Targeted Bioimaging and Multiple Phototherapies of Pancreatic Tumors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406483</link>
      <description>Yiwei Wang, Jie Zhang, Yu Wang, Jie Yu, Yijian Gao, Yang&#65533; Yang, Xiliang Li, Hongcheng Wang, Shengliang Li, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400248100

                Abstract Recent advances are achieved in the design and development of efficient organic photosensitizers (PSs), especially with fluorescence imaging navigation in the second near&#8208;infrared (NIR&#8208;II, 1000&#8211;1700 nm) region. However, there are simply a handful of NIR&#8208;II emissive organic PSs with efficient oxygen&#8208;independent capability due to the scarcity of high&#8208;performance NIR&#8208;responsive organic materials and targeted delivery. Herein, a NIR&#8208;II&#8208;emissive organic nanomedicine with biomimetic engineering for high&#8208;performance NIR&#8208;II imaging and targeted multiple phototherapies of pancreatic tumors is reported. An A&#8208;D&#8208;A&#8208;type conjugated small&#8208;molecule TPC is designed and used to prepare water&#8208;dispersive nanoparticles, which demonstrated high efficiency for type I and type II photodynamic performances, good photothermal conversion of 57%, and bright NIR&#8208;II emission with a quantum yield of 9.8% under 808 nm light irradiation. With pancreatic cancer cell membrane camouflage, the biomimetic TPC nanomedicine achieved high&#8208;resolution and targeted bioimaging of whole&#8208;body blood vessels and tumors. Antitumor experiments demonstrated the high efficiency of the biomimetic TPC nanomedicine for pancreatic tumor elimination and good biosafety with 808 nm light irradiation. This work demonstrated a NIR&#8208;II&#8208;emissive versatile nanomedicine with enhanced tumor&#8208;targeting for high&#8208;resolution NIR&#8208;II bioimaging and superior phototheranostics, providing a feasible idea for the evolution of targeted and high&#8208;performance theranostics.</description>
      <author>Yiwei Wang, Jie Zhang, Yu Wang, Jie Yu, Yijian Gao, Yang&#65533; Yang, Xiliang Li, Hongcheng Wang, Shengliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional stress responses in Glaucophyta: Evidence of ethylene and abscisic acid functions in &lt;i&gt;Cyanophora paradoxa&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jeu.13041</link>
      <description>Baptiste Genot, Margaret Grogan, Michael J. Yost, Giuseppe Iacono, Stephen D. Archer, John A. Burns, &#152;The &#156;journal of eukaryotic microbiology/&#152;The &#156;Journal of eukaryotic microbiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400260684

                Abstract Glaucophytes, an enigmatic group of freshwater algae, occupy a pivotal position within the Archaeplastida, providing insights into the early evolutionary history of plastids and their host cells. These algae possess unique plastids, known as cyanelles that retain certain ancestral features, enabling a better understanding of the plastid transition from cyanobacteria. In this study, we investigated the role of ethylene, a potent hormone used by land plants to coordinate stress responses, in the glaucophyte alga Cyanophora paradoxa . We demonstrate that C. paradoxa produces gaseous ethylene when supplied with exogenous 1&#8208;aminocyclopropane&#8208;1&#8208;carboxylic acid (ACC), the ethylene precursor in land plants. In addition, we show that cells produce ethylene natively in response to abiotic stress, and that another plant hormone, abscisic acid (ABA), interferes with ethylene synthesis from exogenously supplied ACC, while positively regulating reactive oxygen species (ROS) accumulation. ROS synthesis also occurred following abiotic stress and ACC treatment, possibly acting as a second messenger in stress responses. A physiological response of C. paradoxa to ACC treatment is growth inhibition. Using transcriptomics, we reveal that ACC treatment induces the upregulation of senescence&#8208;associated proteases, consistent with the observation of growth inhibition. This is the first report of hormone usage in a glaucophyte alga, extending our understanding of hormone&#8208;mediated stress response coordination into the Glaucophyta, with implications for the evolution of signaling modalities across Archaeplastida.</description>
      <author>Baptiste Genot, Margaret Grogan, Michael J. Yost, Giuseppe Iacono, Stephen D. Archer, John A. Burns</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jeu.13041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tectono&#8208;sedimentary history of the upper Cedar Mountain Formation, Central Utah, &lt;scp&gt;USA&lt;/scp&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/sed.13211</link>
      <description>Ryan T. Tucker, Michael R. King, Michael T. Mohr, Ray K. Renaut, James L. Crowley, Jack Fekete, Peter J. Makovicky, Lindsay E. Zanno, Sedimentology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400205274

                ABSTRACT Current investigations into the Albian&#8211;Cenomanian sedimentary record within the Western Interior have identified multiple complex tectono&#8208;sedimentary process&#8211;response systems during the ongoing evolution of North America. One key sedimentary succession, the upper Cedar Mountain Formation (Short Canyon Member and Mussentuchit Member), has historically been linked to various regionally and continentally significant tectonic events, including Sevier fold&#8208;and&#8208;thrust deformation. However, the linkage between the Short Canyon Member and active Sevier tectonism has been unclear due to a lack of high&#8208;precision age constraints. To establish temporal context, this study compares maximum depositional ages from detrital zircons recovered from the Short Canyon Member with that of a modified Bayesian age stratigraphic model (top&#8208;down) to infer that the Short Canyon Member was deposited at ca 100 Ma, penecontemporaneous with rejuvenated thrusting across Utah [Pavant (Pahvant), Iron Springs and Nebo thrusts]. These also indicate a short depositional hiatus with the lowermost portion of the overlying Mussentuchit Member. The Short Canyon Member and Mussentuchit Member preserve markedly different sedimentary successions, with the Short Canyon Member interpreted to be composed of para&#8208;autochthonous orogen&#8211;transverse (across the Sevier highlands) clastics deposited within a series of stacked distributive fluvial fans. Meanwhile, the muddy paralic Mussentuchit Member was a mix of orogen&#8211;transverse (Sevier highlands and Cordilleran Arc) and orogen&#8211;parallel basinal sediments and suspension settling fines within the developing collisional foredeep. However, the informally named last chance sandstone (middle sandstone of the Mussentuchit Member) is identified as an orogen&#8211;transverse sandy debris flow originating from the Sevier highlands, similar to the underlying Short Canyon Member. During this phase of landscape evolution, the Short Canyon Member &#8211; Mussentuchit Member depocentre was a sedimentary conduit system that would fertilize the Western Interior Seaway with ash&#8208;rich sediments. These volcaniclastic contributions, along with penecontemporaneous deposits across the western coastal margin of the Western Interior Seaway, eventually would have lowered oxygen content and resulted in a contributing antecedent trigger for the Cenomanian&#8211;Turonian transition Oceanic Anoxic Event 2.</description>
      <author>Ryan T. Tucker, Michael R. King, Michael T. Mohr, Ray K. Renaut, James L. Crowley, Jack Fekete, Peter J. Makovicky, Lindsay E. Zanno</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/sed.13211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper&#8208;Cysteine Nanostructures for Synergetic Photothermal Therapy and Chemodynamic Therapy of Bacterial Skin Abscesses</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adtp.202400099</link>
      <description>Hadi Bagheri, Aziz Maleki, Mohammad Seyedhamzeh, Zahra Shokri, Ali Kalantari&#8208;Hesari, Raymond J. Turner, Mahshid Kharaziha, Kimia Esmaeilzadeh, Mehdi Golami, Habib Zeighami, Aziz Maleki, Advanced therapeutics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400208341

                Abstract Skin lesions, including skin bacterial abscesses, have become one of the most important health challenges and usually need systemic high&#8208;dose antibiotics. Therefore, it is of particular importance to develop novel approaches for treating this ever&#8208;growing challenge to human health. To address this challenge, herein a copper nanostructure is developed giving combined photothermal and chemodynamic therapies for focal infection treatment. The Cu&#8208;based nanostructures with intrinsic catalytic properties are prepared by D&#8208;L or L cysteine (Cys) as ligand and copper ions. It is shown that the multifunctional copper&#8208;Cys (Cu&#8208;Cys) nanostructures can produce reactive oxygen species (ROS) and they exhibit near infrared (NIR)&#8208;enhanced catalytic activities to improve ROS production for highly efficient eradication of bacteria. Moreover, the results proved O 2 evolution property of the Cu&#8208;Cys nanoparticles (NPs). The nanostructures show shape&#8208;dependent antibacterial activity where DL&#8208;Cu&#8208;Cys NPs show higher bactericidal performance than L&#8208;Cu&#8208;Cys NPs. In vitro results demonstrate that 2.5 and 1.25 &#181;g mL &#8722;1 of DL&#8208;Cu&#8208;Cys NPs is enough to achieve rapid killing of Escherichia coli ( E. coli ) or Staphylococcus aureus (S. aureus) respectively under 808 nm light irradiation in 10 min. This work introduces a unique photoactive nanoagent to efficiently treat subcutaneous abscess by combining NIR light&#8208;triggered photothermal effect and catalytic generation of ROS without using any antibiotic.</description>
      <author>Hadi Bagheri, Aziz Maleki, Mohammad Seyedhamzeh, Zahra Shokri, Ali Kalantari&#8208;Hesari, Raymond J. Turner, Mahshid Kharaziha, Kimia Esmaeilzadeh, Mehdi Golami, Habib Zeighami, Aziz Maleki</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adtp.202400099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epidemiological, clinical, biological and evolutionary profile of scorpion envenomed children under one year to 15 years in the Souss Massa region of Morocco</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.toxicon.2024.107832</link>
      <description>Bouchra Darkaoui, Bouchra Darkaoui, Bouchra Darkaoui, Rachida Cadi, Rachida Cadi, Rachida Cadi, Rachida Cadi, Bouchra Darkaoui, Toxicon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400105915

                Morocco is one of the main countries affected in North African with the scorpion envenomations. Faced with the threat, significant morbidity and a major risk of death especially in children, a detailed identification of scorpionic profile of stings remains important for health authorities at national or even regional level. The current study aims to establish the epidemiological, clinical, biological and evolutionary data of the scorpionism by analyzing 383 cases of scorpion stings in children from three age groups (&lt; 1 year, 1-5 years and &gt; 5 years), admitted at the Regional Hospital Hassan II-Agadir in the Souss Massa region during the period of 9 years and 10 months from January 2013 to October 2022. Our results showed that patients under 1 year of age presented the most severe cases and had the highest mortality rate. However, the clinical signs and symptoms observed illustrated severe damages to vital systems, particularly the cardiovascular, neurological and pulmonary systems, although the signs associated with the latter were present only in cases admitted in grades 2 and 3 for the three age categories studied. Fluctuations in vital constants (temperature and peripheral oxygen saturation, blood pressure, heart rate and respiratory rate), biochemical parameters (ASAT, ALAT, urea and blood creatine, as well as blood sugar) and CBC results revealed major functional disturbances in vital organs, especially in envenomated cases admitted in grade 3. A positive correlation was mentioned between the state of evolution and the various epidemiological parameters, digestive symptoms, as well as signs and symptoms linked to hemodynamic state, general and neurological state. The main interest is to illustrate the seriousness of scorpion envenomations, especially in the high-risk population, for whom an improved therapeutic approach in health centers will undoubtedly be reinforced, and the admission of immunotherapy, as a fundamental part of the treatment, remains important.</description>
      <author>Bouchra Darkaoui, Bouchra Darkaoui, Bouchra Darkaoui, Rachida Cadi, Rachida Cadi, Rachida Cadi, Rachida Cadi, Bouchra Darkaoui</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.toxicon.2024.107832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Choice of reaction progress variable under preferential diffusion effects in turbulent syngas combustion based on detailed chemistry direct numerical simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-64552-0</link>
      <description>Vinzenz Silvester Wehrmann, Nilanjan Chakraborty, Markus Klein, Josef Ha&#223;lberger, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400083587

                The combustion of hydrogen and carbon-monoxide mixtures, so-called syngas, plays an increasingly important role in the safety context of non-fossil energy generation, more specifically in the risk management of incidents in process engineering plants for ammonia synthesis and in nuclear power plants. In order to characterize and simulate syngas/air combustion on industrially relevant scales, subgrid modelling is required, which is often based on a reaction progress variable. To understand the influence of different fuel compositions, turbulence intensities and flame topologies on different possible definitions of reaction progress variable, detailed chemistry direct numerical simulations data of premixed, lean hydrogen/air and syngas/air flames has been considered. A reaction progress variable based on normalized molecular oxygen mass fraction has been found not to capture the augmentation of the normalized burning rate per unit flame surface area in comparison to the corresponding 1D unstretched premixed flame due to preferential diffusion effects. By contrast, reaction progress variables based on other individual species, such as hydrogen, can capture the augmentation of the rate of burning well, but exhibit a pronounced sensitivity to preferential diffusion effects, especially in response to flame curvatures. However, a reaction progress variable based on the linear combination of the main products can accurately represent the temperature evolution of the flame for different mixtures, turbulence intensities and varying local flame topology, while effectively capturing the augmentation of burning rate due to preferential diffusion effects. However, its tendency to assume values larger than 1.0 in the regions of super-adiabatic temperatures poses challenges for future modeling approaches, whereas the reaction progress variable based on hydrogen mass fraction remains bound between 0.0 and 1.0 despite showing deviations in comparison to corresponding variations obtained from the unstretched laminar flame depending on flame curvature variations.</description>
      <author>Vinzenz Silvester Wehrmann, Nilanjan Chakraborty, Markus Klein, Josef Ha&#223;lberger</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-64552-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Novel SCR Catalysts for Denitration of High Concentrated Nitrogen Oxides and Their Reaction Mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070406</link>
      <description>Bo Yu, Xingyu Liu, Shufeng Wu, Heng Yang, Shouyong Zhou, Yang Li, Fang Liu, Catalysts. 14(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400081612

                With the rapid development of industrialization, the emission of nitrogen oxides (NOx) has become a global environmental issue. Uranium is the primary fuel used in nuclear power generation. However, the production of uranium, typically based on the uranyl nitrate method, usually generates large amounts of nitrogen oxides, particularly NO2, with concentrations in the exhaust gas exceeding 10,000 ppm. High concentrations of nitrogen dioxide are also produced during silver electrolysis processing and the treatment of waste electrolyte solutions. Traditional V-W/TiO2 NH3-SCR catalysts typically exhibit high catalytic activity at temperatures ranging from 300 to 400 &#176;C, under conditions of low NOx concentrations and high gas hourly space velocity. However, their performance is not satisfying when reducing high concentrations of NO2. This study aims to optimize the traditional V-W/TiO2 catalysts to enhance their catalytic activity under conditions of high NO2 concentrations (10,000 ppm) and a wide temperature range (200&#8211;400 &#176;C). On the basis of 3 wt% Mo/TiO2, various loadings of V2O5 were selected, and their catalytic activities were tested. Subsequently, the optimal ratios of active component vanadium and additive molybdenum were explored. Simultaneously, doping with WO3 for modification was selected in the V-Mo/TiO2 catalyst, followed by activity testing under the same conditions. The results show that: the NOx conversion rates of all five catalysts increase with temperature at range of 200&#8211;400 &#176;C. Excessive loading of MoO3 decreased the catalytic performance, with 5 wt% being the optimal loading. The addition of WO3 significantly enhanced the low-temperature activity of the catalysts. When the loadings of WO3 and MoO3 were both 3 wt%, the catalyst exhibited the best denitrification performance, achieving a NOx conversion rate of 98.8% at 250 &#176;C. This catalyst demonstrates excellent catalytic activity in reducing very high concentration (10,000 ppm) NO2, at a wider temperature range, expanding the temperature range by 50% compared to conventional SCR catalysts. Characterization techniques including BET, XRD, XPS, H2-TPR, and NH3-TPD were employed to further study the evolution of the catalyst, and the promotional mechanisms are explored. The results revealed that the proportion of chemisorbed oxygen (O&#945;) increased in the WO3-modified catalyst, exhibiting lower V reduction temperatures, which are favorable for low-temperature denitrification activity. NH3-TPD experiments showed that compared to MoOx species, surface WOx species could provide more acidic sites, resulting in stronger surface acidity of the catalyst.</description>
      <author>Bo Yu, Xingyu Liu, Shufeng Wu, Heng Yang, Shouyong Zhou, Yang Li, Fang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14070406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connected FPSOs Thrive on Automation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/0724-0040-jpt</link>
      <description>Blake Wright, Journal of petroleum technology. 76(07)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400193616

                Modern life is connected. Our computers, phones, and watches are all tapped into personal insights, from a daily planner to keep track of meetings and appointments to a health monitor tracking everything from heart rate to blood oxygen level in real time. This connectivity has bled over into many different facets of our lives, including work. Business and industry maintain critical connections allowing for simplification of complex tasks and the monitoring of machines for safety and performance. As the oil field has become more connected, increasing opportunities for automation have been introduced into both new and existing oilfield technologies with aims to achieve new levels of productivity and safety. Whether it is a robotic arm on the drill floor of a rig bringing pipe from the stand to the well or autonomous robots being used for inspections and other operation observations in hard-to-reach or remote places, if the connectivity is there it opens the door to a vast, new toolkit for contractors and operators alike. In 2023, a group of contractors came together to help define the next steps in automation for floating production, storage, and offloading (FPSO) vessels. The FPSO Coalition&#8212;made up of SLB, Rockwell Automation, Sensia, and Cognite&#8212;is a collaboration designed to accelerate the evolution of FPSOs by developing and employing new digital capabilities aimed at improving the reliability, availability, safety, and efficiency of the assets, while lowering the carbon footprint of their offshore operations. FPSOs have been invaluable tools for offshore development around the world for decades. Some older hardware does not have the benefit of being wired for connection or pieces of equipment being Internet of Things (IoT)-ready. As much as the coalition looks to solutions to integrate into new facilities, it also explores the limitations and potential for bringing older yet still viable components into the digital age. Under the venture, SLB was tapped to bring advanced digital solutions, subsurface domain expertise, and complex integration and project management capabilities to scale up efficiencies and lower the carbon footprint of operations across every stage of the FPSO life cycle. Rockwell would provide expertise in control and safety systems for FPSOs, as well as extensive experience in power systems. &#8220;Keeping in mind that the typical operating life of an FPSO can be 20-25-30 years, a lot can change in terms of technology, process conditions, regulatory requirements, etc.,&#8221; said Greg Trostel, global industry development manager for floating production at Rockwell Automation. &#8220;But ultimately, the main goal of automation is to ensure the reliable and safe operation of the vessel&#8212;no loss of containment, no personnel at risk, no environmental incidents. &#8220;Ideally, automation systems can adapt and grow with the changing technology and changing requirements. We depend on the automation systems to keep all the individual process modules connected to, and operating in concert with, the main vessel systems,&#8221; he said. One of the first things tasked to the coalition was a contract awarded to SLB for a multipurpose dynamic simulation solution providing an immersive digital twin environment to dynamically simulate operational processes and their control and automation systems, train personnel, and strengthen safety elements at five newbuild FPSO units to be installed in B&#250;zios Field in the Santos Basin for Petrobras.</description>
      <author>Blake Wright</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/0724-0040-jpt</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
