<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 01:07:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion of the oxygen evolution reaction by introducing MoS2 into CoFe LDH via improved charge transfer and electrocatalytical activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131993</link>
      <description>Yongping Luo, Yuchen Duan, Yu Xie, Yongya Wang, Xianchan Li, Yike Liu, Shunjian Xu, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399036857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongping Luo, Yuchen Duan, Yu Xie, Yongya Wang, Xianchan Li, Yike Liu, Shunjian Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically thin iridium nanosheets for oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01117a</link>
      <description>Gea&#8208;Jae Joo, Hojin Ahn, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Hojin Ahn, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399051421

                2D nanostructures of noble metals hold great potential for developing efficient electrocatalysts due to their high atom efficiency associated with their large specific surface area and abundant active sites. Here,...</description>
      <author>Gea&#8208;Jae Joo, Hojin Ahn, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Hojin Ahn, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01117a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Evolution Reaction on Nickel Oxyhydroxide&#8217;s Surface: Toward a Super Catalyst for Oxygen-Evolution Reaction with Ultralow Overpotentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00888</link>
      <description>Mohammad Khateri, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054326

                This study challenges the conventional understanding of nickel (hydr)oxides as inefficient catalysts for oxygen-evolution reaction (OER) under alkaline conditions. It is demonstrated that nickel oxyhydroxide, characterized by several methods, forms on Ni foam's surface and exhibits OER activity at extremely low potentials. This activity becomes particularly notable at the peak of Ni(II) oxidation to Ni(III), which follows charge accumulation. Remarkably, this mesoporous, super hydrophilic, and high-surface-area catalyst requires a minimal overpotential, as low as 130 mV, with a current density of 200 &#956;A/cm2, and displays a Tafel slope of 77.9 mV/decade in alkaline media (0.10 M KOH). Considering the amount of oxygen produced and the concentration of redox-active Ni ions in the redox peak region, the turnover frequency was calculated to be 1.1 &#215; 10&#8211;3 s&#8211;1 at a potential of 1.36 V. Achieving these parameters at such a remarkably low overpotential holds significant promise. This study also proposes a mechanism for OER at this low overpotential, based on in situ Raman spectroscopic analysis of the Ni(II) to Ni(III) oxidation peak and the OER region. The observed low overpotential for OER can be attributed to the complex interplay between the OER process and the phenomenon of charge accumulation. All these factors result in an exceptionally low overpotential for OER. Our findings hold profound implications for the development of highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts for OER, particularly in water-splitting applications. This research not only expands our understanding of nickel oxyhydroxide as a potential OER catalyst but also opens avenues for future exploration in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Khateri, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Activation through Deep Oxidation of Co4N by Jahn&#8722;Teller&#8208;active Dopants for Improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405839</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054838

                Triggering the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism is crucial for improving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, because it could bypass the scaling relation limitation associated with the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism through the directly formation of oxygen&#8722;oxygen bond. High&#8208;valence transition metal sites are favorable for activating the lattice oxygen, but the deep oxidation of pre&#8208;catalysts suffers from a high thermodynamic barrier. Here, taking advantage of the Jahn&#8722;Teller (J&#8722;T) distortion induced structural instability, we incorporate high&#8208;spin Mn3+ (t2g3eg1) dopant into Co4N. Mn dopants enable a surface structural transformation from Co4N to CoOOH, and finally to CoO2, as observed by various in&#8208;situ spectroscopic investigations. Furthermore, the reconstructed surface on Mn doped Co4N triggers the lattice oxygen activation, as evidenced experimentally by pH&#8208;dependent OER, tetramethylammonium cation adsorption and on&#8208;line electrochemical mass spectrometry measurements of 18O&#8208;labelled catalysts. In general, this work not only offers the introducing J&#8722;T effect approach to regulate the structural transition, but also provides an understanding about the influence of catalyst&#8217;s electronic configuration on determining the reaction route, which may inspire the design of more efficient catalysts with activated lattice oxygen.</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Activation through Deep Oxidation of Co4N by Jahn&#8722;Teller&#8208;active Dopants for Improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405839</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054892

                Triggering the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism is crucial for improving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, because it could bypass the scaling relation limitation associated with the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism through the directly formation of oxygen&#8722;oxygen bond. High&#8208;valence transition metal sites are favorable for activating the lattice oxygen, but the deep oxidation of pre&#8208;catalysts suffers from a high thermodynamic barrier. Here, taking advantage of the Jahn&#8722;Teller (J&#8722;T) distortion induced structural instability, we incorporate high&#8208;spin Mn3+ (t2g3eg1) dopant into Co4N. Mn dopants enable a surface structural transformation from Co4N to CoOOH, and finally to CoO2, as observed by various in&#8208;situ spectroscopic investigations. Furthermore, the reconstructed surface on Mn doped Co4N triggers the lattice oxygen activation, as evidenced experimentally by pH&#8208;dependent OER, tetramethylammonium cation adsorption and on&#8208;line electrochemical mass spectrometry measurements of 18O&#8208;labelled catalysts. In general, this work not only offers the introducing J&#8722;T effect approach to regulate the structural transition, but also provides an understanding about the influence of catalyst&#8217;s electronic configuration on determining the reaction route, which may inspire the design of more efficient catalysts with activated lattice oxygen.</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Bulk and Surface Engineering for Expeditious and Durable Reversible Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cells Air Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403998</link>
      <description>Xi Chen, Na Yu, Yufei Song, Tong Liu, Hengyue Xu, Daqin Guan, Zheng Li, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Jaka Sunarso, Francesco Ciucci, Meng Ni, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399055707

                Abstract Reversible protonic ceramic electrochemical cells (R&#8208;PCECs) offer the potential for high&#8208;efficiency power generation and green hydrogen production at intermediate temperatures. However, the commercial viability of R&#8208;PCECs is hampered by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) within conventional air electrodes operating at reduced temperatures. To address this challenge, we introduce a novel approach based on the simultaneous optimization of bulk&#8208;phase metal&#8208;oxygen bonds and in&#8208;situ formation of a metal oxide nano&#8208;catalyst surface modification. This strategy is designed to expedite the ORR/OER electrocatalytic activity of air electrodes exhibiting triple (O 2&#8722; , H + , e &#8722; ) conductivity. Specifically, our engineered air electrode nanocomposite&#8208;Ba(Co 0.4 Fe 0.4 Zr 0.1 Y 0.1 ) 0.95 Ni 0.05 F 0.1 O 2.9&#8208;&#948; demonstrates remarkable ORR/OER catalytic activity and exceptional durability in R&#8208;PCECs. This is evidenced by significantly improved peak power density from 626 mW cm &#8722;2 to 996 mW cm &#8722;2 and highly stable reversibility over a 100&#8208;hour cycling period. This research offers a rational design strategy to achieve high&#8208;performance R&#8208;PCEC air electrodes with superior operational activity and stability for efficient and sustainable energy conversion and storage. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Xi Chen, Na Yu, Yufei Song, Tong Liu, Hengyue Xu, Daqin Guan, Zheng Li, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Jaka Sunarso, Francesco Ciucci, Meng Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403998</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-4f as an electron-modulation reservoir weakening Fe-O bond to induce iron vacancies in CeFevNi hydroxide for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.205</link>
      <description>Le Gao, Yue Yao, Yun Chen, Jiajun Huang, Yiling Ma, Wenbin Chen, Huan Li, Yu Wang, Lishan Jia, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399067370

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Le Gao, Yue Yao, Yun Chen, Jiajun Huang, Yiling Ma, Wenbin Chen, Huan Li, Yu Wang, Lishan Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of CuO -decorated TiO2 nanoparticles via oxygen-limited pyrolysis of Cu(II) complex for efficient photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113199</link>
      <description>Chao Yang, Xueying Zhao, Yunlong Zhao, Chenchen Ji, Ren&#8208;Jang Wu, Lu Wang, Xueqing Shao, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399068682

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Yang, Xueying Zhao, Yunlong Zhao, Chenchen Ji, Ren&#8208;Jang Wu, Lu Wang, Xueqing Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous&#8208;Spin&#8208;Polarized 2D &#960;&#8208;d Conjugated Frameworks Towards Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401987</link>
      <description>Won Seok Lee, Hiroaki Maeda, Yen&#8208;Ting Kuo, Koki Muraoka, Naoya Fukui, Kenji Takada, Sono Sasaki, Hiroshi Nishihara, Akira Nakayama, Hong&#8208;Kang Tian, Hiroshi Nishihara, Ken Sakaushi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399070034

                Abstract Alternative strategies to design sustainable&#8208;element&#8208;based electrocatalysts enhancing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics are demanded to develop affordable yet high&#8208;performance water&#8208;electrolyzers for green hydrogen production. Here, it is demonstrated that the spontaneous&#8208;spin&#8208;polarized 2D &#960;&#8208;d conjugated framework comprising abundant elements of nickel and iron with a ratio of Ni:Fe = 1:4 with benzenehexathiol linker (BHT) can improve OER kinetics by its unique electronic property. Among the bimetallic NiFe x:y &#8208;BHTs with various ratios with Ni:Fe = x:y, the NiFe 1:4 &#8208;BHT exhibits the highest OER activity. The NiFe 1:4 &#8208;BHT shows a specific current density of 140 A g &#8722;1 at the overpotential of 350 mV. This performance is one of the best activities among state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art non&#8208;precious OER electrocatalysts and even comparable to that of the platinum&#8208;group&#8208;metals of RuO 2 and IrO 2 . The density functional theory calculations uncover that introducing Ni into the homometallic Fe&#8208;BHT (e.g., Ni:Fe = 0:1) can emerge a spontaneous&#8208;spin&#8208;polarized state. Thus, this material can achieve improved OER kinetics with spin&#8208;polarization which previously required external magnetic fields. This work shows that a rational design of 2D &#960;&#8208;d conjugated frameworks can be a powerful strategy to synthesize promising electrocatalysts with abundant elements for a wide spectrum of next&#8208;generation energy devices.</description>
      <author>Won Seok Lee, Hiroaki Maeda, Yen&#8208;Ting Kuo, Koki Muraoka, Naoya Fukui, Kenji Takada, Sono Sasaki, Hiroshi Nishihara, Akira Nakayama, Hong&#8208;Kang Tian, Hiroshi Nishihara, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401987</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Water Oxidation Catalytic Activity of a Mn-Based Magnetic Metal&#8211;Organic Framework: The Role of Proton Conductivity and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01078</link>
      <description>Sayan Saha, Avik De, Soumadip Banerjee, Abhijit K. Das, C. Andr&#233; Ohlin, Raju Mondal, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399071995

                The present work evaluates the water oxidation catalytic activity of a Mn-based metal-organic framework (MOF), which we envisioned to reduce the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) overpotential because of its high electrical conductivity, facilitated by solvent-encapsulated structural features. The presence of Mn centers induces interesting magnetic features in the MOF, which exhibits impressive cryogenic magnetic refrigeration with a &#916;</description>
      <author>Sayan Saha, Avik De, Soumadip Banerjee, Abhijit K. Das, C. Andr&#233; Ohlin, Raju Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Engineering of 3D Self&#8208;Supported Bifunctional Oxygen Electrodes for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries and Fuel Cell Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400347</link>
      <description>Milan Babu Poudel, Mannix P. Balanay, Prakash Chandra Lohani, Karthikeyan Sekar, Dong Jin Yoo, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399077859

                Abstract The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are cornerstone half reactions involved in many renewable energy technologies. High&#8208;density single&#8208;atom catalysts maximize the atom utilization and isolated active sites. Furthermore, introduction of pyri&#8208;N into the carbon&#8208;based nanostructures as an oxygen electrocatalyst creates an abundance of active sites. Here, an innovative strategy is reported based on atomic scale dispersion of Co atoms into the pyri&#8208;N enriched carbon nanotube encapsulated Ni nanoparticles grown on 3D electrospun carbon nanofiber nano&#8208;assemblies. Notably, the Co SA Ni&#8208;NCNT/CNF electrocatalyst exhibited excellent OER and ORR activity in terms of low overpotentials and higher half&#8208;wave potentials. The atomically distributed Co allows the maximum exposure of active sites on the pyri&#8208;N dominated multidimensional carbon skeleton, and synergistic effects with Ni nanoparticles greatly reduced the delocalization around the metal centers and provided an ideal environment for interactions with oxygen intermediates, thus facilitating the 4e &#8722; pathway, as evidenced by the DFT calculations. Moreover, Zn&#8208;air batteries using a Co SA Ni&#8208;NCNT/CNF air cathode exhibited a high&#8208;power density and admirable specific capacity. This studies may provide an avenue for the rational modulation of single&#8208;atom catalysts and cost&#8208;effective, large&#8208;scale synthesis of bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries and anion exchange membrane fuel cell.</description>
      <author>Milan Babu Poudel, Mannix P. Balanay, Prakash Chandra Lohani, Karthikeyan Sekar, Dong Jin Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress on electronic and active site engineering of cobalt&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.573</link>
      <description>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Jia Wang, Tingting Wang, Jian Ju, Yizhong Lu, Wei Chen, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399077872

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting has been identified as a potential candidate for producing clean hydrogen energy with zero carbon emission. However, the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction on the anode side of the water&#8208;splitting device significantly hinders its practical applications. Generally, the efficiency of oxygen evolution processes depends greatly on the availability of cost&#8208;effective catalysts with high activity and selectivity. In recent years, extensive theoretical and experimental studies have demonstrated that cobalt (Co)&#8208;based nanomaterials, especially low&#8208;dimensional Co&#8208;based nanomaterials with a huge specific surface area and abundant unsaturated active sites, have emerged as versatile electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions, and thus, great progress has been made in the rational design and synthesis of Co&#8208;based nanomaterials for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions. Considering the remarkable progress in this area, in this timely review, we highlight the most recent developments in Co&#8208;based nanomaterials relating to their dimensional control, defect regulation (conductivity), electronic structure regulation, and so forth. Furthermore, a brief conclusion about recent progress achieved in oxygen evolution on Co&#8208;based nanomaterials, as well as an outlook on future research challenges, is given.</description>
      <author>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Jia Wang, Tingting Wang, Jian Ju, Yizhong Lu, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoengineered Cobalt Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110946</link>
      <description>R. Venkatachalam, Sunil Mehla, Lathe A. Jones, Suresh K. Bhargava, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399081051

                The alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a bottleneck in green hydrogen production owing to its slow reaction kinetics and low catalytic efficiencies of earth abundant electrocatalysts in the alkaline OER reaction. This study investigates the OER performance of hierarchically porous cobalt electrocatalysts synthesized using the dynamic hydrogen bubble templating (DHBT) method. Characterization studies revealed that electrocatalysts synthesized under optimized conditions using the DHBT method consisted of cobalt nanosheets, and hierarchical porosity with macropores distributed in a honeycomb network and mesopores distributed between cobalt nanosheets. Moreover, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy studies revealed the presence of Co(OH)2 as the predominant surface cobalt species while Raman studies revealed the presence of the cubic Co3O4 phase in the synthesized electrocatalysts. The best performing electrocatalyst required only 360 mV of overpotential to initiate a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, exhibited a Tafel slope of 37 mV dec&#8722;1, and stable OER activity over 24 h. The DHBT method offers a facile, low cost and rapid synthesis approach for preparation for highly efficient cobalt electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>R. Venkatachalam, Sunil Mehla, Lathe A. Jones, Suresh K. Bhargava</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling electroplating sludge into bioengineering-enabled highly stable dual-site Fe-Ni2P@C electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6719-x</link>
      <description>Jiawen Liu, Zhi&#8208;Liang Zuo, Feng Gao, K. Yi, Jai-Ming Lin, Mengye Wang, Lin Zhang, Haibo Feng, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399099589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawen Liu, Zhi&#8208;Liang Zuo, Feng Gao, K. Yi, Jai-Ming Lin, Mengye Wang, Lin Zhang, Haibo Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6719-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Investigations on CoFe2O4@Co3O4 Nano-composite as an Enhanced Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00877-8</link>
      <description>Xihuan Zhang, Abdelhadi El Jaouhari, Chunyue Li, Maimoune Adnane, Wanying Liu, Abderrahman Mellalou, Fouad Ghamouss, Yuanhua Lin, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399105282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xihuan Zhang, Abdelhadi El Jaouhari, Chunyue Li, Maimoune Adnane, Wanying Liu, Abderrahman Mellalou, Fouad Ghamouss, Yuanhua Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00877-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g</link>
      <description>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao, RSC advances. 14(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399110116

                In this study, we explord the catalytic activity of NiCoFe_phosphide nanosheets as highly active and stable catalysts for OER. Electrochemical analysis exhibits a low overpotential of 259 mV in (1 M KOH), achieving a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a low Tafel slope of 50.47 mV dec &#8722;1 .</description>
      <author>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dy2NiRuO6 perovskite with high activity and durability for the oxygen evolution reaction in acidic electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta06788b</link>
      <description>Isabel Rodr&#237;guez-Garc&#237;a, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, Dmitry Galyamin, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Paula Kayser, Mohamed Abdel Salam, J. A. Alonso, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Sergio Rojas, M. Retuerto, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399110197

                Ru mixed oxides may be suitable materials to replace state-of-the-art Ir-based catalysts in the anode of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. To do that, the activity and especially the durability of...</description>
      <author>Isabel Rodr&#237;guez-Garc&#237;a, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, Dmitry Galyamin, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Paula Kayser, Mohamed Abdel Salam, J. A. Alonso, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Sergio Rojas, M. Retuerto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta06788b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow nanocubic CoP-FeP/NC heterostructures for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131838</link>
      <description>Zhongxian Li, Xingzhao Wang, Yunlin Xu, Xiaoran Li, Jianchao Zhang, Lu Yang, Jiabing Luo, Yan Zhou, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399116895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongxian Li, Xingzhao Wang, Yunlin Xu, Xiaoran Li, Jianchao Zhang, Lu Yang, Jiabing Luo, Yan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping CeO2/Ce(OH)CO3/CF nanohybrids with Gd for structural tuning and oxygen evolution reaction performance enhancing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.359</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Liao, Xi Lu, Xiaojie Jin, Hongyan Chen, Xinyu Huang, Yongxiu Li, Jing Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399116939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Liao, Xi Lu, Xiaojie Jin, Hongyan Chen, Xinyu Huang, Yongxiu Li, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120030

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of Electron Transfer Behavior on Fe2p-Co2p/Npc Oxygen Electrocatalyst by Lattice Cation Substitution Engineering and Charge Transport Network Design for Rechargeable Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4847202</link>
      <description>Long Hao, Yu Chen, Chunming Liu, Junhua You, Rui Guo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120056

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Long Hao, Yu Chen, Chunming Liu, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4847202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120097

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120100

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrative Active Sites of Cathode for Electron-Oxygen-Proton Coupling To Favor H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production in a Photoelectrochemical System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c01601</link>
      <description>Shan Li, Lei Chen, Jian Wang, Li Tian, Dawei Li, Zhi Yang, Xin Xiao, Chiheng Chu, Baoliang Chen, Environmental science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120400

                The oxygen reduction process generating H2O2 in the photoelectrochemical (PEC) system is milder and environmentally friendly compared with the traditional anthraquinone process but still lacks the efficient electron-oxygen-proton coupling interfaces to improve H2O2 production efficiency. Here, we propose an integrated active site strategy, that is, designing a hydrophobic C&#8211;B&#8211;N interface to refine the dearth of electron, oxygen, and proton balance. Computational calculation results show a lower energy barrier for H2O2 production due to synergistic and coupling effects of boron sites for O2 adsorption, nitrogen sites for H+ binding, and the carbon structure for electron transfer, demonstrating theoretically the feasibility of the strategy. Furthermore, we construct a hydrophobic boron- and nitrogen-doped carbon black gas diffusion cathode (BN-CB-PTFE) with graphite carbon dots decorated on a BiVO4 photoanode (BVO/g-CDs) for H2O2 production. Remarkably, this approach achieves a record H2O2 production rate (9.24 &#956;mol min&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2) at the PEC cathode. The BN-CB-PTFE cathode exhibits an outstanding Faraday efficiency for H2O2 production of &#8764;100%. The newly formed h-BN integrative active site can not only adsorb more O2 but also significantly improve the electron and proton transfer. Unexpectedly, coupling BVO/g-CDs with the BN-CB-PTFE gas diffusion cathode also achieves a record H2O2 production rate (6.60 &#956;mol min&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2) at the PEC photoanode. This study opens new insight into integrative active sites for electron-O2-proton coupling in a PEC H2O2 production system that may be meaningful for environment and energy applications.</description>
      <author>Shan Li, Lei Chen, Jian Wang, Li Tian, Dawei Li, Zhi Yang, Xin Xiao, Chiheng Chu, Baoliang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c01601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Pot Template-Free Synthesis of Mesoporous ZnCo2O4 Microbubbles for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11170-1</link>
      <description>Yonggang Zheng, Jian Wu, Zhizhong Guo, Jiayi Qin, Jin&#8208;Ming Wu, Wei Wen, Journal of electronic materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120763

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yonggang Zheng, Jian Wu, Zhizhong Guo, Jiayi Qin, Jin&#8208;Ming Wu, Wei Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11170-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoporous Fe and Co Dually Doped Carbon Nanotube-Based Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Efficient Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02088</link>
      <description>Chaoyang Liu, Shang Wu, Shu Tian, Jincai Yang, Jiankun Li, Xin Wang, Lihong Wang, Chen Chen, Ping Zhang, Quanlu Yang, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoyang Liu, Shang Wu, Shu Tian, Jincai Yang, Jiankun Li, Xin Wang, Lihong Wang, Chen Chen, Ping Zhang, Quanlu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable layered Mn oxides for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01144-1</link>
      <description>E Liu, Drew Higgins, Nature Catalysis. 7(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399121605

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E Liu, Drew Higgins</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01144-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extraordinary Structural Reconstruction of Nanolaminated Ta&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;FeC MAX Phase for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401022</link>
      <description>Shaoping Zhu, Youbing Li, Minghui Yang, Huiyan Xu, Lijuan Cheng, Fei Fang, Qing Huang, Binwu Ying, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399125273

                Abstract Renewable energy technologies, such as water splitting, heavily depend on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Nanolaminated ternary compounds, referred to as MAX phases, show great promise for creating efficient electrocatalysts for OER. However, their limited intrinsic oxidative resistance hinders the utilization of conductivity in M n+1 X n layers, leading to reduced activity. In this study, a method is proposed to improve the poor inoxidizability of MAX phases by carefully adjusting the elemental composition between M n+1 X n layers and single&#8208;atom&#8208;thick A layers. The resulting Ta 2 FeC catalyst demonstrates superior performance compared to conventional Fe/C&#8208;based catalysts with a remarkable record&#8208;low overpotential of 247 mV (@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and sustained activity for over 240 h. Notably, during OER processing, the single&#8208;atom&#8208;thick Fe layer undergoes self&#8208;reconstruction and enrichment from the interior of the Ta 2 FeC MAX phase toward its surface, forming a Ta 2 FeC@Ta 2 C@FeOOH heterostructure. Through density functional theory (DFT) calculations, this study has found that the incorporation of Ta 2 FeC@Ta 2 C not only enhances the conductivity of FeOOH but also reduces the covalency of Fe&#9472;O bonds, thus alleviating the oxidation of Fe 3+ and O 2&#8722; . This implies that the Ta 2 FeC@Ta 2 C@FeOOH heterostructure experiences less lattice oxygen loss during the OER process compared to pure FeOOH, leading to significantly improved stability. These results highlight promising avenues for further exploration of MAX phases by strategically engineering M&#8208; and A&#8208;site engineering through multi&#8208;metal substitution, to develop M 2 AX@M 2 X@AOOH&#8208;based catalysts for oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Shaoping Zhu, Youbing Li, Minghui Yang, Huiyan Xu, Lijuan Cheng, Fei Fang, Qing Huang, Binwu Ying</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst Doped with Phosphorus for Improved Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01861</link>
      <description>Shu&#8208;Fang Li, Xin Li, Dong Yan, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399126209

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shu&#8208;Fang Li, Xin Li, Dong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and characterization of bifunctional 1T-2H MoS2-Sv/CuS catalyst for electrocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128176</link>
      <description>Dan Li, Shumin Fan, Jian Li, Weiguo Li, Yanli Zhuang, Y.B. Li, Lianwei Shan, Limin Dong, Jie Yao, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399133444

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Li, Shumin Fan, Jian Li, Weiguo Li, Yanli Zhuang, Y.B. Li, Lianwei Shan, Limin Dong, Jie Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanospike Nickel-Iron Oxalate as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-2rpfc</link>
      <description>Krishani Teeluck, Gia M. Carignan, Mehmet Do&#287;an, Kate M. Waldie, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399134127

                Obtaining hydrogen as a renewable fuel through water splitting is severely hindered by the energy-intensive oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Transition metal oxides based on low-cost and earth-abundant elements have been shown to provide high OER rivaling that of commercial IrO2, with nickel iron oxide/oxyhydroxide systems exhibiting some of the lowest reported overpotentials. Here, we report a nickel-iron oxalate material with a nanospike morphology synthesized via a simple and novel hydrothermal method, in which oxalate is generated in situ during material preparation under mild conditions. The as-synthesized nanostructured material displays high catalytic activity for OER, requiring a low overpotential of only 284 mV at a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2, lower than that of its amorphous counterpart and commercial IrO2 (326 and 308 mV, respectively). This material also exhibits excellent long-term stability with retention of the nanospike morphology after several hours under OER conditions.</description>
      <author>Krishani Teeluck, Gia M. Carignan, Mehmet Do&#287;an, Kate M. Waldie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-2rpfc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Multifunctional Electrocatalysts for ORR/OER/HER/HOR: Janus Makes Difference</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404000</link>
      <description>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399140360

                Abstract Multifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) have broad application prospects; However, realization of such kinds of materials remain difficulties because it requires the materials to have not only unique electronic properties, but multiple active centers to deal with different reactions. Here, employing density functional theory (DFT) computations, it is demonstrated that by decorating the Janus&#8208;type 2D transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) of TaSSe with the single atoms, the materials can achieve multifunctionality to catalyze the ORR/OER/HER/HOR. Out of sixteen catalytic systems, Pt&#8208;V S (i.e., Pt atom embedded in the sulfur vacancy), Pd&#8208;V Se , and Pt&#8208;V Se @TaSSe are promising multifunctional catalysts with superior stability. Among them, the Pt&#8208;V S @TaSSe catalyst exhibits the highest activity with theoretical overpotentials &#951; ORR = 0.40 V, &#951; OER = 0.39 V, and &#951; HER/HOR = 0.07 V, respectively, better than the traditional Pt (111), IrO 2 (110). The interplays between the catalyst and the reaction intermediate over the course of the reaction are then systematically investigated. Generally, this study presents a viable approach for the design and development of advanced multifunctional electrocatalysts. It enriches the application of Janus, a new 2D material, in electrochemical energy storage and conversion technology.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Stainless Steel Oxide Layers through Potential Cycling&#9472;AEM Water Electrolysis Free of Critical Raw Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01107</link>
      <description>T.B. Ferriday, Suhas Nuggehalli Sampathkumar, Mounir Mensi, Hugh Middleton, Jan Van herle, Mohan Lal Kolhe, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141185

                Anion exchange membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWEs) have an intrinsic advantage over acidic proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers through their ability to use inexpensive, stable materials such as stainless steel (SS) to catalyze the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As such, the study of active oxide layers on SS has garnered great interest. Potential cycling is a means to create such active oxide layers in situ as they are readily formed in alkaline solutions when exposed to elevated potentials. Cycling conditions in the literature are rife with unexplained variations, and a complete account of how these variations affect the activity and constitution of SS oxide layers remains unreported, along with their influence on AEMWE performance. In this paper, we seek to fill this gap in the literature by strategically cycling SS felt (SSF) electrodes under different scan rates and ranges. The SSF anodes were rapidly activated within the first 50 cycles, as shown by the 10-fold decline in charge transfer resistance, and the subsequent 1000 cycles tuned the metal oxide surface composition. Cycling the Ni redox couple (RC) increases Ni content, which is further enhanced by lowering the cycling rate, while cycling the Fe RC increases Cr content. Fair OER activity was uncovered through cycling the Ni RC, while Fe cycling produced SSF electrodes active toward both the OER and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This indicates that inert SSF electrodes can be activated to become efficient OER and HER electrodes. To this effect, a single-cell AEMWE without any traditional catalyst or ionomer generated 1.0 A cm&#8211;2 at 1.94 V &#177; 13.3 mV with an SSF anode, showing a fair performance for a cell free of critical raw materials.</description>
      <author>T.B. Ferriday, Suhas Nuggehalli Sampathkumar, Mounir Mensi, Hugh Middleton, Jan Van herle, Mohan Lal Kolhe</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141696

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in Joule&#8208;heating synthesis of functional nanomaterials for photo and electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/phmt.14</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Li, Laiyu Luo, Siyu Wang, Haojie Song, Baojiang Jiang, PhotoMat . None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399150132

                Abstract Background Catalyst synthesis plays a crucial role in advancing photo and electrocatalysis technologies for sustainable development. However, the traditional thermal radiation heating method suffers from the disadvantages of high energy consumption, low heat transfer efficiency, slow heating speed and long heating time, which leads to the inefficiency and cost increases in catalyst preparation. Aims The Joule&#8208;heating ultrafast synthesis method with rapid heating/quenching and shorter heating time has attracted much attention. Despite its potential, there is a lack of comprehensive reviews specifically addressing the synthesis of advanced photo and electrocatalysts via Joule&#8208;heating. Therefore, this review aims to help people quickly understand the advantages of Joule&#8208;heating in the synthesis of photo and electrocatalysts. Discussion Herein, we firstly introduce the principles and devices of Joule&#8208;heating, and then we discuss breakthroughs in defect modulation, heterojunction construction, single&#8208;atom catalysts, bimetallic alloy catalysts, high&#8208;entropy alloy catalysts and metastable catalysts achieved through Joule&#8208;heating technology. The diverse applications of these catalysts include hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, oxygen reduction reactions, carbon dioxide reduction reactions, nitrogen reduction reaction and degradation of organic pollutants. Furthermore, this review provides a forward&#8208;looking perspective on future directions for employing Joule&#8208;heating methods in the field of photo and electrocatalysis research. Conclusion This review highlights the pivotal role played by Joule&#8208;heating techniques in advancing nanomaterial synthesis as well as developing sustainable high&#8208;performance catalyst systems.</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Li, Laiyu Luo, Siyu Wang, Haojie Song, Baojiang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/phmt.14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D/2D interfacial coupling of NiFe-LDH and Ti3C2T for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.367</link>
      <description>A. Waheed, Sadaf Siddique, Mutawara Mahmood Baig, Muhammad Taqi Mehran, Muhammad Aksam Iftikhar, Jamil Ahmad, Hassan A. Arafat, Faisal Shahzad, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399150460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Waheed, Sadaf Siddique, Mutawara Mahmood Baig, Muhammad Taqi Mehran, Muhammad Aksam Iftikhar, Jamil Ahmad, Hassan A. Arafat, Faisal Shahzad</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excellent ethanol oxidation and oxygen evolution reaction from ultrafine nickel hydroxide nanorods stabilized at room temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2024.117445</link>
      <description>Shweta Kumari, . Sunaina, Sapna Devi, Menaka Jha, Materials science and engineering. B, Solid-state materials for advanced technology/Materials science &amp; engineering. B, Solid-state materials for advanced technology. 306(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399150720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shweta Kumari, . Sunaina, Sapna Devi, Menaka Jha</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2024.117445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of Flower-Like Co 2 P/Wo 3-X /Cc Catalysts with Oxygen Vacancies For Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4848439</link>
      <description>Hui Guo, Dongxv Li, Ping Lu, Huimin Jiang, Mohammed A. Amin, Jianjian Lin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399157500

                Constructing an efficient and low-cost oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalyst is critical for improving the performance of electrolysis in alkaline water. In this study, a self-supported electrocatalyst of flower-like cobalt phosphide and tungsten oxide (Co2P/WO3-x/CC) was prepared on carbon cloth CC surface by hydrothermal reaction with solution immersion etching and phosphorization annealing under H2/Ar atmosphere. This strategy can generate oxygen vacancies (OV), improving the speed of charge transfer between cobalt phosphide (Co2P) and tungsten oxide (WO3-x) components. The catalyst greatly increases the electrochemical active surface area, which is beneficial for efficient oxygen evolution. Electrochemical testing studies show that in 1.0 M KOH solution, Co2P-WO3-x/CC catalyst exhibits good OER activity, with a low overpotential of 254 mV at 10 mA cm-2, a small Tafel slope of 58.32 mV dec-1. The synergistic effect of oxygen vacancies and Co2P with WO3-x can regulate electronic structures, expose more active sites, and cooperatively enhancing the OER activity. This study provides a workable strategy for preparing efficient non-noble metal OER electrocatalysts on engineered interfaces and OV.</description>
      <author>Hui Guo, Dongxv Li, Ping Lu, Huimin Jiang, Mohammed A. Amin, Jianjian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4848439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon quantum dots decorated NiCo layered double hydroxide for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction and supercapacitor application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-024-12793-0</link>
      <description>D. A. Wadkar, Kiran Jadhav, S. D. Jituri, S.H. Mujawar, Journal of materials science. Materials in electronics. 35(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399169730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>D. A. Wadkar, Kiran Jadhav, S. D. Jituri, S.H. Mujawar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-024-12793-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bird Nest-Like Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/CoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosphere Heterojunctions with Amorphous/Crystalline Structure for Enhanced Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01984</link>
      <description>Yingxin Liu, Hao Yan, Mingyang Cai, Wenliang Song, Ziling Huang, Xianggang Huang, Xin Wang, Hongwei Gu, Xueqin Cao, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399169854

                Developing efficient electrocatalysts is very important for water electrolysis technology to deal with the energy crisis. The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in the semireaction of electrolytic water is a crucial step. Herein, we report a facial strategy to fabricate the bird nest-like Fe3O4/CoOx (BN-Fe3O4/CoOx) nanosphere heterojunctions with amorphous/crystalline (a/c) structure through cation-exchange and subsequent calcination treatment in a reducing Ar/H2 atmosphere. Owing to its unique structure and the electron state near the heterogeneous interface, the BN-Fe3O4/CoOx nanosphere exhibits a very competitive overpotential of 286 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 for OER with a low Tafel slope of 55.51 mV dec&#8211;1 in 1.0 M KOH, and long-term durability for more than 20 h. This work may provide an idea and a convenient method for the preparation of a/c-heterostructure electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yingxin Liu, Hao Yan, Mingyang Cai, Wenliang Song, Ziling Huang, Xianggang Huang, Xin Wang, Hongwei Gu, Xueqin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precisely Constructing Orbital&#8208;Coupled Fe&#8208;Co Dual&#8208;atom Sites for High&#8208;Energy&#8208;Efficiency Zn&#8208;Air/Iodide Hybrid Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405533</link>
      <description>Jingyuan Qiao, Yurong You, Lingqiao Kong, Wei Feng, H.-T. Zhang, Haibin Huang, Caifang Li, Wei He, ZhengMing Sun, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399172904

                Abstract Rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) are promising for energy storage and conversion. However, the high charging voltage and low energy efficiency hinder their commercialization. Herein, we address these challenges by employing precisely constructed multifunctional Fe&#8208;Co diatomic site catalyst (FeCo&#8208;DACs) and integrating iodide/iodate redox into ZABs to create Zinc&#8208;air/iodide hybrid batteries (ZAIHBs) with highly efficient multifunctional catalyst. The strong coupling between the 3d orbitals of Fe and Co weakens the excessively strong binding strength between active sites and intermediates, enhancing the catalytic activities for oxygen reduction/evolution reaction and iodide/iodate redox. Consequently, FeCo&#8208;DACs exhibits outstanding bifunctional oxygen catalytic activity with a small potential gap (&#916;E = 0.66 V) and outstanding stability. Moreover, an outstanding catalytic performance towards iodide/iodate redox is obtained. Therefore, FeCo&#8208;DAC&#8208;based ZAIHBs exhibit high energy efficiency of up to 75% at 10 mA cm &#8208;2 and excellent cycling stability (72% after 500 hours). This research offers critical insights into the rational design of DACs, and paves the way for high&#8208;energy efficiency energy storage devices. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Jingyuan Qiao, Yurong You, Lingqiao Kong, Wei Feng, H.-T. Zhang, Haibin Huang, Caifang Li, Wei He, ZhengMing Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolation and Crystallographic Characterization of an Octavalent Co2O2 Diamond Core</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mctcl</link>
      <description>Joseph E. Schneider, Shilin Zeng, Sophie W. Anferov, Alexander S. Filatov, John S. Anderson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399176742

                High-valent cobalt-oxides play a pivotal role in alternative energy technology as catalysts for water splitting and as cath-odes in lithium-ion batteries. Despite this importance, the properties governing the stability of high-valent cobalt-oxides, and specifically possible oxygen evolution pathways, are not clear. One root of this limited understanding is the scarcity of high-valent, Co(IV)-containing model complexes; there are no reports of stable, well-defined complexes with multiple Co(IV) centers. Here, an oxidatively robust fluorinated ligand scaffold enables the isolation and crystallographic charac-terization of a Co(IV)2-bis-&#956;-oxo complex. This complex is remarkably stable, in stark contrast with previously reported Co(IV)2 species which are highly reactive, which demonstrates that oxy-Co(IV)2 species are not necessarily unstable with respect to oxygen evolution. This example underscores a new design strategy for highly oxidizing transition metal frag-ments and provides detailed data on a previously inaccessible chemical unit of relevance to O&#8211;O bond formation and oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Joseph E. Schneider, Shilin Zeng, Sophie W. Anferov, Alexander S. Filatov, John S. Anderson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mctcl</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalysis of Bismuth Doped Zinc Stannate Towards OER and HER Through Oxygen Vacancies: p-block Metal Ion Doping Empowering d-block</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00552j</link>
      <description>Reshmi Thekke Parayil, Santosh Kumar Gupta, K. B. Garg, Sandhaya Jangra, Soumen Samanta, K. Sudarshan, M. Mohapatra, Tharamani C. Nagaiah, Sustainable energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399184880

                In order to meet the energy requirements of the future society, hydrogen production by electrocatalytic water splitting is considered as one of the efficient methods to produce pure hydrogen on...</description>
      <author>Reshmi Thekke Parayil, Santosh Kumar Gupta, K. B. Garg, Sandhaya Jangra, Soumen Samanta, K. Sudarshan, M. Mohapatra, Tharamani C. Nagaiah</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00552j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;Organic-Framework-Derived Nitrogen-Doped Carbon-Matrix-Encapsulating Co0.5Ni0.5 Alloy as a Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17112629</link>
      <description>Jinglin Liu, Lina Han, Song Xiao, Anqi Zhu, Yingjie Zhang, Xiaoyuan Zeng, Peng Dong, Materials. 17(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399185590

                The development of low-cost, high-performance oxygen electrocatalysts is of great significance for energy conversion and storage. As a potential substitute for precious metal electrocatalysts, the construction of efficient and cost-effective oxygen electrocatalysts is conducive to promoting the widespread application of zinc&#8211;air batteries. Herein, CoxNiyMOF nanoparticles encapsulated within a carbon matrix were synthesized and employed as cathode catalysts in zinc&#8211;air batteries. Co0.5Ni0.5MOF exhibits superior oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance and durability. The zinc&#8211;air battery assembled with Co0.5Ni0.5MOF as the air cathode exhibits a maximum power density of 138.6 mW&#183;cm&#8722;2. These improvements are mainly attributed to the optimized metal composition of the cobalt&#8211;nickel alloy, which increases the specific surface area of the material and optimizes its pore structure. Significantly, the optimization of the electronic structure and active sites within the material has led to amplified ORR/OER activity and better zinc&#8211;air battery performance. This study underscores the immense promise of Co0.5Ni0.5MOF catalysts as feasible substitutes for commercial Pt/C catalysts in zinc&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Jinglin Liu, Lina Han, Song Xiao, Anqi Zhu, Yingjie Zhang, Xiaoyuan Zeng, Peng Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17112629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir single atoms on NiFeZn-LDH matrix for exceptional oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6749-4</link>
      <description>Muhammad Israr, Muhammad Humayun, Jiaqi Zhang, Khadim Shah, Xin Tan, Chen Chen, Yadong Li, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399194464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Israr, Muhammad Humayun, Jiaqi Zhang, Khadim Shah, Xin Tan, Chen Chen, Yadong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6749-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical mesoporous N-doped carbon as efficient ORR/OER bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00637b</link>
      <description>Li Ping, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Yanhong Xiang, Meiqi Li, Yongjie Zhao, Jian-Min Dou, Suna Wang, Yun&#8208;Wu Li, Huiyan Ma, Liqiang Xu, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399194950

                The construction of efficient oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER) bifunctional electrocatalysts is crucial for promising rechargeable Zinc-air batteries. Hierarchical mesoporous N doped carbon structures (HMNC) with superior catalytic...</description>
      <author>Li Ping, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Yanhong Xiang, Meiqi Li, Yongjie Zhao, Jian-Min Dou, Suna Wang, Yun&#8208;Wu Li, Huiyan Ma, Liqiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00637b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrangea shaped bimetallic NiRu MOFs directly catalyzing highly-efficient alkaline freshwater/seawater overall splitting based on electronic structure and oxygen vacancy modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132025</link>
      <description>Junfeng Qin, Shijie Hu, Xiaohua Zhang, Maochun Hong, Cuicui Du, Jinhua Chen, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399201488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfeng Qin, Shijie Hu, Xiaohua Zhang, Maochun Hong, Cuicui Du, Jinhua Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrochemical efficiency of the open porous sandrose structured electrocatalyst for sustainable hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.422</link>
      <description>Chandrasekaran Pitchai, Mahalakshmi Vedanarayanan, Chih&#8208;Ming Chen, Mathur Gopalakrishnan Sethuraman, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399205918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chandrasekaran Pitchai, Mahalakshmi Vedanarayanan, Chih&#8208;Ming Chen, Mathur Gopalakrishnan Sethuraman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFeCo Alloy Nanoparticles Composited with Phosphorus-doped Vacancies-abundant Carbon Substrates as Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175050</link>
      <description>Hu-Jun Qian, Zi&#8208;Jie Long, Shuqin Huang, Zhihao Zhang, Jintang Li, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399207582

                Transition metal alloy nanoparticles are cost-effective electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions. Preparing alloy catalysts with flexible controllability, high activity, and long-term stability is a challenge. By adjusting the proportion of metal atoms and engineering vacancies through their composite with a carbon substrate, we can enhance electron transfer and modulate the adsorption capacity of reaction intermediates. Herein, we synthesized a hybrid catalyst using Prussian blue analogs (PBAs) as the precursor, doped with Fe and Ni atoms, and subjected them to a defective engineering and phosphatization process. As an efficient alkaline OER electrocatalyst, the formation of the alloy increases the number of active sites, while the defect-rich phosphorus-doped carbon substrate improves internal electron transfer and mass transfer channels. The synthesized NiFeCoPC-1.5 electrocatalyst exhibits excellent catalytic activity with an overpotential of 211 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 59 mV dec&#8722;1, and demonstrates good stability up to 1000 CV cycles. This work will expand the application of alloy nanoparticles in oxygen evolution electrodes.</description>
      <author>Hu-Jun Qian, Zi&#8208;Jie Long, Shuqin Huang, Zhihao Zhang, Jintang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-doped cerium-iron phosphide as an ultra-efficient Ru-free electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175051</link>
      <description>Sivalingam Gopi, Kyusik Yun, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399208937

                Designing nonprecious metal-based heteroatom-doped electrocatalysts with low overpotential for efficient hydrogen production via oxygen evolution reactions presents significant challenges. We fabricated and carbonized an N-doped bimetallic phosphide (CeFeP) in this study. Scanning electron microscopy and transmission electron microscopy analyses revealed the formation of a uniform spherical nanoparticle morphology, while structural changes were evidenced in the carbonization step at temperatures of 300 and 700 &#8451; by XRD analysis. The synthesized materials were then coated onto carbon paper electrodes in a basic medium, and their performance in the oxygen evolution reaction was evaluated. The results show that the N-doped bimetallic phosphide material carbonized at 700 &#8451; has enhanced catalytic activity, as indicated by its low overpotential of 155 mV and Tafel slope of 57 mV/dec, respectively, for a standard current density of 10 mA/cm2. The catalytic performance of the N-doped CeFeP sample was significantly higher than that of undoped CeFeP and the single metal phosphide, thereby indicating it has significant potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Sivalingam Gopi, Kyusik Yun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloride&#8208; and Hydrosulfide&#8208;Bound 2Fe Complexes as Models of the Oxygen&#8208;Stable State of [FeFe] Hydrogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408142</link>
      <description>Ming-Hsi Chiang, Yu&#8208;Chiao Liu, Kai&#8208;Ti Chu, Hongru Wang, Gene&#8208;Hsiang Lee, Mei&#8208;Chun Tseng, C.C. Wang, Yih&#8208;Chern Horng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399210237

                [FeFe] hydrogenases demonstrate remarkable catalytic efficiency in hydrogen evolution and oxidation processes. However, susceptibility of enzymes to oxygen&#8208;induced degradation impedes their practical deployment in hydrogen&#8208;production devices and fuel cells. Recent investigations into the oxygen&#8208;stable (Hinact) state of the H&#8208;cluster revealed its inherent capacity to resist oxygen degradation. Herein, we present findings on Cl&#8208;/SH&#8208;bound [2Fe&#8208;2S] complexes, bearing relevance to the oxygen&#8208;stable state within a biological context. A characteristic attribute of these complexes is the terminal Cl&#8722;/SH&#8722; ligation to the iron bearing the CO bridge. Structural analysis of the t&#8208;Cl demonstrates a striking resemblance to the Hinact state of DdHydAB and CbA5H. The t&#8208;Cl/t&#8208;SH exhibit reversible oxidation, with both redox species, electronically, being the first biomimetic analogs to the Htrans and Hinact states. These complexes exhibit notable resistance against oxygen&#8208;induced decomposition, supporting the potential oxygen&#8208;resistant nature of the Htrans and Hinact states. The swift reductive release of the Cl&#8208;/SH&#8208; demonstrates its labile and kinetically controlled binding. The findings garnered from these investigations offer valuable insights into properties of the enzymatic O2&#8208;stable state, and key factors governing deactivation and reactivation conversion. This work contributes to advancement of bio&#8208;inspired molecular catalysts and integration of enzymes and artificial catalysts into H2&#8208;evolution devices and fuel&#8208;cell applications.</description>
      <author>Ming-Hsi Chiang, Yu&#8208;Chiao Liu, Kai&#8208;Ti Chu, Hongru Wang, Gene&#8208;Hsiang Lee, Mei&#8208;Chun Tseng, C.C. Wang, Yih&#8208;Chern Horng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Ni-doped Co3O4 oxygen evolution catalysts for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.365</link>
      <description>Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, N. Krishna Chandar, Nisha Devi, Hai Lin, Cheng-Che Huang, Xin-Yu Jiang, Yuan-Yao Li, G. Arthanareeswaran, Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, Neeraj K. Jaiswal, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399212076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, N. Krishna Chandar, Nisha Devi, Hai Lin, Cheng-Che Huang, Xin-Yu Jiang, Yuan-Yao Li, G. Arthanareeswaran, Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, Neeraj K. Jaiswal, Yong&#8208;Song Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional MoC/NiC@N-doped reduced graphene oxide nano electrocatalyst for simultaneous production of hydrogen and oxygen through efficient overall electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2024.100489</link>
      <description>Abdullah Al Mahmud, Mohammad R. Thalji, Ganesh Dhakal, Yuvaraj Haldorai, Woo Kyoung Kim, Jae&#8208;Jin Shim, Materials today nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399219030

                Recently, hydrogen has been an important green energy source for fuel cell-operated vehicles, buildings, power plants, and portable electronics. This study focuses on developing inexpensive, non-noble bifunctional transition metal nano electrocatalysts for producing green hydrogen and industrially important oxygen simultaneously by water splitting. A nanocomposite consisting of two single-metal carbides, MoC and NiC, and nitrogen-doped reduced graphene oxide (N-rGO) was prepared for the first time as an electrocatalyst and used in water splitting. The overpotential of MoC/NiC@N-doped rGO was 185 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 298 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The Tafel slopes for HER and OER were relatively modest, 78 and 80 mV dec&#8722;1, respectively. The nanocomposite had a 6.8% lower overpotential than RuO2 for OER. A symmetric two-electrode setup was prepared to split water through HER/OER to produce hydrogen and water simultaneously. In this apparatus, the nanocomposite electrocatalyst exhibited a high performance, raising the current density to 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and lowering the cell voltage by 2.5% below the standard material. The nanocomposite showed excellent stability for 55 h for overall water splitting. The highly performing MoC/NiC@N-doped rGO nanocomposite may open the horizon for developing efficient, inexpensive, non-noble bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Abdullah Al Mahmud, Mohammad R. Thalji, Ganesh Dhakal, Yuvaraj Haldorai, Woo Kyoung Kim, Jae&#8208;Jin Shim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2024.100489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rational design of bifunctional MOF-ZnFe2O4 hollow sphere-based nanocomposites for ultra-efficient electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction and high-performance symmetric supercapacitor electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175048</link>
      <description>Dong&#8208;Eun Lee, Mohtaram Danish, Ahmad Husain, Wan&#8208;Kuen Jo, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399220781

                Supercapacitors have emerged as versatile energy storage devices, valued for their rapid charge-discharge capabilities and long cycle life. Concurrently, efficient electrocatalysts are essential for promoting the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in sustainable energy applications. Inevitably, this study explores the integration of a Cobalt-Nickel (Co/Ni) based metal-organic framework [CoNi((&#956;3-tp)2(&#956;2-py)2 or CNTP] with ZnFe2O4 hollow spheres (ZHS) to create innovative CNTP/ZHS nanocomposites tailored for supercapacitor and electrocatalytic OER applications. Different weight percentages of CNTP/ZHS nanocomposites were synthesized through a facile and scalable method, and their electrochemical performance was rigorously assessed. Electrochemical characterization revealed that a 40 weight percentage CNTP/ZHS (40-CNTP/ZHS) electrode demonstrated a very high specific capacitance of 1519.2 Fg-1 at 1 Ag-1 and retained 92.6% of its specific capacitance after 10000 cycles. Moreover, it delivered remarkably high specific capacitance (447.2 Fg-1) and energy density (62.1 WhKg-1) along with outstanding cyclic stability (97.5% after 5000 galvanostatic charge-discharge cycles). It also exhibited excellent OER activity, with a very low overpotential (207 mV to attain a current density of 10 mAcm-2), a small Tafel slope (66.5 mVdec-1), and high stability over 2000 cyclic voltammetry cycles. These characteristics underscore the significant potential of renewable energy technologies, particularly for water electrolysis and sustainable energy conversion.1</description>
      <author>Dong&#8208;Eun Lee, Mohtaram Danish, Ahmad Husain, Wan&#8208;Kuen Jo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of CuO/MnAl2O4 nanocomposite as electrocatalysts for robust oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112121</link>
      <description>Muhammad Sadiq, B.M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Khalid I. Hussein, Md. Rezaul Karim, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399222190

                The primary focus of current research is the development of an affordable, effective and reliable electrocatalyst for electrochemical water splitting to generate clean energy. In this context, designing and manipulating the valence states of transition metals is a promising method for developing effective electrocatalysts for the splitting of water. Because increased valence metal sites can accelerate the reaction rates for oxygen evolution process (OER). Herein, the physiochemical features of CuO are modulated by the inclusion of spinel MnAl2O4 with high-valence metal sites and a porous framework comprised of linked tiny nanoparticles. nanocomposite CuO/MnAl2O4 were fabricated through a sonication procedure in 1.0 M KOH for OER. The electrocatalytic measurement of CuO/MnAl2O4 showed outstanding oxygen activity for OER with reduced overpotential of 196 mV at current density (Cd:10 mA cm&#8722;2) and Tafel value (34 mV dec-1) and lower onset potential of 1.28V than pristine CuO. Also, the Nyquist plot illustrates the improved conductivity by illustrating a minor charge transfer resistance (Rct) value (0.13 &#937;), moreover, nanocomposite shows stability for 50 hours at 65% of its current density.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Sadiq, B.M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Khalid I. Hussein, Md. Rezaul Karim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Core-shell Structured NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@CoFe-LDH Nanorods: Performance of Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Overall Water-splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15541/jim20240098</link>
      <description>Yue QuanXin, GUO Ruihua, Ruifen Wang, Shengli An, ZHANG Guofang, Guan LiLi, Wuji cailiao xuebao. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399229005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue QuanXin, GUO Ruihua, Ruifen Wang, Shengli An, ZHANG Guofang, Guan LiLi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15541/jim20240098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-Derived LDHs: Unveiling Their Potential in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100128</link>
      <description>Mohammad Etesami, Shiva Rezaei Motlagh, Ramin Khezri, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Myong Yong Choi, Kasidit Nootong, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Soorathep Kheawhom, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239615

                This review explores the potential of metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) to drive sustainable clean energy solutions and their crucial role in transitioning towards a decarbonized global economy. The paper underscores the remarkable versatility and modifiability of MOFs. Central to this discourse is the conversion of MOFs into layered double hydroxides (LDHs), with a detailed exposition of the synthesis methodologies and their consequential effects on catalytic efficacy. A meticulous evaluation of MOF-derived LDHs is presented, particularly in the context of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), encapsulating cutting-edge progress and probing the feasibility of integrating these materials into next-generation energy technologies. Diverging from existing literature, this research provides an in-depth exploration of MOF-to-LDH conversion, a promising area in OER catalysis. In addition, structural engineering techniques to optimize the performance of MOF-derived LDHs in electrochemical devices are explored, highlighting the potential of MOFs as future electrocatalysts and guiding future research directions.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Etesami, Shiva Rezaei Motlagh, Ramin Khezri, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Myong Yong Choi, Kasidit Nootong, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous MnRuOx Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405641</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Li Gao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239788

                Compared to Ir, Ru&#8208;based catalysts often exhibited higher activity but suffered significant and rapid activity loss during the challenging oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in a corrosive acidic environment. Herein, we developed a hybrid MnRuOx catalyst in which the RuO2 microcrystalline regions serve as a supporting framework, and the amorphous MnRuOx phase fills the microcrystalline interstices. In particular, the MnRuOx&#8208;300 catalyst from an annealing temperature of 300oC contains an optimal amorphous/crystalline heterostructure, providing substantial defects and active sites, facilitating efficient adsorption and conversion of OH&#8208;. In addition, the heterostructure leads to a relative increase of the d&#8208;band center close to the Fermin level, thus accelerating electron transfer with reduced charge transfer resistance at the active interface between crystalline and amorphous phases during the OER. The catalyst was further thoroughly evaluated under various operating conditions and demonstrated exceptional activity and stability for the OER, representing a promising solution to replace Ir in water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Li Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient oxygen evolution activity for heterojunctions CoFe-PBA using a bimetallic probe (Mo/Cu) at room temperature: Construction of multilayered activated structural bodies and cationic vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00863d</link>
      <description>Lihai Wei, Zhihao Liu, Xiaodong Wu, Huabo Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang, Green chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399243418

                The development of efficient and stable active agents is key to accelerating the four-electron process of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Prussian blue (PBA) has greatly limited its application in...</description>
      <author>Lihai Wei, Zhihao Liu, Xiaodong Wu, Huabo Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00863d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cauliflower-like Ni3S2 foam for ultrastable oxygen evolution electrocatalysis in alkaline seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6744-9</link>
      <description>Qing Dai, Xiuli He, Yongchao Yao, Kai Dong, Xuwei Liu, X.H. Guo, Jie Chen, Xiaoya Fan, Dongning Zheng, Yonglan Luo, Shengjun Sun, Luming Li, W. K. Chu, Amr Farouk, Mohamed S. Hamdy, Xuping Sun, Bo Tang, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399246793

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Dai, Xiuli He, Yongchao Yao, Kai Dong, Xuwei Liu, X.H. Guo, Jie Chen, Xiaoya Fan, Dongning Zheng, Yonglan Luo, Shengjun Sun, Luming Li, W. K. Chu, Amr Farouk, Mohamed S. Hamdy, Xuping Sun, Bo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6744-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated iron phosphides and cobalt oxide electrocatalyst for enhanced hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions: A study on activity and stability factors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.449</link>
      <description>Asma A. Alothman, Jafar Hussain Shah, Mehar Un Nisa, S. Noor Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Muhammad Usman, Muhammad Adnan, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399256266

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asma A. Alothman, Jafar Hussain Shah, Mehar Un Nisa, S. Noor Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Muhammad Usman, Muhammad Adnan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on defect modulated electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01805b</link>
      <description>Qianyun He, Lei Han, Chao Lin, Kai Tao, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399259171

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for applications such as water splitting and rechargeable metal-air batteries. Recent research has focused on improving the activity and stability of OER electrocatalysts...</description>
      <author>Qianyun He, Lei Han, Chao Lin, Kai Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01805b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution by &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; Orbital Electron Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404772</link>
      <description>Ning Sun, Zhichuan Zheng, Zhuangzhuang Lai, Junjie Wang, Peng Du, Tianping Ying, Hai Feng Wang, Jianchun Xu, Runze Yu, Kaiming Bi, Ming Lei, Kuo-Si Huang, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399259276

                While high-entropy alloys (HEAs), high-entropy oxides (HEOs), and high-entropy hydroxides (HEHs), have been advanced as a novel frontier in electrocatalytic oxygen evolution, their inherent activity deficiency poses a major challenge. To achieve the unlimited goal to tailor the structure-activity relationship in multicomponent systems, entropy-driven composition engineering presents substantial potential, by fabricating high-entropy anion-regulated transition metal compounds as sophisticated oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. Herein, we developed a versatile two-dimensional high-entropy metal phosphorus trisulfides (HEPS</description>
      <author>Ning Sun, Zhichuan Zheng, Zhuangzhuang Lai, Junjie Wang, Peng Du, Tianping Ying, Hai Feng Wang, Jianchun Xu, Runze Yu, Kaiming Bi, Ming Lei, Kuo-Si Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404772</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Microalgae-Membrane Photobioreactor System for Onboard Oxygen Production in an Aircraft</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-26-0402</link>
      <description>S. Chalathadka Subrahmanya, Naveen Kumar, J.K. Ranjan, Shivaprasad Kotnadh, SAE technical papers on CD-ROM/SAE technical paper series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399266140

                &lt;div class="section abstract"&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;The purpose of the Air Generation System is to provide a constant supply of conditioned fresh air to meet the necessary oxygen availability and to prevent CO2 concentrations for the occupants in an aircraft. The engine bleed energy or electrical load energy consumed towards this circumstance accounts to be approximately 5% of total fuel burn and in turn, contributes to the global emissions of greenhouse gases.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;This paper studies the improvement areas of the present conventional system such as fuel burn consumption associated with an aircraft ECS depending on the amount of bleed, ram air usage and electric power consumption. Improved systems for sustainability and hybridization in environmental control systems are desirable in aircraft.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;This paper explains how a new design of the sustainable hybrid module assists the conventional system, by using a proposed modular MPBR. The MPBR system generates oxygen-enriched air, which is mixed with the traditional fresh air generated from conventional air generation systems.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;MPBR system revitalizes the existing air and establishes more air recirculation when compared to a conventional system. It will reduce the demand for fresh air from the engine bleed in case of engine bleed aircraft or reduce the electrical load in case of more electric aircraft, which hereby improves engine efficiency.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;The proposed system can also be used for redundant life support purposes during an emergency.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;VOCs related to fuel consumption, maintenance, and global emissions of greenhouse gases can be addressed with the proposed solution. It applies to most of the aircraft variants and enhances sustainability, hybridization, reliability, and cost-effective features which would be of value and interest in a business case for the Suppliers, Manufacturers, and Customers side.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <author>S. Chalathadka Subrahmanya, Naveen Kumar, J.K. Ranjan, Shivaprasad Kotnadh</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-26-0402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ semi-etching of bimetallic LDH nanosheet arrays into FeNi-LDH/MOF to boost oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152721</link>
      <description>Hanli Qin, Chenglong Jia, Quanfa Zhou, Zhenyuan Ji, Hanyong Peng, Xiaoping Shen, Hu Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, Juan Yang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399275113

                The inherent sluggish kinetics of water oxidation is the core issue for electrochemical hydrogen production from water splitting. Metal organic frameworks (MOFs) with tunable porous structures, abundant coordination metal centers and large specific surface area are expected as efficient electrocatalysts. In this paper, FeNi-LDH/MOF composite nanostructures were successfully constructed on carbon cloth (CC) through partially converting iron-nickel layered double hydroxide (FeNi-LDH) into FeNi-MOF (NiFe(CN)5NO) by an in-situ semi-etching method. The MOF nanocrystals in this material are in-situ decorated on the surface of FeNi-LDH nanosheets, providing abundant open active sites and mass transfer channels for electrocatalysis. Thanks to the synergistic effect of the LDH and MOF, as well as the exceptional hierarchical architecture, the FeNi-LDH/MOF/CC as a self-supported electrode exhibits distinguished electrocatalytic OER performance, with a low overpotential of 263 mV@100 mA cm&#8722;2 and a small Tafel slope of 50.2 mV dec-1 in 1.0 M KOH. In addition, the catalyst exhibits good durability with almost constant current density during 24 h OER test. This work provides an effective way to design high-performance MOFs-based composite electrocatalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Hanli Qin, Chenglong Jia, Quanfa Zhou, Zhenyuan Ji, Hanyong Peng, Xiaoping Shen, Hu Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, Juan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous MnRuOx Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405641</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Li Gao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399241187

                Compared to Ir, Ru&#8208;based catalysts often exhibited higher activity but suffered significant and rapid activity loss during the challenging oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in a corrosive acidic environment. Herein, we developed a hybrid MnRuOx catalyst in which the RuO2 microcrystalline regions serve as a supporting framework, and the amorphous MnRuOx phase fills the microcrystalline interstices. In particular, the MnRuOx&#8208;300 catalyst from an annealing temperature of 300oC contains an optimal amorphous/crystalline heterostructure, providing substantial defects and active sites, facilitating efficient adsorption and conversion of OH&#8208;. In addition, the heterostructure leads to a relative increase of the d&#8208;band center close to the Fermin level, thus accelerating electron transfer with reduced charge transfer resistance at the active interface between crystalline and amorphous phases during the OER. The catalyst was further thoroughly evaluated under various operating conditions and demonstrated exceptional activity and stability for the OER, representing a promising solution to replace Ir in water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Li Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal vacancies and self-reconstruction of high entropy metal borates to boost the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152758</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Zhang, Kai Luo, Yaning Fan, Xiaoyan L&#252;, Jian Ye, Ning Liu, Jie Dong, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399275414

                Exploring highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is important for industrial water electrolysis. Herein, a new high entropy material was reported, i.e., an amorphous high entropy metal borate (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx was synthesized by a new simple solvothermal method. The key of this new synthesis method was to obtain (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx with a high specific surface area (446 m2/g) and porous structure, being expected to promote OER reaction. (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx provided a low overpotential of 236 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a reduced Tafel slope of 64 mV dec&#8211;1, and good stability. The outstanding OER performance of (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx was attributed to the high entropy structure, generation of metal vacancies, and self-reconstruction during OER. The Cr vacancies generated during the OER process have been demonstrated by Cr 2P XPS and EPR experiments. Various in situ and Ex-situ analyses such as In situ Raman, XPS, and TEM were used to investigate the self-reconstruction of the (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx during the OER. The resulting metal (oxy)hydroxide was believed to be the true active center for OER. The DFT calculation showed the high entropy structure can reduce the adsorption and conversion energy barriers of oxygen-containing intermediates, matching well with the catalytic performance results. This study provided a new simple strategy to construct high entropy metal borate (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx and would inspire the design of high-performance OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Zhang, Kai Luo, Yaning Fan, Xiaoyan L&#252;, Jian Ye, Ning Liu, Jie Dong, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopic Investigations of Complex Electronic Interactions by Elemental Doping and Material Compositing of Cobalt Oxide for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405384</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399080117

                Abstract Doping and compositing are two universal design strategies used to engineer the electronic state of a material and mitigate its disadvantages. These two strategies are extensively applied to design efficient electrocatalysts for water splitting. Using cobalt oxide (CoO) as a model catalyst, it is proven that the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance can be progressively improved, first by Fe&#8208;doping to form Fe&#8208;CoO solid solution, and further by the addition of CeO 2 to produce a Fe&#8208;CoO/CeO 2 composite. X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) reveals that distinct electronic interactions are induced by the processes of doping and compositing. Fe&#8208;doping of CoO can break down the structural symmetry, changing the electronic structure of both Co and O species at the surface and decreasing the flat&#8208;band potential (V fb ). In comparison, subsequent compositing of Fe&#8208;CoO with CeO 2 induces negligible electronic changes in the Fe&#8208;CoO (as seen in ex situ characterizations), but significantly modifies the oxidative transformations of both Co and Fe under OER conditions. The spectroscopic investigations reveal that Fe&#8208;doping and CeO 2 compositing play different roles in modifying the electronic properties of CoO in its pristine state and during OER catalysis, in return, providing useful guidance for the design of more efficient electrocatalysts using these two strategies.</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy as a Powerful Tool for Uncovering Property-Activity Relationships for Oxygen Evolution Transition Metal Oxide Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2533/chimia.2024.320</link>
      <description>Emiliana Fabbri, Thomas J. Schmidt, Chimia. 78(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399135286

                The development of a sustainable and environmentally friendly energy economy encompasses efficient hydrogen production from renewable energy via electrolysis. In this context, great efforts have recently been dedicated to the development of more efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts. Understanding the mechanism of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on transition metal oxide catalysts is of great interest, but the reaction and system complexity render the characterization of active sites and the understanding of reaction mechanisms challenging. Time resolved Quick X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy (XAS) can provide dynamic snapshots of the electronic and local structure of nanocatalysts, revealing the 'real active phase' of the catalyst, which can substantially differ from the as-prepared catalyst powder or the catalyst in form of an electrode under non-operating conditions. In this contribution, several examples will be presented showing how operando XAS can reveal catalyst-support interactions, changes in the reaction mechanism, and dynamic reversible/irreversible changes in the electronic and local structure of OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Emiliana Fabbri, Thomas J. Schmidt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2533/chimia.2024.320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing NiO/Co3O4/KNbO3 heterostructure with NiO and Co3O4 particles coupled on KNO3 cubes for high-performance urea-assisted alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.435</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liping Du, Jingwen Chen, Jing Tan, Xuemin Bai, Yahui Chen, Jikui Zhu, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399067586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liping Du, Jingwen Chen, Jing Tan, Xuemin Bai, Yahui Chen, Jikui Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineering in Composition and Valence Band Center of Y&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(Y&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ru&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; Pyrochlore Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04292</link>
      <description>Barnali Ghosh, Cheng Zhang, Stefanie Frick, En Ju Cho, Toby J. Woods, Ying Yang, Nicola H. Perry, Andreas Klein, Hong Yang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399209196

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) takes place in various types of electrochemical devices that are pivotal for the conversion and storage of renewable energy. This paper describes a strategy in the design of solid-state structures of OER electrocatalysts through controlling the cation substitution on the active metal site and consequently valence band center position of site-mixed Y</description>
      <author>Barnali Ghosh, Cheng Zhang, Stefanie Frick, En Ju Cho, Toby J. Woods, Ying Yang, Nicola H. Perry, Andreas Klein, Hong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Evaluation of Inserted Nanocomposite Hydrogel-Based Phosphorescent Oxygen Biosensors: Evolution of Local Tissue Oxygen Levels and Foreign Body Response</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c00336</link>
      <description>David Chimene, Waqas Saleem, Nichole Longbottom, Brian S. Ko, Ananthakrishna Soundaram Jeevarathinam, Staci J. Horn, Michael J. McShane, ACS applied bio materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141031

                Phosphorescence-based oxygen-sensing hydrogels are a promising platform technology for an upcoming generation of insertable biosensors that are smaller, softer, and potentially more biocompatible than earlier designs. However, much remains unknown about their long-term performance and biocompatibility in vivo. In this paper, we design and evaluate a range of hydrogel sensors that contain oxygen-sensitive phosphors stabilized by micro- and nanocarrier systems. These devices demonstrated consistently good performance and biocompatibility in young adult rats for over three months. This study thoroughly establishes the biocompatibility and long-term suitability of phosphorescence lifetime sensors in vivo, providing the groundwork for expansion of this platform technology into a family of small, unobtrusive biosensors for a range of clinically relevant metabolites.</description>
      <author>David Chimene, Waqas Saleem, Nichole Longbottom, Brian S. Ko, Ananthakrishna Soundaram Jeevarathinam, Staci J. Horn, Michael J. McShane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c00336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product characterization and pore structure evolution of a tar-rich coal following pyrolysis under nitrogen, steam/nitrogen, and oxygen/nitrogen atmospheres</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106563</link>
      <description>Zhibing Chang, Chuchu Wang, Wenhao Kuang, Ying Tang, Xiaodan Wu, Shuqin Li, Journal of analytical and applied pyrolysis. 180(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399071752

                Steam and an oxidative medium could be the most promising atmosphere for the in-situ pyrolysis of tar-rich coal. This study investigated the influence of these two atmospheres by comparing product yields, tar properties, and pore evolution characteristics of a tar-rich coal following pyrolysis under nitrogen (N2), steam/nitrogen (steam/N2), and oxygen/nitrogen (O2/N2). Compared with N2 pyrolysis, steam/N2 pyrolysis increased the tar yield by 0.54&#8211;1.33 wt.% at 350&#8211;600 &#176;C; further, O2/N2 pyrolysis increased the tar yield from 0.57 wt.% to 3.53 wt.% at 350 &#176;C while decreasing this value by 0.31&#8211;1.83 wt.% at 400&#8211;600 &#176;C. At 450 &#176;C and 500 &#176;C, steam addition suppressed the formation of oxygenated compounds, thereby decreasing the O/C ratio of tar from 0.099 and 0.088 to 0.073 and 0.074, respectively. Conversely, O2 introduction presented the oxygen addition of tar by oxidation reactions. Meanwhile, steam inhibited the aromatization of alkanes and the condensation of monocyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (MAHs). By contrast, O2 was able to promote the condensation of phenols and MAHs. At 450 &#176;C, steam/N2 was thought to assist in the cracking of the plastic mass by providing a H2-rich atmosphere, which decreased the pitch content of tar and increased the contents of light fractions. O2/N2 was also beneficial for the formation of light fractions by intensifying the thermal cracking effect. Micro-CT and SEM analysis showed that H2O could promote the formation of micro-sized pores within the coal matrix, decreasing the average pore diameter (APD) from 150.95 &#956;m to 102.67 &#956;m and increasing the average coordination number (ACN) of pores from 6.27 to 8.59. O2 was inclined to enlarge the pyrolysis-induced pore network, which imposed a contrasting effect on APD and ACN parameters. Steam is recommended as the preferred atmosphere for the in-situ pyrolysis of tar-rich coal.</description>
      <author>Zhibing Chang, Chuchu Wang, Wenhao Kuang, Ying Tang, Xiaodan Wu, Shuqin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cauliflower-Like Pd/Moc||Mo2c/C Heterostructure as an Efficient Trifunctional Catalyst for Formic Acid Oxidation, Hydrogen Evolution, and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4844553</link>
      <description>Ting Wang, Yuquan Feng, SU Jian-jun, Wei Qi, Xin Run, Jiannan Cai, Zhang Xiao-feng, Qiufeng Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399109585

                Developing efficient Pd-based multi-functional catalytic materials for formic acid oxidation reaction (FAO), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) remains a significant challenge. Transition metal interstitial carbides (TMICs) have emerged as promising candidates for electrocatalysis due to their unique structure. Cauliflower-shaped Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C nanostructured heterogeneous composites were prepared using a high-temperature pyrolysis and ethanol reduction method. The resulting materials exhibit high electrocatalytic performance towards FAO, HER, and ORR. In terms of FAO, the mass activity of Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C is 1.87 A mgPd-1, which is 2.75 times higher than that of Pd/C (0.68 A mgPd-1). As for the HER, a much lower overpotential of -28 mV is required to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm-2 compared to Pd/C(-40 mV). Fortunately, Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C also exhibits excellent ORR activity with a half-wave potential of 0.798 V and the maximum current density of approximately 5.73 mA cm-2 in alkaline electrolytes. The use of heterostructures enables the rearrangement of surface electrons, modifies active sites, and promotes the interaction between MoC||Mo2C/C and Pd. This leads to significant multifunctional catalytic performance. These findings could lead to the development of other noble metal-based materials loaded on intermetallic compounds with stable and effective electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Ting Wang, Yuquan Feng, SU Jian-jun, Wei Qi, Xin Run, Jiannan Cai, Zhang Xiao-feng, Qiufeng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4844553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of phenols evolution during pyrolysis of Shendong coal macerals swelled with oxygen-containing organic solvents: Experimental and DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152648</link>
      <description>Linyang Wang, Qing Yao, Rui Cao, Lei He, Ming Sun, Xiaoxun Ma, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399068710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linyang Wang, Qing Yao, Rui Cao, Lei He, Ming Sun, Xiaoxun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Electron Redistribution in Platinum for Enhanced Alkaline Water Splitting Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00503a</link>
      <description>Wensheng Zhang, Xu Chen, Jinyu Zhao, Ning Lin, Guipeng Wang, Xiaomin Wang, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399109099

                The potential of hydrogen production via water splitting technology makes it urgent to develop low-cost and highly active bifunctional catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER). In this study,...</description>
      <author>Wensheng Zhang, Xu Chen, Jinyu Zhao, Ning Lin, Guipeng Wang, Xiaomin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00503a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the active interface structure of MnO2 to achieve sustainable water oxidation in Acidic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02256d</link>
      <description>San-Jiang Pan, Shen Wang, Yu Wang, H.B. Li, Deng Zhao, Liu Yang, Hua Liao, Jiajing Kou, Nan Li, Desong Wang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399055133

                Developing cost-effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis is crucial to achieving large-scale hydrogen production through water electrolysis. Here, we propose the...</description>
      <author>San-Jiang Pan, Shen Wang, Yu Wang, H.B. Li, Deng Zhao, Liu Yang, Hua Liao, Jiajing Kou, Nan Li, Desong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02256d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous cobalt-nickel borides boost electrocatalytic ethanol oxidation coupled with energy-saving hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00277f</link>
      <description>Anqi Hong, Xiangbowen Du, Kun Qian, Fang Zheng, Dongli Yu, Jing Sui, Wei Tong, Renhong Li, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399265708

                The thermodynamically more advantageous ethanol oxidation (EOR) can replace anodic oxygen evolution (OER) in electrolysis, offering a practical way to produce energy-efficient hydrogen and simultaneously upgrade biomass. Here, we design...</description>
      <author>Anqi Hong, Xiangbowen Du, Kun Qian, Fang Zheng, Dongli Yu, Jing Sui, Wei Tong, Renhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00277f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Pore Structure and Active Site Modulation in Co&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalysts Enabling Stable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01761</link>
      <description>Xin Li, Xiaowei Lv, Panpan Sun, Xiaohua Sun, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399238599

                Development of cheap, highly active, and durable nonprecious metal-based oxygen electrocatalysts is essential for metal-air battery technology, but achieving the balance of oxygen evolution reaction (OER)/oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) bifunctional performance and long-term durability is still a great challenge. Using a typical Co-N-C catalyst as a model, herein, we introduced ammonium chloride into nitrogen-doped carbon materials containing metal elements during the pyrolysis process (Co-N-C/AC), which not only increases the active area but also realizes the accurate customization of the active site (pyridine nitrogen and cobalt oxide species) so as to achieve the balance of the OER/ORR bifunctional sites. The synthesized Co-N-C/AC bifunctional catalyst with a three-dimensional porous structure exhibits a smaller potential gap of 0.72 V. The peak power density of the aqueous cell at a current density of 308 mA cm</description>
      <author>Xin Li, Xiaowei Lv, Panpan Sun, Xiaohua Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BaCoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Tetrahedral Cobalt Coordination: The Missing Element to Understand Energy Storage and Conversion Applications in BaCoO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14047</link>
      <description>Aliou Diatta, Claire Colin, Romain Viennois, M. Beaudhuin, Julien Haines, Patrick Hermet, Arie van der Lee, Leszek Konczewicz, P. Armand, J&#233;r&#244;me Rouquette, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050116

                Barium&#8211;cobaltate-based perovskite (BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;) and barium&#8211;cobaltate-based nanocomposites have been intensively studied in energy storage and conversion devices mainly due to flexible oxygen stoichiometry and tunable nonprecious transition metal oxidation states. Although a rich and complex family of structural polymorphs has already been reported for these perovskites in the literature, the potential structural evolution that may occur during the oxygen reduction reaction and the oxygen evolution reaction has not been investigated so far. In this study, we synthesized and characterized the lowest Co-oxidation state possible in the compound, BaCoO2, which exhibits a quartz-derived, trigonal structure with a helicoidally corner-sharing, CoO4-tetrahedral-framework as already proposed by Spitsbergen et al. Oxygen can reversibly be inserted in such a crystal structure to form BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;, i.e., with 0 &#8804; &#948; &#8804; 1, based on the results of an in situ coupled thermogravimetric - neutron diffraction study and which presents therefore giant oxygen capacity storage due to the extreme tunability of the electronic configuration of the cobalt cations which defines the fundamental origins of the materials performance. The reversible conversion of BaCoO2 to BaCoO3&#8722;&#948; associated with a similar electronic conductivity above 900 K permits to clarify the high potential of BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;-based energy storage and conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Aliou Diatta, Claire Colin, Romain Viennois, M. Beaudhuin, Julien Haines, Patrick Hermet, Arie van der Lee, Leszek Konczewicz, P. Armand, J&#233;r&#244;me Rouquette</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Enhanced Ni3N-CeO2/NF Nanoparticle Catalysts for Efficient and Stable Electrolytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110935</link>
      <description>Xianghao Meng, Xin Zhao, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Yiting Peng, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399042805

                Highly efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts are of critical significance in the domain of water electrolysis. In this study, a Ni3N-CeO2/NF heterostructure is synthesized through a facile hydrothermal technique followed by a subsequent nitridation process. This catalyst is endowed with an abundance of oxygen vacancies, thereby conferring a richer array of active sites. Therefore, the catalyst demonstrates a markedly low overpotential of 350 mV for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 and a low overpotential of 42 mV for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Serving as a dual-function electrode, this electrocatalyst is employed in overall water splitting in alkaline environments, demonstrating impressive efficiency at a cell voltage of 1.52 V of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The in situ Raman spectroscopic analysis demonstrates that cerium dioxide (CeO2) facilitates the rapid reconfiguration of oxygen vacancy-enriched nickel oxyhydroxide (NiOOH), thereby enhancing the OER performance. This investigation elucidates the catalytic role of CeO2 in augmenting the OER efficiency of nickel nitride (Ni3N) for water electrolysis, offering valuable insights for the design of high-performance bifunctional catalysts tailored for water splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Xianghao Meng, Xin Zhao, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Yiting Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From density functional theory to machine learning predictive models for electrical properties of spinel oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62788-4</link>
      <description>Yuval Elbaz, Maytal Caspary Toroker, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399037502

                Abstract This work focuses on predicting and characterizing the electronic conductivity of spinel oxides, which are promising materials for energy storage devices and for the oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions due to their attractive properties and abundance of transition metals that can act as active sites for catalysis. To this end, a new database was developed from first principles, including band structure and conductivity properties of spinel oxides, and machine learning algorithms were trained on this database to predict electronic conductivity and band gaps based solely on the compositions. The models developed in this study are scaled from the quantum level up to a continuum conductivity model. The relatively small database used in this study allowed for accurate predictions of band gap and conductivity. By altering the composition of spinel oxides, the model was able to predict high conductivity for spinels with high nickel content and to match experimental trends for manganese cobalt spinels. The ability to predict material properties is especially important in energy conversion devices such as batteries and supercapacitors where redox reactions take place.</description>
      <author>Yuval Elbaz, Maytal Caspary Toroker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62788-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoOx/CoMo on Cu nanowires as an efficiently bifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400582</link>
      <description>Xingchen Chai, Cang Yuan, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Lei Wang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399047706

                Electrocatalytic water splitting is a promising approach for sustainable hydrogen production. The design and development of efficient and stable bifunctional catalysts are the key to realizing hydrogen production from water splitting. Herein, we successfully synthesized bifunctional MoOx/CoMo grown on copper nanowires (Cu NWs) through an electrodeposition approach, showing excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performances. The MoOx/CoMo/Cu NWs catalyst exhibited overpotentials as low as 56 mV and 211 mV to deliver a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 for HER and OER in alkaline media, respectively. Moreover, the MoOx/CoMo/Cu NWs as bifunctional electrodes for overall water splitting achieved a low voltage of 1.45 and 1.62 V at 10 and 50 mA cm&#8208;2, respectively, with a stability of 10 h at 50 mA cm&#8208;2. This work provides a promising strategy for designing highly active catalysts that replace precious&#8208;metal&#8208;based catalysts on energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Xingchen Chai, Cang Yuan, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Application of a Gas Diffusion Electrode (GDE) Cell for Operando and In Situ Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2533/chimia.2024.344</link>
      <description>Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Rebecca Pittkowski, Stefanie Punke, Olivia Aalling&#8208;Frederiksen, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Matthias Arenz, Chimia. 78(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399135277

                Presented here is an electrochemical three-electrode Gas Diffusion Electrode (GDE) cell tailored for operandoand in situ investigations of electrocatalytic processes, with a particular focus on X-ray scattering studies. The optimized cell is engineered to accommodate the minimal sample-detector distances requisite for comprehensive X-ray total scattering investigations. An in-depth understanding of catalytic processes requires their study under 'working' conditions. Configured as a flow-cell, the setup therefore enables the examination of electrocatalysts under high current densities and associated gas evolution phenomena, particularly pertinent for reactions like the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Notably, its transparency simplifies cell alignment, troubleshooting, and facilitates scans through the catalyst layer, crucial for background corrections. Demonstrating its versatility, we showcase its utility through Small Angle X-ray Scattering (SAXS), X-ray Diffraction (XRD), and X-ray Pair Distribution Function (PDF) analyses of total scattering data.</description>
      <author>Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Rebecca Pittkowski, Stefanie Punke, Olivia Aalling&#8208;Frederiksen, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2533/chimia.2024.344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Image, Volume 6, Number 5, May 2024</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.606</link>
      <description>Hongyu Gong, Guanliang Sun, Wei Shi, Dongwei Li, Xiangjun Zheng, Huan Shi, Xiu Liang, Ruizhi Yang, Changzhou Yuan, Carbon energy. 6(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399142520

                Front cover image: Enhancing both the number of active sites available and the intrinsic activity of Co-based oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts simultaneously is a desirable goal. In the article number CEY2432, Yuan et al. reported a ZIF-67-derived hierarchical porous cobalt sulfide decorated by Au nanoparticles (denoted as HP-Au@CoxSy@ZIF-67) hybrid. The novel three-dimensional hierarchical structure significantly enlarges the three-phase interfaces, accelerating the mass transfer and exposing the active centers. Meanwhile, the electronic structure of Co is modulated by Au through charge transfer, wherein Au and NaBH4 reductant result in an interesting "competition effect" to regulate the relative ratio of Co2+/Co3+. Consequently, HP-Au@CoxSy@ZIF-67 displayed excellent OER performance, enabling efficient water splitting and Zn&#8211;air battery application.</description>
      <author>Hongyu Gong, Guanliang Sun, Wei Shi, Dongwei Li, Xiangjun Zheng, Huan Shi, Xiu Liang, Ruizhi Yang, Changzhou Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Oxidation of Small Molecules for Energy&#8208;Saving Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401242</link>
      <description>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Liangshuang Fei, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399047723

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting is a promising technique for the production of high&#8208;purity hydrogen. Substituting the slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction with an oxidation reaction that is thermodynamically more favorable enables the energy&#8208;efficient production of hydrogen. Moreover, this approach facilitates the degradation of environmental pollutants and synthesis of value&#8208;added chemicals through the rational selection of small molecules as substrates. Strategies for small&#8208;molecule selection and electrocatalyst design are critical to electrocatalytic performance, with a focus on achieving a high current density, selectivity, Faradaic efficiency, and operational durability. This perspective discusses the key factors required for further advancement, including technoeconomic analysis, new reactor system design, meeting the requirements of industrial applications, bridging the gap between fundamental research and practical applications, and product detection and separation. This perspective aims to advance the development of hybrid water electrolysis applications.</description>
      <author>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Liangshuang Fei, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring tin sulfide electrocatalyst with petroleum coke derived reduced graphene oxide for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100689</link>
      <description>Chandan Kumar&#8208;Sinha, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Pinky Saharan, Ashish Gupta, J.B. Singh, Mandeep Singh, Sanjay R. Dhakate, FlatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399208222

                Metal chalcogenides like Tin sulfide (SnS2) presents as viable alternative electrocatalysts for alkaline water splitting (AWS) due to their huge abundance, stability, and environment friendly nature. However, insufficient exposed active sites and poor conductivity severely impede its large-scale applications. In this work, an in-situ hybridization of hexagonal SnS2 with intercalation of reduced graphene oxide nanosheets (TS-rGOx) overcomes the problem of SnS2 stacking. It further enhances the interlayer spacing thereby boosting the number of active sites. The resulting TS-rGOx exhibited excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activities demanding low overpotential of 313 mV and 196.2 mV at 20 mA/cm2 with long term durability upto 60 h, which can be attributed to enhanced interlayer spacing of SnS2, abundant active sites and higher conductivity resulting from the in-situ hybridization and intercalation of rGO nanosheets. This work opens a prospect towards the design and application of efficient SnS2 based heterostructured electrocatalyst for AWS.</description>
      <author>Chandan Kumar&#8208;Sinha, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Pinky Saharan, Ashish Gupta, J.B. Singh, Mandeep Singh, Sanjay R. Dhakate</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100689</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur Recovery Assisted Electrochemical Water Splitting for H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production Using CoMo-Based Nanorod Arrays Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00695</link>
      <description>Jichuan Huo, Qing Liu, Xiaofang Liu, Xue&#8208;Feng Cheng, Dongyun Chen, Najun Li, Kin Liao, Qingfeng Xu, Jianmei Lu, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399175366

                Swapping the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for the thermodynamically advantageous sulfur ion oxidation reaction (SOR) makes it possible to produce low-energy hydrogen. We report here on an electrocatalytic SOR-coupled HER system that allows for the joint production of sulfur and hydrogen. We prepare a CoMoO4 nanoarray on nickel foam (NF) for anodic SOR and N-doped CoMoO4/NF, CoMoN/NF, for cathodic HER. The current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2 was obtained at 0.29 V (vs RHE) in the SOR process. After nitridation, the electrode can achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in HER at a voltage of only 32 mV (vs RHE). The coupling system (SOR//HER) can run steadily for 150 h. Detailed exploration and discussion were conducted on the pathways of SOR. This work develops an energy-efficient mixed water electrolysis system for H2, providing a viable option for toxic waste treatment.</description>
      <author>Jichuan Huo, Qing Liu, Xiaofang Liu, Xue&#8208;Feng Cheng, Dongyun Chen, Najun Li, Kin Liao, Qingfeng Xu, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible bifunctional electrocatalyst (Ni@(Ni,Fe)Se2/Ni@CC) by adjusting d-band center for high-efficiency HER and overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphma.2024.05.003</link>
      <description>Wenbo Liao, Baojie Zhang, Lan Mu, Ning Zhao, Gang Zhao, Junjie Huang, Xijin Xu, ChemPhysMater. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399206547

                Nickel foam is widely used as a collector for electrocatalysts because of its excellent electrical conductivity; however, it is prone to react with elements such as oxygen, sulfur, and phosphorus during the growth of electrode materials, which makes it brittle and fragile, thus limiting its large-scale application. In this study, bifunctional electrocatalysts with flexible multilevel Ni-based nanoclusters Ni@(Ni,Fe)Se2/Ni@CC were synthesized on carbon cloth(CC) by hydrothermal and electrodeposition methods; these flexible electrocatalysts are convenient for subsequent industrial applications. At a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, the overpotentials of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) reached 98 and 224 mV, respectively, exceeding the catalytic effects of most metal-based collectors. The overall water-splitting potential of the catalyst was only 1.56 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and the performance was maintained after a 24 h stability test. Ni@(Ni,Fe)Se2/Ni@CC significantly improved the activity in alkaline environments by modulating the center of the d-band, thereby increasing the adsorption capacity of the catalyst for H ions. In this study, we improved the intrinsic activity and charge transfer of transition metal electrocatalysts by modifying the carbon cloth and constructing multilevel Ni-based nanoclusters, which provided some insights into the rational design of flexible bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Wenbo Liao, Baojie Zhang, Lan Mu, Ning Zhao, Gang Zhao, Junjie Huang, Xijin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphma.2024.05.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile fabrication of SnO2/MnTe nanocomposite as an efficient electrocatalyst for OER in basic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175036</link>
      <description>Rabab Zahra, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, B.M. Alotaibi, Haifa A. Alyousef, Nuha Al-Harbi, A. Dahshan, Khursheed Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399209327

                There is a strong demand for developing an extremely effective and robust electrocatalyst to facilitate oxygen evolution reaction in water electrolysis applications. Herein, we successfully produced SnO2/MnTe using an efficient ultrasonication technique that is cost-effective and readily accessible along with improved catalytic behavior. The physical properties of fabricated catalysts are examined to analyze textural, structural and morphological characteristics. The SnO2/MnTe nanocomposite exhibited the low overpotential (181 mV) at 10 mA cm-2 and smaller Tafel slope of 33 mV dec-1 in alkaline (1.0 M KOH) medium. Moreover, the material also showed prolonged and excellent stability over 50 h following 5000 stability cycles. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy studies demonstrated that charge transfer kinetics at the catalyst-electrolyte interface could be achievable, with lower Rct values (0.8&#937;) directing it to increase electrochemical behavior. The acquired outcomes obtained from electrochemical activity demonstrate the potential of SnO2/MnTe as a highly promising electrocatalyst for future electrochemical energy generation.</description>
      <author>Rabab Zahra, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, B.M. Alotaibi, Haifa A. Alyousef, Nuha Al-Harbi, A. Dahshan, Khursheed Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrystalline CuOx Thin Films for Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.1556.v2</link>
      <description>E. Silva, F&#225;bio Viadanna Serr&#227;o, Gustavo Henrique dos Santos Domingos, Thiago M.B.F. Oliveira, Marco A. L. Cordeiro, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399138178

                New advances in creating effective and affordable copper-based catalysts for water splitting represent a promising strategy for driving sustainable energy technologies. However, ma- terials containing copper are susceptible to corrosion and agglomeration. In this study, we describe a synthesis route to produce olamine-functionalized CuO nanoparticles using the Hot Injection method. Nanoparticles were obtained and subsequently deposited on FTO substrates, undergoing thermal treatment at 500&amp;deg;C and 600&amp;deg;C in atmospheres containing O2 and N2, aiming to enhance the adhesion of the active material to the substrate and modify its oxidation state. Microstructural properties were analyzed using XRD, SEM, and TEM, while electrochemical properties were studied using CV, LSV, and EIS. Electrodes treated thermally in an N2 atmosphere at 600&amp;deg;C exhibited higher ESCA, indicating a greater area of active sites exposed to surface reactions and, therefore, superior catalytic activity in Hy- drogen Evolution Reaction (HER). These findings show an interesting strategy for avoiding rapid electron-hole recombination and, consequently, CuO corrosion. For Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), samples treated thermally in O2 atmosphere at 500&amp;deg;C and 600&amp;deg;C appear to be more effective.</description>
      <author>E. Silva, F&#225;bio Viadanna Serr&#227;o, Gustavo Henrique dos Santos Domingos, Thiago M.B.F. Oliveira, Marco A. L. Cordeiro</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.1556.v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Phase Separation Engineering of Iron&#8211;Cobalt Alloy Heterojunction for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01147</link>
      <description>Yanhong Ding, Xiao-Tong Han, Qian Yang, Yan Jiang, Gang Bai, Jianping Zhang, Weihua Li, Baoshan Hu, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399175458

                The tailor-made transition metal alloy-based heterojunctions hold a promising prospect for the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, a series of iron&#8211;cobalt bimetallic alloy heterojunctions are purposely designed and constructed via a newly developed controllable phase separation engineering strategy. The results show that the phase separation process and alloy component distribution rely on the metal molar ratio (Fe/Co), indicative of the metal content dependent behavior. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that the electronic structure and charge distribution of iron&#8211;cobalt bimetallic alloy can be modulated and optimized, thus leading to the formation of an electron-rich interface layer, which likely tunes the d-band center and reduces the adsorption energy barrier toward electrocatalytic intermediates. As a result, the Fe0.25Co0.75/Co heterojunction exhibits superior OER activity with a low overpotential of 185 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2. Moreover, it can reach industrial-level current densities and excellent durability in high-temperature and high-concentration electrolyte (30 wt % KOH), exhibiting enormous potential for industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Yanhong Ding, Xiao-Tong Han, Qian Yang, Yan Jiang, Gang Bai, Jianping Zhang, Weihua Li, Baoshan Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent organic framework&#8208;derived Fe, Co&#8208;nitrogen codoped carbon as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable efficient Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.145</link>
      <description>Zhanpeng Chen, Jiabi Jiang, Mingjun Jing, Yiming Bai, Xiaoyan Zhang, Wenhui Deng, Yufeng Wu, Fang Chen, Mingguang Yi, Meixia Yang, Xinkai Xu, Tianjing Wu, Zhiwei Yang, Xianyou Wang, Carbon neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050151

                Abstract The development of cathode materials with controllable physicochemical structures and explicit catalytic sites is important in rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) have garnered increasing attention owing to their facile synthesis methods, ordered pore structure, and selectivity of functional groups. However, the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) or oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) inhibit their practical applications in ZABs. Herein, nucleophilic substitution is adopted to synthesize pyridine bi&#8208;triazine covalent organic framework (denoted as O&#8208;COF), and meanwhile, ionothermal conversion synthesis is employed to load MO x (M=Fe, Co) onto carbon nanosheet (named as FeCo@NC) to modulate the electronic structure. The Fe, Co&#8208;N codoped carbon material possesses a large portion of pyridinic N and M&#8208;N, high graphitization, and a larger BET surface area. An outstanding bifunctional activity has been exhibited in FeCo@NC, which provides a small voltage at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER (E 10 = 1.67 V) and a remarkable half&#8208;wave voltage for ORR (E 1/2 = 0.86 V). More impressively, when assembling ZABs, it displays notable rate performance, significant specific capacity (783.9 mAh g Zn &#8722;1 ), and satisfactory long&#8208;term endurance. This method of regulating covalent organic framework and ionothermal synthesis can be extended to design diverse catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhanpeng Chen, Jiabi Jiang, Mingjun Jing, Yiming Bai, Xiaoyan Zhang, Wenhui Deng, Yufeng Wu, Fang Chen, Mingguang Yi, Meixia Yang, Xinkai Xu, Tianjing Wu, Zhiwei Yang, Xianyou Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A dual spin-controlled chiral two-/three-dimensional perovskite artificial leaf for efficient overall photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49216-x</link>
      <description>Hyungsoo Lee, Chan Uk Lee, Juwon Yun, Chang-Seop Jeong, Wooyong Jeong, Jaehyun Son, Young Sun Park, Subin Moon, Soobin Lee, Junhwan Kim, Jooho Moon, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399263634

                The oxygen evolution reaction, which involves high overpotential and slow charge-transport kinetics, plays a critical role in determining the efficiency of solar-driven water splitting. The chiral-induced spin selectivity phenomenon has been utilized to reduce by-product production and hinder charge recombination. To fully exploit the spin polarization effect, we herein propose a dual spin-controlled perovskite photoelectrode. The three-dimensional (3D) perovskite serves as a light absorber while the two-dimensional (2D) chiral perovskite functions as a spin polarizer to align the spin states of charge carriers. Compared to other investigated chiral organic cations, R-/S-naphthyl ethylamine enable strong spin-orbital coupling due to strengthened &#960;-&#960; stacking interactions. The resulting naphthyl ethylamine-based chiral 2D/3D perovskite photoelectrodes achieved a high spin polarizability of 75%. Moreover, spin relaxation was prevented by employing a chiral spin-selective L-NiFeOOH catalyst, which enables the secondary spin alignment to promote the generation of triplet oxygen. This dual spin-controlled 2D/3D perovskite photoanode achieves a 13.17% of applied-bias photon-to-current efficiency. Here, after connecting the perovskite photocathode with L-NiFeOOH/S-naphthyl ethylamine 2D/3D photoanode in series, the resulting co-planar water-splitting device exhibited a solar-to-hydrogen efficiency of 12.55%.</description>
      <author>Hyungsoo Lee, Chan Uk Lee, Juwon Yun, Chang-Seop Jeong, Wooyong Jeong, Jaehyun Son, Young Sun Park, Subin Moon, Soobin Lee, Junhwan Kim, Jooho Moon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49216-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur doped Zinc Oxide-Nikel Oxide as Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for overall Water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4441679/v1</link>
      <description>Saeed Farahany, Salma Aslam Arain, Yong Wang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399216497

                Abstract A mixed Sulfur-doped zinc oxide-nickel oxide nanocomposite electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) was prepared. By hydrothermal method, we prepared a high-efficiency OER electrocatalyst doped with zinc oxide and nickel oxide. By applying different characterizations, the material was proven to be a new phase of (S-doped-ZnO-NiO). S-doped ZnO-NiO, ZnO-NiO did not show excellent performance. At 10 mA cm&#8722; 2, the generation potential of OER is 1.45 V and that of HER is -0.04 V. This unique morphology results in better OER performance of 240 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722; 2 in the KOH electrolyte, and similarly, the S-doped ZnO-NiO shows us excellent long-term stability in alkaline media with a small Tafel slope (77 mV dec&#8722; 1). S-doped ZnO-NiO hybrid catalysts offer great potential for electrochemical devices due to their low cost and high activity. we have successfully constructed an electrocatalyst with the dual functions of HER and OER, which can achieve efficient water splitting.</description>
      <author>Saeed Farahany, Salma Aslam Arain, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4441679/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Ultrastable Iodide Oxidation Reaction Over Defect&#8208;Passivated Perovskite Photoanode for Unassisted Solar Fuel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401055</link>
      <description>Juwon Yun, Young Sun Park, Hyungsoo Lee, Wooyong Jeong, Chang&#8208;Seop Jeong, Chan Uk Lee, Jeongyoub Lee, Subin Moon, Euna Kwon, Soo Bin Lee, Sumin Kim, Junghwan Kim, Seungho Yu, Jooho Moon, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399044053

                Abstract Recently, lead halide perovskites have emerged as promising photoanode materials for efficient hydrogen production. However, the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and interfacial defect&#8208;mediated charge accumulation inevitably result in efficiency loss and degradation of perovskite photoanodes. Herein, a defect&#8208;passivated electron transport layer&#8208;based perovskite photoanode combined with a catalyst layer favorable is introduced for iodide oxidation reaction bearing a small thermodynamic barrier and rapid kinetics compared to OER for efficient solar fuel generation. The resulting perovskite photoanode revealed a saturated photocurrent density of 22.4 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0.3 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (V RHE ) with an impressive onset potential of &#8722;0.2 V RHE as well as durability for 225 h in a neutral electrolyte. In addition, an unbiased hydrogen&#8208;production device comprising a perovskite photoanode and Pt coil electrocatalyst is demonstrated, achieving a remarkable solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion efficiency of 11.45% and stable operation for 25 h. Moreover, a wireless artificial leaf&#8208;structured device realizing solar&#8208;driven hydrogen generation in natural sea water under outdoor sunlight is presented.</description>
      <author>Juwon Yun, Young Sun Park, Hyungsoo Lee, Wooyong Jeong, Chang&#8208;Seop Jeong, Chan Uk Lee, Jeongyoub Lee, Subin Moon, Euna Kwon, Soo Bin Lee, Sumin Kim, Junghwan Kim, Seungho Yu, Jooho Moon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in water splitting for sustainable energy generation: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24294/can.v7i1.5834</link>
      <description>Razu Shahazi, Amirul Islam Saddam, S.K. Majumdar, Md. Rakibul Islam, Mohammed M. Rahman, M. M. Alam, Ajoy Kumer, Giti Paimard, Characterization and application of nanomaterials. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399244269

                Water splitting, the process of converting water into hydrogen and oxygen gases, has garnered significant attention as a promising avenue for sustainable energy production. One area of focus has been the development of efficient and cost-effective catalysts for water splitting. Researchers have explored catalysts based on abundant and inexpensive materials such as nickel, iron, and cobalt, which have demonstrated improved performance and stability. These catalysts show promise for large-scale implementation and offer potential for reducing the reliance on expensive and scarce materials. Another avenue of research involves photoelectrochemical (PEC) cells, which utilize solar energy to drive the water-splitting reaction. Scientists have been working on designing novel materials, including metal oxides and semiconductors, to enhance light absorption and charge separation properties. These advancements in PEC technology aim to maximize the conversion of sunlight into chemical energy. Inspired by natural photosynthesis, artificial photosynthesis approaches have also gained traction. By integrating light-absorbing materials, catalysts, and membranes, these systems aim to mimic the complex processes of natural photosynthesis and produce hydrogen fuel from water. The development of efficient and stable artificial photosynthesis systems holds promise for sustainable and clean energy production. Tandem cells, which combine multiple light-absorbing materials with different bandgaps, have emerged as a strategy to enhance the efficiency of water-splitting systems. By capturing a broader range of the solar spectrum, tandem cells optimize light absorption and improve overall system performance. Lastly, advancements in electrocatalysis have played a critical role in water splitting. Researchers have focused on developing advanced electrocatalysts with high activity, selectivity, and stability for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). These electrocatalysts contribute to overall water-splitting efficiency and pave the way for practical implementation.</description>
      <author>Razu Shahazi, Amirul Islam Saddam, S.K. Majumdar, Md. Rakibul Islam, Mohammed M. Rahman, M. M. Alam, Ajoy Kumer, Giti Paimard</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24294/can.v7i1.5834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe, Co-induced hydrolysis to prepare &#945;-Ni (OH)2/&#946;-Ni(OH)2 interfaces for improved overall water splitting efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144484</link>
      <description>Guoxu Zhou, Zining Wang, Xichun Zhang, Shan Ji, Rongfang Wang, Xianguo Ma, Xuyun Wang, Vladimir Linkov, Rongfang Wang, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399142500

                The development of effective bifunctional electrode materials is necessary for worldwide adoption of large-scale hydrogen production by water electrolysis. Nickel hydroxide - based transition metal materials are among the most promising electrodes for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). While Ni(OH)2 exists in two crystalline states, namely &#945;-Ni(OH)2 and &#946;-Ni(OH)2, neither can meet requirements for effective bifunctional electrode materials on their own, due to relatively low catalytic activity. In this study, bifunctional catalysts with &#945;-Ni(OH)2/&#946;-Ni(OH)2 interfaces, prepared using Fe, Co-induced hydrolysis, have been successfully applied for electrolytic water splitting. According to physical characterization, Fe3+ and Co2+ are incorporated into Ni(OH)2 layers, where Fe doping leads to the formation of a regular flake structure, while Co doping facilitates surface electron transfer, enhancing electrocatalytic activity towards HER and OER. Overpotentials of the obtained catalysts at 100 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 are as low as 224 mV for HER and 324 mV for OER. Both HER and OER overpotentials remained almost unchanged after 24 h operation at a high current density of 1 A&#183;cm&#8722;2, demonstrating excellent stability of the newly prepared materials during water electrolysis. The synthesis of &#945;-Ni(OH)2/&#946;-Ni(OH)2 interfaces is a new direction for the manufacturing of industrially applicable water splitting electrocatalysts suitable for high current density operation.</description>
      <author>Guoxu Zhou, Zining Wang, Xichun Zhang, Shan Ji, Rongfang Wang, Xianguo Ma, Xuyun Wang, Vladimir Linkov, Rongfang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of Biphasic Boride Electrocatalysts on Dealloyed Bulk Ni&#8211;Mo Alloy as Self-Supporting Electrode for Water Splitting at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04157</link>
      <description>Guangyao Yang, Weiliang Peng, Zhipeng Chen, Shaobo Li, Han Qin, Renzong Hu, Bin Yuan, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050071

                Nickel&#8211;molybdenum&#8211;boron (Ni&#8211;Mo&#8211;B)-based catalysts with biphasic interfaces are highly advantageous in bifunctional electrocatalytic activity in alkaline water-splitting. However, it remains an ongoing challenge to obtain porous Ni&#8211;Mo alloy substrates that provide stable adhesion to catalysts, ensuring the long-term performance of bifunctional self-supporting electrodes at a high current density. Herein, a porous Ni&#8211;Mo alloy substrate was effectively obtained by a cost-effective dealloying process on a commercial Ni&#8211;Mo alloy with high-energy crystal planes. Subsequently, the Mo2NiB2/Ni3B bifunctional catalyst was in situ synthesized on this substrate via boriding heat treatment, resulting in outstanding catalytic activity and stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the abundant biphasic interfaces and surface-reconstructed sites of the Mo2NiB2/Ni3B catalyst can decrease the energy barriers for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively. Thus, the designed self-supporting electrodes show bifunctional catalytic activity with overpotentials of 151 mV for HER and 260 mV for OER at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2. Markedly, the assembled water electrolyzer can be driven up to 10 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.64 V and maintain catalytic activity at a high current density of 1000 mA cm&#8211;2 for 100 h. The new strategy is expected to provide a low-cost scheme for designing self-supporting bifunctional electrodes with high activity and excellent stability and contribute to the development of hydrogen energy technology.</description>
      <author>Guangyao Yang, Weiliang Peng, Zhipeng Chen, Shaobo Li, Han Qin, Renzong Hu, Bin Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating built-in electric field via Bi-VO4-Fe interfacial bridges to enhance charge separation for efficient photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.218</link>
      <description>Yingying Wang, Jie Huang, Yuxuan Chen, Hao Yang, Kai&#8208;Hang Ye, Yongchao Huang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399242567

                Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting on semiconductor electrodes is considered to be one of the important ways to produce clean and sustainable hydrogen fuel, which is a great help in solving energy and environmental problems. Bismuth vanadate (BiVO4) as a promising photoanode for photoelectrochemical water splitting still suffers from poor charge separation efficiency and photo-induced self-corrosion. Herein, we develop heterojunction-rich photoanodes composed of BiVO4 and iron vanadate (FeVO4), coated with nickel iron oxide (NiFeOx/FeVO4/BiVO4). The formation of the interface between BiVO4 and FeVO4 (Bi-VO4-Fe bridges) enhances the interfacial interaction, resulting in improved performance. Meanwhile, high-conductivity FeVO4 and NiFeOx oxygen evolution co-catalysts effectively enhance bulk electron/hole separation, interface water's kinetics and photostability. Concurrently, the optimized NiFeOx/FeVO4/BiVO4 possesses a remarkable photocurrent density of 5.59 mA/cm2 at 1.23 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs RHE) under AM 1.5G (Air Mass 1.5 Global) simulated sunlight, accompanied by superior stability without any decreased of its photocurrent density after 14 h. This work not only reveals the crucial role of built-in electric field in BiVO4-based photoanode during PEC water splitting, but also provides a new guide to the design of efficient photoanode for PEC.</description>
      <author>Yingying Wang, Jie Huang, Yuxuan Chen, Hao Yang, Kai&#8208;Hang Ye, Yongchao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycling the spent cobalt-based perovskites for the high-active oxygen catalysts in zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142685</link>
      <description>Jiaqun Zou, Bo Yuan, Chuanyan Zhao, Jianxin Wang, Haoqi Qiu, Jiaxin Dang, Qin Wang, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan, Journal of cleaner production. 462(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399067328

                Cobalt (Co) is widely used in energy storage and conversion devices, although its content on our planet is not adequate. Therefore, recycling Co from the spent Co-enriched materials is indispensable. Co-based perovskites, which contain abundant Co, are extensively utilized in solid oxide fuel cells, three-way catalysts, and oxygen-permeable membranes, and the recovery of Co from the spent Co-based perovskites is necessary to meet the long-term requirement of Co. In this work, a facile and universal thermal reduction method (750 &#176;C and N2 atmosphere) is employed to convert the spent cobalt-based perovskites into high-performance bifunctional oxygen catalysts for zinc-air batteries (ZABs), achieving high-efficient Co recovery and re-utilization. At high temperatures, melamine and dopamine hydrochloride are transformed into carbon nanotubes, C3N4 and reducing gases (such as NH3 and H2). Simultaneously, the metal elements in the spent Co-based perovskites (SrNb0.1Co0.7Fe0.2O3,SNCF) are converted into nano-scale alloy particles and metal nitrides. Then, the phase structures, micromorphology, and element valences of the obtained multiphase oxygen catalyst (SNCF-Ni-PM) are characterized by X-ray diffraction, scanning/transmission electron microscopy, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, respectively. The electrochemical properties, including oxygen catalytic activities and stability, of SNCF-Ni-PM are measured by linear sweep voltammetry, chronopotentiometry, chronoamperometry, and cyclic voltammetry methods. Considering the practical applications, the aqueous and solid-state ZABs are assembled and measured. The results demonstrate that the multiphase SNCF-Ni-PM mainly includes carbon nanotubes, C3N4 nanosheets, and FeNiN or CoFe nanoparticles. Moreover, SNCF-Ni-PM exhibits excellent bifunctional oxygen catalytic activity, with an oxygen evolution reaction (OER) potential at 10 mA cm-2 of 1.51 V and an oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) half-wave potential of 0.77 V, outperforming most of the reported oxygen catalysts. Using SNCF-Ni-PM, the aqueous and solid-state ZABs can achieve high power densities of 295.9 and 228.4 mW cm-2, respectively, being superior to most ZABs. In addition, the aqueous ZAB with SNCF-Ni-PM can operate stably for 300 hours with a slight degradation. This work provides a feasible method for effectively recycling Co from the spent Co-based perovskites.</description>
      <author>Jiaqun Zou, Bo Yuan, Chuanyan Zhao, Jianxin Wang, Haoqi Qiu, Jiaxin Dang, Qin Wang, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNT/Nafion functionalized Ti/SnO2-Sb/&#946;-PbO2-CNT/Nafion composite electrode toward highly active and robust degradation of octadecylamine and 4-dodecylmorpholine in real high-salinity system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152716</link>
      <description>Miao Liu, Siyuan Zhang, Li Ma, Zhenlun Song, Xiushen Ye, Huifang Zhang, Haining Liu, Ying Wang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399207089

                The efficient removal of recalcitrant organics in high-salinity systems, specifically brine, poses a significant challenge for electrochemically advanced oxidation processes in terms of both activity and stability. Herein, a composite electrode comprising of CNT/Nafion functionalized Ti/SnO2-Sb/&#946;-PbO2-CNT/Nafion was developed for efficient and stable removal of octadecylamine (ODA) and 4-dodecylmorpholine (DMP) in a real high-salinity environment. The degradation efficiencies of ODA and DMP on the composite electrode can reach 100 % within 60 min, respectively. The total organic carbon (TOC) removal efficiency of ODA and DMP was significantly improved to 78 % and 66 % with remarkably low energy consumption (0.414 and 1.402 kWh/g TOC), respectively. The electrochemical characterizations demonstrate that the composite electrode exhibits improved electrochemical activity (oxygen evolution potentials = 1.791 V) and electrode surface area (ECSA = 20 cm2), while maintaining reduced charge transfer resistance (Rct = 18.21 &#937;/cm2) and enhanced corrosion-resistant capacity (corrosion potential = 1.115 V). Based on recycling and accelerated lifespan testing, the composite electrode demonstrates exceptional stability and recyclability. Additionally revealed was the linked stability mechanism. The electrocatalytic degradation of ODA and DMP begins with the removal of amino and morpholine rings, and then the decomposition of the carbon chains. Gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC&#8211;MS) and theoretical calculations were used to identify intermediate products generated during the degradation of ODA and DMP, and possible degradation pathways were provided in high-salinity systems, respectively. This work offered a fresh perspective on electrocatalytic oxidation for a real high-salinity system that is more efficient and stable.</description>
      <author>Miao Liu, Siyuan Zhang, Li Ma, Zhenlun Song, Xiushen Ye, Huifang Zhang, Haining Liu, Ying Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physiological and Proteome Analysis of the Effects of Chitosan Oligosaccharides on Salt Tolerance of Rice Seedlings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25115953</link>
      <description>Xiaohua Qian, Yaqing He, Lu Zhang, Xianzhen Li, Wei Tang, International journal of molecular sciences. 25(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399155713

                Rice (Oryza sativa L.) is an important social-economic crop, and rice seedlings are easily affected by salt stress. Chitosan oligosaccharide (COS) plays a positive role in promoting plant growth and development. To gain a better understanding of the salt tolerance mechanism of rice under the action of COS, Nipponbare rice seedlings were selected as the experimental materials, and the physiological and biochemical indexes of rice seedlings in three stages (normal growth, salt stress and recovery) were measured. Unlabelled quantitative proteomics technology was used to study differential protein and signaling pathways of rice seedlings under salt stress, and the mechanism of COS to improve rice tolerance to salt stress was elucidated. Results showed that after treatment with COS, the chlorophyll content of rice seedlings was 1.26 times higher than that of the blank group (CK). The root activity during the recovery stage was 1.46 times that of the CK group. The soluble sugar in root, stem and leaf increased by 53.42%, 77.10% and 9.37%, respectively. The total amino acid content increased by 77% during the stem recovery stage. Furthermore, the malondialdehyde content in root, stem and leaf increased by 21.28%, 26.67% and 32.69%, respectively. The activity of oxide dismutase (SOD), peroxidase (POD) and oxygenase (CAT) were increased. There were more differentially expressed proteins in the three parts of the experimental group than in the CK group. Gene Ontology (GO) annotation of these differentially expressed proteins revealed that the experimental group was enriched for more entries. Then, through the Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG), the top ten pathways enriched with differentially expressed proteins in the two groups (COS and CK groups) were utilized, and a detailed interpretation of the glycolysis and photosynthesis pathways was provided. Five key proteins, including phosphofructokinase, fructose bisphosphate aldolases, glycer-aldehyde-3-phosphate dehydrogenase, enolase and pyruvate kinase, were identified in the glycolysis pathway. In the photosynthesis pathway, oxygen evolution enhancement proteins, iron redox proteins and ferredoxin-NADPH reductase were the key proteins. The addition of COS led to an increase in the abundance of proteins, a response of rice seedlings to salt stress. COS helped rice seedlings resist salt stress. Furthermore, using COS as biopesticides and biofertilizers can effectively increase the utilization of saline-affected farmland, thereby contributing to the alleviating of the global food crisis.</description>
      <author>Xiaohua Qian, Yaqing He, Lu Zhang, Xianzhen Li, Wei Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25115953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloride&#8208; and Hydrosulfide&#8208;Bound 2Fe Complexes as Models of the Oxygen&#8208;Stable State of [FeFe] Hydrogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408142</link>
      <description>Ming-Hsi Chiang, Yu&#8208;Chiao Liu, Kai&#8208;Ti Chu, Hongru Wang, Gene&#8208;Hsiang Lee, Mei&#8208;Chun Tseng, C.C. Wang, Yih&#8208;Chern Horng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399240729

                [FeFe] hydrogenases demonstrate remarkable catalytic efficiency in hydrogen evolution and oxidation processes. However, susceptibility of enzymes to oxygen&#8208;induced degradation impedes their practical deployment in hydrogen&#8208;production devices and fuel cells. Recent investigations into the oxygen&#8208;stable (Hinact) state of the H&#8208;cluster revealed its inherent capacity to resist oxygen degradation. Herein, we present findings on Cl&#8208;/SH&#8208;bound [2Fe&#8208;2S] complexes, bearing relevance to the oxygen&#8208;stable state within a biological context. A characteristic attribute of these complexes is the terminal Cl&#8722;/SH&#8722; ligation to the iron bearing the CO bridge. Structural analysis of the t&#8208;Cl demonstrates a striking resemblance to the Hinact state of DdHydAB and CbA5H. The t&#8208;Cl/t&#8208;SH exhibit reversible oxidation, with both redox species, electronically, being the first biomimetic analogs to the Htrans and Hinact states. These complexes exhibit notable resistance against oxygen&#8208;induced decomposition, supporting the potential oxygen&#8208;resistant nature of the Htrans and Hinact states. The swift reductive release of the Cl&#8208;/SH&#8208; demonstrates its labile and kinetically controlled binding. The findings garnered from these investigations offer valuable insights into properties of the enzymatic O2&#8208;stable state, and key factors governing deactivation and reactivation conversion. This work contributes to advancement of bio&#8208;inspired molecular catalysts and integration of enzymes and artificial catalysts into H2&#8208;evolution devices and fuel&#8208;cell applications.</description>
      <author>Ming-Hsi Chiang, Yu&#8208;Chiao Liu, Kai&#8208;Ti Chu, Hongru Wang, Gene&#8208;Hsiang Lee, Mei&#8208;Chun Tseng, C.C. Wang, Yih&#8208;Chern Horng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal hematocrit theory - A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00034.2024</link>
      <description>Michal &#352;itina, Heiko Stark, Stefan Schuster, Journal of applied physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399159807

                In humans and higher animals, a trade-off between a sufficiently high concentration of erythrocytes (hematocrit), to bind oxygen and sufficiently low blood viscosity to allow rapid blood flow has been achieved during evolution. The optimal value lies between the extreme cases of pure blood plasma, which cannot practically transport any oxygen, and 100\% hematocrit, which would imply very slow blood flow or none at all. As oxygen delivery to tissues is the main task of the cardiovascular system, it is reasonable to expect that maximum oxygen delivery has been achieved during evolution. Optimal hematocrit theory, based on this optimality principle, has been successful in predicting hematocrit values of about 0.3-0.5, which are indeed observed in humans and many animal species. Similarly, the theory can explain why higher than normal hematocrit, ranging from 0.5 to 0.7, can promote better exertional performance. Here we present a review of theoretical approaches to the calculation of the optimal hematocrit value under different conditions and discuss them in a broad physiological context. Several physiological and medical implications are outlined, e.g. in view of blood doping, temperature adaptation, and life at high altitudes.</description>
      <author>Michal &#352;itina, Heiko Stark, Stefan Schuster</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00034.2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Densely Accessible Fe/Co-Nx Dual-atom Sites Coupled Core-shell Co3Fe7@C as an Efficient Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zinc-air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02444c</link>
      <description>Katam Srinivas, Hesheng Yu, Changhui Zhou, Anran Chen, Ming-Qiang Zhu, Yuanfu Chen, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399144923

                The urgent demand for stable and highly efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction/evolution reactions (ORR/OER) is pivotal in advancing energy conversion and storage technologies. Herein, we introduce a metal-organic...</description>
      <author>Katam Srinivas, Hesheng Yu, Changhui Zhou, Anran Chen, Ming-Qiang Zhu, Yuanfu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02444c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A path towards constraining the evolution of the interstellar medium and
  outflows in the Milky Way using APOGEE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae1362</link>
      <description>Piyush Sharda, Yuan-Sen Ting, Neige Frankel, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399197727

                In recent years, the study of the Milky Way has significantly advanced due to extensive spectroscopic surveys of its stars, complemented by astroseismic and astrometric data. However, it remains disjoint from recent advancements in understanding the physics of the Galactic interstellar medium (ISM). This paper introduces a new model for the chemical evolution of the Milky Way that can be constrained on stellar data, because it combines a state-of-the-art ISM model with a Milky Way stellar disc model. Utilizing a dataset of red clump stars from APOGEE, known for their precise ages and metallicities, we concentrate on the last 6 billion years -- a period marked by Milky Way's secular evolution. We examine the oxygen abundance in the low-$\alpha$ disc stars relative to their ages and birth radii, validating or constraining critical ISM parameters that remain largely unexplored in extragalactic observations. The models that successfully reproduce the radius -- metallicity distribution and the age -- metallicity distribution of stars without violating existing ISM observations indicate a need for modest differential oxygen enrichment in Galactic outflows, meaning that the oxygen abundance of outflows is higher than the local ISM abundance, irrespective of outflow mass loading. The models also suggest somewhat elevated ISM gas velocity dispersion levels over the past 6 billion years compared to galaxies of similar mass. The extra turbulence necessary could result from energy from gas accretion onto the Galaxy, supernovae clustering in the ISM, or increased star formation efficiency per freefall time. This work provides a novel approach to constraining the Galactic ISM and outflows, leveraging the detailed insights available from contemporary Milky Way surveys.</description>
      <author>Piyush Sharda, Yuan-Sen Ting, Neige Frankel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae1362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinG3D: visualizing the spatio-temporal dynamics of clonal evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-024-05813-7</link>
      <description>Alan J. Hu, Awino Maureiq Edith Ojwang, Kayode D. Olumoyin, Katarzyna A. Rejniak, BMC bioinformatics. 25(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399044258

                Abstract Background Cancers are spatially heterogenous, thus their clonal evolution, especially following anti-cancer treatments, depends on where the mutated cells are located within the tumor tissue. For example, cells exposed to different concentrations of drugs, such as cells located near the vessels in contrast to those residing far from the vasculature, can undergo a different evolutionary path. However, classical representations of cell lineage trees do not account for this spatial component of emerging cancer clones. Here, we propose routines to trace spatial and temporal clonal evolution in computer simulations of the tumor evolution models. Results The LinG3D (Lineage Graphs in 3D) is an open-source collection of routines (in MATLAB, Python, and R) that enables spatio-temporal visualization of clonal evolution in a two-dimensional tumor slice from computer simulations of the tumor evolution models. These routines draw traces of tumor clones in both time and space, and may include a projection of a selected microenvironmental factor, such as the drug or oxygen distribution within the tumor, if such a microenvironmental factor is used in the tumor evolution model. The utility of LinG3D has been demonstrated through examples of simulated tumors with different number of clones and, additionally, in experimental colony growth assay. Conclusions This routine package extends the classical lineage trees, that show cellular clone relationships in time, by adding the space component to show the locations of cellular clones within the 2D tumor tissue patch from computer simulations of tumor evolution models.</description>
      <author>Alan J. Hu, Awino Maureiq Edith Ojwang, Kayode D. Olumoyin, Katarzyna A. Rejniak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-024-05813-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulate local chemical order to achieve high strength and ductility in TiZrNbVAl lightweight high entropy alloys via adding oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2024.146721</link>
      <description>Jiaxiang Cui, Bang Dou, Manling Sui, Nan Cui, Benpeng Wang, Shihai Sun, Hongnian Cai, Liang Wang, Yunfei Xue, Materials science and engineering. A, Structural materials: proporties, microstructures and processing/Materials science &amp; engineering. A, Structural materials: properties, microstructure and processing. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399035862

                TiZrNbVAl lightweight high-entropy alloys (LHEAs) with body-centered cubic (BCC) structure have received extensive attention due to their low density and considerable mechanical properties. And the mechanical properties of these LHEAs can be further improved by adjusting the local chemical order (LCO). Here, we report a strategy for regulating LCOs in TiZrNbVAl LHEAs by adding oxygen. The results showed that the yield strength of LHEA increased from 787.8 MPa to 1029.5 MPa after oxygen addition. Moreover, the microstructure evolution proves that LCOs is conducive to promoting the transition of dislocation from plane slip, which is easy to produce stress concentration, to multistage slip, which improves the homogenizing deformation ability, and increasing the ductility from 12.8% to 20.9%, which is an increase of &#8764;63%. Our work provides a paradigm for achieving outstanding strength-ductility tradeoff in BCC-LHEAs via O doping.</description>
      <author>Jiaxiang Cui, Bang Dou, Manling Sui, Nan Cui, Benpeng Wang, Shihai Sun, Hongnian Cai, Liang Wang, Yunfei Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2024.146721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Lower Eyelid in Basal Cell Carcinoma Case with Adjunctive Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy: A Case Report</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35790/msj.v7i1.54895</link>
      <description>Yulius A. M. Chietra, Mendy Hatibie, Ramli Dali, Medical Scope Journal (MSJ). 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399265467

                Abstract: Basal cell carcinomas (BCCs) are the most common cancers in humans, caused by exposure to ultraviolet light and are associated with PTCH1 gene mutation. Its incidence rate significantly increases per year especially in elderly people. Several modalities are available for BCC treatment but surgery is still considered as the gold standard. Oxygen is mandatory for almost all wound healing processes, and oxygen substitution can be delivered in the form of hyperbaric oxygen (HBO) therapy. We presented a 70 years old woman with a major complaint of a tumor located in the left infrapalpebral region, below the left lower lash line with 5 years of evolution. Patient had clinical presentation of solid nodular basal cell carcinoma which was the most common clinical subtype. Patient was diagnosed as having BCC based on history taking, clinical findings, and histopathological examination. Surgical wide excision, skin flap, and HBO as the adjunctive therapy were performed on this patient. With these techniques, healing time was reduced, complications rates were low, and cosmetic outcome was much better. In conclusion, closing defects of BCC case with surgical wide excision and flap yields a remarkable outcome and an adjunctive HBO therapy after surgery optimizes the oxygenation, thus, the healing potential of tissue prior to surgery, and accelerates wound healing post operatively. A good result with short healing duration was observed. Keywords: basal cell carcinoma; hyperbaric oxygen therapy; flap; wound healing</description>
      <author>Yulius A. M. Chietra, Mendy Hatibie, Ramli Dali</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35790/msj.v7i1.54895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 in three waves in a tertiary referral hospital in Belgium: a comparison of patient characteristics, management, and outcome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12985-024-02360-8</link>
      <description>A De Paepe, Erika Vlieghe, Nele Brusselaers, Patrick Soentjens, Caroline Theunissen, Isabel Brosius, Jeroen Grouwels, Lida van Petersen, Hanne Van Tiggelen, Walter Verbrugghe, Philippe G. Jorens, Th&#233;r&#232;se S. Lapperre, Kristel Peeters, Griet Vermeulen, Sabrina H. van Ierssel, Virology journal. 21(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399160099

                Abstract Purpose Few studies have compared patient characteristics, clinical management, and outcome of patients with COVID-19 between the different epidemic waves. In this study, we describe patient characteristics, treatment, and outcome of patients admitted for COVID-19 in the Antwerp University Hospital over the first three epidemic waves of 2020&#8211;2021. Methods Retrospective observational study of COVID-19 patients in a Belgian tertiary referral hospital. All adult patients with COVID-19, hospitalized between February 29, 2020, and June 30, 2021, were included. Standardized routine medical data was collected from patient records. Risk factors were assessed with multivariable logistic regression. Results We included 722 patients, during the first ( n = 179), second ( n = 347) and third ( n = 194) wave. We observed the lowest disease severity at admission during the first wave, and more elderly and comorbid patients during the second wave. Throughout the subsequent waves we observed an increasing use of corticosteroids and high-flow oxygen therapy. In spite of increasing number of complications throughout the subsequent waves, mortality decreased each wave (16.6%,15.6% 11.9% in 1st, 2nd and 3rd wave respectively). C-reactive protein above 150 mg/L was predictive for the need for intensive care unit admission (odds ratio (OR) 3.77, 95% confidence interval (CI) 2.32&#8211;6.15). A Charlson comorbidity index &#8805; 5 (OR 5.68, 95% CI 2.54&#8211;12.70) and interhospital transfers (OR 3.78, 95% CI 2.05&#8211;6.98) were associated with a higher mortality. Conclusions We observed a reduction in mortality each wave, despite increasing comorbidity. Evolutions in patient management such as high-flow oxygen therapy on regular wards and corticosteroid use may explain this favorable evolution.</description>
      <author>A De Paepe, Erika Vlieghe, Nele Brusselaers, Patrick Soentjens, Caroline Theunissen, Isabel Brosius, Jeroen Grouwels, Lida van Petersen, Hanne Van Tiggelen, Walter Verbrugghe, Philippe G. Jorens, Th&#233;r&#232;se S. Lapperre, Kristel Peeters, Griet Vermeulen, Sabrina H. van Ierssel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12985-024-02360-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal and chemical expansion of layered oxygen-deficient double perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29235/1561-8331-2024-60-2-95-104</link>
      <description>&#1040;. I. Klyndyuk, Ya. Yu. Zhuravleva, Vesc&#236; Nacy&#226;nal&#697;naj akad&#232;m&#236;&#236; navuk Belarus&#236;. Sery&#226; h&#236;m&#236;&#269;nyh navuk. 60(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399139045

                Layered oxygen-deficient double perovskites (ODP) based on the rare-earth elements (REE), barium and 3 d -metals (Fe, Co, Cu etc.) are characterized by high values of electrical conductivity and high electrochemical activity in oxygen reduction reaction, and are considered as prospective cathode materials for intermediate-temperature solid oxide fuel cells (SOFC) on the base of proton- and oxygen-ion conducting solid electrolytes (SE). Effective cathode materials should be thermomechanically compatible with materials of SE, which t&#1072;kes place when the values of their thermal expansion coefficients (TEC) are close to each other. Due to this the study of thermal expansion of ODP as well as the isotation of different contributions in it (thermal, chemical, spin etc.), is of considerable interest. In this work using dilatometric method the thermal expansion of NdBa 1&#8211;x SrxFeCo 0,5 Cu0,5O 6&#8722;&#948; (0.0 &#8804; &#1093; &#8804; 1.0) (NBSFCC) ODP was studied using dilatometric method. It was established that the values of average linear thermal expansion coefficient (LTEC) (&#945;) of the samples sharply increased from (15.1&#8211;16.2) &#183; 10 &#8211;6 K &#8211;1 at &#1058; &lt; 630&#8211;920 K to (18.9&#8211;23.5) 10 &#8211;6 K &#8211;1 at &#1058; &gt; 630&#8211;920 K due to the evolution of weaklybonded oxygen from the samples. Values of &#945; in the low-temperature region increase with increasing of values of their oxygen nonstoichiometry index (&#948;), and in the high-temperature one increase with the x increasing due to the increment of chemical contribution in the samples expansion. Based of the results of dilatometry, thermogravimetry, and iodometry, the thermal and chemical contributions in the expansion &#1086;n NBSFCC were isolated, and the effect of crystal structure, cationic and anionic composition of NBSFCC ODP on the values of their thermal and linear chemical expansion coefficient (LCEC, &#945; &#948; ) was investigated. It was found, that LCEC values of the samples sharply increased from (8.6&#8211;11.8) &#183; 10 &#8211;3 at (&#1093; &lt; 0.5) to (12.6&#8211;15.8) &#183; 10 &#8211;3 at (&#1093; &gt; 0.5) when transition from ordered tetragonal (&#1093; &lt; 0.5) to disordered cubic (&#1093; &gt; 0.5) phase took place. It was shown, that dependences of LTEC and LCEC of NBSFCC phases on their crystal structure and chemical compositions obtained in this work are in good accordance with the analogous dependences determined earlier for the ODP of other types.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. I. Klyndyuk, Ya. Yu. Zhuravleva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29235/1561-8331-2024-60-2-95-104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Face&#8208;Dependent Behavior of Single&#8208;Atom Pt: Construct of SA&#8208;FLP Dual Active Sites for Efficient NO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Detection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402038</link>
      <description>Yucheng Ou, B. L. Wang, Nana Xu, Quzhi Song, Tian&#8208;Qing Liu, Hui Xu, Hualong Wang, Kunjie Wang, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141399

                Abstract The strong potential of platinum single atom (Pt SA ) in gas sensor technology is primarily attributed to its high atomic economy. Nevertheless, it is imperative to conduct further exploration to understand the impact of Pt SA on the active sites. In this study, the evolution of Pt SA on (100)CeO 2 and (111)CeO 2 is examined, revealing notable disparities in the position and activity of surface Pt SA on different crystal planes. The Pt SA in (100)CeO 2 surface can enhance the stability of Ce 3+ and construct a frustrated Lewis pair (FLP) to form a double active site by combining the steric hindrance effect of oxygen vacancies, which increases the response value from 1.8 to 27 and reduce the response&#8208;recovery time from 140&#8211;192 s to 25&#8211;26 s toward five ppm NO 2 at room temperature. Conversely, Pt SA tends to bind to terminal oxygen on the surface of (111)CeO 2 and become an independent reaction site. The response value of Pt SA &#8208;(111)CeO 2 surface only increased from 1.6 to 3.8. This research underscores the correlation between single atoms and crystal plane effects, laying the groundwork for designing and synthesizing ultra&#8208;stable and efficient gas sensors.</description>
      <author>Yucheng Ou, B. L. Wang, Nana Xu, Quzhi Song, Tian&#8208;Qing Liu, Hui Xu, Hualong Wang, Kunjie Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exciton Dissociation into Charge Carriers in Porphyrinic Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Light&#8208;Assisted Li&#8208;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405440</link>
      <description>Bo Wen, Yaohui Huang, Zhuoliang Jiang, Yuzhe Wang, Weibo Hua, Sylvio Indris, Fujun Li, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399041581

                Abstract Light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries exhibit a high round&#8208;trip efficiency attributable to the assistance of light&#8208;generated electrons and holes in oxygen reduction and evolution reactions. Nonetheless, the excitonic effect arising from Coulomb interaction between electrons and holes impedes carrier separation, thus hindering efficient utilization of photo&#8208;energy. Herein, porphyrinic metal&#8208;organic frameworks with (Fe 2 Ni)O(COO) 6 clusters were used as photocathodes to accelerate exciton dissociation into charge carriers for light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries. The coupling of Ni 3d and Fe 3d orbitals boosts ligand&#8208;to&#8208;metal cluster charge transfer, and hence drives exciton dissociation and activates O 2 for superoxide ( &#8226; O 2 &#8722; ) radicals, rather than singlet oxygen ( 1 O 2 ) under photoexcitation. These enable the light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries with a low total overvoltage of 0.28 V and round&#8208;trip efficiency of 92% under light irradiation of 100 mW cm &#8722;2 . This work highlights the excitonic effect in photoelectrochemical processes and provides insights into photocathode design for light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Bo Wen, Yaohui Huang, Zhuoliang Jiang, Yuzhe Wang, Weibo Hua, Sylvio Indris, Fujun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elaborate construction of honeycomb-like porous carbon with embedment of N-doped carbon nanotubes as efficient electrocatalyst for zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119299</link>
      <description>Ao Xie, Xuefeng Tai, Yujing Guo, Jinyuan Miao, D. Liu, Rufei Zhang, Linting Cheng, Zemin Zhao, Yang Tang, Xiaojin Yang, Junqing Pan, Pingyu Wan, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399202916

                Devising the synthesis strategy and uncovering the evolution mechanism of carbon-based materials are critical to the development of efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysts for renewable energy storage systems. This study reports a hierarchical ORR electrocatalyst, Co@N-CNTs/3DHC, which features ultrafine cobalt nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen-doped carbon nanotubes (Co@N-CNTs) and Co@N-CNTs firmly anchored in the nano-chambers of a three-dimensional honeycomb-like porous carbon (3DHC). The synthesis strategy of Co@N-CNTs/3DHC involves the initial construction of a precursor, followed by controllable pyrolysis step. Based on detailed analysis of both evolved gases and carbonized products of precursors, the evolution mechanism of Co@N-CNTs/3DHC is specifically proposed. Prompted by the electron reconfiguration, extensive reaction interface and fast mass-transfer pathway, the as-synthesized hierarchical Co@N-CNTs/3DHC displays superior ORR activity in alkaline media (0.88 V of half-wave potential) compared to commercial Pt/C. Impressively, zinc-air battery equipped with Co@N-CNTs/3DHC cathode presents outstanding discharge voltage and exceptional stability. This work highlights a unique perspective on the synthesis strategy and growth mechanism of Co@N-CNTs@3DHC toward creation of hierarchical 3D carbon-based composite for advanced electrochemical energy devices.</description>
      <author>Ao Xie, Xuefeng Tai, Yujing Guo, Jinyuan Miao, D. Liu, Rufei Zhang, Linting Cheng, Zemin Zhao, Yang Tang, Xiaojin Yang, Junqing Pan, Pingyu Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barcoding, structural, and genetic variation of morphologically adopted polychaetes (Annelida: Paronidae, Lumberineridae, Spionidae) using mitochondrial COI gene sequences from the Bay of Bengal shelf including Oxygen Minimum Zone</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsma.2024.103613</link>
      <description>Seerangan Manokaran, Chinnamani PrasannaKumar, Kapuli Gani Mohamed Thameemul Ansari, Thadickal V. Joydas, Karuppasamy P. Manikandan, K.M. Aarif, S. Raja, P. Ramasamy, T. Sudhagar, Regional studies in marine science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399206627

                The structural and genetic variation of morphologically adapted polychaetes from the Bay of Bengal continental shelf (North Indian Ocean) including Oxygen Minimum Zone (OMZ) are described. The density and biomass of polychaetes such as Aricidea curviseta (Paronidae), Lumberineris aberrans (Lumberineridae), Prionospio malmgreni, Paraprionospio pinnata, and Prinospio sexoculata (Spionidae) were significantly differed (P&lt;0.05) in depths (Non-Oxygen Minimum Zone - NOMZ and OMZ), transects and cruises. The response and morphometric measures of branchiae structures were inconsistent between OMZ and NOMZ depths. The species Aricidea curviseta (OR450003 - OR450005), Paraprionospio pinnata (OR436939, OR436941, OR436952 and OR436953), and Prionospio malmgreni (OR436956, OR436957, OR436945, OR436946, OR436947) were barcoded for the first time. The Maximum likelihood tree analysis indicated low ranges of similarity indices among the NOMZ (0.255 - 0.446%) and OMZ (0.257 - 0.443) depths. The total number of mutations and polymorphic sites were 395 and 268, with low haplotypes (12) and nucleotide diversity (among depths: 0.228 - 0.246, and regions: 0.826 - 0.100). The groups of haplotypes were also independent of the geographical locations. The AMOVA revealed that the variation among populations was low (regions: -5%, and depths: -1.86%) and within populations were high (regions:105.45% and depths: 101.86%, respectively). The nMDS indicated that the oxygen factor significantly separated the distribution of density and biomass of polychaetes within transects (density: biomass: F=3.57) and cruises (biomass: F=2.41, P&lt;0.05). Generally, 70-80% of the total variation was described in four pCCAs by salinity (PSU), pressure, Co, Cu, Fe, Mn, Ni, Pb, Zn, Hg (ppm), and clay (%) with NOMZ and OMZ depths, different cruises, transects and or the interaction between this three. OMZs might not influence the genetic variations. Several additional studies, such as physiological, metabolic, enzymatic, and biochemical, are also be essential for understanding the ecology and evolution of organisms in this habitat.</description>
      <author>Seerangan Manokaran, Chinnamani PrasannaKumar, Kapuli Gani Mohamed Thameemul Ansari, Thadickal V. Joydas, Karuppasamy P. Manikandan, K.M. Aarif, S. Raja, P. Ramasamy, T. Sudhagar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsma.2024.103613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-temperature Oxidation mechanism and microstructure evolution of Cr-Mn-Si alloyed steel oxidized by Fe2O3 contained in mold flux</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.438</link>
      <description>Fengkang Wang, Wanlin Wang, Jie Du, Gao Qing, Il Sohn, Jie Zeng, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399242141

                The high-temperature oxidation behavior of Cr-Mn-Si alloyed steel by Fe2O3 contained mold flux in high temperatures, and its effect on microstructure evolution were investigated in detail by TEM, EBSD, CLSM, SEM, and XPS. A novel oxidation mechanism was firstly revealed that the Fe2O3 in mold flux melts during high temperatures plays a role of oxidizing alloyed steels by the released free oxygen ions (O2&#8722;) from the transformation of Fe2O3 (Fe3+) to FeO (Fe2+). The formed oxidized dots within the oxide layer changed from SiO2 and MnSiO3 to MnCr2O4 spinel phases by increasing the content of Fe2O3 in the mold flux. Notably, the amorphous SiO2 was discovered in the core region of MnSiO3 phase due to its selective oxidative behavior in high temperatures. This research provides conclusive evidence that the small size MnSiO3 oxides can be acted as a nucleation core for the refinement of austenite grains through in-situ observation.</description>
      <author>Fengkang Wang, Wanlin Wang, Jie Du, Gao Qing, Il Sohn, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of humidity and oxygen on friction, wear and durability of a polymer-bonded molybdenum disulfide (MoS2)-based dry film lubricant (DFL) coating system in large amplitude fretting.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.wear.2024.205426</link>
      <description>E. Laolu-Balogun, Steven J. Owen, Scott A. Read, P.H. Shipway, K.T. Voisey, Wear. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399189544

                Investigations into effects of humidity and oxygen on a polymer-bonded MoS2-based dry film lubricant (DFL) coating, on grit-blasted Ti-6Al-4V using a cylinder-on-flat configuration, are reported. Sustained low friction and low wear occurred in both low-humidity air and low-humidity argon, producing significant extension of fretting wear lifetimes. A cracked-paved structure was observed in low-humidity air which was not observed in low-humidity argon. The Mo-DFL coatings were observed to be highly sensitive to humidity. As humidity increased, a notable rise of friction and wear ensued which reduced the system lifetime. Different friction evolution was observed in high-humidity air and high-humidity argon before failure, with a short-lived but established low friction phase in high-humidity air and a consistent high friction phase in high-humidity argon. Although oxidation of the MoS2 to MoO3 is a key process of degradation of DFLs of this type, this oxidation reaction does not operate in the absence of humidity.</description>
      <author>E. Laolu-Balogun, Steven J. Owen, Scott A. Read, P.H. Shipway, K.T. Voisey</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.wear.2024.205426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arousal as a universal embedding for spatiotemporal brain dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.njvyzq</link>
      <description>Ryan V. Raut, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4399071520

                Neural activity in awake organisms shows widespread and spatiotemporally diverse correlations with behavioral and physiological measurements. We propose that this covariation reflects in part the dynamics of a unified, arousal-related process that regulates brain-wide physiology on the timescale of seconds. Taken together with theoretical foundations in dynamical systems, this interpretation leads us to a surprising prediction: that a single, scalar measurement of arousal (e.g., pupil diameter) should suffice to reconstruct the continuous evolution of multimodal, spatiotemporal measurements of large-scale brain physiology. To test this hypothesis, we perform multimodal, cortex-wide optical imaging and behavioral monitoring in awake mice. We demonstrate that spatiotemporal measurements of neuronal calcium, metabolism, and blood-oxygen can be accurately and parsimoniously modeled from a low-dimensional state-space reconstructed from the time history of pupil diameter. Extending this framework to behavioral and electrophysiological measurements from the Allen Brain Observatory, we demonstrate the ability to integrate diverse experimental data into a unified generative model via mappings from an intrinsic arousal manifold. Our results support the hypothesis that spontaneous, spatially structured fluctuations in brain-wide physiology&#8212;widely interpreted to reflect regionally-specific neural communication&#8212;are in large part reflections of an arousal-related process. This enriched view of arousal dynamics has broad implications for interpreting observations of brain, body, and behavior as measured across modalities, contexts, and scales.</description>
      <author>Ryan V. Raut</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.njvyzq</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Catalytic Activity of Magnetic Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/magnetochemistry10060040</link>
      <description>Ian Shuttleworth, Magnetochemistry. 10(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399073281

                High-performance catalysts for the oxygen reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions (ORR and HER, respectively) are highly sought-after, particularly with the commitment of numerous agencies to the removal of conventional gas vehicles in the next few decades. Surprisingly little focus has been placed on the development of magnetic models to describe these systems. The current work will review the current understanding of surface heterogeneous catalysis across select magnetic surfaces, with attention focused on studies involving extended surfaces, which inherently are more accessible to fundamental analysis than the more applied nanoparticle systems. However, even the most up-to-date magnetic variants of this theory have focused on the tight binding limit of the d-band model. In this limit, the reactivity of the surface is governed by the position of the center of the d-band, and the model does not account for the higher moments of the d-band, such as the width, asymmetry, and modality. A summary of the theory supporting this analysis will be presented, along with a summary of the current literature on this level of analysis. The review will then conclude with a discussion of suggested directions for future investigations.</description>
      <author>Ian Shuttleworth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/magnetochemistry10060040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directional Growth and Density Modulation of Single&#8208;Atom Platinum for Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406650</link>
      <description>Xinyang Liu, Yuxuan Zhou, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Zhijun Wang, Liangyong Jia, Mengyuan Li, K&#232; Yang, Jinchen Fan, Weiwei Yang, Guisheng Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399240926

                Dispersion of single atoms (SAs) in the host is important for optimizing catalytic activity. Herein, we propose a novel strategy to tune oxygen vacancies in CeO2&#8208;X directionally anchoring the single atom platinum (PtSA), which is uniformly dispersed on the rGO. The catalyst's performance for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) can be enhanced by controlling different densities of CeO2&#8208;X in rGO. The PtSA performs best optimally densified and loaded on homogeneous and moderately densified CeO2&#8208;X/rGO (PtSA&#8208;M&#8208;CeO2&#8208;X/rGO). It exhibited high activity in HER with an overpotential of 25 mV at 0.5 M H2SO4 and 33 mV at 1 KOH than that of almost reported electrocatalysts. Furthermore, it exhibited stability for 90 hours at &#8722;100 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 KOH and &#8722;150 mA cm&#8722;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 conditions, respectively. Through comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations, the suitable dispersion density of PtSA on the defects of CeO2&#8208;X with more active sites gives the potential for practical applications. This research paves the way for developing single&#8208;atom catalysts with exceptional catalytic activity and stability, holding promise in advanced green energy conversion through defects engineering.</description>
      <author>Xinyang Liu, Yuxuan Zhou, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Zhijun Wang, Liangyong Jia, Mengyuan Li, K&#232; Yang, Jinchen Fan, Weiwei Yang, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The evolution process and internal corrosion mechanisms of hot salt corrosion on TC11 titanium alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.05.246</link>
      <description>Mengyao Li, Daoxin Liu, Jing Yang, Xingchen Xu, Kaifa Fan, Xiaohua Zhang, Journal of materials research and technology/Journal of Materials Research and Technology. 30(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399116593

                This study investigates the evolution process of hot corrosion in bi-phase Ti-6.5Al-1.5Zr-3.5Mo-0.3Si (TC11) titanium alloy induced by sodium chloride (NaCl). Through morphological progression and elemental distribution analyses, the integrated processes involved in the onset of internal corrosion during hot corrosion are elucidated, revealing intriguing phenomena that deviate from conventional mechanisms. The development of corrosion can be divided into three stages: First there is the rapid growth of the external corrosion layer induced by Cl; then a Cl and O induced internal corrosion is initiated when the external corrosion layer reaches a critical thickness, at the same time the external corrosion decreases; finally, the chlorine pressure is too low to act as the corrosion depth increases, O becomes a major contributor to deep internal corrosion, leading to O induced internal corrosion. Significant interphase selective corrosion was observed in this internal corrosion zone: the &#946; phase was corroded while the &#945; phase remained uncorroded, challenging the prevailing notion that the &#946; phase is more corrosion-resistant in titanium alloys. This distinctive phenomenon results from the differences in oxygen solubility, element diffusion rates and the reactivity between the &#945; and &#946; phases.</description>
      <author>Mengyao Li, Daoxin Liu, Jing Yang, Xingchen Xu, Kaifa Fan, Xiaohua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.05.246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy, 3D micro-CT and Semiquantitative Elemental Microanalysis in Common carp vertebrae (Cyprinus carpio; Linnaeus, 1758)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4442332/v1</link>
      <description>Paulo Salinas, Antonia Naciff, Felipe Navarro, Florencia Vicencio, Carlos Sandoval, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399159696

                Abstract The study describes the anatomy vertebrae of Common Carp (Cyprinus carpio; Linnaeus, 1758) using 3D micro-CT and Semiquantitative Elemental Microanalysis (EDX), which helps to understand the ontogeny and factors that determine the biomechanics of bones in wild fish. The study of Common carp vertebrae revealed a complex and heterogeneous structure, with a variety of components contributing to their function and stability. The vertebral bodies were composed of lamellar trabeculae and internal hollow spaces, while the neural and hemal arches were composed of bony trabeculae and connected by a lace-like structure. The results of EDX analysis demonstrated the presence of oxygen, nitrogen, sodium, carbon, magnesium, and chlorine, among others. The calcium to phosphorus ratio was within the ranges described in teleost, suggesting good bone health. The presence of magnesium, sodium, potassium, chlorine, and nitrogen is due to their essential role in different biological processes. In addition, a difference was observed between the trabeculae present in the vertebrae of the abdominal and caudal segments, suggesting a relationship between the density of each bone and its function. These findings contribute to the understanding of the structure and function of vertebrae in wild Common carp and may have implications for understanding the evolution of the vertebral column in fish in general.</description>
      <author>Paulo Salinas, Antonia Naciff, Felipe Navarro, Florencia Vicencio, Carlos Sandoval</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4442332/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directional Growth and Density Modulation of Single&#8208;Atom Platinum for Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406650</link>
      <description>Xinyang Liu, Yuxuan Zhou, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Zhijun Wang, Liangyong Jia, Mengyuan Li, K&#232; Yang, Jinchen Fan, Weiwei Yang, Guisheng Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239500

                Dispersion of single atoms (SAs) in the host is important for optimizing catalytic activity. Herein, we propose a novel strategy to tune oxygen vacancies in CeO2&#8208;X directionally anchoring the single atom platinum (PtSA), which is uniformly dispersed on the rGO. The catalyst's performance for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) can be enhanced by controlling different densities of CeO2&#8208;X in rGO. The PtSA performs best optimally densified and loaded on homogeneous and moderately densified CeO2&#8208;X/rGO (PtSA&#8208;M&#8208;CeO2&#8208;X/rGO). It exhibited high activity in HER with an overpotential of 25 mV at 0.5 M H2SO4 and 33 mV at 1 KOH than that of almost reported electrocatalysts. Furthermore, it exhibited stability for 90 hours at &#8722;100 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 KOH and &#8722;150 mA cm&#8722;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 conditions, respectively. Through comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations, the suitable dispersion density of PtSA on the defects of CeO2&#8208;X with more active sites gives the potential for practical applications. This research paves the way for developing single&#8208;atom catalysts with exceptional catalytic activity and stability, holding promise in advanced green energy conversion through defects engineering.</description>
      <author>Xinyang Liu, Yuxuan Zhou, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Zhijun Wang, Liangyong Jia, Mengyuan Li, K&#232; Yang, Jinchen Fan, Weiwei Yang, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An earliest Ediacaran oxygenation episode in the Wilpena Group, Adelaide Superbasin, South Australia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.precamres.2024.107433</link>
      <description>Kelsey G. Lamothe, Malcolm W. Wallace, Ashleigh v.S. Hood, Catherine Rose, Precambrian research. 409(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399149629

                The first appearance of animals during the Ediacaran is arguably related to an increase in oceanic oxygenation during this time. However, there is considerable ambiguity in the global record of Ediacaran oxygenation, making it difficult to assess the potential links between oxygen and metazoan evolution. Here, we examine the earliest Ediacaran Nuccaleena Formation cap dolomite and basal Brachina Formation of the Adelaide Superbasin, South Australia, to determine the redox landscape in which these units were deposited. Red shales are present at the base of the Brachina Formation (lower Moolooloo Siltstone Member) over much of the Adelaide Superbasin but these transition laterally into green shales in the north, correlating with a facies transition into a deeper water setting. Fibrous dolomite cements within sheet cavities of the Nuccaleena Formation cap dolomite display evidence of a primary marine origin. Cathodoluminescence microscopy and laser ablation ICP-MS trace element analysis of these marine dolomite cements indicates a transition from an oxic environment in the south (with low Fe, Mn, and a Ce anomaly) to an anoxic (ferruginous) setting in the north (with high Fe, Mn and no Ce anomaly). This cap carbonate trace element geochemistry is spatially consistent with the overlying red to green shale transition in the basal Brachina Formation. Together, these data suggest the existence of a deep-water chemocline in this basin, separating an oxic upper water column from a ferruginous deeper water mass. This oxic interval directly post-dates the end-Cryogenian Marinoan Glaciation and is synchronous with an earliest Ediacaran oxygenation event previously described from South China. This evidence from the Adelaide Superbasin provides direct evidence for an earliest Ediacaran oxic water mass penetrating to a substantial paleodepth. The synchronous development of oxic intervals in both Australia and South China supports the notion of a globally developed oceanic oxygenation event and is consistent with the hypothesis that Ediacaran continental margin settings were periodically bathed in oxic water, conducive to the evolution of metazoans.</description>
      <author>Kelsey G. Lamothe, Malcolm W. Wallace, Ashleigh v.S. Hood, Catherine Rose</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.precamres.2024.107433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and Evolution In Silico Studies Unlock the h4-HPPD C-Terminal Tail Gating Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines12061196</link>
      <description>Alfonso Trezza, Ancuta Birgauan, Michela Geminiani, Anna Visibelli, Annalisa Santucci, Biomedicines. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399105635

                The enzyme 4-hydroxyphenylpyruvate dioxygenase (4-HPPD) is involved in the catabolism of the amino acid tyrosine in organisms such as bacteria, plants, and animals. It catalyzes the conversion of 4-hydroxyphenylpyruvate to a homogenisate in the presence of molecular oxygen and Fe(II) as a cofactor. This enzyme represents a key step in the biosynthesis of important compounds, and its activity deficiency leads to severe, rare autosomal recessive disorders, like tyrosinemia type III and hawkinsinuria, for which no cure is currently available. The 4-HPPD C-terminal tail plays a crucial role in the enzyme catalysis/gating mechanism, ensuring the integrity of the active site for catalysis through fine regulation of the C-terminal tail conformation. However, despite growing interest in the 4-HPPD catalytic mechanism and structure, the gating mechanism remains unclear. Furthermore, the absence of the whole 3D structure makes the bioinformatic approach the only possible study to define the enzyme structure/molecular mechanism. Here, wild-type 4-HPPD and its mutants were deeply dissected by applying a comprehensive bioinformatics/evolution study, and we showed for the first time the entire molecular mechanism and regulation of the enzyme gating process, proposing the full-length 3D structure of human 4-HPPD and two novel key residues involved in the 4-HPPD C-terminal tail conformational change.</description>
      <author>Alfonso Trezza, Ancuta Birgauan, Michela Geminiani, Anna Visibelli, Annalisa Santucci</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines12061196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genetic isolation and metabolic complexity of an Antarctic subglacial microbiome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4392950/v1</link>
      <description>Ok-Sun Kim, Ki-Hwan Hwang, Hanbyul Lee, Soyeon Kim, Ahnna Cho, Christina Davis, Brent C. Christner, John C. Priscu, Kyung Mo Kim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399247798

                Abstract Microbes inhabiting and evolving in aquatic ecosystems at the base of polar ice sheets subsist under energy-limited conditions while in relative isolation from surface gene pools and their common ancestral populations of origin. Samples recently obtained from the base of West Antarctic Ice Sheet (WAIS) allowed us to examine evolutionary relationships of and identify metabolic pathways in microbial genomes recovered from the Mercer Subglacial Lake (SLM) ecosystem. We obtained 1,374 single-cell amplified genomes from individual bacterial and archaeal cells that were isolated from samples of SLM&#8217;s water column and sediments. Genome-based taxonomic classification coherently identified nearly all of the subglacial microorganisms as new species or novel taxonomic groups, and phylogenomic analyses showed evidence for genetically isolation of the microbial populations from marine and surface biomes. Comparative genomic analysis revealed a lake ecosystem exhibiting a range of metabolisms to oxidize various organic and inorganic compounds via aerobic or anerobic respiration. Network construction identified two distinct organotrophic and chemolithotrophic metabolic guilds that may operate alternatively depending on oxygen availability. Our SAG data imply substantial metabolic flexibility in the microbial assemblage characterized, reveal key energy generating strategies in the subglacial ecosystem, and provide a framework to assess microbial evolution beneath WAIS.</description>
      <author>Ok-Sun Kim, Ki-Hwan Hwang, Hanbyul Lee, Soyeon Kim, Ahnna Cho, Christina Davis, Brent C. Christner, John C. Priscu, Kyung Mo Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4392950/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase Engineering and Dispersion Stabilization of Cobalt toward Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310499</link>
      <description>Chao Zhang, Yihang Luo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399069290

                Abstract Phase engineering is promising to increase the intrinsic activity of the catalyst toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, the polymorphism interface is unstable due to the presence of metastable phases. Herein, phase engineering and dispersion stabilization are applied simultaneously to boost the HER activity of cobalt without sacrificing the stability. A fast and facile approach (plasma cathodic electro deposition) is developed to prepare cobalt film with a hetero&#8208;phase structure. The polymorphs of cobalt are realized through reduced stacking fault energy due to the doping of Mo, and the high temperature treatment resulted from the plasma discharge. Meanwhile, homogeneously dispersed oxide/carbide nanoparticles are produced from the reaction of plasma&#8208;induced oxygen/carbon atoms with electro&#8208;deposited metal. The existence of rich polymorphism interface and oxide/carbide help to facilitate H 2 production by the tuning of electronic structure and the increase of active sites. Furthermore, oxide/carbide dispersoid effectively prevents the phase transition through a pinning effect on the grain boundary. As&#8208;prepared Co&#8208;hybrid/CoO_MoC exhibits both high HER activity and robust stability (44 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , Tafel slope of 53.2 mV dec &#8722;1 , no degradation after 100 h test). The work reported here provides an alternate approach to the design of advanced HER catalysts for real application.</description>
      <author>Chao Zhang, Yihang Luo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ore-forming fluid evolution of the Yechangping Mo-W deposit, Qinling Orogen: A case study of the Dabie-type porphyry system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106101</link>
      <description>Po-Cheng Huang, Nan Qi, Jie Yu, Jincao Yao, Zhiwei Qiu, Yanjing Chen, Ore geology reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399142809

                Dabie-type porphyry Mo deposits have recently emerged as a distinct subtype of porphyry Mo deposits, but questions remain about the magmatic-hydrothermal fluid evolution in the formation of this type deposit. Here, well-developed fluid inclusions in quartz phenocrysts, unidirectional solidification textures (UST) and quartz veins in the Yechangping porphyry Mo-W deposit, Qinling Orogen, completely record the magmatic-hydrothermal mineralization process. The characteristics and evolution of the ore-forming fluid in this deposit are investigated through petrography, microthermometry, and laser Raman spectroscopy analysis of fluid inclusions at different stages in order to improve our understanding of the fluid evolution in the genesis of Dabie-type porphyry Mo deposit. The mineralization process in the porphyry-type orebody can be divided into three periods and five stages: (1) magmatic period, including quartz phenocrysts (stage 1); (2) magmatic-hydrothermal transition period, including UST (stage 2); (3) hydrothermal period, including quartz &#177; K-feldspar veins (stage 3), quartz-molybdenite veins (stage 4), and calcite &#177; quartz veins (stage 5), where stage 4 is the main ore-forming stage. The fluid inclusions in quartz and calcite can be recognized as pure CO2 (PC type), CO2-H2O (C type), daughter minerals-bearing (S type), and H2O (WV type and WL type) inclusions. Ore-forming fluid is initially high temperature, high salinity, and CO2-rich, belonging to the H2O-CO2-NaCl (&#177;KCl) system suggested by the fluid inclusions identified in UST. The estimated lithostatic pressures of stage 1 range from 284&#8211;362 MPa, corresponding to depths of 10.3 to 13.2 km, which are consistent with the formation depth of the underlying magma chamber. The presence of UST in stage 2 indicates that the magma was saturated with fluid. Due to the fluctuating pressure (123&#8211;260 MPa) in UST of stage 2, fluid immiscibility happened soon after the fluid exsolution and is inferred to occur between the CO2-rich and aqueous phases. Then, the fluid boiling and mixing occurred in stages 3 and 4, respectively. The estimated pressures of stage 4 which represent the main mineralization stage range from 45&#8211;175 MPa, corresponding to depths of 4.6&#8211;6.4 km. The immiscibility of CO2, along with the fluid mixing-induced cooling and dilution, caused an increase in pH and a decrease in oxygen fugacity, which serves as a crucial mechanism for Mo mineralization at the Yechangping deposit. Stage 5 is characterized by low temperature (185&#8211;309 &#176;C) and low salinity (2.9&#8211;8.7 wt% NaCl equiv.). The primary high temperature, high salinity, CO2-rich fluids, and relatively deep ore-forming depth suggest that the Yechangping deposit is a typical example of Dabie-type porphyry deposits. The characteristics of fluids and the variation in estimated depth at each stage record the evolutionary process of a magmatic-hydrothermal system extending to depths of nearly 10 km in the Yechangping deposit.</description>
      <author>Po-Cheng Huang, Nan Qi, Jie Yu, Jincao Yao, Zhiwei Qiu, Yanjing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of oxide inclusions and cleanliness control in Al-killed GCr15SiMn bearing steel during secondary refining process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233231222113</link>
      <description>Guolei Zhang, Guoguang Cheng, Tao&#65533; Zhang, Hongsheng Miao, Zhong Xu, Ironmaking &amp; steelmaking. 51(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399057676

                The evolution of oxide inclusions and cleanliness control in Al-killed GCr15SiMn bearing steel was investigated using a combination of industrial tests and thermodynamic calculations during the secondary refining process. Three different refining conditions were employed in the LF process. With varying ranges of slag basicity (about 5.6&#8211;5.7, 4.8&#8211;4.9 and 3.9&#8211;4.3) and Al content (0.028&#8211;0.035 mass%, 0.023&#8211;0.025 mass% and 0.014&#8211;0.02 mass%), the total oxygen content in the steel after VD refining was measured as 0.0019 mass%, 0.0017 mass% and 0.0008 mass%, respectively. Throughout the refining process, the inclusions underwent a transformation from MgO-Al 2 O 3 (or Al 2 O 3 ) into CaO-Al 2 O 3 (-MgO), and eventually to CaO-Al 2 O 3 -SiO 2 inclusions. Furthermore, it was observed that under high Al content and slag basicity refining conditions, a significant number of inclusions in VD treatment were formed and transformed into CaO&#183;Al 2 O 3 &#183;SiO 2 inclusions enriched with 60 mass% CaO. This indicated that when the proportion of CaO in calcium aluminates exceeded 45 mass%, there was an increased risk of larger-sized inclusions. Conversely, refining conditions with a slag basicity of 3.9&#8211;4.3 and an Al content of 0.014&#8211;0.02 mass% demonstrated effective inclusion control, resulting in lower number density, smaller sizes within 10 &#956;m and an average composition located in the liquid region. This study carries important practical significance for the smelting of high cleanliness GCr15SiMn bearing steel.</description>
      <author>Guolei Zhang, Guoguang Cheng, Tao&#65533; Zhang, Hongsheng Miao, Zhong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233231222113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot synthesis of C/N co-doped TiO2 with rich oxygen vacancy for efficient photoreduction CO2-to-CO in pure water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113212</link>
      <description>N. Zhang, Jiwen Li, Xin Sun, Junying Ma, Shijie Li, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399143264

                Photocatalytic technology has emerged as a promising approach for addressing global energy and environmental challenges by enabling the conversion of CO2 into valuable chemicals. In this study, we successfully synthesized TiO2 co-doped with C and N, along with an abundant oxygen vacancy (referred to as C/N-TiO2-VO), utilizing a hydrothermal method. Through various characterization techniques, it has been confirmed that the C and N originated from N, N'-dimethylformamide (DMF), while the VO was mainly generated by isopropyl alcohol (IPA), acting as a reducing agent. These techniques also verified that C/N-TiO2-VO has the strong light absorption ability and longer fluorescence lifetime, all of which contribute to enhancing photocatalytic performance. More importantly, C/N-TiO2-VO exhibited exceptional performance in the photoreduction of CO2 to CO, achieving nearly 100% selectivity in pure water, with a CO evolution rate of 53.97 &#956;mol g-1 h-1. This rate was 10.8 and 8.1 times higher than that of TiO2 and C/N-TiO2, respectively. Further theoretical calculations illustrated that stronger local charges and defect levels are formed on the surface of C/N-TiO2-VO compared with TiO2(101), facilitating the dissociation of CO2 and the conversion of CO2 into *COOH intermediates. Furthermore, in situ DRIFTS results confirmed the formation of crucial intermediate *COOH during CO2 photoreduction. This study presents a viable approach for designing highly active photocatalysts through the synergistic effects of doping and vacancies.</description>
      <author>N. Zhang, Jiwen Li, Xin Sun, Junying Ma, Shijie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon coated and oxygen vacancies incorporated Wadsley-Roth phase molybdenum niobium oxide for high-performance lithium-ion storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118384</link>
      <description>Hao L&#237;u, Yu Lu, Runxiang Yang, Fengqi Lu, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. 966(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399070205

                Nb-based oxides with Wadsley-Roth shear structure have been aroused extensive research interest as promising anode for Li-ion batteries, due to the multi-electron redox, safe working voltage and open structural framework. However, the low intrinsic electronic conductivity limits their further practical applications. Herein, the lithium storage performances of MoNb6O18 with Wadsley-Roth shear structure is optimized by carbon coating and oxygen vacancies (VO-MNO@C), which synthesized with freeze-drying and subsequently heat treatment. As expected, the VO-MNO@C electrode demonstrates a high initial reversible capacity of 259.6 mAh/g at 0.2C and the capacity retention rate of 85.7 % after 200 cycles at 1C. Moreover, the reversible of Mo6+/Mo5+ and Mo5+/Mo4+ redox reaction can be effectively improved. In situ X-ray diffraction (XRD) and ex situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) characterization indicate that VO-MNO@C undergoes a solid-solution structural evolution disclosing the stepwise reaction of Mo5+/Mo6+, Mo4+/Mo5+, Nb4+/Nb5+ and Nb3+/Nb4+ redox couples with a small volume variation of 5.7 %. Also, the full cell based on commercial LiMn2O4 cathode and VO-MNO@C anode displays an operating voltage about 2.4 V with the high energy density of 681.4 Wh/kg (calculated with the mass of anode). This work will offer more insights for the development Wadsley-Roth shear structure anode materials with excellent Li-ion storage properties.</description>
      <author>Hao L&#237;u, Yu Lu, Runxiang Yang, Fengqi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mineral chemistry of chrome- diopside bearing lamprophyre from Mesoproterozoic Settupalle complex of Prakasam Alkaline Province: Insights on the magma dynamics at shallow lithospheric mantle beneath the NE margin of the Cuddapah Basin, Southern India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1144/sp551-2024-35</link>
      <description>N. Sridhar, Ragi Mallikarjuna Reddy, Rohit Pandey, Sourav Naskar, Kirtikumar Randive, Kuldeep Singh, Special publication - Geological Society of London/Geological Society, London, special publications. 551(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399129107

                Abstract The Eastern Dharwar Craton (EDC) shows considerable variations in the activity of Kimberlite, lamproite, and lamprophyre and their related lithospheric thickness, thermal structure, and magmatic source characteristics from the innermost core to the margin. These variations have been revealed through seismic studies and the analysis of xenoliths, and xenocrysts carried in alkaline magmas, particularly kimberlites. This study reports the occurrence of chrome diopside phenocrysts from a lamprophyre of the Settupalle pluton, located on the northeastern margin of the Cuddapah basin, Prakasam Alkaline Province (PAP) in South India. Studied lamprophyre characterized by phenocrystic clinopyroxene (Cpx) and biotite, embedded in a groundmass of amphibole, biotite, opaques, calcite, feldspar, nepheline, and sodalite, with the latter minerals forming ocellar structures. Clinopyroxene displays normal zoning, with a high Mg-Cr rich diopside core (up to 1.92 wt%) and a Na 2 O, Al 2 O 3 , FeO, and TiO 2 -enriched salite rim. These chemical variations, along with elemental substitutions from core to rim, indicate the significant role of fractionation in the evolution of lamprophyre magma. The lack of chemical disparity among the studied Cpx, suggests closed-system fractionation, under high oxygen fugacity conditions. Thermobarometry results indicate polybaric crystallization for the Cpx (1206&#8211;1269 &#176;C, 11.82&#8211;18.04 kbar) and biotite (825&#8211;856 &#176;C, 3.49&#8211;6.94 kbar). The gradient inferred from the pressure of the Cpx suggests that its crystallization occurred at a depth of 43-66 km, implying shallow lithospheric magma contribution for the genesis of the lamprophyre magma. Supplementary material at https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.c.7249493</description>
      <author>N. Sridhar, Ragi Mallikarjuna Reddy, Rohit Pandey, Sourav Naskar, Kirtikumar Randive, Kuldeep Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1144/sp551-2024-35</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni and Co Catalysts on Interactive Oxide Support for Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolysis Cell (AEMEC)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12060153</link>
      <description>Katerina Maksimova-Dimitrova, Boryana Mladenova, G. Borisov, E. Slavcheva, Inorganics. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399215326

                The work presents novel composite catalytic materials&#8212;Ni and Co deposited on Magneli phase titania&#8212;and describes their complex characterization and integration into membrane electrode assemblies to produce hydrogen by electrochemical water splitting in cells with anion exchange membranes (AEMEC). Chemical composition, surface structure, and morphology were characterized by XRD and SEM analysis. The activity in the evolution of the partial electrode reactions of hydrogen (HER) and oxygen (OER) was assessed in an aqueous alkaline electrolyte (25 wt.% KOH) using linear sweep voltammetry. The interactive role of the support was investigated and discussed. Among the tested samples, the sample with 30 wt.% Co (Co30/MPT) demonstrated superior performance in the OER. The reaction started at 1.65 V, and at 1.8 V, the current density reached 75 mA cm&#8722;2. The HER is most efficient on the sample containing 40 wt.% Ni (Ni40/MPT), where the current density reaches 95 mA at a potential of &#8722;0.5 V. The change in catalytic efficiency compared to that of the unsupported Ni and Co is due to synergism resulting from electronic interactions between the transition metal having a hyper-d-electron character and hypo-d-electron support. The pre-selected catalysts were integrated in membrane electrode assembly (MEA) using commercial and laboratory-prepared anion-conductive membranes and tested in a custom-made AEMEC. The performance was compared to that of MEA with a commercial carbon-supported Pt catalyst. It was found that the MEA with newly prepared catalysts demonstrated better performance in long-term operation (50 mA cm&#8722;2 at 1.8 V in a 60 h durability test), which, combined with the higher cost efficiency, gave credence to considering this combination of materials as promising for AEMEC applications.</description>
      <author>Katerina Maksimova-Dimitrova, Boryana Mladenova, G. Borisov, E. Slavcheva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12060153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-precision interpretable framework for marine dissolved oxygen concentration inversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1396277</link>
      <description>Xin Li, Zhenyi Liu, Zhifeng Yang, Meng Fan, Tao Song, Frontiers in marine science. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399246492

                Variations in Marine Dissolved Oxygen Concentrations (MDOC) play a critical role in the study of marine ecosystems and global climate evolution. Although artificial intelligence methods, represented by deep learning, can enhance the precision of MDOC inversion, the uninterpretability of the operational mechanism involved in the &#8220;black-box&#8221; often make the process difficult to interpret. To address this issue, this paper proposes a high-precision interpretable framework (CDRP) for intelligent MDOC inversion, including Causal Discovery, Drift Detection, RuleFit Model, and Post Hoc Analysis. The entire process of the proposed framework is fully interpretable: (i) The causal relationships between various elements are further clarified. (ii) During the phase of concept drift analysis, the potential factors contributing to changes in marine data are extracted. (iii) The operational rules of RuleFit ensure computational transparency. (iv) Post hoc analysis provides a quantitative interpretation from both global and local perspectives. Furthermore, we have derived quantitative conclusions about the impacts of various marine elements, and our analysis maintains consistency with conclusions in marine literature on MDOC. Meanwhile, CDRP also ensures the precision of MDOC inversion: (i) PCMCI causal discovery eliminates the interference of weakly associated elements. (ii) Concept drift detection takes more representative key frames. (iii) RuleFit achieves higher precision than other models. Experiments demonstrate that CDRP has reached the optimal level in single point buoy data inversion task. Overall, CDRP can enhance the interpretability of the intelligent MDOC inversion process while ensuring high precision.</description>
      <author>Xin Li, Zhenyi Liu, Zhifeng Yang, Meng Fan, Tao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1396277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic Ni&#8211;Fe nanoparticles encapsulated with biomass-derived N-doped graphitic carbon core-shell nanostructures an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for enhanced overall seawater splitting and human urine electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100864</link>
      <description>Rajathsing Kalusulingam, Krishnan Ravi, Selvam Mathi, Nikita Yadhav, A.S. Mikheykin, Ankush V. Biradar, Kannan Srinivasan, Tatiana N. Myasoedova, Materials today sustainability. 27(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399187684

                Producing green hydrogen from abundant natural resources such as seawater and human urine is a viable solution for energy and industrial applications. However, the field of electrocatalysis faces challenges in developing cost-effective metal catalysts for efficient electrolysis of seawater and urea sewage. Here, we reported bimetallic NiFe nanoparticles encapsulated in a biomass derived N-doped graphitic carbon core shell structure (NiFe@BNGC-700) as a stable and effective catalyst for seawater and human urine electrolysis. NiFe@BNGC-700 exhibits remarkable electrocatalytic performance, with a low overpotential requiring 300 mV for OER and 297 mV for HER in alkaline 1.0 M KOH + seawater and 1.36 V for UOR in alkaline 1.0 M KOH + human urine at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 current density, respectively. The active bifunctional NiFe@BNGC-700 electrocatalyst symmetry pair facilitates the construction of a seawater electrolyser, achieving a cell voltage of 1.74 V at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 current density. Furthermore, the human urine-mediated electrolyser employing NiFe@BNGC-700//NiFe@BNGC-700 achieves a cell voltage of 1.64 V at the same current density, maintaining stability over 12 h with negligible potential deviation. Continual evolution of hydrogen and oxygen is feasible in a solar seawater a cell assembled with NiFe@BNGC-700 electrocatalyst, delivering at cell voltage of 1.74 V, enabling sustained and effective green hydrogen delivery on a large scale. This study proposes a sustainable strategy for fabricating electrodes consisting of non-precious metals, thereby permitting the economical and extensive generation of green hydrogen on a large scale.</description>
      <author>Rajathsing Kalusulingam, Krishnan Ravi, Selvam Mathi, Nikita Yadhav, A.S. Mikheykin, Ankush V. Biradar, Kannan Srinivasan, Tatiana N. Myasoedova</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-field simulation of high-temperature corrosion of binary Zr-2.5Sn alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.73.20240393</link>
      <description>Liu Xu-Xi, Gao Shi-Sen, La Yong-Xiao, Wenbo Liu, Wuli xuebao. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399236229

                Due to the small neutron absorption cross section and excellent thermal creep performance, zirconium alloy is one of the most important cladding materials for fuel rods in commercial fission reactors. However, quantitative analysis of the effects of temperature and grain boundaries on the corrosion microstructure evolution of zirconium alloys is still needed. It is of great significance to establish a phase field simulation for the corrosion process of polycrystalline zirconium alloy and systematically investigate the thermodynamic impact. In this study, the phase field model of the corrosion process in zirconium alloys was developed by incorporating corrosion electrochemistry to calculate the interfacial energy at the metal-oxide and oxide-fluid boundaries. Then model was then employed to investigate the uniform corrosion behavior on the surface of Zr-2.5Sn alloy, which demonstrated that the corrosion kinetics curve followed a cubic rule. Subsequently, the influence of temperature on the corrosion thickening curve of zirconium alloys was examined, and good agreement between simulation and experimental results was achieved. It was observed that during early stages of oxide layer formation, there is a high growth rate with minimal temperature dependence; however, as the oxide layer thickness increases, temperature becomes a significant factor affecting its growth rate, with higher temperatures resulting in faster corrosion rates. Furthermore, an investigation into the effect of polycrystalline zirconium alloy matrices on corrosion rates revealed that grain boundaries accelerate oxide layer thickening due to enhanced oxygen diffusion rates. Along these grain boundaries towards the metal matrix at metal-oxide interfaces, regions with higher O&lt;sup&gt;2-&lt;/sup&gt; concentrations form an O&lt;sup&gt;2-&lt;/sup&gt; band which primarily influences oxidation-corrosion rates during initial oxidation stages.</description>
      <author>Liu Xu-Xi, Gao Shi-Sen, La Yong-Xiao, Wenbo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.73.20240393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrochemical characteristics of abandoned coal mines derived acid mine drainage in a typical karst basin (Wuma river basin, Guizhou China)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31963</link>
      <description>Yang Lei, Yuegang Tang, Hongbing Sun, Li He, Ruiqing Li, Heliyon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399143242

                The hydrochemical characteristics of acid mine drainage (AMD) were investigated in Wuma River Basin, China. AMD was sampled from nine closed coal mine (CCM) sites to study the temporal and spatial evolution of pH, dissolved oxygen (DO), electrical conductivity (ED), total hardness (THR), total dissolved salt (TDS), and trace elements. The surface water (river) and groundwater surrounding mine sites were sampled to evaluate the potential pollution derived from AMDs. The TDS content of AMD was higher than that of surface water and groundwater. The dominant factors influencing TDS were the pH, temperature, and wet or dry season (which played a role in controlling microbial activity), HCO3- balance, and REDOX during the evolutionary process. The hydrochemical type of AMD was dependent on the evolutionary stage. From observations, most AMDs were in the form of the SO42--Ca2+&#8226;Mg2+ type that was characterized by a low pH, low [HCO3-], high [SO42-], and high [Fe]. In addition, the AMD samples were undergoing stage I and II processes, in which SO42- and trace elements were generated. The surface water and groundwater were primarily classified as the HCO3--Ca2+&#8226;Mg2+ type, which accounted for their self-cleaning capacity, as indicated by the high [HCO3-]. The surface water and groundwater could be affected by the surrounding AMD depending on the geographical location. The surface water and groundwater sites that were located downstream of subsurface and surface runoff were obviously affected by AMD. After being polluted by AMD, surface water and groundwater contained higher levels of trace elements and emerged as the HCO3-&#8226;SO42--Ca2+&#8226;Mg2+ type.</description>
      <author>Yang Lei, Yuegang Tang, Hongbing Sun, Li He, Ruiqing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reignition characteristics of lignite affected by pre-oxidation and liquid nitrogen cold soaking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131847</link>
      <description>Wei Zhang, Biao Wang, Haihui Xin, Chengguang Wang, Zhuo Xu, Zhenhai Hou, Zhangfan Qi, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399186995

                The propensity of residual oxidized coal to be reignited within enclosed fire areas in coal mines under liquid nitrogen (LN2) cold soaking remains unclear. Therefore, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), low-temperature nitrogen adsorption (LTNA), and thermogravimetric (TG) experiments were conducted to characterize the pore structure and secondary oxidation of oxidized cold-soaked coal. The results indicate that pre-oxidation or cold soaking alone can promote the generation and merging of pores and make the pore structure more complex, especially when pre-oxidized. However, pore evolution is suppressed and then improves when lignite is simultaneously subjected to pre-oxidation and cold soaking. In particular, the macropore volume and specific surface area decrease and then increase. The cryogenic shrinking of the LN2 results in the collapse of the loose coal matrix, which subsequently blocks the macropores. In contrast, vaporization expansion enhances pore connectivity with continuous LN2 injections, transforming mesopores into macropores, especially in the pore ranges of 2&#8211;5 nm and &gt;50 nm. Additionally, pre-oxidation or cold soaking alone improves the oxidizing activity and combustion performance of raw coal. However, continuous cold soaking initially increases and subsequently decreases the characteristic temperatures and activation energy of oxidized coal. Oxidization at 200&#176;C with one cold soaking can further lower reignition propensity. The average activation energy of oxidized coal decreases by 22.9%&#8211;29% when soaked more than three times. The improvement in combustion property is closely related to the increasing number of macropores because a larger pore volume and specific surface area are conducive to oxygen diffusion and adsorption. Therefore, pre-oxidation and cold soaking promote and inhibit the reignition of coal when performed simultaneously. These results provide theoretical guidance for rational liquid-nitrogen injection to control coal fires.</description>
      <author>Wei Zhang, Biao Wang, Haihui Xin, Chengguang Wang, Zhuo Xu, Zhenhai Hou, Zhangfan Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-composites of &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si8.svg" display="inline" id="d1e1286"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;NiFe&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mtext&gt;-&lt;/mml:mtext&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;LDH&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;/&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;V Se&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; heterostructures for effective water splitting electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.232</link>
      <description>Arkal Vittal Hegde, P. Mukesh, Lakshmi Sagar G., Arvind Kumar, H.S. Nagaraja, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399113982

                In the realm of sustainable and environmentally friendly "green-hydrogen" fuel demand, water electrolysis stands as a pathway of hope for the extraction of renewable hydrogen. However, the durability and efficiency of electrocatalysts have been a major challenge in this process, owing to factors like the high costs of noble catalysts (Pt, Ir, Ru, etc.) and their limited stability. Layered Nickel-iron double hydroxides (NiFe-LDH) have shown potential as low-cost and efficient electrocatalysts because of their suitable electronic configuration and distinguished orbital confinement. However, their durability In the realm of sustainable and environmentally friendly "green-hydrogen" fuel demand, water electrolysis stands as a pathway of hope for the extraction of renewable hydrogen. However, the durability and efficiency of electrocatalysts have been a major challenge in this process, owing to factors like the high costs of noble catalysts (Pt, Ir, Ru, etc.) and their limited stability. Layered Nickel-iron double hydroxides (NiFe-LDH) have shown potential as low-cost and efficient electrocatalysts because of their suitable electronic configuration and distinguished orbital confinement. However, their performance and durability in corrosive alkaline water at high current density remain limited. In this regard, one can make the nano-composites of this NiFe-LDH with high electronic conductivity materials and layered structures like VSe2. With this motivation, this work presents a novel electrocatalyst, NiFe-LDH, supported with VSe2 nanosheets (V Se2/NiFe&#8722;LDH), designed to address these challenges and enhance water splitting efficiency. Experimental results demonstrate that the heterostructure synergistically reduces charge transfer resistance, increases exposure of active sites, and enhances oxygen gas evolution ability. Consequently, the V Se2/NiFe&#8722;LDH electrocatalyst demonstrated superior sustainability, maintaining an elevated current density (500mAcm&#8722;2) for over 50 h of continuous electrolysis without noticeable degradation. This research opens up new possibilities and shows that nano-compositing can be a good option for achieving efficient and durable electrocatalysts in alkaline water splitting, thereby contributing to sustainable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Arkal Vittal Hegde, P. Mukesh, Lakshmi Sagar G., Arvind Kumar, H.S. Nagaraja</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and durable iridium-doped SnO2 anode for reactive chlorine species-mediated urine wastewater treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152698</link>
      <description>Sukhwa Hong, Gil-Bok Choi, Nhat-Long Phan, Hyungcheol Shin, Jonghun Lim, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399240365

                The prevalence of nitrogen pollutants in urine wastewater has become a pressing environmental issue. Among various methods for addressing this concern, electrochemical oxidation processes that generate reactive chlorine species (RCS) from chloride ions commonly found in urine wastewater stand out as a promising approach. Despite the exploration of diverse anode materials, existing options still suffer from low selectivity in RCS generation, poor stability, and considerable energy consumption. In this study, we synthesized iridium-doped tin oxide (Ir-SnO2) as an efficient, durable, and energy-conserving anode and systematically evaluated its electrochemical activity for RCS-mediated removal of nitrogen pollutants in urine wastewater. The Ir-SnO2 anode outperformed counterparts such as IrO2, SnO2, and Sb-SnO2, demonstrating its superior electrochemical performance characterized by high current density, low charge transfer resistance, and substantial active surface area. It also achieved exceptional current efficiency of 91.7 % and energy efficiency of 7.79 mmol/Wh for RCS generation at 30 mA cm&#8722;2 in diluted 0.1 M chloride solution. Computational analysis from Density Functional Theory (DFT) additionally supported experimental results, revealing that Ir doping to SnO2 enhances chlorine adsorption through electronic structure modification, significantly lowering the overpotential and improving electrocatalytic activity for chlorine evolution reactions. In the electrolysis of synthetic urine wastewater at 30 mA cm&#8722;2 for 5 h, the Ir-SnO2 anode demonstrated remarkable efficacy in degrading ammonia nitrogen (NH3-N), total nitrogen (TN), and chemical oxygen demand (COD) with efficiencies of 100 %, 97.8 %, and 89.1 %, respectively. These results were comparable to those achieved by IrO2 (dimensional stable anode, DSA) and exceeded the performance of the boron-doped diamond (BDD) anode. Furthermore, Ir-SnO2 exhibited the lowest energy consumption compared to benchmark DSA and BDD anodes in the treatment of urine wastewater. In stability assessments, furthermore, the Ir-SnO2 electrode maintained stable anodic cell potential for 100 h of continuous electrolysis in a 0.1 M NaCl electrolyte at 30 mA cm&#8722;2 and remained functional over five cycles without any signs of deactivation. This study provides valuable insights into the development of a suitable anode for energy-efficient urine wastewater treatment.</description>
      <author>Sukhwa Hong, Gil-Bok Choi, Nhat-Long Phan, Hyungcheol Shin, Jonghun Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage of Diabetic Retinopathy with Blood Antioxidants and Gut Microbiota in Type Two Diabetes Mellitus Saudi Patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46889/joar.2024.5202</link>
      <description>Rania Fahmy, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399096455

                Background: The retina is a light-sensitive nerve layer located at the back of the eye that creates images of objects. These cells kept alive by getting oxygen and nutrients from tiny blood vessels in the eye. Retinopathy is a disease of the retina that is more prevalent in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients. Diabetic retinopathy is a leading cause of blindness because hyperglycemia weakens retinal capillaries, resulting in leakage of blood into the surrounding space. This bleeding can result in formation of scar tissue, which can cause traction retinal detachment and maculopathy. The development of a panel of blood biomarkers to monitor diabetic retinopathies is essential for both diagnosis and prognosis. Proteomics as a powerful tool for the analysis of complex mixtures of proteins and the identification of biomarkers can be of great importance. Purpose: To detect early nerve fiber layer changes around macula and optic disc in diabetic patients and to correlate diabetic retinopathy with blood antioxidants and gut microbiota in T2DM in Saudi patients. Materials and Methods: In this cross-sectional case-control study, a total of 77 eyes of 39 subjects aged 40-60 years who did not have any history of eye injuries or eye diseases affecting fundus viewing, were recruited from King Saud University Campus and the department of ophthalmology in King Abdul Aziz university hospital in Riyadh. All subjects underwent full ophthalmic examination including Peripapillary retinal nerve fiber layer thickness and macular profile, Proteomic approach of collected overnight fasting plasma and Microbial stool examination. Results: The nerve fiber layer thickness around the optic disc was measured for all groups and there was no statistically significant difference in all quadrants between groups. The total retinal thickness at the macular area was different among all groups and tends to increase in group 3 due to diabetic retinopathy. The macular thickness in the 4 quadrants revealed no statistical difference except in the inferior quadrant. Glutathione S transferase and lipid peroxides showed no significant difference between the three studied groups; vitamin C and Glutathione were surprisingly higher in controlled diabetic patients relative to controls. Moreover, over growth of bacteroids participated to the evolution of retinopathy in diabetic patients. Conclusion: As hyperglycemia and oxidative stress are implicated in the pathogenesis of diabetic retinopathy, the present study certified that the progressive damage can be delayed in controlled type 2 diabetic patients using different treatment modalities that subside oxidative stress.</description>
      <author>Rania Fahmy</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46889/joar.2024.5202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smooth muscle cell-specific deletion of S100A4 modifies smooth muscle cell fate and inflammation in murine atherosclerotic lesions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvae088.166</link>
      <description>P Azar, L M Cardoso Dos Santos, Marta Correia de Sousa, ML Bochaton-Piallat, Cardiovascular research. 120(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399136901

                Abstract Funding Acknowledgements Type of funding sources: Public grant(s) &#8211; National budget only. Main funding source(s): Swiss National Science Foundation (SNSF) S100A4, a calcium-binding protein, is crucial in smooth muscle cell (SMC) phenotypic switch, yet its role in atherosclerotic plaque development and SMC plasticity remains unclear. Our previous experiments using an S100A4 neutralizing antibody approach in ApoE-/- atherosclerotic-prone mice showed reduced atherosclerotic burden but did not establish a direct link between the various S100A4-expressing cells and atherosclerosis. Herein, we show that aortic Oil RedO staining in ApoE-/-; S100A4-/- mice subjected to a 12-week high-cholesterol-diet (HCD) revealed reduced lesion areas compared to ApoE-/- mice (Figure 1, from 21.29% of the total aorta in ApoE-/-; S100A4+/+ mice to 13.27% in ApoE-/-; S100A4-/- mice), highlighting a pivotal role for S100A4 in atherosclerotic plaque development. We then used a lineage tracing ApoE-/- mouse model, in which we induced an SMC-specific deletion of S100A4 (SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916;). After 12 weeks of HCD, SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; and control mice (SMC-S100A4wt/wt) were sacrificed, and aortas were processed for en face Oil Red O staining, immunohistochemistry, and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq). SMC-specific deletion of S100A4 reduced the necrotic core area (from 29.75% of total plaque area in SMC-S100A4wt/wt to 18.23% in SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; mice) without affecting total atherosclerotic plaque size suggesting a more potent impact on plaque composition. ScRNA-seq analysis from SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; and SMC-S100A4wt/wt mice showed that the inflammatory macrophage-like SMC phenotype was highly suppressed in the plaque and associated with increased SMC repair phenotypes as well as a global reduction of myeloid inflammatory cells. SMCs also retained specific contractile SMC markers, namely Acta2 and Myh11 (fold change of 2.285 and 2.492, respectively) hinting towards a more stable fibrous cap. Immunofluorescence staining on aortic roots plaque (Figure 2) confirmed those results with an increase of SMCs (from 11.02% to 16.18%) as well as a-smooth muscle actin (a-SMA, Acta2)-positive SMCs (from 3.25% to 5.1%) in SMC-S100A4 &#916;/&#916; mice. Furthermore, the Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) of scRNAseq data revealed that, in SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; mice, genes related to mitochondrial metabolism and oxidative respiration were highly downregulated in all SMC clusters. We investigated SMC mitochondrial fitness in vitro and showed that S100A4-/- SMCs have an increased basal oxygen consumption rate and an increased proton leak (fold change of 1.37 and 1.96 respectively) suggestive of differences in cellular metabolic adaptability. In conclusion, our research emphasizes the significant role of S100A4 in plaque development, demonstrating how SMC-derived S100A4 knockdown affects plaque evolution, reducing inflammation, and promoting stability likely through influencing SMC phenotypic switch through metabolic pathways.</description>
      <author>P Azar, L M Cardoso Dos Santos, Marta Correia de Sousa, ML Bochaton-Piallat</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvae088.166</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
