<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 01:20:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>d-Band center theory-guided mixed metal oxide-based oxygen electrocatalysts for ultra-stable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.159005</link>
      <description>Weipeng Zhao, Qicheng Zhang, P. W. Zhao, Bin Chen, Wenchao Peng, Yang Li, Xiaobin Fan, Xiaobin Fan, Xiaobin Fan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405807839

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weipeng Zhao, Qicheng Zhang, P. W. Zhao, Bin Chen, Wenchao Peng, Yang Li, Xiaobin Fan, Xiaobin Fan, Xiaobin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.159005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-controlled evolution of cobalt active sites assisted by carbon substrate for high-efficiency oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.11.044</link>
      <description>Lili Fan, Xiaojie Dai, Fengting Li, Xuting Li, Zhanning Liu, Qiang Guo, C. Zhang, Zixi Kang, Daofeng Sun, Journal of Material Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405808016

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lili Fan, Xiaojie Dai, Fengting Li, Xuting Li, Zhanning Liu, Qiang Guo, C. Zhang, Zixi Kang, Daofeng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.11.044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvent permeation triggers polymetallic gel for highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118904</link>
      <description>Qi Xue, Long Ma, Kun Liu, Pengpeng Du, Qiufang Liu, Yan Yan, Yuan Dang, Shuangli Chen, Shaohua Wen, Yuanzhen Zhou, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405808177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Xue, Long Ma, Kun Liu, Pengpeng Du, Qiufang Liu, Yan Yan, Yuan Dang, Shuangli Chen, Shaohua Wen, Yuanzhen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118904</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Surface State in CoFe (Oxy)Hydroxide for Improved Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010011</link>
      <description>Guo Wen, Chizhong Wang, Lei Qiu, Fanghua Liu, Sizhe Chen, Huazhen Chang, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405808447

                CoFe-based catalysts have shown excellent activity for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), with the oxidation states of the active sites playing a crucial role in determining catalytic performance. However, how to effectively increase the oxidation state of these active sites remains a key challenge. In this work, a facile treatment with NaBH4 solution was employed to modulate the surface state of CoFeOxHy catalysts, inducing an enhanced OER activity. The overpotential at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for the NaBH4-treated CoFe catalyst was reduced to 270 mV, indicating improved OER activity. X-ray diffraction (XRD), Raman spectroscopy, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) results reveal that NaBH4 treatment induced a phase reconstruction of the CoFe oxalate framework, a critical step in enhancing its catalytic properties. The strong reducing ability of NaBH4 strengthened the Co-Fe interaction, allowing the retention of low-valence Co species while facilitating the formation of high-valence Fe sites. This dual modulation of Co and Fe oxidation states significantly accelerated charge transfer kinetics, ultimately boosting OER performance. These findings highlight the importance of improving the oxidation states of active sites in CoFe-based catalysts, providing insights for developing efficient catalysts for electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Guo Wen, Chizhong Wang, Lei Qiu, Fanghua Liu, Sizhe Chen, Huazhen Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic behaviour of Co&#8211;Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;Cr&#8211;V&#8211;Zr eutectic high entropy alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12034-024-03367-1</link>
      <description>Gurinder Mohan, Mayank K. Singh, K. Dhirendra, Sumanta Samal, Bulletin of Materials Science. 48(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405810040

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gurinder Mohan, Mayank K. Singh, K. Dhirendra, Sumanta Samal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12034-024-03367-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the electrocatalytic activity of LaCoO3 core&#8211;shell hollow sphere for oxygen evolution reaction through modulating inner oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4re00539b</link>
      <description>Long Li, Jinbo Guo, Shen Jiang, Qiang Hu, Reaction Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405814190

                Due to the limited active surface area of perovskite oxides, improving their electrocatalytic performance faces many challenges. To solve this problem, defect engineering and hollow nanostructures have become effective strategies....</description>
      <author>Long Li, Jinbo Guo, Shen Jiang, Qiang Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4re00539b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Switchable Acidic Oxygen Evolution Mechanisms on Atomic Skin of Ruthenium Metallene Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13656</link>
      <description>Tianyi Gao, Dongxu Jiao, Lina Wang, Xin Ge, Xin Wen, Lei Zhang, Lirong Zheng, Xiaoxin Zou, Wei Zhang, Weitao Zheng, Jinchang Fan, Xiaoqiang Cui, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405815471

                RuO2 has been considered as a promising, low-cost, and highly efficient catalyst in the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, it suffers from poor stability due to the inevitable involvement of the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM). Here, we construct a unique metallene-based core-skin structure and unveil that the OER pathway of atomic RuO2 skin can be regulated from the LOM to an adsorbate evolution mechanism by altering the core species from metallene oxides to metallenes. This switch is achieved without sacrificing the number of active sites, enabling Pd@RuO2 metallenes to exhibit outstanding acidic OER activity with a low overpotential of 189 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, which is 54 mV lower than that of the counterpart PdO@RuO2 metallenes. Additionally, they also exhibit robust stability with negligible activity decay over 100 h at 50 mA cm&#8211;2, outperforming most reported RuO2-based catalysts. Multiple spectroscopic analyses and theoretical calculations demonstrate that the Pd-metallene core, acting as an electron donor, increases the migration energy of subsurface oxygen atoms and optimizes the adsorption energy of intermediates on the active Ru sites, enabling a switch in the reaction mechanism. Such a unique metallene-based core-skin structure offers a novel way for tuning the catalytic behaviors of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Tianyi Gao, Dongxu Jiao, Lina Wang, Xin Ge, Xin Wen, Lei Zhang, Lirong Zheng, Xiaoxin Zou, Wei Zhang, Weitao Zheng, Jinchang Fan, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c13656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeO2-x decorated CoFe-LDH on nickel foam with moderated oxygen vacancies for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.136055</link>
      <description>Huayun Yang, Yuchen Duan, Yuhua Dai, Yong Chen, Yu Xie, Guangzhen Zhang, Yifan Zhang, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405819067

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huayun Yang, Yuchen Duan, Yuhua Dai, Yong Chen, Yu Xie, Guangzhen Zhang, Yifan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.136055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of ternary W, Ni and Mn metal single atom oxides loaded on metal oxides electrocatalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105922</link>
      <description>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, Gowthami Palanisamy, Tae Hwan Oh, M. Swaminathan, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, S. Sadhasivam, Yueshuai Wang, Heba Taha M. Abdelghani, P. Thiruramanathan, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 168(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405826402

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, Gowthami Palanisamy, Tae Hwan Oh, M. Swaminathan, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, S. Sadhasivam, Yueshuai Wang, Heba Taha M. Abdelghani, P. Thiruramanathan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering oxygen vacancy on nickel-doped iron oxide nanorods as efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution and urea oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105928</link>
      <description>Maged N. Shaddad, Abdulrahman I. Alharthi, Saba A. Aladeemy, Prabhakarn Arunachalam, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405830219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maged N. Shaddad, Abdulrahman I. Alharthi, Saba A. Aladeemy, Prabhakarn Arunachalam</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105928</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Electronic and Structural Dynamics in Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vznhc</link>
      <description>Emily A. Sprague&#8208;Klein, Brian T. Phelan, Michael W. Mara, Jin Yu, Matt Drummer, X. He, Ksenija D. Glusac, Sungsik Lee, Benjamin Reinhart, Xiaoyi Zhang, David M. Tiede, Lin Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405834561

                We investigate the ultrafast electronic and thermal properties of the bulk amorphous cobalt oxide water oxidation catalysts cobalt-phosphate (CoPi) and cobalt borate (CoBi) using optical pump/X-ray probe correlated with in situ electrochemical transient absorption spectroscopy. The electronic signature of a light-generated intermediate species is compared to steady-state in situ heating X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS), suggestive of non-thermal contributions to charge transfer formation on ultrafast timescales. With Co K-edge transient absorption spectroscopy, we observe a net photoreduction following 400 nm excitation that also initiates a potential-dependent increase in the excited-state fraction of trapped charge carriers that persists on nanosecond to microsecond timescales and is identified as a potential precursor state to oxygen evolving reactions (OER). Distinctly, the formation of excited-state species cannot be fully explained by photothermal reaction dynamics alone, with potential contributions from electronic motion acting in concert with macroscopic redox activity. The results can influence the design of water-splitting catalytic materials for tuning dimensionality, confinement, and charge delocalization across structures.</description>
      <author>Emily A. Sprague&#8208;Klein, Brian T. Phelan, Michael W. Mara, Jin Yu, Matt Drummer, X. He, Ksenija D. Glusac, Sungsik Lee, Benjamin Reinhart, Xiaoyi Zhang, David M. Tiede, Lin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vznhc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Ni doping on the catalytic activity and stability of RuO2 electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122691</link>
      <description>Hyunwoo Jang, Seungwon Shim, Youngho Kang, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405835202

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyunwoo Jang, Seungwon Shim, Youngho Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic properties of Ti/RuO2-TiO2 dimensionally stable anode type electrodes modified with SnO2 and Ta2O5 for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2024.207025</link>
      <description>Maria de Lourdes Soprani Vasconcellos, Murilo M. Amaral, Manuel Jonathan Pinz&#243;n C&#225;rdenas, Luciene Paula Roberto Profeti, Demetrius Profeti, Othon S. Campos, Hudson Zanin, Rolando Pedicini, Josimar Ribeiro, Applied Catalysis O Open. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405835888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maria de Lourdes Soprani Vasconcellos, Murilo M. Amaral, Manuel Jonathan Pinz&#243;n C&#225;rdenas, Luciene Paula Roberto Profeti, Demetrius Profeti, Othon S. Campos, Hudson Zanin, Rolando Pedicini, Josimar Ribeiro</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2024.207025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of cerium dioxide anchored in cobalt-iron layered double hydroxide hollow polyhedra via an ion exchange strategy for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.196</link>
      <description>Yibing Chen, Lin Hao, Huizhong Ma, Tingyu Zhang, Hongyuan Yan, Yufan Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 683(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405836024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yibing Chen, Lin Hao, Huizhong Ma, Tingyu Zhang, Hongyuan Yan, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determination of doping strategy on the electrochemical performance of the hydrothermally prepared perovskite material</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06638-9</link>
      <description>Soumaya Gouadria, Muhammad Abdullah, F. F. Alharbi, Salma Aman, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405836494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Soumaya Gouadria, Muhammad Abdullah, F. F. Alharbi, Salma Aman, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06638-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A study on synthesis of an advanced electrocatalyst based on high-conductive carbon nanofibers shelled NiFe2O4 nanorods for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.178</link>
      <description>Tan Nam Luong, Thi Luu Luyen Doan, Patrick M. Bacirhonde, Chan Hee Park, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 99(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405838840

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tan Nam Luong, Thi Luu Luyen Doan, Patrick M. Bacirhonde, Chan Hee Park</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field-induced electron spin polarization of Co-modified black phosphorus for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134207</link>
      <description>Taofen Wang, Hui Qiao, Zongyu Huang, Zhiwen Leng, Ruiyang Yu, Xi Chen, Rong Hu, Xiaohui Ren, Xiang Qi, Fuel. 385(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405841058

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Taofen Wang, Hui Qiao, Zongyu Huang, Zhiwen Leng, Ruiyang Yu, Xi Chen, Rong Hu, Xiaohui Ren, Xiang Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134207</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancy-rich Ni(OH)2-ZnWO4 composites as an effective electrocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113826</link>
      <description>M. Atif, Asmat Ullah, Naveed Akhtar Shad, Jawaria Fatima, Syed Fazil Bin Farukh, Usama Zahid, Dongsheng Geng, Yasir Javed, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405842074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Atif, Asmat Ullah, Naveed Akhtar Shad, Jawaria Fatima, Syed Fazil Bin Farukh, Usama Zahid, Dongsheng Geng, Yasir Javed</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Noble Metal Dependence: Oxygen Evolution Reaction with Ru-Minimized Bi&#8322;Ru&#8322;O&#8327;@MOF-801 Composite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04140b</link>
      <description>P. Sujita, K. C. Gupta, S Sarmila, Vijaya Gopal, S. Vadivel, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405849954

                Developing efficient and noble metal-minimized electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions (OER) is critical for energy conversion reactions. Here we present a Ru-minimized Bi2Ru2O7@MOF-801 that synergistically combines the high catalytic activity...</description>
      <author>P. Sujita, K. C. Gupta, S Sarmila, Vijaya Gopal, S. Vadivel</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04140b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Heteroatomic Bond&#8208;Induced Confined Restructuring on Ir&#8208;Mn Intermetallics Enable Robust PEM Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420470</link>
      <description>Shuang Wang, Yan Shi, Tao Shen, Guangzhe Wang, Yue Sun, Gongwei Wang, Xiao Li, Changfeng Yan, Chundong Wang, Hongfang Liu, Ying Wang, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Lin Zhuang, Deli Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405851691

                Low&#8208;iridium acid&#8208;stabilized electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial for the market deployment of proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis. Manipulating the in situ reconstruction of Ir&#8208;based catalysts with favorable kinetics is highly desirable but remains elusive. Herein, we propose an atomic ordering strategy to modulate the dynamic surface restructuring of catalysts to break the activity/stability trade&#8208;off. Under working conditions, the strong heteroatom&#8208;bonded structure triggers rational surface&#8208;confined reconstruction to form self&#8208;stabilizing amorphous (oxy)hydroxides on the model Ir&#8208;Mn intermetallic (IMC). Combined in&#8208;situ/ex&#8208;situ characterizations and theoretical analysis demonstrate that the induced strong covalent Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Mn units in the catalytic layer weaken the formation barrier of OOH* and promote the preferential dynamic replenishment/conversion pathway of H2O molecules to suppress the uncontrollable participation of lattice oxygen (about 2.6 times lower than that of pure Ir). Thus, a PEM cell with Ir&#8208;Mn IMC as anode &#8220;pre&#8208;electrocatalyst&#8221; (0.24 mgIr cm&#8722;2) delivers an impressive performance (3.0 A cm&#8722;2@1.851 V@80 &#176;C) and runs stably at 2.0 A cm&#8722;2 for more than 2,000 h with the cost of USD 0.98 per kg H2, further validating its promising application. This work highlights surface&#8208;confined evolution triggered by strong heteroatom bonds, providing insights into the design of catalysts involving surface reconstruction.</description>
      <author>Shuang Wang, Yan Shi, Tao Shen, Guangzhe Wang, Yue Sun, Gongwei Wang, Xiao Li, Changfeng Yan, Chundong Wang, Hongfang Liu, Ying Wang, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Lin Zhuang, Deli Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Step Electrochemical Deposition of Transition Metal-Doped CoNi@Ti Nano-Flowers for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00924-4</link>
      <description>Dawit Tibebu Haile, Teketel Yohannes, Getachew Adam Workneh, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405852170

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dawit Tibebu Haile, Teketel Yohannes, Getachew Adam Workneh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00924-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Polyoxometalate for Enhanced OER Performance Using a Porous Manganese Oxide Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402294</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zubair, Lin Shen, Tae Hyeong Lee, Yongteng Qian, Dae Joon Kang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405852435

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical challenge in electrocatalytic water splitting, hindered by high energy demands and slow kinetics. Polyoxometalates (POMs), recognized for their unique redox capabilities, structural archetypes, and molecular precision, are promising candidates for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Yet, their application is hindered by high water solubility, causing rapid degradation and efficiency loss under harsh OER conditions. This study enhances the performance and stability of polyoxometalates (POMs) for OER by anchoring keggin&#8208;type POM [TiCoW11O40]7&#8208; nanosheets onto a conductive, carbon&#8208;protected manganese oxide (C&#8208;Mn2O3) nanospheres support. The acquired porous framework enhances POM/C&#8208;Mn2O3 (PCM) contact, improving stability, reaction kinetics, and redox activity by offering nucleation sites, electronic pathways, and abundant active sites, significantly boosting OER activity. The resulting PCM nanohybrid demonstrates remarkable OER activity in 1M KOH, requiring only a 300 mV overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 with a Tafel slope of 88 mV/dec. The PCM electrocatalyst also shows high mass activity (784 A/g at 1.6 V) and maintains stability over 100 hours at 100 mA cm&#8208;2 without performance fatigue. Consequently, this study offers a viable strategy for developing efficient, durable electrocatalysts using low&#8208;cost materials.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zubair, Lin Shen, Tae Hyeong Lee, Yongteng Qian, Dae Joon Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402294</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective growth of graphdiyne-based vanadium&#8211;iridium oxide interfaces for efficient alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphma.2024.12.003</link>
      <description>Yunhao Zheng, Yurui Xue, Yang Gao, Siao Chen, Si&#8211;Yi Chen, Yuliang Li, ChemPhysMater. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405854833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunhao Zheng, Yurui Xue, Yang Gao, Siao Chen, Si&#8211;Yi Chen, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphma.2024.12.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation-Modulated Ni/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N Compound Heterojunctions as Highly Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15087</link>
      <description>W. Z. Zhong, Qiming Sun, Lin Lv, Yong Han, Zhanghua Hong, Guohua Wang, Xiang Ao, Yuling Zhai, Tao Zhu, Xing Zhu, Hua Wang, Kongzhai Li, Zhishan Li, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405863104

                The exploration and rational design of high-performance, durable, and non-precious-metal bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts are highly desired for the large-scale application of overall water splitting. Herein, an effective and straightforward coupling approach was developed to fabricate high-performance bifunctional OER/HER electrocatalysts based on core&#8211;shell nanostructure comprising a Ni/Ni3N core and a NiFe(OH)x shell. The as-prepared Ni/Ni3N@NiFe(OH)x-4 catalyst exhibited low overpotentials of 57 and 243 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 for the HER and OER in 1.0 m KOH, respectively, superior to most bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts reported so far. Compared to the unmodified Ni/Ni3N, the Ni/Ni3N@NiFe(OH)x-4 catalyst exhibited a 43.3-fold increase in mass activity for the OER and an 8.7-fold increase for the HER, as well as a 29.5-fold increase in intrinsic activity for the OER and a 2.6-fold increase for the HER. When employed as both the cathode and the anode of the electrolyzer for the overall water splitting reaction, its voltage was reduced to 1.58 V at 10 mA cm&#8211;2. This surface reconstruction method increased the electrochemically active surface area and enhanced the catalytic activity. Furthermore, in situ Raman spectroscopy revealed that the Fe etching reduced the onset potential for the active phase NiOOH, promoted its formation, and accelerated the reaction kinetics, thereby enhancing the overall electrocatalytic performance of the catalyst.</description>
      <author>W. Z. Zhong, Qiming Sun, Lin Lv, Yong Han, Zhanghua Hong, Guohua Wang, Xiang Ao, Yuling Zhai, Tao Zhu, Xing Zhu, Hua Wang, Kongzhai Li, Zhishan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c15087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partial etching of ZIF-67 nanosheets for the fabrication of S-FeOx/ZIF-67/NF electrodes enabling highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction at large current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.402</link>
      <description>Yun Wu, Jin-Wei Wang, Weiyi Zhang, Qiang Zhao, Jinping Li, Guang Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 100(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405863970

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yun Wu, Jin-Wei Wang, Weiyi Zhang, Qiang Zhao, Jinping Li, Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Size-confined Co nanoparticles embedded in ultrathin carbon nanosheets for enhanced oxygen electrocatalysis in Zn-air batteries"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07845d/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Yang Liu, Qi Yan, Fa-Yuan Ge, Xinde Duan, Tingting Wu, He&#8208;Gen Zheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864365

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Liu, Qi Yan, Fa-Yuan Ge, Xinde Duan, Tingting Wu, He&#8208;Gen Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07845d/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Size-confined Co nanoparticles embedded in ultrathin carbon nanosheets for enhanced oxygen electrocatalysis in Zn-air batteries"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07845d/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405864375

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07845d/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of Cr-Cofe-Layered Double Hydroxide Via the Synergistic Roles of Fe Etching, Cr Doping, and Anion Intercalation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5075155</link>
      <description>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Anaclet Nsabimana, Huan Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405866980

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Anaclet Nsabimana, Huan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5075155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Promoter Breaks the Linear Scaling Relationship: Ultra&#8208;Rapid High&#8208;Temperature Synthesis of Heterostructured CoS/SnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@C as a Bifunctional Oxygen Catalyst for Li&#8208;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406516</link>
      <description>Nan Wang, Tingxue Fang, Tinghui An, Yuhao Wang, Jiaqi Li, Shuming Yu, Honghai Sun, Dong Xiang, Xiangjie Bo, Kedi Cai, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405879994

                Abstract Li&#8208;O 2 batteries urgently needs high discharge capacity and stable cycling performance, requiring effective and reliable bifunctional catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, Hovenia acerba Lindl &#8208;like heterostructure composed of cobalt sulfide and tin dioxide supported on carbon substrate (CoS/SnO 2 @C) is prepared via CO 2 laser irradiation technology. The half&#8208;wave potential of CoS/SnO 2 @C for the ORR is 0.88 V, while the overpotential of the OER at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 is as low as 270 mV. The Li&#8208;O 2 batteries employing the bifunctional CoS/SnO 2 @C catalyst displays a high discharge specific capacity of 3332.25 mAh g &#8722;1 and long cycling life of 226 cycles. Additionally, theory calculations demonstrate that the construction of heterostructure decreases energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) for both ORR and OER. Notably, SnO 2 behaves as the electronic promoter to optimize the electronic structure of heterostructure interface and triggers charge redistribution of CoS, which weakens the adsorption strength of the * O&#8208;intermediates and allows to break the linear scaling relationship, thus further enhancing the catalytic performance of CoS/SnO 2 @C. This research furnishes directions for the design of heterogeneous catalysts, highlighting its great potential for application in rechargeable Li&#8208;O 2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Nan Wang, Tingxue Fang, Tinghui An, Yuhao Wang, Jiaqi Li, Shuming Yu, Honghai Sun, Dong Xiang, Xiangjie Bo, Kedi Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autogenetic Carbon Oxyanions Enable Interfacial OH&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt; Deconfinement for Reinforced Biomass Electrooxidation over Wide Potential Window</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424435</link>
      <description>Keping Wang, Mei Wu, Yan Zhang, Binbin Jiang, Yaqiong Su, Song Yang, Xihong Lu, Hu Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405880128

                Abstract The preferential adsorption toward OH &#8722; on the anode most likely blocks the accessibility of organic molecules and triggers competitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER), typically precipitating a narrow potential window. Here, an OH &#8722; deconfinement strategy enabled by CO 3 2&#8722; self&#8208;transformed from C 2 O 4 2&#8722; on metallic nickel oxalate (NiC 2 O 4 ) for efficient synthesis of bioplastic monomer 2,5&#8208;furanedicarboxylic acid (FDCA) with faradaic efficiency of &gt;95% via electrocatalytic 5&#8208;hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation reaction (e&#8208;HMFOR) at a wider potential window of 1.38&#8211;1.56 V RHE , outperforming state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art Ni&#8208;based electrocatalysts is presented. In situ, tests corroborate that the construction of NiOOH with surface&#8208;adsorbed CO 3 2&#8722; (NiOOH&#8208;CO 3 2&#8722; ) from NiC 2 O 4 can be facilitated by self&#8208;liberating CO 3 2&#8722; . The CO 3 2&#8722; ions serving as an electric field engine can effectively weaken OH &#8722; coverage through electrostatic repulsion and enhance HMF adsorption at the NiOOH&#8208;CO 3 2&#8722; surface, thereby heightening e&#8208;HMFOR while inhibiting OER. Computational results further indicate that the CO 3 2&#8722; on NiOOH hoists the energy barrier of oxygen intermediate conversion (O* &#8594; OOH*) to suppress OER but promotes the e&#8208;HMFOR kinetics. The precise modulation of OH &#8722; adsorption behavior on the electrocatalyst offers a powerful kit for boosting the oxidative upgrading process while circumventing the competing reaction OER.</description>
      <author>Keping Wang, Mei Wu, Yan Zhang, Binbin Jiang, Yaqiong Su, Song Yang, Xihong Lu, Hu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202424435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineered Ru&#8208;CoMOF@MoS2 Heterointerface Facilitate Water Oxidation Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402533</link>
      <description>Boka Fikadu Banti, Mahendra Goddati, Njemuwa Nwaji, Juyong Gwak, Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Hyo Jin Kang, Sohrab Asgaran, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Jaebeom Lee, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405881167

                Catalyst design plays a critical role in ensuring sustainable and effective energy conversion. Electrocatalytic materials need to be able to control active sites and introduce defects in both acidic and alkaline electrolytes. Furthermore, producing efficient catalysts with a distinct surface structure advances our comprehension of the mechanism. Here, a defect&#8208;engineered heterointerface of ruthenium doped cobalt metal organic frame (Ru&#8208;CoMOF) core confined in MoS2 is reported. A tailored design approach at room temperature was used to induce defects and form an electron transfer interface that enhanced the electrocatalytic performance. The Ru&#8208;CoMOF@MoS2 heterointerface obtains a geometrical current density of 10 mA&#8208;2 by providing hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at small overpotentials of 240 and 289 mV, respectively. Density functional theory simulation shows that the Co&#8208;site maximizes the evolution of hydrogen intermediate energy for adsorption and enhances HER, while the Ru&#8208;site, on the other hand, is where OER happens. The heterointerface provides a channel for electron transfer and promotes reactions at the solid&#8208;liquid interface. The Ru&#8208;CoMOF@MoS2 model exhibits improved OER and HER efficiency, indicating that it could be a valuable material for the production of water&#8208;alkaline and acidic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Boka Fikadu Banti, Mahendra Goddati, Njemuwa Nwaji, Juyong Gwak, Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Hyo Jin Kang, Sohrab Asgaran, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Jaebeom Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress and Perspective of Noble&#8208;Metal&#8208;Free Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400881</link>
      <description>Ning Duan, Jiawen Wang, Ruizhe Wang, Guosheng Han, Xianli Wu, Yanyan Liu, Baojun Li, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405883345

                Abstract Rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) have attracted widespread attention due to their advantages, such as high energy density, low price, and environmental friendliness. However, the sluggish kinetics of ORR/OER greatly prevent the practical application of rechargeable ZABs. In recent years, efficient, durable, and cost&#8208;effective bifunctional catalysts are developed to accelerate the kinetics of ORR/OER and enhance the performance of ZABs. This review provides a systematic overview of ZABs and describes the standards of bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts. The latest research progress in the development of non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based and nano&#8208;metallic electrocatalysts for the air electrode of ZABs is systematically summarized, including the classification, design, synthesis methods, active site structures, and mechanism. Finally, the challenges faced by bifunctional catalysts and probable solutions are proposed. This review will provide a comprehensive guidance for development of efficient oxygen electrocatalyst in the future.</description>
      <author>Ning Duan, Jiawen Wang, Ruizhe Wang, Guosheng Han, Xianli Wu, Yanyan Liu, Baojun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of structurally chiral nickel oxide nanostructures for enhanced spin-dependent oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907222</link>
      <description>Yiran Jin, Cheng Yang, Siyuan Dong, Chengyu Xiao, Zhi Chen, Pengpeng Wang, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405883488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiran Jin, Cheng Yang, Siyuan Dong, Chengyu Xiao, Zhi Chen, Pengpeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26599/nr.2025.94907222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reactions in Two-Dimensional Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks by a Constant Potential Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04034</link>
      <description>Jin Yu, Tianyun Liu, Xuefei Liu, Wei Deng, Wenjun Xiao, Yaqiong Su, Xiaosi Qi, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Xu Wang, Changsong Gao, Hui Xiong, Xiangyu Wu, Jiajin Ge, Jinshun Bi, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405884135

                The evolution of bifunctional catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts that are highly active, stable, and conductive is crucial for advancing metal-air batteries and fuel cells. We have here thoroughly explored the OER and ORR performance for a category of two-dimensional (2D) metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) called TM3(HADQ)2, and Rh3(HADQ)2 exhibits a promising bifunctional OER/ORR activity, with an overpotential of 0.31 V for both OER and ORR. The d-band center (&#949;d) and crystal orbital Hamilton populations (COHP) are utilized to study the relationship between OER/ORR activity and the electronic structure of catalysts, and it is found that the elementary d-electron number (Ne) of the central TM for TM3(HADQ)2, as well as the electronegativity of the ligand TM-N4 and the intermediate O atom, are the main reason that affects the catalytic activity of OER/ORR. Additionally, Rh3(HADQ)2 can be proven through the constant potential method (CPM) and microkinetics method that it is an acidic OER/ORR bifunctional catalyst. Rh3(HADQ)2 has a high toxicity tolerance, making it a potential bifunctional catalyst. Our research contributes to both the rational design of SACs for various catalytic processes and the fabrication of bifunctional, cost-effective oxygen-electric catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jin Yu, Tianyun Liu, Xuefei Liu, Wei Deng, Wenjun Xiao, Yaqiong Su, Xiaosi Qi, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Xu Wang, Changsong Gao, Hui Xiong, Xiangyu Wu, Jiajin Ge, Jinshun Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bifunctional Imidazolyl Iodide Mediator of Electrolyte Boosts Cathode Kinetics and Anode Stability Towards Low Overpotential and Long&#8208;Life Li&#8208;O2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421107</link>
      <description>Jing Liu, Yuejiao Li, Yajun Ding, Lisha Wu, Jieqiong Qin, Tong Chen, Caixia Meng, Xuechang Zhou, Xiangkun Ma, Zhong-Shuai Wu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405891063

                The addition of a redox mediator as soluble catalyst into electrolyte can effectively overcome the bottlenecks of poor energy efficiency and limited cyclability for Li-O2 batteries caused by passivation of insulating discharge products and unfavorable byproducts. Herein we report a novel soluble catalyst of bifunctional imidazolyl iodide salt additive, 1,3-dimethylimidazole iodide (DMII), to successfully construct highly efficient and durable Li-O2 batteries. The anion I- can effectively promote the charge transport of Li2O2 and accelerate the redox kinetics of oxygen reduction/oxygen evolution reactions on the cathode side, thereby significantly decreasing the charge/discharge overpotential. Simultaneously, the cation DMI+ forms an ultrathin stably solid-electrolyte interphase film on Li metal, greatly inhibiting the shuttle effect of I- and improving the stability of anode. Using this DMII additive, our Li-O2 batteries achieve an extremely low voltage of 0.52 V and ultra-long cycling stability over 960 h. Notably, up to 95.8% of the Li2O2 yield further proves the reversible generation/decomposition of Li2O2 without the occurrence of side reactions. Both experimental and theoretical results disclose that DMII enables Li+ easily solvated, testifying the dominance of the solution-induced reaction mechanism. This work provides the possibility to design the soluble catalysts towards high-performance Li-O2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Jing Liu, Yuejiao Li, Yajun Ding, Lisha Wu, Jieqiong Qin, Tong Chen, Caixia Meng, Xuechang Zhou, Xiangkun Ma, Zhong-Shuai Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bifunctional Imidazolyl Iodide Mediator of Electrolyte Boosts Cathode Kinetics and Anode Stability Towards Low Overpotential and Long&#8208;Life Li&#8208;O2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421107</link>
      <description>Jing Liu, Yuejiao Li, Yajun Ding, Lisha Wu, Jieqiong Qin, Tong Chen, Caixia Meng, Xuechang Zhou, Xiangkun Ma, Zhong-Shuai Wu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405891064

                The addition of a redox mediator as soluble catalyst into electrolyte can effectively overcome the bottlenecks of poor energy efficiency and limited cyclability for Li&#8208;O2 batteries caused by passivation of insulating discharge products and unfavorable byproducts. Herein we report a novel soluble catalyst of bifunctional imidazolyl iodide salt additive, 1,3&#8208;dimethylimidazole iodide (DMII), to successfully construct highly efficient and durable Li&#8208;O2 batteries. The anion I&#8722; can effectively promote the charge transport of Li2O2 and accelerate the redox kinetics of oxygen reduction/oxygen evolution reactions on the cathode side, thereby significantly decreasing the charge/discharge overpotential. Simultaneously, the cation DMI+ forms an ultrathin stably solid&#8208;electrolyte interphase film on Li metal, greatly inhibiting the shuttle effect of I&#8722; and improving the stability of anode. Using this DMII additive, our Li&#8208;O2 batteries achieve an extremely low voltage of 0.52 V and ultra&#8208;long cycling stability over 960 h. Notably, up to 95.8% of the Li2O2 yield further proves the reversible generation/decomposition of Li2O2 without the occurrence of side reactions. Both experimental and theoretical results disclose that DMII enables Li+ easily solvated, testifying the dominance of the solution&#8208;induced reaction mechanism. This work provides the possibility to design the soluble catalysts towards high&#8208;performance Li&#8208;O2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Jing Liu, Yuejiao Li, Yajun Ding, Lisha Wu, Jieqiong Qin, Tong Chen, Caixia Meng, Xuechang Zhou, Xiangkun Ma, Zhong-Shuai Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Nickel Cobalt Hydroxide with Oxygen Vacancies by Intercalation of Oxidizing Anions as a High-Performance Electrode for Supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5076345</link>
      <description>L. Zhang, Junrong Zhang, Jilin Wang, Shuaishuai Zhang, Haijiao Xie, lianke zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405891362

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. Zhang, Junrong Zhang, Jilin Wang, Shuaishuai Zhang, Haijiao Xie, lianke zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5076345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field- assisted synthesis of iron-doped cobalt oxide with abundant oxygen defects as an electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178391</link>
      <description>Jiang Liu, Hong&#8208;Tao Sun, Long Wang, Yukun Huang, Yijun Cao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894149

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiang Liu, Hong&#8208;Tao Sun, Long Wang, Yukun Huang, Yijun Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.178391</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt nanoparticles supported on in-situ growth titanium dioxide nanowire arrays with oxygen vacancies for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162257</link>
      <description>Shipeng Wang, Le Sang, Zipan Jiao, Feiyan Zhang, Yingde Wang, Benhua Xu, Peng Zhang, Bingxin Liu, Yunsi Wang, Yongcheng Li, Riming Hu, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shipeng Wang, Le Sang, Zipan Jiao, Feiyan Zhang, Yingde Wang, Benhua Xu, Peng Zhang, Bingxin Liu, Yunsi Wang, Yongcheng Li, Riming Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precision-Engineered Intermetallic Nanostructured Electrocatalysts for Oxygen and Hydrogen Reactions in Renewable Energy Systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31635/renewables.024.202400073</link>
      <description>Song Jin, Seung Min Woo, Shin&#8208;Woo Myeong, Sungjun Heo, Jun Ho Lee, Nam In Kim, Chiho Kim, Jooyoung Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Min Ho Seo, Renewables. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405916509

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Song Jin, Seung Min Woo, Shin&#8208;Woo Myeong, Sungjun Heo, Jun Ho Lee, Nam In Kim, Chiho Kim, Jooyoung Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Min Ho Seo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31635/renewables.024.202400073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advancements of NiFe-layered double hydroxides for enhanced catalytic activity and Durability in alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31613/ceramist.2024.00164</link>
      <description>Hyeryeon Lee, Seung-Wook Beak, Ki Chang Kwon, Ceramist. 27(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405918124

                Since the industrial revolution, the demand for fossil fuels has increased along with technological advancements, resulting in significant environmental pollution and global warming. To address these issues, the development of renewable energy sources such as wind, solar, and hydrogen is essential for reducing greenhouse gas emissions and meeting energy demand. Among these, hydrogen energy is considered as a promising future energy source due to its energy density and environmentally friendly characteristics. Currently, grey hydrogen is predominantly produced through the steam reforming processes, which relies on fossil fuels and emits large amounts of carbon dioxide. Green hydrogen, generated using renewable energy and electrolysis, has emerged as a sustainable alternative. In electrochemical water splitting, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) needs a higher activation energy compared to the hydrogen evolution reaction, making the development of efficient OER catalysts crucial for energy-efficient hydrogen production. Although noble metal catalysts such as IrO2 and RuO2 are commonly used, their high cost and limited availability have prompted research into transition metal-based alternatives.&lt;/br&gt;NiFe layered double hydroxides (LDHs) have gained attention for their excellent redox properties, charge transport abilities, and effective adsorption of reaction intermediates. However, bulk NiFe-LDHs exhibit low catalytic efficiency due to poor electrical conductivity and a limited number of active sites. To overcome these limitations, various structural modification methods have been developed to improve their catalytic activity and stability. This review provides recent research trends focused on enhancing the performance of NiFe-LDHs through strategies such as heteroatom doping, interface engineering, vacancy creation, and intercalation, with representative studies highlighted to demonstrate these advancements.</description>
      <author>Hyeryeon Lee, Seung-Wook Beak, Ki Chang Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31613/ceramist.2024.00164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orthorhombic Cr&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;PO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; (0 &#8804; &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; &#8804; 0.2): An Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalyst in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02538</link>
      <description>Abhijeet Kumar Singh, Soham Mukherjee, Krishna Gopal Nigam, Asha Gupta, Preetam Singh, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405922627

                In the current scenario of the energy crisis and environmental concerns, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts are of vital importance for their application in metal&#8211;air batteries and efficient water splitting to produce hydrogen. The best possible electrocatalysts for the OER are considered to be noble metal-based materials like RuO2 and IrO2, but their high cost and instability have prevented their wider use for application in large-scale water splitting. Here, we envisaged CrPO4 as a cost-efficient host due to the formation of CrO6 octahedra interconnected through PO4 linkage, making it a stable framework structure to harness eg electrons that are pinned over the O(2p) orbital, required for superior OER activity. The presence of more electronegative Fe3+ or Cr3+ sites in the framework structure, through the inductive effect, enhances the iconicity of the Cr&#8211;O bond in the framework, and creation of CrO42&#8211; groups at the surface of the catalyst directly facilitates the adsorption/desorption of OH&#8211; in the form of &#8211;Cr&#8211;O&#8211;OH, which reduces the overpotential of the OER with higher structural stability of the electrocatalyst. In turn, Cr0.9Fe0.1PO4 demonstrated superior electrocatalytic activity toward the OER in the alkaline electrolyte, together with a low overpotential of 292 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 current density with a Tafel slope of 49 mV dec&#8211;1, better than that of the well-known electrocatalyst RuO2. Enhanced OER activity was observed due to the feasibility of 3-electron transfer with Cr3+/6+ redox as there was a significant increase at the redox peak current density and the presence of Cr6+ also facilitates oxygen evolution due to the strong overlap between Cr(3d) and O(2p) orbitals, which generates superior charge transfer from O(2p) bands to the Cr(3d) orbital, resulting in the reduction of oxygen or evolution of oxygen at a lower overpotential.</description>
      <author>Abhijeet Kumar Singh, Soham Mukherjee, Krishna Gopal Nigam, Asha Gupta, Preetam Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02538</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt and Cerium Dual-Doped Nickel Sulfide Nanostructures as a Bifunctional Catalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06898</link>
      <description>Yu Zhou, Shengnan Song, Yuwei Dong, Xiaotian Gao, Qi Jiang, Zhen Zhao, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405925777

                Developing efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a pivotal challenge in harnessing hydrogen energy. Among the promising candidates, transition metal sulfides have garnered significant research attention due to their low cost and exceptional catalytic capabilities. In this work, we present a strategy to fabricate Co and Ce dual-doping Ni3S2 nanosheets in situ on nickel foam (CoCe-Ni3S2/NF) as an efficient and robust catalyst for overall water splitting. The introduction of Co and Ce dopants can induce an internal electronic interaction for exposing more active sites and accelerating faster electron transfer. Meanwhile, the unique ultrathin two-dimensional (2D) nanosheet array nanostructure, with a thickness of 10 nm, facilitates enhanced electrolyte infiltration and establishes efficient pathways for the release of H2 and O2 bubbles. Density functional theory (DFT) reveals that Co and Ce dual-doping can effectively optimize the d-band center and improve the absorption energy of intermediates. The synergy derived from these design features enables CoCe-Ni3S2/NF to exhibit a remarkable performance in both the OER and the HER, as well as in overall water splitting. In 1.0 M KOH electrolyte, this catalyst achieves impressive low overpotentials of 285 and 193 mV at 50 mA cm&#8211;2 for the OER and HER, respectively. Notably, during overall water-splitting tests, a potential of 1.68 V is achieved at 20 mA cm&#8211;2, accompanied by an outstanding durability for 100 h. These results underscore the exceptional potential of CoCe-Ni3S2/NF as an efficient and robust catalyst for water splitting, paving the way for advancements in sustainable hydrogen energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Yu Zhou, Shengnan Song, Yuwei Dong, Xiaotian Gao, Qi Jiang, Zhen Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Nanogrid-Like Cu-Doped Co-Based Materials via Rapid Self-Exothermic and Chemical Dealloying as Efficient Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-07081-5</link>
      <description>Weijia Guo, Xuewei Xu, Chengyi Xu, Farid Akhtar, Xiaoping Cai, Peizhong Feng, JOM. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405925954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weijia Guo, Xuewei Xu, Chengyi Xu, Farid Akhtar, Xiaoping Cai, Peizhong Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11837-024-07081-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composites of NiFe-Based Layered Double Hydroxide Nanosheets and Ni-Doped Carbon Nanofibers for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06227</link>
      <description>Ziyu Guo, Zihan Wang, Zijia Shang, Jianing Guo, Mingxing Wu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405939666

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyu Guo, Zihan Wang, Zijia Shang, Jianing Guo, Mingxing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Reduction Reconstruction of Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Nanocatalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06077</link>
      <description>Feifei Chen, Yong Zhang, Chang Q. Sun, Yangfan Song, Guozhu Gao, Meiqin Xu, Hong Dong, Feng Lu, Weihua Wang, Hui Liu, Yahui Cheng, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405941491

                Finding effective electrocatalysts from earth-abundant materials for water splitting is crucial for advancing the future hydrogen economy. Fe-based oxides have been identified as highly efficient transition-metal electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, their performance is hindered by inappropriate intermediate binding, low intrinsic conductivity, and poor stability, preventing them from competing with precious metal catalysts. This study presents an effective electrochemical reduction strategy for incorporating oxygen vacancies in situ into Fe3O4/iron foam (IF) nanocatalysts by applying a constant negative voltage. The results indicate that the reduced Fe3O4/IF (referred to as Re-Fe3O4/IF) exhibits enhanced OER performance due to the increased oxygen vacancy, substantial electron transfer rate, and greater electrochemically active surface area. Subsequently, this strategy was applied to Ni element-doped iron oxides with electron redistribution, achieving excellent OER performance. The electrochemically optimized Re-Ni0.8Fe2.2O4&#8211;x/IF nanocatalyst demonstrates a low overpotential of 239 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2, a small Tafel slope of 41.78 mV dec&#8211;1, and an exceptional long-term electrolysis stability of 300 h under alkaline conditions. This study presents a simple and promising approach to induce oxygen vacancies into transition-metal oxides (TMOs)-based OER nanocatalysts for efficient water-splitting systems.</description>
      <author>Feifei Chen, Yong Zhang, Chang Q. Sun, Yangfan Song, Guozhu Gao, Meiqin Xu, Hong Dong, Feng Lu, Weihua Wang, Hui Liu, Yahui Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic Optimization of Single-Atom Catalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A First-Principles and Entropy-Based Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-6thzh</link>
      <description>Chidi Daniel Chukwu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405949083

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER), a cornerstone of electrochemical energy conversion systems such as water splitting and metal-air batteries, is inherently limited by its sluggish kinetics due to the multistep proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) mechanism and high activation barriers. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as a revolutionary strategy to address the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, we present a novel design thermodynamically enhanced for optimizing the rate determining stage of the OER. In line with the Second law of thermodynamics we report the findings from a first principle examination of a novel high-density fish patch single-atom catalyst for OER. We employed DMOL3 and MATLAB for the molecular modelling and computation while MATLAB was used to determine the overpotential constant. With a focus on the effect of the entropy on the reaction rate for Hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the optimum entropy for efficient OER was determine. Applying an external pressure of (0, 0.1333, 0.2667 and 0.4 Pascal) on the system and studying the Gibbs free energy, the study revealed that 0.2667 Pa, is the best position for efficient OER. At this value, &#916;GO2 and &#916;GO -0. 066993 and -0. 06297 (J)</description>
      <author>Chidi Daniel Chukwu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-6thzh</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-fast preparing carbon nanotube-supported Ni-Fe bimetallic compounds as robust electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134227</link>
      <description>Taotao Gao, Qi An, Shumin Yu, Xiangrui Feng, Bing Li, Yanyan Huang, Hai Lan, Dan Xiao, Fuel. 386(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405954677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Taotao Gao, Qi An, Shumin Yu, Xiangrui Feng, Bing Li, Yanyan Huang, Hai Lan, Dan Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of F doped sulfide bifunctional catalyst and investigation on the mechanism transformation of oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158921</link>
      <description>N. Song, Keyi Lv, Bo Feng, Ziyong Zhang, Xiangwen Tan, Yanfei Wei, Ziyang Yan, Yuchao Zhang, Xiaofei Yu, Lanlan Li, Xinghua Zhang, Xiaojing Yang, Ying Li, Zunming Lu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405954787

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. Song, Keyi Lv, Bo Feng, Ziyong Zhang, Xiangwen Tan, Yanfei Wei, Ziyang Yan, Yuchao Zhang, Xiaofei Yu, Lanlan Li, Xinghua Zhang, Xiaojing Yang, Ying Li, Zunming Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158921</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene Supported NiFe-LDH and PbO2 Catalysts Prepared by Plasma Process for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18010121</link>
      <description>Tingting Yang, Zheng Zhang, Fei Tan, Huayu Liu, Xingyu Li, Hongqi Wang, Qing Yang, Materials. 18(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405954956

                The development of efficient catalysts for water electrolysis is crucial for advancing the low-carbon transition and addressing the energy crisis. This work involves the fabrication of graphene-based catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by integrating NiFe-LDH and PbO2 onto graphene using plasma treatment. The plasma process takes only 30 min. Graphene&#8217;s two-dimensional structure increases the available reaction surface area and improves surface electron transport. Plasma treatment further improves catalyst performance by facilitating nanoparticle attachment and creating carbon defects and sulfur vacancies. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations at the PBE provide valuable insights into the role of vacancies in enhancing catalyst performance for OER. The catalyst&#8217;s conductivity and electronic structure are greatly impacted by vacancies. While modifications to the electronic structure increase the kinetics of charge transfer, the vacancy structure can produce more active sites and improve the adsorption and reactivity of OER intermediates. This optimization of intermediate adsorption and electronic properties leads to increased overall OER activity. The catalyst NiFe-PbO2/S/rGO-45, synthesized through plasma treatment, demonstrated an overpotential of 230 mV at 50 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 44.26 mV dec&#8722;1, exhibiting rapid reaction kinetics and surpassing the OER activity of commercial IrO2. With its excellent performance, the prepared catalyst has broad prospects in commercial applications such as water electrolysis and air batteries.</description>
      <author>Tingting Yang, Zheng Zhang, Fei Tan, Huayu Liu, Xingyu Li, Hongqi Wang, Qing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18010121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Mediated High-Entropy Oxide Electrocatalysts for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2024.100086</link>
      <description>Ruonan Liu, Yaotian Yan, Liang Dun, Taili Yang, Bin Qin, Peijia Wang, Wei Cai, Shude Liu, Xiaohang Zheng, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405962068

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruonan Liu, Yaotian Yan, Liang Dun, Taili Yang, Bin Qin, Peijia Wang, Wei Cai, Shude Liu, Xiaohang Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2024.100086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Neuron-like Structured NiS2/MOF Composites with Enhanced Regulation of Electron Transport and Active Sites for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30010080</link>
      <description>Yanli Guo, Di Zhou, Yanyan Huang, Xiaolong Song, Wei He, Molecules. 30(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405974844

                Constructing fast electron transfer pathways and abundant electro-active sites is an effective strategy to improve the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of catalysts. Herein, structural engineering and dual-phase engineering were employed to construct a NiS2 nanoparticle-encapsulated MOF configured with a pseudo-neuronal structure (NiS2/MOF/HT). It was found that the pseudo-neuronal structure, constructed with a carbon nanohorn (CNH) and carbon nanotube (CNT), provided fast electron transfer pathways and abundant exposed active sites. Moreover, the NiS2/MOF/HT composite obtained via partial vulcanization not only inherited the pseudo-neuronal structure but also prevented the aggregation and growth of NiS2 particles. NiS2/MOF composites provide various active sites. With the combination of the promotion of electronic transfer and enrichment of electro-active sites (NiS2, MOF), NiS2/MOF/HT showed excellent performance, whose overpotential at 25 mA cm&#8722;2 was reduced by 19.5% compared with MOF/HT.</description>
      <author>Yanli Guo, Di Zhou, Yanyan Huang, Xiaolong Song, Wei He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30010080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Significantly Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of RuO2 Nanoparticles by Introducing Oxygen Vacancy with Polytetrafluoroethylene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/polym17010059</link>
      <description>Jinyang Zhang, Xinru Wang, Xinyue Zhao, Honglei Chen, Peng Jia, Polymers. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405934607

                The supported RuO2 catalysts are known for their synergistic and interfacial effects, which significantly enhance both catalytic activity and stability. However, polymer-supported RuO2 catalysts have received limited attention due to challenges associated with poor conductivity. In this study, we successfully synthesized the RuO2-polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) catalyst via a facile annealing process. The optimized nucleation and growth strategies enable the formation of RuO2 particles (~13.4 nm) encapsulating PTFE, establishing a conductive network that effectively addresses the conductivity issue. Additionally, PTFE induces the generation of oxygen vacancies and the formation of stable RuO2/PTFE interfaces, which further enhance the acidic OER activity and the stability of RuO2. As a result, the RuO2-PTFE catalyst exhibits a low overpotential of 219 mV at 10 mA cm&#8315;2 in the three-electrode system, and the voltage of the RuO2-PTFE||commercial Pt/C system can keep 1.50 V for 800 h at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. This work underscores the versatility of PTFE as a substrate for fine-tuning the catalyst morphology, the crystal defect, and the stable interface outerwear. This work not only broadens the application scope of PTFE in catalyst synthesis but also provides a novel approach to the design of high-performance metallic oxide catalysts with tailored oxygen vacancy concentration and stable polymer outerwear.</description>
      <author>Jinyang Zhang, Xinru Wang, Xinyue Zhao, Honglei Chen, Peng Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/polym17010059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction activity of Ni3(PO4)2 and bimetallic Ni3M3(PO4)4 (M = Mn, Fe, Co): Insights from DFT and experimental validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134183</link>
      <description>Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, C. Mariani, Fadjar Fathurrahman, Brian Yuliarto, Hermawan Kresno Dipojono, Hamad AlMohamadi, Sasfan Arman Wella, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro, Fuel. 385(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405841347

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Arkan Nuruzzahran, Dzaki Ahmad Syaifullah, C. Mariani, Fadjar Fathurrahman, Brian Yuliarto, Hermawan Kresno Dipojono, Hamad AlMohamadi, Sasfan Arman Wella, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Adhitya Gandaryus Saputro</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.134183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A mathematical model of dissolved oxygen transport during the thermal bar evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17223/19988621/86/14</link>
      <description>Bair O. Tsydenov, Vestnik Tomskogo gosudarstvennogo universiteta Matematika i mekhanika. None(86)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4405951519

                The article describes &#1072; 2.5D non-hydrostatic model of dissolved oxygen transport in a freshwater lake. The oxygen dynamics are carried out through oxygen exchange with the atmosphere and physical transfer due to the effect of the thermal bar. An intraday change in wind speed (that influences the rate of oxygen transition from gas to liquid) is taken into account at the air-water interface. Space-time distributions of temperature and dissolved oxygen concentration were obtained during the spring thermal bar on an example of Barguzin Bay of Lake Baikal. The results of simulation showed that the vertical flows generated by the spring thermal bar contributed to an increase in dissolved oxygen content in the thermoactive region of the bay. Due to the action of the thermal bar, areas with different levels of oxygen are formed in the body of water. There is not only a quantitative but also a qualitative difference between the oxygen distributions obtained for the thermoactive and the thermoinert regions. It has been also found that the wind speed and the wind duration affect the oxygen saturation of water at the thermal bar. The results of this study confirm the barrier function of the thermal bar.</description>
      <author>Bair O. Tsydenov</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17223/19988621/86/14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How biofilm and granular sludge cope with dissolved oxygen exposure in anammox process: Performance, bioaccumulation characteristics and bacterial evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123986</link>
      <description>Ben-ze Chang, Xiaolan Huang, Dongzhi Chen, Ren&#8208;Cun Jin, Guangfeng Yang, Journal of Environmental Management. 373(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405926079

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ben-ze Chang, Xiaolan Huang, Dongzhi Chen, Ren&#8208;Cun Jin, Guangfeng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.123986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Dynamic Phase Evolution in Cuo/Al&#8322;O&#8323; Oxygen Carriers for High-Temperature Chemical Looping Combustion Via in Situ Xas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5077502</link>
      <description>Sharmin Sharna, Virgile Rouchon, Arnold Lambert, Val&#233;rie BRIOIS, David Chiche, Anne&#8208;Sophie Gay, C. Legens, Ovidiu Ersen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405953449

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sharmin Sharna, Virgile Rouchon, Arnold Lambert, Val&#233;rie BRIOIS, David Chiche, Anne&#8208;Sophie Gay, C. Legens, Ovidiu Ersen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5077502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Highly Effective Bifunctional Catalyst to Oxygen Reduction and Evolution Reactions by Coupling Nickel Hydroxide with Mesoporous Nitrogen-Doped Carbon Networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5077608</link>
      <description>Zhongping Xiong, Jingqi Sha, Tao Xu, Min Yao, Chao Wu, Qingxiu Shi, Xingwen Zheng, Yujun Si, Zhiwei Jiang, Chaozhong Guo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405918017

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongping Xiong, Jingqi Sha, Tao Xu, Min Yao, Chao Wu, Qingxiu Shi, Xingwen Zheng, Yujun Si, Zhiwei Jiang, Chaozhong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5077608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Tailoring of a Multi-Element Nanocomposite for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma01262c</link>
      <description>Mohamed Okasha, Vivek Maheshwari, Materials Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405836307

                Multielement combinations either as high entropy alloys or as nanocomposites are highly effective electrocatalysts for key reactions such as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER)....</description>
      <author>Mohamed Okasha, Vivek Maheshwari</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma01262c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy formation mechanism and synergy with doping in NiS2-based electrocatalyst for benzyl alcohol oxidation and hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03098b</link>
      <description>Fang Li, Haili Lin, Huiqin Yu, Pengfei Du, Yang Wang, Jing Cao, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405947619

                Substituting the kinetic-sluggish oxygen evolution reaction with the thermodynamically favorable benzyl alcohol oxidation reaction is a compelling strategy to produce high-value chemicals and hydrogen. Herein, phosphorus (P) doped hollow spherical...</description>
      <author>Fang Li, Haili Lin, Huiqin Yu, Pengfei Du, Yang Wang, Jing Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03098b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating electronic structure of Co-N5S1 sites in Co single atom catalysts via phosphorus incorporation and nanoclusters to promote oxygen electrocatalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2024.247</link>
      <description>Jing Peng, Ting Xue, Zhitong Li, Junwei Shi, Xingzhu Wang, Baomin Xu, Energy Materials. 4(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405882734

                Atomically dispersed metal catalysts coordinated with nitrogen coordination and anchored to carbon substrates (M-N-C) have become highly effective alternatives to platinum-group catalysts for oxygen electrocatalysis. However, the catalytic efficacy of M-N-C systems remains constrained by the suboptimal performance associated with the symmetric charge distribution around the active metal centers. The synergistic co-design of asymmetric metal single-atom catalytic centers with heteroatom doping significantly enhances the bifunctional oxygen electrocatalytic activity and durability, advancing the capabilities of next-generation flexible zinc-air batteries. Herein, we developed a pyrolysis-secondary coordination strategy to generate a bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst, characterized by single Co atoms integrated within an asymmetrical Co-N5S1 moiety, along with nanocluster complexes embedded in N,P,S-codoped carbon frameworks, labeled CoSA+NC/NPSC. In the CoSA+NC/NPSC catalyst, the Co-N5S1 active sites exhibit an optimized electronic configuration, achieved through the synergistic coordination of heteroatom doping and nanocluster integration. Theoretically, this configuration significantly lowers the energy barriers and adjusts the d-band center, ensuring a more balanced binding strength between active sites and the oxygen-containing intermediates and contributing to the promoted bifunctional oxygen reduction reaction/oxygen evolution reaction efficiency. The experimentally analytical results reveal that the CoSA+NC/NPSC demonstrates an impressive oxygen evolution reaction activity (Ej=10 = 1.58 V) and a narrow bifunctional potential gap (&#916;E = 0.75 V), remarkably superior to the counterparts with symmetric Co-S coordination or phosphorus-free doping. When assembled as an air electrode, the CoSA+NC/NPSC-based flexible zinc-air battery exhibits ultralong charge-discharge life (&gt;105 h) and impressive initial round-trip efficiency of 72.42% even at 0 &#176;C.</description>
      <author>Jing Peng, Ting Xue, Zhitong Li, Junwei Shi, Xingzhu Wang, Baomin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/energymater.2024.247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Alkali Metal Ions in Cooperative Electrocatalysis by Bifunctional Co&#8208;Mn&#8208;Mixed Phosphates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401177</link>
      <description>Ramaswamy Murugavel, Savi Chaudhary, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405947590

                Developing cost-effective, non-precious metal bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for advancing sustainable energy storage and conversion technologies, including zinc-air batteries, fuel cells, and water electrolyzers. This study presents a one-pot synthesis of cobalt-manganese mixed phosphates as effective bifunctional electrocatalysts for both ORR and OER. Among the catalysts tested, Na-Co-Mn-P [NaCo1.5Mn1.5(HPO4)2(PO4)] exhibited the highest catalytic activity, with a minimal &#916;E of 0.86 V, indicating superior performance. The incorporation of alkali metals and the synergistic effects of metal and phosphate components enhance conductivity, electrochemical surface area, and mixed valency of transition metals, contributing to improved electrocatalytic activity. This work highlights a straightforward synthesis method and the beneficial role of metal-phosphate synergy in oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Ramaswamy Murugavel, Savi Chaudhary</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying and tuning coordinated water molecules for efficient electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55120-1</link>
      <description>Geng Zhang, Wei Guo, Hong Zheng, Xiang Li, Jinxin Wang, Qiuyu Zhang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894862

                Coordination complexes are promising candidates for powerful electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction but challenges remain in favoring the kinetics behaviors through local coordination regulation. Herein, by refining the synergy of carboxylate anions and multiconjugated benzimidazole ligands, we tailor a series of well-defined and stable coordination complexes with three-dimensional supramolecular/coordinated structures. The coordinated water as potential open coordination sites can directly become intermediates, while the metal center easily achieves re-coordination with water molecules in the pores to resist lattice oxygen dissolution. In situ experiments and theory simulations indicate that nickel centers with neighboring coordinated water molecules follow an intramolecular oxygen coupling mechanism with a low thermodynamic energy barrier. With more coordinated water introduced, an optimized intramolecular oxygen coupling process may appear for favoring the reaction kinetics. As such, a low overpotential of 248 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Geng Zhang, Wei Guo, Hong Zheng, Xiang Li, Jinxin Wang, Qiuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55120-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing the Fe Species of Nickel&#8208;Iron Double Hydroxide via Chelating Asymmetric Aldehyde&#8208;Containing THB Ligand for Long&#8208;Lasting Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202419887</link>
      <description>Yifan Huang, Fantao Kong, Yu Xu, Tao Yang, Ping Wu, Ruxiang Shen, Shangjun Zhuo, Xiangzhi Cui, Jianlin Shi, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405950807

                Nickel-iron layered double hydroxides (NiFe LDHs) are considered as promising substitutes for precious metals in oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, most of the reported NiFe LDHs suffer from poor long-term stability because of the Fe loss during OER resulting in severe inactivation. Herein, a dynamically stable chelating interface through in situ transformation of asymmetric aldehyde-ligand (THB, 1,3,5-Tris(3'-hydroxy-4'-formylphenyl)-benzene) modified NiFe LDHs to anchor Fe and significantly enhance the OER stability is reported. The fabricated asymmetric aldehyde-containing ligand THB is capable of stimulating much more interfacial charge transfer from NiFe LDHs to the oxygen group of THB and accelerating the formation of highly valent active Fe species leading to the strong combination between Fe and ligand and the reduced activation energy barrier of the intermediate, respectively. The optimized aldehyde-ligand-chelated NiFe LDHs (NiFe LDH/THB) shows enhanced OER performance featuring an overpotential of 224 mV at 100 mA cm</description>
      <author>Yifan Huang, Fantao Kong, Yu Xu, Tao Yang, Ping Wu, Ruxiang Shen, Shangjun Zhuo, Xiangzhi Cui, Jianlin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202419887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anodic Activation of Prussian Blue Analog Leads to Highly Active Cobalt&#8208;doped Nickel (Oxy)hydroxide for Organic Oxidation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202404174</link>
      <description>Toufik Ansari, Debabrata Bagchi, Suptish Ghosh, J. Niklas Hausmann, Arindam Indra, Prashanth W. Menezes, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405888854

                Water-assisted electrocatalytic oxidation of alcohols into valuable chemicals is a promising strategy to circumvent the sluggish kinetics of water oxidation, while also reducing cell voltage and improving energy efficiency. Recently, transition metal (TM)-based catalysts have been investigated for anodic alcohol oxidation, but success has been limited due to competition from the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) within the working regime. In this study, NiCo-based Prussian blue analog (PBA) was electrochemically activated at the anodic potential to produce a Co-Ni(O)OH active catalyst with a nanosheet-like architecture. This catalyst was further employed for the selective oxidation of benzyl alcohol (PhCH2OH) to benzoic acid (PhCOOH), achieving a 97% Faradaic efficiency (FE). The electrochemical activity of Co-Ni(O)OH was also compared with hydrothermally prepared CoNi-LDH, demonstrating that the PBA-derived Co-Ni(O)OH was more effective.</description>
      <author>Toufik Ansari, Debabrata Bagchi, Suptish Ghosh, J. Niklas Hausmann, Arindam Indra, Prashanth W. Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202404174</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research and Progress in Mitigating Carbon Oxidation in Air Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417580</link>
      <description>Jin&#8208;Ge Fan, Jianmin Pan, Han Wang, Sheng Liu, Yi Zhan, Xingbin Yan, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405814509

                Abstract Oxygen electrocatalysis plays a pivotal role in fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries, which hold immense potential for energy conversion and storage systems due to their superior theoretical energy density, cost&#8208;effectiveness, and safety profile. However, carbon&#8208;based materials in air electrode face challenges stemming from the harsh oxidative environment of oxygen catalysis, leading to thermodynamic instability. This underscores the urgent necessity for the development of effective carbon anti&#8208;oxidation strategies. This comprehensive review initially explores the complex mechanisms underlying the oxygen reduction/oxygen evolution reactions (ORR/OER) and the prevalent issue of carbon corrosion in carbon&#8208;based materials. It then delves into diverse strategies aimed at mitigating catalyst corrosion through doped carbons, encompassing techniques such as graphitization, active site management, surface modification using functional groups, and corrosion resistance coating. Moreover, the review discusses methods to counteract carbon oxidation in catalyst supports, including the utilization of novel carbons, highly active catalysts to minimize oxidation, and the exploration of non&#8208;carbon alternatives. Furthermore, the review also sheds light on protecting current collectors and conductive additives within the air electrode from corrosion. Ultimately, it outlines emerging challenges and opportunities for addressing carbon oxidation in air electrode, paving the way for enhanced performance and longevity in fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Jin&#8208;Ge Fan, Jianmin Pan, Han Wang, Sheng Liu, Yi Zhan, Xingbin Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417580</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study on the Photoelectrochemical Hydrogen Production from the Layout Optimization in a Unit Cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaelm.4c01817</link>
      <description>M.-H. Lee, Jun Kim, Jeehye Kim, Youn Jeong Jang, Jin Young Kim, ACS Applied Electronic Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405943124

                Solar-driven water splitting is achieved by connecting photovoltaics with electrolysis. Recently, integrated approaches of the two configurations for photoelectrochemical reactions have shown great potential in a combined unit, but strategies to address further material and cell development face significant scientific challenges. Here we present an experimental demonstration of photoelectrochemical (PEC) unit-cells with efficient separate dual compartments for oxygen evolution and hydrogen evolution reactions. The design and fabrication of cell architectures with various degrees of integration are investigated efficient and sustainable PEC processes. The effect of the nanostructured silicon (Si) photoelectrodes, including the adoption of layer architectures, surface protection layer deposition, and membrane electrode assembly is further studied to optimize the design parameters of the PEC unit-cells. This developed PEC cell with the Si photocathode achieved a photocurrent density of &#8722;4.8 mA cm&#8211;2 at &#8722;2.0 Vcell and &#8722;2.87 mA cm&#8211;2 at &#8722;1.6 Vcell. It clearly provides a critical milestone for unbiased solar water splitting. Practical solar to hydrogen (STH) can be directly estimated in investigating PEC performance in this unit-cell as assembled with a solar cell. It is a significantly meaningful step forward in practical solar fuel production.</description>
      <author>M.-H. Lee, Jun Kim, Jeehye Kim, Youn Jeong Jang, Jin Young Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaelm.4c01817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Heteroatomic Bond&#8208;Induced Confined Restructuring on Ir&#8208;Mn Intermetallics Enable Robust PEM Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420470</link>
      <description>Shuang Wang, Yan Shi, Tao Shen, Guangzhe Wang, Yue Sun, Gongwei Wang, Xiao Li, Changfeng Yan, Chundong Wang, Hongfang Liu, Ying Wang, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Lin Zhuang, Deli Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405826771

                Low&#8208;iridium acid&#8208;stabilized electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial for the market deployment of proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis. Manipulating the in situ reconstruction of Ir&#8208;based catalysts with favorable kinetics is highly desirable but remains elusive. Herein, we propose an atomic ordering strategy to modulate the dynamic surface restructuring of catalysts to break the activity/stability trade&#8208;off. Under working conditions, the strong heteroatom&#8208;bonded structure triggers rational surface&#8208;confined reconstruction to form self&#8208;stabilizing amorphous (oxy)hydroxides on the model Ir&#8208;Mn intermetallic (IMC). Combined in&#8208;situ/ex&#8208;situ characterizations and theoretical analysis demonstrate that the induced strong covalent Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Mn units in the catalytic layer weaken the formation barrier of OOH* and promote the preferential dynamic replenishment/conversion pathway of H2O molecules to suppress the uncontrollable participation of lattice oxygen (about 2.6 times lower than that of pure Ir). Thus, a PEM cell with Ir&#8208;Mn IMC as anode &#8220;pre&#8208;electrocatalyst&#8221; (0.24 mgIr cm&#8722;2) delivers an impressive performance (3.0 A cm&#8722;2@1.851 V@80 &#176;C) and runs stably at 2.0 A cm&#8722;2 for more than 2,000 h with the cost of USD 0.98 per kg H2, further validating its promising application. This work highlights surface&#8208;confined evolution triggered by strong heteroatom bonds, providing insights into the design of catalysts involving surface reconstruction.</description>
      <author>Shuang Wang, Yan Shi, Tao Shen, Guangzhe Wang, Yue Sun, Gongwei Wang, Xiao Li, Changfeng Yan, Chundong Wang, Hongfang Liu, Ying Wang, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Lin Zhuang, Deli Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Tuning of Fe&#8208;O Covalency via Bioengineering for Facilitating Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423330</link>
      <description>Guang Li, Shengqi Zhang, W.-J. Li, Zhuangzhuang Bi, Jiajie Wu, Yuxi Chen, Ge Lin, Bo Wu, Lei Li, Qing Qu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405951176

                Abstract The applications of Fe&#8208;based electrocatalysts in oxygen evolution reactions (OER) and hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) are hindered due to poor stability and catalytic activity originating from rapid Fe leaching and the intrinsic electronic structure of FeOOH. Here, the study presents a strategy to precisely and continuously tune the morphology of FeOOH and the covalent characteristics of Fe&#8211;O bonds by controlling the coverage of extracellular polymeric substances (EPS) on the FeOOH surface. Operando spectroscopy and theoretical calculations reveal that regulating Fe&#8211;O covalency induces changes in intermediate adsorption strength and metal leaching, leading to a volcano&#8208;shaped trend in durability and activity as a function of Fe&#8211;O covalency. Notably, in HER, negatively charged sites of EPS exhibit superior *H adsorption compared to bare FeOOH. In particular, EPS 2 @FeOOH exhibits excellent catalytic performance for both OER (&#951; 10 = 240 mV) and HER (&#951; 10 = 52 mV), with outstanding stability over 200 hours at 100 mA cm&#8315; 2 . The current density also reaches 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 at merely 1.51 V in a two&#8208;electrode configuration, significantly surpassing other bifunctional electrocatalysts. This approach will provide a promising pathway to enhance the stability and activity of water electrolysis through precise modulation of EPS coverage.</description>
      <author>Guang Li, Shengqi Zhang, W.-J. Li, Zhuangzhuang Bi, Jiajie Wu, Yuxi Chen, Ge Lin, Bo Wu, Lei Li, Qing Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering Induced Homogeneous Isomeric Bimetallic of CoSe/NiSe&#8322; Electrocatalysts for High Performance Water/Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400849</link>
      <description>Huiya Zhou, Ruiyu Li, Songlin Xu, Boyao Zhang, Rongda Zhao, Xing&#8208;Ming Zhao, Fufa Wu, Depeng Zhao, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405953372

                Abstract As a subclass of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), zeolitic imidazolate frameworks (ZIFs) possess a highly ordered porous structure, extensive surface area, and accessible catalytically active sites, demonstrating significant potential in catalytic applications. Although the catalytic activity of individual ZIFs is relatively low, their pore structure and size distribution can be rationally designed and optimized through appropriate chemical modifications and post&#8208;treatment strategies to enhance their catalytic performance. This process requires meticulous control of ZIFs materials to meet the specific demands of catalytic reactions. In this study, a series of CoSe/NiSe 2 nanosheets is synthesized with precisely engineered morphology and architecture using a precursor route involving ZIFs. Notably, the CoSe/NiSe 2 &#8208;3 nanosheets exhibit a remarkable overpotential of 250.5 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline seawater and 215.3 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1.0 m KOH electrolyte for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Furthermore, when used as a hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst, the material also shows excellent electrocatalytic activity. When integrated with the a forementioned electrocatalyst into a full cell configuration, the device operates at a low voltage of 1.956 V at a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in an alkaline seawater medium, while maintaining excellent stability over a 12&#8208;h operational period.</description>
      <author>Huiya Zhou, Ruiyu Li, Songlin Xu, Boyao Zhang, Rongda Zhao, Xing&#8208;Ming Zhao, Fufa Wu, Depeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Significant Reduction of Anode Reaction Overpotential in Alkaline Water Electrolysis by Ultrathin NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide in Ethanol&#8208;added Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401950</link>
      <description>Huiying Wang, Mengtian Huo, Yu Liang, Kaichi Qin, Qianyu Li, Wei Liu, Zihao Xing, Jinfa Chang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405919280

                Electrochemical alkaline water electrolysis (AWE) is regarded as an effective method for producing high&#8208;purity hydrogen without relying on platinum group metal (PGM) as catalyst. However, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), as the anode half&#8208;reaction, involves a four&#8208;electron transfer process with slow kinetics, which significantly reduces the overall reaction efficiency of AWE. Although highly efficient catalysts can accelerate the OER reaction rate, the high overpotential of the anode still remains an important factor hindering AWE. Herein, ultrathin NiFe layered double hydroxide (U&#8208;NiFe LDH) nanosheet arrays were synthesized and used as anode catalysts due to their robust structure, excellent flexibility, and effective interlayer anion compensation. Only 250 mV of overpotential was required for OER to reach a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 1 M KOH. Incorporating the additive ethanol into KOH electrolyte further reduces the required overpotential of AWE to 114 mV. The anode overpotential could be decreased by 130 mV at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8208;2 in a three&#8208;electrode electrolysis system with U&#8208;NiFe LDH as the anode. This work provides a possible approach for the development of low&#8208;energy and green AWE technology for electrocatalytic hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Huiying Wang, Mengtian Huo, Yu Liang, Kaichi Qin, Qianyu Li, Wei Liu, Zihao Xing, Jinfa Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructed Hydroxyl Coordination Field Enhances Mass Transfer for Efficient Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409111</link>
      <description>Haomin Jiang, Haohai Dong, Yicheng Liu, Qiuhong Wan, Feng Pan, Shuting Zhang, Zhuojin Yang, Yingzhi Chen, Le Chen, Xiaofang Zheng, Lanke Luo, Peiyuan Su, Jie Wu, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405880488

                Abstract Mass transfer factor plays an indispensable role in high current density to accelerate the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process, yet research on modulating reactant mass transport remains limited. Herein, by leveraging the dual acid&#8208;base properties of aluminum sites, both the activation of the electronic activity of the layer for layered double hydroxides (LDH) and construction of the interlayer hydroxide coordination field (IHCF) have been achieved through in situ electrochemical reconstruction. It not only facilitates charge transfer and the surface catalytic transformation of reaction intermediates but, most notably, the presence of the IHCF significantly enhances the mass transport of reactants. As a result, the overpotential of LDHs with IHCF is only 164 mV, significantly better than the reported Ni&#8208;based catalysts. Deuterium kinetic isotope effect experiments and pH&#8208;dependence measurements demonstrate that the IHCF effectively enhances substrate mass transport capability and structural stability, thereby accelerating the proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer process. To further validate the high mass transport characteristics, stability tests of the alkaline flow electrolyzer show that catalysts maintain over 1000 h of stability at a high current density. This work suggests that the IHCF effect can be utilized for further design and synthesis of efficient water oxidation catalysts for practical application.</description>
      <author>Haomin Jiang, Haohai Dong, Yicheng Liu, Qiuhong Wan, Feng Pan, Shuting Zhang, Zhuojin Yang, Yingzhi Chen, Le Chen, Xiaofang Zheng, Lanke Luo, Peiyuan Su, Jie Wu, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Modulation Induced by the Synergy of Cobalt Low-Nuclearity Clusters and Mononuclear Sites for Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c15035</link>
      <description>Zhijun Li, Hongxue Liu, Yuhao Wang, Siqi Ji, Yuqi Zhang, Yu Liu, Xue Lu, H Teng, J. Hugh Horton, Yu Wang, Xinzhi Ma, Yujia Tang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405829683

                The development of high-performance bifunctional single-atom catalysts for use in applications, such as zinc-air batteries, is greatly impeded by mild oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER). Herein, we report a bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst designed to overcome these limitations. The catalyst consists of well-dispersed low-nuclearity Co clusters and adjacent Co single atoms over a nitrogen-doped carbon matrix (Co</description>
      <author>Zhijun Li, Hongxue Liu, Yuhao Wang, Siqi Ji, Yuqi Zhang, Yu Liu, Xue Lu, H Teng, J. Hugh Horton, Yu Wang, Xinzhi Ma, Yujia Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c15035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unearthing the secrets of Australia&#8217;s most enigmatic and cryptic mammal, the marsupial mole</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado4140</link>
      <description>Stephen Frankenberg, Sarah Lucas, Charles Y. Feigin, Liliya Doronina, Raphael Steffen, Gabrielle A. Hartley, Patrick G. S. Grady, Brandon R. Menzies, Ricardo De Paoli&#8208;Iseppi, Stephen C. Donnellan, M Klein, Axel H. Newton, J. Roy Black, Michael B. Clark, Steven J. Cooper, Rachel J. O&#8217;Neill, Nathan L. Clark, J&#252;rgen Schmitz, Andrew J. Pask, Science Advances. 11(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405967775

                The marsupial moles are arguably Australia&#8217;s most enigmatic marsupials. Almost indistinguishable from placental (eutherian) moles, they provide a striking example of convergent evolution. Exploring the genome of the southern marsupial mole, we provide insights into its unusual biology. We show definitively by retrophylogenomic analysis that marsupial moles are most closely related to bandicoots and bilbies (order Peramelemorphia). We find evidence of a marked decline in marsupial mole effective population size, most likely preceding the arrival of humans in regions near its range, and potentially corresponding to periods of climatic change. Our analysis of loss of eye function&#8212;an adaptation to subterranean life&#8212;reveals a structured order of loss of gene function associated first with the lens, then cone, and finally rod cells. Last, we identify genetic changes suggestive of adaptation to an oxygen-poor environment and of its evolution of partially descended testes.</description>
      <author>Stephen Frankenberg, Sarah Lucas, Charles Y. Feigin, Liliya Doronina, Raphael Steffen, Gabrielle A. Hartley, Patrick G. S. Grady, Brandon R. Menzies, Ricardo De Paoli&#8208;Iseppi, Stephen C. Donnellan, M Klein, Axel H. Newton, J. Roy Black, Michael B. Clark, Steven J. Cooper, Rachel J. O&#8217;Neill, Nathan L. Clark, J&#252;rgen Schmitz, Andrew J. Pask</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.ado4140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transit absorption in the oxygen lines for constraining the atmosphere temperature of hot exoplanets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26119/vak2024.139</link>
      <description>A V Shepelin, M. P. Golubovsky, &#1048;. &#1060;. &#1064;&#1072;&#1081;&#1093;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1072;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405840985

                Atomic oxygen, due to its unique chemical properties, is widely used in astrophysics to study chemical composition, nucleosynthesis conditions, and the processes of formation and evolution. The recent detection of the O I 1304 &#197; and 7774 &#197; lines in the upper atmospheres of exoplanets using space and ground-based telescopes opens the possibility to evaluate its abundance in these objects and constrain important atmospheric parameters. However, the simple approximation of thermodynamic equilibrium is often inaccurate in describing the formation and absorption for many spectral lines in stars and hot exoplanets. The development of a kinetic model that takes into account detailed radiative and collisional processes in advanced atomic models is required to interpret the observations. In this work we for the first time analyze the advantages of transit absorption measurement of two oxygen lines simultaneously.</description>
      <author>A V Shepelin, M. P. Golubovsky, &#1048;. &#1060;. &#1064;&#1072;&#1081;&#1093;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1072;&#1084;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26119/vak2024.139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium Isotopes: A Window into Atmospheric Oxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31223/x5t14q</link>
      <description>YunQian Zhang, EarthArXiv (California Digital Library). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405923964

                Chromium (Cr) isotopes are pivotal proxies for understanding Earth&#8217;s atmospheric oxygenation history. This review highlights &#948;53Cr signatures as tools for reconstructing redox dynamics during events like the Great Oxidation Event (GOE) and the Neoproterozoic Oxygenation Event (NOE). Advances in analytical techniques, particularly multi-collector inductively coupled plasma mass spectrometry (MC-ICP-MS), have enhanced &#948;53Cr measurement precision, revealing critical insights into oxidative weathering and atmospheric oxygenation. Challenges such as local environmental variability and uncertainties in oxygen thresholds remain, but integrating &#948;53Cr with complementary proxies promises a more comprehensive view of Earth&#8217;s redox evolution. This synthesis underscores the transformative role of Cr isotopes in tracing oxygenation processes and their implications for the evolution of the biosphere.</description>
      <author>YunQian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31223/x5t14q</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ visualization of interfacial processes at nanoscale in non-alkaline Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55239-1</link>
      <description>Jiao Wang, Shuang&#8208;Yan Lang, Zhen-Zhen Shen, Yanliang Zhang, Guixian Liu, Yuexian Song, Ruizhi Liu, Bing Liu, Rui Wen, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894530

                Zn-air batteries (ZABs) present high energy density and high safety but suffer from low oxygen reaction reversibility and dendrite growth at Zn electrode in alkaline electrolytes. Non-alkaline electrolytes have been considered recently for improving the interfacial processes in ZABs. However, the dynamic evolution and reaction mechanisms regulated by electrolytes at both the positive and Zn negative electrodes remain elusive. Herein, using in situ atomic force microscopy, we disclose that thin ZnO</description>
      <author>Jiao Wang, Shuang&#8208;Yan Lang, Zhen-Zhen Shen, Yanliang Zhang, Guixian Liu, Yuexian Song, Ruizhi Liu, Bing Liu, Rui Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55239-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Classification of Young Stellar Objects and Evolved Stars in the Magellanic Clouds Using the Probabilistic Random Forest Classifier</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52526/25792776-24.71.2-377</link>
      <description>Sepideh Ghaziasgar, Mahdi Abdollahi, Atefeh Javadi, Jacco Th. van Loon, Iain McDonald, J. M. Oliveira, Habib G. Khosroshahi, Communications of the Byurakan Astrophysical Observatory. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405851336

                The Magellanic Clouds (MCs) are excellent locations to study stellar dust emission and its contribution to galaxy evolution. Through spectral and photometric classification, MCs can serve as a unique environment for studying stellar evolution and galaxies enriched by dusty stellar point sources. We applied machine learning classifiers to spectroscopically labeled data from the Surveying the Agents of Galaxy Evolution (SAGE) project, which involved 12 multiwavelength filters and 618 stellar objects at the MCs. We classified stars into five categories: young stellar objects (YSOs), carbon-rich asymptotic giant branch (CAGB) stars, oxygen-rich AGB (OAGB) stars, red supergiants (RSG), and post-AGB (PAGB) stars. Following this, we augmented the distribution of imbalanced classes using the Synthetic Minority Oversampling Technique (SMOTE). Therefore, the Probabilistic Random Forest (PRF) classifier achieved the highest overall accuracy, reaching 89% based on the recall metric, in categorizing dusty stellar sources before and after data augmentation. In this study, SMOTE did not impact the classification accuracy for the CAGB, PAGB, and RSG categories but led to changes in the performance of the OAGB and YSO classes.</description>
      <author>Sepideh Ghaziasgar, Mahdi Abdollahi, Atefeh Javadi, Jacco Th. van Loon, Iain McDonald, J. M. Oliveira, Habib G. Khosroshahi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52526/25792776-24.71.2-377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A molecular dynamics study of the local structure evolution with temperature in Gd-doped CeO2: Focus on the bond length</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0240023</link>
      <description>S. Viv&#232;s, David Ramel, Cathy Meunier, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405834357

                Since the long-range structure of the Gd-doped system (Ce1&#8722;xGdxO2&#8722;x/2) remains in the fluorite structure in the x-range [0&#8211;0.3], it is of interest to study this system in the local range. Molecular dynamics simulations seem to be particularly suitable for this purpose. Among all the possible parameters used to describe the local order/disorder, we focus on the behavior of the bond lengths. Doping cations and oxygen vacancies are introduced inside the fluorite structure following two arrangements, the random (R) and the neighbor (N). We investigate the evolution of the bond lengths with the temperature and doping level and identify different trends depending on the bond type (cation&#8211;anion, cation&#8211;cation). The bond length thermal expansion can be drastically different from the long-range thermal expansion mainly for the bonds implying Gd3+ cation. The presence of C-type Gd2O3 clusters is discussed through the study of the double component of the Gd&#8211;Gd Radial Distribution Function. Comments are provided for evolution of distances beyond the first and second shells of the cations&#8217; environment. This study also demonstrates the impact of point defect distribution (R or N) on the evolution of the local structure, while maintaining the long-range fluorite structure.</description>
      <author>S. Viv&#232;s, David Ramel, Cathy Meunier</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0240023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On improved inorganic gas&#8208;sensing characteristics of microwave&#8208;treated tungsten oxide quantum dots at room temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.15033</link>
      <description>M. Salot, K. Santhy, Venkata Ramesh Naganaboina, Shiv Govind Singh, A K Pramanick, D. Mandal, G. Avasthi, S. K. Chaudhury, International Journal of Applied Ceramic Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405971363

                Abstract Tungsten oxide (WO 3 ) based metal oxide semiconductor material has been conventionally used for sensing inorganic gases at elevated temperatures. However, in this study, the gas sensing performance of tungsten oxide&#8208;based sensors is evaluated at room temperature. In this study, WO 3 quantum dots (QDs) are synthesized via the electrochemical method, followed by a microwave treatment to dehydrate them. The newly developed process is relatively less expensive and offers the flexibility to alter the structure in terms of phase, size, shape, and vacancy concentration. It is observed that electrochemical process parameters play an important role in phase evolution and control the oxygen vacancy concentration in the powder, which are essential for enhancing its gas sensing characteristics. Results showed an enhanced gas&#8208;sensing ability of WO 3 QDs at room temperature toward inorganic gases, such as CO, NO 2 , NH 3 , and H 2 when subjected to microwave treatment. The enhanced gas&#8208;sensing performance of microwave&#8208;treated WO 3 QDs is attributed to its smaller size and high oxygen vacancy concentration. The minimum limit of detection values for CO, NO 2 , NH 3 , and H 2 at room temperature using microwave&#8208;treated hydrated tungsten oxide QDs were 4.60, 1.5, 0.35, and 10.25 ppm, respectively.</description>
      <author>M. Salot, K. Santhy, Venkata Ramesh Naganaboina, Shiv Govind Singh, A K Pramanick, D. Mandal, G. Avasthi, S. K. Chaudhury</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.15033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nematode-Trapping Fungus&lt;i&gt;Arthrobotrys oligospora&lt;/i&gt;is Hungry for COQ7 to Alleviate Environmentally Triggered Iron Overload</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.24.630212</link>
      <description>Qunfu Wu, Jiao Zhou, Donglou Wang, Songhan Xue, Ling Li, Li Wu, Junxian Yan, Xue&#8208;Mei Niu, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405975783

                Abstract Choosing the right and appropriate amount of substances in a changing environment is essential for the growth and survival of all species. We found that elevated oxygen levels significantly enhanced the iron-rich trapping devices of a nematode-trapping fungus (NTF), Arthrobotrys oligospora . Interestingly, genomic analysis revealed that all NTFs lacked coq7 , a key gene involved in ubiquinol (UQ) biosynthesis and iron chelation. Notably, A. oligospora utilizes UQ instead of UQ for low-aerobic respiration. Transcriptional, metabolic, mutational, and phenotypic analyses revealed that A. oligospora produces a chemotaxonomic class of highly oxygenated arthrobotrins with characteristics similar to UQ skeleton, for high-aerobic respiration. Disruption of arthrobotrin biosynthesis in the &#916; art mutant not only enhanced UQ biosynthesis, but also triggered trapping device formation and nematicidal activity under elevated oxygen conditions. The addition of UQ to both wild-type and &#916; art mutants strongly inhibited trapping device development. Remarkably, the iron-rich trapping devices preferentially capture N2 nematodes harboring iron-chelating COQ7 with ferritin properties. Time-calibrated evolutionary analyses, combined with geological data, indicated that the NTF ancestor lost the coq7 gene after acquiring the arthrobotrin biosynthetic gene cluster during the "superoligotrophy" period, characterized by dramatic shifts in global oxygen levels and temperature changes. Our results demonstrate that oxygen is a critical factor in inducing iron overload, highlighting the origin and role of coq7 loss in the evolution of predatory behavior of NTFs. Our finding that NTFs capture nematodes for iron chelation therapy, rather than for food, explains a long standing debate about the limited carnivorous ability of trapping devices.</description>
      <author>Qunfu Wu, Jiao Zhou, Donglou Wang, Songhan Xue, Ling Li, Li Wu, Junxian Yan, Xue&#8208;Mei Niu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.24.630212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative Dissolution of Sulfide Minerals in Porous Media Under Evaporative Conditions: Multiphase Experiments and Process&#8208;Based Modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024wr037317</link>
      <description>Navid Ahmadi, Muhammad Muniruzzaman, Jacopo Cogorno, Massimo Rolle, Water Resources Research. 61(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405855142

                Abstract The dissolution of sulfide minerals in subsurface porous media has important environmental implications. We investigate the oxidative dissolution of pyrite under evaporative conditions and advance a mechanistic understanding of the interactions between multiple physical processes and mineral/surface reactions. We performed a set of experiments in which initially water saturated and anoxic soil columns, containing a top layer of pyrite, are exposed to the atmosphere under no evaporation (single&#8208;phase) and natural evaporative (two&#8208;phase) conditions. The oxidative dissolution of pyrite was monitored by non&#8208;invasive high&#8208;resolution measurements of oxygen and pH. Additionally, we developed and applied a multiphase and multicomponent reactive transport model to quantitatively describe the experimental outcomes and elucidate the interplay between the physico&#8208;chemical mechanisms controlling the extent of pyrite dissolution. The results confirm that the extent of pyrite dissolution under single&#8208;phase conditions was constrained by the slow diffusive transport of oxygen in the liquid phase. In contrast, during evaporation, the evolution of fluid phases and interphase mass transfer processes imposed distinct physical constraints on the dynamics of pyrite oxidation. Initially, the invasion of the gaseous phase led to a fast delivery of high oxygen concentrations in the reactive zone and thus markedly increased pyrite oxidation and acidity/sulfate production. However, such enhanced release of reaction products was progressively limited over time as drying conditions prevailed in the reactive zone and inhibited pyrite oxidation. The transient phase displacement was also found to control the distribution of aqueous species and formation of secondary minerals by creating spatio&#8208;temporally variable redox conditions.</description>
      <author>Navid Ahmadi, Muhammad Muniruzzaman, Jacopo Cogorno, Massimo Rolle</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024wr037317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Ultraviolet Spectroscopic Analysis of Structural Phases in TiO2 Sol&#8211;Gel Thin Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings15010019</link>
      <description>Helena Cristina Vasconcelos, Maria Meirelles, Re&#351;it &#214;zmente&#351;, Abdulkadir Korkut, Coatings. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405922151

                This study investigates the structural and electronic transitions of sol&#8211;gel derived titanium dioxide (TiO2) thin films using vacuum ultraviolet (VUV) spectroscopy, to elucidate the impact of annealing-induced phase evolution. As the annealing temperature increased from 400 &#176;C to 800 &#176;C, the films transitioned from amorphous to anatase, mixed anatase&#8211;rutile, and finally rutile phases. VUV spectroscopy revealed distinct absorption features: a high-energy &#963; &#8594; &#960;* transition below 150 nm, associated with bonding to antibonding orbital excitations, and lower-energy absorption bands in the range 175&#8211;180 nm and near 280 nm, attributed to &#960; &#8594; &#960;* and t2g(&#960;) &#8594; t*2g(&#960;*) transitions, respectively. These spectral features highlight the material&#8217;s intrinsic electronic states and defect-related transitions. A slight redshift of the absorption band from 176 nm to 177 nm with annealing reflects bandgap narrowing, attributed to increased rutile content, crystallite growth, and defect-induced effects. Broadening and additional absorption features around 280 nm were attributed to oxygen vacancies and reduced titanium oxidation states (Ti3&#8314;), as corroborated by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). XPS further confirmed the presence of Ti3&#8314; species and oxygen vacancies, providing complementary evidence of defect-mediated transitions observed in the VUV spectra. While complementary techniques such as X-ray diffraction (XRD) and Fourier Transform Infrared Spectroscopy (FTIR) confirmed phase transitions and the reduction of hydroxyl groups, respectively, VUV spectroscopy uniquely captured the dynamic interplay between structural defects, phase evolution, and optical properties. This study underscores the utility of VUV spectroscopy as a powerful tool for probing the electronic structure of TiO2 films, offering insights critical for tailoring their functional properties in advanced applications.</description>
      <author>Helena Cristina Vasconcelos, Maria Meirelles, Re&#351;it &#214;zmente&#351;, Abdulkadir Korkut</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings15010019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methylene Blue degradation using plasma: A comparative study between the microwave plasma jet over water surface and the nanosecond pulsed discharge in gas bubbles in water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53907/enpesj.v4i2.272</link>
      <description>Nadir Aloui, Ibtissem Belgacem, ENP Engineering Science Journal. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405889855

                In this paper investigates the Methylene Blue degradation using two common reactors: the nanosecond pulsed discharge in oxygen bubbles and the Argon Microwave plasma jet above the treated solution. The aim of this study is to compare the evolution of the reactors' performance when the electrical conductivity increases. In deionized water, the Methylene Blue degradation and the energy efficiency in the nanosecond pulsed discharge configuration were significantly higher than the Argon microwave plasma jet. However, when the solution electrical conductivity is increased, the energy efficiency of the nanosecond pulsed discharge drops significantly by ~82%, whereas the performance of the microwave plasma jet reactors decreases by ~37% only for a greater variation of the electrical conductivity of the solution. Under these conditions, the efficiency of both reactors becomes comparable, suggesting the necessity to consider various parameters to compare the reactors' efficiency.</description>
      <author>Nadir Aloui, Ibtissem Belgacem</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53907/enpesj.v4i2.272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optical characterization of actively cooled switching arcs in SF6 alternatives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ada450</link>
      <description>Joseph Engelbrecht, Deepshikha Kumari, Christian M. Franck, Journal of Physics D Applied Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405930182

                Abstract A detailed study of the evolution of transient arc properties in SF6 alternative gas mixtures was carried out on an experimental puffer circuit breaker. Thermal interruption tests were performed in several CO2-based mixtures under short-line fault-like current and voltage stresses, with the test-device providing a similar arc environment and interruption performance to a commercial circuit breaker. The time-evolution of arc properties including the radius, temperature, and electron density were investigated using high speed imaging and optical emission spectroscopy techniques. These results were compared with simulation results from a simple 1-D, two zone arc model. Spatially resolved measurements of the arc were obtained in the critical interruption regions of the nozzle, including the first reported 2-D measurements of the temperature distribution during the interruption process in CO2. These measurements revealed a faster temperature decay in the nozzle throat, indicative of stronger cooling in this region compared to the upstream stagnation zone. Comparisons between the behavior of SF6 and its alternatives largely agreed with the model predictions, with lower temperatures and earlier temperature decay observed in SF6, followed by CO2-based mixtures, while air exhibited the highest temperatures and latest onset of temperature decay. No significant influence of oxygen content was observed on the maximum arc temperature of CO2/O2 mixtures at currents above 500 A, where values ranging from 20 kK to 25 kK were typically observed.</description>
      <author>Joseph Engelbrecht, Deepshikha Kumari, Christian M. Franck</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ada450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Insights into Enhanced Stability of Li&#8208;Rich Layered and High&#8208;Voltage Olivine Phosphate Cathodes for Advanced Batteries through Surface Modification and Electron Structure Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202413054</link>
      <description>Zhili Liang, Abdulaziz Baubaid, Mariusz Radtke, Maximilian Mellin, Cl&#233;ment Maheu, Sandipan Maiti, Hadar Sclar, Igor P&#237;&#353;, Silvia Nappini, Elena Magnano, Federica Bondino, Robert Winkler, Ren&#233; Hausbrand, Christian He&#223;, Lambert Alff, Boris Markovsky, Doron Aurbach, W. Jaegermann, Gennady Cherkashinin, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405868339

                Abstract The design of cathode/electrolyte interfaces in high&#8208;energy density Li&#8208;ion batteries is critical to protect the surface against undesirable oxygen release from the cathodes when batteries are charged to high voltage. However, the involvement of the engineered interface in the cationic and anionic redox reactions associated with (de&#8208;)lithiation is often ignored, mostly due to the difficulty to separate these processes from chemical/catalytic reactions at the cathode/electrolyte interface. Here, a new electron energy band diagrams concept is developed that includes the examination of the electrochemical&#8208; and ionization&#8208; potentials evolution upon batteries cycling. The approach enables to forecast the intrinsic stability of the cathodes and discriminate the reaction pathways associated with interfacial electronic charge&#8208;transfer mechanisms. Specifically, light is shed on the evolution of cationic and anionic redox in high&#8208;energy density lithium&#8208;rich 0.33Li 2 MnO 3 &#183;0.67LiNi 0.4 Co 0.2 Mn 0.4 O 2 (HE&#8208;NCM) cathodes, particularly those that undergo surface modification through SO 2 and NH 3 double&#8208;gas treatment to suppress the structural degradation. The chemical composition and energy distribution of the occupied and unoccupied electronic states at the different charging/discharging states are quantitatively estimated by using advanced spectroscopy techniques, including operando Raman spectroscopy. The concept is successfully demonstrated in designing artificial interfaces for high&#8208;voltage olivine structure cathodes enabling stable battery operation up to 5.1 V versus Li + /Li.</description>
      <author>Zhili Liang, Abdulaziz Baubaid, Mariusz Radtke, Maximilian Mellin, Cl&#233;ment Maheu, Sandipan Maiti, Hadar Sclar, Igor P&#237;&#353;, Silvia Nappini, Elena Magnano, Federica Bondino, Robert Winkler, Ren&#233; Hausbrand, Christian He&#223;, Lambert Alff, Boris Markovsky, Doron Aurbach, W. Jaegermann, Gennady Cherkashinin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202413054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;adjustable High&#8208;Entropy Alloy Nanoparticles as an Efficient Platform for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423765</link>
      <description>Huizhu Cai, Hengpan Yang, Shijie He, Da Ping Wan, Deliang Li, Xingxing Jiang, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405858797

                The high entropy alloy (HEA) possesses distinctive thermal stability and electronic characteristics, which exhibits substantial potential for diverse applications in electrocatalytic reactions. However, accurately controlling the size of HEA still remains a challenge, especially for the ultrasmall HEA nanoparticles. Herein, we firstly calculate and illustrate the size impact on the electronic structure of HEA and the adsorption energies of crucial intermediates in typical electrocatalytic reactions, such as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), CO2 electroreduction (CO2RR) and NO3&#8211; electroreduction (NO3RR). Under the guidance of theoretical calculations, we synthesize a range of ultrasmall PtRuPdCoNi HEA nanoparticles with adjustable sizes (1.7, 2.3, 3.0, and 3.9 nm) using a one&#8208;step spatially confined approach. Specifically, HEA nanoparticles with 1.7 nm size (HEA&#8208;1.7) endows a 16 mV overpotential at current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, yielding a mass activity of 31.9 A mgNM&#8208;1 of noble metal in HER, significantly outperforming commercial Pt/C catalyst. This strategy can also be easily applicable to other reduction reactions attributed to the richness of metal components and size adjustability, presenting a promising platform for various electrocatalytic applications as advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Huizhu Cai, Hengpan Yang, Shijie He, Da Ping Wan, Deliang Li, Xingxing Jiang, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene dot-embedded porous WO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; photoanode for highly efficient photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819805778_0004</link>
      <description>Zhenyan Xu, Xianfeng Zhao, Xiao Yan, Huidan Lu, Yongping Liu, WORLD SCIENTIFIC eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405810376

                Functional Materials Based on or Derived from Coordination Compounds for a Sustainable Society, pp. 53-73 (2025) No AccessChapter 4: Graphene dot-embedded porous WO3 photoanode for highly efficient photoelectrochemical water splittingZhenyan Xu, Xianfeng Zhao, Xiao Xu Yan, Huidan Lu, and Yongping LiuZhenyan XuGuangxi Key Laboratory of Electrochemical and Magneto-chemical Functional Materials, P. R. ChinaCollege of Chemistry and Bioengineering, Guilin University of Technology Guilin 541004, P. R. China, Xianfeng ZhaoGuangxi Key Laboratory of Electrochemical and Magneto-chemical Functional Materials, P. R. ChinaCollege of Chemistry and Bioengineering, Guilin University of Technology Guilin 541004, P. R. China, Xiao Xu YanGuangxi Key Laboratory of Electrochemical and Magneto-chemical Functional Materials, P. R. ChinaCollege of Chemistry and Bioengineering, Guilin University of Technology Guilin 541004, P. R. China, Huidan LuGuangxi Key Laboratory of Electrochemical and Magneto-chemical Functional Materials, P. R. ChinaCollege of Chemistry and Bioengineering, Guilin University of Technology Guilin 541004, P. R. ChinaCorresponding authors., and Yongping LiuGuangxi Key Laboratory of Electrochemical and Magneto-chemical Functional Materials, P. R. ChinaCollege of Chemistry and Bioengineering, Guilin University of Technology Guilin 541004, P. R. ChinaCorresponding authors.https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819805778_0004Cited by:0 (Source: Crossref) PreviousNext AboutFiguresReferencesRelatedDetailsPDF/EPUB ToolsAdd to favoritesDownload CitationsTrack CitationsRecommend to Library ShareShare onFacebookTwitterLinked InRedditEmail Cite Recommend Abstract: The development of semiconductor photoanodes with improved photo-electrochemical (PEC) efficiency and stability for the purpose of realizing solar water splitting is a crucial challenge that carries substantial practical implications. In this study, GQDs/WO3 composite porous photoanodes were fabricated using a pulsed anodization method in an aqueous electrolyte containing hydroxyl GQDs. The morphology and crystal structure of the as-prepared GQDs/WO3 porous films were characterized by SEM, TEM, XRD, XPS, Raman spectra, and FTIR. The successful embedding of GQDs into the WO3 walls to form tightly bound heterojunctions was confirmed. It was investigated how the GQD content influenced the photoelectrochemical properties of the GQDs/WO3 heterojunctions. The optimal photocurrent densities observed in the GQDs/WO3 samples (10-WO3) were found to be three times higher compared to those obtained from pure WO3 porous films. This significant enhancement clearly indicates the positive impact of GQDs on the PEC performance. The boosted PEC activity of the GQDs/WO3 heterojunction photoanode was attributed to the fact that the introduction of GQDs promotes more efficient light absorption, charge separation, and transport processes within the heterojunction structure. Moreover, the GQDs/WO3 composites photoelectrodes exhibited excellent PEC stability, predicting its enormous potential for practical applications. Keywords: Tungsten oxidegraphene quantum dotscomposites photoanodePEC performancewater splitting We recommendImpact of a unilateral horizontal gene transfer on the evolutionary equilibria of a populationAlejandro Garriz, Mathematical Models and Methods in Applied Sciences, 2024Diffuse-interface two-phase flow models with different densities: A new quasi-incompressible form and a linear energy-stable methodM. Shokrpour Roudbari, Mathematical Models and Methods in Applied Sciences, 2018Stochastic persistency of nematic alignment state for the Justh&#8211;Krishnaprasad model with additive white noisesSeung-Yeal Ha, Mathematical Models and Methods in Applied Sciences, 2020Asymptotic behavior and control of a "guidance by repulsion" modelDongnam Ko, Mathematical Models and Methods in Applied Sciences, 2020Uniform-in-time error estimate of the random batch method for the Cucker&#8211;Smale modelSeung-Yeal Ha, Mathematical Models and Methods in Applied Sciences, 2021Curried, pulled lamb kota Red Meat / Rooivleis, 2018Running &#8211; Or Walking at a Reasonable Pace &#8211; Towards a Biosecure Future Andries Wiese, Red Meat / Rooivleis, 2023RPO transformation training project : from 2016 to 2020 Red Meat / Rooivleis, 2020Genotype imputation : an essential, promising, and cheap tool for assembling the reference population for genomic selection in the Afrikaner and Brahman cattle ... M.L. Makgahlela, Red Meat / Rooivleis, 2020Plants against parasites : research &amp; training Red Meat / Rooivleis, 2015Powered by Privacy policyGoogle Analytics settings FiguresReferencesRelatedDetailsNone Recommended Recommended Graphene dot-embedded porous WO3 photoanode for highly efficient photoelectrochemical water splittingZhenyan Xu, Xianfeng Zhao, Xiao Xu Yan, Huidan Lu, and Yongping LiuFunctional Materials LettersVol. 16, No. 07Surface Phosphation of 3D NiCo2O4 Nanowires Grown on Ni Foam as an Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Water SplittingLanzi Cheng, Rui Zhang, Weixin Lv, Luyu Shao, Zheng Wang, and Wei WangNanoVol. 15, No. 02Multicomponent nickel-based phosphide catalyst for overall water splittingXiuzhang Lan, Sie Gao, Wenbin Wang, Rufeng Li, Buqi Ke, Shaopeng Lu, and Guoling LiFunctional Materials LettersVol. 14, No. 07FeCoNi sulphide-derived nanodots as electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reactionHan Wang, Jinlong Yang, Luyi Yang, Guangxing Zhang, Chaokun Liu, Hanting Tang, Qinghe Zhao, and Feng PanFunctional Materials LettersVol. 11, No. 03Photoelectrochemical Properties and Photocatalytic Activity of Fluorine-Doped Plate-Like WO3 from Hydrothermal Radio-Frequency (RF) Sputtered Tungsten Thin FilmsYahui Yang, Guanhua Jin, and Hang LiNanoVol. 12, No. 04Ni-MOF in-situ Decorating ZnO photoelectrode for photoelectrochemical water splittingZhen Qian Liu, Kejia Qiu, Hongye Bai, Fagen Wang, Yilin Ge, Weicheng Cui, Guoli Zheng, Jianguo Cui, and Weiqiang FanFunctional Materials LettersVol. 11, No. 04Enhanced photoelectrochemical water oxidation of a BiVO4/tetra(amino)phthalocyanine composite photoanodeM. Shire Sudi, Long Zhao, Yuqin Dou, Xin Yang, Qi Wang, Aijian Wang, and Weihua ZhuJournal of Porphyrins and PhthalocyaninesVol. 27, No. 07n10Rational structure design of FeCo-based materials as efficient electrodes for overall water-splittingTongxin Yang, Weikang Zheng, Zuguang Yang, and Chaohe XuFunctional Materials LettersVol. 15, No. 03 Functional Materials Based on or Derived from Coordination Compounds for a Sustainable SocietyMetrics Downloaded 0 times History KeywordsTungsten oxidegraphene quantum dotscomposites photoanodePEC performancewater splittingPDF download</description>
      <author>Zhenyan Xu, Xianfeng Zhao, Xiao Yan, Huidan Lu, Yongping Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819805778_0004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size&#8208;adjustable High&#8208;Entropy Alloy Nanoparticles as an Efficient Platform for Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423765</link>
      <description>Huizhu Cai, Hengpan Yang, Shijie He, Da Ping Wan, Deliang Li, Xingxing Jiang, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405858796

                The high entropy alloy (HEA) possesses distinctive thermal stability and electronic characteristics, which exhibits substantial potential for diverse applications in electrocatalytic reactions. However, accurately controlling the size of HEA still remains a challenge, especially for the ultrasmall HEA nanoparticles. Herein, we firstly calculate and illustrate the size impact on the electronic structure of HEA and the adsorption energies of crucial intermediates in typical electrocatalytic reactions, such as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), CO2 electroreduction (CO2RR) and NO3&#8211; electroreduction (NO3RR). Under the guidance of theoretical calculations, we synthesize a range of ultrasmall PtRuPdCoNi HEA nanoparticles with adjustable sizes (1.7, 2.3, 3.0, and 3.9 nm) using a one&#8208;step spatially confined approach. Specifically, HEA nanoparticles with 1.7 nm size (HEA&#8208;1.7) endows a 16 mV overpotential at current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, yielding a mass activity of 31.9 A mgNM&#8208;1 of noble metal in HER, significantly outperforming commercial Pt/C catalyst. This strategy can also be easily applicable to other reduction reactions attributed to the richness of metal components and size adjustability, presenting a promising platform for various electrocatalytic applications as advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Huizhu Cai, Hengpan Yang, Shijie He, Da Ping Wan, Deliang Li, Xingxing Jiang, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Chuanxin He</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Warfare: The Plant Genome's Role in Fending Off Insect Invaders</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/arch.70021</link>
      <description>Aleena Alam, Sohail Abbas, Noman Waheed, Arzlan Abbas, Weibo Qin, Jingxuan Huang, Khalid Ali Khan, Hamed A. Ghramh, Jamin Ali, Ri-Zhao Chen, Archives of Insect Biochemistry and Physiology. 117(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405826247

                ABSTRACT The plant defense against insects is multiple layers of interactions. They defend through direct defense and indirect defense. Direct defenses include both physical and chemical barriers that hinder insect growth, development, and reproduction. In contrast, indirect defenses do not affect insects directly but instead suppress them by releasing volatile compounds that attract the natural enemies of herbivores. Insects overcome plant defenses by deactivating biochemical defenses, suppressing defense signaling through effectors, and altering their behavior through chemical regulation. There is always a genetic war between plants and insects. In this genetic war, plant&#8211;insect co&#8208;evolution act as both weapons and messengers. Because plants always look for new strategies to avoid insects by developing adaptation. There are molecular processes that regulate the interaction between plants and insect. Here, we examine the genes and proteins involved in plant&#8211;insect interactions and explore how their discovery has shaped the current model of the plant genome's role. Plants detect damage&#8208;associated and herbivore&#8208;associated molecular patterns through receptors, which trigger early signaling pathways involving Ca 2+ , reactive oxygen species, and MAP kinases. The specific defense mechanisms are activated through gene signaling pathways, including phytohormones, secondary metabolites, and transcription factors. Expanding plant genome approaches to unexplored dimensions in fending off insects should be a future priority in order to develop management strategies.</description>
      <author>Aleena Alam, Sohail Abbas, Noman Waheed, Arzlan Abbas, Weibo Qin, Jingxuan Huang, Khalid Ali Khan, Hamed A. Ghramh, Jamin Ali, Ri-Zhao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/arch.70021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Oxidative Coupling of Methane to Ethane Using CO2 as a Soft Oxidant Over the Au/TiO2&#8208;Vo Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414814</link>
      <description>Mingyu Wu, Juncheng Zhu, Yang Wu, Siying Liu, Kai Zheng, Shumin Wang, Bangwang Li, Jing Li, Chengyuan Liu, Jun Hu, Junfa Zhu, Yongfu Sun, Yang Pan, Yi Xie, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405868663

                Herein, we first report a photocatalytic OCM using CO2 as a soft oxidant for C2H6 production under mild conditions, where an efficient photocatalyst with unique interface sites is constructed to facilitate CO2 adsorption and activation, while concurrently boosting CH4 dissociation. As a prototype, the Au quantum dots anchored on oxygen&#8208;deficient TiO2 nanosheets are fabricated, where the Au&#8208;Vo&#8208;Ti interface sites for CO2 adsorption and activation are collectively disclosed by in situ Kelvin probe force microscopy, quasi in situ X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and theoretical calculations. Compared with single metal site, the Au&#8208;Vo&#8208;Ti interface sites exhibit the lower CO2 adsorption energy and decrease the energy barrier of the *CO2 hydrogenation step from 1.05 to 0.77 eV via Au&#8208;C and Ti&#8208;O dual&#8208;site bonding. The adsorbed CO2 reduces the energy barrier of *CH4 dissociation to *CH3 from 2.13 to 1.59 eV, contributing to CH4 oxidation. Additionally, in situ Fourier&#8208;transform infrared spectroscopy unveils the Au site facilitates ethane production by engaging in *CH3&#8208;Au interaction and accelerating CH3&#8208;CH3 coupling. Thus, the photocatalyst demonstrates a high C2H6 evolution rate of 2.60 mmol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1 for OCM using CO2 as the soft oxidant, surpassing most of previously reported photocatalysts regardless of OCM and nonoxidative coupling of methane.</description>
      <author>Mingyu Wu, Juncheng Zhu, Yang Wu, Siying Liu, Kai Zheng, Shumin Wang, Bangwang Li, Jing Li, Chengyuan Liu, Jun Hu, Junfa Zhu, Yongfu Sun, Yang Pan, Yi Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Electron&#8208;Deficient Ru Nanoclusters via Strong Electronic Metal&#8208;Support Interaction for Practical Anion&#8208;Exchange Membrane Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418617</link>
      <description>Wang Haidong, Yongxin Jiao, Guanghui Zhang, Weizhi Ma, Wenjun Fan, Xinyi Liu, Yun Zhao, Haijiao Xie, Weiguang Ma, Xu Zong, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405814469

                Abstract Ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;based hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalysts are promising candidates for assembling high&#8208;performance anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) while their intrinsic activities are restricted due to the strong Ru&#9472;H bond strength. Herein, we present the synthesis and stabilization of electron&#8208;deficient Ru nanoclusters on oxygen&#8208;functionalized carbon nanotube (Ru/O&#8208;CNT) via strong electronic metal&#8208;support interaction (EMSI) toward highly efficient and stable alkaline HER. A scalable high&#8208;temperature shock method is used to anchor Ru nanoclusters on O&#8208;CNT, which suppresses the aggregation of Ru clusters and the loss of O anion during synthesis, thus strengthening the EMSI between the two components via Ru&#8211;O&#8211;C link. The strong EMSI helps to stabilize Ru at electron&#8208;deficient state at reductive potentials and optimizes the Ru&#9472;H bond strength. Consequently, Ru/O&#8208;CNT delivers outstanding performances for alkaline HER with a small overpotential of 10 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is superior to the benchmark Pt/C and most reported Ru&#8208;based electrocatalysts. More impressively, an AEMWE assembled with Ru/O&#8208;CNT as cathode achieves high current densities of 1 and 5 A cm &#8722;2 at low cell voltages of 1.68 and 2.09 V, respectively, at a Ru mass loading of only 20 &#181;g cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Wang Haidong, Yongxin Jiao, Guanghui Zhang, Weizhi Ma, Wenjun Fan, Xinyi Liu, Yun Zhao, Haijiao Xie, Weiguang Ma, Xu Zong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418617</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Current Status and Future Trends of Wearable Devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/2025.18829</link>
      <description>X. F. Shang, Applied and Computational Engineering. 120(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405821219

                Wearable devices have emerged as a revolutionary advancement in modern technology, reshaping how individuals interact with their surroundings and manage personal health. These compact, portable tools integrate seamlessly into daily life, enabling real-time monitoring of health metrics, fitness progress, and environmental factors. Evolving from basic fitness trackers to sophisticated multifunctional gadgets, wearables now facilitate diverse applications, including chronic disease management, augmented reality experiences, and smart home automation. The rapid integration of sensors, artificial intelligence, and wireless connectivity has amplified their utility, transforming them into essential components of the Internet of Things. Wearable technology plays a critical role in promoting preventative healthcare by tracking vital signs, such as heart rate, oxygen levels, and sleep patterns, providing users and healthcare professionals with actionable insights. Furthermore, their applications extend beyond healthcare to fields like sports, education, and entertainment, where AR and virtual reality technologies create immersive experiences. Despite their potential, wearable devices face challenges such as data privacy concerns, limited battery life, and high costs. This paper examines the technological evolution, current applications, and societal implications of wearable devices while exploring future trends and innovations. These include advancements in AI-powered diagnostics, non-invasive biosensors, and their expanding role in connected ecosystems.</description>
      <author>X. F. Shang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/2025.18829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfuric acid speleogenesis in Greece</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3986/ac.v53i2-3.13668</link>
      <description>Georgios Lazaridis, Vasilios Melfos, Lambrini Papadopoulou, Bogdan P. Onac, Christos L. Stergiou, Angelos G. Maravelis, Panagiotis Voudouris, Despoina Dora, Michalis Fitros, Haritakis Papaioannou, Konstantinos Vouvalidis, Acta Carsologica. 53(2-3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405847012

                Manifestations of sulfuric acid speleogenesis (SAS) documented in several caves in the areas of Aghia Paraskevi, Konitsa, W. Peloponnese, Elassona, Lavrion and Kammena Vourla in Greece are examined and discussed in this work. Carbonate and sulfate samples collected from caves in Aghia Paraskevi and western Peloponnese areas were investigated using methods, such as fluid inclusion, scanning electron microscopy, carbon, sulfur and oxygen stable isotopes, X-ray powder diffraction, and chemical analysis. The examined caves are mainly developed at or in the proximity of the local water table and they are related to hydrothermal springs and geothermal fields. In addition to the documentation of SAS in one case study from Aghia Paraskevi, calcite spar with a homogenization temperature peak at 280&#176;C, indicates an early speleogenetic stage that involves meteoric-origin hydrothermal fluids under deep-seated settings. Sulfur isotope composition of sulfates (&#8211;4 &#8240;) is indicative for pyrite oxidation. The Konitsa caves represent a system developed at multiple altitudes that is related to the evolution of Sarantaporos River. The caves in West Peloponnese are located in two different geotectonic units. However, the caves in both units are active and share common characteristics, such as their development near sea level, morphology and fracture-guided pattern, and the presence of gypsum with &#948;34S values (average &#8211;26 &#8240;) that are plausibly related to hydrocarbons and bacterial activity. Morphological and geochemical aspects of the caves in these two regions suggest long-lasting, multiphase speleogenetic systems.</description>
      <author>Georgios Lazaridis, Vasilios Melfos, Lambrini Papadopoulou, Bogdan P. Onac, Christos L. Stergiou, Angelos G. Maravelis, Panagiotis Voudouris, Despoina Dora, Michalis Fitros, Haritakis Papaioannou, Konstantinos Vouvalidis</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3986/ac.v53i2-3.13668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Oxidative Coupling of Methane to Ethane Using CO2 as a Soft Oxidant Over the Au/TiO2&#8208;Vo Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414814</link>
      <description>Mingyu Wu, Juncheng Zhu, Yang Wu, Siying Liu, Kai Zheng, Shumin Wang, Bangwang Li, Jing Li, Chengyuan Liu, Jun Hu, Junfa Zhu, Yongfu Sun, Yang Pan, Yi Xie, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405868349

                Herein, we first report a photocatalytic OCM using CO2 as a soft oxidant for C2H6 production under mild conditions, where an efficient photocatalyst with unique interface sites is constructed to facilitate CO2 adsorption and activation, while concurrently boosting CH4 dissociation. As a prototype, the Au quantum dots anchored on oxygen&#8208;deficient TiO2 nanosheets are fabricated, where the Au&#8208;Vo&#8208;Ti interface sites for CO2 adsorption and activation are collectively disclosed by in situ Kelvin probe force microscopy, quasi in situ X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and theoretical calculations. Compared with single metal site, the Au&#8208;Vo&#8208;Ti interface sites exhibit the lower CO2 adsorption energy and decrease the energy barrier of the *CO2 hydrogenation step from 1.05 to 0.77 eV via Au&#8208;C and Ti&#8208;O dual&#8208;site bonding. The adsorbed CO2 reduces the energy barrier of *CH4 dissociation to *CH3 from 2.13 to 1.59 eV, contributing to CH4 oxidation. Additionally, in situ Fourier&#8208;transform infrared spectroscopy unveils the Au site facilitates ethane production by engaging in *CH3&#8208;Au interaction and accelerating CH3&#8208;CH3 coupling. Thus, the photocatalyst demonstrates a high C2H6 evolution rate of 2.60 mmol g&#8208;1 h&#8208;1 for OCM using CO2 as the soft oxidant, surpassing most of previously reported photocatalysts regardless of OCM and nonoxidative coupling of methane.</description>
      <author>Mingyu Wu, Juncheng Zhu, Yang Wu, Siying Liu, Kai Zheng, Shumin Wang, Bangwang Li, Jing Li, Chengyuan Liu, Jun Hu, Junfa Zhu, Yongfu Sun, Yang Pan, Yi Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagenesis and Reservoir Evolution of Low Permeability Sandstones: A Case Study of the Second Member of the Jurassic Sangonghe Formation, Central Junggar Basin, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/gj.5109</link>
      <description>Zheng Cao, Hairuo Qing, Karem Azmy, Lei Zhang, Zhipeng Li, Shijie Zhu, Changcheng Han, Qing Wei, Nanxin Yin, Geological Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405851920

                ABSTRACT The low&#8208;permeability oil&#8208;bearing tuffaceous sandstones of the second member of the lower Jurassic Sangonghe Formation (J 1 s 2 ) in the Well Pen&#8208;1 west sag of the central Junggar Basin occur in a deep burial setting (&gt; 4000 m). They contain abundant oil and gas shows and hold promising exploration prospects. However, the reservoir heterogeneity is strong due to complex lithofacies and diagenesis, leading to significant productivity differences between adjacent wells. Therefore, identifying the lithofacies and diagenesis of the J 1 s 2 sandstones and elucidating their influence on the evolution of relatively high&#8208;quality reservoirs is of utmost importance for oil and gas exploration and development in this area. Samples from the Well Pen&#8208;1 west sag, representing the J 1 s 2 sandstones, were investigated utilising core and thin section observations, scanning electron microscopy, X&#8208;ray diffraction, fluid inclusions and carbon and oxygen isotope analyses. The J 1 s 2 sandstones are mainly medium&#8208; to fine&#8208;grained and moderate&#8208; to&#8208;well&#8208;sorted feldspathic litharenites and litharenites. The tuffaceous contents range from 2.6% to 25% and the authigenic clay contents, produced by diagenesis, range from 0.6% to 12%, although carbonate cements are not abundant (av. 3.1%). Four sandstone lithofacies have been identified based on mineral compositions, leading to variations in diagenetic evolution and reservoir quality. Early diagenetic events included compaction, alteration of tuffaceous matrix and feldspar, and development of smectite, chlorite, kaolinite and early calcite. Mesogenic alteration included feldspar and tuffaceous matrix dissolution, alteration of kaolinite, chlorite and illite, and precipitation of quartz, anhydrite, late calcite and ferrocalcite. The alteration of the tuffaceous matrix resulted in a complex pore&#8208;throat structure in the J 1 s 2 sandstones. The pebbly sandstone and conglomerate (SC) and fine&#8208;grained sandstone (Sm) lithofacies are generally characterised by high compaction resistance, low tuffaceous matrix and cement contents, and abundant secondary dissolution pores, and they exhibit better reservoir quality and great potential for oil and gas enrichment.</description>
      <author>Zheng Cao, Hairuo Qing, Karem Azmy, Lei Zhang, Zhipeng Li, Shijie Zhu, Changcheng Han, Qing Wei, Nanxin Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/gj.5109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subduction zone rocks oxidized by supercritical fluid: Constraints from an ultrahigh-pressure eclogite-vein system in the Dabie orogen, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1130/b37979.1</link>
      <description>Tienan Chen, Ren&#8208;Xu Chen, Yong&#8208;Fei Zheng, Kun Zhou, Wan-Cai Li, Geological Society of America Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405896862

                The role of subducting slab-derived supercritical fluids in transferring oxidized components in subduction zones remains poorly constrained. We investigated the oxidation state and effect of supercritical fluids by a combined study of petrology and geochemistry on an ultrahigh-pressure eclogite-vein system from the Dabie orogen, China. These samples record the composition and evolution of supercritical fluids at subarc depths. Multiphase crystal inclusions trapped within minerals in the vein encompass calcite, anhydrite, and magnetite, suggesting that the supercritical fluids contain such cations as S6+, C4+, and Fe3+. Whole-rock and mineral compositions of the eclogites vary systematically with distance from the vein, suggesting that the eclogites adjacent to the vein were metasomatized by vein-forming supercritical fluids. The garnet-clinopyroxene oxybarometric results indicate that the metasomatism of supercritical fluids resulted in the elevation of oxygen fugacity in the eclogites. The metasomatized eclogites exhibit decreases in Fe and S contents, Fe3+/Fetotal ratios, and modes of omphacite and pyrite. This observation suggests that the supercritical fluids dissolving omphacite and pyrite were accompanied by a Fe-S redox coupling process during fluid-rock reactions. This process further releases Fe3+ and S6+ from the eclogites to supercritical fluids. In combination with the mineral composition of the vein, it is inferred that sulfur was likely transported farther by the supercritical fluids. Therefore, some supercritical fluids were oxidizing at the subducting slab-mantle wedge interface and thus can oxidize the metasomatized rocks. Therefore, supercritical fluids are efficient carriers of oxidized components from the subducting slab to the mantle wedge, eventually contributing to the oxidization of arc magma sources.</description>
      <author>Tienan Chen, Ren&#8208;Xu Chen, Yong&#8208;Fei Zheng, Kun Zhou, Wan-Cai Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1130/b37979.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Throughput Exploration of Ti&#8211;V&#8211;Nb&#8211;Mo Carbide MXenes Using Neural Network Potentials and Their Evaluation as Catalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16965</link>
      <description>Mohammed Wasay Mudassir, Sriram Goverapet Srinivasan, Mahesh Mynam, Beena Rai, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405860570

                Realization of a sustainable hydrogen economy in the future requires the development of efficient and cost-effective catalysts for its production at scale. MXenes (Mn+1Xn) are a class of 2D materials with 'n' layers of carbon or nitrogen (X) interleaved by 'n+1' layers of transition metal (M) and have emerged as promising materials for various applications including catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Their properties are intimately related to both their composition and their atomic structure. Recently, high entropy MXenes were synthesized, opening a vast compositional space of potentially stable and functionally superior materials. Detailed atomistic modeling enables us to systematically explore this extensive design space, which is otherwise infeasible in experiments. We have developed a Neural Network Potential (NNP) to model (TixVyNbzMop)n+1Cn MXenes (x+y+z+p = 1; n = 1,2,3) by training against Density Functional Theory (DFT) data in an active learning fashion. We then used the developed NNP to perform hybrid Monte Carlo-Molecular Dynamics (MC-MD) simulations to identify thermodynamically stable compositions and investigate the relative arrangement of transition metal atoms within and across layers. Thermodynamic stability increased with Mo content and its presence on the surface layer. We further investigated the catalytic performance of stable MXenes for the HER and observed that the center of the oxygen p-band (&#949;p) correlated well with the energy of adsorption of a hydrogen atom &#916;G(*H). Subsurface metal atoms significantly influenced the &#916;G(*H) values at the surface via both ligand and strain effects. Our work expands the space of potentially stable MXene compositions, providing targets for synthesis and their evaluation in various applications.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Wasay Mudassir, Sriram Goverapet Srinivasan, Mahesh Mynam, Beena Rai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-term adaptation to hypoxia provides insight into mechanisms facilitating the switch of&lt;i&gt;Pseudomonas aeruginosa&lt;/i&gt;to chronic lung infections</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.26.630387</link>
      <description>Joanna Drabinska, Lucy O&#8217;Connor, Niamh Duggan, Conn Carey, Siobh&#225;n McClean, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405825044

                Opportunistic bacterial infections emerging from the environment are an increasing threat, especially for immunocompromised individuals such as people with cystic fibrosis (CF), driving morbidity, and mortality. Pseudomonas aeruginosa is a key pathogen from this group associated with chronic lung infections that has been extensively studied in this context, but the mechanism driving its adaptation towards chronic colonisation in the CF lung is not fully understood. This work focuses on the adaptations of P. aeruginosa to long-term hypoxia, one of the important environmental pressures present in the CF lung, to investigate whether it drives the development of persistence in CF patients. We examined how an early CF isolate adapted to 6% oxygen over 28 days using an experimental evolution approach and showed that two distinct P. aeruginosa small colony variants (SCVs) emerged, one exclusively in hypoxia exposure cultures. Importantly, SCVs were more prevalent in hypoxia-adapted cultures than in normoxia-adapted cultures (98% vs &lt;35%). Proteomic analysis revealed significant changes in the abundance of &gt;200 proteins within 28 days, including proteins involved in antibiotic resistance, stress response, iron acquisition, biofilm formation and those previously associated with chronic infection. Importantly the observed changes in the proteome were distinct from changes reported after short-term exposure to hypoxia. Phenotypic characterisation of adapted cultures supported these findings, showing that hypoxia-adapted cultures developed higher resistance to 8 of 13 antibiotics tested; increased biofilm (1.8-4.1-fold (p&lt;0.0001) and decreased pyocyanin production (2.6-fold, p&lt;0.0001). All hypoxia-adapted cultures showed decreased siderophore production (2.9-3.6-fold, p&lt;0.02). Two distinct patterns of adaptation to hypoxic conditions were observed, with the phenotypes of one culture being markedly different from the other two. Overall, we demonstrate that long-term hypoxia exposure contributes to multiple phenotype and proteome changes that are also observed in P. aeruginosa CF lung chronic infection, possibly opening the path to treatment of chronic infections.</description>
      <author>Joanna Drabinska, Lucy O&#8217;Connor, Niamh Duggan, Conn Carey, Siobh&#225;n McClean</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.12.26.630387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inclusive and diffractive neutrino-nucleus scattering at high energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevd.110.114048</link>
      <description>Anh Dung Le, Heikki M&#228;ntysaari, Physical review. D/Physical review. D.. 110(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405892050

                We calculate the energy dependence of inclusive and diffractive neutrino-nucleus deep-inelastic scattering cross sections within the dipole picture, focusing on the ultrahigh-energy regime. We predict an up to &#8764;10% nuclear suppression in the inclusive neutrino-oxygen scattering originating from the nonlinear QCD dynamics in the small-x Balitsky-Kovchegov evolution. Diffraction is found to be a small 1%&#8722;4% contribution to the total cross section across a wide range of neutrino energies relevant for current and near-future experiments. The diffractive cross section is calculated separately for the coherent and incoherent channels that are found to be of equal importance. Additionally, we include the dominant contribution from the |qq&#175;g&#10217; Fock state of the W&#177; and Z bosons in the high-Q2 limit, along with the lowest-order |qq&#175;&#10217; contribution. The |qq&#175;g&#10217; contribution is found to be numerically significant, reaching up to 40% of the diffractive cross section. Published by the American Physical Society 2024</description>
      <author>Anh Dung Le, Heikki M&#228;ntysaari</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevd.110.114048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Dimensional Nanomaterials and Their Assembled Structures and Interfaces for Energy Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06610</link>
      <description>Hongtao Sun, Jian Zhu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. 7(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405850948

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. ACS Applied Nano MaterialsVol 7/Issue 24Article This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse EditorialDecember 27, 2024Low-Dimensional Nanomaterials and Their Assembled Structures and Interfaces for Energy ApplicationsClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Hongtao Sun*Hongtao SunThe Harold &amp; Inge Marcus Department of Industrial &amp; Manufacturing Engineering, The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania 16802, United StatesMaterials Research Institute (MRI), The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania 16802, United States*Email: [email protected]More by Hongtao Sunhttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-3259-6091Jian Zhu*Jian ZhuState Key Laboratory for Chemo/Biosensing and Chemometrics, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Hunan Key Laboratory of Two-Dimensional Materials, Hunan University, Changsha 410082, China*Email: [email protected]More by Jian Zhuhttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-9852-1645Open PDFACS Applied Nano MaterialsCite this: ACS Appl. Nano Mater. 2024, 7, 24, 27797&#8211;27800Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsanm.4c06610https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06610Published December 27, 2024 Publication History Received 25 November 2024Published online 27 December 2024Published in issue 27 December 2024editorialCopyright &#169; Published 2024 by American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS PublicationsCopyright &#169; Published 2024 by American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.BatteriesNanomaterialsNanoparticlesStabilityTwo dimensional materialsSPECIAL ISSUEThis article is part of the Low-Dimensional Nanomaterials and Their Assembled Structures and Interfaces for Energy Applications special issue.Over the past two decades, low-dimensional nanomaterials&#9472;ranging from zero-dimensional (0D) nanoparticles, (1&#8722;5) one-dimensional (1D) nanotubes, nanofibers, and nanowires, (6&#8722;11) and two-dimensional (2D) layered materials (12&#8722;20) to 3D hierarchical assemblies (21&#8722;25)&#9472;have garnered immense interest due to their unique dimensional properties. Characterized by confined structures, these materials exhibit exceptional properties that differ fundamentally from their bulk counterparts, including enhanced electronic, optical, chemical, and catalytic functionalities. With applications spanning energy storage, catalysis, and optoelectronics, low-dimensional nanomaterials offer unparalleled opportunities for developing advanced technologies. (1,13&#8722;15,26&#8722;29) This Forum (Special Issue) explores the design, synthesis, characterization, and application of low-dimensional nanomaterials, with a particular focus on their role in energy applications.The versatility of low-dimensional nanomaterials lies in their ability to undergo precise tuning at the atomic or molecular level, which allows for optimization in a wide range of energy applications. 0D nanoparticles and clusters, characterized by a high proportion of surface atoms relative to their volume and exhibiting quantum confinement effects, are ideal for catalytic and energy storage applications. For example, FeCo bimetallic alloy nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen-doped porous carbon significantly enhance the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity in zinc&#8211;air batteries. (3) This synergy between bimetallic nanoparticles and pyridinic nitrogen-active sites delivers a half-wave potential superior to commercial Pt/C, showcasing the potential of nanoparticle-based catalysts. (3) For lithium-ion batteries (LIBs), boron and phosphorus co-doped silicon nanoparticles (&#8764;7 nm) exhibit high capacity (3300 mAh/g) and cycling stability. These single-nanometer-sized particles mitigate volume expansion during lithiation and demonstrate the value of precise size control in optimizing LIB performance. (4)1D nanostructures, such as nanowires, nanotubes, and nanofibers, enable anisotropic charge and ion transport. Nickel and sulfur co-confinement in nitrogen-rich carbon nanofibers leverages pseudocapacitive charge storage to enhance sodium-ion storage, achieving a high capacity of 320 mAh/g at 0.1 A/g and excellent cycling stability. (10)2D materials, including graphene, MXenes, and transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs), are celebrated for their tunable interlayer chemistry, high surface area, and unique electronic properties. An article about 2D materials discusses their applications in batteries and highlights their ability to improve ion diffusion and capacity retention. (15) Moreover, post-transition metal monochalcogenides (PTMMCs) represent an advanced class of 2D materials with remarkable electronic and optical properties. These 2D materials, with their tunable bandgap and unique interfacial behaviors, are poised to play a significant role in next-generation devices, including photovoltaics and nanoscale transistors. (30) Additionally, 2D organic&#8211;inorganic hybrid perovskites were identified as promising materials for polarization-sensitive photodetectors. (17) Their layered structures enable stability and efficient charge transport, making them ideal for optoelectronic applications. (17)3D architectures and nanocomposites amplify the benefits of low-dimensional materials. Fe7Se8 nanoparticles encapsulated in a carbon skeleton form a core&#8211;shell structure that mitigates volume expansion during lithiation. (24) The resulting anode demonstrates a high capacity of 457.8 mAh/g after 300 cycles. (24) A SnO2 nanoflower-holey graphene composite achieves high areal capacity (3 mAh/cm2) in sodium-ion batteries (SIBs). (23) This hierarchical 3D structure enhances Na+ transport, ensuring high performance even at high mass loading.The synthesis and assembly of low-dimensional nanomaterials require advanced fabrication techniques. The ability to assemble atoms, molecules, and particles at interfaces with atomic precision has opened new frontiers in materials science. Advances in processing and assembling, such as layer-by-layer (LbL) self-assembly, nanoparticle assembly, and 3D printing technologies, are enabling the development of novel nanomaterial architectures with tailored properties. For example, a scalable wet-chemistry method produced SiOx@ZrO2@C nanospheres, addressing issues of volume expansion and low conductivity in LIBs. (31) The resulting electrodes retain 72.2% of their capacity after 500 cycles, showcasing the practical scalability of this method. (31) A light-driven nanonetwork assembly via 3D printing integrates top-down patterning with bottom-up nanoparticle assembly to create high-resolution structures for optical sensing. (32) This innovative method balances fabrication resolution and scalability. (32) An article highlights LbL self-assembly as a method for constructing multilayered composites from atomically thin 2D nanomaterials. (33) LbL assembly uses noncovalent interactions to create stable, controllable structures, with applications in energy storage, catalysis, sensors, and drug delivery. The article also discusses various LbL methods, such as van der Waals, electrostatic, Langmuir&#8211;Blodgett, and hydrogen-bonded assembly, and highlights challenges and future directions in using LbL for constructing multifunctional composites. (33) Moreover, the utilization of molten salt electrolysis for CO2 reduction represents a dual-purpose approach for decarbonization and the synthesis of valuable nanomaterials. An article highlights the potential of CO2-derived carbon-based nanomaterials, which are produced through the electroreduction of CO2 in molten salt. (34) These materials exhibit unique properties suitable for energy storage and electrocatalysis. By offering a sustainable route to synthesize carbon-based nanostructures, this process aligns with the goals of low-carbon-footprint technologies. (34) These innovations not only push the boundaries of material design but also bring us closer to realizing scalable, high-performance energy devices.This Forum (Special Issue) illustrates innovative solutions using low-dimensional nanomaterials and their assembled hierarchical forms to address challenges across various energy applications. In addition to LIBs, metal&#8211;air batteries, including zinc&#8211;air and lithium&#8211;air systems, rely heavily on efficient catalysts to overcome the sluggish oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER). Low-dimensional materials have enabled significant breakthroughs in this field. In lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries, amorphous RuO2 supported on TiO2 nanosheets outperforms its crystalline counterpart by promoting smaller and more reversible Li2O2 deposits. (35) This amorphous structure improves the discharge capacity (2.3 mAh/cm2) and extends cycling stability to 160 cycles, demonstrating the critical role of material morphology in optimizing catalytic performance. (35)Sodium-ion batteries (SIBs) and potassium-ion batteries (PIBs) have garnered interest as a cost-effective and sustainable alternative to LIBs. However, the larger ionic radius of Na+ or K+ poses challenges for electrode materials to deliver stable cycling performance. Low-dimensional structures offer practical solutions. For example, by a nanoscale coating of octadecylamine chains, hydrophobic Prussian blue (PB) cathodes with open structures overcome moisture sensitivity during fabrication and usage. (36) This modification ensures stable capacities (145 mAh/g at 1 C) even after extended exposure to humid environments. (36) A hybrid cathode design combining Na3V2(PO4)3 and activated carbon introduces a dual energy storage mechanism. (37) The "nanoreservoir" effect enhances both energy density (218.6 Wh/kg) and cycle life (over 14,000 cycles), bridging the gap between batteries and capacitors. (37) For PIBs, challenges such as dendrite growth and unstable solid electrolyte interphase (SEI) layers hinder their development. An in situ-formed Fe-based protective layer provides a novel solution by suppressing dendrite formation and enhancing ionic conductivity. (38) This artificial SEI improves the cycling stability of potassium metal anodes to over 1700 h, highlighting the importance of interface engineering in ensuring long-term battery performance. (38)Lithium&#8211;sulfur batteries (Li&#8211;S) promise high energy density but are plagued by polysulfide shuttling and poor sulfur utilization. Advanced nanostructures have enabled significant progress in this area. Self-supporting nanoporous carbon films decorated with Co&#8211;N&#8211;C single-atom sites address these challenges by catalyzing sulfur conversion reactions and stabilizing polysulfides. (39) These materials achieve a specific capacity of 1310.1 mAh/g and an areal capacity of 5.6 mAh/cm2 at a high sulfur loading of 6.7 mg/cm2, showcasing the potential of single-atom catalysis for high-performance Li&#8211;S batteries. (39)Separators are critical for maintaining safety and performance in batteries, particularly in aqueous systems where dendrite growth and electrolyte instability pose significant challenges. Functionalized nanoporous separators designed for zinc-ion batteries improve electrolyte transport, enhance mechanical toughness, and mitigate dendrite formation. (40) These modifications extend cycle life and improve overall safety, emphasizing the role of separator engineering in advancing aqueous battery systems. (40)Supercapacitors, with their high power density and rapid charge&#8211;discharge cycles, benefit greatly from low-dimensional nanomaterials. &#948;-MnO2 nanosheets activated by Zn2+ intercalation demonstrate enhanced oxygen vacancies, facilitating Na+ adsorption and improving charge transport. (41) These materials achieve a capacitance of 3240 mF/cm2 even at high mass loading (16 mg/cm2), making them viable for commercial applications. (41) The assembly of 2D nanosheets into layered stacking structures provides open pathways for ion diffusion and electron transport. These architectures exhibit excellent stability and bridge the functionality gap between batteries and supercapacitors, demonstrating the versatility of 2D materials in hybrid energy devices. (16)Electrochemical CO2 reduction (eCO2R) provides a pathway for sustainable energy conversion and carbon capture. Copper nanowires, with diameters as small as 0.8 nm, exhibit enhanced selectivity for converting CO2 into carbon monoxide due to uncoordinated surface atoms. (11) These findings highlight the importance of surface structure in tuning catalytic activity and selectivity. (11) A Z-scheme heterojunction photocatalyst, comprising Cu-doped ZIF-67 and Bi4O5Br2, achieves a remarkable CO2-to-CO conversion rate of 6469.88 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8211;1&#183;h&#8211;1 with a high selectivity of 97%. (25) The synergistic band alignment and intermediate desorption properties underscore the importance of heterostructure design in advancing CO2 photoreduction technologies. (25)Low-dimensional materials also play a pivotal role in optoelectronics. Hybrid organic&#8211;inorganic 2D perovskites exhibit exceptional polarization-sensitive properties, making them ideal for high-performance photodetectors. Their tunable layered structures and environmental stability position them as promising candidates for next-generation optoelectronic devices. (17)In summary, the studies presented in this Forum (Special Issue) illustrate the immense potential of low-dimensional nanomaterials to transform energy technologies. Moving forward, the integration of machine learning and high-throughput experimentation will accelerate material discovery. Interface engineering, particularly in heterogeneous structures, holds the key to unlocking synergistic performance enhancements. As we push the boundaries of nanomaterial capabilities, collaboration across disciplines will be essential. Advances in operando techniques and computational modeling will provide deeper insights into material behavior, guiding the rational design of next-generation energy devices. This Forum (Special Issue) underscores the transformative potential of low-dimensional nanomaterials in energy applications, offering innovative solutions to global challenges in energy storage, conversion, and sustainability.Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorsHongtao Sun, The Harold &amp; Inge Marcus Department of Industrial &amp; Manufacturing Engineering, The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania 16802, United States; Materials Research Institute (MRI), The Pennsylvania State University, University Park, Pennsylvania 16802, United States, https://orcid.org/0000-0003-3259-6091, Email: [email protected]Jian Zhu, State Key Laboratory for Chemo/Biosensing and Chemometrics, College of Chemistry and Chemical Engineering, Hunan Key Laboratory of Two-Dimensional Materials, Hunan University, Changsha 410082, China, https://orcid.org/0000-0001-9852-1645, Email: [email protected]NotesViews expressed in this editorial are those of the authors and not necessarily the views of the ACS.ReferencesClick to copy section linkSection link copied! This article references 41 other publications. 1Kaiser, S. K.; Chen, Z.; Faust Akl, D.; Mitchell, S.; P&#233;rez-Ram&#237;rez, J. Single-Atom Catalysts across the Periodic Table. Chem. Rev. 2020, 120 (21), 11703&#8211; 11809, DOI: 10.1021/acs.chemrev.0c00576 Google Scholar1Single-Atom Catalysts across the Periodic TableKaiser, Selina K.; Chen, Zupeng; Faust Akl, Dario; Mitchell, Sharon; Perez-Ramirez, JavierChemical Reviews (Washington, DC, United States) (2020), 120 (21), 11703-11809CODEN: CHREAY; ISSN:0009-2665. (American Chemical Society) A review. Isolated atoms featuring unique reactivity are at the heart of enzymic and homogeneous catalysts. In contrast, although the concept has long existed, single-atom heterogeneous catalysts (SACs) have only recently gained prominence. Host materials have similar functions to ligands in homogeneous catalysts, detg. the stability, local environment, and electronic properties of isolated atoms and thus providing a platform for tailoring heterogeneous catalysts for targeted applications. Within just a decade, we have witnessed many examples of SACs both disrupting diverse fields of heterogeneous catalysis with their distinctive reactivity and substantially enriching our understanding of mol. processes on surfaces. To date, the term SAC mostly refers to late transition metal-based systems, but numerous examples exist in which isolated atoms of other elements play key catalytic roles. This review provides a compositional encyclopedia of SACs, celebrating the 10th anniversary of the introduction of this term. By defining single-atom catalysis in the broadest sense, we explore the full elemental diversity, joining different areas across the whole periodic table, and discussing historical milestones and recent developments. In particular, we examine the coordination structures and assocd. properties accessed through distinct single-atom-host combinations and relate them to their main applications in thermo-, electro-, and photocatalysis, revealing trends in element-specific evolution, host design, and uses. Finally, we highlight frontiers in the field, including multimetallic SACs, atom proximity control, and possible applications for multistep and cascade reactions, identifying challenges, and propose directions for future development in this flourishing field. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3cXitFSltL3P&amp;md5=f4c3e96ec0d47aa32db16737ef0965e62Fei, H.; Dong, J.; Feng, Y.; Allen, C. S.; Wan, C.; Volosskiy, B.; Li, M.; Zhao, Z.; Wang, Y.; Sun, H. General synthesis and definitive structural identification of MN4C4 single-atom catalysts with tunable electrocatalytic activities. Nature Catalysis 2018, 1 (1), 63&#8211; 72, DOI: 10.1038/s41929-017-0008-y Google Scholar2General synthesis and definitive structural identification of MN4C4 single-atom catalysts with tunable electrocatalytic activitiesFei, Huilong; Dong, Juncai; Feng, Yexin; Allen, Christopher S.; Wan, Chengzhang; Volosskiy, Boris; Li, Mufan; Zhao, Zipeng; Wang, Yiliu; Sun, Hongtao; An, Pengfei; Chen, Wenxing; Guo, Zhiying; Lee, Chain; Chen, Dongliang; Shakir, Imran; Liu, Mingjie; Hu, Tiandou; Li, Yadong; Kirkland, Angus I.; Duan, Xiangfeng; Huang, YuNature Catalysis (2018), 1 (1), 63-72CODEN: NCAACP; ISSN:2520-1158. (Nature Research) Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have recently attracted broad research interest as they combine the merits of both homogeneous and heterogeneous catalysts. Rational design and synthesis of SACs are of immense significance but have so far been plagued by the lack of a definitive correlation between structure and catalytic properties. Here, we report a general approach to a series of monodispersed at. transition metals (for example, Fe, Co, Ni) embedded in nitrogen-doped graphene with a common MN4C4 moiety, identified by systematic X-ray absorption fine structure analyses and direct transmission electron microscopy imaging. The unambiguous structure detn. allows d. functional theor. prediction of MN4C4 moieties as efficient oxygen evolution catalysts with activities following the trend Ni &gt; Co &gt; Fe, which is confirmed by electrochem. measurements. Detn. of atomistic structure and its correlation with catalytic properties represents a crit. step towards the rational design and synthesis of precious or nonprecious SACs with exceptional atom utilization efficiency and catalytic activities. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BC1MXhtFGisLzN&amp;md5=ba4f0c2bc55d7aa8cc41ca3196bd2cde3Li, W.; Zhang, M.; Xie, X.; Liang, A.; Peng, H.; Ma, G.; Xu, Y. FeCo Bimetallic Alloy Nanoparticles Embedded in Nitrogen-Doped Porous Carbon for Effective Oxygen Reduction in Zinc-Air Batteries. ACS Applied Nano Materials 2023, DOI: 10.1021/acsanm.3c03751 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.4Yoshikawa, H.; Ueshima, T.; Sugimoto, H.; Xu, J.; Mizuhata, M.; Fujii, M. Single-Nanometer-Sized Boron and Phosphorus Co-Doped Silicon Nanoparticles for Negative Electrode of Lithium-Ion Batteries. ACS Applied Nano Materials 2023, DOI: 10.1021/acsanm.3c04824 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.5Shao, D.; Yu, M.; Sun, H.; Hu, T.; lian, J.; Sawyer, S. High responsivity, fast ultraviolet photodetector fabricated from ZnO nanoparticle-graphene core-shell structures. Nanoscale 2013, 5 (9), 3664&#8211; 3667, DOI: 10.1039/c3nr00369h Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.6Duan, X.; Huang, Y.; Cui, Y.; Wang, J.; Lieber, C. M. Indium phosphide nanowires as building blocks for nanoscale electronic and optoelectronic devices. Nature 2001, 409 (6816), 66&#8211; 69, DOI: 10.1038/35051047 Google Scholar6Indium phosphide nanowires as building blocks for nanoscale electronic and optoelectronic devicesDuan, Xiangfeng; Huang, Yu; Cui, Yl; Wang, Jianfang; Lieber, Charles M.Nature (London) (2001), 409 (6816), 66-69CODEN: NATUAS; ISSN:0028-0836. (Nature Publishing Group) Nanowires and nanotubes carry charge and excitons efficiently, and are therefore potentially ideal building blocks for nanoscale electronics and optoelectronics. Carbon nanotubes have already been exploited in devices such as field-effect and single-electron transistors, but the practical utility of nanotube components for building electronic circuits is limited, as it is not yet possible to selectively grow semiconducting or metallic nanotubes. Here we report the assembly of functional nanoscale devices from indium phosphide nanowires, the elec. properties of which are controlled by selective doping. Gate-voltage-dependent transport measurements demonstrate that the nano- wires can be predictably synthesized as either n- or p-type. These doped nanowires function as nanoscale field-effect transistors, and can be assembled into crossed-wire p-n junctions that exhibit rectifying behavior. Significantly, the p-n junctions emit light strongly and are perhaps the smallest light-emitting diodes that have yet been made. Finally, we show that elec.-field-directed assembly can be used to create highly integrated device arrays from nanowire building blocks. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BD3MXkt1WqsA%253D%253D&amp;md5=4afc91799c3ba9d1f2b1627f3861c3d97Huang, Y.; Duan, X.; Wei, Q.; Lieber, C. M. Directed Assembly of One-Dimensional Nanostructures into Functional Networks. Science 2001, 291 (5504), 630&#8211; 633, DOI: 10.1126/science.291.5504.630 Google Scholar7One-dimensional nanostructures into functional networksHuang, Yu; Duan, Xiangfeng; Wei, Qingqiao; Lieber, Charles M.Science (Washington, DC, United States) (2001), 291 (5504), 630-633CODEN: SCIEAS; ISSN:0036-8075. (American Association for the Advancement of Science) One-dimensional nanostructures, such as nanowires and nanotubes, represent the smallest dimension for efficient transport of electrons and excitons and thus are ideal building blocks for hierarchical assembly of functional nanoscale electronic and photonic structures. The authors report an approach for the hierarchical assembly of one-dimensional nanostructures into well-defined functional networks. They show that nanowires can be assembled into parallel arrays with control of the av. sepn. and, by combining fluidic alignment with surface-patterning techniques, that it is also possible to control periodicity. In addn., complex crossed nanowire arrays can be prepd. with layer-by-layer assembly with different flow directions for sequential steps. Transport studies show that the crossed nanowire arrays form elec. conducting networks, with individually addressable device function at each cross point. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BD3MXntlWlsw%253D%253D&amp;md5=a2fcb7702dd0b767a9d2716c00d3105b8Hao, G.; Xiao, J.; Hao, Y.; Zhou, G.; Zhu, H.; Gao, H.; Xu, Z.; Zhao, Z.; Miao, L.; Li, J. Van der waals epitaxial growth of mixed-dimensional 1D/2D heterostructures with tellurium nanowires and transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets for nonlinear optical applications. Materials Today Physics 2023, 34, 101069, DOI: 10.1016/j.mtphys.2023.101069 Google Scholar8Van der waals epitaxial growth of mixed-dimensional 1D/2D heterostructures with tellurium nanowires and transition metal dichalcogenide nanosheets for nonlinear optical applicationsHao, Guolin; Xiao, Jinbiao; Hao, Yulong; Zhou, Guoliang; Zhu, Hao; Gao, Hui; Xu, Zhiqiang; Zhao, Zhongkun; Miao, Lili; Li, Jin; Sun, Hongtao; Zhao, ChujunMaterials Today Physics (2023), 34 (), 101069CODEN: MTPAD5; ISSN:2542-5293. (Elsevier Ltd.) One-dimensional (1D) tellurium (Te) nanowires (NWs) have triggered intense attention due to their remarkable properties in electronics, optoelectronics and nonlinear optics. However, the saturable absorption properties of Te NWs and the ability to be bleached by strong pulsed energy need to be further improved. Van der Waals (vdW) heterostructures based on two-dimensional (2D) transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDCs) exhibit prominent nonlinear optical properties. Direct epitaxial growth of large-area 1D/2D Te-TMDC vdW heterostructures is still rarely investigated. Herein, we demonstrate the controllable epitaxial growth of large-scale 1D/2D vertical Te-TMDC heterostructures via two-step vapor phase deposition method. Our exptl. results have confirmed that the saturable absorption properties of as-prepd. Te-TMDC heterostructures can be obviously enhanced. The first principle calcns. and surface potential measurements demonstrate that effective interlayer charge transfer between Te NWs and TMDC nanosheets is beneficial for promoting the saturable absorption properties. Systematic investigation of vdW Te-TMDC heterostructures with nonlinear optical properties is vital for the next generation of nanophotonics and integrated photonics, which paves the way for the development of saturable absorbers and light modulators based on Te-TMDC vdW heterostructures. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3ADC%252BB3sXntlyqtLY%253D&amp;md5=7c55c94e2eaaffd6580ecb1adc8a16fd9Wang, K.; Sun, J.; Yang, H.; Zhang, Y.; Zhong, X.; Song, Y.; Hou, F.; Zhang, Y.; Zhang, Z.; Wang, H. MOF-derived 3D interconnected amorphous carbon nanowire networks for robust lithium storage. Microporous Mesoporous Mater. 2023, 348, 112388, DOI: 10.1016/j.micromeso.2022.112388 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.10Yue, P.; Li, D.; Zhong, X.; Wen, J.; He, L.; Wu, J.; Li, M.; Wang, X.; Cao, W.; Jing, M. Nickel and Sulfur Coconfined Nitrogen-Rich Carbon Nanofibers as Anode Materials for Pseudocapacitive Sodium Storage. ACS Applied Nano Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsanm.3c05996 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.11Lin, W.; Ghulam Nabi, A.; Palma, M.; Di Tommaso, D. Copper Nanowires for Electrochemical CO2 Reduction Reaction. ACS Applied Nano Materials 2024, DOI: 10.1021/acsanm.3c06116 Google ScholarThere is no corresponding record for this reference.12Geim, A. K. Graphene: Status and Prospects. Science 2009, 324 (5934), 1530&#8211; 1534, DOI: 10.1126/science.1158877 Google Scholar12Graphene: Status and ProspectsGeim, A. K.Science (Washington, DC, United States) (2009), 324 (5934), 1530-1534CODEN: SCIEAS; ISSN:0036-8075. (American Association for the Advancement of Science) A review. Graphene is a wonder material with many superlatives to its name. It is the thinnest known material in the universe and the strongest ever measured. Its charge carriers exhibit giant intrinsic mobility, have zero effective mass, and can travel for micrometers without scattering at room temp. Graphene can sustain current densities six orders of magnitude higher than that of copper, shows record thermal cond. and stiffness, is impermeable to gases, and reconciles such conflicting qualities as brittleness and ductility. Electron transport in graphene is described by a Dirac-like equation, which allows the investigation of relativistic quantum phenomena in a benchtop expt. This review analyzes recent trends in graphene research and applications, and attempts to identify future directions in which the field is likely to develop. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=ACS&amp;resolution=options&amp;coi=1%3ACAS%3A528%3A</description>
      <author>Hongtao Sun, Jian Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c06610</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Demographics of Isolated Neutron Stars From X-ray Survey Data</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819800643_0003</link>
      <description>A. M. Pires, WORLD SCIENTIFIC eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405832449

                Pulsar Astronomy, pp. 51-76 (2025) No AccessChapter 3: The Demographics of Isolated Neutron Stars From X-ray Survey DataAdriana Mancini PiresAdriana Mancini PiresCenter for Lunar and Planetary Sciences, Institute of Geochemistry, Chinese Academy of Sciences, 99 West Lincheng Road, Guiyang 550051, ChinaLeibniz-Insititut f&#252;r Astrophysik Potsdam (AIP), an der Sternwarte 16, 14482 Potsdam, Germanyhttps://doi.org/10.1142/9789819800643_0003Cited by:0 (Source: Crossref) PreviousNext AboutFiguresReferencesRelatedDetailsPDF/EPUB ToolsAdd to favoritesDownload CitationsTrack CitationsRecommend to Library ShareShare onFacebookTwitterLinked InRedditEmail Cite Recommend Abstract: Since the discovery of the first radio pulsar, the population of neutron stars in our galaxy has grown to over 3,400. A handful of these sources, exclusively seen in X-rays, are key to understanding aspects of the neutron star phenomenology and evolution that cannot be probed by the rest of the population. In this contribution, I review their properties and highlight the role of X-ray surveys at complementing our view of galactic neutron stars. Prospects for future investigations are discussed especially in the context of the aftermath of the eROSITA All-Sky Survey. Keywords: Neutron starsX-ray surveyseROSITA All-Sky Survey We recommendA survey on an analysis of big data open source datasets, techniques and tools for the prediction of corona virus diseaseR. Ame Rayan, Journal of Circuits, Systems and Computers, 2023FROM EMPIRICAL DATA TO INTER-INDIVIDUAL INTERACTIONS: UNVEILING THE RULES OF COLLECTIVE ANIMAL BEHAVIORMathematical Models and Methods in Applied Sciences, 2011Normative Values of QuickDASH in the Elderly Japanese: a Cohort Survey Randomly Sampled from a Basic Resident RegistryFumihiro Isobe, The Journal of Hand Surgery (Asian-Pacific Volume), 2020Lancemaside A Isolated from the Root of Codonopsis lanceolata Inhibits Ovarian Cancer Cell Invasion via the Reactive Oxygen Species (ROS)-Mediated p38 PathwayJi-Hye Ahn, The American Journal of Chinese Medicine, 2020Effect of Dehydrocostus Lactone Isolated from the Roots of Aucklandia lappa on the Apoptosis of Endometriotic Cells and the Alternative Activation of Endometrio...Jeong-Hwa Woo, The American Journal of Chinese Medicine, 2019From Finite Nuclei to Neutron Stars: The Essential Role of High-Order Density Dependence in Effective Forces Chinese Physics LettersThe View from the Developmental and Behavioral Pediatrics Trenches: A Workforce Survey Lewis First, AAP Blogs, 2018Blockchain Data Analysis from the Perspective of Complex Networks: Overview Wanshui Song, Tsinghua Science and Technology, 2022The Structuring and Good Governance of the Pulses Sector in Morocco: Results from an e-Delphi Survey International Journal of Food Science and AgricultureCaught in the Act&#8212;What We Can Learn from Current Physician Workforce Data Dr. Lydia Furman, AAP Blogs, 2016Powered by Privacy policyGoogle Analytics settings FiguresReferencesRelatedDetailsNone Recommended Recommended ACCRETION OF THE INTERSTELLAR MEDIUM ONTO ISOLATED NEUTRON STARSR. TUROLLAThe Ninth Marcel Grossmann MeetingUltra-stripped supernovae and double neutron star systemsBy (author): Thomas M. TaurisThe Fourteenth Marcel Grossmann MeetingNeutron star mergers as sites of r-process nucleosynthesis and short gamma-ray burstsKenta Hotokezaka, Paz Beniamini, and Tsvi PiranInternational Journal of Modern Physics DVol. 27, No. 13SURFACE EMISSION FROM X-RAY DIM ISOLATED NEUTRON STARSROBERTO TUROLLAExotic States of Nuclear MatterTemperature of neutron starsBy (author): Sachiko TsurutaThe Fourteenth Marcel Grossmann MeetingEVIDENCE FOR MAGNETO-LEVITATION ACCRETION IN LONG-PERIOD X-RAY PULSARSNAZAR IKHSANOV, NINA BESKROVNAYA, and YURY LIKHInternational Journal of Modern Physics: Conference SeriesVol. 28Temperature of neutron starsSachiko TsurutaInternational Journal of Modern Physics DVol. 25, No. 10ABSORPTION FEATURES IN THE SPECTRA OF X-RAY BURSTING NEUTRON STARSVALERY F. SULEIMANOV, THOMAS RAUCH, and KLAUS WERNERThe Twelfth Marcel Grossmann Meeting Pulsar AstronomyMetrics History KeywordsNeutron starsX-ray surveyseROSITA All-Sky SurveyPDF download</description>
      <author>A. M. Pires</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819800643_0003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Conversation with Alexandra Navrotsky</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c02126</link>
      <description>Rachel Brazil, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405894213

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. ACS Central ScienceASAPArticle This publication is Open Access under the license indicated. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse Center StageDecember 30, 2024A Conversation with Alexandra NavrotskyClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!The nanogeoscientist aims to uncover how planets formed and evolved.Rachel BrazilRachel BrazilMore by Rachel BrazilOpen PDFACS Central ScienceCite this: ACS Cent. Sci. 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acscentsci.4c02126https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c02126Published December 30, 2024 Publication History Published online 30 December 2024news&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is licensed under CC-BY 4.0 . License Summary*You are free to share (copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format and to adapt (remix, transform, and build upon) the material for any purpose, even commercially within the parameters below:Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license.Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.View full license*DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. This publication is licensed underCC-BY 4.0 . License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format and to adapt(remix, transform, and build upon) the material for any purpose, even commercially within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format and to adapt(remix, transform, and build upon) the material for any purpose, even commercially within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. License Summary*You are free to share(copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format and to adapt(remix, transform, and build upon) the material for any purpose, even commercially within the parameters below: Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license. Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator. View full license *DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.Geological materialsMaterialsMineralsNanoparticlesPlanets&#8203;In collaboration with C&amp;EN.Alexandra Navrotsky knows a lot about the little things. She is a leader in the field of nanogeoscience, which centers around how nanoparticles lead to mineral formation in geological systems. In over half a century of research, she has made major contributions in mantle mineralogy, deep earth geophysics, and the thermodynamics behind mineral formation. She even lent her name to a recently discovered mineral&#9472;navrotskyite.Credit: Alexandra NavrotskyNow Navrotsky heads up the Navrotsky Eyring Center for Materials of the Universe at Arizona State University. The center represents a unique multidisciplinary initiative aiming to better understand what materials make up other planets, how the planets have formed, and how they evolve over time. Navrotsky is also exploring how materials form in the kinds of extreme conditions found in the universe, using ASU's new facilities for high-pressure and high-temperature materials research.Rachel Brazil talked with Navrotsky about the importance of looking at planets on the nanoscale, what we already know about the universe's many materials, and what she is still hoping to discover. This interview was edited for length and clarity.What is nanogeoscience, and why is it important for understanding the chemistry of other planets?Click to copy section linkSection link copied!If you think of how many atoms make up a nanometer, it's about four or five atoms in a row. So nanogeoscience focuses on the behavior of atoms at that scale.From the geologic and essentially planetary point of view, much, if not almost all, of the reactivity that occurs in the universe occurs with the involvement of small particles. Big particles, big single crystals are really chemically pretty unreactive, and once they are reactive, they will corrode, form small particles, etc. So the majority of reactions&#9472;whether we're talking about our solar system, whether we're talking exoplanets&#9472;most of those reactions involve small particles.Now what is interesting about it is that the small particles have very different properties from large particles. They will be different in their chemical reactivity; they will be different in their thermodynamic properties; they will be different in how they absorb impurities and how they catalyze chemical reactions.What do we know about materials on other planets?Click to copy section linkSection link copied!One has a general picture of the likely compositions [of elements on other planets], but if one looks at the variety of exoplanets, or one even looks at Mars or Jupiter, then one knows much less about the fundamental chemistry. We know the range of pressures because those are constrained by the size of the planets, and we make educated guesses about the temperatures.[We have] quite a bit of information now from the [Mars] rovers and of course the various planetary probes. But that information has to be brought together with what the likely chemistry is and what the reactions are or could be. Right now we have more ideas than facts.You're the director of the Materials of the Universe Center at Arizona State University. What is the objective of that center, and what do you hope to achieve?Click to copy section linkSection link copied![We] are addressing the fundamental question of, how do the intrinsic properties of materials determine the evolution of planets, the properties of planets, the properties of resources?Venus, Earth, and Mars: They're similar in size; they're similar in containing a lot of silicate minerals. But they're very different in how those minerals react; they're very different in what their surfaces are; they're very different in how much water and oxygen they contain; therefore, they're very different in how their properties are influenced by nanoparticles.The fascinating thing is to try to bring together what we've observed in terms of planetary atmospheres and a lot of things that we think we understand about how planets formed, and then look at this at a nanoscopic scale to understand the actual chemistry of what has gone on and what will go on. And that gets us into evolution because if you think of the way planets have changed since their formation, since the formation of the Earth, and since the eventual evolution that led to life, this is all chemistry.We're [also] interested in extracting resources from the Earth and eventually from other places in space, perhaps even bringing an asteroid to Earth for its metal content. Maybe there are planets out there that are made entirely of metals; maybe there are planets out there that are made entirely of sulfides.ASU recently received a $14.7 million US National Science Foundation grant to set up a facility for high-pressure and high-temperature materials research. What can studying materials in these conditions tell us?Click to copy section linkSection link copied!The biggest unanswered question is why materials compress and change their structures the way they do. What is that telling you about how atoms interact? That's the fundamental physics and chemistry question.The fundamental materials and geological question is, how do these reactions determine what materials form? And finally, can you harness this richness of pressure and temperature to make new materials? For example, there have been some indications that high pressures can make some interesting new superconducting materials.High pressure got started, of course, because one wanted it to make diamonds. Well, now one makes diamonds by all sorts of other methods, not just by high pressure.So similarly, if we find some materials at high pressure that really have interesting properties, then the next step always is going to be to find easier, more economical, more scalable ways of making them. But first you have to discover new materials at high pressure and temperature.The mineral navrotskyite was recently discovered in Utah. How did it get named after you?Click to copy section linkSection link copied!A mineral is typically named after somebody who has done something significant, perhaps related to that mineral. The second part is you need to have somebody that has identified and characterized a mineral and wants to name it after you. It's a long proposition through the International Mineralogical Association.[It] came as an absolute surprise to me. You don't go through life thinking you will get a mineral named after you. You go through life doing the science that you find fascinating, that you can get funding for. I'm as surprised as anybody that my career has taken me as far as it has.Rachel Brazil is a freelance contributor to Chemical &amp; Engineering News, the independent news outlet of the American Chemical Society.Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!AuthorRachel BrazilCited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferences Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsACS Central ScienceCite this: ACS Cent. Sci. 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c02126Published December 30, 2024 Publication History Published online 30 December 2024&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is licensed under CC-BY 4.0 . License Summary*You are free to share (copy and redistribute) this article in any medium or format and to adapt (remix, transform, and build upon) the material for any purpose, even commercially within the parameters below:Creative Commons (CC): This is a Creative Commons license.Attribution (BY): Credit must be given to the creator.View full license*DisclaimerThis summary highlights only some of the key features and terms of the actual license. It is not a license and has no legal value. Carefully review the actual license before using these materials. Article Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesAbstractHigh Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThis publication has no References.</description>
      <author>Rachel Brazil</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c02126</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
