<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 01:19:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electrospun Iridium-Based Nanofiber Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Influence of Calcination on Activity&#8211;Stability Relation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07831</link>
      <description>Mikl&#243;s M&#225;rton Kov&#225;cs, Birk Fritsch, Leopold Lahn, Julien Bachmann, Olga Kasian, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Andreas Hutzler, Dominik Dworschak, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402588976

                The enhanced utilization of noble metal catalysts through highly porous nanostructures is crucial to advancing the commercialization prospects of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). In this study, hierarchically structured IrO</description>
      <author>Mikl&#243;s M&#225;rton Kov&#225;cs, Birk Fritsch, Leopold Lahn, Julien Bachmann, Olga Kasian, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Andreas Hutzler, Dominik Dworschak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge Transfer in n-FeO and p-&#945;-Fe2O3 Nanoparticles for Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14181515</link>
      <description>Amir Humayun, Nandapriya Manivelan, Prabakar Kandasamy, Nanomaterials. 14(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402599911

                This study aims to explore the n-FeO and p-&#945;-Fe2O3 semiconductor nanoparticles in hydrogen (HER) and oxygen (OER) evolution reactions and a combined full cell electrocatalyst system to electrolyze the water. We have observed a distinct electrocatalytic performance for both HER and OER by tuning the interplay between iron oxidation states Fe2+ and Fe3+ and utilizing phase-transformed iron oxide nanoparticles (NPs). The Fe2+ rich n-FeO NPs exhibited superior HER performance compared to p-&#945;-Fe2O3 and Fe(OH)x NPs, which is attributed to the enhancement in n-type semiconducting nature under HER potential, facilitating the electron transfer for the reduction in H+ ions. In contrast, p-&#945;-Fe2O3 NPs demonstrated excellent OER activity. An H-cell constructed using n-FeO||p-&#945;-Fe2O3 NPs as cathode and anode achieved a cell voltage of 1.87 V at a current density of 50 mA/cm2. The cell exhibited remarkable stability after 30 h of activation and maintained the high current density of 100 mA/cm2 for 80 h with a negligible increase in cell voltage. This work highlights the semiconducting properties of n-FeO and p-&#945;-Fe2O3 for the electrochemical water splitting system using the band bending phenomenon under the applied potential.</description>
      <author>Amir Humayun, Nandapriya Manivelan, Prabakar Kandasamy</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14181515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active and Robust Electrocatalyst Based on Nickel Phosphide Supported by Borophene for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00652</link>
      <description>Klaudia Ma&#347;lana, Xuecheng Chen, Ewa Mijowska, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402621252

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Klaudia Ma&#347;lana, Xuecheng Chen, Ewa Mijowska</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00652</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid oxygen evolution reaction: Mechanisms, design principles, and prospects for application in membrane electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155901</link>
      <description>Zhao Liu, Xiaoxia Wang, Guanqun Xie, Junjie Ge, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402654330

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhao Liu, Xiaoxia Wang, Guanqun Xie, Junjie Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402669476

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402669520

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402669528

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402669536

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v3/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402680871

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v3/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681002

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681075

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681089

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681112

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681139

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681141

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681196

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681201

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance the Proportion of Fe3+ in NiFe&#8208;Layered Double Hydroxides by utilizing Citric Acid to Improve the Efficiency and Durability of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401582</link>
      <description>Guoqi Li, Lin Li, Jihao Zhang, Shiran Shan, Chunze Yuan, Tsu&#8208;Chien Weng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402720922

                NiFe-layered double hydroxides (NiFe-LDH) are a type of catalyst known for their exceptional catalytic performance during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, citric acid was incorporated into the synthesis process of NiFe-LDH, resulting in the NiFe-LDH-CA catalyst with superior OER performance. The catalytic efficacy is evaluated using linear sweep voltammetry (LSV), which demonstrates a significant reduction in the OER overpotential from 320 mV to 240 mV at a current density of 100 mA cm-2. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and X-ray absorption spectrum (XAS) indicate that the distribution of nickel valence states showed no significant difference between two samples, yet the NiFe-LDH-CA has a significantly higher proportion of Fe3+ ions in its iron content. In-situ Raman spectroscopes reveal that Fe3+ broadens the redox potential of nickel and Pourbaix diagrams indicate that higher Fe3+ levels could facilitate the interaction with oxygen active sites. Based on the analysis of test data, we propose a hypothesis that the high proportion of Fe3+ in catalysts may accelerate the oxygen evolution process by modulating the redox potential of nickel and engaging with reactive oxygen species. This provides valuable insights into how to improve the reaction rate of nickel-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Guoqi Li, Lin Li, Jihao Zhang, Shiran Shan, Chunze Yuan, Tsu&#8208;Chien Weng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic activity of La0.6Sr0. 4Co1-yCuyO3 (y = 0.1, 0.2, and 0.3) for oxygen evolution in an alkaline medium at 25&#8451;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i9.10838</link>
      <description>, Indian Journal of Chemistry. 63(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402782270

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i9.10838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Oxygen and Nitrogen Flow Ratios on the Microstructure Evolution in AlCrTaTiZr High-Entropy Oxynitride Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14091199</link>
      <description>Yung-Chu Liang, Ching-Yin Lee, Miao-I. Lin, Ting-En Shen, Jung-Fan Hung, Jien&#8208;Wei Yeh, Che&#8208;Wei Tsai, Coatings. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402599913

                This study explores the influence of oxygen and nitrogen flow ratios on the microstructure and mechanical properties of AlCrTaTiZr high-entropy oxynitride films. Oxygen flow rates (0%&#8211;0.75%) were adjusted while maintaining a fixed nitrogen flow ratio (RN = 15%) to fabricate films with similar compositions. The results show that increasing oxygen flow enhanced hardness through solid solution strengthening and grain refinement, though excessive oxygen caused an amorphous structure and reduced hardness. After annealing at 900 &#176;C, the hardness of all films was further increased. The film with a nitrogen flow ratio 40 times higher than oxygen exhibited the highest hardness of 21.8 GPa, along with superior mechanical performance. These findings highlight the potential of high-entropy oxynitride films for applications requiring high wear resistance and adhesion.</description>
      <author>Yung-Chu Liang, Ching-Yin Lee, Miao-I. Lin, Ting-En Shen, Jung-Fan Hung, Jien&#8208;Wei Yeh, Che&#8208;Wei Tsai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14091199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Silver Performance in Electrocatalytic Oxidation of HCHO via SMSI between Ag&#8208;Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Interfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405358</link>
      <description>Peiyuan Mao, Bingbing Chen, Rui Huang, Jing Wang, Long Xiao, B. Zhang, Chuan Shi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402605034

                Abstract The replacement of oxygen evolution reactions with organic molecule oxidation reactions to enable energy&#8208;efficient hydrogen production has been a subject of interest. However, further reducing reaction energy consumption and releasing hydrogen from organic molecules continue to pose significant challenges. Herein, a strategy is proposed to produce hydrogen and formic acid from formaldehyde using Ag/Co 3 O 4 interface catalysts at the anode. The key to improving the performance of Ag&#8208;based catalysts for formaldehyde oxidation lies in the strong SMSI achieved through the well&#8208;designed &#8220;spontaneous redox reaction&#8221; between Ag and Co 3 O 4 precursors. Nano&#8208;sized Ag particles are uniformly dispersed on Co 3 O 4 nanosheets, and electron&#8208;deficient Ag &#948;+ are formed by the SMSI between Ag and Co 3 O 4. Ag/Co 3 O 4 demonstrates exceptional formaldehyde oxidation activity at low potentials of 0.32 V versus RHE and 0.65 V versus RHE, achieving current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The electrolyzer &#8220;Ag/Co 3 O 4 ||20% Pt/C&#8221; achieves over 195% hydrogen efficiency and over 98% formic acid selectivity, maintaining stable operation for 60 hours. This work not only presents a novel approach to precisely modulate Ag particle size and interface electronic structure via SMSI, but also provides a promising approach to efficient and energy&#8208;saving hydrogen production and the transformation of harmful formaldehyde.</description>
      <author>Peiyuan Mao, Bingbing Chen, Rui Huang, Jing Wang, Long Xiao, B. Zhang, Chuan Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405358</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fate of nitrogen in deep magma oceans</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31223/x5db0k</link>
      <description>Ekanshu Mallick, Kelsey B. Prissel, K. Righter, Colin J. Jackson, EarthArXiv (California Digital Library). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402591600

                Nitrogen is important in planetary evolution because it is essential to life and the most abundant element in Earth&#8217;s atmosphere. Here, we investigate how core formation affects the distribution of N within accreting terrestrial planets. We conducted laser-heated diamond anvil cell experiments (LH-DAC) over a wide range of high pressure-temperature-compositional (PTX) conditions (38-103 GPa, 2728-5609 K, -1.95 to -1.03 &#8710;IW, 0.5-3.7 NBO/T) to study nitrogen partitioning in metal-silicate systems. Combining our data with existing low and high PT results, we developed a nitrogen partitioning model applicable from early accretion to extreme PT stages associated with giant impacts. We test the robustness of our model by accurately predicting nitrogen partitioning in a multi-anvil experiment conducted independently at 15 GPa, 2573 K with oxygen fugacity of -2.5 &#8710;IW. Our model shows that increasing pressure, oxygen fugacity, and N concentration in the alloy make nitrogen more siderophile, while increasing temperature, oxygen and silicon contents in the alloy, and the SiO2 content of the silicate melt make nitrogen less siderophile. Application of our model to core formation conditions under oxidized and reduced scenarios suggest that nitrogen can be siderophile or lithophile under low PT conditions but exhibits a neutral partitioning at high PT conditions (&amp;gt; 100 GPa, 5000 K) over a wide range of bulk planet compositions. Using our model, along with partitioning models for S and C, we examine how core formation scenarios can fractionate C/N and S/N ratios in the BSE. Our model suggests that backreaction of volatile rich cores from reduced, smaller impactors (sub-Mars-sized) within deep magma oceans can impart a wide range of C/N and S/N ratios on the magma ocean. We find that the amount of silicate entrainment has a strong control on elemental fractionations imparted to the magma oceans. Elevated C/N and S/N ratios are associated with larger degrees of silicate entrainment, and vice versa. Thus, Earth&#8217;s apparent depletion of N may relate to its volatiles being reprocessed within deep magma oceans, possibly during the end stages of accretion.</description>
      <author>Ekanshu Mallick, Kelsey B. Prissel, K. Righter, Colin J. Jackson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31223/x5db0k</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
