<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 01:22:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Entropy Ag&#8208;Ru&#8208;based Electrocatalysts with Dual&#8208;Active&#8208;Center for Highly Stable Ultra&#8208;Low&#8208;Temperature Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415216</link>
      <description>Ziming Qiu, Xiaotian Guo, Shuai Cao, Meng Du, Qinchao Wang, Yecan Pi, Chun&#8208;Sen Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403165063

                The development of advanced bifunctional catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is significant for rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, a unique dual active center alloying strategy is proposed to achieve the efficient bifunctional oxygen catalysis, and the high entropy effect is further exploited to modulate the structure and performance of the catalysts. The MOF&#8208;assisted pyrolysis&#8208;replacement&#8208;alloying method was employed to construct the CoCuFeAgRu high&#8208;entropy alloy (HEA), which are uniformly anchored in porous nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanosheets. Notably, the obtained HEA catalyst exhibits excellent catalytic performance for both ORR and OER, and a peak power density of 136. 53 mW cm&#8208;2 and an energy density of 987.9 mAh gZn&#8208;1, surpassing the most of the previously reported bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts. Moreover, the assembled flexible rechargeable ZAB enables excellent performance even at the ultralow temperature of &#8208;40&#176;C, with an energy density of 601.6 mAh gZn&#8208;1 and remarkable cycling stability up to 1,650 hours. Combined experimental and theoretical calculation results reveal that the excellent bifunctional catalytic activity of the HEA catalyst originated from the synergistic effect of the Ag and Ru dual active centers, and the optimization of the electronic structure by alloying effect.</description>
      <author>Ziming Qiu, Xiaotian Guo, Shuai Cao, Meng Du, Qinchao Wang, Yecan Pi, Chun&#8208;Sen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus Doping Heterostructure La(OH)3@CuO @NF as an Advanced Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoes.2024.100826</link>
      <description>Decui Liang, Weishun Hou, Ying Zhang, Jihua SHANG, Haibo Ren, Yufeng Sun, International Journal of Electrochemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403168525

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Decui Liang, Weishun Hou, Ying Zhang, Jihua SHANG, Haibo Ren, Yufeng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoes.2024.100826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Progress in Structure Evolution and Durability Modulation of Ir&#8208; and Ru&#8208;Based OER Catalysts under Acidic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406657</link>
      <description>You Zi, Chengxu Zhang, Jian-Qiang Zhao, Ying Cheng, Jinliang Yuan, Jue Hu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403170675

                Abstract Green hydrogen energy, as one of the most promising energy carriers, plays a crucial role in addressing energy and environmental issues. Oxygen evolution reaction catalysts, as the key to water electrolysis hydrogen production technology, have been subject to durability constraints, preventing large&#8208;scale commercial development. Under the high current density and harsh acid&#8208;base electrolyte conditions of the water electrolysis reaction, the active metals in the catalysts are easily converted into high&#8208;valent soluble species to dissolve, leading to poor structural durability of the catalysts. There is an urgent need to overcome the durability challenges under acidic conditions and develop electrocatalysts with both high catalytic activity and high durability. In this review, the latest research results are analyzed in depth from both thermodynamic and kinetic perspectives. First, a comprehensive summary of the structural deactivation state process of noble metal oxide catalysts is presented. Second, the evolution of the structure of catalysts possessing high durability is discussed. Finally, four new strategies for the preparation of stable catalysts, &#8220;electron buffer (ECB) strategy&#8221;, combination strength control, strain control, and surface coating, are summarized. The challenges and prospects are also elaborated for the future synthesis of more effective Ru/Ir&#8208;based catalysts and boost their future application.</description>
      <author>You Zi, Chengxu Zhang, Jian-Qiang Zhao, Ying Cheng, Jinliang Yuan, Jue Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raman Spectroscopic Observation of Electrolyte-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Reaction Intermediates in Nickel-Based Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k9mr8</link>
      <description>Tomohiro Fukushima, Kanji Tsuchimoto, Nobuaki Oyamada, Daiki Sato, Hiro Minamimoto, Kei Murakoshi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403172070

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the counterpart in the hydrogen production by the water electrolysis. Further challenges have been required to bypass the energy consumption processes in OER. It is still important to unveil the OER intermediates toward the effective green hydrogen production. In this study, we conducted the in-situ Raman observation of the OER intermediates over Ni nanohole-array electrodes in the various electrolyte conditions. Ni nanohole-array electrodes were prepared with the interference exposure methods. Intense Raman peaks were observed from the Ni-OH, Ni-OOH, and active oxygen species as OER intermediates. The OER behavior can be classified with the reactants, such as OH&#8722; and H2O. The presented study demonstrates the importance of the electrolyte for the designing active OER catalysis for the next generation energy society.</description>
      <author>Tomohiro Fukushima, Kanji Tsuchimoto, Nobuaki Oyamada, Daiki Sato, Hiro Minamimoto, Kei Murakoshi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-k9mr8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Modulating of W 18 O 49 Nanospheres by Niobium Doping for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403043</link>
      <description>Hui Guo, Pan Lu, Mengyou Gao, Linghui Kong, Jingpeng Zhang, Aslam Khan, Nadeem Siddiqui, Jianjian Lin, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403193963

                Developing efficient electrocatalysts to reduce HER overpotential is vital to enhance hydrogen production efficiency and minimize energy consumption. Adjusting the electronic structure of transition metal oxides via elemental doping is a potent strategy to improve the effectiveness of electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution. In this work, we synthesized a set of niobium&#8208;doped tungsten oxides (Nbx&#8208;W18O49) under anoxic conditions using a straightforward &#8220;one&#8208;pot&#8221; solvothermal approach. After doping Nb, the oxygen vacancy content inside W18O49 was increased, which induced a synergistic effect with the active sites of tungsten. In acidic environments, the hydrogen evolution activity of the Nb0.6&#8208;W18O49 electrocatalyst is second only by 20 wt% Pt/C. It attains a current density of &#8208;10 mA cm&#8208;2 at an overpotential of 102 mV. By comparison with W18O49, Nb0.4&#8208;W18O49 and Nb0.5&#8208;W18O49, Nb0.6&#8208;W18O49 demonstrates a reduced charge transfer resistance, which significantly enhances its conductivity and the speed of electron movement across interfaces. Coupled with this feature are notably faster HER kinetics. Additionally, it exhibits excellent stability, meaning it maintains its performance and structural integrity over prolonged periods and under various operational conditions. This article provides a new perspective for discovering inexpensive and efficient hydrogen evolution electrocatalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Hui Guo, Pan Lu, Mengyou Gao, Linghui Kong, Jingpeng Zhang, Aslam Khan, Nadeem Siddiqui, Jianjian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Dynamic Surface Transformation on the Activity and Stability of Mixed Co&#8208;Mn Cubic Spinel Oxides in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403096</link>
      <description>Biao He, Pouya Hosseini, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Jonas Schulwitz, Serena DeBeer, Ulrich Hagemann, Markus Heidelmann, Serena DeBeer, Martin Muhler, Serhiy Cherevko, Kristina Tschulik, Tong Li, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403194568

                Abstract An atomic&#8208;scale understanding of how electrocatalyst surfaces reconstruct and transform during electrocatalytic reactions is essential for optimizing their activity and longevity. This is particularly important for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), where dynamic and substantial structural and compositional changes occur during the reaction. Herein, a multimodal method is developed by combining X&#8208;ray fine structure absorption and photoemission spectroscopy, transmission electron microscopy, and atom probe tomography with electrochemical measurements to interrogate the temporal evolution of oxidation states, atom coordination, structure, and composition on Co 2 MnO 4 and CoMn 2 O 4 cubic spinel nanoparticle surfaces upon OER cycling in alkaline media. Co 2 MnO 4 is activated at the onset of OER due to the formation of &#8776;2 nm Co&#8208;Mn oxyhydroxides with an optimal Co/Mn ratio of &#8776;3. As OER proceeds, Mn dissolution and redeposition occur for the CoMn oxyhydroxides, extending the OER stability of Co 2 MnO 4 . Such dynamic dissolution and redeposition are also observed for CoMn 2 O 4 , leading to the formation of less OER&#8208;active Mn&#8208;rich oxides on the nanoparticle surfaces. This study provides mechanistic insights into how dynamic surface reconstruction and transformation affect the activity and stability of mixed CoMn cubic spinels toward OER.</description>
      <author>Biao He, Pouya Hosseini, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Jonas Schulwitz, Serena DeBeer, Ulrich Hagemann, Markus Heidelmann, Serena DeBeer, Martin Muhler, Serhiy Cherevko, Kristina Tschulik, Tong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403096</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Efficiency Photo&#8208;Assisted Large Current&#8208;Density Water Splitting with Mott&#8208;Schottky Heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415492</link>
      <description>Minming Jiang, Jiang Xu, Yujie Chen, Luqi Wang, Paul Munroe, Zonghan Xie, Shengjie Peng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403195683

                The development of bifunctional photogenerated carrier&#8208;assisted electrocatalytic (PCA&#8208;EC) electrodes that operate with stability at large current&#8208;density remains a significant challenge. Herein, we demonstrate a simple sputtering&#8208;deposition process to synthesize a novel MnWO4/FeCoNi Mott&#8208;Schottky heterojunction coating and deposit it on a pure Ti substrate to prepare high&#8208;performance PCA&#8208;EC electrodes, which exhibits enhanced light absorption range/intensity and rapidly separated photogenerated electron&#8208;hole pairs. This design allows photogenerated electrons to directly participate in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), while the strong oxidation of photogenerated holes significantly reduces the defect formation energy of active metals, thereby facilitating the rapid reconstruction of highly active Ni(FeCo)OOH/MnOOH species for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As expected, the as&#8208;prepared electrode demonstrates the overpotentials of 64 mV for the HER and 204 mV for the OER at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 under illumination. Benefiting from the stable interface with Fe/Co/Ni&#8208;O&#8208;Mn/W bonding units, the dual&#8208;electrode photoassisted electrolytic cell achieves long&#8208;term stability at current densities of 500 and 1000 mA cm&#8722;2. This work provides detailed insights into the enhancement mechanism of PCA&#8208;EC and contributes to the development of photo&#8208;assisted water splitting electrodes for large current&#8208;density applications.</description>
      <author>Minming Jiang, Jiang Xu, Yujie Chen, Luqi Wang, Paul Munroe, Zonghan Xie, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Closed&#8208;Loop and Precipitation&#8208;Free CO2 Capture Process Enabled by Electrochemical pH Gradient</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401533</link>
      <description>Jiayin Zhou, Xiaofei Guan, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403199271

                Carbon dioxide (CO2) capture is a crucial negative&#8208;emission technology for the mitigation of climate change and global warming. The urgent need of combating climate change motivates the research and development of economical, effective and environmentally benign processes for CO2 capture. Herein, we design and report a flow cell for the CO2 capture from air or flue gas in a precipitate&#8208;free and closed&#8208;loop manner. No ion&#8208;exchange membrane is used in the electrolyser. The water electrolysis produces acidic solution near the anode and alkaline solution near the cathode, while generating valuable hydrogen and oxygen byproducts. The dilute CO2 in air or flue gas is captured by the alkaline solution, which is then mixed with the acidic solution to release the concentrated CO2. The process operates in a cyclic manner as driven by the water electrolysis and the mechanical pumping. No precipitation of calcium carbonate is involved for fixing CO2, which may simplify the separation process and minimizing the materials loss. The simple process enabled by electrochemical pH gradient shows promise for efficient CO2 capture on both small and large scales.</description>
      <author>Jiayin Zhou, Xiaofei Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced &lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Spectroscopic Techniques for Probing the Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05891</link>
      <description>Suk-Kyoung Hong, Ze&#8208;Cheng Yao, Xing Cheng, Zhe Jiang, Tang Tang, Jin&#8208;Song Hu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403199440

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Suk-Kyoung Hong, Ze&#8208;Cheng Yao, Xing Cheng, Zhe Jiang, Tang Tang, Jin&#8208;Song Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05891</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Tuning of Ni/Fe Complexes based Electrocatalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b</link>
      <description>Hong Zhou, Xuan Hao, Jiexin Guan, Yilin Deng, Zi Wei, Yashu Liu, Guofeng Zhu, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403201390

                Non-noble oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts have garnered considerable attention in recent years. Alkaline OER catalysts based on coordination complexes exhibit high performance but often undergo irreversible ligand dissociation, resulting...</description>
      <author>Hong Zhou, Xuan Hao, Jiexin Guan, Yilin Deng, Zi Wei, Yashu Liu, Guofeng Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of electrocatalytic properties of high entropy alloy electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04984e</link>
      <description>Xiaojun Lv, kaixin wang, Guoqiang Wang, Ye Liu, Qianqian Cai, Xueyuan Chen, Lei Zhang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403202259

                With the rapid increase of demand for green hydrogen, the development of electrolytic water technology has been widely concerned. The efficient oxygen evolution catalyst provides the feasibility of hydrogen production...</description>
      <author>Xiaojun Lv, kaixin wang, Guoqiang Wang, Ye Liu, Qianqian Cai, Xueyuan Chen, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04984e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline water electrolysis using bimetallic NiFe metal-organic frameworks integrated with carbon nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.039</link>
      <description>Sungwon Cho, Joo Hyun Kang, Huy Du Nguyen, Kwon Seok Chae, Nguyen Anh Thu Tran, Young&#8208;Woo Lee, Jinkee Hong, Dongwon Shin, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Younghyun Cho, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 90(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403204122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sungwon Cho, Joo Hyun Kang, Huy Du Nguyen, Kwon Seok Chae, Nguyen Anh Thu Tran, Young&#8208;Woo Lee, Jinkee Hong, Dongwon Shin, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Younghyun Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atom&#8208;Doped Triphasic VP&#8208;Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;P&#8208;MoP Heterostructure: Unveiling a Breakthrough Electrocatalyst for Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405952</link>
      <description>Ganesh Bhandari, Purna Prasad Dhakal, Duy Thanh Tran, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213720

                Abstract Enhancement of an alkaline water splitting reaction in Pt&#8208;based single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) relies on effective metal&#8208;support interactions. A Pt single atom (Pt SA )&#8208;immobilized three&#8208;phased Pt SA @VP&#8208;Ni 3 P&#8208;MoP heterostructure on nickel foam is presented, demonstrating high catalytic performance. The existence of Pt SA on triphasic metal phosphides gives an outstanding performance toward overall water splitting. The Pt SA @VP&#8208;Ni 3 P&#8208;MoP performs a low overpotential of 28 and 261 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at a current density of 10 and 25 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The Pt SA @VP&#8208;Ni 3 P&#8208;MoP (+,&#8722;) alkaline electrolyzer achieves a minimum cell voltage of 1.48 V at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for overall water splitting. Additionally, the electrocatalyst exhibits a substantial Faradaic yield of &#8776;98.12% for H 2 and 98.47% for O 2 at a current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . Consequently, this study establishes a connection for understanding the active role of single metal atoms in substrate configuration for catalytic performance. It also facilitates the successful synthesis of SACs, with a substantial loading on transition metal phosphides and maximal atomic utilization, providing more active sites and, thereby enhancing electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Ganesh Bhandari, Purna Prasad Dhakal, Duy Thanh Tran, Thanh Hai Nguyen, Van An Dinh, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Structure and Dissociation of Interfacial Water on RuO2 for Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413334</link>
      <description>Liqing Wu, Wenxia Huang, Dongyang Li, Hongnan Jia, Bingbing Zhao, Juan Zhu, Haiqing Zhou, Wei Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403214909

                Understanding the structure and dynamic process of interfacial water molecules at the catalyst&#8208;electrolyte interface on acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics is highly desirable for the development of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers. Herein, we construct a series of p&#8208;block metallic elements (Ga, In, Sn) doped RuO2 catalysts with manipulated electronic structure and Ru&#8208;O covalency to investigate the effect of electrochemical interfacial engineering on the improvement of acidic OER activity. Associated with operando attenuated total reflectance surface&#8208;enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy measurements and theoretical analysis, we uncover the free&#8208;H2O enriched local environment and dynamic evolution from 4&#8208;coordinated hydrogen&#8208;bonded water and 2&#8208;coordinated hydrogen&#8208;bonded water to free&#8208;H2O on the surface of Ga&#8208;RuO2, are responsible for the optimized connectivity of hydrogen bonding network in the electrical double layer by promoting solvent reorganization. In addition, the structurally ordered interfacial water molecules facilitate high&#8208;efficiency proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer across the interface, leading to reduced energy barrier of the follow&#8208;up dissociation process and enhanced acidic OER performance. This work highlights the key role of structure and dynamic process of interfacial water for acidic OER, and demonstrates the electrochemical interfacial engineering as an efficient strategy to design high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Liqing Wu, Wenxia Huang, Dongyang Li, Hongnan Jia, Bingbing Zhao, Juan Zhu, Haiqing Zhou, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Structure and Dissociation of Interfacial Water on RuO2 for Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413334</link>
      <description>Liqing Wu, Wenxia Huang, Dongyang Li, Hongnan Jia, Bingbing Zhao, Juan Zhu, Haiqing Zhou, Wei Luo, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403218349

                Understanding the structure and dynamic process of interfacial water molecules at the catalyst&#8208;electrolyte interface on acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics is highly desirable for the development of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers. Herein, we construct a series of p&#8208;block metallic elements (Ga, In, Sn) doped RuO2 catalysts with manipulated electronic structure and Ru&#8208;O covalency to investigate the effect of electrochemical interfacial engineering on the improvement of acidic OER activity. Associated with operando attenuated total reflectance surface&#8208;enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy measurements and theoretical analysis, we uncover the free&#8208;H2O enriched local environment and dynamic evolution from 4&#8208;coordinated hydrogen&#8208;bonded water and 2&#8208;coordinated hydrogen&#8208;bonded water to free&#8208;H2O on the surface of Ga&#8208;RuO2, are responsible for the optimized connectivity of hydrogen bonding network in the electrical double layer by promoting solvent reorganization. In addition, the structurally ordered interfacial water molecules facilitate high&#8208;efficiency proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer across the interface, leading to reduced energy barrier of the follow&#8208;up dissociation process and enhanced acidic OER performance. This work highlights the key role of structure and dynamic process of interfacial water for acidic OER, and demonstrates the electrochemical interfacial engineering as an efficient strategy to design high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Liqing Wu, Wenxia Huang, Dongyang Li, Hongnan Jia, Bingbing Zhao, Juan Zhu, Haiqing Zhou, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional catalytic activity of anion-doped LaSrCoO &lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.240387</link>
      <description>Ittoku Nozawa, Hidehisa Hagiwara, Royal Society Open Science. 11(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403259305

                Here, we synthesized Co-based, anion-incorporated&#8205; &#8204;R&#8204;u&#8204;d&#8204;d&#8204;l&#8204;e&#8204;s-d&#8204;e&#8204;n&#8204;-&#8204;Popper perovskite electrocatalysts (LaSrCoO</description>
      <author>Ittoku Nozawa, Hidehisa Hagiwara</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.240387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molten salt electrolytic CO2-derived NiCo2@C catalysts with enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176950</link>
      <description>Xinxin Liang, Yihan Wang, Yi Zheng, Peng Wang, Xiaodong Jia, Wei Weng, Wei Xiao, Jianbo Zhao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403287527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinxin Liang, Yihan Wang, Yi Zheng, Peng Wang, Xiaodong Jia, Wei Weng, Wei Xiao, Jianbo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn2+-doped Co3Si2O5(OH)4 serpentine nanosheets with tuned d-band centers for efficient oxygen evolution in alkaline and neutral electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02937-w</link>
      <description>Shi-Cheng Huang, Yulong Zhou, Dongdong Zhang, Dingzhong Luo, Baopeng Yang, Gen Chen, Xiaohe Liu, Jia Tang, Ning Zhang, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403295903

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shi-Cheng Huang, Yulong Zhou, Dongdong Zhang, Dingzhong Luo, Baopeng Yang, Gen Chen, Xiaohe Liu, Jia Tang, Ning Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02937-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strontium Doped IrOx Triggers Direct O&#8208;O Coupling to Boost Acid Water Oxidation Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418456</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Lu, Zhiyi Lu, Caihan Zhu, Yingjie Wen, Minli Wang, Yunan Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403299748

                The discovery of efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic conditions is crucial for the commercialization of proton&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolyzers. In this work, we propose a Sr(OH)2&#8208;assisted method to fabricate a (200) facet highly exposed strontium&#8208;doped IrOx catalyst to provide available adjacent iridium sites with lower Ir&#8208;O covalency. This design facilitates direct O&#8208;O coupling during the acidic water oxidation process, thereby circumventing the high energy barrier associated with the generation of *OOH intermediates. Benefiting from this advantage, the resulting Sr&#8208;IrOx catalyst exhibits an impressive overpotential of 207 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4. Furthermore, a PEMWE device utilizing Sr&#8208;IrOx as the anodic catalyst demonstrates a cell voltage of 1.72 V at 1 A cm&#8208;2 and maintains excellent stability for over 500 hours. Our work not only provides guidance for the design of improved acidic OER catalysts but also encourages the development of iridium&#8208;based electrocatalysts with novel mechanisms for other electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Lu, Zhiyi Lu, Caihan Zhu, Yingjie Wen, Minli Wang, Yunan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strontium Doped IrOx Triggers Direct O&#8208;O Coupling to Boost Acid Water Oxidation Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418456</link>
      <description>Zhiyi Lu, Zhiyi Lu, Caihan Zhu, Yingjie Wen, Minli Wang, Yunan Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403299861

                The discovery of efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic conditions is crucial for the commercialization of proton&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolyzers. In this work, we propose a Sr(OH)2&#8208;assisted method to fabricate a (200) facet highly exposed strontium&#8208;doped IrOx catalyst to provide available adjacent iridium sites with lower Ir&#8208;O covalency. This design facilitates direct O&#8208;O coupling during the acidic water oxidation process, thereby circumventing the high energy barrier associated with the generation of *OOH intermediates. Benefiting from this advantage, the resulting Sr&#8208;IrOx catalyst exhibits an impressive overpotential of 207 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4. Furthermore, a PEMWE device utilizing Sr&#8208;IrOx as the anodic catalyst demonstrates a cell voltage of 1.72 V at 1 A cm&#8208;2 and maintains excellent stability for over 500 hours. Our work not only provides guidance for the design of improved acidic OER catalysts but also encourages the development of iridium&#8208;based electrocatalysts with novel mechanisms for other electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Zhiyi Lu, Zhiyi Lu, Caihan Zhu, Yingjie Wen, Minli Wang, Yunan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilization of High&#8208;Valent Molecular Cobalt Sites through Oxidized Phosphorus in Reduced Graphene Oxide for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416274</link>
      <description>Xin Wang, Jing Wang, Guoliang Dai, Wenjuan Song, Poe Ei Phyu Win, Sheng Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403299947

                Heterogeneous molecular cobalt (Co) sites represent one type of classical catalytic sites for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline solutions. There are dynamic equilibriums between Co2+, Co3+ and Co4+ states coupling with OH&#8722;/H+ interaction before and during the OER event. Since the emergence of Co2+ sites is detrimental to the OER cycle, the stabilization of high&#8208;valent Co sites to shift away from the equilibrium becomes critical and is proposed as a new strategy to enhance OER. Herein, phosphorus (P) atoms were doped into reduced graphene oxide to link molecular Co2+ acetylacetonate toward synthesizing a novel heterogeneous molecular catalyst. By increasing the oxidation states of P heteroatoms, the linked Co sites were spontaneously oxidized from 2+ to 3+ states in a KOH solution through OH&#8722; ions coupling at an open circuit condition. With excluding the Co2+ sites, the as&#8208;derived Co sites with 3+ initial states exhibited intrinsically high OER activity, validating the effectiveness of the strategy of stabilizing high valence Co sites.</description>
      <author>Xin Wang, Jing Wang, Guoliang Dai, Wenjuan Song, Poe Ei Phyu Win, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecting double-shelled hollow carbon nanocages embedded bimetallic sites as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110538</link>
      <description>Congcong Wang, Kai Zhang, Bai Yang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403302736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Congcong Wang, Kai Zhang, Bai Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110538</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Electrocatalytic Behavior of Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;MnS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoflake-Anchored rGO for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in an Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02824</link>
      <description>Harshini Sharan, Jayachandran Madhavan, Ganeshbabu Mariappan, R. Kalai Selvan, A. Daya Mani, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403324220

                A catalyst of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) that is viable, affordable, and active for effective water-splitting applications is critical. A variety of electrocatalysts have been discovered to replace noble metal-based catalysts. Of these, transition metal-based sulfides are essential for incorporating carbonaceous materials to improve electrical conductivity, resulting in better electrocatalytic performance. Our study illustrates the synthesis of Cu</description>
      <author>Harshini Sharan, Jayachandran Madhavan, Ganeshbabu Mariappan, R. Kalai Selvan, A. Daya Mani</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiIr nanowire assembles as an efficient electrocatalyst towards oxygen evolution reaction in both acid and alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400851</link>
      <description>Ning Zhang, Yalun Wang, Ronglan Wu, Xianwen Yang, Yan Wu, Fangmu Wang, Ping Cui, Guigao Liu, Wei Jiang, Haijiao Xie, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403334253

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the rate&#8208;limiting step in water electrolysis due to its sluggish kinetic, and it is challenging to develop an OER catalyst that could work efficiently in both acid and alkaline environment. Herein, NiIr nanowire assembles (NAs) with unique nanoflower morphology were prepared by a facile hydrothermal method. As a result, the NiIr NAs exhibited superior OER activity in both acid and alkaline media. Specifically, in 0.1 M HClO4, NiIr NAs presented a superior electrocatalytic performance with a low overpotential of merely 242 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and a Tafel slope of only 58.1 mV dec&#8208;1, surpassing that of commercial IrO2 and pure Ir NAs. And it achieved a significantly higher mass activity of 148.40 A/g at &#8208;1.5 V versus RHE. In 1.0 M KOH, NiIr NAs has an overpotential of 291 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and a Tafel slope of 42.1 mV dec&#8208;1. Such remarkable activity makes the NiIr NAs among the best of recently reported representative Ir&#8208;based OER electrocatalysts. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations confirmed alloying effect promotes surface bonding of NiIr with oxygen&#8208;containing reactants, resulting in excellent catalytic properties.</description>
      <author>Ning Zhang, Yalun Wang, Ronglan Wu, Xianwen Yang, Yan Wu, Fangmu Wang, Ping Cui, Guigao Liu, Wei Jiang, Haijiao Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Straightforward Model for Quantifying Local pH Gradients Governing the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09521</link>
      <description>Samuel S. Veroneau, Alaina C. Hartnett, Jaeyune Ryu, Hyukhun Hong, Cyrille Costentin, Daniel G. Nocera, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403326469

                The production and consumption of protons by an electrocatalyst will, under certain conditions, generate localized microenvironments with properties distinct from those of the bulk solution. These local properties are particularly impactful for reactions involving proton-coupled electron transfer, where the generation of locally basic or acidic environments may significantly influence the energy efficiency and reaction selectivity of the electrocatalyst. Whereas local pH environments have been observed and characterized in reductive half-reactions, including the CO2 reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions, the incompatibility of conventional techniques and materials has limited studies in oxidative half-reactions, including the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which provides the reducing equivalents for solar-to-fuels electrolysis. With the straightforward parameters bulk pH, buffer composition and pKa, and mass transport, we develop a model for describing local pH as a function of current density regardless of the microscopic details of the mechanism. Using an acid-stable PbOx OER catalyst, we observe the formation and dissipation of pH gradients during the OER and validate the model with voltammetric and potentiometric studies. The model predicts how local acidic environments can develop over a narrow OER current density window, thus providing further motivation for the development of OER catalysts that are stable to acid, even when operating in basic aqueous conditions. More generally, the model is not restricted to the OER and is useful for determining the onset of local pH gradients for other electrocatalytic reactions that involve the consumption or generation of protons in energy conversion reactions.</description>
      <author>Samuel S. Veroneau, Alaina C. Hartnett, Jaeyune Ryu, Hyukhun Hong, Cyrille Costentin, Daniel G. Nocera</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Local Coordination Sphere of Ir Single Atoms at the Atomic Interface for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08847</link>
      <description>Ashwani Kumar, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, Pascal Fandr&#233;, Olaf R&#252;diger, Min Gyu Kim, Serena DeBeer, Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403208726

                Single-atom catalysts dispersed on an oxide support are essential for overcoming the sluggishness of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the durability of most metal single-atoms is compromised under harsh OER conditions due to their low coordination (weak metal-support interactions) and excessive disruption of metal-O</description>
      <author>Ashwani Kumar, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, Pascal Fandr&#233;, Olaf R&#252;diger, Min Gyu Kim, Serena DeBeer, Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction: Plasma-assisted fabrication of ultra-dispersed copper oxides in and on C-rich carbon nitride as functional composites for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90176b</link>
      <description>Mattia Benedet, Angelica Fasan, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato, C. Sada, Silvia Maria Deambrosis, Valentina Zin, Francesco Montagner, Oleg I. Lebedev, Evgeny Modin, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403335485

                Correction for &#8216;Plasma-assisted fabrication of ultra-dispersed copper oxides in and on C-rich carbon nitride as functional composites for the oxygen evolution reaction&#8217; by Mattia Benedet et al. , Dalton Trans. , 2024, https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02186j.</description>
      <author>Mattia Benedet, Angelica Fasan, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato, C. Sada, Silvia Maria Deambrosis, Valentina Zin, Francesco Montagner, Oleg I. Lebedev, Evgeny Modin, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90176b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Supporting FeCoNiCuTiGa High-Entropy Alloy Electrodes for Alkaline Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions: Experimental and Theoretical Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01036</link>
      <description>Yezeng He, Jiazhen Wu, Fangyu Hu, Liang Mao, Tejraj M. Aminabhavi, Yasser Vasseghian, Akbar Hojjati&#8211;Najafabadi, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403215206

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yezeng He, Jiazhen Wu, Fangyu Hu, Liang Mao, Tejraj M. Aminabhavi, Yasser Vasseghian, Akbar Hojjati&#8211;Najafabadi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Manipulation to Create High-Valent Fe&lt;sup&gt;4+&lt;/sup&gt; for Efficient and Ultrastable Oxygen Evolution at Industrial-Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c09259</link>
      <description>Yong Feng, Huan Wang, Kun Feng, Chengyu Li, Shuo Li, Cheng L&#252;, Youyong Li, Ding Ma, Jun Zhong, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403318150

                Manipulating the electronic structure of a catalyst at the atomic level is an effective but challenging way to improve the catalytic performance. Here, by stretching the Fe-O bond in FeOOH with an inserted Mo atom, a Fe-O-Mo unit can be created, which will induce the formation of high-valent Fe</description>
      <author>Yong Feng, Huan Wang, Kun Feng, Chengyu Li, Shuo Li, Cheng L&#252;, Youyong Li, Ding Ma, Jun Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c09259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Size-Dependent Core&#8211;Shell Fine Structures and Oxygen Evolution Activity of Electrochemical IrO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles Revealed by Cryogenic Electron Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c10657</link>
      <description>Jingbo Xu, Liang Chang, Yinping Wei, Jie Wei, Wenting Cui, Taokai Ying, Lin Gan, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213920

                Electrochemically oxidized amorphous iridium oxides (IrO</description>
      <author>Jingbo Xu, Liang Chang, Yinping Wei, Jie Wei, Wenting Cui, Taokai Ying, Lin Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c10657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe single atoms coupled Fe3C multi-functional catalysts on P, F, N-doped carbon nanotubes for stable Zn-air batteries with ultra-high power densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04194a</link>
      <description>R. Manigandan, Hongsong Yu, Anand Rajkamal, Gun Jin Yun, Ziheng Zhang, Jing Wang, Wei Wang, Wu Yu, Chen Daiqian, Bo Yu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403214915

                It is still challengeable to develop low-cost, efficient, and stable multi-functional electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution (OER), overall water splitting (OWS), oxygen reduction (ORR), and zinc-air batteries (ZABs). To address such...</description>
      <author>R. Manigandan, Hongsong Yu, Anand Rajkamal, Gun Jin Yun, Ziheng Zhang, Jing Wang, Wei Wang, Wu Yu, Chen Daiqian, Bo Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04194a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Hybrid Seawater Electrolysis with Anodic Oxidation Reactions (AORs): Recent Progress and Prospect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01191k</link>
      <description>Baghendra Singh, Anuj Goyal, Sunil Verma, Lakhwinder Singh, Apparao Draksharapu, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403173965

                The major obstacle in electrocatalytic seawater splitting (ESS) is the electro-oxidation of dissolved ions at the anode, which causes significant electrode corrosion and competes with the oxygen evolution reaction (OER),...</description>
      <author>Baghendra Singh, Anuj Goyal, Sunil Verma, Lakhwinder Singh, Apparao Draksharapu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01191k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous and B&#8208;site Substituted Y2[Mn0.2Ru0.8]2O7 Pyrochlore for Boosting Acidic Water Oxidation Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401419</link>
      <description>Zhan Tian, Xin Yang, Hongrui Jia, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Guoqiang Li, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403164899

                Boosting the reaction stability without sacrificing the activity and cost is extremely important but full of challenging for the RuO2&#8208;based oxygen evolution catalysts. Herein, porous and B&#8208;site substituted Y2[Mn0.2Ru0.8]2O7 (p&#8208;Y2[Mn0.2Ru0.8]2O7) pyrochlore toward oxygen evolution reaction is innovatively synthesized. The formed meso/macro&#8208;porous structure can increase the specific surface area and corresponding active sites, meanwhile, Mn&#8208;substitution can modulate the electronic structure, stabilize the morphology, and reduce the dosage of Ru species. Excitingly, the p&#8208;Y2[Mn0.2Ru0.8]2O7 performs 50 h stable operation, significantly outperforming the commercial RuO2(CM) counterpart with less than 2 h life. Furthermore, the required overpotential to achieve 10 mA cm&#8208;2 is only 266 mV, accompanied with favorable reaction kinetics and catalyst utilization.</description>
      <author>Zhan Tian, Xin Yang, Hongrui Jia, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Guoqiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401419</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Aspects to Select Suitable Substrate for Anodic Oxidation Reactions (AORs)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00907j</link>
      <description>Baghendra Singh, Neetu Verma, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403189434

                Hybrid water electrolysis (HWE) stands out as a promising avenue for simultaneously producing high-value-added chemicals and clean H2 fuel. In HWE, instead of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) typical in...</description>
      <author>Baghendra Singh, Neetu Verma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00907j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Soft Molecular Single-Source Precursor Approach to Nanostructured Co9S8 (Pre)Catalyst for Efficient Water Oxidation and Biomass Valorization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05436a</link>
      <description>Basundhara Dasgupta, Suptish Ghosh, Carsten Walter, Markus Stefan Budde, Georg J. Marquardt, Hong Chen, Markus G. M. Breithaupt, Taner Y&#305;lmaz, Christoph Garmatter, Tansir Ahamad, Ingo Zebger, Matthias Drie&#223;, Prashanth W. Menezes, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403201437

                The molecular single-source precursor (SSP) route emerges as a promising avenue for synthesizing highly efficient electro(pre)catalysts tailored for both oxygen evolution (OER) and organic electrooxidation reactions. This study introduces a...</description>
      <author>Basundhara Dasgupta, Suptish Ghosh, Carsten Walter, Markus Stefan Budde, Georg J. Marquardt, Hong Chen, Markus G. M. Breithaupt, Taner Y&#305;lmaz, Christoph Garmatter, Tansir Ahamad, Ingo Zebger, Matthias Drie&#223;, Prashanth W. Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05436a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Construction of Face-to-Face Combination between NiFe-layered Double Hydroxide Nanosheets and Monolayer rGO for Efficient Water Splitting and Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10721</link>
      <description>Daoxin Liu, Yang Yang, Bing Xue, Dongxu Zhang, Fangfei Li, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403243018

                Developing cost-effective and efficient electrocatalysts is essential for advancing a green energy future. Herein, a NiFe-layered double hydroxide loaded on reduced graphene oxide (NiFe-LDHs@rGO) hybrid was synthesized using a straightforward three-step process involving exfoliation tearing, electrostatic self-assembly, and chemical reduction. The face-to-face packing and ultrathin exfoliation enable strong heterogeneous interactions, fully harnessing the potential of these complementary two-dimensional counterparts. Consequently, the resultant catalyst displays outstanding oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic activity and stability, whose overpotential is as low as 241 mV at 30 mA cm</description>
      <author>Daoxin Liu, Yang Yang, Bing Xue, Dongxu Zhang, Fangfei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing NiFe-Modified Graphite for Enhanced Catalytic Performance in Alkaline Water Electrolysis: Influence of Substrate Geometry and Catalyst Loading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29194755</link>
      <description>Mateusz Kuczy&#324;ski, Tomasz Miko&#322;ajczyk, Bogus&#322;aw Piero&#380;y&#324;ski, Jakub Karczewski, Molecules. 29(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403218313

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) are critical processes in water splitting, yet achieving efficient performance with minimal overpotential remains a significant challenge. Although NiFe-based catalysts are widely studied, their performance can be further enhanced by optimizing the interaction between the catalyst and the substrate. Here, we present a detailed investigation of NiFe-modified graphite electrodes, comparing the effects of compressed and expanded graphite substrates on catalytic performance. Our study reveals that substrate geometry plays a pivotal role in catalyst distribution and activity, with expanded graphite facilitating more effective electron transfer and active site utilization. Additionally, we observe that increasing the NiFe loading leads to only modest gains in performance, due to catalyst agglomeration at higher loadings. The optimized NiFe&#8211;graphite composites exhibit superior stability and catalytic activity, achieving lower overpotentials and higher current densities, making them promising candidates for sustainable hydrogen production via alkaline electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Mateusz Kuczy&#324;ski, Tomasz Miko&#322;ajczyk, Bogus&#322;aw Piero&#380;y&#324;ski, Jakub Karczewski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29194755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Entropy Ag&#8208;Ru&#8208;based Electrocatalysts with Dual&#8208;Active&#8208;Center for Highly Stable Ultra&#8208;Low&#8208;Temperature Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415216</link>
      <description>Ziming Qiu, Xiaotian Guo, Shuai Cao, Meng Du, Qinchao Wang, Yecan Pi, Bo Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403165108

                The development of advanced bifunctional catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is significant for rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, a unique dual active center alloying strategy is proposed to achieve the efficient bifunctional oxygen catalysis, and the high entropy effect is further exploited to modulate the structure and performance of the catalysts. The MOF&#8208;assisted pyrolysis&#8208;replacement&#8208;alloying method was employed to construct the CoCuFeAgRu high&#8208;entropy alloy (HEA), which are uniformly anchored in porous nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanosheets. Notably, the obtained HEA catalyst exhibits excellent catalytic performance for both ORR and OER, and a peak power density of 136. 53 mW cm&#8208;2 and an energy density of 987.9 mAh gZn&#8208;1, surpassing the most of the previously reported bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts. Moreover, the assembled flexible rechargeable ZAB enables excellent performance even at the ultralow temperature of &#8208;40&#176;C, with an energy density of 601.6 mAh gZn&#8208;1 and remarkable cycling stability up to 1,650 hours. Combined experimental and theoretical calculation results reveal that the excellent bifunctional catalytic activity of the HEA catalyst originated from the synergistic effect of the Ag and Ru dual active centers, and the optimization of the electronic structure by alloying effect.</description>
      <author>Ziming Qiu, Xiaotian Guo, Shuai Cao, Meng Du, Qinchao Wang, Yecan Pi, Bo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All&#8208;in&#8208;One Polymer Gel Electrolyte towards High&#8208;Efficiency and Stable Fiber Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414772</link>
      <description>Zhe Yang, Pengzhou Li, Jiaxin Li, Chuanfa Li, Yanan Zhang, Taoyi Kong, Meng Liao, Tianbing Song, Jinyan Li, Peiyu Liu, Siwei Cao, Yonggang Wang, Peining Chen, Huisheng Peng, Bingjie Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403202689

                Fiber zinc&#8208;air batteries are explored as promising power systems for wearable and portable electronic devices due to their intrinsic safety and the use of ambient oxygen as cathode material. However, challenges such as limited zinc anode reversibility and sluggish cathode reaction kinetics result in poor cycling stability and low energy efficiency. To address these challenges, we design a polydopamine&#8208;based all&#8208;in&#8208;one gel electrolyte (PAGE) that simultaneously regulates the reversibility of zinc anodes and the kinetics of air cathodes through polydopamine interfacial and redox chemistry, respectively. The intrinsic catechol and carboxylate groups in PAGE regulate the transport and solvation structure of Zn2+, facilitating dendrite&#8208;free zinc deposition with a lamellar stacking morphology. Additionally, the oxidation of redox&#8208;active catechol groups in PAGE replaces the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction on the air cathode and reduces the energy barrier for charging, enabling fiber zinc&#8208;air batteries to achieve a significantly improved energy efficiency of 95% and a longer lifespan of 40 hours. Further integration into self&#8208;powered electronic textiles underscores its potential for next&#8208;generation wearable systems.</description>
      <author>Zhe Yang, Pengzhou Li, Jiaxin Li, Chuanfa Li, Yanan Zhang, Taoyi Kong, Meng Liao, Tianbing Song, Jinyan Li, Peiyu Liu, Siwei Cao, Yonggang Wang, Peining Chen, Huisheng Peng, Bingjie Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414772</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>All&#8208;in&#8208;One Polymer Gel Electrolyte towards High&#8208;Efficiency and Stable Fiber Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414772</link>
      <description>Zhe Yang, Pengzhou Li, Jiaxin Li, Chuanfa Li, Yanan Zhang, Taoyi Kong, Meng Liao, Tianbing Song, Jinyan Li, Peiyu Liu, Siwei Cao, Yonggang Wang, Peining Chen, Huisheng Peng, Bingjie Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403202690

                Fiber zinc&#8208;air batteries are explored as promising power systems for wearable and portable electronic devices due to their intrinsic safety and the use of ambient oxygen as cathode material. However, challenges such as limited zinc anode reversibility and sluggish cathode reaction kinetics result in poor cycling stability and low energy efficiency. To address these challenges, we design a polydopamine&#8208;based all&#8208;in&#8208;one gel electrolyte (PAGE) that simultaneously regulates the reversibility of zinc anodes and the kinetics of air cathodes through polydopamine interfacial and redox chemistry, respectively. The intrinsic catechol and carboxylate groups in PAGE regulate the transport and solvation structure of Zn2+, facilitating dendrite&#8208;free zinc deposition with a lamellar stacking morphology. Additionally, the oxidation of redox&#8208;active catechol groups in PAGE replaces the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction on the air cathode and reduces the energy barrier for charging, enabling fiber zinc&#8208;air batteries to achieve a significantly improved energy efficiency of 95% and a longer lifespan of 40 hours. Further integration into self&#8208;powered electronic textiles underscores its potential for next&#8208;generation wearable systems.</description>
      <author>Zhe Yang, Pengzhou Li, Jiaxin Li, Chuanfa Li, Yanan Zhang, Taoyi Kong, Meng Liao, Tianbing Song, Jinyan Li, Peiyu Liu, Siwei Cao, Yonggang Wang, Peining Chen, Huisheng Peng, Bingjie Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414772</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Vertical Graphene&#8208;Exsolved Perovskite to Boost Reaction Kinetics for Flexible Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202415351</link>
      <description>Juwei Du, Nan Zhang, Wenyu Zhang, Xiaojun Shi, Yansheng Gong, Rui Wang, Huanwen Wang, Jun Jin, Ling Zhao, Beibei He, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403214087

                Abstract Zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) hold significant promise for flexible electronics due to their high energy density and low cost. However, their practical application is hindered by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions (OER/ORR). This study highlights a novel design of vertical graphene arrays (VGs) anchored on PrBa 0.5 Sr 0.5 Co 1.8 Ru 0.2 O 5+&#948; (PBSCRu) perovskite nanofibers, fabricated via plasma&#8208;enhanced chemical vapor deposition. Notably, the VG growth induces the exsolution of Co nanoparticles from the PBSCRu perovskite, resulting in a unique PBSCRu&#8208;Co&#8208;VG heterostructure. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that constructing PBSCRu&#8208;Co&#8208;VG heterojunction regulates interfacial electronic redistribution, thereby lowering energy barriers for both OER and ORR. As a result, the PBSCRu@VG&#8208;5 electrocatalyst exhibits superior stability and higher peak power density in both liquid and flexible solid&#8208;state ZABs compared to the pristine PBSCRu electrocatalyst. This protocol advances the integration of synergetic perovskite/metal/graphene composites, offering considerable potential for next&#8208;generation energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Juwei Du, Nan Zhang, Wenyu Zhang, Xiaojun Shi, Yansheng Gong, Rui Wang, Huanwen Wang, Jun Jin, Ling Zhao, Beibei He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202415351</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renaissance of Chlorine Evolution Reaction: Emerging Theory and Catalytic Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417293</link>
      <description>Jinjong Kim, Muhammad Usama, Kai S. Exner, Sang Hoon Joo, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403191457

                Chlorine (Cl2) is one of the most important commodity chemicals that has found widespread utility in chemical industry. Most Cl2 is currently produced via the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) at the anode of chlor&#8211;alkali electrolyzers, for which precious group&#8208;metal&#8208;based mixed metal oxides (MMOs) have been used for more than half a century. However, MMOs suffer from the use of platinum&#8208;group metals, which are costly and scarce, and the selectivity issue arises from the parasitic oxygen evolution reaction. Over the last decade, the field of CER catalysis has seen dramatic advances in both the theory and discovery of new catalysts. Theoretical approaches have enabled a fundamental understanding of CER mechanisms and provided catalyst design principles. The exploration of new materials has led to the discovery of CER catalysts other than MMOs, including non&#8208;PGM&#8208;based oxides, atomically dispersed single&#8208;site catalysts, and organic molecules, with some of which following novel reaction pathways. This minireview provides an overview of the recent advances in CER electrocatalyst research and suggests future directions for this revitalized field.</description>
      <author>Jinjong Kim, Muhammad Usama, Kai S. Exner, Sang Hoon Joo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renaissance of Chlorine Evolution Reaction: Emerging Theory and Catalytic Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417293</link>
      <description>Jinjong Kim, Muhammad Usama, Kai S. Exner, Sang Hoon Joo, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403192334

                Chlorine (Cl2) is one of the most important commodity chemicals that has found widespread utility in chemical industry. Most Cl2 is currently produced via the chlorine evolution reaction (CER) at the anode of chlor&#8211;alkali electrolyzers, for which precious group&#8208;metal&#8208;based mixed metal oxides (MMOs) have been used for more than half a century. However, MMOs suffer from the use of platinum&#8208;group metals, which are costly and scarce, and the selectivity issue arises from the parasitic oxygen evolution reaction. Over the last decade, the field of CER catalysis has seen dramatic advances in both the theory and discovery of new catalysts. Theoretical approaches have enabled a fundamental understanding of CER mechanisms and provided catalyst design principles. The exploration of new materials has led to the discovery of CER catalysts other than MMOs, including non&#8208;PGM&#8208;based oxides, atomically dispersed single&#8208;site catalysts, and organic molecules, with some of which following novel reaction pathways. This minireview provides an overview of the recent advances in CER electrocatalyst research and suggests future directions for this revitalized field.</description>
      <author>Jinjong Kim, Muhammad Usama, Kai S. Exner, Sang Hoon Joo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Nanoarchitectures: CuO:Er&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Synergy for Enhanced Performance in Energy Storage and Generation Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7795</link>
      <description>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Tenzin Ingsel, Ram K. Gupta, Essam A. Al&#8208;Ammar, Ghulam Abbas Ashraf, Mahwash Mahar Gul, Applied Organometallic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403173993

                ABSTRACT In this study, we have synthesized facile Cu&#8208;based CuO:Er 2 O 3 nanoelectrode material for energy storage and generation. CuO:Er 2 O 3 nanomaterial was synthesized employing phyto&#8208;extract of Amaranthus viridis L. (AVL) as stabilizing and reducing agents. Spherical&#8208;shaped CuO:Er 2 O 3 nanomaterial was initially employed to study supercapacitor behavior. The specific capacitance of 82.25 F/g was found at 0.5 A/g by galvanostatic charge&#8211;discharge, whereas the value of 319 F/g was achieved at 2 mV/s by cyclic voltammetry (CV) measurements. Furthermore, CuO:Er 2 O 3 electrode was investigated for water splitting energy generation potential and revealed an overpotential value of 323 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), an overpotential value of 370 mV was found. The electrochemical impedance analysis revealed the faster flow of electrons and ions, suggesting great conductivity and lower resistance of the fabricated electrode. Thus, current electrochemical results are proposing CuO:Er 2 O 3 as an competent electrode for overall energy&#8208;generating as well as storage applications.</description>
      <author>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Tenzin Ingsel, Ram K. Gupta, Essam A. Al&#8208;Ammar, Ghulam Abbas Ashraf, Mahwash Mahar Gul</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe LDH/Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure with a Superhydrophilic/Superaerophobic Surface for Solar-Driven Electrolytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03664</link>
      <description>Daijie Deng, Qian Li, Sufen Lei, Wei Zhang, Henan Li, Li Xu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403298525

                The development of a bifunctional electrocatalyst with high efficiency, high stability, and low cost is of great significance in practical applications of electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, a self-supporting bifunctional electrocatalyst with a NiFe layered double hydroxide/Fe2O3/Ni3S2 heterostructure (NiFe LDH/Fe2O3/Ni3S2/IF) for hydrogen evolution and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) is synthesized by the self-corrosion of iron foam (IF) and hydrothermal strategies. The constructed NiFe LDH/Fe2O3/Ni3S2/IF hierarchical heterostructure was not only beneficial to expose active sites and promote charge/mass transfer but also generate a superhydrophilic/superaerophobic surface, thereby accelerating the reaction kinetics to improve the HER/OER activity. Therefore, NiFe LDH/Fe2O3/Ni3S2/IF exhibited superior overpotentials of 226.2 and 162.8 mV for the OER and HER at 100 mA cm&#8211;2, respectively. NiFe LDH/Fe2O3/Ni3S2/IF was employed as both the cathode and the anode to assemble a device for overall water splitting and displayed a voltage of 1.55 V at 10 mA cm&#8211;2. The overall water splitting device was coupled with a solar cell to simulate a solar-powered water splitting system, resulting in a superior solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency of 15.16%. This work can promote the development of clean energy sources such as solar hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Daijie Deng, Qian Li, Sufen Lei, Wei Zhang, Henan Li, Li Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Efficiency Photo&#8208;Assisted Large Current&#8208;Density Water Splitting with Mott&#8208;Schottky Heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415492</link>
      <description>Minming Jiang, Jiang Xu, Yujie Chen, Luqi Wang, Paul Munroe, Zonghan Xie, Shengjie Peng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403193807

                The development of bifunctional photogenerated carrier&#8208;assisted electrocatalytic (PCA&#8208;EC) electrodes that operate with stability at large current&#8208;density remains a significant challenge. Herein, we demonstrate a simple sputtering&#8208;deposition process to synthesize a novel MnWO4/FeCoNi Mott&#8208;Schottky heterojunction coating and deposit it on a pure Ti substrate to prepare high&#8208;performance PCA&#8208;EC electrodes, which exhibits enhanced light absorption range/intensity and rapidly separated photogenerated electron&#8208;hole pairs. This design allows photogenerated electrons to directly participate in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), while the strong oxidation of photogenerated holes significantly reduces the defect formation energy of active metals, thereby facilitating the rapid reconstruction of highly active Ni(FeCo)OOH/MnOOH species for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As expected, the as&#8208;prepared electrode demonstrates the overpotentials of 64 mV for the HER and 204 mV for the OER at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 under illumination. Benefiting from the stable interface with Fe/Co/Ni&#8208;O&#8208;Mn/W bonding units, the dual&#8208;electrode photoassisted electrolytic cell achieves long&#8208;term stability at current densities of 500 and 1000 mA cm&#8722;2. This work provides detailed insights into the enhancement mechanism of PCA&#8208;EC and contributes to the development of photo&#8208;assisted water splitting electrodes for large current&#8208;density applications.</description>
      <author>Minming Jiang, Jiang Xu, Yujie Chen, Luqi Wang, Paul Munroe, Zonghan Xie, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioinspired synthesis of &lt;scp&gt;ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;&lt;scp&gt;Zr&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Er&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;based mixed nanomaterial; characterization and analyzing its potential as an electrode material in energy&#8208;based devices and its electrocatalytic property</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jccs.202400187</link>
      <description>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Tenzin Ingsel, Ram K. Gupta, Dan Liu, S. Noor Mohammad, Mahwash Mahar Gul, Journal of the Chinese Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403213331

                Abstract The sustainable and ecofriendly synthesis of transition metal oxide&#8208;based nanomaterials has always been a matter of concern. In this study, a bioinspired synthesis route was adopted to synthesize ZrO 2 &#8208;Zr 3 Er 4 O 12 &#8208;based mixed nanomaterial using leaf extract of medicinal plant Amaranthus viridis as reducing and stabilizing agent in replacement of the obnoxious chemicals which are a great threat to the sustainable environment. The synthesized material revealed the spherical shaped morphology through scanning electron microscopy, whereas crystal size of 15.7 nm was observed through Xray&#8208;diffraction, and band gap value of 2.7 eV was acquired using Tauc plot. Newly synthesized ZrO 2 &#8208;Zr 3 Er 4 O 12 nanocomposite was then investigated for its role as electrocatalyst in a generation of energy through the hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. The ZrO 2 &#8208;Zr 3 Er 4 O 12 &#8208;based electrocatalyst showed better potential for hydrogen evolution reaction measurements with the overpotential value of 242 mV. Furthermore, the notable capacitance value of 495.6 F/g was obtained through cyclic voltammetry for energy storage studies. The cyclic stability was also analyzed using linear sweep voltammetry and results showed promising stability for 2000 cycles. Consequently, the green and economical synthesis route as well as promising electrochemical behavior of ZrO 2 &#8208;Zr 3 Er 4 O 12 &#8208;based electrode make it feasible choice for large scale application.</description>
      <author>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Tenzin Ingsel, Ram K. Gupta, Dan Liu, S. Noor Mohammad, Mahwash Mahar Gul</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jccs.202400187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvent-free Synthesis of Transition Metals Nanoparticles Decorated Foamy Flakes-like Nitrogen-doped Carbon as Bifunctional-catalyst for High-performance Rechargeable Zn-air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5614/j.eng.technol.sci.2024.56.5.10</link>
      <description>Pilar Bela Persada, Davin Adinata Tan, Rachendra Akmalia, Yuyun Irmawati, Afriyanti Sumboja, Journal of Engineering and Technological Sciences. 56(5)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4403218810

                Transition metal-nitrogen-carbon (M/NC) demonstrates a promising effective electrocatalyst for enhancing oxygen evolution/reduction reactions (OER/ORR). However, synthesizing these catalysts is often complex, time-consuming, and involves hazardous solvents while producing a low yield. This work introduces a versatile, eco-friendly, and straightforward solvent-free method to produce M/NC (M = Co, Ni, and Fe) catalysts in ~3 h using a glucose, urea, and metal nitrate hydrate mixture. The high-yield M/NC catalysts exhibit a porous architecture and uniform distribution of metal nanoparticles within a foaming flakes-like nitrogen-doped carbon matrix. The metal nanoparticles are wrapped with protective nitrogen-doped carbon layers, producing stable active sites. Possessing these unique properties, the obtained M/NC catalysts show high-performance and stable bifunctional OER/ORR. As the best result, Co/NC presents an OER/ORR potential difference (&#916;E) of 0.78 V and retains 96% and 89% of its OER and ORR performance after a 10 h stability test. In practical application, the Co/NC-based Zn-air battery depicts a high power density of 184 mW cm&#8722;2 and good rechargeability of up to 120 h, outperforming the battery with noble metal-based catalysts. This work sheds light on the versatile, eco-friendly, and scalable synthesis of M/NC catalysts while presenting a strategy to accelerate the generation of inexpensive and highly effective bifunctional OER/ORR catalysts.</description>
      <author>Pilar Bela Persada, Davin Adinata Tan, Rachendra Akmalia, Yuyun Irmawati, Afriyanti Sumboja</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5614/j.eng.technol.sci.2024.56.5.10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composites Based on Electrodeposited WO3 and TiO2 Nanoparticles for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17194914</link>
      <description>Ram&#363;nas Levinas, Elizabeth J. Podlaha, &#1053;. &#1062;&#1099;&#1085;&#1094;&#1072;&#1088;&#1091;, H. Cesiulis, Materials. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403217581

                Photoelectrochemically active WO3 films were fabricated by electrodeposition from an acidic (pH 2), hydrogen-peroxide-containing electrolyte at &#8722;0.5 V vs. SCE. WO3-TiO2 composites were then synthesized under the same conditions, but with 0.2 g/L of anatase TiO2 nanoparticles (&#8960; 36 nm), mechanically suspended in the solution by stirring. After synthesis, the films were annealed at 400 &#176;C. Structural characterization by XRD showed that the WO3 films exhibit the crystalline structure of a non-stoichiometric hydrate, whereas, in WO3-TiO2, the WO3 phase was monoclinic. The oxidation of tungsten, as revealed by XPS, was W6+ for both materials. Ti was found to exist mainly as Ti4+ in the composite, with a weak Ti3+ signal. The efficiency of the WO3 films and composites as an oxygen evolution reaction (OER) photo-electrocatalyst was examined. The composite would generate approximately three times larger steady-state photocurrents at 1.2 V vs. SCE in a neutral 0.5 M Na2SO4 electrolyte compared to WO3 alone. The surface recombination of photogenerated electron&#8211;hole pairs was characterized by intensity-modulated photocurrent spectroscopy (IMPS). Photogenerated charge transfer efficiencies were calculated from the spectra, and at 1.2 V vs. SCE, were 86.6% for WO3 and 62% for WO3-TiO2. Therefore, the composite films suffered from relatively more surface recombination but generated larger photocurrents, which resulted in overall improved photoactivity.</description>
      <author>Ram&#363;nas Levinas, Elizabeth J. Podlaha, &#1053;. &#1062;&#1099;&#1085;&#1094;&#1072;&#1088;&#1091;, H. Cesiulis</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17194914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Room-Temperature Synthesis of Phosphate-Intercalated NiFe Layered Double Hydroxides for High-Performance Alkaline Seawater Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03660</link>
      <description>Lin Ye, Zhipeng Chen, Xinyue Xu, Wei Ma, Kaicai Fan, Lingbo Zong, Lei Wang, Guanjun Chen, Xingwei Li, Tianrong Zhan, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403327950

                Quick and easy synthetic methods and highly efficient catalytic performance are equally important to anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts for alkaline seawater electrolysis. Herein, we report a facile one-step route to in situ growing PO43&#8211; intercalated NiFe layered double hydroxides (NiFe-LDH) on Ni foam (denoted as NiFe-P/NF) by a room-temperature immersion for several minutes. This ultrafast approach transforms the NF surface into a rough PO43&#8211; intercalated NiFe-LDH overlayer, which demonstrates outstanding OER performance in both alkaline simulated and natural seawaters owing to good hydrophilic interface and the electrostatic repulsion of PO43&#8211; against Cl&#8211; anions. Density functional theory calculations reveal that the intercalated PO43&#8211; can not only promote electron transfer but also prevent Cl&#8211; from entering the interlayer and simultaneously inhibit the migration of Cl&#8211; over the NiFe-LDH surface. In alkaline simulated and natural seawater electrolytes, NiFe-P/NF needs low overpotentials of 248 and 298 mV to achieve a current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2, respectively. NiFe-P/NF can stably run over 42 h in an alkaline high-salty electrolyte (1 M KOH + 2.5 M NaCl) at 250 mA cm&#8211;2, more than 70 times that of NiFe/NF (0.6 h), emphasizing the critical role of the intercalated PO43&#8211; anions on the excellent durability. This study offers a new strategy to modify commercial NF to prepare efficient and stable OER catalysts for seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Lin Ye, Zhipeng Chen, Xinyue Xu, Wei Ma, Kaicai Fan, Lingbo Zong, Lei Wang, Guanjun Chen, Xingwei Li, Tianrong Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The earliest phases of CNO enrichment in galaxies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451189</link>
      <description>M. Rossi, D. Romano, A. Mucciarelli, Edoardo Ceccarelli, D. Massari, G. Zamorani, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403294259

                The recent detection of super-solar carbon-to-oxygen and nitrogen-to-oxygen abundance ratios in a group of metal-poor galaxies at high redshift by the James Webb Space Telescope has sparked renewed interest in exploring the chemical evolution of carbon, nitrogen, and oxygen (the CNO elements) at early times and prompted fresh inquiries into their origins. The main goal of this paper is to shed light onto the early evolution of the main CNO isotopes in the Galaxy and in young distant systems, such as GN-z11 at $z = 10.6$ and GS-z12 at $z = 12.5$ To this aim, we incorporated a stochastic star formation component into a chemical evolution model calibrated with high-quality Milky Way (MW) data while focusing on the contribution of Population III (Pop III) stars to the early chemical enrichment. By comparing the model predictions with CNO abundance measurements from high-resolution spectroscopy of an homogeneous sample of Galactic halo stars, we first demonstrate that the scatter observed in the metallicity range $-4.5 Fe/H -1.5$ can be explained by pre-enrichment from Pop III stars that explode as supernovae (SNe) with different initial masses and energies. Then, by exploiting the chemical evolution model, we provide testable predictions for log(C/N), log(N/O), and log(C/O) versus log(O/H)+12 in MW-like galaxies observed at different cosmic epochs (redshifts). Finally, by calibrating the chemical evolution model to replicate the observed properties of GN-z11 and GS-z12 we provide an alternative interpretation of their high N/O and C/O abundance ratios demonstrating that an anomalously high N or C content can be reproduced through enrichment from faint Pop III SNe. Stochastic chemical enrichment from primordial stars explains both the observed scatter in CNO abundances in MW halo stars and the exceptionally high C/O and N/O ratios in some distant galaxies. These findings emphasize the critical role of Pop III stars in shaping early chemical evolution.</description>
      <author>M. Rossi, D. Romano, A. Mucciarelli, Edoardo Ceccarelli, D. Massari, G. Zamorani</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Inclusion Characteristics and Mechanical Properties of M2 High-Speed Steel Treated with a Vacuum Carbon Deoxidation Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14101146</link>
      <description>Yuheng Dai, Tinghui Man, Zhongliang Wang, Yu Liu, Yan-ping Bao, Xicheng Wei, Metals. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403217185

                The oxygen content of M2 high-speed steel has not been intentionally controlled in industrial production through secondary refinement in vacuum furnaces. However, a lower oxygen content has a significant effect on the cleanliness, toughness, and addition of rare-earth elements to M2 high-speed steel. The changes in total oxygen content controlled by vacuum carbon deoxidation (VCD) treatment and inclusion evolution were investigated in M2 high-speed steel to understand the effects of carbon on dissolved oxygen and oxides in the carbon&#8211;oxygen (C-O) reaction process. Furthermore, the microstructure and properties of M2 high-speed steel caused by vacuum insulation and the role of reducing oxygen content in rare-earth alloying were briefly demonstrated. The results showed that the [O%] decreased from 30 ppm to 3 ppm in a vacuum at holding times above 25 min through the C-O reaction, leading to an inclusion reduction of approximately 70%. In the case of [O%] = 3 ppm in M2 high-speed steel, the addition of rare-earth elements has a greater effect on the inclusion characteristics. Lowering the oxygen content of M2 high-speed steel improves cleanliness and plays a significant role in rare-earth alloying.</description>
      <author>Yuheng Dai, Tinghui Man, Zhongliang Wang, Yu Liu, Yan-ping Bao, Xicheng Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14101146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling high-temperature stability and growth dynamics of CVD-SiOC coatings across different deposition conditions and environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2053-1591/ad8411</link>
      <description>Weiguo Jing, Naeem ul Haq Tariq, Wenkang Hou, Tianying Xiong, Mingqiang Tang, Materials Research Express. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403175808

                Abstract In this study, we systematically investigated the high-temperature protection performance and evolution behavior of three different SiOC coatings (1050SiOC, 1100SiOC, 1150SiOC) under different atmospheres. The coatings were prepared by the organometallic chemical vapor deposition (CVD) method and characterized using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), grazing incidence X-ray diffraction (GIXRD), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) techniques. It was found that the composition and microstructure of SiOC coatings, environmental atmosphere, and heat treatment temperature can affect the thermal stability and high-temperature reaction mechanism of SiOC coatings. Further, it was revealed that the three SiOC coatings only exhibit the same high-temperature evolution behavior and reaction mechanism in an air environment while exhibiting different high-temperature evolution behavior and reaction mechanisms in both an inert atmosphere and a reduced air atmosphere. Among the coatings prepared, the 1050SiOC coating demonstrated the highest on-set oxidation temperature under identical oxygen content conditions. This characteristic may contribute to the coating&#8217;s excellent resistance to high-temperature oxidation.&amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Weiguo Jing, Naeem ul Haq Tariq, Wenkang Hou, Tianying Xiong, Mingqiang Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2053-1591/ad8411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molten Salt&#8208;Assisted Synthesis of Ferric Oxide/M&#8211;N&#8211;C Nanosheet Electrocatalysts for Efficient Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401278</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Lu, Weiming Gong, Jinpeng Chen, Peng Guo, Yingxian Zhang, Lan Zhang, Minglei Yan, Chun&#8208;Yi Wu, Mengmeng Sun, Gehong Su, Yan Wang, Yanying Wang, Jianshan Ye, Wenxin Zhu, Jianlong Wang, Hanbing Rao, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403215671

                Abstract Efficient, stable, and low&#8208;cost oxygen reduction catalysts are the key to the large&#8208;scale application of metal&#8211;air batteries. Herein, high&#8208;dispersive Fe 2 O 3 nanoparticles (NPs) with abundant oxygen vacancies uniformly are anchored on lignin&#8208;derived metal&#8211;nitrogen&#8211;carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) hierarchical porous nanosheets as efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts (Fe 2 O 3 /M&#8211;N&#8211;C, M&#9552;Cu, Mn, W, Mo) based on a general and economical KCl molten salt&#8208;assisted method. The combination of Fe with the highly electronegative O induces charge redistribution through the Fe&#8211;O&#8211;M structure, thereby reducing the adsorption energy of oxygen&#8208;containing substances. The coupling effect of Fe 2 O 3 NPs with M&#8211;N&#8211;C expedites the catalytic activity toward ORR by promoting proton generation on Fe 2 O 3 and transfer to M&#8211;N&#8211;C. Experimental and theoretical calculation further revealed the remarkable electronic structure evolution of the metal site during the ORR process, where the emission density and local magnetic moment of the metal atoms change continuously throughout their reaction. The unique layered porous structure and highly active M&#8211;N 4 sites resulted in the excellent ORR activity of Fe 2 O 3 /Cu&#8211;N&#8211;C with the onset potential of 0.977 V, which is superior to Pt/C. This study offers a feasible strategy for the preparation of non&#8208;noble metal catalysts and provides a new comprehension of the catalytic mechanism of M&#8211;N&#8211;C catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Lu, Weiming Gong, Jinpeng Chen, Peng Guo, Yingxian Zhang, Lan Zhang, Minglei Yan, Chun&#8208;Yi Wu, Mengmeng Sun, Gehong Su, Yan Wang, Yanying Wang, Jianshan Ye, Wenxin Zhu, Jianlong Wang, Hanbing Rao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observations of Extremely Metal-poor O Stars: Weak Winds and Constraints for Evolution Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad697e</link>
      <description>O. Grace Telford, John Chisholm, A. A. C. Sander, V. S. Ramachandran, Kristen B. W. McQuinn, Danielle A. Berg, The Astrophysical Journal. 974(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403198149

                Abstract Metal-poor massive stars drive the evolution of low-mass galaxies, both locally and at high redshift. However, quantifying the feedback they impart to their local surroundings remains uncertain because models of stellar evolution, mass loss, and ionizing spectra are unconstrained by observations below 20% solar metallicity ( Z &#8857; ). We present new Keck Cosmic Web Imager optical spectroscopy of three O-type stars in the nearby dwarf galaxies Leo P, Sextans A, and WLM, which have gas-phase oxygen abundances of 3%&#8211;14% Z &#8857; . To characterize their fundamental stellar properties and radiation-driven winds, we fit PoWR atmosphere models to the optical spectra simultaneously with Hubble Space Telescope far-ultraviolet (FUV) spectra and multiwavelength photometry. We find that all three stars have effective temperatures consistent with their spectral types and surface gravities typical of main-sequence dwarf stars. Yet, the combination of those inferred parameters and luminosity for the two lower- Z stars is not reproduced by stellar evolution models, even those that include rotation or binary interactions. The scenario of multiple-star systems is difficult to reconcile with all available data, suggesting that these observations pose a challenge to current evolution models. We highlight the importance of validating the relationship between stellar mass, temperature, and luminosity at very low Z for accurate estimates of ionizing photon production and spectral hardness. Finally, all three stars&#8217; FUV wind profiles reveal low mass-loss rates and terminal wind velocities in tension with expectations from widely adopted radiation-driven wind models. These results provide empirical benchmarks for future development of mass-loss and evolution models for metal-poor stellar populations.</description>
      <author>O. Grace Telford, John Chisholm, A. A. C. Sander, V. S. Ramachandran, Kristen B. W. McQuinn, Danielle A. Berg</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad697e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure Evolution Analysis of Ni/YSZ Cermet Electrode using Cross-Sectional Model Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad83f6</link>
      <description>Nanako Bisaka, Takashi Sato, Riyan Achmad Budiman, M. Yamaguchi, &#8234;Tatsuya Kawada, Keiji Yashiro, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403175959

                Abstract Degradation of solid oxide cells can be partially attributed to the microstructural changes in Ni/YSZ fuel electrodes owing to Ni migration. This study aims to evaluate the microstructural evolution of Ni/YSZ fuel electrodes as a function of the oxygen potential along the thickness direction. To this end, comb-shaped Ni-patterned electrodes were designed on the top layer of a YSZ thin film using two different systems: (a) a symmetrical Ni-patterned electrode and (b) an asymmetrical Ni&#8211;Pt electrode with a reference electrode. In the symmetrical electrode, one side of the Ni-patterned electrode operated at the fuel cell (FC) mode, exhibiting expansion that led to an increase in triple-phase boundary (TPB) length and a decrease in electrolyte width. Conversely, the Ni-patterned electrodes that operated in electrolysis (EC) mode showed a slight migration away from the electrolyte. Detailed microstructural changes in the EC mode were examined using the asymmetrical electrode, revealing a correlation between water vapor content and Ni morphology. The results suggest that the amount of water vapor adsorbed on the electrode surface causes the decrease of oxygen potential at TPB. This causes the decrease in the wettability that led to significant change of Ni microstructure across the electrode length.</description>
      <author>Nanako Bisaka, Takashi Sato, Riyan Achmad Budiman, M. Yamaguchi, &#8234;Tatsuya Kawada, Keiji Yashiro</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad83f6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Inhibition Phenomena in Cu&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Pt Oxidation by CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02218</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Shyam Bharatkumar Patel, J. Anibal Boscoboinik, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, Guangwen Zhou, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403183740

                This study investigates the oxidation behavior of Cu3Pt(100) in CO2 using a combination of ambient-pressure X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, mass spectroscopy, and density functional theory modeling. Our in situ measurements reveal the simultaneous oxidation and reduction of Cu2O due to the opposing effects of atomic oxygen and CO generated from dissociative CO2 adsorption, leading to a dynamic equilibrium state of simultaneously occurring redox reactions. Complementary atomistic calculations elucidate the inhibitory effects of subsurface Pt enrichment and the counteracting roles of CO2 and CO in surface oxidation and reduction. These results provide mechanistic insights into the dissociative pathway of CO2 molecules and dynamic evolution of surface composition and reactivity of Cu-based alloy catalysts in CO2-rich environments, with broader implications for tuning gas&#8211;surface reactions by manipulating gas reactants or solid surface composition.</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Shyam Bharatkumar Patel, J. Anibal Boscoboinik, Adrian Hunt, Iradwikanari Waluyo, Guangwen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extraembryonic Membranes and Placentation in the Mexican Snake &lt;i&gt;Conopsis lineata&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/jmor.21783</link>
      <description>Cecilia de Dios&#8208;Arcos, Maricela Villagr&#225;n&#8208;SantaCruz, Journal of Morphology. 285(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403315420

                Extraembryonic membranes provide protection, oxygen, water, and nutrients to developing embryos, and their study generates information on the origin of the terrestrial egg and the evolution of viviparity. In this research, the morphology of the extraembryonic membranes and the types of placentation in the viviparous snake Conopsis lineata are described through optical microscopy during early and late gestation. When embryos develop inside the uterus, they become surrounded by a thin eggshell membrane. In early gestation, during stages 16 and 18, the embryo is already surrounded by the amnion and the chorion, and in a small region by the chorioallantois, which is product of the contact between the chorion and the growing allantois. A trilaminar omphalopleure covers the yolk sac from the embryonic hemisphere to the level of the equator where the sinus terminalis is located, and from there a bilaminar omphalopleure extends into the abembryonic hemisphere. Thus, according to the relationship of these membranes with the uterine wall, the chorioplacenta, the choriovitelline placenta, and the chorioallantoic placenta are structured at the embryonic pole, while the omphaloplacenta is formed at the abembryonic pole. During late gestation (stages 35, 36, and 37), the uterus and allantois are highly vascularized. The allantois occupies most of the extraembryonic coelom and at the abembryonic pole, it contacts the omphaloplacenta and form the omphalallantoic placenta. This is the first description of all known placenta types in Squamata for a snake species member of the subfamily Colubrinae; where an eggshell membrane with 2.9 &#956;m in width present throughout development is also evident. The structure of extraembryonic membranes in C. lineata is similar to that of other oviparous and viviparous squamate species. The above indicates not only homology, but also that the functional characteristics have been maintained throughout the evolution of the reproductive type.</description>
      <author>Cecilia de Dios&#8208;Arcos, Maricela Villagr&#225;n&#8208;SantaCruz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/jmor.21783</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transformation Dynamics of Nanosized Bi Films into Semiconductor Films of Bismuth Oxide in the Cold Plasma Device</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pssb.202400364</link>
      <description>Emrah Ko&#231;, B. G. Salamov, T. G. Mammadov, Nelli N. Lebedeva, V. I. Orbukh, physica status solidi (b). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403204707

                This work proposes an original method that reveals the transformation dynamics of nanosized Bi films into semiconductor films of bismuth oxide (Bi 2 O 3 ) and the factors affecting the low&#8208;energy cold plasma on the electro&#8208;optical properties of Bi 2 O 3 . In the plasma microreactor with a photosensitive GaAs:Cr electrode, the transformed Bi films 400&#8211;1100 nm thick are analyzed by X&#8208;ray diffraction to determine the crystal structure of Bi 2 O 3 and by an electron probe microanalyzer to explore the evolution of the composition. The morphological properties of the Bi films exposed to electron&#8211;ion flow are examined by processing the scanning electron microscope images. It is found that as a result of the combined effect of photoactive illumination, charged particles, and active plasma components: 1) an absorption spectrum of a new substance is formed in the range &#955; = 330&#8211;1100 nm; 2) the optical width of the bandgap of the resulting substance is E g &#8776; 3 eV, which satisfactorily coincides with the width of the bandgap of Bi 2 O 3 ; and 3) to overcome the potential barrier and formation of semiconducting Bi 2 O 3 film energy is required, which is provided by the combined kinetic energy of electrons and negatively charged oxygen ions bombarding on the Bi film.</description>
      <author>Emrah Ko&#231;, B. G. Salamov, T. G. Mammadov, Nelli N. Lebedeva, V. I. Orbukh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pssb.202400364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas&#8211;Liquid&#8211;Solid Three-Phase Boundary in Scanning Electrochemical Cell Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmeasuresciau.4c00061</link>
      <description>C. Hyun Ryu, Depdeep Mandal, Hang Ren, ACS Measurement Science Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403297057

                The gas&#8211;liquid&#8211;solid interface plays a crucial role in various electrochemical energy conversion devices, including fuel cells and electrolyzers. Understanding the effect of gas transfer on the electrochemistry at this three-phase interface is a grand challenge. Scanning electrochemical cell microscopy (SECCM) is an emerging technique for mapping the heterogeneity in electrochemical activity; it also inherently features a three-phase boundary at the nanodroplet cell. Herein, we quantitatively analyze the role of the three-phase boundary in SECCM involving gas via finite element simulation. Oxygen reduction reaction is used as an example for reaction with a gas reactant, which shows that interfacial gas transfer can enhance the overall mass transport of reactant, allowing measuring current density of several A/cm2. The hydrogen evolution reaction is used as an example for reaction with a gas product, and fast interfacial gas transfer kinetics can significantly reduce the concentration of dissolved gas near the electrode. This helps to measure electrode kinetics at a high current density without the complication of gas bubble formation. The contribution of interfacial gas transfer can be understood by directly comparing its kinetics to the mass transfer coefficient from the solution. Our findings aid the quantitative application of SECCM in studying electrochemical reactions involving gases, establishing a basis for investigating electrochemistry at the three-phase boundary.</description>
      <author>C. Hyun Ryu, Depdeep Mandal, Hang Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmeasuresciau.4c00061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into Structure, Regulatable Photoluminescence of Stably Self and Codoped Phosphor Ba&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Y&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;B&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;15&lt;/sub&gt;: Dy/Eu for &lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;UV &lt;i&gt;w&lt;/i&gt;LEDs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/lpor.202400874</link>
      <description>Wang Chang, Li Yue, Wanyuan Li, Yifeng Lei, Man Xu, Wubin Dai, Laser &amp; Photonics Review. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403196243

                Abstract The exploitation of borate&#8208;based phosphors is garnered tremendous attention in w LEDs. Although previous research provided some insights into borates from the viewpoints of synthesis, structure, and defect evolutions, their photoluminescence (PL) with dopants is still insufficient for actual application, especially on aspects of efficiency/stability. Herein, to alleviate the above issues, a new type of lesser&#8208;known high symmetry Ba 3 Y 2 B 6 O 15 (BYB) codoped with Dy 3+ /Eu 3+ phosphors are synthesized via multistep solid&#8208;state reaction and possessed controllable PL based on n UV excitation, defect&#8208;induced (self&#8208;) PL, and energy transfer (ET) from Dy 3+ to Eu 3+ . The origin of blue self&#8208;PL is clarified based on oxygen&#8208;related defects and optimized via adjusting synthetic atmosphere (air/Ar) and (co)doping dopants to control the defect content. Thanks to dense connectivity, and highly symmetric structure with perfectly ordered octahedral sites of Y 3+ for accommodation of Dy/Eu and ET, &#8220;cool&#8221; white and red PL from Dy 3+ and Eu 3+ , respectively, show high PL efficiency with narrow full width at half the maximum (fwhm). The phosphor also exhibits excellent thermal stability because of high bandgap and low electron&#8208;phonon coupling. Finally, a high&#8208;quality phosphor&#8208;converted w LED (pc&#8208; w LED) device is assembled via remote &#8220;capping&#8221; packaging by adopting the BYB: Dy/Eu and a 350 nm n UV LED chip.</description>
      <author>Wang Chang, Li Yue, Wanyuan Li, Yifeng Lei, Man Xu, Wubin Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/lpor.202400874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ocean oxygenation and ecological restructuring caused by the late Paleozoic evolution of land plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1130/g52502.1</link>
      <description>Jack Stacey, Malcolm W. Wallace, Ashleigh v.S. Hood, Alice Shuster, Hilary Corlett, Chris Reed, Conor Moynihan, Geology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403205883

                The dramatic increase in ocean-atmosphere oxygen levels during the Devonian and Mississippian is increasingly linked to the diversification of land plants, yet the timing and extent of this event remain uncertain. This study uses the redox-sensitive rare earth element cerium (cerium anomaly&#8212;Ce/Ce*) to investigate ocean redox conditions during the deposition of globally distributed Paleozoic carbonate strata. Our Paleozoic Ce/Ce* record suggests that Cambrian, Ordovician, and Silurian oceans had relatively low O2 levels (mean Ce/Ce* = 0.86 &#177; 0.10, 0.91 &#177; 0.14, and 0.91 &#177; 0.10 [&#177;1&#963;], respectively). In contrast, short-lived ocean oxygenation events, possibly related to the diversification of small land plants, likely occurred throughout the Early and Middle Devonian (mean Ce/Ce* = 0.80 &#177; 0.07 and 0.58 &#177; 0.14, respectively). &#8220;Modern&#8221; Ce/Ce* values (&amp;lt;0.36) first occurred during the Late Devonian, suggesting that the main phase of Devonian and Mississippian oceanic oxygenation was related to the evolution of large vascular plants and the first forests. Despite this, the significant variability of Ce/Ce* values during this time suggests that shallow marine settings were susceptible to redox instability, possibly caused by upwelling of anoxic deep waters. This redox instability potentially provides evidence of a mechanism for contemporaneous mass extinction and metazoan reef collapse events. Development of strongly oxic conditions during the Late Devonian may have resulted in the demise of many Paleozoic-type organisms, facilitated the radiation of the modern evolutionary fauna, and established the modern oxygenated ocean-atmosphere system.</description>
      <author>Jack Stacey, Malcolm W. Wallace, Ashleigh v.S. Hood, Alice Shuster, Hilary Corlett, Chris Reed, Conor Moynihan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1130/g52502.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental investigation of the swirling steam jet condensation at low mass flux</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231525</link>
      <description>Hongchuan Cong, Peidong Han, Ziqi Zhou, Sun Zhong, Guang Xi, Physics of Fluids. 36(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403216499

                Swirling steam jet condensation holds significant applications in industrial processes such as nuclear safety and gas&#8211;liquid mixing in the oxygen transmission pipeline of the liquid rocket engine. However, due to its involvement with complex flow and phase-change heat transfer, the application and optimization of related condensation technologies still face challenges. Therefore, this paper aims to investigate the condensation characteristics of the swirling steam jet by numerous experiments. The steam mass flux is 15&#8211;45 kg/(m2&#183;s), and the water temperature ranges from 40 to 85 &#176;C. A novel X-type swirl pressure nozzle is selected to achieve the swirling flow of the steam jet. A comparative analysis is conducted on the interface behavior and evolution of condensation parameters of the non-swirling and swirling steam jets during condensation processes. Results show that the swirling jet condensation includes three flow patterns, namely, chugging regime, smooth grown bubble regime, and rough grown bubble regime. Compared with the non-swirling steam jet condensation, swirling steam jets exhibit a 10.36% increase in the smooth grown bubble regime region and a 14.63% decrease in the rough grown bubble regime. Swirling bubble morphology evolves steadily, and the surface is smoother and more rounded. Simultaneously, irregular deformation behaviors can also occur in the swirling bubble condensation process, such as spiral growth of jet bulge, neck torsion, and the corolla pattern. This deformation helps to increase the contact area and prolongs the bubble lifetime, allowing for more adequate heat transfer at the steam&#8211;water interface. The swirling motion of the steam jet will reduce the bubble collapse frequency. As the water temperature rises from 60 to 80 &#176;C, the bubble condensation rate and collapse frequency decrease. The bubble radius increases and the condensation time is extended. With the increasing steam mass flux, the collapse frequency gradually increases. The condensation rate and the bubble radius vary nonlinearly. At the higher steam mass flux, the swirling motion can effectively release the heat that accumulates inside the bubble after reaching the condensation equilibrium state.</description>
      <author>Hongchuan Cong, Peidong Han, Ziqi Zhou, Sun Zhong, Guang Xi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0231525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mycoplasma pneumoniae Mediastinal Lymphadenitis in Children: A Case Series and a Review of the Literature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1097/inf.0000000000004578</link>
      <description>Laura Martino, Maria Cristina Savastano, Rosa Morello, Ilaria Lazzareschi, Francesco Proli, Giulia Bersani, Marilena La Sorda, Piero Valentini, Danilo Buonsenso, The Pediatric Infectious Disease Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403299606

                To the Editors: Mycoplasma pneumoniae is a common cause of upper and lower respiratory tract infections in children. The most frequent clinical manifestations include pharyngotonsillitis, acute bronchitis and community-acquired pneumonia, which is usually mild and self-limited while it can be severe and complicated in patients with immunodeficiency and chronic cardiorespiratory diseases. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection accounts for 10%&#8211;40% of community-acquired pneumonia in children between 9 and 14 years old, and it is less frequent before 5 years of age.1,2 Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection can also be responsible for rare extrapulmonary manifestations.3,4 Macrolides (azithromycin, clarithromycin, erythromycin) are the recommended first-line treatment for moderate to severe Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in school-aged children.5,6 However, the efficacy and clinical benefit of antibiotic therapy for this kind of infection is controversial. In this article, we report the cases of 2 children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection detected through polymerase chain reaction on nasopharyngeal swab who were admitted to our emergency department for persistent fever and had radiologic evidence of parenchymal hypoventilation and severe mediastinal lymphadenitis suspicious of active pulmonary tuberculosis. In addition, we performed a review literature to better investigate the association between Mycoplasma pneumoniae and mediastinal lymphadenitis. CASE 1 A 12-year-old girl with no significant medical history was admitted to our emergency department for fever for 4 days and chest pain. She came back from Romania the month before the appearance of clinical manifestations, where she met her grandfather who was receiving antitubercular treatment. The patient had just completed a 3-day treatment with clarithromycin prescribed by her pediatrician without clinical benefit. She had not experienced increased work of breathing and her vital parameters were the following: temperature 37.7&#176;C, blood pressure, heart rate, respiratory rate and peripheral oxygen saturation were normal. The physical examination showed bilateral basal hypophonesis in the respiratory auscultation, with abolished vesicular murmur, no wheezing. Blood laboratory tests revealed a C-reactive protein of 173.5 mg/L [normal values (n.v.) 0.00&#8211;5.00 mg/L], white blood cells 15.400/mmc (n.v 4.5&#8211;13.000/mmc), neutrophils 11.110/mmc (n.v. 1.5&#8211;6.000/mmc), normal hepato-renal function. Chest radiograph (Fig. 1A) was required and it showed left pleural effusion associated with basal consensual parenchymal hypoventilation and a bit enlarged cardiac shape.FIGURE 1.: Radiologic findings in 2 patients. A: Chest radiograph showing left pleural effusion associated with basal consensual parenchymal hypoventilation; (B) chest CT scan revealing a ribbon-like area of parenchymal consolidation with air bronchogram. This formation is surrounded by several areas of slightly increased density of the pulmonary parenchyma, with ground-glass appearance, with multiple centrilobular micronodules some of which had a tree-in-bud aspect. In the right superior lobe, some calcified nodular formations are described, associated with calcified lymph nodes, compatible with the primary complex. Furthermore, there are several mediastinal lymphadenopathies. C: Chest radiograph showing a right hilar round-shaped parenchymal hypoventilation, surrounded by another medio-basal hypoventilation; (D) Chest CT scan revealing several bilateral areas of parenchymal consolidation, with irregular margins and a confluent appearance, and partially obstructed bronchi; several mediastinal lymphadenopathies, some of which characterized by internal necrosis. CT indicates computed tomography.The patient was started on amoxicillin and clavulanic acid endovenous treatment and was admitted to the pediatric ward. We performed a bedside lung ultrasound showing bilateral pleural effusion and several atelectasis, so the antibiotic treatment was shifted to ceftriaxone. Since we did not observe clinical benefit, we added vancomycin to the treatment. In addition, due to the provenience from a high-tuberculosis (TB) burden country, we performed Mantoux intradermal skin test which resulted positive. Quantiferon test and microbiologic diagnostic tests to find Mycobacterium tuberculosis on 3 samples of sputum were negative. A chest computed tomography (CT) scan (Fig. 1B) was required to better characterize the images revealed with lung ultrasound and it showed a ribbon-like area of parenchymal consolidation with air bronchogram. This formation was surrounded by several areas of slightly increased density of the pulmonary parenchyma, with ground-glass appearance, with multiple centrilobular micronodules some of which had a tree-in-bud aspect. In the right superior lobe, some calcified nodular formations were described, associated with calcified lymph nodes, compatible with the primary complex. Interestingly, the CT scan showed several reactive mediastinal lymphadenopathies. In suspicion of active pulmonary tuberculosis, specific first-line antitubercular treatment was started. Because of the persistence of fever 15 days after the admission and the negativity of microbiologic analysis made on sputum, a fibrobronchoscopy was performed to obtain bronchoalveolar lavage fluid and to do a needle aspiration of the subcarinal lymphadenopathies. Mycoplasma pneumoniae was found both on nasopharyngeal swab and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid. The patient underwent a new chest CT scan 3 weeks later showing a significant reduction of the areas of parenchymal consolidation, whereas the mediastinal lymphadenitis was not resolved at all. In consideration of negativity of microbiologic examinations, during a follow-up evaluation, the antitubercular treatment was interrupted. Long-term follow-up confirmed full recovery and no new diagnosis of TB. CASE 2 A 9-year-old boy with no significant medical history was referred to our emergency department for fever and productive cough for 10 days. He was originally from India and his father was diagnosed with TB 1 year earlier. He had completed a 7-day course of amoxicillin and clavulanic acid on the recommendation of his pediatrician and he was afebrile only 1 day at the end of the antibiotic therapy. On clinical evaluation, his vital parameters were the following: temperature 39.4&#176;C, heart rate 80 bpm, peripheral oxygen saturation 98%&#8211;99%, normal respiratory rate. Physical examination revealed right basal hypophonesis, with diffuse wheezing. Laboratory tests found an increased value of C-reactive protein (39.5 mg/L, n.v. 0.00&#8211;5.00 mg/L), normal white blood cell count (7.890/mmc, n.v 4.5&#8211;13.000/mmc) and neutrophils (6.050/mmc, n.v. 1.5&#8211;6.000/mmc), normal hepatorenal function. Chest radiograph (Fig. 1C) showed a right hilar round-shaped parenchymal hypoventilation, surrounded by another medio-basal hypoventilation compatible with a tubercular excavation. He was admitted to the pediatric ward and isolated according to the suspicion of active pulmonary tuberculosis. We performed Quantiferon test and microscopic, molecular and cultural diagnostic tests on 3 samples of sputum to detect Mycobacterium tuberculosis but all of them resulted negative. Bedside lung ultrasound showed 3 consolidated areas of parenchyma with air-arborized bronchograms and left basal pleural effusion. Chest CT scan (Fig. 1D) performed to better characterize the formations described by radiograph and ultrasound revealed several bilateral areas of parenchymal consolidation, with irregular margins and a confluent appearance, and partially obstructed bronchi. Furthermore, the images showed areas with ground-glass appearance and several centrilobular micronodules, some of which had a tree-in-bud aspect. Also, in this case, there were several mediastinal lymphadenopathies, some of which were characterized by internal necrosis. Because of the high suspicion of tuberculosis, we prescribed first-line antitubercular treatment, interrupted 6 days later for intolerance. To obtain a definitive diagnosis, we required microbiologic analysis also on bronchoalveolar lavage fluid, which excluded a mycobacterium tuberculosis infection so we interrupted antitubercular treatment. The main microbiologic finding was a nasopharyngeal swab positive for Mycoplasma pneumoniae. Since the general clinical conditions of the patient were improving and the fever disappeared 6 days after the admission, we did not prescribe a specific macrolide treatment and we repeated 1 month after the beginning of the clinical manifestations in outpatient setting a lung ultrasound which was normal. Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection in children can cause different and noncharacteristic clinical, laboratory and radiologic manifestations.7 It is often responsible for self-limited community-acquired pneumonia, but sometimes it is the pathogen of severe low respiratory tract inflammation causing atelectasis and massive lung infiltration. In this article, we reported the cases of 2 children who came to our attention for persistent fever and with evidence of basal ipophonesis on respiratory auscultation. In both cases, CT scan showed parenchymal hypoventilation, areas with ground-glass appearance and centrilobular micronodules, some of which with a tree-in-bud aspect, compatible with the suspicion of tuberculosis. Interestingly both had severe mediastinal lymph node swelling. In a retrospective audit, we acknowledge the excessive diagnostic procedures (including invasive ones like CT and bronchoalveolar lavage), due to lack of awareness of this possible Mycoplasma pneumoniae localization and the social risk factors for TB. Pediatric mediastinal lymphadenitis has been rarely reported in literature as a possible radiographic pattern of Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection. Lee et al8 analyzed the CT features of Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia in 11 pediatric patients and they described hilar and/or mediastinal lymphadenopathies in 9 of them. In a Chinese prospective study published in 2016,4 the authors made an analysis of the diagnostic value of CT scan images in Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia during the pediatric age. Among the 1280 children included in the study, 128 (corresponding to 10%) had hilar and/or mediastinal lymphadenitis. Hsieh et al9 described clinical and radiographic features in 39 children with Mycoplasma pneumoniae and they found lymphadenopathy in 5 children, corresponding to 13% of the population. The authors also looked for a relationship between lymphadenopathy, duration of hospitalization, C reactive protein level and patient age but they found no significative values. As van der Pijl et al10 suggested, Mycoplasma pneumoniae infection should be suspected also in adults with radiologic evidence of enlarged mediastinal lymph nodes. These cases highlight the importance of considering Mycoplasma pneumoniae as a possible exclusive cause of mediastinal lymphadenitis, particularly if no other active tuberculosis clues like weight loss or positive interferon gamma release assays are associated. These reports are particularly important nowadays considering the huge increase in postpandemic Mycoplasma pneumoniae infections that is being recorded worldwide.11 As we learned from our experience, in these cases, close follow-up may be more reasonable rather than performing invasive diagnostic procedures. Our literature review showed that many authors focused only on the diagnostic phase, however it should be interesting to examine the clinical and radiologic evolution of these patterns as in our case the patients healed without a specific treatment in few weeks, therefore adding to the available knowledge about possible outcomes of Mycoplasma pneumoniae&#8211;associated mediastinal lymphadenitis.</description>
      <author>Laura Martino, Maria Cristina Savastano, Rosa Morello, Ilaria Lazzareschi, Francesco Proli, Giulia Bersani, Marilena La Sorda, Piero Valentini, Danilo Buonsenso</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1097/inf.0000000000004578</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
