<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:41:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic water splitting: A review under the shade of metal-organic frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.12.225</link>
      <description>Rida Zahid, Muhammad Ramzan Abdul Karim, Muhammad Waqas Khan, Mohsin Ali Marwat, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 57(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390837323

                The topic of water electrolysis has garnered significant interest in modern years due to its potential as a crucial element in the advancement of renewable and environmentally friendly energy sources. The demand for the development of highly efficient catalysts that exhibit exceptional performance and possess multiple functionalities in the context of electrochemical water splitting is of utmost importance. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have garnered significant attention as a highly promising category of materials for facilitating electrochemical water decomposition. This is primarily due to their remarkable characteristics such as abundant porosities, expansive surface areas, and customizable structures. The objective of this article is to provide a thorough examination of the latest advancements in MOF-based electro-catalysts utilized in the process of water electrolysis. Herein, we will begin by providing an overview of the reaction mechanisms involved in hydrogen and oxygen evolution, followed by the discussion of the significant parameters that are used to evaluate the active response of electro-catalysts in these reactions and also the techniques which can be adopted to fabricate the MOF-based electrodes are discussed. The investigation of recent advancements in the structure and functionalities of various types of MOF-based electro-catalysts, including pristine MOFs, dual-metal MOFs, carbon based derivatives of MOFs, and MOF-composites, has been stated in a critical manner. Besides, other strategies to enhance the stability and catalytic performance of the MOFs without tuning the elements and mixing linkers are briefly discussed. Furthermore, we aim to comprehensively assess the key challenges that impede the successful commercialization of MOF-based electro-catalysts. This review presents significant perspectives for researchers and engineers who are engaged in the advancement of electro-catalysts with high activity and stability for water electrolysis as well as policymakers and investors who are keen on fostering the commercialization of sustainable green energy technologies can benefit from the information provided.</description>
      <author>Rida Zahid, Muhammad Ramzan Abdul Karim, Muhammad Waqas Khan, Mohsin Ali Marwat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.12.225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge Engineering in Black Phosphorene with Tunable Electronic Structures as Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4694215</link>
      <description>Huating Liu, Zongyu Huang, Hui Qiao, Xiang Qi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390837510

                Layered black phosphorus (BP) has unique electronic structure, which makes it an ideal candidate material for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Charge doping effectively improves the environmental stability and catalytic activity of BP by providing electron transfer channels and reducing the charge transfer barrier. Therefore, based on the method of first principles calculation, this paper theoretically discusses how the intrinsic charge doping without introducing impurities changes the electronic structure and improves the catalytic activity of BP. It is found that charge engineering can stimulate the hybridization between different P-p orbitals, effectively regulate and change the electronic structure and work function while maintaining the direct bandgap semiconductor characteristics of monolayer BP system. More importantly, in the catalytic process of OER, electrons and hole doping as free charges provide different donor and acceptor energy levels for the system depending on the doping concentration, and affect the adsorption capacity of monolayer BP to different reaction intermediates. When the doping concentration is 0.15 e/u.c, monolayer BP can achieves the optimal Gibbs free energy and overpotential, the rate-determining step of reaction free-energy diagram is downhill and exothermal, and carrier mobility is significantly increased. These results provide new opportunities and possibilities for designing charge-engineered BP catalysts with adjustable electronic structure and excellent OER activity.</description>
      <author>Huating Liu, Zongyu Huang, Hui Qiao, Xiang Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4694215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing zinc&#8211;air battery performance by constructing three-dimensional N-doped carbon coating multiple valence Co and MnO heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-023-6404-5</link>
      <description>Qi Liu, Panzhe Qiao, Miaomiao Tong, Ying Xie, Xinxin Zhang, Kuo Chiang Lin, Liang Zhang, Lei Wang, Hongtuo Fu, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390840108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Liu, Panzhe Qiao, Miaomiao Tong, Ying Xie, Xinxin Zhang, Kuo Chiang Lin, Liang Zhang, Lei Wang, Hongtuo Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-023-6404-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversion of magnetron-sputtered sacrificial intermediate layer into a stable FeCo-LDH catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-023-6385-4</link>
      <description>Zhiquan Lang, Guang&#8208;Ling Song, Xiaozhou Liao, Wenzhong Huang, Yaxian Zhu, Haipeng Wang, Dajiang Zheng, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390840173

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiquan Lang, Guang&#8208;Ling Song, Xiaozhou Liao, Wenzhong Huang, Yaxian Zhu, Haipeng Wang, Dajiang Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-023-6385-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-molybdenum bimetallic phosphide grown in situ on nickel foam as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for efficient water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05376-w</link>
      <description>Qiangqiang Wang, Yameng Song, Xiuzhen Liu, Haojun Liang, Shiqi Li, Shanshan Wang, Yan Sun, Yingjiu Zhang, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390841608

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiangqiang Wang, Yameng Song, Xiuzhen Liu, Haojun Liang, Shiqi Li, Shanshan Wang, Yan Sun, Yingjiu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05376-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Deficient Tungsten Oxide Inducing Electron and Proton Transfer: Activating Ruthenium Sites for Hydrogen Evolution in Wide pH and Alkaline Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.064</link>
      <description>Bowen Zhou, Hao Ding, Wei Jin, Yihe Zhang, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843450

                The design of electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) that perform effectively across a broad pH spectrum is paramount. The efficiency of hydrogen evolution at ruthenium (Ru) active sites, often hindered by the kinetics of water dissociation in alkaline or neutral conditions, requires further enhancement. Metal oxides, due to superior electron dynamics facilitated by oxygen vacancies (OVS) and shifts in the Fermi level, surpass carbon-based materials. In particular, tungsten oxide (WO3) promotes the directed migration of electrons and protons which significantly activates the Ru sites. Ru/WO3-OV is prepared through a simple hydrothermal and low-temperature annealing process. The prepared catalyst achieves 10 mA cm-2 at overpotentials of 23 mV (1 M KOH), 36 mV (0.5 M H2SO4), 62 mV (1 M PBS), and 38 mV (1 M KOH + seawater). At an overpotential corresponding to 10 mA cm-2 in 1 M KOH and 1 M KOH + seawater, the mass activity of Ru/WO3-OV is about 7.7 and 7.86 times that of 20 wt% Pt/C. The improvement in activity and stability arises from electronic modifications attributed to metal-support interaction. This work offers novel insights for modulating the HER activity of Ru sites across a wide pH range.</description>
      <author>Bowen Zhou, Hao Ding, Wei Jin, Yihe Zhang, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The strategies to improve TMDs represented by MoS2 electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109515</link>
      <description>Junan Pan, Xin-Yi Liu, Hangjie Ji, Yi Zhu, Yanling Zhuang, Kang Chen, Ning Sun, Yongqi Liu, Yongquan Lei, Kun Wang, Bowen Zang, Longlu Wang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843576

                The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are the two half reactions that make up the over water splitting reaction. Increasing oxygen evolution reaction rate wound immensely raise the efficiency of over water splitting reaction because it is the rate limiting reaction in water splitting reaction. The key to improve OER performance is the development and utilization of advanced catalysts. As one of the most potential catalysts for HER, it has gradually attracted the attention of researchers in the aspect of catalytic OER. It is very necessary to review the research progress of Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) in catalytic OER to promote the research process in the field. In this review, we comprehensively and systematically summarized the strategies to improve TMDs electrocatalytic OER. First of all, structural regulation of TMDs-based electrocatalyst was summarized in detail, mainly including size engineering, defect engineering, doping engineering, phase engineering and heterojunction engineering. Once more, magnetic field regulation as a representative of external field regulation to improve TMDs electrocatalytic OER performance was discussed in depth. Last but not least, the strategies to improve TMDs electrocatalytic OER is prospected and some views on the development of this field are also put forward, which are expected to enhance the catalytic efficiency of TMDs for OER.</description>
      <author>Junan Pan, Xin-Yi Liu, Hangjie Ji, Yi Zhu, Yanling Zhuang, Kang Chen, Ning Sun, Yongqi Liu, Yongquan Lei, Kun Wang, Bowen Zang, Longlu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow CoVOx/Ag nanoprism with tailored electronic structure for high efficiency oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.073</link>
      <description>Siru Chen, Yingying Yao, Jing Xu, Junyan Chen, Zhuo Wang, Pengyu Li, Yanqiang Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843673

                Developing high-active and inexpensive electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is very important in the field of water splitting. The catalytic performance of electrocatalysts can be significantly improved by optimizing the electronic structure and designing suitable nanostructure. In this work, we represent the synthesis of hollow CoVOx/Ag-5 for OER. Due to the interaction of CoVOx and Ag nanoparticles, the electronic structure is optimized to improve the intrinsic catalytic activity. Additionally, the extrinsic catalytic activity of CoVOx/Ag is enhanced by the abundant active sites from the hollow structure. As a result, the CoVOx/Ag-5 demonstrates significantly enhanced OER catalytic activity with a low overpotential of 247 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. In addition, it also exhibits excellent durability, without obvious attenuation in performance after continuous operation for 60 h. Furthermore, the catalyst can enable full water splitting with appropriate 100 % Faraday efficiency, demonstrating its practical application.</description>
      <author>Siru Chen, Yingying Yao, Jing Xu, Junyan Chen, Zhuo Wang, Pengyu Li, Yanqiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancies enhanced electrocatalytic water splitting of P-FeMoO4 initiated via phosphorus doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.067</link>
      <description>Weilu Zhang, Qingcui Liu, Wenhua Cheng, Wei Wang, Juan Ding, Yudai Huang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843684

                Transition metal oxides (TMOs) are abundant and cost-effective materials. However, poor conductivity and low intrinsic activity limit their application in electrolyzed water catalysts. Herein, we prepared P-FeMoO4 in situ on nickel foam (P-FMO@NF) by phosphorylation-modified FeMoO4 to optimize its electrocatalytic properties. Interestingly, phosphorus doping is accompanied by the generation of oxygen vacancies and surface phosphates. Oxygen vacancies accelerated Mo dissolution during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), leading to the rapid reconfiguration of P-FMO@NF to FeOOH and regulating the electronic structure of P-FMO@NF. The formation of phosphates is caused by the substitution of some molybdates with phosphates, which further increases the amount of oxygen vacancies. Hence, the OER overpotential of P-FMO@NF at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 is only 206 mV, and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) overpotential is 154 mV. It was assembled into a water splitting cell with a voltage of just 1.59 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and shows excellent stability over 50 h. These excellent electrocatalytic properties are mainly attributed to the oxygen vacancies, which improve the interfacial charge transfer properties of the catalysts. This study provides new insights into phosphorus doping and offers a new perspective on the design of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Weilu Zhang, Qingcui Liu, Wenhua Cheng, Wei Wang, Juan Ding, Yudai Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polypyrrole-wrapped Hofmann type metal&#8211;organic framework nanoflowers to boost oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.124559</link>
      <description>Yuhang Wu, Yuwen Li, Ling Shen, Quanwen Pan, Ye Tao, Junkuo Gao, Journal of Solid State Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843720

                The exploration of efficient and stable metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has received increasing attention. However, the limited electronic conductivity of MOFs hinders the electron transfer rate. Herein, we report the preparation of conducting polypyrrole (PPy)-modified MOF nanoflowers (MOF-NFs@PPy) as promising electrocatalysts for OER. The PPy layer significantly increases the electrical conductivity and modulates the ionic transmittance between MOF-NFs and the electrolyte. The interaction of PPy with the MOF-NFs modifies the electronic structure and improves the reaction efficiency at the active sites. The obtained MOF-NFs@PPy exhibits excellent electrocatalytic activity with an OER overpotential of only 218 mV@10 mA cm&#8722;2 and small Tafel slope of 47.4 mV dec&#8722;1. In addition, the MOF-NFs@PPy exhibited excellent long-term stability (&gt;24 h). This work may provide a new idea and a novel construction strategy for MOFs to improve OER performance.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Wu, Yuwen Li, Ling Shen, Quanwen Pan, Ye Tao, Junkuo Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.124559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Role of Catalytically Active MXene Supports in Enhancing the Performance and Durability of Cobalt Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123731</link>
      <description>Young Sang Park, Ari Chae, Gwan Hyun Choi, Swetarekha Ram, Seung&#8208;Cheol Lee, Satadeep Bhattacharjee, Jiyoon Jung, Hyo Sang Jeon, Cheol&#8208;Hee Ahn, Seung Sang Hwang, Dong&#8208;Yeun Koh, Insik In, Taegon Oh, Seon Joon Kim, Chong Min Koo, Albert S. Lee, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843834

                The role of 2D transition metal carbides, also known as MXenes, as active catalyst supports in Co-based oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts was elucidated through a combination of experimental and computation electrochemistry. Through facile seeding of commericial Co nanoparticles on three different MXene supports (Ti3C2Tx, Mo2Ti2C3Tx, Mo2CTx), Co@MXene catalysts were prepared and their electrochemical properties examined for alkaline OER electrocatalysts. The OER activity enhancement of Co was significantly improved for Mo2CTx and Mo2Ti2C3Tx supports, but marginal on the Ti3C2Tx in rotating disk electrode and membrane electrode assembly tests. The Co@Mo2CTx exhibited the highest anion exchange water electrolysis performance of 2.11 A cm-2 at 1.8 V with over 700 hours of stable performance, exceeding previous benchmarks for non-platinum group (non-PGM) metal OER catalysts. The superior performance was attributed to the strong chemical interaction of Co nanoparticle with the Mo2CTx MXene support. Insights into the electrochemical and chemical oxidation according to MXene type as related to cell durability, as well the effect of electrical conductivity and inherent boosting of electrocatalytic activity of Mo-based MXenes elucidated through density functional theory (DFT) calculations helped explain the performance and durabilty enhancement of Mo-based MXene supports over Ti3C2Tx supports.</description>
      <author>Young Sang Park, Ari Chae, Gwan Hyun Choi, Swetarekha Ram, Seung&#8208;Cheol Lee, Satadeep Bhattacharjee, Jiyoon Jung, Hyo Sang Jeon, Cheol&#8208;Hee Ahn, Seung Sang Hwang, Dong&#8208;Yeun Koh, Insik In, Taegon Oh, Seon Joon Kim, Chong Min Koo, Albert S. Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123731</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anisotropic structural carbon skeleton decorated with Co nanoparticles towards oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133228</link>
      <description>Changshui Wang, Qian Zhang, B. Li, Zhenlu Liu, Cenlin He, Guangli Yang, Longjun Jiang, Chunmei Zhang, Kunming Liu, Shuijian He, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843849

                Hierarchical carbon skeletons derived from natural wood can be employed as the substrates to fabricate self-supported catalysts. The typically three sections (cross section, radial section, and tangential section) of wood would significantly affect the electrocatalytic performance. Therefore, the correlations between anisotropy structure of wood derived hierarchical carbon skeletons and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performances was systematically investigated. The cross-sectional wood-derived carbon decorated with Co nanoparticles requires an overpotential of 370 mV to deliver 50 mA cm-2 superior to those of radial-sectional and tangential-sectional counterparts. The cross-section of wood derived carbon skeleton possesses higher content of Co nanoparticles, which is accounted for the enhanced OER catalytic activity. This work highlights the critical contribution of anisotropy of carbon skeletons in promoting the OER properties and provides a new paradigm for designing advanced electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Changshui Wang, Qian Zhang, B. Li, Zhenlu Liu, Cenlin He, Guangli Yang, Longjun Jiang, Chunmei Zhang, Kunming Liu, Shuijian He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Zr in promoted activity of urea oxidation reaction and oxygen evolution reaction for NiFe layered double hydroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.018</link>
      <description>Jingting He, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 57(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390848411

                Electrolysis of water and splitting of urea to produce hydrogen are identified as one of the most attractive approach to reduce environmental pollution. However, this approach is both promising and challenging. In the paper, the NiFeZr LDH material was in situ grown on Ni foam through a one-step hydrothermal process. The electrochemistry activity of the NiFeZr LDH electrode was investigated by two probe reactions, one for the oxidation of urea and the other for the oxidation of water. It is worth mentioning that whether it is the oxidation reaction of urea (potential of 1.42 V @ 10 mA cm&#8722;2) or water (overpotential of 350 mV @ 10 mA cm&#8722;2), the doping of Zr improves the catalytic activity of the material. What is worth mentioning that the oxidation of urea does significantly decrease energy consumption compared to the oxidation of water. However, experiments show that the catalytic active sites are different in the two reactions. We speculate that iron is the active site for the oxidation of water, while zirconium is the active site for the oxidation of urea. Experiments demonstrate that the promoted performance is assigned to the exposure of the centre site, the rapid charge transfer rate and the improved electron configuration. Density functional theory analysis indicates that this NiFeZr LDH electrode presents optimal adsorption energy for urea, which improves the catalytic activity of the material.</description>
      <author>Jingting He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogel derived N, P co-doped porous defective carbon framework anchored with Co2P nanoparticles as robust electrocatalysts for Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.110440</link>
      <description>Feiyun Jia, Wenjing Huan, Ping Zhu, Xinsheng Zhao, Sa Liu, Journal of Energy Storage. 81(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390848586

                Recently, it is critical but a challenge to exploit economical, high active and stable bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for advanced rechargeable Zn-air batteries (ZABs). Herein, a robust ORR/OER electrocatalyst (Co2P/H-NPC) was prepared using Co2P nanoparticles (NPs) anchored on a N,P-doped three-dimensional (3D) hierarchically porous carbon framework with rich defects through carbonizing a hydrogel, involving starch, polyinosinic acid, cobalt(II) acetate and NH4Cl. Co2P NPs and the dual doping of heteroatoms (N and P), as well as the hierarchically porous feature, synergistically endow Co2P/H-NPC with an excellent ORR and OER activities, in terms of positive half-wave potential (0.83 V) and low overpotential (390 mV) at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. Additionally, the assembled ZAB based on Co2P/H-NPC delivers a peak power density of 120 mW cm&#8722;2, and a wonderful discharge-charge cycling stability, indicating good potential for further application in the fields of energy storage and conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Feiyun Jia, Wenjing Huan, Ping Zhu, Xinsheng Zhao, Sa Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.110440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anodic leaching plus chronopotentiometric aging of Ni2Fe ingot for sustainable oxygen evolution and urea oxidation reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.067</link>
      <description>Lin L&#252;, Luyao Wang, Peiyuan Li, Siqian Zhang, Haoyu Zhang, Ge Zhou, Lijia Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 57(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390848610

                A Ni&#8211;Fe binary alloy ingot, prepared by conventional vacuum smelting, was adopted as substrate in this work to fabricate the anode for water splitting. To improve the surface roughness of anode surface, the electrode was firstly subjected to anodic leaching in a simple KSCN solution. The as-leached electrode was subsequently activated through linear sweep voltammetry in 1 M KOH solution with or without 0.33 M urea addition to finish the final step for electrode preparation. The as-prepared anode delivers the 10 mA cm&#8722;2 current density at an overpotential of 284 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and at 1.361 V (RHE) for urea oxidation reaction (UOR), respectively. No apparent change of OER and UOR performance was observed after chronopotentiometric aging. The more complex UOR behavior was analyzed to elucidate the synergy among all constituents functioning through direct or indirect mechanisms for the half-reaction on this binder-free, self-supporting and substrate-rejuvenating anode.</description>
      <author>Lin L&#252;, Luyao Wang, Peiyuan Li, Siqian Zhang, Haoyu Zhang, Ge Zhou, Lijia Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.01.067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered oxidation states in NiCo2O4@CeO2 nanourchin architectures with abundant oxygen vacancies for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148787</link>
      <description>Shiyu Xu, Peng Zhang, Ruiqing Zhao, Jong Wook Bae, Hao Li, Jin Yong Lee, Pil J. Yoo, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390849521

                Sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) as the half reaction of water electrolysis hindered the production of clean hydrogen, necessitates a cost-effective electrocatalyst. Spinel nickel cobaltite (NiCo2O4), characterized by its lower cost, flexibility in oxidation states of cations, and stable spinel structure, holds promise as an OER electrocatalyst. However, there is still room for improvement in terms of its intrinsic electrochemical activity, conductivity, and active surface area. Inspired by the flexible valence states of Ni and Co, in this study, CeO2 was introduced into NiCo2O4 for further electronic structure adjustment. The result was the synthesis of an urchin-like NiCo2O4@CeO2 (NCOC), and the elucidation of its formation mechanisms, expressed conclusively through reaction formulas. NCOC, characterized by an open architecture and a rough surface, ensures rapid mass transportation and charge diffusion. Within NCOC, numerous oxophilic Ce3+ sites with oxygen vacancies construct electron transport pathways, accelerating charge-transfer. This simultaneously induces an increase in the oxidation states and proportions of Ni3+ and Co3+ in NCOC, reinforcing the covalence of Ni&#8211;O and Co&#8211;O bonds, expediting the ad/desorption of intermediates during OER. The electronic structure variations of NCOC were further verified through density functional theory (DFT) analyses, revealing alterations in adsorption configurations of intermediates and a decrease in adsorption free energies for intermediates on NCOC during OER. In practical terms, NCOC demonstrated a low overpotential of 228 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 under 1 M KOH, maintaining long-term electrochemical stability for 100 h. Overall, this study provides a universal approach for designing highly cost-efficient electrocatalysts for OER.</description>
      <author>Shiyu Xu, Peng Zhang, Ruiqing Zhao, Jong Wook Bae, Hao Li, Jin Yong Lee, Pil J. Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-temperature oxidation behavior of a 9Cr oxide dispersion strengthened alloy under limited oxygen condition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173544</link>
      <description>Jianqiang Wang, Xiang Liu, Weifeng Liu, Bin Xu, Mingyue Sun, Dianzhong Li, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390849580

                Hot compression bonding is a promising process to fabricate large-scale oxide dispersion strengthened alloys. Inevitable interface oxidation could affect the effectiveness of the joint. The high-temperature oxidation behavior of a 9Cr ODS alloy under limited oxygen condition was investigated. The oxidized surface consisted of inner Fe2O3 scale and outer Cr2O3 particles at 800 oC. Reoxidation at 1000 oC, Cr2O3 particles were decomposed and converted into Cr(Ti)O2. With increasing oxidation time, Fe2O3 and Cr(Ti)O2 were decomposed and Y2O3 pegs formed. Furthermore, TiO2, Y2O3 and Y-Ti-O nanoparticles formed along grain boundaries. In conclusion, the oxide evolution could be summarized as Fe2O3&#8594;Cr2O3&#8594;Cr(Ti)O2&#8594;TiO2&#8594;Y2O3&#8594;Y-Ti-O nanoparticles. The evolution from initial coarse Cr-rich and Fe-rich oxides to fine Y-Ti-O nanoparticles is expected to be critical for hot compression bonding processes.</description>
      <author>Jianqiang Wang, Xiang Liu, Weifeng Liu, Bin Xu, Mingyue Sun, Dianzhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile and scalable synthesis of Ni3S2/Fe3O4 nanoblocks as an efficient and stable electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.072</link>
      <description>Jing Mei, Yu Deng, Xiaohong Cheng, Qi Wu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390858579

                This study employed a one-step hydrothermal process to synthesize Ni3S2/Fe3O4 nanoblocks in situ on nickel foam (NF). The resulting Ni3S2/Fe3O4/NF catalyst demonstrates exceptional electrocatalytic activity for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and robust long-term stability. It achieves a low overpotential of only 220 mV for a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 with a Tafel slope of 54.1 mV dec&#8722;1 and remains stable in 1.0 M KOH for 66 h. The binder-free self-supported three-dimensional nanoblocks enhance the reaction region and long-term stability. Electronic interactions between Fe3O4 and Ni3S2, coupled with heterogeneous interfaces, optimize the electronic structure, fostering the formation of highly reactive species. Density-functional theory (DFT) calculations confirm that Ni3S2/Fe3O4, with a heterogeneous interfacial structure, modulates the chemisorption of reaction intermediates on the catalyst surface, optimizing the Gibbs free energies (&#916;G) of oxygen-containing intermediates. The synergistic effect between the two active materials within the heterogeneous structure enhances OER catalytic performance. This finding offers a valuable approach to designing efficient and stable OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jing Mei, Yu Deng, Xiaohong Cheng, Qi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on cationic vacancy engineering application of oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalyst in seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111946</link>
      <description>Hong Liang, Bo Li, Chenchen Jing, Zihan Zhuang, Yuji Zhang, Huajie Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390858649

                Seawater oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a kind of feasible method to solve energy problems. Through studying seawater OER, it can not only reduce the dependence on traditional energy sources, but also protect the environment and reducing pollution. Cationic defect engineering can effectively enhance the properties of seawater OER. This way can make more catalysts active sites exposed and simultaneously change the electronic properties of materials to improve the conductivity of materials. Meanwhile, defects lead to electron delocalization, promote carrier migration and increase the charge transfer rate of materials. Cationic vacancy defects can effectively improve the OER properties of materials. Therefore, studying relationship between structure and function of vacancy defect electrocatalysts is beneficial to improve the seawater OER performance better. The transition metal-based vacancy catalyst has good seawater OER performance, for example, Fe, Co and Ni based vacancy catalysts. The influence of cationic vacancy on the improvement of OER performance in seawater was further expounded by the DFT of analysis of cationic vacancy catalyst. With the continuous progress of technology, the cost of seawater electrolysis technology will be gradually reduced, which can greatly promote the development of sustainable and renewable clean energy.</description>
      <author>Hong Liang, Bo Li, Chenchen Jing, Zihan Zhuang, Yuji Zhang, Huajie Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Conversion of Nitrates to Ammonia: Fuel from Waste</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301570</link>
      <description>Prattakorn Metem, Esteban Toledo-Carrillo, Fei Ye, Joydeep Dutta, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390863806

                Ammonia (NH3) is globally one of the most produced chemicals. Despite being known for its use as a fuel and as a precursor of multiple chemicals, during its production, it is responsible for more than 1.2% of the total global CO2 emission and consumes a large amount of energy. In this work, we studied a flow&#8208;through membrane&#8208;free electrocatalytic device (CMED) to produce continuous stream of NH3 from a common water contaminant, nitrate (NO3&#8722;). Indium&#8208;palladium (In&#8208;Pd) nanoparticles were impregnated in activated carbon cloth (ACC) and used as a cathode in the electrochemical device. It is found that in the counter electrode, adding oxygen evolution reaction (OER) active catalysts like platinum (Pt) for the regeneration of hydrogen ions enhances the rate of ammonia conversion to 7.28 &#181;mol min&#8722;1 cm&#8722;2, eliminate the production of toxic nitrite by&#8208;products, as well as provide a platform for a stable energy consumption over long periods of time. This method for the conversion of NO3&#8722; into NH3 promises a way forward for sustainable resource utilization while generating fuel from waste and contributing to future circular economies, and managing the nitrogen cycle in water that is a major challenge of the 21st century society.</description>
      <author>Prattakorn Metem, Esteban Toledo-Carrillo, Fei Ye, Joydeep Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mil-101(Fe)-Derivatized Cathode as an Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zn-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4695712</link>
      <description>Long Hao, Rui Guo, Ting Yu, Chunming Liu, Jingbi You, Hangzhou Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390870941

                The exploration of multifunctional electrocatalysts with cost-effective and high kinetic activity for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for the development of advanced energy conversion and storage equipment. Herein, A novel hierarchical mesoporous/macropores MIL-101(Fe) derivative carbon catalyst material was prepared by a simple molten ZnCl2-assisted synthesis route. Specifically, 1H-benzotriazole (BTA) organic ligands were intentionally introduced as nitrogen sources in order to induce the formation of charge-rich regions through an electronegative nitrogen doping control strategy, and most importantly, the lone pair electron-rich nature of element N could facilitate the separation and anchoring of iron species enchanted the utilization rate of active sites. Because of these properties, the as-prepared catalyst (denoted as FeSACs/NxC) possesses unrivalled bifunction electrocatalytic activity and durability for the ORR and OER. The FeSACs/N1.25C as working electrode exhibits a quite satisfactory electrochemical performance for the ORR (half-wave potential of 0.82 V) and OER (a small overpotential of 302 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2) in the classic three-electrode configuration. Moreover, the FeSACs/N1.25C-based air cathode imparts encouraging performance in a rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery prototype with an open-circuit voltage of 1.45 V, a specific capacity of 792.16 mAh g&#8722;1, an energy density of 871.38 Wh kg&#8722;1, and excellent stability for 120 h. This work has opened the way for the development of low-cost, fast kinetic and stable non-noble metal multifunctional catalysts.</description>
      <author>Long Hao, Rui Guo, Ting Yu, Chunming Liu, Jingbi You, Hangzhou Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4695712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Surface Area Mesoporous Sc&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;o&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; with Abundant Oxygen Vacancies as New and Advanced Electrocatalyst for Electrochemical Biomass Valorization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202311698</link>
      <description>Yufeng Wu, Lei Ma, Jialing Wu, Maoyong Song, Changlong Wang, Jun L&#252;, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390871310

                Scandium oxide (Sc2 O3 ) is considered as omnipotent "Industrial Ajinomoto" and holds promise in catalytic applications. However, rarely little attention have been paid to its electrochemistry. Here, we reported the first nanocasting design of high-surface area Sc2 O3 with abundant oxygen vacancies (mesoporous VO -Sc2 O3 ) for efficient electrochemical biomass valorization. In the case of the electro-oxidation of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) to 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA), quantitative HMF conversion, high yield and high faradic efficiency of 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) via the hydroxymethylfurancarboxylic acid (HMFCA) pathway were achieved by this advanced electrocatalyst. The beneficial effect of the VO on the electrocatalytic performance of the mesoporous VO -Sc2 O3 was revealed by the enhanced adsorption of reactants and the reduced energy barrier in the electrochemical process. The concerted design, in-situ and ex-situ experimental studies and theoretical calculations shown in this work should shed light on the rational elaboration of advanced electrocatalysts, and contribute to the establishment of a circular carbon economy since the bio-plastic monomer and green hydrogen are efficiently synthesized. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Yufeng Wu, Lei Ma, Jialing Wu, Maoyong Song, Changlong Wang, Jun L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202311698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni2p-Nise2 Heterostructure Aerogel for Highly Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution and 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4695647</link>
      <description>Hongchen Liu, Fan Yang, Zhengyang Chen, Jialin Qian, Jianfeng Wang, Yongfeng Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390872314

                Green hydrogen prepared by the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) of renewable energy water electrolysis is one of the best choices for future energy. However, the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with high theoretical potential limits the efficiency of overall water splitting. Herein, a bifunctional Ni2P-NiSe2 heterostructure aerogel (Ni-P-Se aerogel) was constructed to boost HER and replace OER by 5-hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation reaction (HMFOR) to produce high-valued 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) with low operating voltage and high conversion. The NiSe2 with cubic pyrite-type crystal structure was favor for anodic reconstruction, which allowed the effective generation of activated oxygen species and further promoted HMFOR. Moreover, the coupling of Ni2P modulated the adsorption energy of OH- in HMFOR and enhanced the activity toward HER. Besides, the aerogel structure with porous network structure provides abundant active sites and mass-transfer pathways. Benefit from these advantages, the optimized Ni-P-Se aerogel exhibited high HER performance (68 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm-2), low onset oxidation potential (1.30 V) and high Faradaic efficiency (97.4%) and FDCA production rate (99.2 &#956;molFDCA&#183;h-1&#183;cm-2) of HMFOR. Compared to OER, the two-electrode system coupled with HMFOR had significantly increased current density at low operating voltage (87 mA&#183;cm-2 increase at 1.50 V), proving the superiority of HMFOR as alternative anodic reaction. This work offers an anticipated perspective of bifunctional electrocatalysts toward the combination of HER and organics oxidation.</description>
      <author>Hongchen Liu, Fan Yang, Zhengyang Chen, Jialin Qian, Jianfeng Wang, Yongfeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4695647</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategically Designed Pd-Induced Changes in Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performances of Electrochemical Water Oxidation by the Galvanically Synthesized MoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/MoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Composite Thin Film</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c16499</link>
      <description>Uday Kumar Ghorui, Bibhutibhushan Show, Dipayan Roy, Arindam Basak, Bibhutosh Adhikary, Anup Mondal, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390873823

                Electrochemical water oxidation is believed to be an effective pathway to produce clean, carbon-free, and environmentally sustainable green energy. In this work, we report a simple, easy-to-construct, facile, low-cost, and single-step galvanic technique to synthesize a Pd-supported temperature-assisted MoOx thin film nanocomposite for effective water oxidation. The most suitable nanocomposite exhibits very low overpotential at 10 mA/cm2 with smaller Tafel slope values for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) processes in an alkaline medium. The formation of a metal oxide-metal junction accelerates the growth of more active sites, promoting induced electronic synergism at the MoOx-Pd interface. This endows higher electrical conductivity and faster electron transfer kinetics, thus accelerating the faster water dissociation reaction following the Tafel-Volmer mechanism to boost the HER process in an alkaline medium. The excellent electrochemical HER and OER performances of our electrocatalyst even supersede the accomplishments of the benchmark catalysts Pt/C and RuO2. Moreover, neither of these two catalysts demonstrates both catalytic reactions, i.e., HER and OER at the same time, which have been observed for our synthesized catalyst. Our findings illustrate the potential of a thin-film MoOx-Pd nanocomposite to be an exceedingly effective electrocatalyst developed by interface engineering strategies. This also provides insight into designing several other semiconductor composite catalysts using simple synthesis techniques for highly efficient HER/OER processes that could be alternatives to benchmark electrocatalysts for water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Uday Kumar Ghorui, Bibhutibhushan Show, Dipayan Roy, Arindam Basak, Bibhutosh Adhikary, Anup Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c16499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microzone-Acidification-Driven Degradation Mechanism of the NiFe-Based Anode in Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c13929</link>
      <description>Mengyi Tang, Keming Du, Rui Yu, Hao Shi, Peilin Wang, Yifan Guo, Qinyi Wei, Huayi Yin, Dihua Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390882210

                The anode stability is critical for efficient and reliable seawater electrolyzers. Herein, a NiFe-based film catalyst was prepared by anodic oxidation to serve as a model electrode, which exhibited a satisfactory oxygen evolution performance in simulated alkaline seawater (1 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl) with an overpotential of 348 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 and a long-term stability of over 100 h. After that, the effects of the current density and bulk pH of the electrolyte on its stability were evaluated. It was found that the electrode stability was sensitive to electrolysis conditions, failing at 20 mA cm&#8211;2 in 0.1 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl but over 500 mA cm&#8211;2 in 0.5 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl. The electrode dissolved, and some precipitates immediately formed at the region very close to the electrode surface during the electrolysis. This can be ascribed to the pH difference between the electrode/electrolyte interface and the bulk electrolyte under anodic polarization. In other words, the microzone acidification accelerates the corrosion of the electrode by Cl&#8211;, thus affecting the electrode stability. The operational performances of the electrode under different electrolysis conditions were classified to further analyze the degradation behavior, which resulted in three regions corresponding to the stable oxygen evolution, violent dissolution&#8211;precipitation, and complete passivation processes, respectively. Thereby increasing the bulk pH could alleviate the microzone acidification and improve the stability of the anode at high current densities. Overall, this study provides new insights into understanding the degradation mechanism of NiFe-based catalysts and offers electrolyte engineering strategies for the application of anodes.</description>
      <author>Mengyi Tang, Keming Du, Rui Yu, Hao Shi, Peilin Wang, Yifan Guo, Qinyi Wei, Huayi Yin, Dihua Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c13929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing oxygen evolution electrocatalysis with human-machine intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100868</link>
      <description>Liping Liu, Siwen Wang, Chen Ling, Hongliang Xin, Chem Catalysis. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391043168

                In this article, Hongliang Xin (associate professor at Virginia Tech), Chen Ling (senior principal research scientist at Toyota), and their colleagues discuss the critical challenges in developing high-performance electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), particularly by emphasizing the role of artificial intelligence (AI) in materials exploration and discovery. They highlight the necessity of a collaborative human-machine intelligence approach to overcome the complexities of OER catalysis and accelerate the advancement of sustainable energy solutions.</description>
      <author>Liping Liu, Siwen Wang, Chen Ling, Hongliang Xin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights on MOF-derived metal&#8211;carbon nanostructures for oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt04263d</link>
      <description>Junliang Chen, Jinjie Qian, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391225155

                This article focuses on elucidating the fabrication and design of metal-organic framework derived metal-carbon nanostructures for oxygen evolution. It is categorized into three following topics: MOF selection, metal introduction and carbon structure.</description>
      <author>Junliang Chen, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt04263d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface reconstruction of La0.6Sr0.4Co0.8Ni0.2O3- perovskite nanofibers for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.01.211</link>
      <description>Yusong Niu, Xin Chang, Mingyi Zhang, Jingbo Mu, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390942237

                Perovskites have become promising alternatives to precious metal-catalyzed oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we report the synthesis of several perovskite nanofibers, specifically La0.6Sr0.4CoxNi1-xO3-&#948; (LSCN), and investigate their electrocatalytic water oxidation activity in alkaline electrolytes. La0.6Sr0.4Co0.8Ni0.2O3-&#948; (LSCN-0.8) is selected and immersed in an aqueous NaBH4 solution for 1 h for surface reconstruction. The perovskite nanofibers' electrocatalytic OER activity and stability are rigorously evaluated using a standard three-electrode system. Results reveal that even a slight Co substitution for Ni content within the LSCN perovskite structure has a notable impact on electrocatalytic activity. Moreover, LSCN-0.8 exhibits an overpotential of 363 mV at 20 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 M KOH. However, significant improvement is observed after the surface reconstruction process. The optimized LSCN-0.8 (now called LSCN-2) displays the lowest OER overpotential (320 mV) under the same conditions. Furthermore, the LSCN-2 nanostructure demonstrates exceptional electrode stability, as evidenced by only a slight decrease in electrocatalytic performance during 5000 cycles of linear sweep voltammetry.</description>
      <author>Yusong Niu, Xin Chang, Mingyi Zhang, Jingbo Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.01.211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced catalytic activity of ZnWO4 by nickel-doping in oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108151</link>
      <description>Meng Li, Deijun Xiong, Jinxing Wang, Xiaoyang Dong, Peiyang Zhang, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 173(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391197664

                The development of efficient and low-cost metal materials is indispensable in clean energy technology. Metal tungstates have previously been reported as catalysts for oxygen evolution reactions (OER). However, ZnWO4 alone does not exhibit significant catalytic activity for OER, it requires 330 mV to drive the reaction at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. To address this issue, a self-supporting electrode mixed with tungstate is synthesized by a hydrothermal method. Notably, the Ni-doped ZnWO4 self-supporting material demonstrates improved OER catalytic activity. Specifically, when comparing ZnWO4 to ZnNiWO4, it exhibits a reduced Tafel slope by 190 mV&#183;dec&#8722;1, resulting in an overpotential of only 110 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, with long-term stability for at least 20 h. Furthermore, the d-band center of ZnNiWO4 is modeled using Materials Studio and simulated through projected density of states (PDOS) calculations. These calculations reveal that the presence of Ni activates the metal ion as an OER active site with strong orbital overlap with the reaction intermediate. This adjustment in the electronic structure of the Ni&#8211;Zn metal active site during the oxygen evolution reaction alters the adsorption energy. Consequently, doping of Ni enhances the metal's ability to adsorb *OOH radical, shifting the d-band center of ZnNiWO4 further away from the Fermi level, and facilitates rapid oxygen release.</description>
      <author>Meng Li, Deijun Xiong, Jinxing Wang, Xiaoyang Dong, Peiyang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Promotion of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Programmable Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-gs6zn</link>
      <description>Sallye R. Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar Abdel&#8208;Rahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391172933

                Hydrogen gas is a promising renewable energy storage medium when produced via water electrolysis, but this process is limited by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we used a microkinetic model to investigate promoting the OER using programmable oxide catalysts (i.e., forced catalyst dynamics). We found that programmable catalysts could increase current density at a fixed overpotential (100X to 600X over static rates) or reduce the overpotential required to reach a fixed current density of 10 mA/cm^2 (45 &#8211; 140% reduction vs. static). In our kinetic parameterization, the key parameters controlling the quality of the catalytic ratchet were the O*-to-OOH* and O*-to-OH* activation barriers. Our findings indicate that programmable catalysts may be a viable strategy for accelerating the OER or enabling lower-overpotential operation, but a more accurate kinetic parameterization is required for precise predictions of performance, ratchet quality, and resulting energy efficiency.</description>
      <author>Sallye R. Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar Abdel&#8208;Rahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-gs6zn</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material Dynamics of Manganese-Based Oxychlorides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02362</link>
      <description>Ruihan Li, Dennis Nordlund, Linsey C. Seitz, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390918522

                Earth-abundant manganese-based oxides have emerged as promising alternatives to noble-metal-based catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic conditions; however, their inferior activity and stability present critical challenges for the sustainable production of hydrogen via water electrolysis. Moving beyond oxides, heteroanionic materials, which incorporate anions with lower electronegativity than oxygen, have shown potential for improving the OER performance, but a detailed understanding of the underlying mechanisms is lacking. Here, we investigate manganese-based oxychlorides (Mn8O10Cl3 and FeMn7O10Cl3) that exhibit excellent activity and stability for acidic OER to elucidate material property dynamics and correlate them with OER behaviors. Our rigorous electrochemical stability testing reveals that the high operating potential mitigates Mn dissolution over prolonged exposure to the OER conditions. Through a combination of ex situ and in situ surface and bulk-sensitive X-ray spectroscopy analyses, we observe a trade-off between increasing Mn valence and maintaining structural integrity, which results in dynamic bond length changes within the [MnCl6] octahedra during the activation and degradation processes of these oxychloride catalysts. This study provides insights into the fundamental relationships between the chemical, electronic, and geometric properties of the catalysts and their electrocatalytic outcomes.</description>
      <author>Ruihan Li, Dennis Nordlund, Linsey C. Seitz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of hexagonal Cu2O nanocrystals on CNTs for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2023.111853</link>
      <description>Salma Aman, Meznah M. Alanazi, Shaimaa A. M. Abdelmohsen, Saeed D. Alahmari, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Suleman Waheed, A.M.A. Henaish, Zubair Ahmad, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391179968

                Electrocatalytic water (H2O) splitting relies heavily on the rational formation of most effective, long-lasting catalysts that should be cheaper and earth abundant. Therefore, an effective electrocatalyst is the need of the hour that may effectively pursue both electrocatalytic OER and HER. This study paves the way for the straightforward preparation of conductive polymer tailored metal oxide nanocomposite Cu2O/CNTs by a facile hydrothermal approach to be employed as overall water splitting electrocatalyst. The techniques comprising SEM, XRD, EDX and the BET test were employed to characterize the synthesized Cu2O/CNTs electrocatalyst. The generated Cu2O/CNTs electrocatalysts exhibited a Tafel value of 39 mV/dec, an overpotential of 267 mV@10 mA/cm2, and stability of OER activity that lasted for at least 70 hours. The electrocatalytic results show that the combination of Cu2O and CNTs has a synergistic impact to reduce the overpotential value. In an effort to pinpoint the rate determining processes for OER, the voltage of OER is connected to the electrolyte pH and exhibits a non-proton concerted approach. The above designed nanocomposite is quite promising for modern hydrogen production systems due to their quick electron transfer mechanism, remarkable durability, and good activity for OER.</description>
      <author>Salma Aman, Meznah M. Alanazi, Shaimaa A. M. Abdelmohsen, Saeed D. Alahmari, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Suleman Waheed, A.M.A. Henaish, Zubair Ahmad, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2023.111853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Design and Insights into Lanthanum and Strontium Perovskite Oxides for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308443</link>
      <description>Sagar Ingavale, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Carolin Mercy Enoch, Chanon Pornrungroj, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Kasadit Nootong, Rojana Pornprasertsuk, Soorathep Kheawhom, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391142464

                Abstract Perovskite oxides exhibit bifunctional activity for both oxygen reduction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER), making them prime candidates for energy conversion in applications like fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries. Their intrinsic catalytic prowess, combined with low&#8208;cost, abundance, and diversity, positions them as compelling alternatives to noble metal and metal oxides catalysts. This review encapsulates the nuances of perovskite oxide structures and synthesis techniques, providing insight into pivotal active sites that underscore their bifunctional behavior. The focus centers on the breakthroughs surrounding lanthanum (La) and strontium (Sr)&#8208;based perovskite oxides, specifically their roles in zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). An introduction to the mechanisms of ORR and OER is provided. Moreover, the light is shed on strategies and determinants central to optimizing the bifunctional performance of La and Sr&#8208;based perovskite oxides.</description>
      <author>Sagar Ingavale, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Carolin Mercy Enoch, Chanon Pornrungroj, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Kasadit Nootong, Rojana Pornprasertsuk, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel-type high-entropy oxide nanotubes for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133315</link>
      <description>Yanbin Zhu, Qing Xiang, Guo Le, Shuanglong Lu, Fang Duan, Mingliang Du, Han Zhu, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391177777

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) involved 4-electron transfers is generally considered as the bottleneck for electrocatalytic water splitting. High-entropy oxides (HEO) show promising potential for OER due to their flexible structures and tunable compositions. Herein, we report a facile strategy to synthesize spinel-type (FeCoNiMnCr)3O4 HEO nanotubes (NTs) with unique hollow structures by combining electrospinning process and calcination treatment. The (FeCoNiMnCr)3O4 HEO NTs prepared at 400 &#176;C exhibit the low overpotential of 353 mV at 50 mA cm-2 and small Tafel slope of 55.6 mV dec-1 in 1 M KOH electrolyte. The three-dimensional (3D) nanofiber-based architecture ensure the superior stability, as evidenced by the stable current density under continuous OER process for more than 60 h. Meanwhile, the hollow structure provides abundant exposed active sites, which could significantly improve the OER activity. This work provides new design of low-cost and high-efficient HEO with ensemble active sites for OER.</description>
      <author>Yanbin Zhu, Qing Xiang, Guo Le, Shuanglong Lu, Fang Duan, Mingliang Du, Han Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nanotubes immobilized copper(salen) nanocomposite for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i1.2312</link>
      <description>, Indian Journal of Chemistry. 63(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391174987

                An efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts are widely required in the realm of water electrolysis and rechargeable metal-air batteries. This work describes an easy and simple method for the synthesis of copper salen (Cu(Salen))-functionalized multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) nanocomposite materials (Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs). It was used for OER in the basic medium (0.1 M KOH). The resulting nanocomposite, Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs, was studied using spectroscopic and microscopic techniques. For example, Fourier transform infrared (FT-IR), UV-visible spectroscopy, powder X-ray diffraction (p-XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and energy dispersive X-ray analysis (EDAX). The electrochemical characterization of prepared Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs nanocomposite based modified glassy carbon (GC) electrodes (GC/Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs) and their application towards OER were performed using an electrochemical method. The Tafel slope of nanocomposite material is 159.6 mv/dec in 0.1 M KOH solution, indicating that GC/Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs could be a promising and cost-effective electrode material for the OER. This study demonstrates a novel way for creating an active nanocomposite catalyst for OER in alkaline media.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i1.2312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper oxide nanofibers obtained by solution blow spinning as catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.01.213</link>
      <description>Alessandra Patr&#237;cia de Ara&#250;jo Dantas, Rafael A. Raimundo, Pedro de Lima Neto, Caio M. S. Lopes, Jakeline R.D. Santos, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, Tatiany Barata Pereira, Marco A. Morales, Eliton S. Medeiros, Daniel A. Macedo, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390965940

                In this work, we report copper oxide nanofibers (CuO &#8211; N) synthesized by Solution Blow Spinning (SBS) for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and their comparison with a control sample based on a commercial powder (CuO &#8211; C). Both materials were characterized by various techniques, including X-ray diffraction (XRD), magnetometry, scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and spectroscopy (Fourier transform infrared (FT-IR), Raman and X-ray photoelectron (XPS)) to confirm the purity, and microstructural and surface chemical properties. Subsequently, the performance of copper oxide catalysts in a 1.0 M KOH solution was investigated. Copper oxide with nanofiber morphology (CuO &#8211; N) exhibited a small overpotential of 385 mV @ 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel coefficient of only 76 mV dec&#8722;1, i.e., fast kinetics for water splitting, a result that is modulated by oxygen vacancies (O2/O1 = 0.83). The oxygen vacancies are due to the presence of Cu1+ in the lattice. The analyses of the magnetization measurements at 5 K suggest a larger amount of Cu1+ in sample CuO &#8211; N. Therefore, this work sheds light on how to design low-cost nanofibrous catalysts based on abundant transition metals in the earth's crust by SBS, an economical and scalable technique, which is promising for energy applications.</description>
      <author>Alessandra Patr&#237;cia de Ara&#250;jo Dantas, Rafael A. Raimundo, Pedro de Lima Neto, Caio M. S. Lopes, Jakeline R.D. Santos, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, Tatiany Barata Pereira, Marco A. Morales, Eliton S. Medeiros, Daniel A. Macedo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.01.213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing highly efficient bifunctional catalysts for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution by modifying MXene with transition metal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.089</link>
      <description>Dai Yu, Xiuyun Zhao, Desheng Zheng, Qingrui Zhao, Jing Feng, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391063505

                Exploring highly active electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has become a growing interest in recent years. Herein, an efficient pathway for designing MXene-based ORR/OER catalysts is proposed. It involves introducing non-noble metals into Vo (vacancy site), H1 and H2 (the hollow sites on top of C and the metal atom, respectively) sites on M2CO2 surfaces, named TM-VO/H1/H2-M2CO2 (TM = Fe, Co, Ni, M = V, Nb, Ta). Among these recombination catalysts, Co-H1-V2CO2 and Ni-H1-V2CO2 exhibit the most promising ORR catalytic activities, with low overpotential values of 0.35 and 0.37 V, respectively. Similarly, Fe-H1-V2CO2, Co-VO-Nb2CO2, and Ni-H2-Nb2CO2 possess low OER overpotential values of 0.29, 0.39, and 0.44 V, respectively, suggesting they have enormous potential as effective catalysts for OER. Notably, Co-H2-Ta2CO2 possesses the lowest potential gap value of 0.53 V, demonstrating it has an extraordinary bifunctional catalytic activity. The excellent catalytic performance of these recombination catalysts can be elucidated through an electronic structure analysis, which primarily relies on the electron-donating capacity and synergistic effects between transition metals and sub-metals. These results provide theoretical guidance for designing new ORR and OER catalysts using 2D MXene materials.</description>
      <author>Dai Yu, Xiuyun Zhao, Desheng Zheng, Qingrui Zhao, Jing Feng, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the role of iron in Fe5Ni4S8 toward oxygen evolution through modulation of electronic orbital occupancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.028</link>
      <description>Zhengyan Du, Zeshuo Meng, H. Sun, Yifan Li, Chao Jiang, Yaxin Li, Xiaoying Hu, Yi Cui, Shansheng Yu, Hongwei Tian, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391152145

                Ni-Fe-based catalysts are considered to be among the most active catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under alkaline conditions, with Fe playing a crucial role. However, Fe leaching occurs during the reaction due to thermodynamic instability, which has resulted in conflicting reports within the literature regarding its role. To clarify this point, we propose a strategy consisting of modulating the electronic orbital occupancy to suppress the extensive loss of Fe atoms during the OER process. Theoretical calculations, in-situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, molecular dynamics simulations, and a series of characterization showed that the stable presence of Fe not only accelerates the electron transfer process but also optimizes the reaction barriers of the oxygen evolution intermediates, promoting the phase transition of Fe5Ni4S8 to highly active catalytic species. The modulated Fe5Ni4S8-based pre-catalysts exhibit improved OER activity and long-term durability. This study provides a novel perspective for understanding the role of Fe in the OER process.</description>
      <author>Zhengyan Du, Zeshuo Meng, H. Sun, Yifan Li, Chao Jiang, Yaxin Li, Xiaoying Hu, Yi Cui, Shansheng Yu, Hongwei Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo2S4 octahedral configuration doped by Mn, Zn and Cu for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc06171j</link>
      <description>Yi-Ting Chen, Wu H, Ning Tang, Mengjie Zhang, Yuqiao Wang, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390883323

                Transition metals with similar atomic radius were used to doping spinel NiCo2S4 to adjust octahedral configuration. Mn dopants adjusted the morphology and surface charge distribution, optimized the electron transport and...</description>
      <author>Yi-Ting Chen, Wu H, Ning Tang, Mengjie Zhang, Yuqiao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc06171j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser assisted oxygen vacancy engineering on Fe doped CoO nanoparticles for oxygen evolution at large current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143841</link>
      <description>Min Zhu, Zong&#8208;Qiang Sheng, Zhifen Fu, Yang Li, Juan Gao, Chao Zhang, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391037653

                Exploring cost-effective non-noble metal-based catalysts with high activity and stability is of great significance for energy conversion and storage involving oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, we employed a laser irradiation technique to synthesis Fe doped CoO nanoparticles with ultrafine size (&#8776; 5.4 nm) and abundant oxygen vacancies (Fe-Ov-CoO). The ultrafine size of Fe-Ov-CoO nanoparticles provides more active sites to be exposed. Fe doping and oxygen vacancy promote the intrinsic activity and electron transfer rates of Fe-Ov-CoO, giving rise to high activity and stability catalyst for OER. Fe-Ov-CoO delivers a large current density of 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 at an overpotential of 548 mV, which is much better than commercial RuO2. Moreover, Fe-Ov-CoO presents a remarkable long-term stability with negligible degeneration at a high current density of 500 mA cm&#8722;2 for 120 h. This work provides a new route to develop OER electrocatalyst with high activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Min Zhu, Zong&#8208;Qiang Sheng, Zhifen Fu, Yang Li, Juan Gao, Chao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Ru(II) Polypyridyl Complex based AIEgen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3qi02380j</link>
      <description>Snehadrinarayan Khatua, Monosh Rabha, Sreenivasan Nagappan, Bhaskar Sen, Khanindram Baruah, Subrata Kundu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390987133

                Ruthenium polypyridyl complexes are known for their excellent photophysical properties and rich electrochemical behavior. Thus, developing complexes with multifunctional behavior showing potential applications in multiple fields is of great importance....</description>
      <author>Snehadrinarayan Khatua, Monosh Rabha, Sreenivasan Nagappan, Bhaskar Sen, Khanindram Baruah, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3qi02380j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient oxygen evolution using conductive cobalt-based metal-organic framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131044</link>
      <description>Munzir H. Suliman, Lolwah Tawfiq Alfuhaid, Mohd Yusuf Khan, Muhammad Usman, Aasif Helal, Fuel. 363(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391143814

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munzir H. Suliman, Lolwah Tawfiq Alfuhaid, Mohd Yusuf Khan, Muhammad Usman, Aasif Helal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional ordered macroporous design of heterogeneous cobalt-iron phosphides as oxygen evolution electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad21a5</link>
      <description>Suqing Zhao, Weijin Cao, Lu Lu, Zhaoyang Tan, Yanji Wang, Lanlan Wu, Jingde Li, Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391127015

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a key role in electrochemical conversion, which needs efficient and economical electrocatalyst to boost its kinetics for large-scale application. Herein, a bimetallic CoP/FeP2 heterostructure with a three-dimensional ordered macroporous structure (3DOM-CoP/FeP2) was synthesized as an OER catalyst to demonstrate a heterogeneous engineering induction strategy. By adjusting the electron distribution and producing a lot of active sites, the heterogeneous interface enhances catalytic performance. High specific surface area is provided by the 3DOM structure. Additionally, at the solid-gas-electrolyte threephase interface, the electrocatalytic reaction exhibits good mass transfer. In-situ Raman spectroscopy characterization revealed that FeOOH and CoOOH reconstructed from CoP/FeP2 were the true OER active sites. Consequently, the 3DOM-CoP/FeP2 demonstrates superior OER activity with a low overpotentials of 300/420 mV at 10/100 mA cm&#8211;2 and meritorious OER durability. It also reveals promising performance as the overall water splitting anode.&amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Suqing Zhao, Weijin Cao, Lu Lu, Zhaoyang Tan, Yanji Wang, Lanlan Wu, Jingde Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad21a5</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
