<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 01:23:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Cocatalytic Sites Synergize NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402046</link>
      <description>Yue Shi, Lumin Song, Yan Liu, Tiantian Wang, Caixia Li, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403584566

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;iron layered double hydroxide (LDH) is a promising cost&#8208;efficient catalyst to replace noble metals for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER), yet its intrinsic activity under high current density conditions is not satisfactory, which greatly constrains the industrial application of NiFe LDH catalysts. Herein, a new class of integrated Co and W co&#8208;doped NiFe LDH catalysts is reported with dual cocatalytic sites for alkaline OER catalysis. The optimized Co 2.8 , W 3.8 &#8208;NiFe LDH integrated catalyst has superior alkaline OER activity (255 mV@1000 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and excellent catalytic stability (200 h@500 mA cm &#8722;2 ). The turnover frequency value of Co 2.8 , W 3.8 &#8208;NiFe LDH can reach 4.02 s &#8722;1 at 1.49 V versus RHE, which is 9.6 times higher than that of NiFe LDH and superior to the noble metal catalysts. Moreover, it can achieve 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.86 V and maintain 300&#8208;h stable operation in anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Theoretical and experimental studies indicate that W sites promote the *OH adsorption and Co sites favor protons desorption of OH*. These dual cocatalytic sites jointly promote *O coverage, effectively accelerating alkaline OER kinetic.</description>
      <author>Yue Shi, Lumin Song, Yan Liu, Tiantian Wang, Caixia Li, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural, magnetic and electrocatalytic properties of rock salt oxide nanofibers (Ni0.2Mg0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2-xCo0.2+x)O produced by air-heated solution blow spinning (A-HSBS) for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161593</link>
      <description>Ronaldo M. Oliveira Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Mederios, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403590066

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ronaldo M. Oliveira Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Mederios, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile fabrication of nickel selenide with manganese telluride (NiSe/MnTe) nanocomposite employed as strong electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00433-6</link>
      <description>Nirma Rasool, Haifa A. Alyousef, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Basel Al-Otaibi, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Khursheed Ahmad, Journal of the Korean Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403596747

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nirma Rasool, Haifa A. Alyousef, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Basel Al-Otaibi, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Khursheed Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00433-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-coordinated cobalt single atom Steered by Doped-O and CoO for efficient hydrogen evolution at industrial current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156990</link>
      <description>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Ruyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Peng Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Ruyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Peng Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D -Band Center Theory-Guided Mixed Metal Oxide-Based Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Ultra-Stable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994483</link>
      <description>Weipeng Zhao, Qicheng Zhang, P. W. Zhao, Bin Chen, Yang Li, Wenchao Peng, Xiaobin Fan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weipeng Zhao, Qicheng Zhang, P. W. Zhao, Bin Chen, Yang Li, Wenchao Peng, Xiaobin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomass-Derived-Carbon-Supported Spinel Cobalt Molybdate as High-Efficiency Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29204953</link>
      <description>Baoli Wang, Xiujiu Yang, Yan Chen, Jiahan Wang, Mingguo Lan, Kai Tang, Feng Yang, Molecules. 29(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403603383

                Ananas comosus leaves were converted to a porous graphitized carbon (GPLC) material via a high-temperature pyrolysis method by employing iron salt as a catalyst. A cobalt molybdate (CoMoO4)-and-GPLC composite (CoMoO4/GPLC) was then prepared by engineering CoMoO4 nanorods in situ, grown on GPLC. N2 adsorption&#8211;desorption isothermal curves and a pore size distribution curve verify that the proposed composite possesses a porous structure and a large specific surface area, which are favorable for charge and reactant transport and the rapid escape of O2 bubbles. Consequently, the as-synthesized CoMoO4/GPLC shows low overpotentials of 289 mV and 399 mV to afford the current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2 towards the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is superior to many CoMoO4-based catalysts in previous studies. In addition, the decrease in current density is particularly small, with a reduction rate of 3.2% after a continuous OER procedure for 30 h, indicating its good stability. The excellent performance of the CoMoO4/GPLC composite proves that the GPLC carrier can obviously impel the catalytic activity of CoMoO4 by improving electrical conductivity, enhancing mass transport and exposing more active sites of the composite. This work provides an effective strategy for the efficient conversion of waste ananas comosus leaves to a biomass-derived-carbon-supported Co-Mo-based OER electrocatalyst with good performance, which may represent a potential approach to the development of new catalysts for OER, as well as the treatment of waste biomass.</description>
      <author>Baoli Wang, Xiujiu Yang, Yan Chen, Jiahan Wang, Mingguo Lan, Kai Tang, Feng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29204953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasmall RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles with robust interfacial interactions for the enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00719k</link>
      <description>Ming Wei, Liuhua Mu, Zhi&#8208;Wei Liu, Feng Gao, Guangjian Song, Qiankang Si, Mao Zhang, Fangfang Dai, Min Zhang, Rui Ding, Li Yang, Zhonggui Gao, Sanzhao Song, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403606874

                Ultrasmall RuO 2 /CoFe 2 O 4 nanoparticles with strong interfacial interactions exhibit enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, driven by efficient charge transfer between RuO 2 and CoFe 2 O 4 .</description>
      <author>Ming Wei, Liuhua Mu, Zhi&#8208;Wei Liu, Feng Gao, Guangjian Song, Qiankang Si, Mao Zhang, Fangfang Dai, Min Zhang, Rui Ding, Li Yang, Zhonggui Gao, Sanzhao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00719k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Out-of-plane coordination of iridium single atoms with organic molecules and cobalt&#8211;iron hydroxides to boost oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-024-01807-x</link>
      <description>Jie Zhao, Yue Guo, Zhiqi Zhang, Xilin Zhang, Qianqian Ji, Han Zhang, Zhaoqi Song, Dongqing Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Erhuan Zhang, Yuhao Wang, Guangzhi Hu, Muhammad Asim Mushtaq, Waseem Raza, Xingke Cai, Francesco Ciucci, Nature Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403609594

                Abstract Advancements in single-atom-based catalysts are crucial for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance while reducing precious metal usage. A comprehensive understanding of underlying mechanisms will expedite this progress further. Here we report Ir single atoms coordinated out-of-plane with dimethylimidazole (MI) on CoFe hydroxide (Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI). This Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI catalyst, which was prepared using a simple immersion method, delivers ultralow overpotentials of 179 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and 257 mV at 600 mA cm &#8722;2 as well as an ultra-small Tafel slope of 24 mV dec &#8722;1 . Furthermore, Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI has a total mass activity exceeding that of commercial IrO 2 by a factor of 58.4. Ab initio simulations indicate that the coordination of MI leads to electron redistribution around the Ir sites. This causes a positive shift in the d -band centre at adjacent Ir and Co sites, facilitating an optimal energy pathway for OER.</description>
      <author>Jie Zhao, Yue Guo, Zhiqi Zhang, Xilin Zhang, Qianqian Ji, Han Zhang, Zhaoqi Song, Dongqing Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Erhuan Zhang, Yuhao Wang, Guangzhi Hu, Muhammad Asim Mushtaq, Waseem Raza, Xingke Cai, Francesco Ciucci</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-024-01807-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Developments in Membrane&#8208;Free Hybrid Water Electrolysis for Low&#8208;Cost Hydrogen Production Along with Value&#8208;Added Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407845</link>
      <description>Neshanth Vadivel, Arun Prasad Murthy, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403610580

                Abstract Water electrolysis using renewable energy is considered as a promising technique for sustainable and green hydrogen production. Conventional water electrolysis has two components &#8211; hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) occurring at the cathode and anode respectively. However, electrolysis of water suffers from high overpotential due to the slow kinetics of OER. To overcome this hybrid water electrolysis has been developed by replacing conventional anode oxidation producing oxygen with oxidation of cost&#8208;effective materials producing value&#8208;added chemicals. This review summarizes recent advances in organic oxidative reactions such as alcohols, urea, hydrazine, and biomass at the anode instead of OER. Furthermore, the review also highlights the use of membrane&#8208;free hybrid water electrolysis as a method to overcome the cost and complexity associated with conventional membrane&#8208;based electrolyzer thereby improving overall efficiency. This approach holds promise for scalable and cost&#8208;effective large&#8208;scale hydrogen production along with value&#8208;added products. Finally, current challenges and future perspectives are discussed for further development in membrane&#8208;free hybrid water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Neshanth Vadivel, Arun Prasad Murthy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuCo@C Hollow Nanoprisms Derived from ZIF&#8208;67 for Enhanced Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401862</link>
      <description>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Samah A. Mahyoub, Fahim A. Qaraah, Abdo Hezam, Q.A. Drmosh, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403612479

                Zeolitic imidazolate frameworks (ZIFs) are commonly used to create complex hollow structures for energy applications. This study presents a simple method to produce a novel hollow nanoprism Co@C hierarchical composite from ZIF&#8208;67 through high&#8208;temperature treatment at 800 &#176;C. This composite serves as a platform for Ru nanoparticle deposition, forming RuCo@C hollow nanoprism (RuCo@C HNP). As an electrocatalyst in 1 M KOH, RuCo@C HNP exhibits excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance, with a low overpotential of 32 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a Tafel slope of 39.67 mV dec&#8722;1, a high turnover frequency (TOF) of 3.83 s&#8722;1 at &#414;200, and stable performance over 50 h. It also achieves a low &#414;10 of 266 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with a Tafel slope of 45.22 mV dec&#8722;1. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that Ru doping in Ni/Co maintains a low water dissociation barrier, reduces the energy barrier for the OER rate&#8208;determining step, and creates active sites for H*, enhancing adsorption/desorption abilities. These results are attributed to the synergy between Co and Ru and the hollow prism structure's increased surface area. This method for synthesizing hollow structures using ZIF composites shows promise for applications in the energy sector.</description>
      <author>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Samah A. Mahyoub, Fahim A. Qaraah, Abdo Hezam, Q.A. Drmosh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Conversion of Metal Organic Frameworks into Porous Rugby Phosphides by Plasma for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03525</link>
      <description>Guochang Li, Mang Niu, Rongzheng An, Huayu Zhang, Bingxue Sun, Guoling Li, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403613070

                Electrolytic seawater is a green, sustainable, and promising approach for hydrogen production. Benefiting from the cost-effectiveness, crystal structures, and tailorable modification, transition metal phosphides become a highly attractive catalyst for the electrolysis of water. Considering the sufficient exposure and intrinsic catalytic activity of metal sites, here, carbon layer-coated NiFeP nanocrystals with a porous rugby structure are synthesized by Ar-H</description>
      <author>Guochang Li, Mang Niu, Rongzheng An, Huayu Zhang, Bingxue Sun, Guoling Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially Immobilized PtPdFeCoNi as an Excellent Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202414537</link>
      <description>Mingkuan Xie, Yu Lu, Xinke Xiao, Duojie Wu, Bing Shao, Hao Nian, Chunsheng Wu, Wenjuan Wang, Jun Gu, Songbai Han, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615140

                Abstract Developing efficient oxygen electrocatalysts with low cost, high catalytic activity, and robust stability remains a formidable challenge for rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, highly dispersed ultrasmall PtPdFeCoNi high&#8208;entropy alloy nanoparticles with a size of &#8776; 2 nm and randomly distributed multimetallic single atoms spatially immobilized on the 3D hierarchically ordered porous nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon skeleton (denoted as PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC) are successfully synthesized via ultra&#8208;rapid Joule heating process. The spatial immobilization on 3D HOPNC skeleton is the key to the high dispersion of multi&#8208;active sites of oxygen electrocatalysts, and the formed hierarchical pore structure is conducive to the successful construction of the rapid mass transfer channel. As a result, the as&#8208;prepared PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC exhibits a positive half&#8208;wave potential of 0.866 V versus RHE for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), a low overpotential of 310 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and low Tafel slopes for both ORR and OER. Furthermore, ZAB using PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC as bifunctional oxygen catalysts exhibits excellent rate performances and superior cycling stability, surpassing that of a commercial Pt/C&#8208;RuO 2 mixture. The spatial immobilization strategy of HOPNC provides a new idea for the design and synthesis of efficient catalysts for various applications.</description>
      <author>Mingkuan Xie, Yu Lu, Xinke Xiao, Duojie Wu, Bing Shao, Hao Nian, Chunsheng Wu, Wenjuan Wang, Jun Gu, Songbai Han, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202414537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c</link>
      <description>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615829

                The design of efficient and active electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for renewable energy generation. Here, crystalline iron-doped nickel sulfide core, amorphous iron-doped nickel phosphate shell heterostructured...</description>
      <author>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution performance by single metal (tungsten, nickel and manganese) atom oxides anchored nanorods of CeO2-MnO2-rGO as electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105800</link>
      <description>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Yueshuai Wang, Tae Hwan Oh, Vanthana Jeyasingh, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, M. Swaminathan, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 165(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403623601

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Yueshuai Wang, Tae Hwan Oh, Vanthana Jeyasingh, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, M. Swaminathan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Site-Enabled O&#8211;O Coupling in Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</link>
      <description>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403624087

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Spin Channels in SrCoO3 through Triagonal&#8208;to&#8208;Cubic Structural Transformation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415797</link>
      <description>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403627497

                Oxygen evolution and reduction reactions (OER and ORR) play crucial roles in energy conversion processes such as water splitting and air batteries, where spin dynamics inherently influence their efficiency. However, the specific contribution of spin has yet to be fully understood. In this study, we intentionally introduce a spin channel through the transformation of trigonal antiferromagnetic SrCoO2.5 into cubic ferromagnetic SrCoO3, aiming to deepen our understanding of spin dynamics in catalytic reactions. Based on the results from spherical&#8208;aberration&#8208;corrected microscope, synchrotron absorption spectra, magnetic characterizations, and density functional theory calculations, it is revealed that surface electron transfer is predominantly governed by local geometric structures, while the presence of the spin channel significantly enhances the bulk transport of spin&#8208;polarized electrons, particularly under high current densities where surface electron transfer is no longer the limiting factor. The overpotential for OER is reduced by at least 70 mV at 150 mA cm&#8208;2 due to the enhanced conductivity from spin&#8208;polarized electrons facilitated by spin channels, with an expectation of even more significant reductions at higher current densities. This work provides a clearer picture of the role of spin in oxygen&#8208;involved electrocatalysis, providing critical insights for the design of more efficient catalytic systems in practical applications.</description>
      <author>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629653

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629654

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629734

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629769

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403630496

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403630497

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemistry of Nickelocene-Ferrocene Organometallic Complexes for Electrodeposition of Nickel&#8211;Iron&#8211;Based Nanostructured Film under Ambient Conditions for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04084</link>
      <description>Kamlesh, Parul Aggarwal, Manish Mudgal, Avanish Kumar Srivastava, Pankaj Raizada, Archana Singh, Amit Paul, Archana Singh, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633314

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kamlesh, Parul Aggarwal, Manish Mudgal, Avanish Kumar Srivastava, Pankaj Raizada, Archana Singh, Amit Paul, Archana Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile synthesis of N-doped carbon encapsulated multimetallic carbonitride as a robust electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.120</link>
      <description>Xiaojuan Cao, Haozhou Feng, Yu Lin, Lei Shi, Ning Yan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojuan Cao, Haozhou Feng, Yu Lin, Lei Shi, Ning Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Coprecipitation-Thermal Synthesis of Nano-Ni-Co Alloy for Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00902-w</link>
      <description>Yuanjun Sun, Zelin Li, Zhu Fei, Yin Fei, Songwei Ge, Fairy Fan Yang, Lili Gao, Guoju Chen, Fan Yang, PingAn Hu, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403638522

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanjun Sun, Zelin Li, Zhu Fei, Yin Fei, Songwei Ge, Fairy Fan Yang, Lili Gao, Guoju Chen, Fan Yang, PingAn Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00902-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In&#8208;situ Reconstruction of Catalyst in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411688</link>
      <description>Jinxian Feng, X.&#8208;S. Wang, Hui Pan, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403645863

                Abstract Reconstruction of catalysts is now well recognized as a common phenomenon in electrocatalysis. As the reconstructed structure may promote or hamper the electrochemical performance, how to achieve the designed active surface for highly enhanced catalytic activity through the reconstruction needs to be carefully investigated. In this review, the genesis and electrochemical effects of reconstruction in various electrochemical catalytic processes, such as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), and nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) are first described. Then, the strategies for optimizing the reconstruction, such as valence states control, active phase retention, phase evolution engineering, and surface poisoning prevention are comprehensively discussed. Finally, the general rules of reconstruction optimization are summarized and give perspectives for future study. It is believed that the review shall provide deep insights into electrocatalytic mechanisms and guide the design of pre&#8208;catalysts with highly improved activity.</description>
      <author>Jinxian Feng, X.&#8208;S. Wang, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrospun Co&#8208;MoC Nanoparticles Embedded in Carbon Nanofibers for Highly Efficient pH&#8208;Universal Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Alkaline Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401103</link>
      <description>Shan Zhang, Fuhe Le, Wei Jia, Xue Yang, Pengfei Hu, Xueyan Wu, Wanting Shu, Yanmei Xie, Wuyang Xiao, Dianzeng Jia, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403646373

                Abstract The construction of highly efficient and self&#8208;supported electrocatalysts with abundant active sites for pH&#8208;universal hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and alkaline water splitting is significantly challenging. Herein, Co and MoC nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanofibers (Co&#8208;MoC/NCNFs) which display a bamboo&#8208;like morphology are prepared by electrospinning followed by the carbonization method. The electrospun MoC possesses an ultrasmall size (&#8776;5 nm) which can provide more active sites during electrocatalysis, while the introduction of Co greatly optimizes the electronic structure of MoC. Both endow the Co&#8208;MoC/NCNFs with superior HER performances over a wide pH range, with low overpotentials of 86, 116, and 145 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline, acidic, and neutral media, respectively. Additionally, the catalyst exhibits remarkable alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity with an overpotential of 254 mV to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Density functional theory calculations confirm that electron transfer from Co to MoC regulates the adsorption free energy for hydrogen, thereby promoting HER. Moreover, an electrolyzer assembled with Co&#8208;MoC/NCNFs requires only a cell voltage of 1.59 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH. This work opens new pathways for the design of high&#8208;efficiency electrocatalysts for energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Shan Zhang, Fuhe Le, Wei Jia, Xue Yang, Pengfei Hu, Xueyan Wu, Wanting Shu, Yanmei Xie, Wuyang Xiao, Dianzeng Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Cobalt Spinel-Based Oxygen Evolution Electrode for Zinc-Air Flow Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4995648</link>
      <description>P&#345;emysl Richtr, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Ji&#345;&#237; Charv&#225;t, Martin Bure&#353;, Jarom&#237;r Pocedi&#269;, Martin Paidar, Juraj Ko&#353;ek, Petr Maz&#250;r, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403647198

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P&#345;emysl Richtr, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Ji&#345;&#237; Charv&#225;t, Martin Bure&#353;, Jarom&#237;r Pocedi&#269;, Martin Paidar, Juraj Ko&#353;ek, Petr Maz&#250;r</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4995648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recognizing the Reactive Site of SnFe2O4 for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Synergistic Effect of SnII and FeIII in Stabilizing Reaction Intermediates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03107e</link>
      <description>Anubha Rajput, Pandiyan Sivasakthi, Pralok K. Samanta, Biswarup Chakraborty, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403648589

                Among the reported spinel ferrites, the p-block metal containing SnFe2O4 is scarcely explored, but it is a promising water-splitting electrocatalyst. This study focuses on the reaction kinetics and atomic scale...</description>
      <author>Anubha Rajput, Pandiyan Sivasakthi, Pralok K. Samanta, Biswarup Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03107e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Photo&#8208;Assisted Zinc&#8211;Air Battery with MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Oxygen Vacancies Rich TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction Photocathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408627</link>
      <description>Yongjian Wu, Yi Ding, Mengyu Chen, Hui Zhang, Yu Jing, Tongtong Jiang, Mingzai Wu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403657995

                Abstract Converting solar energy into electrochemical energy is a sustainable strategy, but the design of photo&#8208;assisted zinc&#8211;air battery (ZAB) with efficient utilization of sunlight faces huge challenges. Herein, a photo&#8208;assisted ZAB of a three&#8208;electrode system using MoS 2 /oxygen vacancies&#8208;rich TiO 2 heterojunction as charge cathode and Fe, N&#8208;doped carbon matrix (FeNC) as discharge cathode is constructed, where MoS 2 is chosen as solar light&#8208;responsive catalytic material and TiO 2 acts as electron transport layer and hole blocking layer, arising from a train of thought for efficient charging under sunlight irradiation and light&#8208;independent discharging. The introduction of oxygen vacancies in TiO 2 facilitates the temporary trapping of carriers and triggers rapid carrier transfer at the interface of the heterojunction, which hinders the recombination of photogenerated holes, thereby facilitating their further participation in the oxygen evolution reaction. Moreover, FeNC exhibits superior oxygen reduction reaction performance due to strong d&#8208;&#960; interactions. As a result, the well&#8208;built ZABs deliver a low charge voltage (0.71 V) under illumination at 0.1 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a high power density (167.6 mW cm &#8722;2 ) in dark. This work paves a special way for the development of ZABs by directly harvesting solar energy in charging and efficiently discharging regardless of lighting conditions.</description>
      <author>Yongjian Wu, Yi Ding, Mengyu Chen, Hui Zhang, Yu Jing, Tongtong Jiang, Mingzai Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning of Oxygen Vacancies in Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst for Effectiveness in Urea Oxidation and Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403744</link>
      <description>Pandian Mannu, Ranjith Kumar Dharman, Ta Thi Thuy Nga, Athibala Mariappan, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yucheng Huang, Asokan Kandasami, Tae Hwan Oh, Wu&#8208;Ching Chou, Chi&#8208;Liang Chen, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403658604

                Abstract The development of an excellent multifunctional electrocatalyst that is based on non&#8208;precious metal is critical for improving the electrochemical processes of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and the urea oxidation reaction (UOR) in alkaline media. This study demonstrates that incorporating Mo into Co 3 O 4 facilitated the formation of rich oxygen vacancies (Vo), which promotes effective nitrate adsorption and activation in urea electrolysis. Subsequently, in situ/operando X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy is used to explore the active sites in Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 &#8208;3 under OER, indicating the oxygen vacancies are first filled with OH &#8226; in Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 ; facilitated the pre&#8208;oxidation of low&#8208;valence Co, and promoted the reconstruction/deprotonation of intermediate Co&#8208;OOH &#8226; . Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 &#8208;3 electrocatalysts show impressive HER, OER, and UOR with low overpotentials of 141 mV, 220 mV, and 1.32 V, respectively, at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in an alkaline medium. Furthermore, in situ/Operando Raman spectroscopy results reveal the importance of CoOOH active sites for enhanced electrochemical performance in Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 &#8208;3 compared to the pure Co 3 O 4 . The urea electrolyzer with Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 electrocatalysts acts as an anode and the cathode delivers 1.42 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . A viable approach to creating effective UOR electrocatalysts involves synergistic engineering exploiting doping and oxygen vacancies.</description>
      <author>Pandian Mannu, Ranjith Kumar Dharman, Ta Thi Thuy Nga, Athibala Mariappan, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yucheng Huang, Asokan Kandasami, Tae Hwan Oh, Wu&#8208;Ching Chou, Chi&#8208;Liang Chen, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Chung&#8208;Li Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rutile-structured high-entropy oxyfluorides: A platform for oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.009</link>
      <description>Shengliang Qi, Kaixin Zhu, Ting Xu, Weiguang Ma, Xu Zong, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403660312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengliang Qi, Kaixin Zhu, Ting Xu, Weiguang Ma, Xu Zong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Titanate Perovskites with Different Morphologies for Oxygen-evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.10.306</link>
      <description>Jin Goo Lee, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403660645

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jin Goo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.10.306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media using Co-spinels and stainless steel based electrodes</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4403664806</link>
      <description>Garance Cossard, Gw&#233;na&#235;lle K&#233;rangu&#233;ven, Elena R. Savinova, Marian Chatenet, &#201;ric Sibert, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403664806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Garance Cossard, Gw&#233;na&#235;lle K&#233;rangu&#233;ven, Elena R. Savinova, Marian Chatenet, &#201;ric Sibert</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4403664806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-Boosted Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Via a 2d/2d Heterostructure Constructed by Integrating Reduced Graphene Oxide on Nife-Ldh Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4993388</link>
      <description>Qian Liu, Jinyi Wang, Yuxia Zhang, Wa Gao, Hongzhi Cui, Jingxiang Low, Haiming Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403667387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Liu, Jinyi Wang, Yuxia Zhang, Wa Gao, Hongzhi Cui, Jingxiang Low, Haiming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4993388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating oxygen vacancies to optimize the electronic structure and catalytic activity of tungsten oxides for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.287</link>
      <description>Jun Yang, Pengfei Jia, Yifan Cao, Peng Yu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403669922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Yang, Pengfei Jia, Yifan Cao, Peng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tetrahydroxybenzoquinone-Based Two-Dimensional Conductive Metal&#8211;Organic Framework via &#960;-d Conjugation Modulation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04977</link>
      <description>Yantao Wang, Xiaowan Bai, Junfeng Huang, Wangzu Li, Jinhua Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403671924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yantao Wang, Xiaowan Bai, Junfeng Huang, Wangzu Li, Jinhua Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest advances in the deep reconstruction of pre-catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177225</link>
      <description>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403679718

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study of Zinc Sulfide, Tin Selenide, and Their Composite Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Towards Efficient and Stable Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145279</link>
      <description>Rida Fatima, Kareem Yusuf, Muhammad Shuaib Khan, Mehar Un Nisa, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403681815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rida Fatima, Kareem Yusuf, Muhammad Shuaib Khan, Mehar Un Nisa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects in LaNiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Perovskites between Nickel and Iron Heterostructures for Improving Durability in Oxygen Evolution Reaction for AEMWE (Small Methods 9/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202470051</link>
      <description>Nam In Kim, Jun Ho Lee, Song Jin, Junyoung Park, Jae&#8208;Yeop Jeong, Jooyoung Lee, Young Do Kim, Chiho Kim, Sung Mook Choi, Small Methods. 8(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403684356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nam In Kim, Jun Ho Lee, Song Jin, Junyoung Park, Jae&#8208;Yeop Jeong, Jooyoung Lee, Young Do Kim, Chiho Kim, Sung Mook Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202470051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in carbon-free oxygen evolution electrocatalysts for high-current-density water electrolysis in acid media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05278a</link>
      <description>Haowen Xu, R. Liu, Jinxiu Zhao, Konghu Tian, Hongyu Gong, Linrui Hou, Changzhou Yuan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403689258

                Hydrogen production by water electrolysis technology has received great attention toward global mission of carbon neutrality. Industrial proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzers stand out from other water electrolysis techniques due...</description>
      <author>Haowen Xu, R. Liu, Jinxiu Zhao, Konghu Tian, Hongyu Gong, Linrui Hou, Changzhou Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05278a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting Synergy of Alloy &amp;amp; Metal Nanoparticles Within Nitrogen&#8208;Doped Carbon Nanosheets for Zn&#8208;Air Batteries with Ultralong Cycling Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401338</link>
      <description>Baoyu Qing, Yijiang Liu, Duanguang Yang, Mei Yang, Bei Liu, Hongbiao Chen, Huaming Li, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403690200

                Abstract The exploration of efficient, robust, and low&#8208;cost bifunctional electrocatalysts to drive the commercial application of Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) is of great significance but still remains a challenge. Herein, a 1D coordination polymer (1D&#8208;CP) derived FeNi alloy &amp; Co nanoparticles (NPs) co&#8208;implanted N&#8208;doped carbon nanosheets (FNC/NCS) is judiciously crafted and employed as a high&#8208;performance electrocatalyst for ultralong lifetime ZABs. The key to this strategy is the leveraging of metal&#8208;coordinated melamine to direct the pyrolysis of 1D&#8208;CP, enabling the in situ formation of well&#8208;dispersed FeNi alloy and Co NPs within the carbon matrix. The resulting FNC/NCS exhibits prominent oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity with a small overall oxygen potential difference (&#916;E = 0.68 V). Density functional theory (DFT) simulation demonstrates that the synergistic effect between FeNi alloy and Co NPs can reduce energy barriers, promote electron transfer, and optimize the formation of crucial intermediates, thereby largely boost ORR/OER activity of FNC/NCS. The FNC/NCS&#8208;assembled ZABs possess high specific capacity, large power density, and ultralong cycling life in both aqueous (&gt; 3300 h) and solid&#8208;state (150 h) electrolytes. This work provides a viable strategy for 1D&#8208;CP&#8208;derived bifunctional electrocatalysts and dissects the synergistic effect between different metal species, affording significant guidance for the development of renewable energy materials.</description>
      <author>Baoyu Qing, Yijiang Liu, Duanguang Yang, Mei Yang, Bei Liu, Hongbiao Chen, Huaming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet Engineering of Cobalt Manganese Oxide for Highly Stable Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402786</link>
      <description>Chi-Wing Lee, Claudio Cazorla, Yingtang Zhou, Ding Zhang, Hanyu Xu, Wenyu Zhong, Mingxing Zhang, Dewei Chu, Zhaojun Han, Rose Amal, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403699810

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective, robust, and durable catalysts for water oxidation in acidic conditions remains a significant challenge for the practical application of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. Cobalt&#8208;based spinel catalysts, known for their effective oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity in acidic environments, are promising alternatives to the costly iridium&#8208;based catalysts. However, their application is often limited by poor stability under corrosive acidic conditions and oxidative potential. Here it is demonstrated that doping Co 2 MnO 4 with Ni effectively regulates the structural and electronic properties of the catalysts, enabling stable operation for over 285 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 . This stability enhancement is primarily due to the increased exposure of the (400) facet, a result supported by theoretical studies. The proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) performance of Ni(5%)Co 2 MnO 4 further demonstrates its potential, achieving 1 A cm &#8722; 2 at a cell voltage of 2.3 V, with minimal degradation over 100 h at 500 mA cm &#8722; 2 . This study not only provides insights into the design of advanced OER catalysts through the doping of heteroatoms but also offers a pathway to enhance the sustainability and economic viability of acidic OER applications.</description>
      <author>Chi-Wing Lee, Claudio Cazorla, Yingtang Zhou, Ding Zhang, Hanyu Xu, Wenyu Zhong, Mingxing Zhang, Dewei Chu, Zhaojun Han, Rose Amal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Defect Engineering Enabled Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Reconstructed Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202412406</link>
      <description>Yinqiang Zhang, Ming Liu, Letian Zhang, Nan L&#252;, Xuemin Wang, Zhigang Li, Xinghao Zhang, Na Li, Xian&#8208;He Bu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403699912

                Abstract Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) have emerged as promising pre&#8208;catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their marvelous structural reconstruction process in strongly alkaline media. However, targeting design MOF structures to achieve excellent OER performance of reconstructed products is a challenge. Here, a strategic defect engineering is used to promote the OER performance of reconstructed products. Briefly, modified linkers with monocarboxylic acids (ferrocene carboxylic acid, FcCA) are incorporated into MOF (NiBDC&#8208;FcCA), leading to its stepwise reconstruction into Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 and NiOOH during the OER process, with the oxygen vacancy and strategic doping of metal Fe persisting throughout the multi&#8208;step reconstruction. Benefiting from the synergistic interaction of oxygen vacancies and Fe doping, NiBDC&#8208;FcCA delivers the extremely enhanced current density at 1.6 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode by &#8776;9 times compared with that of NiBDC. Moreover, the optimized NiBDC&#8208;FcCA/Fe foam exhibits excellent OER catalytic activity and stability with a low overpotential of 250 mV at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 and negligible activity decay after 1200 h at 1 A cm &#8722;2 . Density function theory calculations reveal that Fe doping weakens the interaction of oxygen intermediate with Ni sites, favoring the formation of OOH* to accelerate the OER process.</description>
      <author>Yinqiang Zhang, Ming Liu, Letian Zhang, Nan L&#252;, Xuemin Wang, Zhigang Li, Xinghao Zhang, Na Li, Xian&#8208;He Bu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202412406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioinspired Oxygen-Evolution Reaction: Achieving Oxygen-Evolution Reaction on Layered Manganese-Oxide Surface with Extremely Low Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02187</link>
      <description>Maryam Gharedaghloo, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403705363

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maryam Gharedaghloo, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Cationic Cobalt Vacancies in Molybdenum&#8211;Cobalt Selenide Derived from POM@ZIF-67 for Enhanced Electrocatalysis in Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03299</link>
      <description>Yongming Zhu, Hong Sun, Tianyu Zhang, Qiang Li, Zhichao Xue, Mingfu Yu, Jie Li, Li Wang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403706668

                Slow reaction kinetics during redox reactions limits the utilization of the high theoretical energy density of lithium-oxygen batteries (LOBs). Vacancy engineering, a potential strategy for modulating active sites, is critical in the development of high performance catalysts. This study investigates cobalt vacancies in Mo-CoSe</description>
      <author>Yongming Zhu, Hong Sun, Tianyu Zhang, Qiang Li, Zhichao Xue, Mingfu Yu, Jie Li, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma Assisted Single-Step Synthesis of Carbon-Coated SrFe2O4 Electrodes for Enhancing Supercapacitor and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105339</link>
      <description>Lakshmanan Kumaresan, Amarnath Pasupathi, B. Narayanan, Yugeswaran Subramaniam, G. Shanmugavelayutham, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403707551

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lakshmanan Kumaresan, Amarnath Pasupathi, B. Narayanan, Yugeswaran Subramaniam, G. Shanmugavelayutham</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored IrO2@ZIF-67 nanocomposites for efficient oxygen evolution reaction: Insights into catalyst design and performance enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.255</link>
      <description>Seyeon Cho, Komal Patil, So Young Lee, Daim Choe, Yujin Cho, Jincheol Kim, Jae Sung Yun, Dong Han Seo, Jongsung Park, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403712536

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seyeon Cho, Komal Patil, So Young Lee, Daim Choe, Yujin Cho, Jincheol Kim, Jae Sung Yun, Dong Han Seo, Jongsung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/crystalline Ni-Fe based electrodes with rich oxygen vacancies enable highly active oxygen evolution in seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.128</link>
      <description>Jingcheng Zhang, Xinru Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403714494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingcheng Zhang, Xinru Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward High Corrosion Resistivity and High Efficiency in Seawater Oxygen Evolution: The Synergy of Fe and Ni Dopants in Co Layered Double Hydroxide Ultrathin Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06117</link>
      <description>Cheng Luo, Dandan Cai, Yang Yang, Shipeng Geng, Yi Wang, Shuqin Song, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403716296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Luo, Dandan Cai, Yang Yang, Shipeng Geng, Yi Wang, Shuqin Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Co bimetallic electrocatalysts atomically dispersed on zeolitic imidazolate frameworks (ZIFs) to enhance oxygen reduction reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0236710</link>
      <description>Narumon Jongmanwattana, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, Konlayutt Punyawudho, AIP conference proceedings. 3236(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403725810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Narumon Jongmanwattana, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, Konlayutt Punyawudho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0236710</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel&#8208;Nitrogen Doped MnO2 as Oxygen Reduction Reaction Catalyst for Aluminum Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401385</link>
      <description>Lizi He, Ning Han, Zhongling Lang, Mei Wang, Y.-W. Wang, Lishuang Li, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403726094

                Aluminum&#8208;air battery has the advantages of high energy density, low cost and environmental protection, and is considered as an ideal next&#8208;generation energy storage conversion system. However, the slow oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in air cathode leads to its unsatisfactory performance. Here, we report an electrode made of N and Ni co&#8208;doped MnO2 nanotubes. In alkaline solution, Ni/N&#8208;MnO2 has higher oxygen reduction activity than undoped MnO2, with an initial potential of 1.00 V and a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.75 V. This is because it has abundant defects, high specific surface area and sufficient Mn3+ active sites, which promote the transfer of electrons and oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that MnO2 doped with N and Ni atoms reduces the reaction overpotential and improves the ORR kinetics. The peak power density and energy density of the Ni/N&#8208;MnO2 air electrode increased by 34.03 mW&#183;cm&#8208;2 and 316.41 mWh&#183;g&#8208;1, respectively. The results show that N and Ni co&#8208;doped MnO2 nanotubes are a promising air electrode, which can provide some ideas for the research of aluminum&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Lizi He, Ning Han, Zhongling Lang, Mei Wang, Y.-W. Wang, Lishuang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valence electronic engineering of hollow-nanocube-structured CoFeNi-layered double hydroxides for highly efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156764</link>
      <description>H. Liu, Lingxing Zan, Yunchuan Tu, Hongling Zhang, Dan Zhu, Zhe Li, Jiawen Zheng, Zhuangzhuang Zhang, Yu Sun, Qihao Weng, Jian Li, Qingbo Wei, Huicong Xia, Xin Bo, Feng Fu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Liu, Lingxing Zan, Yunchuan Tu, Hongling Zhang, Dan Zhu, Zhe Li, Jiawen Zheng, Zhuangzhuang Zhang, Yu Sun, Qihao Weng, Jian Li, Qingbo Wei, Huicong Xia, Xin Bo, Feng Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating metal-oxygen covalency of TiO2 by Ru doping and phase transition for boosted hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177239</link>
      <description>Fengting Li, Nannan Cui, Yanan Zhou, Shuangqing Sun, Chunling Li, Zhikun Wang, Songqing Hu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403741271

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengting Li, Nannan Cui, Yanan Zhou, Shuangqing Sun, Chunling Li, Zhikun Wang, Songqing Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activities of Highly Crystalline Ni&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-LDH (0.20 &#8804; &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; &#8804; 0.51) Synthesized Using Soft Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05347h</link>
      <description>Atsunori Ikezawa, Shinji Koito, Hajime Arai, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403742483

                Developing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is an urgent issue for the practical application of electrochemical devices such as water electrolysers and rechargeable batteries. NiFe-based layered double hydroxides (NiFe-LDH) are...</description>
      <author>Atsunori Ikezawa, Shinji Koito, Hajime Arai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05347h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chirality Engineering of Nanostructured Copper Oxide for Enhancing Oxygen Evolution from Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</link>
      <description>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745745

                Abstract The exploration of a new conceptual strategy for improving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) of earth&#8208;abundant electrocatalysts is critical. In this study, chiral copper oxide nanoflower is explored by a self&#8208;assembly method. The characterization suggests the chiral structure originates from the crystal plane&#8208;level helical stack of the secondary nanosheets. Of note, the assembly illustrates a record&#8208;high degree of spin polarization of 96%, indicating the ideal alignment of electron spin. Moreover, density function theory calculations show the chiral structure reducing the reaction energy barrier (REB) while switching the potential&#8208;determining step from *O&#8594;*OOH to *OH&#8594;*O. Together with the enhanced electrochemical active surface area and accelerated charge transfer, the production of ground&#8208;state triplet O 2 is improved via a spin&#8208;forbidden route that involves the singlet H 2 O/OH&#8226;. Consequently, the chiral nanoflower shows a overpotential of 308 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 93.5 mV dec &#8722;1 , which is even superior to the commercial RuO 2 (310 mV, 101 mV dec &#8722;1 ). This study presents a new strategy for improving the OER activity by simultaneously enhancing electronic properties and lowering the REB of an non&#8208;noble electrocatalyst via chirality engineering.</description>
      <author>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of bifunctional oxygen evolution reaction and oxygen reduction reaction catalyst CoO-TiO2@NG by high gravity-hydrothermal method for rechargeable Zn air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235675</link>
      <description>Qihui Ding, Qi Zhang, Binbin Li, Ding Cai, Wei Wu, Journal of Power Sources. 625(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403752987

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qihui Ding, Qi Zhang, Binbin Li, Ding Cai, Wei Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic Study of Highly Active Bifunctional Double-Atom Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02759</link>
      <description>Wei Zhang, Xueqi Cheng, Xiongyi Liang, Keke Mao, Xiao Cheng Zeng, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757553

                Dual-atom catalysts (DACs) can be very effective for catalyzing both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we present theoretical evidence of a new class of highly active DACs, namely, the double-atom embedded in nitrogen-doped graphene sheet 2M-N-C (M = Mn, Fe) on the basis of density functional theory calculations. Importantly, we find that the double active sites of 2M-N-C DACs entail an unconventional catalytic reaction pathway for ORR and OER. We also show that the local coordination environment of the active sites can significantly affect the stability and oxygen catalytic activity of 2M-N-C DACs. In particular, MnFe-N-C DAC not only exhibits good stability but also possesses outstanding bifunctional ORR/OER catalytic activity with the potential difference (&#916;</description>
      <author>Wei Zhang, Xueqi Cheng, Xiongyi Liang, Keke Mao, Xiao Cheng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02759</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Lattice Oxygen Regeneration of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide Enhances Oxygen Evolution Catalysis Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413250</link>
      <description>Fengyu Wu, Fenyang Tian, Menggang Li, Shuo Geng, Longyu Qiu, Lin He, Lulu Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Yongsheng Yu, Weiwei Yang, Yanglong Hou, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403764296

                The lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) endows NiFe layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH) with superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, yet the frequent evolution and sluggish regeneration of lattice oxygen intensify the dissolution of active species. Herein, we overcome this challenge by constructing the NiFe hydroxide/Ni4Mo alloy (NiFe&#8208;LDH/Ni4Mo) heterojunction electrocatalyst, featuring the Ni4Mo alloy as the oxygen pump to provide oxygenous intermediates and electrons for NiFe&#8208;LDH. The released lattice oxygen can be timely offset by the oxygenous species during the LOM process, balancing the regeneration of lattice oxygen and assuring the enhancement of the durability. In consequence, the durability of NiFe&#8208;LDH is significantly enhanced after the modification of Ni4Mo with an impressively durability for over 60 h, much longer than that of NiFe&#8208;LDH counterpart with only 10 h. In&#8208;situ spectra and first&#8208;principle simulations reveal that the adsorption of OH&#8722; is significantly strengthened owing to the introduction of Ni4Mo, ensuring the rapid regeneration of lattice oxygen. Moreover, NiFe&#8208;LDH/Ni4Mo&#8208;based anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) presents an impressive durability for over 150 h at 100 mA cm&#8722;2. The oxygen pump strategy opens opportunities to balance the evolution and regeneration of lattice oxygen, enhancing the durability of efficient OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Fengyu Wu, Fenyang Tian, Menggang Li, Shuo Geng, Longyu Qiu, Lin He, Lulu Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Yongsheng Yu, Weiwei Yang, Yanglong Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Lattice Oxygen Regeneration of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide Enhances Oxygen Evolution Catalysis Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413250</link>
      <description>Fengyu Wu, Fenyang Tian, Menggang Li, Shuo Geng, Longyu Qiu, Lin He, Lulu Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Yongsheng Yu, Weiwei Yang, Yanglong Hou, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403766152

                The lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) endows NiFe layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH) with superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, yet the frequent evolution and sluggish regeneration of lattice oxygen intensify the dissolution of active species. Herein, we overcome this challenge by constructing the NiFe hydroxide/Ni4Mo alloy (NiFe&#8208;LDH/Ni4Mo) heterojunction electrocatalyst, featuring the Ni4Mo alloy as the oxygen pump to provide oxygenous intermediates and electrons for NiFe&#8208;LDH. The released lattice oxygen can be timely offset by the oxygenous species during the LOM process, balancing the regeneration of lattice oxygen and assuring the enhancement of the durability. In consequence, the durability of NiFe&#8208;LDH is significantly enhanced after the modification of Ni4Mo with an impressively durability for over 60 h, much longer than that of NiFe&#8208;LDH counterpart with only 10 h. In&#8208;situ spectra and first&#8208;principle simulations reveal that the adsorption of OH&#8722; is significantly strengthened owing to the introduction of Ni4Mo, ensuring the rapid regeneration of lattice oxygen. Moreover, NiFe&#8208;LDH/Ni4Mo&#8208;based anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) presents an impressive durability for over 150 h at 100 mA cm&#8722;2. The oxygen pump strategy opens opportunities to balance the evolution and regeneration of lattice oxygen, enhancing the durability of efficient OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Fengyu Wu, Fenyang Tian, Menggang Li, Shuo Geng, Longyu Qiu, Lin He, Lulu Li, Zhaoyu Chen, Yongsheng Yu, Weiwei Yang, Yanglong Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt oxide/cerium oxide heterogeneous interfaces as advanced durable and bifunctional electrocatalysts for robust industrially relevant overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05895j</link>
      <description>Akbar I. Inamdar, Amol S. Salunke, Jun Ho Seok, Harish S. Chavan, Nabeen K. Shrestha, Sang Uck Lee, Sangeun Cho, Hyunsik Im, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403771846

                Non-precious mixed-phase Co oxide and Ce oxide heterostructured electrodes are investigated as bifunctional electrocatalysts for both oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions in an alkaline medium. They are capable to operate at industrial relevant current density.</description>
      <author>Akbar I. Inamdar, Amol S. Salunke, Jun Ho Seok, Harish S. Chavan, Nabeen K. Shrestha, Sang Uck Lee, Sangeun Cho, Hyunsik Im</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05895j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Probing Coupled with Density Functional Theory Calculation to Reveal the Influence of Fe Doping on Fe&#8208;NiOOH Electrode for High Current Density of Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202304260</link>
      <description>Feng Li, Shiyuan Xu, Xueru Zhao, Wei Ma, Zhulin Niu, Xing Zhong, Jing Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776213

                Abstract Fe&#8208;doped NiOOH electrocatalysts have attracted wide interest for the exceptional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, but the precise role of Fe doping on the improved intrinsic activity remains unclear. Herein, the molecular probe technique combined with density functional theory calculation is used to reveal the influence of the Fe atom on the rate&#8208;determining step of the OER reaction, where the pre&#8208;catalyst of hierarchical self&#8208;supporting NiFe layered double hydroxide [LDH] nanosheets equipped on nickel foam (NiFe LDH/NF) is generated via a facile and industrially well&#8208;matched one&#8208;pot corrosion method. The physical characterization results reveal the reconstruction of NiFe LDH into Fe&#8208;doped NiOOH for promoted OER, which has a lower OH* adsorption energy with fast subsequent steps that help in obtaining an improved charge injection efficiency compared to NiOOH. In addition, more exposed electroactive species and facile delivery of mass/electron inside the catalytic procedure actually have a high&#8208;quality contribution to the outstanding catalytic activity. Therefore, the NiFe LDH 36 /NF electrocatalyst provides high catalytic activities of 241 and 320 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 toward the OER and overall water&#8208;splitting in 1 m KOH. This work provides a promising avenue for the rational design of durable self&#8208;supporting electrodes toward large&#8208;scale water splitting.</description>
      <author>Feng Li, Shiyuan Xu, Xueru Zhao, Wei Ma, Zhulin Niu, Xing Zhong, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202304260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Ultrastable Seawater Electrolysis at Industrial Current Density with Strong Metal&#8208;Support Interaction and Dual Cl&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt;&#8208;Repelling Layers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408982</link>
      <description>Dong Liu, Xiaotian Wei, Jianxi Lu, Xin Wang, Lei Zhu, Yaohai Cai, Yingwei Qi, Lei Wang, Haoqiang Ai, Zhen&#8208;Bo Wang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776351

                Abstract Direct seawater electrolysis is emerging as a promising renewable energy technology for large&#8208;scale hydrogen generation. The development of Os&#8208;Ni 4 Mo/MoO 2 micropillar arrays with strong metal&#8208;support interaction (MSI) as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for seawater electrolysis is reported. The micropillar structure enhances electron and mass transfer, extending catalytic reaction steps and improving seawater electrolysis efficiency. Theoretical and experimental studies demonstrate that the strong MSI between Os and Ni 4 Mo/MoO 2 optimizes the surface electronic structure of the catalyst, reducing the reaction barrier and thereby improving catalytic activity. Importantly, for the first time, a dual Cl &#8722; repelling layer is constructed by electrostatic force to safeguard active sites against Cl &#8722; attack during seawater oxidation. This includes a strong Os&#9472;Cl adsorption and an in situ&#8208;formed MoO 4 2&#8722; layer. As a result, the Os&#8208;Ni 4 Mo/MoO 2 catalyst exhibits an ultralow overpotential of 113 and 336 mV to reach 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for HER and OER in natural seawater from the South China Sea (without purification, with 1 m KOH added). Notably, it demonstrates superior stability, degrading only 0.37 &#181;V h &#8722;1 after 2500 h of seawater oxidation, significantly surpassing the technical target of 1.0 &#181;V h &#8722;1 set by the United States Department of Energy.</description>
      <author>Dong Liu, Xiaotian Wei, Jianxi Lu, Xin Wang, Lei Zhu, Yaohai Cai, Yingwei Qi, Lei Wang, Haoqiang Ai, Zhen&#8208;Bo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408982</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a Z-scheme heterojunction of oxygen-deficient WO3-x and g-C3N4 for superior photocatalytic evolution of H2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105346</link>
      <description>Fengyun Su, Mengzhen Tian, Hailong Cao, Zhishuai Wang, Qiang Zhao, Haiquan Xie, Yezhen Zhang, Xiaoli Jin, Xin Li, Zhengdao Li, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengyun Su, Mengzhen Tian, Hailong Cao, Zhishuai Wang, Qiang Zhao, Haiquan Xie, Yezhen Zhang, Xiaoli Jin, Xin Li, Zhengdao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Back Cover: Rationalizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction over IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Essential Role of Hydronium Cation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418265</link>
      <description>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Jingguang G. Chen, Ping Liu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403777461

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Jingguang G. Chen, Ping Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside Back Cover: Rationalizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction over IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;: Essential Role of Hydronium Cation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418265</link>
      <description>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Jingguang G. Chen, Ping Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403777477

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianyou Mou, Daniela A. Bushiri, Daniel V. Esposito, Jingguang G. Chen, Ping Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long&#8208;Term Selective Photoelectrochemical Glycerol Oxidation via Oxygen Vacancy Modulated Tungsten Oxide with Self&#8208;Healing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409082</link>
      <description>Yoonsung Jung, Seung&#8208;Hwan Kim, Seung&#8208;Kyu Kim, Yejoon Kim, Jun Beom Hwang, Dong&#8208;Yu Kim, Sanghan Lee, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403778140

                Abstract The photoelectrochemical selective oxidation of biowaste glycerol into the high value&#8208;added material, along with hydrogen production, holds significant promise for advancing renewable and sustainable energy technologies. Here, the surface oxygen state of tungsten oxide is modified to selectively oxidize glycerol into glyceraldehyde, a high&#8208;value&#8208;added material, and the selectivity is maintained over a prolonged period using the photo&#8208;stimulated self&#8208;recovery capability. The surface&#8208;coordinated photoelectrode exhibits high charge transfer efficiency to glycerol and favorable glycerol adsorption capacity, enabling the selective conversion of glycerol. At 1.2 V RHE in a 2 m glycerol electrolyte adjusted to pH 2, the tungsten oxide photoelectrode achieves a photocurrent density of 2.58 mA cm &#8722;2 and a production rate of 378.8 mmol m &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 with selectivity of 86.1%. The high selectivity is preserved for 18 h by utilizing the self&#8208;healing capability of tungsten oxide to restore initial states modified by photoelectrochemical oxidation. This work sheds light on the design of highly efficient metal oxide photoelectrodes for selective biomass oxidation over extended periods.</description>
      <author>Yoonsung Jung, Seung&#8208;Hwan Kim, Seung&#8208;Kyu Kim, Yejoon Kim, Jun Beom Hwang, Dong&#8208;Yu Kim, Sanghan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo Bimetallic ZIF Derivatives decorated with CoFe&#8208;LDH to Promote Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401556</link>
      <description>Feng Zhang, Yu Lei, Guang Li, Yi Xie, Jiaxin Guo, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xianyou Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779574

                Reasonably screening the targeted oxygen reduction reaction (ORR)/oxygen evolution reaction (OER) constituents and constructing high&#8208;efficiency and stabilized ORR/OER bifunctional electrocatalysts are pivotal for the advancement of rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). Here, CoFe layered double hydroxide (CoFe&#8208;LDH) nanosheets are deposited on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphite&#8208;carbon polyhedra with FeCo alloy nanoparticles (FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP). Due to the synergic effect between FeCo&#8208;NGCP, CoFe&#8208;LDH and FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP, the electrocatalyst with the abundant and accessible active sites can provide good charge/mass transfer, and thus shows wonderful ORR and OER bifunctional electrocatalytic performance. In ORR tests, FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP catalyst displays larger half&#8208;wave potential (E1/2, 0.89 V vs. 0.85 V), higher limiting current density (JL, 5.91 mA/cm2 vs. 5.14 mA/cm2) and better stability than commercial Pt/C. As for OER, FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP possesses a smaller overpotential (&#951;) of 299.6 mV at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and more durable stability than commercial RuO2 (330.6 mV). Furthermore, in ZAB tests, the cycling stability of ZAB&#8208;FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP (over 470 h) outperforms the ZAB&#8208;Pt/C+RuO2 (92 h) with commercial electrocatalyst (Pt/C+RuO2). Therefore, the FeCo/LDH&#8208;NGCP catalyst offers a new perspective to construct ZABs bifunctional catalysts and their commercial application in ZABs.</description>
      <author>Feng Zhang, Yu Lei, Guang Li, Yi Xie, Jiaxin Guo, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xianyou Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A&#8208;site Regulated (PrBa)xCo1.5Fe0.5O6&#8208;&#948; Double Perovskite Oxides: Highly Active and Durable Electrocatalysts for the Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401236</link>
      <description>Changjing Fu, Shibo Ma, Huizhu Xu, Weiling Zhao, Xuedong Xie, Tiantian Cang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779917

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) represents a significant bottleneck in many energy technologies such as electrochemical water splitting, metal&#8208;oxygen (O) batteries, and solid oxide fuel cells (SOFCs), because of the complexity of the reaction process. Double perovskite oxides (ABO3), recognized for their compositional flexibility, have emerged as excellent OER activity and stability. This study investigates the catalytic potential of B&#8208;site ordered double ABO3 with (PrBa)xCo1.5Fe0.5O6&#8208;&#948; (PBCF&#8208;x, x=0.9&#8208;1.1) in alkaline media. The results reveal that PBCF&#8208;0.9, characterized by an A&#8208;site deficient composition, exhibits exceptional OER activity. It demonstrates a low Tafel slope of 76.12 mV&#8901;dec&#8208;1 and a low overpotential (&#951;) of 270 mV at 10 mA&#8901;cm&#8208;2. Notably, the intrinsic OER activity of PBCF&#8208;0.9 is 25% higher than that of the stoichiometric PBCF&#8208;1.0. Additionally, PBCF&#8208;0.9 exhibits remarkable durability, as evidenced by its stable performance during a 6&#8208;hour chronopotentiometry (CP) test and minimal microstructural changes. These results underscore the effectiveness of A&#8208;site deficiency in optimizing the structure of double ABO3 for improved OER performance. This approach presents a promising strategy for designing highly efficient, stable, and inexpensive catalysts for energy&#8208;related applications.</description>
      <author>Changjing Fu, Shibo Ma, Huizhu Xu, Weiling Zhao, Xuedong Xie, Tiantian Cang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homologous Metal-Organic Complexes Reconstructed Oxy-Hydroxide Heterostructures as Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5000343</link>
      <description>Yuting Chen, Haikuo Lan, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Kang Liu, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Yuchen Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403783175

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuting Chen, Haikuo Lan, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Kang Liu, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Yuchen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5000343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-Etched Silver Electrodes Loaded with Iron/Cobalt Catalysts for Enhanced Plasmon-Induced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5000473</link>
      <description>Jian Wu, Zhichen dong, Yimin Niu, Xuguang Chen, Yuchuan Cheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403784494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Wu, Zhichen dong, Yimin Niu, Xuguang Chen, Yuchuan Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5000473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of agroindustry residues for their usage as oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114527</link>
      <description>Aida M. D&#237;ez, Mar&#237;a Bola&#241;os-V&#225;zquez, S. Chiussi, Marta Pazos, M.&#193;. Sanrom&#225;n, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403626228

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aida M. D&#237;ez, Mar&#237;a Bola&#241;os-V&#225;zquez, S. Chiussi, Marta Pazos, M.&#193;. Sanrom&#225;n</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and Activity of Organometallic Phthalocyanine Sheets for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999676</link>
      <description>Walter Orellana, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403757695

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Walter Orellana</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4999676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing electronic structure modulation strategies toward the development of low&#8208;cost oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elt2.65</link>
      <description>Zhen Zhang, Shaobo Han, Li Cheng, Chao Cai, Meng Gu, Electron. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779894

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reactions (OER) are critical to electrochemical synthesis reactions, including hydrogen production and organic hydrogenation. However, the high cost of existing OER catalysts (primarily Ir/Ru and its derived oxides) limits their practical application for electrochemical synthesis. To develop a low&#8208;cost, high&#8208;efficiency alternative, we need a deeper understanding of both the mechanisms that drive OER and the relationship between the catalyst's electronic structure and active sites. Here, we summarized recent developments of catalysts, especially focusing on the electronic structure modulation strategies and their subsequent activity enhancement. Most importantly, we pointed out the study directions for further work.</description>
      <author>Zhen Zhang, Shaobo Han, Li Cheng, Chao Cai, Meng Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elt2.65</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Progress in Non&#8208;Noble Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Focus on Transition and Rare&#8208;Earth Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400151</link>
      <description>Jala Bib Khan, Yuan&#8208;Chang Liang, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403792218

                Abstract The demand for renewable energy sources has become more urgent due to climate change and environmental pollution. The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role in green energy sources. This article primarily explores the potential of using non&#8208;noble metals, such as transition and rare earth metals, to enhance the efficiency of the OER process. Due to their cost&#8208;effectiveness and unique electronic structure, these non&#8208;noble metals could be a game&#8208;changer in the field. &#8242;Doping,&#8242; which is the process of adding a small amount of impurity to a material to alter its properties, and &#8242;synergistic effects,&#8242; which refer to the combined effect of two or more elements that is greater than the sum of their individual effects, are two key concepts in this field. Transition and rare earth metals can reduce the overpotential, a measure of the excess potential required to drive a reaction, thus enhancing the OER process by engineering the electronic and surface molecular structure. This article summarizes the roles of various non&#8208;noble metals in the OER process and highlights opportunities for researchers to propose innovative ways to optimize the OER process.</description>
      <author>Jala Bib Khan, Yuan&#8208;Chang Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Spin Channels in SrCoO3 through Triagonal&#8208;to&#8208;Cubic Structural Transformation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415797</link>
      <description>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403627665

                Oxygen evolution and reduction reactions (OER and ORR) play crucial roles in energy conversion processes such as water splitting and air batteries, where spin dynamics inherently influence their efficiency. However, the specific contribution of spin has yet to be fully understood. In this study, we intentionally introduce a spin channel through the transformation of trigonal antiferromagnetic SrCoO2.5 into cubic ferromagnetic SrCoO3, aiming to deepen our understanding of spin dynamics in catalytic reactions. Based on the results from spherical&#8208;aberration&#8208;corrected microscope, synchrotron absorption spectra, magnetic characterizations, and density functional theory calculations, it is revealed that surface electron transfer is predominantly governed by local geometric structures, while the presence of the spin channel significantly enhances the bulk transport of spin&#8208;polarized electrons, particularly under high current densities where surface electron transfer is no longer the limiting factor. The overpotential for OER is reduced by at least 70 mV at 150 mA cm&#8208;2 due to the enhanced conductivity from spin&#8208;polarized electrons facilitated by spin channels, with an expectation of even more significant reductions at higher current densities. This work provides a clearer picture of the role of spin in oxygen&#8208;involved electrocatalysis, providing critical insights for the design of more efficient catalytic systems in practical applications.</description>
      <author>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-Covalent Coupling of Carbon Nitrides and Dyes for Selective and Sensitive Electrochemiluminescent Detection of Local H+ in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l831h</link>
      <description>Yu Wang, Zhou Sijia, Yunying Zhen, Yongji Wang, Y.H. Hou, Kaiqing Wu, Chaofeng Huang, Songqin Liu, Yanfei Shen, Ran Chen, Yuanjian Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776137

                An accurate understanding of the mechanism of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for the design of efficient catalysts and the development of hydrogen energy. Despite significant advancements in microscopic pH detection studies through the use of mainstream strategies, such as scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM), rotating ring-disc electrode (RRDE), and spectroscopic techniques, selective and sensitive detection of the change of proton (H+) concentration near the vicinity of the electrode during OER with high temporal resolution remains elusive. In this study, we pioneered the creation of an efficient hybrid electrochemiluminescence-based (ECL-based) pH sensor that enables the detection of H+ in the vicinity of the electrodes during OER. A new class of luminophore based on ECL resonance energy transfer (ECL-RET) was theoretically predicted and further synthesized by grafting fluorescent dyes onto carbon nitride nanosheets (CN) through non-covalent interaction. We present that one of the newly synthesized emitters, CN-FITC, is capable of detecting proton with fast response time, where the ECL intensity of CN-FITC is regulated by proton concentration. By coating this emitter onto an electrode positioned near OER catalysts, proton generation near the vicinity of the catalysts could be qualitatively detected, providing details of the reaction mechanism of OER and unveiling the catalyst degrading pathway caused by proton accumulation. Additionally, the average proton generation rate on the catalyst was extracted from the local pH measurement, leading to a quantitative descriptor of the OER reaction rate. Owing to the high designability of the dye, this study opens up a new strategy for the detection of more reaction intermediates.</description>
      <author>Yu Wang, Zhou Sijia, Yunying Zhen, Yongji Wang, Y.H. Hou, Kaiqing Wu, Chaofeng Huang, Songqin Liu, Yanfei Shen, Ran Chen, Yuanjian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l831h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Entropy Metallic-High Entropy Nonmetallic Community as High Performance Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc05326e</link>
      <description>Chunyan Zhang, Hang Li, Mengfei Su, Shengfa Li, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403607529

                The multi-element synergism in high-entropy materials (HEMs) provides great opportunities to promote the tandem reaction or meet the requirement of multi-functional catalysts. Herein, a high entropy precursor strategy is proposed...</description>
      <author>Chunyan Zhang, Hang Li, Mengfei Su, Shengfa Li, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc05326e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Oxygen Evolution Performance by Introducing Pd-Cu Alloy Supported Rod-Like Hollow Titanium Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4995223</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Mingying Zhao, Lei E, Dan Zhao, Chengyi Wang, Zhifeng Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403659770

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Mingying Zhao, Lei E, Dan Zhao, Chengyi Wang, Zhifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4995223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of High-Valence Metal Dissolution in Oxygen Evolution Kinetics of the Advanced FeNiO&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04454</link>
      <description>Jun Ke, Jiaxi Zhang, Longhai Zhang, Shunyi He, Chengzhi Zhong, Li Du, Jiajun Huang, Xiaoming Fang, Zhengguo Zhang, Zhiming Cui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403624235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Ke, Jiaxi Zhang, Longhai Zhang, Shunyi He, Chengzhi Zhong, Li Du, Jiajun Huang, Xiaoming Fang, Zhengguo Zhang, Zhiming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur Doping and Heterostructure on Nise@Co(Oh)2 with Facilitated Surface Reconstruction and Interfacial Electron Regulation to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994506</link>
      <description>Fei Nie, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Xiaodan Chong, Xiaoping Dai, Yikai Yang, Jinsheng Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600648

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Nie, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Xiaodan Chong, Xiaoping Dai, Yikai Yang, Jinsheng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-doped carbon decorated by Cu3P nanoparticle derived from Aspartic acid - Cu MOF as suitable catalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.261</link>
      <description>Elham Soltani, Mohammad Bagher Gholivand, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403655663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elham Soltani, Mohammad Bagher Gholivand</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reaction Activity of Transition Metal-Doped T-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Monolayer: A Density Functional Theory Study Assisted by Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04467</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Lin Ju, Zhenjie Tang, Shu Zhang, Genqiang Zhang, Wentao Wang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403674764

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Lin Ju, Zhenjie Tang, Shu Zhang, Genqiang Zhang, Wentao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superior electrocatalytic performance of nitrogen-doped carbon-embeded Ni/NiO/NiB nanocrystals for urea oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03424d</link>
      <description>Xiaofei Zhao, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403764167

                Electrocatalytic urea oxidation reaction (UOR) can serve as an alternative to the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water splitting. Therefore, to improve the kinetics of UOR, it is of...</description>
      <author>Xiaofei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03424d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A theoretical investigation on the OER and ORR activity of graphene-based TM-N3 and TM-N2X (X=B, C, O, P) single atom catalysts by density functional theory calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03779k</link>
      <description>Jiaxiang Wu, Erjun Kan, Cheng Zhan, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403772462

                Single-atom catalysts (SAC) have shown promising activity in electrocatalysis, such as CO2 reduction (CO2RR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Transition metal-embedded N-doped graphene (M-N-C) with TM-N4...</description>
      <author>Jiaxiang Wu, Erjun Kan, Cheng Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03779k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering high-valence nickel sites in Ni3S2/Ni3Se2 architectures enabling urea-assisted hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc04318a</link>
      <description>AI Tao-tao, Miaomiao Bai, Weiwei Bao, Jie Han, Xue-Ling Wei, Xiangyu Zou, Jungang Hou, Lizhai Zhang, Zhifeng Deng, Yuxin Zhang, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403753780

                A more thermodynamically favorable organic oxidation reaction should be used instead of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to avoid high power consumption. Implementing this technology requires the development of stable, highly...</description>
      <author>AI Tao-tao, Miaomiao Bai, Weiwei Bao, Jie Han, Xue-Ling Wei, Xiangyu Zou, Jungang Hou, Lizhai Zhang, Zhifeng Deng, Yuxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc04318a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Electrocatalytic Activity of Bifunctional Iron&#8208;Niobium Double Perovskites for Overall Water Splitting: A&#8208;Site Cation Influence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400559</link>
      <description>Celal Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Maged F. Bekheet, Suna Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Figen Kaya, Byung Chul Kim, Cengiz Kaya, Aleksander Gurlo, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403699860

                Abstract Capitalizing on the electrochemical conversion of water into hydrogen stands as a pivotal strategy in the global transition toward sustainable energy sources. This study investigates the influence of the A&#8208;site cation type within A 2 FeNbO 6 double perovskites (where A = Ca, Sr, or Ba) on their bifunctional electrocatalytic activities. The electrocatalytic performance is scrutinized in relation to charge transfer resistance, oxygen vacancy concentration, and metal&#8208;oxygen covalency. Among the variants, Sr 2 FeNbO 6 is distinguished as the optimal catalyst, achieving a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 at overpotentials of 260 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and 176 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), thus matching the performance of leading metal oxide electrocatalysts. The study reveals pH&#8208;dependent kinetics for Sr 2 FeNbO 6 , indicative of a lattice oxygen evolution mechanism for OER. An electrolyzer employing Sr 2 FeNbO 6 electrodes for both the anode and cathode delivers a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 at an efficient cell voltage of 1.76 V for complete alkaline water splitting, while also demonstrating exceptional stability. These insights advance the understanding of material optimization for electrocatalysis and position Sr 2 FeNbO 6 as a viable catalyst for the sustainable production of hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Celal Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Maged F. Bekheet, Suna Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Figen Kaya, Byung Chul Kim, Cengiz Kaya, Aleksander Gurlo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir Doping Modulates the Electronic Structure of Flower-Shaped Phosphides for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</link>
      <description>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633322

                Electrolysis of water to produce hydrogen is an efficient, clean, and environmentally friendly hydrogen production method with unlimited development prospects. However, its overall efficiency is hampered by the slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with complex electron transfer processes. Therefore, designing efficient and low-cost OER catalysts is the key to solving this problem. In this paper, Ir-doped Co</description>
      <author>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1 min synthesis of phase-pure nanocrystalline high-entropy sulphides for efficient water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-n5r4n</link>
      <description>Judith Zander, Roland Marschall, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403774326

                The development of noble-metal free electrocatalysts with low production cost is of utmost importance for sustainable water electrolysis. Herein, we present a fast, flexible synthesis pathway for the preparation of a variety of different medium- and high-entropy spinel sulphides of various compositions, using a non-aqueous microwave-assisted synthesis without any H2S. Nanoparticulate high-entropy sulphides containing up to 8 different metal cations can be obtained after an extremely short synthesis time of only 1 min and comparatively low temperatures of 200-230 &#176;C. We further demonstrate the high activity of the obtained sulphides for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Judith Zander, Roland Marschall</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-n5r4n</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis of Metal/Carbide Hybrid toward Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100730</link>
      <description>Jinpeng Mo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403601518

                The development of cost-effective and high-performance bifunctional catalysts for overall water splitting is crucial for achieving sustainable clean energy. In this study, a metal/carbide hybrid (NiFeMo/NiFeMoCx) was prepared through fast and facile cathodic plasma electrolytic deposition. Due to the synergistic effect between the metal and carbide, NiFeMo/NiFeMoCx exhibited high activity in both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), with overpotentials of 230 mV and 60 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. In addition, robust stability was demonstrated during the overall water splitting (1.52 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, with little degradation after 18 h of catalysis). This work provides a useful strategy for designing advanced water splitting catalysts for real application.</description>
      <author>Jinpeng Mo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Co(II) Isostructural Bifunctional MOFs via Mixed-Ligand Strategy: Syntheses, Crystal Structure, Photocatalytic Degradation of Dyes, and Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29214989</link>
      <description>Si&#8208;Yu Yue, Meng&#8208;Qi Tuo, Yemeng Sheng, Xinyu Guo, Jiu-Fu Lu, Dong Wang, Molecules. 29(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403649818

                The solvothermal reactions involving cobalt ions with 5-methylisophthalic acid (H2MIP) and 1,3-bis(2-methylimidazol)propane (BMIP) yielded two cobalt(II) organic frameworks: {[Co4(MIP)4(BMIP)3]&#183;1/2DMA}n (SNUT-31) and {[Co4(MIP)4(BMIP)3]&#183;(EtOH)2&#183;H2O]}n (SNUT-32) where DMA represents N,N-dimethylacetamide and EtOH signifies ethyl alcohol. Single-crystal X-ray diffraction analyses reveal that SNUT-31 and SNUT-32 possess an isomorphic structure, featuring a unique 2-fold interpenetration of 3D frameworks in a parallel manner. Notably, both SNUT-31 and SNUT-32 demonstrate remarkable performance in electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions and exhibit exceptional photocatalytic degradation capabilities against a model comprising three distinct dyes: rhodamine B, methyl orange, and methyl blue.</description>
      <author>Si&#8208;Yu Yue, Meng&#8208;Qi Tuo, Yemeng Sheng, Xinyu Guo, Jiu-Fu Lu, Dong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29214989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Modulation of RuCo Catalysts on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanotubes Promoting Durable Acidic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</link>
      <description>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745765

                Abstract The development of efficient and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts is essential for hydrogen production from acidic water splitting. Herein, a TiO 2 nanotube&#8208;loaded Co&#8208;doped Ru nanoparticle catalyst (RuCo/TiO 2 NTs) is reported that exhibits excellent activity and stability toward acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The Ru&#9472;O&#9472;Ti bonding is enhanced by Co doping, and the metal carrier interaction between Ru nanoparticles and TiO 2 NTs is enhanced, which effectively stabilizes Ru species during OER and initiates hydrogen spillover accelerating HER kinetics. As a result, RuCo/TiO 2 NTs catalyst requires only 156 mV OER overpotential and 17 mV HER overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a stability more than 500 h in acidic conditions. More importantly, benefiting from the excellent bifunctional activities, the proton exchange membrane electrolyte assembled from RuCo/TiO 2 NTs has excellent activity and robust stability (1000 h). This work opens a new avenue for the efficient energy conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering Induced by Low Ru Doping in Ni/Co@NC Derived from Ni-ZIF-67 for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13769</link>
      <description>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Fahim A. Qaraah, Samah A. Mahyoub, Anas A. Ahmed, Q.A. Drmosh, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403666057

                Electrochemical water splitting is a promising approach for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER); however, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a major bottleneck due to its high energy requirements. High-performance electrocatalysts capable of facilitating HER, OER, and overall water splitting (OWS) are highly needed to improve OER kinetics. In this work, we synthesized a trimetallic heterostructure of Ru, Ni, and Co incorporated into N-doped carbon (denoted as Ru/Ni/Co@NC) by first synthesizing Ni/Co@NC from Ni-ZIF-67 polyhedrons via high-temperature carbonization, followed by Ru doping using the galvanic replacement method. Benefiting from increased active surface sites, modulated electronic structure, and enhanced interfacial synergistic effects, Ru/Ni/Co@NC exhibited exceptional electrocatalytic performance for both HER and OER processes. The optimized Ru/Ni/Co@NC catalyst, with a minimal Ru mass ratio of &#8764;2.07%, demonstrated significantly low overpotential values of 34 mV for HER and 174 mV for OER at a current density of 10 mA/cm</description>
      <author>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Fahim A. Qaraah, Samah A. Mahyoub, Anas A. Ahmed, Q.A. Drmosh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface and doping engineering of V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C&#8208;MXene&#8208;based electrocatalysts for enhanced electrocatalysis of overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.583</link>
      <description>Yousen Wu, Jinlong Li, Guozhe Sui, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Yue Li, Dongxuan Guo, Dawei Chu, Kun Liang, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403694082

                Abstract The restacking and oxidizable nature of vanadium&#8208;based carbon/nitride (V 2 C&#8208;MXene) poses a significant challenge. Herein, tellurium (Te)&#8208;doped V 2 C/V 2 O 3 electrocatalyst is constructed via mild H 2 O 2 oxidation and calcination treatments. Especially, this work rationally exploits the inherent easy oxidation characteristic associated with MXene to alter the interfacial information, thereby obtaining stable self&#8208;generated vanadium&#8208;based heterointerfaces. Meanwhile, the microetching effect of H 2 O 2 creates numerous pores to address the restacking issues. Besides, Te element doping settles the issue of awkward levels of absorption/desorption ability of intermediates. The electrocatalyst obtains an unparalleled hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction with the overpotential of 83.5 and 279.8 mV at &#8722;10 and 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. In addition, the overall water&#8208;splitting device demonstrates a low cell voltage of 1.41 V to obtain 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Overall, the inherent drawbacks of MXene can be turned into benefits based on the planning strategy to create these electrocatalysts with desirable reaction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Yousen Wu, Jinlong Li, Guozhe Sui, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Yue Li, Dongxuan Guo, Dawei Chu, Kun Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Threefold Impact on Reaction Coordinate Mapping of Zirconium Based Tri&#8208;Chalcogenide Pseudo&#8208;Monolayers as Emerging Ultrathin Catalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400816</link>
      <description>Ponnappa Kechanda Prasanna, Sudip Chakraborty, Advanced Theory and Simulations. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403782112

                Abstract The continuous quest of finding optimum catalysts for photo&#8208;electrocatalytic (PEC) water splitting has been revolving around 2D ultrathin materials because of the fact of exploiting both the surface area. In this work, a threefold impact is envisaged route to enhance the activity both in terms of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in the emerging Zirconium Tri&#8208;sulfides (ZrS 3 ) based pseudo&#8208;monolayers. Due to the unique and distinct electronic properties of the tri&#8208;chalcogenide systems as compared to the di&#8208;chalcogenide counterpart of Zirconium, one could afford to explore the implications of not only single&#8208;atom functionalization and vacancy defect, but also the external strain to expedite the bifunctional catalytic activity in this promising material. Rigorous electronic structure calculations have been performed for the mentioned threefold effect on not only the band&#8208;edge alignment, but going beyond to it by further constructing the reaction coordinate mapping corresponding to HER and OER mechanism. The repercussion of external strain in addition to the single atom functionalization and vacancy defect on the adsorption free energies of the prime intermediates of HER and OER reaction has been further correlated with the work function variation in this pseudo&#8208;monolayer system.</description>
      <author>Ponnappa Kechanda Prasanna, Sudip Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adts.202400816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene&#8208;Transition Metal Electrocatalysts for Sustainable Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403155</link>
      <description>Prerna Tripathi, Amit Verma, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, Shikha Singh, ChemistrySelect. 9(40)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403650622

                Abstract Transition metal compounds (TMCs) are potentially fruitful substitutes for noble metals for electrocatalytic splitting of water due to their intrinsic electrocatalytic activity, modifiable morphology, tunable electronic structure and their earth&#8208;abundance. The combination of TMCs with graphene improves the dispersion of loaded catalysts, providing more catalytic active sites, enhancing the conductivity of hybrids, affording accelerated charge&#8208;transfer kinetics, and minimizing catalyst bleaching, aggregation, and sintering under harsh reaction conditions. Additionally, graphene incorporation into TMCs modulates the electronic structure of active centers because of the synergistic interaction between them, thereby improving their catalytic performance. This review paper focuses on the recent progress made in designing different graphene&#8208;transition metal&#8208;based materials that can be used in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and overall water splitting (OWS). In&#8208;situ characterization methodologies and DFT calculations that facilitate catalyst development are discussed elaborately. Finally, the advancements made in the development of graphene&#8208;supported transition metal compounds for use in a functional water electrolyzer have been explored. In conclusion, a few specific recommendations have been made about the current challenges related to the widespread production of effective HER/OER electrocatalysts for water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Prerna Tripathi, Amit Verma, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, Shikha Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Synthetic NiCoP Nanoparticles Encapsulated in N-Doped Carbon for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04798</link>
      <description>Xin Ye, Haodong Zhang, Fan Wu, He Ma, Shaoyang Wu, Xiangqun Zhuge, Yurong Ren, Wei Peng, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403705252

                Transition metal phosphides (TMPs) have drawn widespread attention as promising electrocatalysts due to their special electronic structure, good electrochemical activity, low cost, and high abundance. Although a great deal of effort has been expended in the pursuit of TMPs, the majority of synthesis processes are complex and hazardous due to the use of flammable and toxic phosphorus sources. Herein, we propose a nontoxic and scalable synthetic strategy for the synthesis of NiCoP@NC by using green and cheap diethylenetriaminepentakis (methylphosphonic acid) (DTPMP) as the phosphorus source. DTPMP can also act as a chelating agent and displays strong coordination ability with metal ions, thereby reducing particle size and forming nanoparticles. The NiCoP@NC exhibits outstanding stability and electrocatalytic activity in both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Furthermore, water electrolysis performance also is measured using NiCoP@NC as both anode and cathode, which delivers a cell voltage of 1.73 V at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 and can operate stably for 24 h. This work not only constructs efficient bifunctional catalysts, but also broadens the green synthesis method of nanosized TMPs, paving the way for further large-scale practical applications.</description>
      <author>Xin Ye, Haodong Zhang, Fan Wu, He Ma, Shaoyang Wu, Xiangqun Zhuge, Yurong Ren, Wei Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectonics of Nickel Nitride&#8208;V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CT&lt;sub&gt;X&lt;/sub&gt; Mxene: An Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Alkaline Water/Seawater Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400656</link>
      <description>Deepak Deepak, Tanuja Singh, Abhinav Mahapatra, Abhishek Panghal, C.H.R.V.S. Nagesh, Susanta Sinha Roy, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403690186

                Abstract Seawater, being the most plentiful natural water source worldwide, is a highly abundant and cost&#8208;efficient medium for producing hydrogen by alkaline water electrolysis. However, the advancement of seawater electrolysis is hindered by notable impediments caused by chloride corrosion at the anode and the simultaneous chlorine evolution process. Only a limited number of non&#8208;noble electrocatalysts demonstrate noteworthy bifunctional catalytic efficacy and long&#8208;term durability. In this regard, Nickel Nitride tailored V 2 CT X Mxene nanostructures is reported as a bifunctional catalyst for overall water/seawater applications. The optimized sample Ni 3 N@3000&#8208;V 2 CT x exhibits low overpotential values of 90 and 300 mV in acidic and alkaline + seawater solutions respectively at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction. Similarly, this catalyst shows 70 and 240 mV overpotential values in alkaline water and alkaline + seawater solutions respectively at the same current density for oxygen evolution reaction. Synergetic effects of Multiple Vanadium and Nickel valency along with compelling nitrogen bonds creates elevated density of exposed functional sites for electrocatalytic activity. Furthermore, the notable electrochemical active surface area and mass activity suggest an enhanced and significant presence of abundant active sites. Additionally, the high stability and significantly decreased charge transfer resistance expedited the overall water/seawater&#8208;splitting reaction rate.</description>
      <author>Deepak Deepak, Tanuja Singh, Abhinav Mahapatra, Abhishek Panghal, C.H.R.V.S. Nagesh, Susanta Sinha Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal nanomaterial-based electrocatalysts for water and CO2 electrolysis: preparation, catalytic activity, and prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1433103</link>
      <description>Govindhan Maduraiveeran, Frontiers in Energy Research. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745372

                The production of hydrogen (H 2 ) and multi-carbon fuels through water electrolysis (oxygen evolution reaction (OER)/hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)) and water&#8211;CO 2 co-electrolysis (OER/CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR)), respectively, is supposed to be the emergent energy carrier. These electrochemical processes are essential chemical conversion pathways that initiate the changes toward production of renewable energy. This review summarizes the systematic design of earth-abundant transition metal-based nanomaterials and their electrocatalytic activities toward electrochemical energy conversion reactions such as OER, HER, and CO 2 RR. The primary focus is on fabricating highly effective, low-cost, and advanced transition metal-based nanostructures for both the OER/HER and OER/CO 2 RR systems. Developing synthetic strategies for surface morphology-controlled nanostructured electrocatalysts, engineering the electrode surface, enhancing the electrocatalytic activity, understanding the relationship between intrinsic catalytic activity and preparation approaches or precursor choices, and exploring the reaction mechanism are focused on. Furthermore, the current challenges, figure-of-merit, and prospects of transition metal-based nanomaterials and their electrocatalytic activities toward water electrolysis and water&#8211;CO 2 co-electrolysis are described. This study may open new opportunities to develop shape-controlled and high-performance electrocatalysts for electrochemical energy conversion and storage reactions.</description>
      <author>Govindhan Maduraiveeran</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1433103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and Electrochemical Characterization of Ru-Modified Iridium Oxide Catalysts for PEM Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/appliedchem4040022</link>
      <description>Stanford Chidziva, Dorcas Zide, Joshua John Bambo, Anele Sinto, Sivakumar Pasupathi, Bernard Jan Bladergroen, AppliedChem. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403732683

                In the search of sustainable energy solutions, proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs) have emerged as a promising alternative for sustainable clean hydrogen production. This study focuses on synthesis and characterization of Ruthenium (Ru)-modified iridium oxide (IrO2) catalysts. The anode is the principal reason for the high overpotential of PEMWEs and it also greatly increases the cost of the electrolyzers. IrO2 is highly stable and corrosion-resistant, particularly in acidic environments, making it a durable catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in PEMWEs, though it suffers from a relatively high overpotential. Ruthenium oxide (RuO2), on the other hand, is more catalytically active with a lower overpotential, but is less stable under the same conditions. In this study, the goal was to improve the catalytic activity and stability of the anode catalyst, IrO2, through the controlled incorporation of Ru and to reduce overall catalyst cost due to the reduced iridium content. This synergistic combination allows for better performance in terms of conductivity, efficiency, and durability, making Ru-modified IrO2 an ideal catalyst for OER in PEMWE applications. The Adams fusion method was adapted and used to synthesize the catalysts. The modified catalysts were characterized using analytical instruments. These analyses provided insights into the structural, morphological, and electrochemical properties of the Ru-modified IrO2 catalysts.</description>
      <author>Stanford Chidziva, Dorcas Zide, Joshua John Bambo, Anele Sinto, Sivakumar Pasupathi, Bernard Jan Bladergroen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/appliedchem4040022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Transfer by Mechanical Alloying and Electrocatalytic Performance of the As&#8208;Sintered Self&#8208;Supported High&#8208;Entropy Alloy FeNiCoCuMo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202400807</link>
      <description>Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, P. M&#225;rt&#237;n, E. P&#237;o, Jorg&#233; Pavez, Claudio Aguilar, C. Suryanarayana, Maritza P&#225;ez, Advanced Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403609811

                Efficient, stable, and cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are essential for clean energy generation through water splitting. This study presents a FeNiCoCuMo high&#8208;entropy alloy (HEA) synthesized via mechanical alloying (MA) and sintering using hot&#8208;pressing. The energy transfer from the milling process influences phase transformations, with the High&#8208;Entropy Alloys Prediction Software (HEAPS) predicting the formation of an FCC phase. X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD) and scanning electron microscopy reveal an FCC phase after 150 h of milling, with no elemental segregation observed. The Burgio kinetic model estimates 448 kJ mol &#8722;1 is needed to achieve a 99% FCC phase. The crystallite size is 4 nm, with a lattice parameter of 0.371 nm. The as&#8208;milled phases were preserved during hot&#8208;pressing sintering. Electrodes (M1, M2, M3) fabricated from the HEA demonstrated high electrocatalytic efficiency, with an average overpotential of 380 mV and Tafel slope of 77 mV dec &#8722;1 . At a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , the electrodes maintained operation for up to 100 h. The synergy between constituent elements is key to the superior electrocatalytic performance of FeNiCoCuMo HEAs, demonstrating their potential as promising materials for OER electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, P. M&#225;rt&#237;n, E. P&#237;o, Jorg&#233; Pavez, Claudio Aguilar, C. Suryanarayana, Maritza P&#225;ez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202400807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Iron Oxide Electrocatalysis for Efficient Overall Water Splitting: A Study of Tailored Synthesis for Advanced Energy Generation and Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/est2.70062</link>
      <description>N. Maley, Pratik Patel, Felipe M. de Souza, Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta, Energy Storage. 6(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403755619

                ABSTRACT Water splitting, a critical milestone in the development of renewable energy, allows the production of pure hydrogen and oxygen. Iron oxide (Fe 2 O 3 ), a fundamental component in electrochemical water splitting for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), offers potential because of its accessibility, low cost, and environmental safety. Herein, to analyze the impact of the methodology on its properties, Fe 2 O 3 was produced in three different ways: freeze&#8208;drying (aerogel) (Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;AG), hydrothermal (Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;HT), and microwave (Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;MW). The Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;AG outperformed Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;HT and Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;MW in most properties which showed improved current and overall water&#8208;splitting efficiency. The resulting materials demonstrated good electrocatalytic performance for both HER and OER in alkaline media, with overpotentials for HER of 204, 235, and 255 mV and overpotentials for OER of 222, 288, and 292 mV for the Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;AG, Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;HT, and Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;MW samples, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA/cm 2 . The freeze&#8208;drying synthesis process has significant potential as a feasible method for the manufacture of Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;based electrocatalysts for water&#8208;splitting applications. This study provides important insights into the influence of electrocatalytic and energy storage properties of Fe 2 O 3 based on the use of different methodologies, that is, hydrothermal, microwave&#8208;assisted, and freeze&#8208;drying. Through that, a more assertive analysis can be made concerning changes in morphology, conductivity, exposure of active area, and electrochemical stability which are crucial for the overall performance, hence providing valuable information and considerations for possible large&#8208;scale applications for energy generation and energy storage.</description>
      <author>N. Maley, Pratik Patel, Felipe M. de Souza, Anuj Kumar, Ram K. Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/est2.70062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Hybrid Transition Metal Dichalcogenide as Highly Active Electrode for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403263</link>
      <description>Jeffrey Joseph John Jeya Kamaraj, Keerthivasan Thamotharan, Muthu Senthil Pandian, Umamaheswari Rajaji, P. Ramasamy, Ting&#8208;Yu Liu, ChemistrySelect. 9(40)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403733781

                Abstract Water electrolysis plays a vital role in green energy systems and there is an absolute need for abundant, affordable, and effective catalysts for both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Despite existing challenges, the exploration of transition metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts with superior performance in alkaline water splitting is critical for advancing the hydrogen economy. This study focuses on the electrocatalytic potentials of FeS 2 , CoSe 2 , and FeS 2 @CoSe 2 hybrid nanocomposites in response to the increasing demand for sustainable energy production. The prepared materials were synthesized hydrothermally and characterized using X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD), X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), energy&#8208;dispersive X&#8208;ray spectroscopy (EDX), field emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM), and transmission electron microscopy (TEM) to examine their structural properties, elemental composition, and morphological features. Notably, the F@C&#8722;B nanocomposite exhibited outstanding HER performance, requiring only 97 mV of overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Similarly, the F@C&#8722;C nanocomposite demonstrated impressive OER efficiency with an overpotential of merely 302 mV at the same current density. The involvement of the Volmer&#8211;Heyrovsky mechanism was confirmed through Tafel slope analysis, revealing the improved surface&#8208;active sites and reduced charge transfer resistance of the nanocomposite. The FeS 2 @CoSe 2 nanocomposite with synergistic effects, displayed exceptional electrocatalytic properties, positioning it as a promising candidate for overall water splitting. This work introduces a novel approach to developing highly efficient and cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts, offering a viable alternative to precious metal&#8208;based counterparts.</description>
      <author>Jeffrey Joseph John Jeya Kamaraj, Keerthivasan Thamotharan, Muthu Senthil Pandian, Umamaheswari Rajaji, P. Ramasamy, Ting&#8208;Yu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous oxide/sulfide materials as superior bifunctional electrocatalysts for carbon-neutral green hydrogen production: A short review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221098</link>
      <description>Akbar I. Inamdar, Amol S. Salunke, Nabeen K. Shrestha, Hyunsik Im, Applied Physics Reviews. 11(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403731581

                Maintaining an acceptable quality of life worldwide increasingly depends on the availability of clean and cost-effective energy, with power consumption expected to double by 2050. Therefore, the need for sustainable and affordable green energy has spurred innovative electrocatalysis research with the goal to develop materials and processes that are capable of producing environmentally friendly, carbon-neutral, clean, and green hydrogen fuel as an alternative to fossil fuel. In particular, heterostructured catalysts consisting of transition metal oxides and sulfides have emerged as a capable component of green energy technology. The dual functionality of these catalysts allows for water splitting, while the selectivity of the catalytic materials creates synergetic effects based on their electronic structure, surface composition, and electrochemical surface area. In this review, we examine the latest research and developments, synthesis methods, design strategies, reaction mechanisms, and performance outcomes for oxide/sulfide heterostructures. The review begins by introducing the current demand for hydrogen energy and electrocatalytic water-splitting and then describes the fundamental design principles for oxide/sulfide heterostructures and their hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. A large part of the review is then dedicated to a comprehensive discussion of the various transition metal oxide/sulfide heterostructures designed for the OER, the HER, and two-electrode electrolyzer applications. In addition, the use of in situ and operando techniques, which provide crucial information for the design of effective electrocatalysts, is described. We also discuss the present status of electrocatalysis technology, including the challenges it faces and its future prospects as a means to achieve carbon-neutral hydrogen production. Overall, this review delivers a summary of the latest developments in electrocatalysis based on oxide/sulfide heterostructures for use in green hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Akbar I. Inamdar, Amol S. Salunke, Nabeen K. Shrestha, Hyunsik Im</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Water Confinement and Dual Electrolyte&#8211;Electrode Interfaces by Zwitterionic Oligomer for High&#8208;Voltage Aqueous Lithium&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416566</link>
      <description>Yinyan Deng, Chunxian Xing, Chuan Li, Yangbo Zhou, Zhiping Peng, Linfeng Fei, Chunyi Zhi, Tao Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403792624

                Abstract Aqueous lithium&#8208;ion batteries (ALIBs) have attracted significant interest due to their inherent advantage on safety. However, water itself has a narrow electrochemical stability window (ESW), limiting the energy density of ALIBs. Here, a low&#8208;molecular&#8208;weight zwitterionic oligomer, oligo(propylsulfonate dimethylammonium propylmethacrylamide) (OPDP), as an effective water binding agent for high&#8208;voltage ALIBs is demonstrated. The OPDP can effectively confine water molecules while reducing water activity. The OPDP&#8208;based electrolyte, with an ultra&#8208;high water weight percentage of 25.4%, possesses an outstanding ESW of up to 3.26 V and an ionic conductivity as high as 3.18 mS cm &#8722;1 . Furthermore, the aqueous Mo 6 S 8 //LiMn 2 O 4 full cell with OPDP&#8208;based electrolyte achieves a 99.7% capacity retention after 200 cycles at 0.5C with a high Coulombic efficiency (CE) of 98.7% and a specific energy of 88&#8211;101 Wh kg &#8722;1 . Also, it achieves an 89% capacity retention after 2000 cycles at 10C with a high CE of 99.9%. These postmortem characterizations suggest that robust organic&#8211;inorganic hybrid cathode/anode&#8208;electrolyte interfaces have been constructed during the cycling through the heteroatoms of N, S, and O in the zwitterionic oligomer, leading to the inhibited hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions and high performance of the full cell. This work provides a promising strategy for developing low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;voltage aqueous batteries.</description>
      <author>Yinyan Deng, Chunxian Xing, Chuan Li, Yangbo Zhou, Zhiping Peng, Linfeng Fei, Chunyi Zhi, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416566</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additive Manufacturing of Multiscale NiFeMn Multi-Principal Element Alloys with Tailored Composition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2752-5724/ad89e1</link>
      <description>Shahryar Mooraj, Jintao Fu, Shuai Feng, Alexander K. Ng, Eric B. Duoss, Sarah E. Baker, Cheng Zhu, Eric Detsi, Wen Chen, Materials Futures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403628641

                Abstract Nanostructured multi-principal element alloys (MPEAs) have been explored as next-generation engineering materials due to unique mechanical and functional properties which have significant advantages over traditional dilute alloys. However, the practical applications of nanostructured MPEAs are still limited due to the lack of scalable processing approaches to prepare a large quantity of nanostructured MPEAs, as well as lack of an efficient pathway for high-throughput discovery of better functional nanostructured MPEAs within their vast compositional space. Here we tackle these challenges by presenting an integrated approach by combining direct-ink-writing-based additive manufacturing, solid-state sintering, and chemical dealloying to manufacture hierarchically porous MPEAs. The hierarchical structure is comprised of macro- and micro-scale pores introduced via extrusion printing and polymer decomposition during sintering, as well as nanoscale pores formed via chemical dealloying. The macro- and micro-scale pores allow efficient dealloying of a large mass of material as the diffusion length that the corroding medium must penetrate remains at the scale of the ligaments formed after sintering (~10 &#956;m), despite the large volume of the 3D-printed samples. In addition, this integrated approach enables versatile control of the alloy composition via precisely tuning the ratio of elemental powders in the starting ink, thus offering a pathway for high-throughput discovery of novel functional MPEAs. As a case study, multiscale macro/micro/nanoporous NiFeMn MPEAs with three different compositions were investigated as catalysts to reduce the overpotential of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), where NiFeMn-based electrocatalysts display composition-dependent performance such that the overpotential measured at a current of 0.5 A/g for OER increases in the order of Ni58Fe29Mn13 &#8804; Ni64Fe26Mn10 &lt; Ni76Fe18Mn6. This introduced manufacturing process offers new opportunities for scalable fabrication and rapid screening of nanostructured multi-component complex alloys. &amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Shahryar Mooraj, Jintao Fu, Shuai Feng, Alexander K. Ng, Eric B. Duoss, Sarah E. Baker, Cheng Zhu, Eric Detsi, Wen Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2752-5724/ad89e1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D single-faceted IrO2(101) monolayer enabling high-performing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis beyond 8,000 h stability at 1.5 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</link>
      <description>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745568

                Abstract Both commercially available and laboratory-synthesized IrO2 catalysts typically possess rutile-type structures and diverse facet orientations. According to the theoretical results from density functional theory calculations, distinct IrO2 facets will result in divergent electrocatalytic properties, among which the (101) crystal facet is theoretically predicted as the most energetically favorable for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) owing to its lowest energy barrier. Maintaining a single-unit-cell thickness while exposing a desired facet of 2D IrO2 presents a significant opportunity and challenge for the development of high-performance OER anode catalysts. Herein, we develop an ammonia-induced facet engineering for oriented modulation of crystal facets in the ultimate limit of monolayer thickness, and successfully synthesize 2D monolayer IrO2 exposing unique (101) facet. At the current density of 10 mA cm-2geo, an ultralow overpotential of 230 mV has been achieved on the highly activated (101) facet in a three-electrode system. More importantly, in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, the IrO2 anode reaches a low voltage of 1.74 V at an industrial-level current density of 2 A cm-2geo, much lower than that of all commercial IrO2 electrocatalysts. Though facet engineering primarily contributes to modulating the intrinsic activity rather than stability, the as-prepared IrO2(101) monolayer performs over 8,000 hours of PEM water electrolysis (PEMWE) stability at constant 1.5 A cm-2geo, with a negligible decay rate of 4.0 mV kh-1. Furthermore, even a long-term PEMWE test of 1000 h using the membrane electrode assembly (MEA) with ultra-low Ir loading of 0.2 mgIr cm-2geo under fluctuating operating conditions is performed, ECell remains highly electrochemically stable over time at 1.5 A cm-2geo, without any signs of catalyst degradation. This work proposes that ammonia-induced facet engineering of 2D monolayer IrO2 could represent a novel approach to selectively expose the desired (101) facet, thereby enabling unique facet-dependent OER performance and ultrahigh stability in industrial-scale PEM electrolysis, even under voltage fluctuations generated by solar and wind power.</description>
      <author>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Active Oxygen Species of Two-Dimensional Borophene Oxide toward Advanced Metal-Free Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c09002</link>
      <description>Qingqing Gu, Haojian Lin, Chaowei Si, Zhen Wang, Aiqin Wang, Liu Fei, Bo Li, Bing Yang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403738330

                Two-dimensional (2D) borophene materials are predicted to be ideal catalytic materials due to their structural analogy to graphene. However, the lack of chemical functionalization of borophene hinders its practical application in catalysis. Herein, we reported a massive production of freestanding few-layer 2D borophene oxide (BO) sheets with tunable active oxygen species by a moderate oxidation-assisted exfoliation method. State-of-the-art characterizations demonstrated the evolution of active oxygen species from surface B-O species at the initial stage to the intermediate B</description>
      <author>Qingqing Gu, Haojian Lin, Chaowei Si, Zhen Wang, Aiqin Wang, Liu Fei, Bo Li, Bing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c09002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic simulations of white dwarf-white dwarf mergers and the origin of R Coronae Borealis stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2343</link>
      <description>Sagiv Shiber, Orsola De Marco, Patrick M. Motl, Bradley Munson, Dominic Marcello, Juhan Frank, P. Diehl, Geoffrey C. Clayton, Bennett N. Skinner, Hartmut Kaiser, Gregor Dai&#223;, Dirk Pfl&#252;ger, Jan E. Staff, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745654

                Abstract We study the properties of double white dwarf (DWD) mergers by performing hydrodynamic simulations using the new and improved adaptive mesh refinement code Octo-Tiger. We follow the orbital evolution of DWD systems of mass ratio q = 0.7 for tens of orbits until and after the merger to investigate them as a possible origin for R Coronae Borealis (RCB) type stars. We reproduce previous results, finding that during the merger, the helium WD donor star is tidally disrupted within 20-80 minutes since the beginning of the simulation onto the accretor carbon-oxygen WD, creating a high temperature shell around the accretor. We investigate the possible helium burning in this shell and the merged object&#8217;s general structure. Specifically, we are interested in the amount of oxygen-16 dredged-up from the accretor to the hot shell and the amount of oxygen-18 produced. This is critical as the discovery of very low oxygen-16 to oxygen-18 ratios in RCB stars pointed out the merger scenario as a favorable explanation for their origin. A small amount of hydrogen in the donor may help keep the oxygen-16 to oxygen-18 ratios within observational bounds, even if moderate dredge-up from the accretor occurs. In addition, we perform a resolution study to reconcile the difference found in the amount of oxygen-16 dredge-up between smoothed-particle hydrodynamics and grid-based simulations.</description>
      <author>Sagiv Shiber, Orsola De Marco, Patrick M. Motl, Bradley Munson, Dominic Marcello, Juhan Frank, P. Diehl, Geoffrey C. Clayton, Bennett N. Skinner, Hartmut Kaiser, Gregor Dai&#223;, Dirk Pfl&#252;ger, Jan E. Staff</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mitochondrial genomes of the reef-dwelling spiny lobsters Panulirus echinatus and Panulirus interruptus with insights into the phylogeny and adaptive evolution of protein-coding genes in the Achelata</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00338-024-02569-7</link>
      <description>Alyssa Baker, Natalie C. Stephens, F&#225;bio Mendon&#231;a Diniz, Francisco J. Garc&#237;a&#8208;D&#233; Le&#243;n, J. Antonio Baeza, Coral Reefs. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403607195

                Abstract Temperature and oxygen levels drive the evolution of morphological, behavioral, and physiological traits in marine invertebrates, including crustaceans. Environmental conditions are also expected to prompt the adaptive evolution of mitochondrial protein-coding genes (PCGs), which are vital for energy production via the oxidative phosphorylation pathway. We formally tested for adaptive evolution in mitochondrial protein-coding genes in representatives of the decapod infraorder Achelata, including two spiny lobsters, Panulirus echinatus and P. interruptus , for which we sequenced complete mitochondrial genomes (15,644 and 15,659 bp long, respectively). A phylomitogenomic analysis supported the monophyly of the genus Panulirus , the families Palinuridae and Scyllaridae, and the infraorder Achelata. Over the strong negative selection background observed for mitochondrial PCGs in the Achelata, signatures of positive selective pressure were detected within PCGs in equatorial Panulirus spp. and deepwater Scyllaridae. In Panulirus spp. inhabiting equatorial latitudes with consistently high temperatures, the Datamonkey analysis RELAX suggested intensified purifying selection strength in 9 of the 13 PCGs and relaxation in purifying selection strength in atp6 , while aBSREL, BUSTED, and MEME recovered signatures of positive selection on PCGs within Complex I, III, and IV PCGs. Likewise, in Scyllaridae species inhabiting depths with low-oxygen levels, RELAX indicated relaxed selection strength in 6 of the 13 PCGs, while aBSREL, BUSTED, and MEME recovered signatures of positive selection on PCGs within Complexes I, III, IV, and V. The newly assembled mitochondrial genomes of P. echinatus and P. interruptus represent new genomic resources to aid with the conservation and management of lobsters targeted by major fisheries and contribute to our understanding of how environmental conditions drive adaptive evolution in spiny and slipper lobster mitochondrial PCGs.</description>
      <author>Alyssa Baker, Natalie C. Stephens, F&#225;bio Mendon&#231;a Diniz, Francisco J. Garc&#237;a&#8208;D&#233; Le&#243;n, J. Antonio Baeza</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00338-024-02569-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Metal&#8208;Support Interactions in Heterogeneous Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407167</link>
      <description>Zhiqian Hou, Chenghao Cui, Yanan Yang, Zhikun Huang, Yu Zhuang, Ye Zeng, Xi Gong, Tao Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403791868

                Abstract Molecular oxygen redox electrocatalysis involves oxygen reduction and evolution as core reactions in various energy conversion and environmental technology fields. Strong metal&#8208;support interactions (SMSIs) based nanomaterials are regarded as desirable and state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art heterogeneous electrocatalysts due to their exceptional physicochemical properties. Over the past decades, considerable advancements in theory and experiment have been achieved in related studies, especially in modulating the electronic structure and geometrical configuration of SMSIs to enable activity, selectivity, and stability. In this focuses on the concept of SMSI, explore their various manifestations and mechanisms of action, and summarizes recent advances in SMSIs for efficient energy conversion in oxygen redox electrocatalysis applications. Additionally, the correlation between the physicochemical properties of different metals and supports is systematically elucidated, and the potential mechanisms of the structure&#8211;activity relationships between SMSIs and catalytic performance are outlined through theoretical models. Finally, the obstacles confronting this burgeoning field are comprehensively concluded, targeted recommendations and coping strategies are proposed, and future research perspectives are outlined.</description>
      <author>Zhiqian Hou, Chenghao Cui, Yanan Yang, Zhikun Huang, Yu Zhuang, Ye Zeng, Xi Gong, Tao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diverse Transient Chiral Dynamics in Evolutionary distinct
  Photosynthetic Reaction Centers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.06996</link>
      <description>Yong Yang, Zihui Liu, Fulu Zheng, Panpan Zhang, Hongxing He, Ajay Jha, Hong-Guang Duan, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403621288

                The evolution of photosynthetic reaction centers (RCs) from anoxygenic bacteria to oxygenic cyanobacteria and plants reflects their structural and functional adaptation to environmental conditions. Chirality plays a significant role in influencing the arrangement and function of key molecules in these RCs. This study investigates chirality-related energy transfer in two distinct RCs: Thermochromatium tepidum (BRC) and Thermosynechococcus vulcanus (PSII RC) using two-dimensional electronic spectroscopy (2DES). Circularly polarized laser pulses reveal transient chiral dynamics, with 2DCD spectroscopy highlighting chiral contributions. BRC displays more complex chiral behavior, while PSII RC shows faster coherence decay, possibly as an adaptation to oxidative stress. Comparing the chiral dynamics of BRC and PSII RC provides insights into photosynthetic protein evolution and function.</description>
      <author>Yong Yang, Zihui Liu, Fulu Zheng, Panpan Zhang, Hongxing He, Ajay Jha, Hong-Guang Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.06996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Heart of the Matter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/oso/9780197664797.003.0010</link>
      <description>Gary C. Howard, Oxford University Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403735747

                Abstract Blood is a miracle fluid. It uses the protein hemoglobin to carry oxygen to all cells. It also carries nutrients to tissues and carries away carbon dioxide and waste products. It transports signaling molecules, hormones, and other important molecules. Finally, it has an intricate system that initiates clotting to stop bleeding. Three organs are intimately linked with the blood. The heart pumps blood to the lungs, where the blood gas exchange occurs, and the kidneys remove waste products and help to maintain blood pressure. The evolution of blood and the heart is also fascinating.</description>
      <author>Gary C. Howard</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/oso/9780197664797.003.0010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Nanoparticle Oxidation by NO2 and O2: Chemical Kinetics and Reaction Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413325</link>
      <description>Thomas Berkemeier, Ulrich P&#246;schl, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403707629

                Carbon nanoparticle interactions with gases are central to many environmental and technical processes, but the underlying reaction kinetics and mechanisms are not well understood. Here, we investigate the oxidation and gasification of carbon nanoparticles by NO2 and O2 under combustion exhaust conditions. We build on a comprehensive experimental data set and use a kinetic multilayer model (KM&#8208;GAP&#8208;CARBON) to trace the uptake and release of gas molecules alongside the temporal evolution of particle size and surface composition. The experimental results are captured by a model mechanism that involves different types of carbon atoms (edge/plane&#8208;like) and the formation of a reactive oxygen intermediate (activated CO complex) as the rate&#8208;limiting step. A transition between distinct chemical regimes driven by NO2 at lower temperatures and O2 at higher temperatures is reflected by an increase in the observable activation energy from ~60 kJ/mol to ~130 kJ/mol. We derive energy profiles for three alternative reaction pathways that involve uni&#8208; or bimolecular decomposition of reactive oxygen intermediates.</description>
      <author>Thomas Berkemeier, Ulrich P&#246;schl</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Nanoparticle Oxidation by NO2 and O2: Chemical Kinetics and Reaction Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413325</link>
      <description>Thomas Berkemeier, Ulrich P&#246;schl, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728363

                Carbon nanoparticle interactions with gases are central to many environmental and technical processes, but the underlying reaction kinetics and mechanisms are not well understood. Here, we investigate the oxidation and gasification of carbon nanoparticles by NO2 and O2 under combustion exhaust conditions. We build on a comprehensive experimental data set and use a kinetic multilayer model (KM&#8208;GAP&#8208;CARBON) to trace the uptake and release of gas molecules alongside the temporal evolution of particle size and surface composition. The experimental results are captured by a model mechanism that involves different types of carbon atoms (edge/plane&#8208;like) and the formation of a reactive oxygen intermediate (activated CO complex) as the rate&#8208;limiting step. A transition between distinct chemical regimes driven by NO2 at lower temperatures and O2 at higher temperatures is reflected by an increase in the observable activation energy from ~60 kJ/mol to ~130 kJ/mol. We derive energy profiles for three alternative reaction pathways that involve uni&#8208; or bimolecular decomposition of reactive oxygen intermediates.</description>
      <author>Thomas Berkemeier, Ulrich P&#246;schl</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haemoglobin Gene Repertoire in Teleost and Cichlid Fishes Shaped by Gene Duplications and Genome Rearrangements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.17559</link>
      <description>Dmytro Omelchenko, Arnold Roger Bitja Nyom, Michael Matschiner, Milan Malinsky, Adrian Indermaur, Walter Salzburger, Old&#345;ich Barto&#353;, Zuzana Musilov&#225;, Molecular Ecology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403619473

                ABSTRACT Haemoglobin is a key molecule for oxygen transport in vertebrates. It exhibits remarkable gene diversity in teleost fishes, reflecting adaptation to various aquatic environments. In this study, we present the dynamic evolution of haemoglobin subunit genes based on a comparison of high&#8208;quality genome assemblies of 24 vertebrate species, including 17 teleosts (of which six are cichlids). Our findings indicate that teleost genomes contain a range of haemoglobin genes, from as few as five in fugu to as many as 43 in salmon, with the latter being the largest repertoire found in vertebrates. We find evidence that the teleost ancestor had at least four Hb&#945; and three or four Hb&#946; subunit genes, and that the current gene diversity emerged during teleost radiation, driven primarily by (tandem) gene duplications, genome compaction, and rearrangement dynamics. We provide insights into the genomic organisation of haemoglobin clusters in different teleost species. We further show that the evolution of paralogous rhbdf1 genes flanking both teleost clusters (LA and MN) supports the hypothesis for the origin of the LA cluster by rearrangement within teleosts, rather than by the teleost specific whole&#8208;genome duplication. We specifically focus on cichlid fishes, where adaptation to low oxygen environment plays role in species diversification. Our analysis of six cichlid genomes, including Pungu maclareni from the Barombi Mbo crater lake, for which we sequenced a representative genome, reveals 18&#8211;32 copies of the Hb genes, and elevated rates of non&#8208;synonymous substitutions compared to other teleosts. Overall, this work facilitates a deeper understanding of how haemoglobin genes contribute to the adaptive potential of teleosts.</description>
      <author>Dmytro Omelchenko, Arnold Roger Bitja Nyom, Michael Matschiner, Milan Malinsky, Adrian Indermaur, Walter Salzburger, Old&#345;ich Barto&#353;, Zuzana Musilov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.17559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Perfect Imperfections of Perovskite Oxide Catalysts in the Aspect of Defect Equilibria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400386</link>
      <description>Maria Christy, Seunggun Choi, Jiseok Kwon, Jin-Woo Jeong, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song, Small Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403780594

                ABX 3 (X = O) perovskite oxides are an uprising class of alternative electrocatalysts in eminent technologies like electrocatalysis, photocatalysis, thermocatalysis, and energy storage. The perquisites of perovskite oxide catalysts encompass ordered atomic structure, structural/compositional extensibility, flexible electronic structure, lucrativeness, and so on. The ingenuity to precisely control and tune the inherent properties by reconstructing their crystal structure is particularly advantageous in electrocatalysis reactions like oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER). Incorporating multidimensional imperfections in the presumably perfect crystal structure of the perovskite catalysts is garnering booming attention among researchers. This concept can expertly influence the electronic structure and boost the reaction kinetics during electrocatalysis. Defects or imperfections are achieved by substituting A&#8208; and/or B&#8208;sites with heteroatoms or by oxygen vacancies. Defect engineering points to a promising new direction in the development of perovskite oxide catalysts. This work surveys the recent progress in defect engineering and how it plays a vital role in their design, and application in electrocatalysis, mainly ORR/OER. The architecture, dimensionality, and the types of perovskite oxides based on their cations, crystal structures, and stoichiometries are surveyed for a comprehensive understanding. This review aims to provide an extensive outlook on oxide perovskite catalysts concerning structural defects.</description>
      <author>Maria Christy, Seunggun Choi, Jiseok Kwon, Jin-Woo Jeong, Ungyu Paik, Taeseup Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field Evolution for Crystallization-driven Dynamos in C/O White Dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad7a6a</link>
      <description>Matias Castro-Tapia, Shuang&#8208;Nan Zhang, A. Cumming, The Astrophysical Journal. 975(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403776482

                Abstract We investigate the evolution of magnetic fields generated by the crystallization-driven dynamo in carbon&#8211;oxygen white dwarfs (WDs) with masses &#8818;1.05 M &#8857; . We use scalings for the dynamo to demonstrate that the initial magnetic field strength ( B 0 ) has an upper limit that depends on the initial convection zone size ( R out,0 ) and the WD mass. We solve the induction equation to follow the magnetic field evolution after the dynamo phase ends. We show that the predicted surface magnetic field strength ( B surf ) differs from B 0 by at least a factor of &#8764;0.3. This reduction depends on R out,0 , where values smaller than half of the star radius give B surf &#8818; 0.01 B 0 . We implement electrical conductivities that account for the solid phase effect on the ohmic diffusion. We observe that the conductivity increases as the solid core grows, freezing in the magnetic field at a certain point of the evolution and slowing its outward transport. We study the effect of turbulent magnetic diffusivity induced by the convection and find that for a small R out,0 , B surf is stronger than the nonturbulent diffusion cases because of the more rapid transport, but still orders of magnitude smaller than B 0 . Given these limitations, the crystallization-driven dynamo theory could explain only magnetic C/O WDs with field strengths less than a few megagauss for the mass range 0.45&#8211;1.05 M &#8857; . Our results also suggest that a buried fossil field must be at least 100 times stronger than observed surface fields if crystallization-driven convection is responsible for its transport to the surface.</description>
      <author>Matias Castro-Tapia, Shuang&#8208;Nan Zhang, A. Cumming</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad7a6a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Performance of Mn2O3 Electrodes for Hydrogen Evolution Using Natural Bischofite Salt from Atacama Desert: A Novel Application for Solar Saline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205129</link>
      <description>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Edward Fuentealba, Susana Leiva-Guajardo, Luis C&#225;ceres, Carlos Portillo, Felipe D. Sep&#250;lveda, Iv&#225;n Brito, J.A. Cobos-Murcia, Omar F. Rojas-Moreno, Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, Eduardo Schott, &#193;lvaro Soliz, Materials. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403602520

                Solar saline water splitting is a promising approach to sustainable hydrogen production, harnessing abundant solar energy and the availability of brine resources, especially in the Atacama Desert. Bischofite salt (MgCl2&#183;6H2O) has garnered significant attention due to its wide range of industrial applications. Efficient hydrogen production in arid or hyper arid locations using bischofite solutions is a novel and revolutionary idea. This work studied the electrochemical performance of Mn2O3 electrodes using a superposition model based on mixed potential theory and evaluated the superficial performance of this electrode in contact with a 0.5 M bischofite salt solution focusing on the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) that occur during saline water splitting. The application of the non-linear superposition model provides valuable electrochemical kinetic parameters that complement the understanding of Mn2O3, this being one of the novelties of this work.</description>
      <author>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Edward Fuentealba, Susana Leiva-Guajardo, Luis C&#225;ceres, Carlos Portillo, Felipe D. Sep&#250;lveda, Iv&#225;n Brito, J.A. Cobos-Murcia, Omar F. Rojas-Moreno, Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, Eduardo Schott, &#193;lvaro Soliz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of gas envelopes and outgassed atmospheres of rocky planets
  formed via pebble accretion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.11005</link>
      <description>Piia Maria Tomberg, Anders Johansen, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403706170

                We present here results of numerical simulations of the formation and early evolution of rocky planets through pebble accretion, with an with an emphasis on hydrogen envelope longevity and the composition of the outgassed atmosphere. We model planets with a range in mass from 0.1 to 5 Earth masses that orbit between 0.7 and 1.7 AU. The composition of the outgassed atmosphere is calculated with the partial pressure of free oxygen fit to geophysical models of magma ocean self-oxidation. XUV radiation powered photoevaporation is considered as the main driver of atmospheric escape. We model planets that remain below the pebble isolation mass and hence accrete tenuous envelopes only. We consider slow, medium or fast initial stellar rotation for the temporal evolution of the XUV flux. The loss of the envelope is a key event that allows the magma ocean to crystallise and outgas its bulk volatiles. The atmospheric composition of the majority of our simulated planets is dominated by CO$_2$. Our planets accrete a total of 11.6 Earth oceans of water, the majority of which enters the core. The hydrospheres of planets lighter than the Earth reach several times the mass of the Earth's modern oceans, while the hydrospheres of planets ranging from 1 to 3.5 Earth masses are comparable to those of our planet. However, planets of 4-5 Earth masses have smaller hydrospheres due to trapping of volatiles in their massive mantles. Overall, our simulations demonstrate that hydrogen envelopes are easily lost from rocky planets and that this envelope loss triggers the most primordial partitioning of volatiles between the solid mantle and the atmosphere.</description>
      <author>Piia Maria Tomberg, Anders Johansen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.11005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inclusive and diffractive neutrino-nucleus scattering at high energy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.16705</link>
      <description>Anh Dung Le, Heikki M&#228;ntysaari, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403784375

                We calculate the energy dependence of inclusive and diffractive neutrino-nucleus deep-inelastic scattering cross sections within the dipole picture, focusing on the ultra-high-energy regime. We predict an up to $\sim 10\%$ nuclear suppression in the inclusive neutrino-Oxygen scattering originating from the non-linear QCD dynamics in the small-$x$ Balitsky-Kovchegov evolution. Diffraction is found to be a small $1\dots 4\%$ contribution to the total cross section across a wide range of neutrino energies relevant for current and near-future experiments. The diffractive cross section is calculated separately for the coherent and incoherent channels that are found to be of equal importance. Additionally, we include the dominant contribution from the $|q\bar q g\rangle$ Fock state of the $W^\pm$ and $Z$ bosons in the high-$Q^2$ limit, along with the lowest-order $|q\bar q\rangle$ contribution. The $|q\bar{q}g\rangle$ contribution is found to be numerically significant, reaching up to 40\% of the diffractive cross section.</description>
      <author>Anh Dung Le, Heikki M&#228;ntysaari</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.16705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulatory Mechanisms and Applications of Rare Earth Elements&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts&lt;sup&gt;&#8224;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400578</link>
      <description>Q. Gao, Sheng Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Laihao Luo, Xu Li, Qiu Jiang, Yuan Ji, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403770835

                Comprehensive Summary Amidst the pressing environmental challenges posed by the prevalent reliance on fossil fuels, it becomes imperative to seek sustainable alternatives and prioritize energy efficiency. Electrocatalysis, which is renowned for its high efficiency and environmental friendliness, has garnered significant attention. Rare earth elements (REEs), distinguished by their unique electronic and orbital structures, play a crucial role in electrocatalysis. The strategic integration of REEs into catalysts allows for the fine&#8208;tuning of atomic structures, which in turn, significantly boosts catalytic performance. Despite substantial advancements in rare earth&#8208;based materials for electrocatalysis, a comprehensive overview of the regulatory mechanisms involving REEs is lacking. In this mini&#8208;review, we systematically explore the regulatory mechanisms of REEs within electrocatalysts and their pivotal roles in essential electrocatalytic processes such as the CO 2 reduction reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, and hydrogen evolution reaction. We commence with an elucidation of REEs, proceed to delineate their regulatory impacts on electrocatalysts and delve into their applications in key electroreduction reactions. We conclude with discussions on current limitations and prospects for further advancements in this burgeoning field of research. Key Scientists</description>
      <author>Q. Gao, Sheng Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Laihao Luo, Xu Li, Qiu Jiang, Yuan Ji, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abundances of iron-peak elements in 58 bulge spheroid stars from APOGEE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.13751</link>
      <description>B. Barbuy, A. C. S. Fria&#231;a, H. Ernandes, Patricia Siqueira Silva, S. O. Souza, J. G. Fern&#225;ndez-Trincado, K&#225;tia Cunha, V. V. Smith, T. Masseron, &#193;ngeles P&#233;rez-Villegas, C. Chiappini, A. B. A. Queiroz, B. X. Santiago, T. C. Beers, F. Anders, Ricardo P. Schiavon, M. Valentini, D. Minniti, D. Geisler, Diogo Souto, Vinicius M. Placco, M. Zoccali, S. Feltzing, M. Schultheis, C. Nitschelm, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403580076

                Stars presently identified in the bulge spheroid are probably very old, and their abundances can be interpreted as due to the fast chemical enrichment of the early Galactic bulge. The abundances of the iron-peak elements are important tracers of nucleosynthesis processes, in particular oxygen burning, silicon burning, the weak s-process, and alpha-rich freeze-out. Aims. The aim of this work is to derive the abundances of V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu in 58 bulge spheroid stars and to compare them with the results of a previous analysis of data from APOGEE. We selected the best lines for V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu located within the H-band of the spectrum, identifying the most suitable ones for abundance determination, and discarding severe blends. Using the stellar physical parameters available for our sample from the DR17 release of the APOGEE project, we derived the individual abundances through spectrum synthesis. We then complemented these measurements with similar results from different bulge field and globular cluster stars, in order to define the trends of the individual elements and compare with the results of chemical-evolution models. We verify that the H-band has useful lines for the derivation of the elements V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu in moderately metal-poor stars. The resulting abundances indicate that: V, Cr, and Ni vary in lockstep with Fe; Co tends to vary in lockstep with Fe, but could be showing a slight decrease with decreasing metallicity; and Mn and Cu decrease with decreasing metallicity. These behaviours are well reproduced by chemical-evolution models except for Cu, which appears to drop faster than the models predict for moderate metallicities. Finally, abundance indicators combined with kinematical and dynamical criteria appear to show that our 58 sample stars are likely to have originated in situ.</description>
      <author>B. Barbuy, A. C. S. Fria&#231;a, H. Ernandes, Patricia Siqueira Silva, S. O. Souza, J. G. Fern&#225;ndez-Trincado, K&#225;tia Cunha, V. V. Smith, T. Masseron, &#193;ngeles P&#233;rez-Villegas, C. Chiappini, A. B. A. Queiroz, B. X. Santiago, T. C. Beers, F. Anders, Ricardo P. Schiavon, M. Valentini, D. Minniti, D. Geisler, Diogo Souto, Vinicius M. Placco, M. Zoccali, S. Feltzing, M. Schultheis, C. Nitschelm</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.13751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Reversible Zn Anode Design Through Oriented ZnO(002) Facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408908</link>
      <description>Chengwu Yang, Pattaraporn Woottapanit, Sining Geng, Kittima Lolupiman, Qian Zhang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Guanjie He, Jiaqian Qin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615344

                Abstract The practical implementation of aqueous Zn&#8208;ion batteries presents formidable hurdles, including uncontrolled dendrite growth, water&#8208;induced side reactions, suboptimal Zn metal utilization, and intricate Zn anode manufacturing. Here, large&#8208;scale construction of a highly oriented ZnO(002) lattice plane on Zn anode (ZnO(002)@Zn) with thermodynamic inertia and kinetic zincophilicity is designed to address such problems. Both theoretical calculations and experiment results elucidate that the ZnO(002)@Zn possesses high Zn chemical affinity, hydrogen evolution reaction suppression, and dendrite&#8208;free deposition ability due to the abundant lattice oxygen species in ZnO(002) and its low lattice mismatch with Zn(002). These features synergistically promote ion transport and enable homogeneous Zn deposition. Consequently, the ZnO(002)@Zn anode displays a stable and prolonged cycling lifespan exceeding 500 h even under a larger depth of discharge (85.6%) and realizes an impressive average Coulombic efficiency of 99.7%. Moreover, its efficacy is also evident in V 2 O 5 &#8208;cathode coin cells and pouch cells with not only high discharge capacity but also exceptional cycling stability. This integrated approach presents a promising avenue for addressing the challenges associated with Zn metal anodes, thereby advancing the prospects of aqueous Zn&#8208;ion battery technologies.</description>
      <author>Chengwu Yang, Pattaraporn Woottapanit, Sining Geng, Kittima Lolupiman, Qian Zhang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Guanjie He, Jiaqian Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the Mechanism of Oxidative Potential Increase in Atmospheric Particulate Matter during Photoaging: Important Role of Aromatic Nitrogenous Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03199</link>
      <description>Qingwen Wang, Qingcai Chen, Hao Lin, Jiale Ding, Tong Sha, Yuemei Han, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633329

                Particulate matter (PM) undergoing various aging processes in the atmosphere changes its toxicity. However, the mechanism of toxicity evolution is not fully clarified currently. This study demonstrates that photoaging promotes an increase in the oxidative potential (OP) of atmospheric PM by about 30%, and the increased OP is mainly attributed to the production of secondary organic compounds, while water-soluble metal ions contribute only 11%. The OP of nonextractable matters (NEMs) of atmospheric PM was mostly increased after photoaging, followed by water-soluble matters (WSMs). NEM can produce quinone-like functional groups and secondary persistent free radicals during photoaging, which are most likely to produce reactive oxygen species (ROS). For WSM, the conversion of low-oxidation humic-like substances (HULIS) to high-oxidation HULIS is the main reason for the increase in OP. Quinones, nitrophenols, and N-containing heterocycles are the OP contributors produced during the conversion process. Among them, quinones are the main secondary oxidizing active compounds, while nitro-phenolic compounds and N-containing heterocyclic compounds may play a catalyst-like role, facilitating the production of oxidizing active compounds and ROS in the newly converted high-oxidation HULIS. This study clarifies the secondary OP generation mechanism and provides new insights into the uncertainty of PM toxicity during atmospheric aging.</description>
      <author>Qingwen Wang, Qingcai Chen, Hao Lin, Jiale Ding, Tong Sha, Yuemei Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of gas film formation and evolution on anode in microbubbles flow electrolytic plasma polishing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5303937/v1</link>
      <description>Juan Wang, Huanwu Sun, Rongzheng Fan, Dongliang Yang, Yuxia Xiang, Haidong Duan, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403779450

                Abstract Microbubbles flow electrolytic plasma polishing (MF-EPP) facilitates controllable electrolytic plasma polishing (EPP) using a low-power supply. It is well established that a vapor gaseous envelope (VGE) around a workpiece is essential for EPP polishing. Nonetheless, the generation condition and its control parameter of a local gas film on the workpiece surface in MF-EPP is not fully understood. In this study, an analysis by the electrochemical and hydrothermal reactions revealed that the gas composition on the anode surface is mainly composed of water vapor, which is heated by Joule heat, and electrolysis gases such as oxygen, fluorine, hydrogen, and nitrogen. By analyzing formation conditions and calculating the volume flux of each gas, it was found that vapor is the main component of the gas film. For the vapor characteristics, the bubble nucleation and growth model has been established. On this basis, the main factors affecting the nucleation, growth, and coalescence of bubbles were then analyzed, indicating that superheating and heat flow density are the principal factors affecting the aggregation of bubbles and thus the formation of a gas film. It was determined that the presence of electrolytic gases exerts a beneficial influence on the nucleation of vapor bubbles. Additionally, a bubble dynamics model was constructed based on the conservation of energy, and the impact of processing parameters on the evolution of bubbles was analyzed. The threshold for the formation of a stable gas film under the conditions of this experiment was determined to be a voltage of 350 V and an initial electrolyte temperature of 80&#176;C. The applicability of the model was validated through experimentation, and the establishment of the model provides theoretical and experimental references for the formulation and optimization of MF-EPP machining process parameters.</description>
      <author>Juan Wang, Huanwu Sun, Rongzheng Fan, Dongliang Yang, Yuxia Xiang, Haidong Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5303937/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vapor&#8211;Solid Interface Synthesis of Highly Crystalline Covalent Triazine Frameworks for Use as Efficient Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407782</link>
      <description>Minghui Chen, Ji Xiong, Quan Shi, Weiwei Zhang, Zhuoran Chen, Li Wang, Xinyue Zhu, Kai Guo, Feng Ya-qing, Bao Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403778312

                Abstract Harsh synthetic conditions for crystalline covalent triazine frameworks (CTFs) and associated limitations on structural diversities impede not only further development of functional CTFs, but also practical large&#8208;scale synthesis. Herein, a mild and universal vapor&#8211;solid interface synthesis strategy is developed for highly crystalline CTFs employing trifluoromethanesulfonic acid vapor as catalysts. A series of highly ordered simple and functional CTFs (CTF&#8208;TJUs) can be facilely produced. In particular, the porphyrin&#8208;involved functional CTF (CTF&#8208;TJU&#8208;Por1) with high crystallinity is synthesized for the first time via this universal approach. The mechanism of vapor&#8208;catalyzed trimerization of nitrile monomers is thoroughly investigated through semi in situ characterizations. As a proof of concept, the photocatalytic performance of synthesized CTFs for water splitting is evaluated. CTF&#8208;TJU&#8208;133 exhibits significantly greater photocatalytic rates for hydrogen (4.35 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 ) and oxygen (2.18 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 ) evolutions during overall water splitting under visible light irradiations compared to other CTF&#8208;TJUs, representing one of the highest values among reported CTF photocatalysts. Further studies reveal that enhanced photocatalytic performance of CTF&#8208;TJU&#8208;133 results from optimized band structure, extended visible&#8208;light absorption, and high carrier separation efficiency. This study provides a promising strategy to synthesize various simple and functional CTFs, which significantly enriched diversities of CTF family for different application purposes.</description>
      <author>Minghui Chen, Ji Xiong, Quan Shi, Weiwei Zhang, Zhuoran Chen, Li Wang, Xinyue Zhu, Kai Guo, Feng Ya-qing, Bao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accretion and Core Formation of Earth-like Planets: Insights from Metal&#8211;Silicate Partitioning of Siderophile and Volatile Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences14110281</link>
      <description>Dominik Loroch, S. Hackler, Arno Rohrbach, Jasper Berndt, Stephan Klemme, Geosciences. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403646963

                The origin of volatile elements, the timing of their accretion and their distribution during Earth&#8217;s differentiation are fundamental aspects of Earth&#8217;s early evolution. Here, we present the result of a newly developed accretion and core formation model, which features the results of high P&#8211;T metal&#8211;silicate partitioning experiments. The model includes well-studied reference elements (Fe, Ni, Ca, Al, Mg, Si) as well as trace elements (V, Ga, Ag, Au, S) covering a wide range from refractory to volatile behavior. The accretion model simulates the different steps of planet formation, such as the effects of continuous, heterogenous core formation at high P&#8211;T, the effect of the Moon-forming giant impact and the addition of matter after the core formation was completed, the so-called &#8220;late veneer&#8221;. To explore the &#8220;core formation signature&#8221; of the volatile depletion patterns and the quantitative influence of a late veneer, we modeled planets that would have formed from known materials, such as CI, CM, CV, CO, EH and EL meteorites, and from a hypothetical volatile depleted material, CI*. Some of the resulting planets are Earth-like in key properties, such as overall core size, major element composition, oxygen fugacity and trace element composition. The model predicts the chemical signatures of the main planetary reservoirs, the metallic core and bulk silicate planet (BSP) of the modeled planets, which we compare with the chemical signature of Earth derived previously from core formation models and mass balance-based approaches. We show that planets accreted from volatile depleted carbonaceous chondrites (CM, CV, CO and CI*) are closest in terms of major element (Si, Mg, Fe, Ca, Al, Ni) and also siderophile volatile element (Ge, Ga, Au) concentrations to the components from which Earth accreted. Chalcophile volatile elements (S, Ag), instead, require an additional process to lower their concentrations in the BSP to Earth-like concentrations, perhaps the late segregation of a sulfide melt.</description>
      <author>Dominik Loroch, S. Hackler, Arno Rohrbach, Jasper Berndt, Stephan Klemme</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences14110281</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
