<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 01:10:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>MOF&#727;derived sulfur&#727;doped iron&#727;nickel bimetallic phosphide nanowires: A bifunctional electrode for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.332</link>
      <description>Munisamy Maniyazagan, Esakkimuthu Shanmugasundaram, Naveenkumar Perumal, Hyeon-Woo Yang, Nayoung Kang, Woo Seung Kang, Stalin Thambusamy, Sun-Jae Kim, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 81(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401011361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munisamy Maniyazagan, Esakkimuthu Shanmugasundaram, Naveenkumar Perumal, Hyeon-Woo Yang, Nayoung Kang, Woo Seung Kang, Stalin Thambusamy, Sun-Jae Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transfer learning guided discovery of efficient perovskite oxide for alkaline water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50605-5</link>
      <description>Chang Jiang, Hongyuan He, Hongquan Guo, Shouxin Zhang, Qingjun Han, Youliang Weng, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Yinlong Zhu, Ning Yan, Xin Tu, Yifei Sun, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401011715

                Abstract Perovskite oxides show promise for the oxygen evolution reaction. However, numerical chemical compositions remain unexplored due to inefficient trial-and-error methods for material discovery. Here, we develop a transfer learning paradigm incorporating a pre-trained model, ensemble learning, and active learning, enabling the prediction of undiscovered perovskite oxides with enhanced generalizability for this reaction. Screening 16,050 compositions leads to the identification and synthesis of 36 new perovskite oxides, including 13 pure perovskite structures. Pr 0.1 Sr 0.9 Co 0.5 Fe 0.5 O 3 and Pr 0.1 Sr 0.9 Co 0.5 Fe 0.3 Mn 0.2 O 3 exhibit low overpotentials of 327 mV and 315 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. Electrochemical measurements reveal coexistence of absorbate evolution and lattice oxygen mechanisms for O-O coupling in both materials. Pr 0.1 Sr 0.9 Co 0.5 Fe 0.3 Mn 0.2 O 3 demonstrates enhanced OH - affinity compared to Pr 0.1 Sr 0.9 Co 0.5 Fe 0.5 O 3 , with the emergence of oxo-bridged Mn-Co conjugate facilitating charge redistribution and dynamic reversibility of O lattice /V O , thereby slowing down Co dissolution. This work paves the way for accelerated discovery and development of high-performance perovskite oxide electrocatalysts for this reaction.</description>
      <author>Chang Jiang, Hongyuan He, Hongquan Guo, Shouxin Zhang, Qingjun Han, Youliang Weng, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Yinlong Zhu, Ning Yan, Xin Tu, Yifei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50605-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hexavalent iridium boosts oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.greenca.2024.07.003</link>
      <description>Mengtian Huo, Y. T. Liang, Kaichi Qin, Guanzhi Wang, Zihao Xing, Jinfa Chang, Green Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401014289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengtian Huo, Y. T. Liang, Kaichi Qin, Guanzhi Wang, Zihao Xing, Jinfa Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.greenca.2024.07.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium Dioxide Induced Nickel-iron Alloy-based Precatalyst towards Efficient and Durable Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175729</link>
      <description>Ran Qiao, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Hongtao Bai, Xiangchao Meng, Jingde Li, Guihua Liu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401025947

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ran Qiao, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Hongtao Bai, Xiangchao Meng, Jingde Li, Guihua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Stern Layer Water Alignment Prior to and During the Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2023-m9d1z-v4</link>
      <description>Raiden Speelman, Franz M. Geiger, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401026900

                While water's oxygen is the electron source in the industrially important oxygen evolution reaction, the strong absorber problem clouds our view of how the Stern layer water molecules orient themselves in response to applied potentials. Here, we report nonlinear optical measurements on nickel electrodes held at pH 13 indicating a disorder-to-order transition in the Stern layer water molecules prior to the onset of Faradaic current. A full water monolater (1.1 x 10^15 cm-2) aligns with oxygen atoms pointing towards the electrode at +0.8 V and the associated work is 80 kJ mol-1. Our experiments identify water flipping energetics as a target for understanding overpotentials, advance molecular electrochemistry, provide benchmarks for electrical double layer models, and serve as a diagnostic tool for understanding electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Raiden Speelman, Franz M. Geiger</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2023-m9d1z-v4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Doping Approach to Activate Lattice Oxygen Participation in K2WO4 Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124423</link>
      <description>Selvaraj Seenivasan, M. H. Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027067

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Selvaraj Seenivasan, M. H. Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-deficient annealing boosts performance of CoNiFe oxide electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115675</link>
      <description>Thi-Thu-Hien Pham, Michaela Plevov&#225;, Stephan Bartling, Nils Rockstroh, Armin Springer, Adam Slabon, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401032956

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thi-Thu-Hien Pham, Michaela Plevov&#225;, Stephan Bartling, Nils Rockstroh, Armin Springer, Adam Slabon, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation-Triggered Growth of Nanowires for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02315</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Weiying Ye, Zhilin Zhang, Yuan&#8208;Zhao Hua, Chenyang Cai, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Wenshu Yang, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401034705

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which occurs in a variety of energy-related devices, necessitates optimization of the reaction pathways for efficient and scalable deployment. Nevertheless, fully harnessing the advanced structure of synthetic electrocatalysts remains a significant challenge due to the inevitable surface reconstruction process during OER. Here we present an efficient and flexible method to control the surface reconstruction process by engineering an electrolyte containing trace Co</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Weiying Ye, Zhilin Zhang, Yuan&#8208;Zhao Hua, Chenyang Cai, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Wenshu Yang, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core&#8211;Shell Co&#8208;Co&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;P Nanoparticle&#8208;Embedded N&#8208;Doped Carbon Nanowhiskers Hollow Sphere for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409390</link>
      <description>Wei Zhu, Wenhui Hu, Ying Wei, Yongcai Zhang, Kunming Pan, Songtao Zhang, Xinxin Hang, Mingbo Zheng, Huan Pang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401035151

                Abstract The development of efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is critical to overcome the efficiency bottleneck in hydrogen generation via water electrolysis. Hollow nanostructured materials have emerged as a hot topic for electrocatalysis research because of their advantages, including abundant active sites, a large contact area between the catalyst and the electrolyte, and a short transmission path. As highly efficient and stable OER electrocatalysts, cobalt&#8208;based nanostructured materials have attracted more and more attention. In this work, cobalt metal/cobalt phosphides/nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon composites (Co&#8208;Co x P/NC) with a hierarchical hollow structure are designed by using hollow ZIF&#8208;67 microspheres as precursors. By coating ZIF&#8208;8 on the surface of hollow ZIF&#8208;67 microspheres and further carbonizing, carbon nanowhiskers are successfully formed on the surface of hollow carbon spheres under the catalytic effect of Co nanoparticles at a high temperature. In the subsequent phosphating process, solid Co nanocrystalline particles are transformed into core&#8211;shell CoP and Co 2 P nanoparticles on account of the Kirkendall effect. Through the optimization of the microstructure of the material and the synergistic effect of transition metal, transition metal phosphide, and nitrogen doping, the overpotential of the optimal material is only 287 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 current density in 1 m KOH.</description>
      <author>Wei Zhu, Wenhui Hu, Ying Wei, Yongcai Zhang, Kunming Pan, Songtao Zhang, Xinxin Hang, Mingbo Zheng, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Different N/C Coordination Electronic Structures on the Activity of Bifunctional Rare-Earth Ytterbium Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01797</link>
      <description>Tao Xu, Daomiao Wang, Qiming Fu, Chao Liu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401035209

                The research and development of bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen electrode is of great significance to solve the problem of electrochemical energy. Herein, the effect of different structure-activity relationships on the performance of YbN</description>
      <author>Tao Xu, Daomiao Wang, Qiming Fu, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeNi&#8208;LDH COATED WITH ORANGE&#8208;PEEL CARBON AEROGEL FOR OXYGEN EVOLUTION REACTION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401276</link>
      <description>Hai Jia, Peng-Cheng Ji, Yang Teng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401038504

                In this work, the waste orange-peel was used as carbon source, and the orange-peel derived carbon material can be obtained through simple pyrolysis. Then, we designed the structure of orange-peel carbon aerogel grown on iron-nickel layered double hydroxides in situ to achieve the effect of carbon coating (FeNi-LDH/CA). The oxygen evolution reaction catalytic performance of FeNi-LDH/CA is excellent, far exceeding that of commercial RuO2. In 1 M KOH, the overpotential of FeNi-LDH/CA is only 250 mV (10 mA cm-2), obviously better than that of commercial RuO2 (295 mV). FeNi-LDH/CA shows good cycling stability, and after long-term i-t testing, the performance only decays by 3% after running at 100 mA cm-2 for 100 h. When used as an anode, the voltage of water-splitting is only 1.48 V at 10 mA cm-2. The rechargeable liquid zinc-air battery based on Pt/C-FeNi-LDH/CA catalyst has higher open-circuit voltage (1.543 V) and galvanostatic discharge capacity at 1.23 V (830 min, 10 mA cm-2). Moreover, the zinc-air battery based on Pt/C-FeNi-LDH/CA has a small charge-discharge voltage gap (0.65 V) at 10 mA cm-2, after 200 consecutive cycles (66 h), the charge-discharge voltage gap only increased by about 30 mV, indicating good cycling stability.</description>
      <author>Hai Jia, Peng-Cheng Ji, Yang Teng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selection of metal halide redox mediator suitable for lithium air battery by evaluating oxygen evolution efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53619/kobs.2024.6.4.1.58</link>
      <description>Juhyoung Kim, Dongwook Kim, Journal of the Korean Battery Society. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401040180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juhyoung Kim, Dongwook Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53619/kobs.2024.6.4.1.58</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic behavior of transition metal Cr and Co doped ZnO nanoparticles for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.137095</link>
      <description>Bodicherla Naresh, Muthuviveganandavel Veerappan, Kisoo Yoo, Jonghoon Kim, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401045722

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bodicherla Naresh, Muthuviveganandavel Veerappan, Kisoo Yoo, Jonghoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.137095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inducing Intermolecular Oxygen Coupling by Introducing S and FeOOH on Co(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoneedle Arrays for Industrial Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405080</link>
      <description>Yijie Zhang, Weiyi Zhang, Xiaowen Zhang, Yuan Gao, Qiang Zhao, Jinping Li, Guang Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401059420

                Abstract The design of electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a limitation of industrial hydrogen production by electrolysis of water. Excellent and stable OER catalysts can be developed by activating lattice oxygen and changing the reaction path. Herein, S and FeOOH on the Co(OH) 2 nanoneedle arrays are introduced to construct a heterostructure (S&#8208;FeOOH/Co(OH) 2 /NF) as a proof of concept. Theoretical calculations and experimental suggest that the Co&#8208;O&#8208;Fe motif formed at the heterogeneous interface with the introduction of FeOOH, inducing electron transfer from Co to Fe, enhancing Co&#9472;O covalency and reducing intramolecular charge transfer energy, thereby stimulating direct intramolecular lattice oxygen coupling. Doping of S in FeOOH further accelerates electron transfer, improves lattice oxygen activity, and prevents dissolution of FeOOH. Consequently, the overpotential of S&#8208;FeOOH/Co(OH) 2 /NF is only 199 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and coupled with the Pt/C electrode can be up to 1 A cm &#8722;2 under 1.79 V and remain stable for over 120 h in an anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE). This work proposes a strategy for the design of efficient and stable electrocatalysts for industrial water electrolysis and promotes the commercialization of AEMWE.</description>
      <author>Yijie Zhang, Weiyi Zhang, Xiaowen Zhang, Yuan Gao, Qiang Zhao, Jinping Li, Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Long-Term Stability in Oxygen Evolution through In-Situ Etching of Phase Segregation Fe-Mn Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124453</link>
      <description>Mao Sun, Yueming Zhai, Jike Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401063655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mao Sun, Yueming Zhai, Jike Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124453</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Defect Engineering Approach to Generate a Ru-Comof@Mos2 Heterointerface with Enhanced Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4912480</link>
      <description>Boka Fikadu Banti, Mahendra Goddati, Njemuwa Nwaji, Juyong Gwak, Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Hyojin Kang, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Jaebeom Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401160688

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boka Fikadu Banti, Mahendra Goddati, Njemuwa Nwaji, Juyong Gwak, Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Hyojin Kang, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Jaebeom Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4912480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen and Sulfur Incorporated Chitosan-Derived Carbon Sphere Hybrid MXene as Highly Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101528</link>
      <description>Mohamedazeem M. Mohideen, Abdul Qadir, S. Balachandran, Saeideh Kholghi Eshkalak, Yong Liu, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401170316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohamedazeem M. Mohideen, Abdul Qadir, S. Balachandran, Saeideh Kholghi Eshkalak, Yong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructure Fe7S8/Mn(OH)2 of incomplete sulfurization induces Mn atoms with high density of states for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction and supercapacitor electrochemical performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.244</link>
      <description>Dexing Meng, Hong Liang, Zhaojun Fang, Qianqian Jiang, Huabo Huang, Xiaodong Wu, Jianguo Tang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401171992

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dexing Meng, Hong Liang, Zhaojun Fang, Qianqian Jiang, Huabo Huang, Xiaodong Wu, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photosynthesis of CH3OH via oxygen-atom-grafting from CO2 to CH4 enabled by AuPd/GaN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50801-3</link>
      <description>Hui Su, Jing&#8208;Tan Han, Botong Miao, Mahdi Salehi, Chao&#8208;Jun Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401178530

                The direct co-conversion of methane and carbon dioxide into valuable chemicals has been a longstanding scientific pursuit for carbon neutrality and combating climate change. Herein, we present a photo-driven chemical process that reforms these two major greenhouse gases together to generate green methanol and CO, two high-valued industrial chemicals. Isotopic labeling and control experiments indicate an oxygen-atom-graft occurs, wherein CO</description>
      <author>Hui Su, Jing&#8208;Tan Han, Botong Miao, Mahdi Salehi, Chao&#8208;Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50801-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous&#8208;Crystalline Heterostructured Nanoporous High&#8208;Entropy Alloys for High&#8208;Efficiency pH&#8208;Universal Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400793</link>
      <description>Xueqian Yu, Xianzu Gong, Haiqing Qiao, Xiaobing Liu, Chao Ma, Ruijuan Xiao, Ran Li, Zhang Tao, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401188558

                Abstract Developing high&#8208;efficiency durable electrocatalysts in wide pH range for water splitting is significant for environmentally&#8208;friendly synthesis of renewable hydrogen energy. Herein, a facile method by dealloying designable multicomponent metallic glass precursors is reported to synthesize amorphous&#8208;crystalline heterostructured nanoporous high&#8208;entropy alloys (AC&#8208;HEAs) of CuAgAuPtPd, CuAgAuIrRu, and CuAgAuPtPdIrRu, heaped up by nanocrystalline particles with an average size of 2&#8208;3 nm and the amorphous glued phase. The synthesized AC&#8208;HEA&#8208;CuAgAuPtPd owns highly catalytic performances for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), with 9.5 and 20 mV to reach 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 and 1.0 m KOH, and AC&#8208;HEA&#8208;CuAgAuIrRu delivers 208 and 200 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Moreover, a two&#8208;electrode electrolyzer made of the AC&#8208;HEA&#8208;CuAgAuIrRu bifunctional electrodes exhibit a low cell voltage of 1.48 and 1.49 V in the acidic and alkaline conditions at 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 for overall water splitting. Combining the enhanced catalytic activities from nanoscale amorphous structure and atom&#8208;level synergistic catalyst in AC&#8208;HEAs provides an effective pathway for pH&#8208;universal electrocatalysts of water splitting.</description>
      <author>Xueqian Yu, Xianzu Gong, Haiqing Qiao, Xiaobing Liu, Chao Ma, Ruijuan Xiao, Ran Li, Zhang Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Organic Anions on Metal Hydroxide Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01907</link>
      <description>Shujin Hou, Li&#8208;Li Xu, Soumya Mukherjee, Jian Zhou, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Zhenyu Zhou, Shengli Zhang, Xiaoxin Ma, Julien Warnan, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Roland A. Fischer, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401074450

                Structural metamorphosis of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) eliciting highly active metal-hydroxide catalysts has come to the fore lately, with much promise. However, the role of organic ligands leaching into electrolytes during alkaline hydrolysis remains unclear. Here, we elucidate the influence of organic carboxylate anions on a family of Ni or NiFe-based hydroxide type catalysts during the oxygen evolution reaction. After excluding interfering variables, i.e., electrolyte purity, Ohmic loss, and electrolyte pH, the experimental results indicate that adding organic anions to the electrolyte profoundly impacts the redox potential of the Ni species versus with only a negligible effect on the oxygen evolution activities. In-depth studies demonstrate plausible reasons behind those observations and allude to far-reaching implications in controlling electrocatalysis in MOFs, mainly where compositional modularity entails fine-tuning organic anions.</description>
      <author>Shujin Hou, Li&#8208;Li Xu, Soumya Mukherjee, Jian Zhou, Kun&#8208;Ting Song, Zhenyu Zhou, Shengli Zhang, Xiaoxin Ma, Julien Warnan, Aliaksandr S. Bandarenka, Roland A. Fischer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding intermediates adsorption in oxygen reduction/evolution reactions from the local aromaticities of catalyst sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160843</link>
      <description>Yinsheng Zhao, Peng Jin, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401059280

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yinsheng Zhao, Peng Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparent TiO2 nanotubes supporting silver sulfide for photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01440e</link>
      <description>Wiktoria Lipi&#324;ska, Stefania Wolff, Katharina E. Dehm, Simon Hager, Justyna Gumieniak, Agnieszka Kramek, Ryan W. Crisp, Emerson Coy, Katarzyna Grochowska, Katarzyna Siuzdak, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401029688

                Differences between photoelectrochemical and electrochemical activity were thoroughly investigated for the oxygen evolution reaction mediated by Ag</description>
      <author>Wiktoria Lipi&#324;ska, Stefania Wolff, Katharina E. Dehm, Simon Hager, Justyna Gumieniak, Agnieszka Kramek, Ryan W. Crisp, Emerson Coy, Katarzyna Grochowska, Katarzyna Siuzdak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01440e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Revealing the Electrocatalytic Mechanism for Hydrogen Energy Conversion System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405008</link>
      <description>Mingxin Cai, Yiran Zhang, Peilei He, Zhicheng Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401150154

                In light of the intensifying global energy crisis and the mounting demand for environmental protection, it is of vital importance to develop advanced hydrogen energy conversion systems. Electrolysis cells for hydrogen production and fuel cell devices for hydrogen utilization are indispensable in hydrogen energy conversion. As one of the electrolysis cells, water splitting involves two electrochemical reactions, hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. And oxygen reduction reaction coupled with hydrogen oxidation reaction, represent the core electrocatalytic reactions in fuel cell devices. However, the inherent complexity and the lack of a clear understanding of the structure-performance relationship of these electrocatalytic reactions, have posed significant challenges to the advancement of research in this field. In this work, the recent development in revealing the mechanism of electrocatalytic reactions in hydrogen energy conversion systems is reviewed, including in situ characterization and theoretical calculation. First, the working principles and applications of operando measurements in unveiling the reaction mechanism are systematically introduced. Then the application of theoretical calculations in the design of catalysts and the investigation of the reaction mechanism are discussed. Furthermore, the challenges and opportunities are also summarized and discussed for paving the development of hydrogen energy conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Mingxin Cai, Yiran Zhang, Peilei He, Zhicheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Blue-Green Gold</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003219156-25</link>
      <description>Sai Kishore Butti, M. Madhumala, Nivedita Sahu, S. Sridhar, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401079888

                Photo-biocatalysts are one of nature's finest in transmuting inorganic carbon into complex organic molecules using solar energy through the photosynthetic machinery. Photosynthesis has been the governing factor for global sustenance, keeping the detrimental fluctuations caused by natural and man-made activities at bay. The photo-biocatalysts cluster encompasses microalgae, cyanobacteria, photobacteria, and plants, each of which is uniquely equipped with the potential to produce essential biocommodities and sequester CO2. The numerous applications of photo-biocatalysts include oxygen evolution, the foremost reason for life's existence, provide valuable resources to derive medicinal, edible, and biobased products, etc. Current photosynthetic research is rapidly progressing towards understanding the molecular mechanics, enhancing the light harvestation efficiency, and renewable energy production. This chapter elaborates on the carbon assimilation mechanism, the diverse range of products synthesized, and the versatility of the photo-biocatalysts to integrate with other bioprocesses which effectively collate into a biorefinery and further lead to a green bioeconomy.</description>
      <author>Sai Kishore Butti, M. Madhumala, Nivedita Sahu, S. Sridhar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003219156-25</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe2O4 Nanoparticles on Bio-Based Polymer Derived Nitrogen Doped Carbon as Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Li-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad69c9</link>
      <description>Pirapath Arkasalerks, Amarshi Patra, Kottisa Sumala Patnaik, Koichi Higashimine, Noriyoshi Matsumi, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401160320

                Abstract Lithium-air batteries (LABs) are gaining attention as a promising energy storage solution. Their theoretical energy density of 3,505 Whkg-1 exceeds that of conventional lithium-ion batteries (500&#8211;800 Whkg-1). The commercial viability and widespread adoption of lithium-air batteries face challenges such as poor cycling stability, limited lifespan, and unresolved side reactions. In this study, we synthesized spinel CoFe2O4-decorated on bio-based poly(2,5-benzimidazole) derived N-doped carbon for electrocatalysts. Notably, strong metal-substrate interaction (SMSI) was observed through various characterizations. The bifunctional electrocatalytic activity and stability toward oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction were significantly enhanced by the SMSI, The LAB demonstrated a high discharge capacity of 18,356 mAhg-1 at a current density of 200 mAg-1, maintaining a remarkable discharge capacity of 1,000 mAhg-1 even at a high current density of 400 mAg-1 for 200 cycles. CoFe2O4-decorated on bio-derived ABPBI holds promise as a practical air-breathing electrode for high-capacity rechargeable LABs.</description>
      <author>Pirapath Arkasalerks, Amarshi Patra, Kottisa Sumala Patnaik, Koichi Higashimine, Noriyoshi Matsumi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad69c9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of Acetone on the Kinetics of Water Electrolysis Examined at Polycrystalline Pt Electrode in Alkaline Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080488</link>
      <description>Aleksandra Adamicka, Tomasz Miko&#322;ajczyk, Mateusz Kuczy&#324;ski, Bogus&#322;aw Piero&#380;y&#324;ski, Catalysts. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401124839

                This study investigated the impact of acetone on the electrochemical behavior of polycrystalline platinum electrodes in 0.1 M NaOH solution, with respect to the kinetics of hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER) and indirectly to the underpotential deposition of hydrogen (UPDH). Cyclic voltammetry (CV) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) techniques were employed to analyze these processes for acetone concentrations ranging from 1.0 &#215; 10&#8722;6 to 1.0 &#215; 10&#8722;3 M. The addition of (CH3)2C=O enhanced the catalytic efficiency of alkaline water splitting, which was believed to be a result of a significant reduction in the surface tension phenomenon (due to mutual interaction of acetone and water molecules), thus considerably facilitating hydrogen bubble detachment from the Pt electrode. Key findings in this work are described with respect to facilitation of both the HER and the OER reactions&#8217; kinetics by the presence of acetone (also undergoing Pt electroreduction over the potential range for UPDH) in the working solution, without an electrode surface poisoning effect. The latter implies significant opportunities for traces of organic additives into alkaline electrolyte to improve the industrial alkaline water electrolysis process.</description>
      <author>Aleksandra Adamicka, Tomasz Miko&#322;ajczyk, Mateusz Kuczy&#324;ski, Bogus&#322;aw Piero&#380;y&#324;ski</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Enhanced Raman Scattering Coupled with In Situ Raman Spectroscopy for the Detection of the OER Mechanism: A Mini-Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03607</link>
      <description>Suprobhat Singha Roy, Sreenivasan Nagappan, Asha K. Satheesan, Arun Karmakar, Subrata Kundu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401094877

                Electrocatalysis has emerged as a pivotal field for sustainable energy and environmental solutions, fueling the development of diverse electrocatalysts over the past 2 decades. However, a comprehensive understanding of the intricate dynamical processes governing electrochemical reactions remains elusive and is hampering efficient catalyst design. Surface-sensitive techniques like in situ/operando Raman spectroscopy are indispensable for characterizing these dynamic processes and guiding the development of novel catalysts. This review systematically summarizes recent advances in employing in situ/operando Raman techniques, with a particular emphasis on surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS), for probing various electrocatalytic systems. It discusses the development, advantages, and available configurations of these Raman techniques. Moreover, the review underscores the potential of in situ SERS in unraveling the intricate mechanisms of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) through innovative strategies and methodological advancements. Notably, leveraging SERS for novel OER catalysts, such as single-atom catalysts, metal&#8211;organic frameworks, and electrolyte&#8211;electrode interfaces, can unveil unexplored reaction pathways, guiding the development of superior catalytic materials. Overcoming challenges and harnessing SERS' capabilities can deepen our mechanistic understanding of the OER, enabling the rational design of efficient and durable electrocatalysts crucial for renewable energy advancement.</description>
      <author>Suprobhat Singha Roy, Sreenivasan Nagappan, Asha K. Satheesan, Arun Karmakar, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Performance of a Hybrid NiCo2O4@NiFelt Electrode at Different Operating Temperatures and Electrolyte pH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153703</link>
      <description>Ataollah Niyati, Arianna Moranda, Pouya Beigzadeh Arough, Federico Navarra, Ombretta Paladino, Energies. 17(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401015177

                Transition metals such as nickel and cobalt as an alternative to Pt and Pd can be used for oxygen evolution reactions (OERs) and hydrogen production reactions (HERs) in alkaline environments, facilitating green hydrogen production as a sustainable alternative to fossil fuels. In this study, an NiCo2O4 catalyst was produced by a sono-hydrothermal method using urea as a hydrolysis agent. The electrochemical performance of the catalyst-coated NiFelt electrode was evaluated at different KOH concentrations (0.25, 0.5, and 1 M) and four operating temperatures in the interval of 20&#8211;80 &#176;C. The electrode characteristics were investigated via electrochemical spectroscopy (cyclic voltammetry, EIS, multistep chronopotentiometry, multistep chronoamperometry) using two different reference electrodes (Ag/AgCl and Hg/HgO), to obtain insight into the anodic and cathodic peaks. XRD, SEM, EDS, and TEM analyses confirmed the purity, structure, and nanoscale particle size (20&#8211;45 nm) of the NiCo2O4 catalyst. The electrode showed symmetric CV with Ag/AgCl, making this reference electrode more appropriate for capacitance measurements, while Hg/HgO proved advantageous for EIS in alkaline solutions due to reduced noise. The overpotential of the catalyst-coated NiFelt decreased by 108 mV at 10 mA/cm2 compared to bare NiFelt, showing a good potential for its application in anion exchange membranes and alkaline electrolyzers at an industrial scale.</description>
      <author>Ataollah Niyati, Arianna Moranda, Pouya Beigzadeh Arough, Federico Navarra, Ombretta Paladino</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Modification of Aluminum Oxide Inclusions in Bearing Steel under Different Cleanliness Conditions by Rare Earth Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14080861</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Guang-da Bao, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang, Metals. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401014801

                The impact of rare earth treatment on the chemical morphology evolution of non-metallic inclusions in bearing steel under different initial cleanliness conditions was studied through simulation. Thermodynamic calculations indicate that at an oxygen content of 0.001%, the evolution route of inclusions with increasing Ce content was Al2O3 &#8594; CeAl11O18 + CeAlO3 &#8594; CeAlO3 + Ce2O2S &#8594; Ce2O2S &#8594; Ce2O2S + CeS. As the initial oxygen content decreases, the proportion of CeAlO3 decreases, leading to easier conversion of CeAlO3 to Ce2O2S. Vacuum induction furnace experiments demonstrated that with an oxygen content of 0.001%, an increase in Ce content results in a gradual rise in the proportion of inclusions in steel sized 1~2 &#956;m. In contrast, the proportion of inclusions sized 2~5 &#956;m decreases. Consequently, the overall content of inclusions in steel decreases, along with a reduction in both the number density and average size of inclusions. Introducing bearing steel melt with approximately 0.01% Ce rare earth to bearing steel with initial oxygen contents of 0.0005%, 0.001%, and 0.0015% showed an evolution of inclusions from Ce2O2S and CeS to Ce2O3, CeAlO3, etc. The average inclusion size significantly increased from 0.7 &#956;m to 2.16 &#956;m. Morphologically, the transition of inclusions from precipitated to polymerized forms occurred as the initial oxygen content rose. High-temperature laser confocal microscopy experiments demonstrated that inclusions in low cleanliness conditions tend to agglomerate more than those in high cleanliness conditions, contributing to the increase in average size.</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Guang-da Bao, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14080861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution and persistence of SiO emission in nanosecond laser ablation plumes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ad687f</link>
      <description>Abdul Kalam Shaik, Mark C. Phillips, S. S. Harilal, Journal of Physics D Applied Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401067381

                Abstract Analyzing laser-produced plasmas (LPP) in a controlled oxygen-containing environment provides insight into the formation and evolution of molecular species through gas-phase oxidation. This study explores the role of ambient pressure and oxygen availability in forming SiO molecular species in laser ablation plumes. The self-emission emanating during the reactive ablation of Si targets was characterized by optical emission spectroscopy and optical time-of-flight techniques. Our results showed that the SiO species formation was greatly influenced by both the ambient pressure and oxygen availability. The intensity and the persistence of SiO emission bands are lower at higher oxygen concentrations, indicating they are depopulated by the formation of more complex silicon oxides. The oxygen partial pressure effects on plume chemistry showed that SiO formation is favored even with a minimal oxygen concentration in the environment.</description>
      <author>Abdul Kalam Shaik, Mark C. Phillips, S. S. Harilal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6463/ad687f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Evolution of Antisite Defect and Coupling Anionic Redox in High&#8208;Voltage Ultrahigh&#8208;Ni Cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410326</link>
      <description>Kang Wu, Peilin Ran, Wen Yin, Lunhua He, Bao&#8208;Tian Wang, Jinming Jian, Enyue Zhao, Jinkui Zhao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401037985

                High-voltage ultrahigh-Ni cathodes (LiNixCoyMn1-x-yO2, x &#8805; 0.9) can significantly enhance the energy density and cost-effectiveness of Li-ion batteries beyond current levels. However, severe Li-Ni antisite defects and their undetermined dynamic evolutions during high-voltage cycling limit the further development of these ultrahigh-Ni cathodes. In this study, we quantify the dynamic evolutions of the Li-Ni antisite defect using operando neutron diffraction and reveal its coupling relationship with anionic redox, another critical challenge restricting ultrahigh-Ni cathodes. We detect a clear Ni migration coupled with an unstable oxygen lattice, which accompanies the oxidation of oxygen anions at high voltages. Based on these findings, we propose that minimized Li-Ni antisite defects and controlled Ni migrations are essential for achieving stable high-voltage cycling structures in ultrahigh-Ni cathodes. This is further demonstrated by the optimized ultrahigh-Ni cathode, where reduced dynamic evolutions of the Li-Ni antisite defect effectively inhibit the anionic redox, enhancing the 4.5 V cycling stability.</description>
      <author>Kang Wu, Peilin Ran, Wen Yin, Lunhua He, Bao&#8208;Tian Wang, Jinming Jian, Enyue Zhao, Jinkui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab Initio Investigation of Oxygen Ion Diffusion in the Layered Perovskite System YSr2Cu2FeO7+&#948; (0 &amp;lt; &#948; &amp;lt; 1)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app14156586</link>
      <description>Marianela G&#243;mez-Toledo, M. Elena Arroyo-de Dompablo, Applied Sciences. 14(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401118505

                Extensive research on transition metal perovskite oxides as electrodes in solid oxide cells (SOC) has highlighted the potential ability of Fe-based perovskite oxides to catalyze oxygen reduction/evolution reactions (ORR/OER). The layered perovskite-type system YSr2Cu2FeO7+&#948; has been reported to possess attractive electrocatalytic properties. This work applies density functional theory (DFT) calculations to investigate oxygen ion diffusion in the YSr2Cu2FeO7+&#948; system. For &#948; = 0.5, it is found that in the most stable configuration, the oxygen vacancies in the FeO1+&#948; plane are arranged to form Fe ions in tetrahedral, square pyramid, and octahedral coordination. Ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations for YSr2Cu2FeO7.5 (&#948; = 0.5) yield an oxygen ion diffusion coefficient of 1.28 &#215; 10&#8722;7 cm2/s at 500 &#176;C (Ea = 0.37 eV). Complementary results for YSr2Cu2FeO7.2 (&#948; = 0.2) and YSr2Cu2FeO7.75 (&#948; = 0.75) indicate that the oxygen diffusion occurs in the FeO1+&#948; plane, and depends on the oxygen vacancies distribution around the Fe centers.</description>
      <author>Marianela G&#243;mez-Toledo, M. Elena Arroyo-de Dompablo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app14156586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Evolution of Antisite Defect and Coupling Anionic Redox in High&#8208;Voltage Ultrahigh&#8208;Ni Cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410326</link>
      <description>Kang Wu, Peilin Ran, Wen Yin, Lunhua He, Bao&#8208;Tian Wang, Jinming Jian, Enyue Zhao, Jinkui Zhao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401038097

                High&#8208;voltage ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathodes (LiNixCoyMn1&#8722;x&#8722;yO2, x &#8805; 0.9) can significantly enhance the energy density and cost&#8208;effectiveness of Li&#8208;ion batteries beyond current levels. However, severe Li&#8208;Ni antisite defects and their undetermined dynamic evolutions during high&#8208;voltage cycling limit the further development of these ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathodes. In this study, we quantify the dynamic evolutions of the Li&#8208;Ni antisite defect using operando neutron diffraction and reveal its coupling relationship with anionic redox, another critical challenge restricting ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathodes. We detect a clear Ni migration coupled with an unstable oxygen lattice, which accompanies the oxidation of oxygen anions at high voltages. Based on these findings, we propose that minimized Li&#8208;Ni antisite defects and controlled Ni migrations are essential for achieving stable high&#8208;voltage cycling structures in ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathodes. This is further demonstrated by the optimized ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathode, where reduced dynamic evolutions of the Li&#8208;Ni antisite defect effectively inhibit the anionic redox, enhancing the 4.5 V cycling stability.</description>
      <author>Kang Wu, Peilin Ran, Wen Yin, Lunhua He, Bao&#8208;Tian Wang, Jinming Jian, Enyue Zhao, Jinkui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time-Dependent Study of Inclusions in Bearing Steel Subjected to Rare Earth Treatment with Secondary Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14080697</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Guang-da Bao, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang, Crystals. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401111828

                Due to the strong reducibility and chemical activity of rare earths, the diffusion behavior and secondary oxidation of rare earths in the steel liquid will also have a significant impact on the modified products when rare earths are added to bearing steel, resulting in poor control of distribution behavior. Therefore, this paper studies the influence of time factors on the evolution of rare earth inclusions. The inclusion evolution behavior at different times when the bearing steel was treated with rare earths and subjected to secondary oxidation was simulated at 1873 K (1600 &#176;C). At a cerium content of 0.012% in steel and a secondary oxidation of 0.0025%, the cerium content in steel and the total oxygen (T.O.) content in steel were determined at the 30 s, 3 min, 5 min, and 7 min after the addition and the inclusions were characterized by automatic scanning electron microscopy. The results demonstrated the formation of a cerium-enriched zone after the addition of the cerium alloy to the steel. As time progressed, a considerable number of inclusions were generated in the cerium-enriched zone, which subsequently disappeared. The trend in the composition of the inclusions can be described as Al2O3 &#8594; Ce2O2S + CeS &#8594; Ce2O2S. The final composition of the inclusions matches the thermodynamic phase diagram. Following the addition of the transient oxidant Fe2O3 to the molten steel, an oxygen-enriched zone was formed. As time progressed, a considerable number of inclusions were generated in the oxygen-enriched zone and subsequently disappeared. The trend of inclusions composition was as follows: Ce2O3 + CeAlO3 + Al2O3 &#8594; Ce2O3 + CeAlO3 &#8594; Ce2O2S + CeAlO3. The final inclusion composition coincides with the thermodynamic phase diagram.</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Guang-da Bao, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14080697</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetite geochemistry of giant alkalic-type epithermal gold deposits: Insights into the magmatic evolution of mineralized alkaline systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1144/sp551-2024-57</link>
      <description>Micha&#235;l Schirra, Zolt&#225;n Zajacz, Daniel M&#252;ller, Geological Society London Special Publications. 551(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401134345

                Magnetite, a common mineral in alkaline magmatic complexes hosting giant epithermal Au deposits, is examined to obtain insights into the magmatic evolution and ore fertility of alkaline systems. Textural and compositional analyses of magmatic magnetite from Cripple Creek, USA, and Lihir Island, Papua New Guinea, reveal distinct magma sources and evolution paths. High HFSE concentrations and high La/Yb ratios in magnetite from Cripple Creek suggest relatively low-degree partial melting of lithospheric and asthenospheric mantle sources, whereas magnetite from Lihir Island indicates higher degree partial melting from subduction-modified mantle. Chromium concentrations track magma evolution, while V systematics record decreasing oxygen fugacity with magma differentiation. Sulfide saturation is observed at Cripple Creek, potentially affecting ore fertility. Magnetite itself bears the capability to scavenge Au from melts as indicated by Au concentrations of up to 40 ng/g. This might point towards elevated Au concentrations in the parental magmas, although experimental data on Au partitioning is lacking. Magnetite compositions overlap across different mineralization styles, challenging its reliability as an exploration tool but analysis of noble metals in magnetite and its inclusion cargo could offer promising alternative approaches. Overall, magnetite serves as a valuable tool for investigating ore deposit petrogenesis and holds potential for exploration.</description>
      <author>Micha&#235;l Schirra, Zolt&#225;n Zajacz, Daniel M&#252;ller</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1144/sp551-2024-57</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure and oxidation behaviour of Mo&#8211;Si&#8211;B&#8211;Hf alloys at 800 &#176;C and 1100 &#176;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/02670836241266451</link>
      <description>Shuo Sun, Xiaohui Lin, Xuanqiao Gao, Yanchao Li, Jing Liang, Wei Zai, Wen Zhang, Materials Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401033451

                The influences of the microstructure evolution and oxidation behaviour of Hf-modified Mo&#8211;12Si&#8211;12B alloys were systematically studied at 800 &#176;C and 1100 &#176;C. Vickers hardness tests show that the Hf addition increases the hardness of Mo&#8211;Si&#8211;B&#8211;Hf alloys. The oxidation experiments were conducted at 800 &#176;C and 1100 &#176;C for 12 h; the detailed analysis revealed that the formation of HfSiO 4 in Mo&#8211;12Si&#8211;12B&#8211;10Hf alloy can effectively decrease the content of oxygen and make the surface of the oxide layer more complete at 800 &#176;C. At 1100&#176;C, the distinct difference in the expansion coefficient among the oxide films results in the formation of cracks and holes in Mo&#8211;12Si&#8211;12B&#8211;10Hf alloy, so the Mo&#8211;12Si&#8211;12B&#8211;10Hf alloy shows poor oxidation resistance.</description>
      <author>Shuo Sun, Xiaohui Lin, Xuanqiao Gao, Yanchao Li, Jing Liang, Wei Zai, Wen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/02670836241266451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biological Fuel Cells with Oxygenic Photosynthetic Microorganisms for Wastewater Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003219194-6</link>
      <description>Cristina Moisescu, Ana-Valentina Ardelean, Serban Stamatin, Adrian Ghinea, Matei-Tom Iacob, Sanda Voinea, Ioan Stamatin, I. Ardelean, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401080372

                For the treatment of wastewater, biological fuel cells (BFCs) using heterotrophic microorganisms have received much attention in the last 15 years. Lately, electrochemical devices such as BFCs using oxygenic phototrophic microorganisms (OPhM) that can simultaneously perform wastewater treatment, biomass synthesis, O2 evolution, and electricity generation have begun to receive special consideration. In this chapter we aim to summarize the main published results in this growing field of wastewater treatment, focusing on different BFCs that use OPhM in the anode or cathode compartment, as well as to propose some future trends. These trends are based on OPhM's already-proven abilities to donate electrons directly to the anode or to receive electrons directly from the cathode, with significant expectations from the appropriate genetic modification of living cells, as well as the modification of electrodes at the nanoscale level.</description>
      <author>Cristina Moisescu, Ana-Valentina Ardelean, Serban Stamatin, Adrian Ghinea, Matei-Tom Iacob, Sanda Voinea, Ioan Stamatin, I. Ardelean</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003219194-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORIGIN AND EVOLUTION OF A PEAT BOG FROM NORTHEASTERN ROMANIA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30892/auog.34201-918</link>
      <description>Gheorghe B&#259;d&#259;lu&#355;&#259;, Carmen&#8211;Andreea B&#259;d&#259;lu&#355;&#259;, Marcel M&#238;ndrescu, Diana ISTRATE, Ionu&#539; Bogdan NIGA, Analele Universit&#259;&#355;ii din Oradea Seria Geografie. 34(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401184871

                Peatlands are highly sensitive ecosystems that respond to hydrological, climatic, and geomorphological changes. In this study, we investigate the origin and historical evolution of a peatland located in Northeastern Romania, on the Suceava plateau. Our approach includes the analysis of historical maps and physical characteristics of both the peat (grain size, LOI - loss on ignition) and water (pH, dissolved oxygen, electrical conductivity). Our findings suggest that the development of this peatland has been more prominent along the surface than the depth. The presence of gravel and sand at the base of the peat deposit, along with surface morphological evidence, supports the hypothesis that this peatland originated in an ancient paleomeander. pH analysis indicates that the peatland is mesotrophic, while granulometric and LOI analyses suggest a fluviogenic origin.The significant changes observed in the sedimentary structure of the peatland may be attributed to climate change, with potential anthropogenic influences over the past 50 years. Furthermore, our study contributes valuable insights to geomorphological research in the Suceava valley, revealing visible changes spanning the last 250 years.</description>
      <author>Gheorghe B&#259;d&#259;lu&#355;&#259;, Carmen&#8211;Andreea B&#259;d&#259;lu&#355;&#259;, Marcel M&#238;ndrescu, Diana ISTRATE, Ionu&#539; Bogdan NIGA</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30892/auog.34201-918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History of Earth evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/85/20240962</link>
      <description>Yifei Zhang, Applied and Computational Engineering. 85(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401185646

                The paper delves deeply into crucial subjects spanning the birth of our solar system to humanitys ascendancy on Earth. It aims to enable humankind to gain a deeper understanding of our own origins and the Earths genesis and evolution. Given that Earth is our sole habitat, we must gain insights into the conditions necessary for it to sustain life or identify potential terrestrial planets suitable for human habitation. Throughout its history, Earth has weathered countless encounters with meteorites, comets, and asteroids, dating back to the formation of the solar system. These events, though rare, played a pivotal role in shaping our planets atmosphere, magnetic field, and unique environmental characteristics. Perhaps the most extraordinary aspect of Earths history is the emergence of life itselfa true marvel. Starting with single-celled protists, life evolved into complex multicellular organisms. Yet, a pivotal moment in Earths history came with a momentous global extinction event triggered by the rise of oxygen. This event reshaped the planets natural ecosystem, leading to the extinction of many species and the emergence of new ones. Humanitys own journey, navigating the depths of history, eventually led to our dominance over the Earth.</description>
      <author>Yifei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/85/20240962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of the Surface Magnetic Dead Layer in Rare&#8208;Earth Titanates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400489</link>
      <description>Rapha&#235;l Aeschlimann, Manuel Bib&#232;s, Alexandre Gloter, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401038578

                Abstract Perovskite rare&#8208;earth titanates RTiO 3 display a rich array of magnetic and electronic properties, with a Mott&#8208;insulating ground state and ferro&#8208; or antiferromagnetic spin orders depending on the rare&#8208;earth R. The nominal Ti valence is 3+ with a corresponding 3 d 1 configuration. Yet, at the surface of both bulk and thin films of RTiO 3 , the Ti valence has been found to strongly deviate towards the more stable 4+ state, adversely affecting magnetic properties. While this finding is rather ubiquitous, its exact origin is still poorly understood, which hampers the integration of RTiO 3 into complex heterostructures harnessing their rich physics. Here, scanning transmission electron microscope and electron energy loss spectroscopy experiments are used to analyze the top part of an epitaxial DyTiO 3 thin film displaying a well&#8208;developed Ti 4+ &#8208;rich layer over several nanometres. It shows that this valence evolution is related to a combination of short&#8208;range ordered interstitial oxygen planes and Ti&#8208;Dy cationic imbalance. Both defects synergistically contribute to enough hole doping for a complete transition toward Ti 4+ over a few unit&#8208;cells from the surface while a structure primarily of the perovskite&#8208;type is maintained.</description>
      <author>Rapha&#235;l Aeschlimann, Manuel Bib&#232;s, Alexandre Gloter</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging insights into the pathogenesis and therapeutic strategies for vascular endothelial injury-associated diseases: focus on mitochondrial dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10456-024-09938-4</link>
      <description>Boxian Pang, Guangtong Dong, Tieliang Pang, Xinyao Sun, Xin Liu, Yifeng Nie, Xing Chang, Angiogenesis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401010620

                As a vital component of blood vessels, endothelial cells play a key role in maintaining overall physiological function by residing between circulating blood and semi-solid tissue. Various stress stimuli can induce endothelial injury, leading to the onset of corresponding diseases in the body. In recent years, the importance of mitochondria in vascular endothelial injury has become increasingly apparent. Mitochondria, as the primary site of cellular aerobic respiration and the organelle for "energy information transfer," can detect endothelial cell damage by integrating and receiving various external stress signals. The generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and mitochondrial dysfunction often determine the evolution of endothelial cell injury towards necrosis or apoptosis. Therefore, mitochondria are closely associated with endothelial cell function, helping to determine the progression of clinical diseases. This article comprehensively reviews the interconnection and pathogenesis of mitochondrial-induced vascular endothelial cell injury in cardiovascular diseases, renal diseases, pulmonary-related diseases, cerebrovascular diseases, and microvascular diseases associated with diabetes. Corresponding therapeutic approaches are also provided. Additionally, strategies for using clinical drugs to treat vascular endothelial injury-based diseases are discussed, aiming to offer new insights and treatment options for the clinical diagnosis of related vascular injuries.</description>
      <author>Boxian Pang, Guangtong Dong, Tieliang Pang, Xinyao Sun, Xin Liu, Yifeng Nie, Xing Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10456-024-09938-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Ion Transport in the Upper Ionosphere of Mars: Exploring the Effect of Crustal Magnetic Fields</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024ja032500</link>
      <description>A. R. Renzaglia, T. E. Cravens, O. Hamil, Journal of Geophysical Research Space Physics. 129(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401108703

                Abstract Statistically ion and electron densities are enhanced above strong crustal magnetic field regions according to measurements made by the Mars Atmosphere and Volatile Evolution (MAVEN) spacecraft. Plasma created by ionization of neutrals in the lower ionosphere (where chemistry dominates) flows upward and becomes trapped on closed magnetic field loops. Enhanced ion density in the ionosphere (particularly O 2+) is associated with enhanced photochemical escape of atomic oxygen. This paper presents a quasi&#8208;1D multi&#8208;fluid time&#8208;dependent model of the Martian ionosphere for nine ion species. Ionospheric temperatures are adopted but ion densities and velocities (along the field lines) are determined using a numerical solution of the continuity and momentum equations. Diurnal effects are explored by varying photoionization rates. Three crustal field cases are considered: a low altitude closed, a high altitude closed, and a high altitude open field line. Additionally, a case with no crustal field is modeled to provide a comparison between regions with and without crustal fields in the upper Martian ionosphere. Model results show higher ion and electron densities in the crustal field cases than in the purely induced field case. Additionally, we find that densities are generally higher on the closed field lines than on the open field lines, and ion velocities are generally up the field lines, away from the Martian surface. We also find that velocities are larger on the open field line case. We compare modeled density results to MAVEN data and find general agreement. Implications for atmospheric escape, particularly photochemical escape of O, are also discussed.</description>
      <author>A. R. Renzaglia, T. E. Cravens, O. Hamil</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024ja032500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genomic Evolution of Influenza During the 2023-2024 Season, the Johns Hopkins Health System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcv.2024.105718</link>
      <description>Madeline Yunker, David A. Villafuerte, Amary Fall, Julie M. Norton, Omar Abdullah, Richard E. Rothman, Katherine Fenstermacher, C. Paul Morris, Andrew Pekosz, Eili Klein, Heba H. Mostafa, Journal of Clinical Virology. 174(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401022367

                Influenza, a human disease caused by viruses in the Orthomyxoviridae family, is estimated to infect 5% -10 % of adults and 20% -30 % of children annually. Influenza A (IAV) and Influenza B (IBV) viruses accumulate amino acid substitutions (AAS) in the hemagglutinin (HA) and neuraminidase (NA) proteins seasonally. These changes, as well as the dominating viral subtypes, vary depending on geographical location, which may impact disease prevalence and the severity of the season. Genomic surveillance is crucial for capturing circulation patterns and characterizing AAS that may affect disease outcomes, vaccine efficacy, or antiviral drug activities. In this study, whole-genome sequencing of IAV and IBV was attempted on positive remnant clinical samples (587) collected from 580 patients between June 2023 and February 2024 in the Johns Hopkins Health System (JHHS). Full-length HA segments were obtained from 424 (72.2 %) samples. H1N1pdm09 (71.7 %) was the predominant IAV subtype, followed by H3N2 (16.7 %) and IBV-Victoria clade V1A.3a.2 (11.6 %). Within H1N1pdm09 HA sequences, the 6B1A.5a.2a.1 (60.5 %) clade was the most represented. Full-length NA segments were obtained from 421 (71.7 %) samples. Within H1N1pdm09 and IBV, AAS previously proposed to change susceptibility to NA inhibitors were infrequently detected. Phylogeny of HA and NA demonstrated heterogeneous HA and NA H1N1pdm09 and IBV subclades. No significant differences were observed in admission rates or use of supplemental oxygen between different subtypes or clades. Influenza virus genomic surveillance is essential for understanding the seasonal evolution of influenza viruses and their association with disease prevalence and outcomes.</description>
      <author>Madeline Yunker, David A. Villafuerte, Amary Fall, Julie M. Norton, Omar Abdullah, Richard E. Rothman, Katherine Fenstermacher, C. Paul Morris, Andrew Pekosz, Eili Klein, Heba H. Mostafa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcv.2024.105718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Common Misconceptions in the Analysis of Critical Figures of Merit for Functioning Electrocatalyst/Semiconductor Photoelectrocatalysts under Solar Water-Splitting Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01365</link>
      <description>Aarti Mathur, Ahmet Sert, Suljo Linic, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401069559

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. ACS Energy LettersASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse ViewpointJuly 29, 2024Common Misconceptions in the Analysis of Critical Figures of Merit for Functioning Electrocatalyst/Semiconductor Photoelectrocatalysts under Solar Water-Splitting ConditionsClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Aarti MathurAarti MathurDepartment of Chemical Engineering, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United StatesCatalysis Science and Technology Institute, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United StatesMore by Aarti MathurAhmet SertAhmet SertDepartment of Chemical Engineering, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United StatesCatalysis Science and Technology Institute, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United StatesMore by Ahmet Serthttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-2802-3485Suljo Linic*Suljo LinicDepartment of Chemical Engineering, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United StatesCatalysis Science and Technology Institute, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48109, United States*[email protected]More by Suljo Linichttps://orcid.org/0000-0003-2153-6755Open PDFACS Energy LettersCite this: ACS Energy Lett. 2024, 9, XXX, 4136&#8211;4146Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01365https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01365Published July 29, 2024 Publication History Received 19 May 2024Accepted 18 July 2024Published online 29 July 2024article-commentary&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.InterfacesLayersNanoparticlesOxidesPhotovoltagePhotoelectrocatalytic solar water-splitting systems employ a semiconductor (SC) light absorber, which generates a photovoltage when illuminated, coupled to metal nanoparticle electrocatalysts (ECs) that drive oxygen (OER) and hydrogen evolution (HER) half-reactions. (1,2) The thermodynamic energy requirement to split water is 1.23 V, and when kinetic and ohmic losses are accounted for, around 1.6 V (&#177;0.2 V) of photovoltage must be generated by the SC. (3&#8722;5) Naturally, higher efficiencies can be achieved using multiple SC light absorbers. (6) For example, a combination of two SCs with band gaps between 1 and 1.4 eV for the bottom SC, and 1.7&#8211;2.1 eV for the top SC, has a maximum solar-to-hydrogen (STH) efficiency of over 10%, which could be commercially viable for certain device architectures. (7,8) Silicon, with a band gap of &#8764;1.1 eV, has emerged as a viable candidate as a low-band-gap SC material, mainly due to its earth abundance and use in the solar cell industry. (9)One problem with using Si in photoelectrochemical water-splitting devices is its lack of stability under reaction conditions. (10,11) This is particularly the case for highly oxidizing OER conditions where the operating potential of the EC needs to be above &#8764;1.6 V vs RHE. Under these conditions, there is a strong thermodynamic driving force to oxidize the Si SC. (12) As shown in Figure 1a, similar issues impact a range of other optically attractive SCs with band gaps between 1.0 and 2.4 eV. In a large majority of cases, the SC light absorbers are thermodynamically or kinetically easier to oxidize than water. (13) As a result, the SC will either passivate to form a stable surface oxide or corrode to dissolve into the solution.Figure 1Figure 1. (a) Band edge positions (V vs NHE) at pH = 0 for common SCs used in photoelectrochemical devices. The conduction and valence band positions are shown in the bottom and top bars, respectively, with OER and HER thermodynamic potentials represented as blue and green dashed lines, respectively. The red and blue bars are the oxidation and reduction potentials of each SC. SC will self-oxidize if the oxidation potential is below the OER potential and self-reduce if the reduction potential is above the HER potential. (b, c) STEM cross-sectional images of (b) a Ni nanoparticle electrodeposited on an n-Si wafer, tested under OER reaction conditions, and (c) a planar Ni EC evaporated on an n-Si wafer, tested under OER reaction conditions. (d) Experimental photovoltage plotted for three experimental Ni/n-Si systems. In blue is pf-Ni/n-Si, in orange is pf-Ni/SiO2/n-Si, and in yellow is np-Ni/SiO2/n-Si. Data in panel (a) adapted from ref (13). Remaining data adapted from ref (49).High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThe high thermodynamic driving force to oxidize the SCs has practical consequences. (14) In Figure 1b, we show that in an EC/SC system that employs nanoparticles of Ni on Si (np-Ni/n-Si, where np- stands for nanoparticle), a Si oxide layer evolves on top of Si and the regions between the Ni catalysts and the Si SC are oxidized. The evolved SiO2 insulating layers protect the Si SC from further degradation. In addition, we measured (Figure 1d) that these oxidized np-Ni/Si photoelectrocatalysts generate significantly higher photovoltages under OER conditions compared to planar films of the identical ECs (Ni) covering the same Si SC (pf-Ni/n-Si, where pf- stands for planar film), shown in Figure 1c, which does not evolve interfacial SiO2 under reaction conditions due to the interface being screened from the electrolyte. (15&#8722;18)It is important to note that, while Si can be partially protected by the growth of the SiO2 layers, many other optically attractive SCs will oxidize and degrade by evolving oxidized species into the electrolyte. It has been shown that these unstable SCs can be somewhat protected against this oxidation by the introduction of protective layers of more stable materials. For example, it has been demonstrated that fabricating stable oxide insulator layers (e.g., TiO2, Al2O3, or HfO2) at the EC/SC interface and forming metal&#8211;insulator&#8211;semiconductor (MIS) junctions improves the system stability. (19&#8722;22)The focus of this Viewpoint is to discuss how the physical properties and atomistic features of the oxidized EC/SC interfaces impact the performance of these systems. Specifically, we aim to highlight common misconceptions present in the literature in the evaluation of these systems and in the description of underlying physical processes that govern their performance. We also provide guidelines on how to experimentally measure the physical properties of these systems, which are critical for our understanding of the mechanisms responsible for the performance. We use Ni ECs on a Si light absorber as a model case study to illustrate the interplay between the physical and chemical phenomena present in these systems. Insights obtained from this system should be generalizable to other SC systems which form surface oxides under reaction conditions. Examples include InP, (23&#8722;25) GaAs, (26) GaxIn1&#8211;xP, (27,28) and BiVO4, (14,29) which are of great interest for practical photoelectrochemical applications. However, we note that specific EC/SC combinations will require detailed characterization to determine how system-specific oxidation processes will dictate their performance. Separating Electrocatalytic Activity and PhotovoltageWhen evaluating the performance of photoelectrochemical systems executing electrocatalytic half-reactions, the key macroscopic performance metrics are electrocatalytic activity and photovoltage. In principle, electrocatalytic activity quantifies the ability of the ECs to drive electrocatalytic half-reactions, and superior ECs will drive the reaction with lower overpotentials. (30) Photovoltage is a measure of the propensity of the SC to generate an electromotive force that is imparted on the ECs. (31,32) Photovoltage is a function of the inherent properties of the SC light absorber and the quality of the EC/SC interface. One critical objective of fundamental research has been to identify EC/SC systems with photovoltage and electrocatalytic activity as high as possible.It is somewhat challenging to evaluate these two performance metrics in functioning photoelectrocatalytic systems in a typical three-electrode experimental setup used to assess the rate of reaction (i.e., current density) as a function of voltage. Improvements in both electrocatalysis and photovoltage show up as a lower overpotential required to execute the reaction at a particular rate. We also note that while measuring current density alone without quantifying reaction products does not always lead to an accurate assessment of the desired product formation rate, OER on redox-active ECs (e.g., Ni) has consistently demonstrated high Faradaic efficiencies, and the OER rate can most often be equated to the measured oxidation current. (16,33)To illustrate the difficulty in deconvoluting photovoltage from catalytic activity, the data in Figure 2a show the performance of an illuminated np-Ni/n-Si sample, containing nanoparticles of Ni on planar n-Si SC under basic (i.e., 1 M KOH) OER conditions, measured in a classical three-electrode setup. The data show improvements in the OER onset potential as a function of oxidation/reduction cycling. Similar data have also been interpreted as improvements to the photovoltage of the EC/SC systems as a function of potential cycling. (15,34,35) The improvements in the photovoltage could be due to the gradual evolution of the EC/SC interface that leads to atomistic changes in junction characteristics that affect the photovoltage. For example, the oxidation of the metal EC could change the effective barrier height of the junction under reaction conditions. (36) This improvement in onset potential, however, could also be a consequence of the reaction-conditions-induced improvements in electrocatalysis. Improvements in electrocatalysis could be due to the reaction-induced changes in the surface area of the EC or incorporation of some impurities from the electrolyte into the EC or even the evolution of new sites (perhaps at the EC/SC interface) that could lead to an increase in the measured reaction rates. (37&#8722;42)Figure 2Figure 2. (a) Current density versus voltage (J&#8211;V) plots of the illuminated np-Ni/n-Si system over 10&#8211;30 cyclic voltammetry sweeps under OER conditions in a base. (b) Nanoparticle size distributions for the np-Ni/n-Si and np-Ni/p+-Si systems shown in panels (a) and (c). (c) Current density versus voltage plots (J&#8211;V) of dark np-Ni/p+-Si system over 10&#8211;30 cyclic voltammetry sweeps under OER conditions in a base. (d) Photovoltage as a function of cyclic voltammetry sweeps for pf-Ni/n-Si, pf-Ni/SiO2/n-Si, and np-Ni/n-Si, showing that the photovoltage remains nearly constant under the reaction conditions. Data adapted from ref (49).High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideOne way to deconvolute the electrocatalytic activity from the photovoltage is to perform electrochemical measurements in the dark using an EC with a form factor (i.e., size distribution, coverage, and shape of metal nanoparticles) that is approximately equal to that of the photoelectrocatalytic system of interest. Ideally, this EC should be deposited on a SC degenerately doped with the opposite charge. If inverse doping of the SC is not possible, the EC could be deposited on an inert conductive support (e.g., FTO) using identical synthesis methods. In the above case of a Ni/Si system, this can be done by depositing Ni nanoparticles on a p+-type Si (np-Ni/p+-Si) substrate which provides a steady supply of holes for water oxidation (i.e., OER). The similarity between the systems used in the dark electrocatalytic and the light-on photoelectrocatalytic measurements (shown in Figure 2b) in principle supposes that reaction-induced changes to the ECs will be identical, allowing us to isolate the changes in photovoltage. For example, the data in Figure 2a,c show examples of illuminated and dark electrocatalytic OER measurements for np-Ni/n-Si and np-Ni/p+-Si, respectively, over 30 cycles. The data show similar trends in changes in the OER onset potential for both systems under reaction conditions. This indicates that the improvements seen in the photoelectrochemical behavior of np-Ni/n-Si (Figure 2a) are mainly due to the improvements in the electrocatalytic behavior of the system (Figure 2c) and not due to the improvements in photovoltage. This is shown in Figure 2d, where photovoltages for both planar and nanoparticle Ni/n-Si systems are plotted over 30 voltage sweeps. Here, we measured the photovoltage by comparing the onset potential at 1 mA cm&#8211;2 for illuminated n-Si and dark electrochemical p+-Si samples. The data show that the photovoltage is relatively constant for all systems when averaged over multiple samples.The data in Figure 2d show that for Ni/Si systems the photovoltage generated by the system does not change over multiple oxidation and reduction cycling steps and that the changes in the current&#8211;voltage data in Figure 2a can be attributed to the changes in the rates of electrocatalytic reactions on the Ni ECs. As we have mentioned, changes in the rates of electrocatalytic reactions can be a consequence of multiple variables, including the changes in the number of catalytically active sites and the changes in the inherent catalytic activity of the active sites. In the case of OER on Ni ECs, it appears that the number of active electrocatalytic sites increases over time as a consequence of oxidation/reduction cycling. This can be seen in the data in Figure 2a,c, which show that the Ni(OH)2/NiOOH oxidation and reduction peaks (observed just prior to the onset of OER) grow in magnitude for both illuminated and dark samples. This indicates an increase in the amount of catalytically active Ni sites during OER testing under basic conditions. (37,43,44) Furthermore, the data in Figure 2a,c also show a shift in the Ni oxidation peak to the right, closer to the onset of OER, indicating that the nature of the catalytic sites is changing. The shifting oxidation peak has been attributed to incorporation of Fe from the electrolyte, which has been shown to improve Ni catalytic activity as it integrates into the oxide shell. (43,45) Overall, this type of analysis demonstrates the need for detailed assessment of electrocatalytic activity in determining the performance of EC/SC photoelectrocatalysts. Impact of EC Coverage and EC/SC Interfacial Oxide Layers on PerformanceAnother critical complexity associated with np-EC/SC photoelectrocatalysts is that small changes in the atomistic features of the EC/SC interface can impact the system photovoltage. For example, oxide layers between the EC and the SC (Figure 1b) can influence the photovoltage. (46&#8722;48) This is supported by the data in Figures 1d and 2d which show that the np-Ni/Si OER photoelectrocatalyst (np- stands for nanoparticle) generates a higher photovoltage than the pf-Ni/Si and pf-Ni/SiO2/Si systems (pf- stands for planar film). We note that in one system (pf-Ni/Si), the Ni EC and n-Si SC are in direct contact with each other, with the Ni/Si interface protected from the aqueous electrolyte by the Ni EC. In the second system (pf-Ni/SiO2/Si), we grew a thin layer of SiO2 (&#8764;1.6 nm) between planar Ni and n-Si, and in the third (np-Ni/Si), the Ni EC is in the form of nanoparticles on planar SiO2/n-Si. In the np-Ni/Si system, the SiO2 layer is formed in a self-limiting growth process as soon as the EC/SC system is introduced to the electrolyte (i.e., the oxidation of the top layers of Si takes place upon the interaction of Si with the water electrolyte). The data show that the generated photovoltage is higher for the systems that contain an interfacial SiO2 layer and that it is highly dependent on the atomistic features of the EC/SC interface.To understand the differences in the measured photovoltages of these three systems, we can write an equation that captures the relationship between photovoltage and current for a photoelectrochemical system. This equation is essentially a variation of the illuminated diode equation: (19,20,46,49&#8722;51)|Vph|=nkTq[ln(Jph&#8722;JnetJs+1)](1)where Vph is the photovoltage, which is the electromotive force developed across the SC under illumination at a given rate (given Jnet), Jph is the photo-limiting current (i.e., the current of photogenerated minority charge carriers toward the metal ECs), Js is the reverse saturation recombination current density, n is the ideality factor, k is the Boltzmann's constant, T is the temperature (assumed to be 298 K), q is the elementary charge, and Jnet is the net current (i.e., the hole current plus the electron current). Under a given illumination intensity (i.e., fixed Jph), the photovoltage can be maximized by reducing the reverse saturation current, Js. The reverse saturation current is dominated by the thermionic emission recombination mechanism at the metal EC/SC interface, given as (52)Js=A*T2fcexp(&#8722;q&#981;bkT)(2)where fc is the interfacial EC/SC electrocatalyst coverage, A* is the Richardson's constant, and &#981;b is the barrier height of the system.The use of eq 1 allows us to determine photovoltage across different systems as a function of operating conditions and system parameters by inputting Jph, Jnet, Js, and n for a given experimental system. We set the illumination intensity to AM 1.5 G 1-sun illumination intensity in all cases, except for when light intensity is varied for the measurement of the ideality factor. We experimentally measured system photovoltages by comparing the voltage difference between light and dark samples at 1 mA/cm2 (i.e., Jnet = 1 mA/cm2) under OER conditions. We can look at each of the variables that govern the saturation current to attempt to quantify their impact on the performance of EC/SC photoelectrocatalysts.It is clear from eq 2 that Js should be impacted by the coverage of the metal EC nanoparticles on the SC (more specifically the EC/SC contact area). The main reason for this is that the EC/SC contact area provides a path for the majority charge carriers to reach the EC and recombine with the minority charge carriers, thus leading to parasitic loss. (53) If this contact area for recombination is smaller, and all other variables are kept constant (we assume that Jph is not affected by the EC/SC contact area due to negligible changes in the degree of parasitic light absorption among different samples), the recombination current will decrease. (54) For the case of Ni on Si, using a combination of top-down (SEM) and cross-sectional (STEM) imaging, we showed that the Ni nanoparticles assemble on n-Si in a spherical shape, with Ni/Si having a contact area that is &#8764;50% of the top-down geometrically projected area of the Ni nanoparticle. We note that the ratio of the top-down projected and the interfacial contact areas is ultimately affected by the degree of wetting between the EC and SC, which is in turn governed by the adhesion energy between them and the surface energies of the EC. (55) For the case of the Ni/Si system, we showed that the photovoltage increases by &#8764;110 mV when the EC coverage decreases from a planar film (fc = 1) to Ni nanoparticles (fc = 0.11, corresponding to geometrically projected SEM coverage = 0.21) when all other variables are kept constant. While this contribution is significant, it does not account for the total photovoltage difference between np-Ni/n-Si and planar Ni/n-Si photoelectrocatalysts observed experimentally.As we described above, another feature of the illuminated np-Ni/n-Si is that an interfacial layer of SiO2 develops between the EC and SC due to the tendency of Si to oxidize under reaction conditions. These interfacial oxide layers (shown in Figure 3a), which are often insulating in nature, can significantly impact the photovoltage of the illuminated EC/SC photoelectrocatalysts since they modulate the flux of energetic electrons and holes from the SC to EC, and therefore the recombination currents. (19) Therefore, the mathematical expression for Js (eq 2 above) needs to be modified to include the impact of the interfacial oxide layer on the flux of charge carriers. For example, if the majority charge carriers need to tunnel through an insulator, the tunneling probability through the interfacial oxide layer needs to be included in the expression for the reverse saturation current: (56)Js=fcA*T2exp(&#8722;q&#981;bkT)Tt(3)Tt=exp(&#8722;&#945;d&#981;e)(4)where Tt is the tunneling probability, &#981;e is the potential barrier height for tunneling of the majority charge carriers from SC to EC, d is the insulator thickness, and &#945; is a constant and is assumed to be unity (in &#197;&#8211;1/eV&#8211;1/2 units) in many cases. (20,47,57,58) The tunneling probability term describes the likelihood that an electron will tunnel through an oxide of thickness d and recombine with holes at the metal EC site, as illustrated in the band diagram in Figure 3b. The tunneling probability for a specific system can be measured independently or approximated based on the electronic structure of the SC and the insulating oxide. (50)Figure 3Figure 3. (a) High-resolution TEM cross section of the np-Ni/Si interface. (b) Illustration of the energy band diagram and the movement of charge carriers for a metal EC/insulator/SC interface in equilibrium with relevant physical parameters. Here, Esol is the solution Fermi level, Em is the metal EC Fermi level, Es is the SC Fermi level, ECB is the conduction band energy level, EVB is the valence band energy level, &#981;b is the barrier height, &#981;e is the potential barrier height for electrons, d is the thickness of the insulator, Vn is the difference between the SC Fermi level and the conduction band edge, Vfb is the flat band potential, Je is the electron current density, and Js is the reverse saturation current density. (c) Measured photovoltage as a function of the insulator thickness for pf-Ir/HfO2/n-Si and pf-Ni/HfO2/n-Si systems, with data adapted from refs (13) and (24).High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideBased on the analysis above, it is evident that the thickness of the evolved interfacial oxide (d) at the np-EC/SC interface will have a strong impact on the performance, as it will directly affect the tunneling probability (Tt). We have demonstrated this relationship between the insulating layer thickness and performance in multiple contributions (see Figure 3c). (19,20,50) In general, we found, as shown in Figure 3c, that the photovoltage generated by EC/SC photoelectrocatalysts exhibits a volcano behavior with respect to the thickness of the insulator between the EC and SC. The observed volcano behavior is a consequence of the fact that, in the limit of overly thick insulators, the performance is limited by the inability of photogenerated minority charge carriers to reach the EC and execute the desired reactions. On the other hand, a very thin oxide layer is not able to impose a significant tunneling barrier for the majority charge carriers, resulting in large recombination losses. The specific value of the insulator thickness that maximizes photovoltage ultimately depends on the inherent properties of the EC and SC junctions and the insulator layer. (19) In the specific case of planar Ni or Ir ECs on Si, the optimal thickness of the protective HfO2 layer was found to be &#8764;2 nm. We note that the photovoltage generated in the absence of HfO2 is higher for the Ir system compared to the Ni system due to the difference in the electric work functions of the two materials (i.e., Ir has a higher work function and therefore leads to a higher as-fabricated direct metal EC/SC barrier height). Impact of Non-idealities on the Barrier Height of SystemsAs we have described in the previous section, the interfacial oxide layers will impact the flux of charge carriers from the SC to the EC and therefore the overall photovoltage. In addition, the interfacial oxide layers can also impact the overall Schottky barrier height (&#981;b) of the system by, for example, changing the work function of the EC due to a change in its oxidation state under reaction conditions. (36) Also, defects and trap sites can evolve at the interface of these oxides with the SC and EC or within the oxide. (56,59) These states could add a level of complexity since they serve as recombination centers, which can lead to an electrical potential drop across the oxide layers. The presence of these defects leads to complex relationships between the ideality factor (n) and the Schottky barrier height (&#981;b) (see eqs 1 and 2 for the description of these variables).Generally, an ideal system will have n = 1, while non-idealities will increase n to values greater than 1. There are often misconceptions in the literature related to the physical meaning and experimental evaluation of the barrier height and its relation to the ideality factor. In general, these misconceptions seem to be related to the way barrier height and ideality factor are measured in these systems. The barrier height for planar EC/SC systems is generally measured experimentally using the Mott&#8211;Schottky method. Specifically, the Mott&#8211;Schottky method uses electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) over a wide range of applied potentials in a solution with a kinetically facile redox couple (e.g., ferri-/ferrocyanide (Fe(CN)63&#8211;/4&#8211;)) to measure the flat band potential (Vfb), which is then used to calculate the barrier height. This method extracts the barrier height in the form of what is known as the flat-band barrier height, which assumes an ideal case of n = 1. Physically, this flat-band condition refers to the situation when there is no electric field in the SC and the band energies of the SC at the interface are flat. Therefore, the non-idealities present at the interface (e.g., in the form of defects) will not be charged under flat-band conditions and will not contribute to the barrier height measured with the Mott&#8211;Schottky method. Consequently, the Mott&#8211;Schottky method measures the ideal barrier height (&#981;b,ideal) with n = 1. This barrier height (&#981;b,ideal) will always present an upper bound to the actual barrier height of the system (&#981;b). &#981;b is defined as the barrier height of the system at equilibrium when there is no applied voltage (i.e., zero bias). Under these conditions non-idealities will influence the system, and it is necessary to evaluate the ideality factor n to measure &#981;b. If the ideality factor n is larger than 1, the barrier height &#981;b will be lower than &#981;b,ideal. Unfortunately, one can find mistaken assertions in the EC/SC photoelectrocatalytic literature suggesting that non-idealities at the interface (n &gt; 1) can lead to higher barrier heights relative to the situations with no non-idealities (n = 1) and that these non-idealities improve the performance of systems.One approach to find &#981;b is to measure n and &#981;b,ideal and use these two variables to compute the barrier height. We can experimentally measure n by using the following equation to fit the open-circuit photovoltage to light intensity: (22,35,60)VOC&#8776;nkTqln(Jph)&#8722;nkTqln(Js)(5)where VOC is the open-circuit photovoltage. Based on this equation, varying the light intensity (i.e., varying the Jph) will lead to changes in the measured VOC. As a result, the plot of VOC versus ln(Jph) under varying light intensity conditions will yield a straight line with a slope that can be used to evaluate n and an intercept that can be used to evaluate Js. This analysis using eq 5 assumes that Js is independent of changes in the light intensity and the condition Jph/Js &#8811; 1 holds. These assumptions generally hold for the systems discussed here. The measured ideality factor (n) and ideal barrier height (&#981;b,ideal) values (obtained using the Mott&#8211;Schottky method) can be used to determine the actual barrier height (&#981;b) of the system under the reaction conditions using the following equation: (61)&#981;b=&#981;b,idealn+(n&#8722;1n)Vn(6)where Vn is the difference between the SC Fermi level and the conduction band edge, as illustrated in Figure 3b. Vn can be calculated using the following equation:Vn=kTqlnNCND(7)where NC is the effective density of states in the conduction band of the SC (this is an inherent property of the SC material) and ND is the doping density. ND is experimentally determined from the Mott&#8211;Schottky plot. (62)Data in Figure 4a show the actual barrier heights compared to the ideal barriers measured as described above for pf-Ni/n-Si and pf-Ni/SiO2/n-Si systems. The data show that the SiO2 interfacial layer lowers the actual barrier height, most likely due to the formation of defects and trap sites (i.e., non-idealities) at the additional interfaces introduced by the oxide layers. (63)Figure 4Figure 4. (a) Experimentally derived ideal barrier height and actual barrier height for pf-Ni/n-Si and pf-Ni/SiO2/n-Si systems. (b) Current density versus voltage (J&#8211;V) curves of pf-Ni/SiO2/Si systems as well as computational model fits and model error bounds. (c) Current density versus voltage (J&#8211;V) curves of np-Ni/Si systems as well as computational model fits and model error bounds. (d) Recombination currents depicted for three systems: pf-Ni/n-Si, pf-Ni/SiO2/n-Si, and np-Ni/n-Si, broken down further into contributions from the barrier height (&#981;b), oxide tunneling probability (Tt), and catalyst coverage (fc). Data adapted from ref (49).High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideAn important limitation of the Mott&#8211;Schottky method is that it is challenging to use it in the analysis of photoe</description>
      <author>Aarti Mathur, Ahmet Sert, Suljo Linic</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01365</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
