<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 01:27:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>High stability cubic perovskite Sr0.9Y0.1Co1-Fe O3- oxygen evolution by phase control and electrochemical reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177709</link>
      <description>Hongyuan Song, Yijia Pang, Linjie Dong, Kun Dong, Haorong Wu, Liang-Wei Chen, Bin Liu, Zhen&#8208;Hua Ge, Lan Yu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1010(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404678888

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongyuan Song, Yijia Pang, Linjie Dong, Kun Dong, Haorong Wu, Liang-Wei Chen, Bin Liu, Zhen&#8208;Hua Ge, Lan Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Iridium Aerogel-Like Structures for Efficient and Stable Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4404681212</link>
      <description>Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Maillard, Delphine Clauss, Vincent Martin, Marta Mirolo, Jakub Drnec, Rapha&#235;l Chattot, La&#235;titia Dubau, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404681212

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Maillard, Delphine Clauss, Vincent Martin, Marta Mirolo, Jakub Drnec, Rapha&#235;l Chattot, La&#235;titia Dubau</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4404681212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Complex Oxide Containing Inherent Peroxide Ions for Catalyzing Oxygen Evolution Reactions in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11477</link>
      <description>Jie Dai, Zihan Shen, Yu Chen, Mengran Li, Vanessa K. Peterson, Jiayi Tang, Xixi Wang, Yu Li, Daqin Guan, Chuan Zhou, Hainan Sun, Zhiwei Hu, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Guangming Chen, Yinlong Zhu, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404690511

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers powered by sustainable energy represent a cutting-edge technology for renewable hydrogen generation, while slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics still remains a formidable obstacle that necessitates basic comprehension for facilitating electrocatalysts' design. Here, we report a low-iridium complex oxide La</description>
      <author>Jie Dai, Zihan Shen, Yu Chen, Mengran Li, Vanessa K. Peterson, Jiayi Tang, Xixi Wang, Yu Li, Daqin Guan, Chuan Zhou, Hainan Sun, Zhiwei Hu, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Guangming Chen, Yinlong Zhu, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymorph &#947;-MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Optimal Phase Composition for Stable Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06977</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Shuang Kong, Yimeng Sun, Qinqin Hu, Pengfei Zhang, Ailong Li, Kiyohiro Adachi, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura, Taifeng Liu, Can Li, Hongxian Han, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404691832

                The development of non-noble-metal oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts stable in acid to replace rare and expensive iridium catalysts is crucial yet challenging for the large-scale application of proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis technology. Here, we show that increasing the Pr (pyrolusite ratio) in &#947;-MnO2 from 73% to 84% results in about 10 times longer durability at a high working current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1 M H2SO4 for more than 1000 h. Dramatic stability enhancement is due to the inhibition of lattice Mn or O dissolution by leveraging the formation of more stable corner-shared pyrolusite MnO6 octahedra with a higher oxidation state of Mn, fewer defects, a shorter Mn&#8211;O bond distance, an increase in stable mono-oxo-bridged Mn&#8211;O&#8211;Mn pyrolusite MnO6 octahedra, and a decrease in di-oxo-bridged Mn&#8211;O2&#8211;Mn ramsdellite MnO6 octahedra with more Mn&#8211;Mn tension. Because polymorph materials like &#947;-MnO2 are quite common in nature, phase composition turning may serve as an effective strategy for the development of stable OER catalysts in acidic environments.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Shuang Kong, Yimeng Sun, Qinqin Hu, Pengfei Zhang, Ailong Li, Kiyohiro Adachi, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura, Taifeng Liu, Can Li, Hongxian Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction: Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi90086c</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhou, Xuan Hao, Jiexin Guan, Yilin Deng, Wei Zi, Yashu Liu, Guoxing Zhu, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404694208

                Correction for &#8216;Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution&#8217; by Hongbo Zhou et al. , Inorg. Chem. Front. , 2024, 11 , 8110&#8211;8122, https://doi.org/10.1039/D4QI01934B.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhou, Xuan Hao, Jiexin Guan, Yilin Deng, Wei Zi, Yashu Liu, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi90086c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological semimetals with intrinsic chirality as spin-controlling electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01674-9</link>
      <description>Xia Wang, Qun Yang, Sukriti Singh, Horst Borrmann, Vicky Hasse, Changjiang Yi, Yongkang Li, Marcus Schmidt, Xiaodong Li, Gerhard H. Fecher, Dong Zhou, Binghai Yan, Claudia Felser, Nature Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404699558

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting is a promising approach for clean hydrogen production, but the process is hindered by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) owing to the spin-dependent electron transfer process. Efforts to control spin through chirality and magnetization have shown potential in enhancing OER performance. Here we harnessed the potential of topological chiral semimetals (RhSi, RhSn and RhBiS) and their spin-polarized Fermi surfaces to promote the spin-dependent electron transfer in the OER, addressing the traditional volcano-plot limitations. We show that OER activities follow the trend RhSi &lt; RhSn &lt; RhBiS, corresponding to the increasing extent of spin&#8211;orbit coupling (SOC). The chiral single crystals outperform achiral counterparts (RhTe 2 , RhTe and RuO 2 ) in alkaline electrolyte, with RhBiS exhibiting a specific activity two orders of magnitude higher than RuO 2 . Our work reveals the pivotal roles of chirality and SOC in spin-dependent catalysis, facilitating the design of ultra-efficient chiral catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xia Wang, Qun Yang, Sukriti Singh, Horst Borrmann, Vicky Hasse, Changjiang Yi, Yongkang Li, Marcus Schmidt, Xiaodong Li, Gerhard H. Fecher, Dong Zhou, Binghai Yan, Claudia Felser</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41560-024-01674-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurate regulation of carbon skeletons bonded to Fe-N4 single atom nanozymes for efficient generation of reactive oxygen species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2268-7</link>
      <description>Fuchun Nan, Qilin Wei, Tongtong Kou, Yuxuan Zhao, Lanbo Shen, Dawei Li, Tong Chang, Li Wang, Fangfang Lang, William W. Yu, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404700779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuchun Nan, Qilin Wei, Tongtong Kou, Yuxuan Zhao, Lanbo Shen, Dawei Li, Tong Chang, Li Wang, Fangfang Lang, William W. Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2268-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineered Nickel&#8211;Iron Nitride Electrocatalyst for Industrial&#8208;Scale Seawater Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202415421</link>
      <description>Huashuai Hu, Xunlu Wang, Zhaorui Zhang, Jiahao Liu, Xiaohui Yan, Xiaoli Wang, Jiacheng Wang, J. Paul Attfield, Minghui Yang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404700885

                Abstract Seawater electrolysis under alkaline conditions is a crucial technology for sustainable hydrogen production. However, achieving the long&#8208;term stability of the electrocatalyst remains a significant challenge. In this study, it is demonstrated that surface reconstruction of a transition metal nitride (TMN) can be used to develop a highly stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalyst. Rapid introduction of phosphate groups (PO 4 3&#8722; ) accelerates the in situ surface reconstruction of Ni 3 FeN, generating a catalyst, with a conductive nitride core and Cl &#8722; &#8208;resistant hydroxide shell that demonstrates outstanding performance, maintaining stability for over 2500 h at 1 A cm &#8722;2 current density in alkaline seawater. In situ characterization and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal the dynamic evolution of active sites, providing insights into the mechanisms driving long&#8208;term stability. This work not only introduces an efficient approach to TMN&#8208;based catalyst design but also advances the development of durable electrocatalysts for industrial&#8208;scale seawater hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Huashuai Hu, Xunlu Wang, Zhaorui Zhang, Jiahao Liu, Xiaohui Yan, Xiaoli Wang, Jiacheng Wang, J. Paul Attfield, Minghui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202415421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bead-Structured Triple-Doped Carbon Nanocage/Carbon Nanofiber Composite as a Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05385</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Yige Zhao, Bo Zhang, Yukun Li, Xiang Li, Guosheng Shao, Peng Zhang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404702649

                Zeolitic imidazolate framework (ZIF)-derived metal&#8211;nitrogen carbon (M&#8211;N&#8211;C) materials are considered as promising electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) applied in rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). However, due to their unsatisfied conductivity and aggregation, appropriate regulations about structure and components are still necessary to achieve superior bifunctional performance. Herein, by simple ion exchange and one-step electrospinning method, a beaded composite electrocatalyst (Fe, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C/CNF) with Fe, Co, N codoped carbon nanocages uniformly embedded in the carbon nanofibers one by one was synthesized, achieving simultaneous structural and compositional regulation. Benefiting from the beaded-like structure and dual sites, the Fe, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C/CNF exhibits outstanding bifunctional catalytic performance for the ORR and the OER. Ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopy (UPS) reveals that Fe, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C/CNF has a low electron transfer barrier between active centers and the ORR (OER) intermediates, ultimately accelerating the reaction kinetics. In addition, the Fe, Co&#8211;N&#8211;C/CNF-based ZAB also demonstrates superior charge&#8211;discharge performance compared to the Pt/C-RuO2-based ZAB. This study not only offers an effective structural design strategy but also provides a component regulation method for ZIF-derived materials as bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Yige Zhao, Bo Zhang, Yukun Li, Xiang Li, Guosheng Shao, Peng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable and Energy-Saving Hydrogen Production via Binder-free and In-situ Electrodeposited Ni-Mn-S Nanowires on Ni-Cu 3-D Substrate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03486d</link>
      <description>Ghasem Barati Darband, Danial Iravani, Meiling Zhang, Meysam Maleki, Shun Huang, Seyyed Mehdi Khoshfetrat, Reza Andaveh, Jinyang Li, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404704477

                Electrochemical water splitting, with its oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), is undoubtedly the most eco-friendly and sustainable method to produce hydrogen. However, water splitting still requires...</description>
      <author>Ghasem Barati Darband, Danial Iravani, Meiling Zhang, Meysam Maleki, Shun Huang, Seyyed Mehdi Khoshfetrat, Reza Andaveh, Jinyang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03486d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe Dimers Incorporated within Ni(OH)2 Nanosheets to Enable Rapid Oxygen Radical Coupling and Exceptional Durability in Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124861</link>
      <description>Huanli Jia, Haiyan Wang, Fangfang Yan, Ze Li, Ruijian Li, Shenshen Li, Jianji Wang, Hucheng Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404704730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huanli Jia, Haiyan Wang, Fangfang Yan, Ze Li, Ruijian Li, Shenshen Li, Jianji Wang, Hucheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Economical iron-based catalyst electrode for highly stable catalytic industrial-scale overall seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43979-024-00112-9</link>
      <description>Weiju Hao, Guoqing Huang, Xunwei Ma, Fengjing Lei, Shouxin Zhang, Jiacheng Zhang, Y. P. Guo, Guisheng Li, Carbon Neutrality. 3(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404704869

                Abstract The development of economical and stable catalyst electrodes for industrial-scale seawater splitting is one of the current challenges in hydrogen production. The economical transition metals possess high electrical conductivity and offer the potential for designing electrodes with high intrinsic activity through appropriate modifications, thus holding promising applications in industrial contexts. Herein, a durable and economical self-supported bifunctional electrode (Fe@Ni) with high efficiency and large area is successfully constructed by one step in-situ deposition of iron on the porous structure of nickel foam (NF) via mild (298 K) electroplating method. Transition metals like iron and nickel offer high electrical conductivity and can be properly modified to achieve electrodes with high intrinsic activity. Due to the in-situ growth of cost-effective iron on the NF surface, the electrode surface morphology and electronic structure are reconstructed, which significantly improves the electrochemical activity surface area and electron transfer capability of the electrode. The hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction (HER/OER) in simulated seawater (1 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl) require only 129 mV and 323 mV overpotentials to achieve a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Overall seawater splitting (OWS) achieves 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at a low voltage of 1.49 V and with a faradaic efficiency of nearly 100%. More importantly, the bifunctional electrodes remain stable at industrial-level current density (1.0 A cm &#8722;2 ) for more than 50 days. More attractively, this work realizes the universal construction of large-area electrode for multiple metals (e.g., Fe, Cu, Al, etc . ) with mild and simple process, which provides a new strategy for the current research of energy and materials.</description>
      <author>Weiju Hao, Guoqing Huang, Xunwei Ma, Fengjing Lei, Shouxin Zhang, Jiacheng Zhang, Y. P. Guo, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43979-024-00112-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pr&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;11&lt;/sub&gt; clusters anchored CoFe-LDH on vertical graphene nanosheets as oxygen evolution electrocatalyst for long-term high-current-density seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07515c</link>
      <description>Quan Wu, Xiaoyu Dong, Kefeng Ouyang, Youfa Liu, Hao Lei, Jie Yu, Yan Huang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404708300

                The severe catalyst corrosion caused by chlorides as well as industry-scale high current density are two critical issues for seawater electrolysis that need to be solved. Herein, due to the...</description>
      <author>Quan Wu, Xiaoyu Dong, Kefeng Ouyang, Youfa Liu, Hao Lei, Jie Yu, Yan Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07515c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core-shell cobalt-iron silicide electrocatalysts with enhanced bifunctional performance in hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.195</link>
      <description>Zhixuan Han, Yifu Zhang, Tianming Lv, Xianfang Tan, Qiushi Wang, Sheng Wang, Changgong Meng, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 682(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404710333

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhixuan Han, Yifu Zhang, Tianming Lv, Xianfang Tan, Qiushi Wang, Sheng Wang, Changgong Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monolithic medium-entropy alloy electrode enables efficient and stable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110535</link>
      <description>Xiaoke Xi, Xinpeng Li, Yang Liu, Yucheng Zhang, Linmei Li, Jianming Li, Jin Xu, Shuhong Jiao, Zhanwu Lei, Ruiguo Cao, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404710412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoke Xi, Xinpeng Li, Yang Liu, Yucheng Zhang, Linmei Li, Jianming Li, Jin Xu, Shuhong Jiao, Zhanwu Lei, Ruiguo Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Surface and In-Depth Operational Performances of Oxygen-Evolving Anode Coatings: A Guideline for the Synthesis of Inert Durable Anodes in Metal Electrowinning from Acid Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14121339</link>
      <description>Jovana Bo&#353;njakovi&#263;, Vladimir Pani&#263;, Maja Stevanovi&#263;, Sre&#267;ko Stopi&#263;, Jasmina Stevanovi&#263;, Branimir Grgur, Gavrilo &#352;ekularac, Metals. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404711836

                The electrochemical performances of an oxygen-evolving anode produced by the reactivation of waste Ti substrate by a typical IrO2-Ta2O5 coating are correlated to the textural (non)uniformities of the coating and its exhaustion state. Coating degradation is considered operational loss of the activity in a metal electrowinning process. It was found that (pseudo)capacitive performances can vary over the coating surface by 20&#8211;30% and depend on the type of dynamics of the input perturbation: constant through cyclic voltammetry (CV) or discontinuous time-dependent through electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). CV-EIS data correlation enabled profiling of the capacitive properties through the depth of a coating and over its surface. The correlation was confirmed by the findings for the analysis of coating activity for an oxygen evolution reaction, finally resulting in the reliable proposition of a mechanism for the operational loss of the anode. It was found that the less compact and thicker coating parts performed better and operated more efficiently, especially at lower operational current densities.</description>
      <author>Jovana Bo&#353;njakovi&#263;, Vladimir Pani&#263;, Maja Stevanovi&#263;, Sre&#267;ko Stopi&#263;, Jasmina Stevanovi&#263;, Branimir Grgur, Gavrilo &#352;ekularac</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14121339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Dense CoRu&#8208;CoMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Heterointerfaces with Electron Redistribution for Synergistically Boosted Alkaline Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409159</link>
      <description>Huamei Tong, Shengjie Xu, Xinyu Zheng, Mengyue Qi, Jianjun Zhu, Di Li, Deli Jiang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718235

                Abstract Constructing metal alloys/metal oxides heterostructured electrocatalysts with abundant and strongly coupling interfaces is vital yet challenging for practical electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, CoRu nanoalloys uniformly anchored on CoMoO 4 nanosheet heterostructured electrocatalyst (CoRu&#8208;CoMoO 4 /NF) are synthesized via a self&#8208;templated strategy by simply annealing of Ru&#8208;etched CoMoO 4 /NF precursor in a reduction atmosphere. The dense and robustly coupled interface not only provides abundant active sites for water splitting but also strengthens the charge transfer efficiency. Furthermore, the theoretical calculations unveil that the strong electronic interaction at CoRu&#8208;CoMoO 4 interface can induce an interfacial electron redistribution and reduce the energetic barriers for the hydrogen and oxygen intermediates, thereby accelerating the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics. The resultant catalyst only requires the overpotentials of 49 mV for HER and 209 mV for OER at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Moreover, the constructed CoRu&#8208;CoMoO 4 ||CoRu&#8208;CoMoO 4 two&#8208;electrode cell achieves a cell voltage of 1.54 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , outperforming the benchmark Pt/C||IrO 2 . This work explores an avenue for the rational design of heterostructured electrocatalysts with abundant interfaces for practical water&#8208;splitting electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Huamei Tong, Shengjie Xu, Xinyu Zheng, Mengyue Qi, Jianjun Zhu, Di Li, Deli Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Nitride Controlled Atomic Doping of Mo&lt;sup&gt;x+&lt;/sup&gt; in NiFe (Oxy)Hydroxide to Trigger Lattice Oxygen&#8208;Mediated Mechanism for Superior Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418439</link>
      <description>J.G. Wang, Zhenyu Xing, Ran Kang, Yijuan Zheng, Zhen Zhang, Tian Ma, Yi Wang, Bo Yin, Yaozu Liao, Liang Li, Chong Cheng, Shuang Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718250

                Abstract The covalency of the metal&#9472;oxygen (M&#9472;O) bond is significantly amplified in the transition metal sites with elevated oxidation states, thereby enabling the lattice oxygen&#8208;mediated mechanism (LOM) to transcend the traditional linear scaling limitations of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, an innovative surface atom release speed&#8208;mediated doping of Mo atoms in NiFe (oxy)hydroxides by controlled dissolution of Mo atoms from the Mo 2 N surface, which resulted in the formation of NiFeMo(OH) 2 with high valence Ni species for OER. Structural characterizations, coupled with in situ Raman and theoretical calculations, elucidate that the incorporation of Mo in NiFeMo(OH) 2 modulates the electronic configuration of the metal centers, thereby diminishing the formation energy of Ni 3+/4+ species. This modulation augments the M&#9472;O bond covalency, facilitating a shift in the OER pathway from the conventional absorbate evolution mechanism to the more efficient LOM. Consequently, the NiFeMo(OH) 2 displays a low overpotential of 236 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , along with long stability (&gt;500 h) at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . Furthermore, when integrated into an anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer, it achieves a current density of 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at a cell voltage of merely 2.27 V, underscoring its potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>J.G. Wang, Zhenyu Xing, Ran Kang, Yijuan Zheng, Zhen Zhang, Tian Ma, Yi Wang, Bo Yin, Yaozu Liao, Liang Li, Chong Cheng, Shuang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shedding Light on the Active Species in a Cobalt&#8208;Based Covalent Organic Framework for the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202413555</link>
      <description>Pouya Hosseini, Andr&#233;s Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Camargo, Yiqun Jiang, Shouxin Zhang, Christina Scheu, Liang Yao, Bettina V. Lotsch, Kristina Tschulik, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404723714

                Abstract While considerable efforts have been devoted to developing functionalized covalent organic frameworks (COFs) as oxygen evolution electrocatalysts in recent years, studies related to the investigation of the true catalytically active species for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remain lacking in the field. In this work, the active species of a cobalt&#8208;functionalized COF (TpBpy&#8208;Co) is studied as electrochemical OER catalyst through a series of electrochemical measurements and post&#8208;electrolysis characterizations. These results suggest that cobalt oxide&#8208;based nanoparticles are formed in TpBpy&#8208;Co from Co(II) ions coordinated to the COF backbone when exposing TpBpy&#8208;Co to alkaline media, and these newly formed nanoparticles serve as the primary active species for oxygen evolution. The study thus emphasizes that caution is warranted when assessing the catalytic activity of COF electrocatalysts, as the pristine COF may act as the pre&#8208;catalyst, with the active species forming only under catalyst operating conditions. Specifically, strong coordination between COFs and metal centers under electrochemical operation conditions is crucial to avoid unintended transformation of COF electrocatalysts. This work thus contributes to the rational development of earth&#8208;abundant COF OER catalysts for the production of green hydrogen from renewable resources.</description>
      <author>Pouya Hosseini, Andr&#233;s Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Camargo, Yiqun Jiang, Shouxin Zhang, Christina Scheu, Liang Yao, Bettina V. Lotsch, Kristina Tschulik</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202413555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering of bifunctional nanocomposite with enhanced redox-type energy storage and oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158014</link>
      <description>Samikannu Prabu, Goli Nagaraju, Sivaprakash Sengodan, Kung&#8208;Yuh Chiang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404726700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samikannu Prabu, Goli Nagaraju, Sivaprakash Sengodan, Kung&#8208;Yuh Chiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-dimensional multilevel stalactite-like Ni3S2-Fe(Mo2S4) bifunctional electrocatalyst with excellent oxygen evolution reaction and overall water splitting performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.193</link>
      <description>Ning Zhao, Lan Mu, Wenbo Liao, Gang Zhao, Mei Xue, Meng Ding, Yuxiang Dai, Xijin Xu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404728328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ning Zhao, Lan Mu, Wenbo Liao, Gang Zhao, Mei Xue, Meng Ding, Yuxiang Dai, Xijin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Organized Integrated Electrocatalyst on Oxygen Conversion for Highly Durable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416664</link>
      <description>Qian Chang, Feng He, Zhihui Zhang, Xinlong Fu, Wei Wang, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730109

                Efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are key for clean energy applications such as rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries. Highly efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts have been the focus of great attention by scientists. Here, an innovative and continuous growth method is established to fabricate integrated Janus structure Co3O4/CoNGDY catalyst, which can work for bifunctional oxygen catalytic conversion, achieving highly durable zinc&#8208;air batteries. Embedded in the hydrangea&#8208;shaped N&#8208;doped graphdiyne (NGDY), the Co3O4/CoNGDY is self&#8208;organized by CoNGDY at the NGDY contact sites and Co3O4 at the upper part, in which Co3O4 works as OER catalyst and CoNGDY acts as ORR catalyst. Due to the incomplete charge transfer within integrated structure, NGDY reduces the d&#8208;band center of the Co sites, so the adsorption strength of intermediates is balanced, and the catalytic activity for ORR/OER is increased. The Co3O4/CoNGDY can serve as an efficient air electrode of rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries. The rechargeable Co3O4/CoNGDY&#8208;based aqueous zinc&#8208;air batteries demonstrate excellent performance with a high specific capacity of 746.8 mAh g&#8722;1 and an extremely long lifetime of more than 5000 hours. The recoverable modularized cylindrical Co3O4/CoNGDY&#8208;based solid&#8208;state zinc&#8208;air batteries with a power density of up to 167.6 mW cm&#8722;2 can be achieved.</description>
      <author>Qian Chang, Feng He, Zhihui Zhang, Xinlong Fu, Wei Wang, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Organized Integrated Electrocatalyst on Oxygen Conversion for Highly Durable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416664</link>
      <description>Qian Chang, Feng He, Zhihui Zhang, Xinlong Fu, Li Wang, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404730180

                Efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are key for clean energy applications such as rechargeable metal&#8208;air batteries. Highly efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts have been the focus of great attention by scientists. Here, an innovative and continuous growth method is established to fabricate integrated Janus structure Co3O4/CoNGDY catalyst, which can work for bifunctional oxygen catalytic conversion, achieving highly durable zinc&#8208;air batteries. Embedded in the hydrangea&#8208;shaped N&#8208;doped graphdiyne (NGDY), the Co3O4/CoNGDY is self&#8208;organized by CoNGDY at the NGDY contact sites and Co3O4 at the upper part, in which Co3O4 works as OER catalyst and CoNGDY acts as ORR catalyst. Due to the incomplete charge transfer within integrated structure, NGDY reduces the d&#8208;band center of the Co sites, so the adsorption strength of intermediates is balanced, and the catalytic activity for ORR/OER is increased. The Co3O4/CoNGDY can serve as an efficient air electrode of rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries. The rechargeable Co3O4/CoNGDY&#8208;based aqueous zinc&#8208;air batteries demonstrate excellent performance with a high specific capacity of 746.8 mAh g&#8722;1 and an extremely long lifetime of more than 5000 hours. The recoverable modularized cylindrical Co3O4/CoNGDY&#8208;based solid&#8208;state zinc&#8208;air batteries with a power density of up to 167.6 mW cm&#8722;2 can be achieved.</description>
      <author>Qian Chang, Feng He, Zhihui Zhang, Xinlong Fu, Li Wang, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution kinetics, supercapacitor and display applications of Europium doped ZnSnO3 nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.140801</link>
      <description>Vishwalinga Prasad B., C. Ningappa, H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, R. Sahana, K.N. Sridhar, K. Manjunatha, Sheng Yun Wu, Journal of Molecular Structure. 1324(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404738480

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vishwalinga Prasad B., C. Ningappa, H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, R. Sahana, K.N. Sridhar, K. Manjunatha, Sheng Yun Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.140801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alternating current and electrolyte engineering-promoted surface reconstruction of NiFeOxHy catalysts for amper-level oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.192</link>
      <description>Chenyang Cai, Zhilin Zhang, Yutao Hua, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Xinchuan Du, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Jinhui Hao, Weidong Shi, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404739506

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenyang Cai, Zhilin Zhang, Yutao Hua, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Xinchuan Du, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Jinhui Hao, Weidong Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Water Splitting in Isoindigo&#8208;based Covalent Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419836</link>
      <description>Ali Trabolsi, Gobinda Das, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Fayrouz Abou Ibrahim, Areej Merhi, Huda N. Dirawi, Farah Benyettou, Akshaya Kumar Das, Thirumurugan Prakasam, Sabu Varghese, Sudhir Kumar Sharma, Serdal K&#305;rm&#305;z&#305;alt&#305;n, Ramesh Jagannathan, Felipe G&#225;ndara, Samer Aouad, Mark A. Olson, Subrata Kumar Kundu, Bilal R. Kaafarani, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404739567

                Developing a low&#8208;cost, robust, and high&#8208;performance electrocatalyst capable of efficiently performing both the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under both basic and acidic conditions is a major challenge. This area of research has attracted much attention in recent decades due to its importance in energy storage and conversion. Herein, we report the synthesis of two imine&#8208;linked isoindigo&#8208;based covalent organic networks. The combination of isoindigo dialdehyde with a planar triazine core, leads to the formation of thin, highly crystalline, planar 2D&#8208;nanosheets covalent organic framework (I&#8208;TTA COF), whereas its combination with ionic non&#8208;planar guanidinium core leads to an amorphous covalent organic polymer (I&#8208;TG COP) with a fibrous morphology. The sheet&#8208;like crystalline I&#8208;TTA COF shows better electrocatalytic activity compared to the amorphous fibrous I&#8208;TG COP. I&#8208;TTA exhibits a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at an overpotential of ~134 mV for HER (in 0.5 M H2SO4) and ~283 mV for OER (in 1 M KOH). The electrocatalytic activity of the I&#8208;TTA COF in the OER exceeds that of other metal&#8208;free COFs. The catalytic activity is maintained even after 24 hours of chronoamperometry and 500 cycles of cyclic voltammetry (CV) at high scan rates.</description>
      <author>Ali Trabolsi, Gobinda Das, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Fayrouz Abou Ibrahim, Areej Merhi, Huda N. Dirawi, Farah Benyettou, Akshaya Kumar Das, Thirumurugan Prakasam, Sabu Varghese, Sudhir Kumar Sharma, Serdal K&#305;rm&#305;z&#305;alt&#305;n, Ramesh Jagannathan, Felipe G&#225;ndara, Samer Aouad, Mark A. Olson, Subrata Kumar Kundu, Bilal R. Kaafarani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Screening of Multifunctional Single-Atom Catalysts Supported by Vs2 Monolayer for the Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution, Oxygen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5034793</link>
      <description>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404749614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5034793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unsymmetric Protonation Driven Highly Efficient H2O2 Photosynthesis in Supramolecular Photocatalysts via One&#8208;Step Two&#8208;Electron Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421356</link>
      <description>Wenting Li, Bing Han, Yuhan Liu, Jingyi Xu, Huarui He, Gege Wang, Junshan Li, Yaxin Zhai, Xiaolin Zhu, Yongfa Zhu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404755108

                Photocatalytic hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) production has emerged as an attractive alternative to the traditional anthraquinone process. However, its performance is often hindered by low selectivity and sluggish kinetics of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Herein, we report an anthrazoline&#8208;based supramolecular photocatalyst, SA&#8208;SADF&#8208;H+, featuring an unsymmetric protonation structure for H2O2 photosynthesis from water and air. The introduction of unsymmetric protonation disrupts the initial mirror symmetry of SADF, significantly enhancing the molecular dipole and facilitating efficient charge separation and electron transfer. Additionally, this modification increases the hydrophilicity of SA&#8208;SADF&#8208;H+, enabling the interaction of water and dissolved oxygen with the catalytic sites. The altered electron density distribution creates numerous dual active sites for Yeager&#8208;type O2 adsorption, facilitating an efficient ORR towards H2O2 via a direct one&#8208;step two&#8208;electron pathway. Notably, SA&#8208;SADF&#8208;H+ achieves an outstanding photocatalytic H2O2 production at a rate of 4667 &#956;mol L&#8208;1 h&#8208;1, with a remarkable solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion (SCC) of 1.35%, surpassing most organic photocatalytic systems. Furthermore, SA&#8208;SADF&#8208;H+ demonstrates remarkable photocatalytic antibacterial activity, achieving 100% antibacterial efficiency against Staphylococcus aureus within 60 min.</description>
      <author>Wenting Li, Bing Han, Yuhan Liu, Jingyi Xu, Huarui He, Gege Wang, Junshan Li, Yaxin Zhai, Xiaolin Zhu, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeNi/Ni2P nanoparticles encapsulated in nitrogen-doped porous carbon: efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-10433-w</link>
      <description>Tianrui Yu, Yuhong Zhang, Jinzhou Chen, Mingxin Feng, Zewu Zhang, Yuming Zhou, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404757609

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tianrui Yu, Yuhong Zhang, Jinzhou Chen, Mingxin Feng, Zewu Zhang, Yuming Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-10433-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing In2S3/FeVO4/CNT Photoelectrode for Enhanced Visible Light Driven Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401192</link>
      <description>Nitika Garg, Sandeep Kumar, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404763487

                The development of efficient and stable photoelectrodes is essential for the advancement of photoelectrochemical (PEC) water&#8208;splitting technologies, which hold promise for efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER), necessary for sustainable hydrogen production. In this study, the synthesis of a ternary composite, In2S3/FeVO4/CNT has been reported, designed for highly efficient PEC oxygen evolution. The formation of In2S3/FeVO4 heterostructure enhances PEC performance significantly due to the type&#8208;II band alignment, which minimizes electron&#8208;hole recombination and improves charge separation The addition of CNTs further enhances performance by providing conductive pathways that improve electron transport and reduce charge transfer resistance. The resulting In2S3/FeVO4/CNT ternary composite achieves a current density of 14.70 mAcm&#8722;2 at 1.8 V vs. RHE, representing a notable increase in performance. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) shows that the ternary composite has the lowest charge transfer resistance, while Bode phase analysis indicates a longer carrier lifetime, emphasizing the synergistic effect of heterostructure formation and CNT inclusion. The ternary composite also demonstrates excellent stability and responsiveness during transient photocurrent cycling, maintaining performance under repeated illumination, making it a strong candidate for water&#8208;splitting applications driven by visible light.</description>
      <author>Nitika Garg, Sandeep Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Doping of 2D Nickel-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks Enhances the Lattice Heterogeneous Interface Coupling Effect for Improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04507</link>
      <description>T. C. Huang, Ya&#8208;Ling Wu, Zhaopeng Sun, Yingying Chen, Shuangying Lei, Yangdan Pan, Lian&#8208;Wen Zhu, Dan Li&#365;, Xuebo Cao, Yan Zheng, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404765783

                The coupling of lattice and heterostructure interfaces represents an effective strategy for disrupting the so-called scalar relationship and accelerating reactions involving multiple intermediates. In view of this, a lattice-heterostructure interfacial catalyst consisting of a crystalline Fe/Ni bimetallic MOF and amorphous Fe-MOF was designed in this paper for high-performance alkaline oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysis. The strongly coupled lattice-heterostructure interface induces a unique synergistic effect that promotes electron transfer of the catalyst. The resulting catalyst exhibits exceptionally high catalytic activity for the oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media, the</description>
      <author>T. C. Huang, Ya&#8208;Ling Wu, Zhaopeng Sun, Yingying Chen, Shuangying Lei, Yangdan Pan, Lian&#8208;Wen Zhu, Dan Li&#365;, Xuebo Cao, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04507</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical NiFe-Layered Double Hydroxide Coupled with Bimetallic NiFe-MOF Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04815</link>
      <description>Weipeng Wang, Chunbo Liu, Jihui Lang, Tianyu Zhou, Feifan Guo, Wei Jiang, Jingdong Feng, Xiaotian Yang, Guangbo Che, Yuanyuan Wu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404767492

                It is crucial to utilize extremely efficient and economical catalysts for the energy-intensive and kinetically slow oxygen evolution process. Here, we fabricated a NiFeLDH coupled with the NiFe-MOF catalyst with a unique hierarchical structure using a facile and rapid electrodeposition and electrochemical activation strategy. With a low overpotential of about 187 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, the NiFeLDH/NiFe-MOF/NF demonstrates exceptional stability for more than 1000 h. Additionally, the produced NiFeLDH/NiFe-MOF/NF could provide high current densities of 500 and 1000 mA cm&#8211;2 in 6 M KOH at relatively low overpotentials of 293 and 353 mV, respectively. The construction of heterojunctions provides abundant interfacial active sites and optimizes catalytic activity by adjusting the surface electronic structure and energy levels. This serves to enhance the intrinsic activity of the catalyst. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations further prove that the construction of NiFeLDH regulates the band structure of metal sites, enhances the catalytic performance for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and lowers the intermediate medium's adsorption free energy.</description>
      <author>Weipeng Wang, Chunbo Liu, Jihui Lang, Tianyu Zhou, Feifan Guo, Wei Jiang, Jingdong Feng, Xiaotian Yang, Guangbo Che, Yuanyuan Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04815</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in electric field guides oxygen evolution electrocatalysts reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04740k</link>
      <description>Chunmei Ni, Kun Wang, LJ Jin, Yan Liu, Jie Chen, Lida Yang, Chang&#8208;Hyeon Ji, Hui Xu, Li Zhao, Lin Tian, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404767653

                Creating built-in electric field (BIEF) in catalysts represents an effective strategy to promote electron transfer and induce asymmetric charge distribution, thereby facilitating surface dynamic reconstruction under oxygen evolution reaction (OER)...</description>
      <author>Chunmei Ni, Kun Wang, LJ Jin, Yan Liu, Jie Chen, Lida Yang, Chang&#8208;Hyeon Ji, Hui Xu, Li Zhao, Lin Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04740k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Engineering of B/N-Doped Graphene with Phosphorus-Transition Metal Diatomic Catalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Bifunctionality Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105532</link>
      <description>Bo Yang, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Liang Tian, Xuefei Liu, Mingqiang Liu, Wenjun Xiao, Xiangyu Wu, Jiajin Ge, Yanchun Li, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Zhen Wang, Wu Yan, Wei Deng, Changsong Gao, Jinshun Bi, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404768559

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Yang, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Liang Tian, Xuefei Liu, Mingqiang Liu, Wenjun Xiao, Xiangyu Wu, Jiajin Ge, Yanchun Li, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Zhen Wang, Wu Yan, Wei Deng, Changsong Gao, Jinshun Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cef3-Accelerated Surface Reconstruction of Moo2 Nanosheets into 3d Coral-Like Cef3/Moo2 Composites Enhances the Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5036853</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Chenglin Liu, Xianglin Qiu, Tianshuo Zhang, Shanshan Gao, Fushan Chen, Xiaoming Song, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Chenglin Liu, Xianglin Qiu, Tianshuo Zhang, Shanshan Gao, Fushan Chen, Xiaoming Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5036853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Oxygen Vacancy in SrTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles to Achieve Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Performance in Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05558</link>
      <description>Xiaoli Ran, Yang Bai, Hao Zeng, Junhao Zhang, Haitao Fu, Xizhong An, Xiaohong Yang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404773317

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoli Ran, Yang Bai, Hao Zeng, Junhao Zhang, Haitao Fu, Xizhong An, Xiaohong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05558</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni/Fe Fluorides (Hydroxide) Nanocomposite as Efficient OER Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400701</link>
      <description>Yanli Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Liangliang Dong, Li Wang, Xiangming He, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404773412

                The synthesis of efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts that markedly reduce the overpotential over an extended period is crucial for electrolytic water splitting toward hydrogen production. A kind of Ni/Fe fluoride (hydroxide) nanocomposite OER catalyst is designed and prepared by a two&#8208;step method for the first time. The nanocomposite with the optimal OER performance (Ni:Fe precursor ratio of 9:1) is observed to possess a nanoparticle morphology with size of about 100 nm. Each nanoparticle hosts extensive nanoregions of Ni4OHF7, NiFeF5&#8729;2H2O and Fe1.9F4.75&#8729;0.95H2O phases. The optimal nanocomposite (Ni:Fe precursor ratio of 9:1) exhibits OER overpotential of merely 208 mV and 349 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and 100 mA cm&#8208;2 respectively, tafel slope of 53.1, and outstanding stability for 10 h duration at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. The superior OER catalytic performance of the optimal nanocomposite after CV activation is mainly ascribed to the comprehensive catalytic effect of multiple Ni, Fe active sites from three phases, the smaller charge transfer resistance achieved at this particular Ni:Fe precursor ratio. The abundant resources of Ni, Fe, F elements and the superior OER properties of the Ni/Fe fluorides (hydroxide) nanocomposite, makes it a good OER catalyst candidate for electrolytic water splitting toward hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Yanli Zhang, Qiang Zhang, Liangliang Dong, Li Wang, Xiangming He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation&#8208;Modified Co&#8208;Based Borophosphates for Efficient and Robust Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202404089</link>
      <description>Meng Yan, Dong&#8208;Sheng Pan, Ao Wang, Jun&#8208;Ling Song, ChemistrySelect. 9(45)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404780805

                Abstract The development of cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical and challenging in the field of electrocatalytic water splitting for industrial applications. Herein, a series of cations (Fe, Ni, and Zn)&#8208;doped Co&#8208;based borophosphates with an anion skeleton (Na 2 CoB 3 P 2 O 11 (OH)&#183; n H 2 O are prepared by a simple hydrothermal method, in which the cation dopants could be easily achieved via a simple cation exchange during the hydrothermal reaction process. Especially, the Fe dopant increases active sites, improves charge&#8208;mass transfer, and tunes the electronic structures of the Co&#8208;based borophosphate electrode. The optimal Fe&#8208;doped NaCBPO (NaC 3 FBPO), with the cobalt to iron molar ratio of 3, shows a low overpotential of 289 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and it can be stable for 16 h at this current density. Above all, it has a fast reaction rate with a low Tafel slope of 84.25 mV&#183;dec &#8722;1 . This work provides a promising transition metal&#8208;based borophosphates materials with high efficiency and durability toward water splitting.</description>
      <author>Meng Yan, Dong&#8208;Sheng Pan, Ao Wang, Jun&#8208;Ling Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202404089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trisodium Citrate&#8208;Assisted Synthesis of Edge&#8208;Abundant Nickel&#8208;iron Layered Double Hydroxides for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401667</link>
      <description>Jiang Qu, Xiao Hu, Marielle Deconinck, Lixiang Liu, Yapeng Cheng, Ruyan Zhao, Mingchao Wang, Haining Zhang, Yana Vaynzof, J&#246;rg Schuster, Andreu Cabot, Karin Leistner, Fei Li, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404787231

                The edges of layered double hydroxides (LDHs) display an exceptionally efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity than the (001) basal plane as demonstrated by both theoretical calculations and experimental studies. However, a controllable synthesis method of LDHs with abundant edges has yet to be described. Herein, we report a strategy enabling the synthesis of nickel&#8208;iron LDHs with abundant edges (NiFe LDHs&#8208;E) based on the use of citrate anions as the structure&#8208;directing agent. The edge density is characterized using spectroscopy techniques and its OER performance is compared with that of nickel&#8208;iron LDHs with abundant basal planes (NiFe LDHs&#8208;B). In alkaline electrolyte (1M KOH), NiFe LDHs&#8208;E exhibits excellent OER activity with very low overpotential (235 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2) and current densities up to sixfold (at &#951; = 320 mV) higher than those of NiFe LDHs&#8208;B. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations confirm the high OER activities ascribed to the abundant side&#8208;plane edges with optimal strength of binding of OER intermediates. Overall, a comprehensive investigation, employing both experimental and computational methodologies, yields new insights to fabricate superior catalysts meticulously designed with specific crystal planes and unveils the crucial structural attributes, thus unleashing the limitless potential of the catalytic domain.</description>
      <author>Jiang Qu, Xiao Hu, Marielle Deconinck, Lixiang Liu, Yapeng Cheng, Ruyan Zhao, Mingchao Wang, Haining Zhang, Yana Vaynzof, J&#246;rg Schuster, Andreu Cabot, Karin Leistner, Fei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implications for Oxygen Evolution Spinel-based Electrocatalyst in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyser: A Review from Structural Engineering perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177819</link>
      <description>Iswary Letchumanan, Wei Shi Ng, Mohd Shahbudin Masdar, Azim Fitri Zainul Abidin, Nurul Akidah Baharuddin, Rozan Mohamad Yunus, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404794496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Iswary Letchumanan, Wei Shi Ng, Mohd Shahbudin Masdar, Azim Fitri Zainul Abidin, Nurul Akidah Baharuddin, Rozan Mohamad Yunus</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nanotubes cross-linked Fe/Fe3C Nanoparticles and Fe Single Atoms as High-efficiency Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145427</link>
      <description>Zhiwen Xu, Lanlu Lu, Weiwei Chen, Fei Yang, Guimei Liu, Yan Sun, Xiaoyi Qiu, Meng Gu, Ping Gao, Dong Su, Minhua Shao, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404797231

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiwen Xu, Lanlu Lu, Weiwei Chen, Fei Yang, Guimei Liu, Yan Sun, Xiaoyi Qiu, Meng Gu, Ping Gao, Dong Su, Minhua Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium-based electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.033</link>
      <description>Yanhui Yu, Gai Li, Yutong Xiao, Chi Chen, Yuhang Bai, Wei Wang, Jing Li, Yingjie Hua, Daoxiong Wu, Peng Rao, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Y. Yuan, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404801259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanhui Yu, Gai Li, Yutong Xiao, Chi Chen, Yuhang Bai, Wei Wang, Jing Li, Yingjie Hua, Daoxiong Wu, Peng Rao, Peilin Deng, Xinlong Tian, Y. Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrosion-resistant NiFe anode towards kilowatt-scale alkaline seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54754-5</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Sun, Wei Shen, Hao Liu, Pinxian Xi, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404814271

                Development of large-scale alkaline seawater electrolysis requires robust and corrosion-resistant anodes. Here we propose engineering NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH)-based anodes by incorporating a series of anions into the LDH interlayers. The most optimal NiFe LDH anode with intercalated phosphates demonstrates stable operation at a high current density of 1.0 A cm&#8722;2 for over 1000 hours in a 2 W-scale alkaline seawater electrolyzer (ASWE). Fundamental studies indicate that the basicity, indicated by pKa values, of the intercalated anions in NiFe LDH governs its oxygen evolution reaction activity and corrosion resistance. Highly basic anions (i.e., phosphates) securely anchor Fe sites and facilitate proton transfer to boost both durability and activity. Notably, we demonstrate the proof-of-concept for the NiFe anode in an industrial 1 kW-scale ASWE stack (1,081.2 cm2 anode area in total). This unit achieves a stable operating current density of 0.5 A cm&#8722;2 at about 2.0 V, twice that of the commercial alkaline pure water electrolyzer, contributing to an economically competitive hydrogen production cost of US$ 1.96 kgH2&#8722;1. Large-scale alkaline seawater electrolysis demands robust anodes for efficient hydrogen production. Here, the authors report a NiFe layered double hydroxide anode with intercalated phosphates, achieving stable performance at 1.0 A cm&#8722;2 for over 1,000 hours, offering improved durability and activity.</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Sun, Wei Shen, Hao Liu, Pinxian Xi, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54754-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Electrochemical Performance of Co3O4/ZnO Composite Nanostructures through Interface Engineering for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135858</link>
      <description>K. Mallikarjuna, Kiran Kumar Ganta, Tarun Kumar, Nadavala Siva Kumar, Mohammad Asif, S.V. Prabhakar Vattikuti, Jaesool Shim, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404814566

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Mallikarjuna, Kiran Kumar Ganta, Tarun Kumar, Nadavala Siva Kumar, Mohammad Asif, S.V. Prabhakar Vattikuti, Jaesool Shim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancy mediated TiO2-x-MoS2/FTO heterostructure as an efficient photoanode for photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.11.043</link>
      <description>Mahdieh Rezaei, Ali A. Ensafi, Esmaeil Heydari&#8208;Bafrooei, Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404814699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mahdieh Rezaei, Ali A. Ensafi, Esmaeil Heydari&#8208;Bafrooei</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.11.043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic MIL&#8208;88/Polyaniline Hybrid Hollow Structure: In&#8208;situ Synthesis and Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction at High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403141</link>
      <description>Ying Liu, Hong&#8208;Yan Lin, Congcong Wang, Kai Zhang, Bai Yang, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404817862

                Abstract Developing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts in an efficient strategy, while maintaining high catalytic activity and stability under high current densities, remains a crucial problem. In this study, a bimetallic iron&#8208;cobalt phytic acid complex loaded with polyaniline hollow structure (FCP@PAn) was successfully constructed, via a progress of selective etching and surface modification in one step without high&#8208;temperature phosphating or carbonization. The as&#8208;obtained FCP@PAn required only 329 and 385 mV overpotentials at high current densities of 500 and 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively, due to phytic acid and polyaniline incorporation and the coordinated effect of each component. Additionally, the FCP@PAn exhibited the lowest Tafel slope values of 44.6 mV dec &#8722;1 and was able to continuously operate for 120 h at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 , displaying high catalytic activity and stability. Hence, the hollow structure of the conductive polymer and MOFs composites provided a new surface modification strategy for transition metal&#8208;based catalysts that are prone to dissolution or corrosion during the OER process, as well as for high current density applications.</description>
      <author>Ying Liu, Hong&#8208;Yan Lin, Congcong Wang, Kai Zhang, Bai Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Situ Electrochemical Modification of Crystallinity of Nife Layered Double Hydroxide Electrocatalyst to Accelerate Oxygen Evolution Rate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5037529</link>
      <description>Seunghyun Jo, Jieun Lim, Hyunjun Oh, Pilsoo Choi, Je-Myung Oh, KwangSup Eom, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404819198

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seunghyun Jo, Jieun Lim, Hyunjun Oh, Pilsoo Choi, Je-Myung Oh, KwangSup Eom</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5037529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile and ecofriendly green synthesis of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/MgO&#8211;SiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; composites towards efficient asymmetric supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra07337a</link>
      <description>Gulzar Ali, Aneela Tahira, Asma Hayat, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Syed Nizam Uddin Shah Bukhari, Elmuez A. Dawi, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Matteo Tonezzer, Muhammad Kashif Samoon, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, RSC Advances. 14(51)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404820884

                The development of low-cost, eco-friendly, and earth-friendly electrode materials for energy storage and conversion applications is a highly desirable but challenging task for strengthening the existing renewable energy systems.</description>
      <author>Gulzar Ali, Aneela Tahira, Asma Hayat, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Syed Nizam Uddin Shah Bukhari, Elmuez A. Dawi, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Matteo Tonezzer, Muhammad Kashif Samoon, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra07337a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic cation and anion co-vacancy defects boosted the oxide path mechanism of the oxygen evolution reaction on NiFeAl-layered double hydroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05839a</link>
      <description>Zhaoyan Li, Duo Wang, Jidong Li, Zhongning Shi, Xianwei Hu, Hong Sun, Junli Xu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404823936

                The uniform cation and anion defects on Ni 6 Fe 2 Al-LDH shorten the interatomic M&#8211;M distance and trigger the oxide path mechanism of the oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Zhaoyan Li, Duo Wang, Jidong Li, Zhongning Shi, Xianwei Hu, Hong Sun, Junli Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05839a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Design for High-Efficiency Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) Catalysts by Triggering Lattice Oxygen Oxidation in Cobalt Spinel Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14158</link>
      <description>Qingming Deng, Hui Li, Ke Pei, Lok Wing Wong, Xiaodong Zheng, Chi Shing Tsang, Honglin Chen, Wenqian Shen, Thuc Hue Ly, Jiong Zhao, Qiang Fu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404827664

                High-efficiency catalysts with refined electronic structures are highly desirable for promoting the kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and enhancing catalyst durability. This study comprehensively explores strategies involving metal doping and oxygen vacancies for enhancing the acidic OER catalytic activity of Co</description>
      <author>Qingming Deng, Hui Li, Ke Pei, Lok Wing Wong, Xiaodong Zheng, Chi Shing Tsang, Honglin Chen, Wenqian Shen, Thuc Hue Ly, Jiong Zhao, Qiang Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly porous NiCo2O4 nanostructures for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05972-w</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Mondal, Ajay K. Potbhare, P.R. Bhilkar, Rohit S. Madankar, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Ratiram G. Chaudhary, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404828781

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Mondal, Ajay K. Potbhare, P.R. Bhilkar, Rohit S. Madankar, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Ratiram G. Chaudhary</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05972-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically engineered interfaces inducing bridging oxygen-mediated deprotonation for enhanced oxygen evolution in acidic conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54798-7</link>
      <description>Han Wu, Jiangwei Chang, Jingkun Yu, Siyang Wang, Zhongjian Hu, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Xue Yong, Zhiyong Tang, Junbiao Chang, Siyu Lu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404829402

                The development of efficient and stable electrocatalysts for water oxidation in acidic media is vital for the commercialization of the proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. In this work, we successfully construct Ru&#8211;O&#8211;Ir atomic interfaces for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The catalysts achieve overpotentials as low as 167, 300, and 390 mV at 10, 500, and 1500 mA cm&#8722;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4, respectively, with the electrocatalyst showing robust stability for &gt;1000 h of operation at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and negligible degradation after 200,000 cyclic voltammetry cycles. Operando spectroelectrochemical measurements together with theoretical investigations reveal that the OER pathway over the Ru&#8211;O&#8211;Ir active site is near-optimal, where the bridging oxygen site of Ir&#8211;OBRI serves as the proton acceptor to accelerate proton transfer on an adjacent Ru centre, breaking the typical adsorption-dissociation linear scaling relationship on a single Ru site and thus enhancing OER activity. Here, we show that rational design of multiple active sites can break the activity/stability trade-off commonly encountered for OER catalysts, offering good approaches towards high-performance acidic OER catalysts. Efficient and stable electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution are essential for proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. Here, the authors report Ru&#8211;O&#8211;Ir atomic interfaces that enable bridging oxygen-mediated deprotonation pathways, overcoming the activity/stability trade-off in acidic oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Han Wu, Jiangwei Chang, Jingkun Yu, Siyang Wang, Zhongjian Hu, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Xue Yong, Zhiyong Tang, Junbiao Chang, Siyu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54798-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turning the Surface Electronic Effect Over Core&#8208;Shell CoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#9472;Fe&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;1&#8208;x&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanooctahedra Toward Electrochemical Water Splitting in the Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411622</link>
      <description>Lian&#8208;Ming Lyu, Yu&#8208;Chung Chang, Han&#8208;Jung Li, P. Y. Wang, Ruei&#8208;Hung Juang, Ming&#8208;Yen Lu, Kwang&#8208;Hwa Lii, Chun&#8208;Hong Kuo, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404829792

                Abstract The long&#8208;term challenge in overall water splitting is the conflict in the pH condition of electrolytes for achieving efficient hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the same time, in addition to the typical cost issue in catalysts. It hence raises an intense research interest in seeking cost&#8208;efficient non&#8208;noble metal electrocatalysts as well as compromising electrolyte conditions for electrocatalytic HER and OER. To tackle the problems, various approaches are demonstrated to engineer the electronic effect on the active sites of catalysts for enhancing the activities. In this work, the core&#8208;shell CoS 2 &#9472;Fe x Co 1&#8208;x S 2 nanooctahedra is fabricated with a tunable Fe content over the surface and took them as the model catalyst for systematic studies in alkaline OER and HER. By various X&#8208;ray spectroscopies as well as electron microscopy, the results showed that the shells of CoS 2 &#9472;Fe x Co 1&#8208;x S 2 nanooctahedra formed the {111} surfaces of Fe 0.9 Co 1.0 S 2 and Fe 0.25 Co 0.75 S 2 with and without the promotion by OH &#8722; anions during the syntheses. Catalyzed by the CoS 2 , Fe 0.25 Co 0.75 S 2 , and Fe 0.9 Co 1.0 S 2 {111} surfaces, the results of alkaline OER and HER indicated the Fe 0.9 Co 1.0 S 2 the most superior activities by virtue of the optimized Fe&#9472;Co electronic effect. From the predictions by density functional theory (DFT) calculations in reaction thermodynamics, the energy barriers in OER and HER both follow the order of Fe 0.9 Co 0.1 S 2 (111) &lt; Fe 0.25 Co 0.75 S 2 (111) &lt; CoS 2 (111). However, FeS 2 (111) is worse than Fe 0.9 Co 0.1 S 2 (111). From the confirmations by in&#8208;situ X&#8208;ray spectroscopies in reaction kinetics, the Co sites of Fe 0.9 Co 0.1 S 2 (111) on the core&#8208;shell nanooctahedra exhibited much higher activities than those of CoS 2 (111) under the applied potentials for OER and HER, which reflected the electronic benefits from the existing Fe neighbors.</description>
      <author>Lian&#8208;Ming Lyu, Yu&#8208;Chung Chang, Han&#8208;Jung Li, P. Y. Wang, Ruei&#8208;Hung Juang, Ming&#8208;Yen Lu, Kwang&#8208;Hwa Lii, Chun&#8208;Hong Kuo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Self&#8208;Assembled 200 nm&#8208;Depth Highly Active Layer Non&#8208;Precious Metals Catalyst for Industrial Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408495</link>
      <description>Xin You, Jizhou Duan, Xiaolu Xiong, Zhiwei Hu, Chang&#8208;Yang Kuo, F Q Chang, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Zhenya Li, Wen&#8208;Jie Bian, Jing Wang, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Linjuan Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404830333

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;based electrocatalysts are promising for industrial water electrolysis, but the dense hydroxyl oxide layer formed during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limits active sites accessibility and presents challenges in balancing structural stability with effective charge transfer. Based on this, an efficient in situ leaching strategy is proposed to construct grain boundary&#8208;rich catalyst structure with high charge transfer ability and a deep catalytic active layer reached &gt;200&#8208;nm. Under OER conditions, stable sub&#8208;nano Ni 3 Al particles are embedded in Ni(Fe)OOH, originating from leaching out the unstable Ni 2 Al 3 phase of the initial Ni 2 Al 3 /Ni 3 Al alloy doped with Fe. The structural evolutions are characterized using in situ Raman spectroscopy, transmission electron microscopy, and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy. The catalyst exhibits exemplary performance, evidenced by a low overpotential of 212 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , a minimal Tafel slope of 25.0 mV dec &#8722;1 . The catalyst maintains stable for &gt;500 h at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 under industrial conditions. Furthermore, its performance in seawater electrolysis is notably superior, exhibiting an overpotential of 223 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 37.5 mV dec &#8722;1 . The in situ high activity in the deep porous phase by leaching out unstable phases provides a new method for engineering high&#8208;performance industrial catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xin You, Jizhou Duan, Xiaolu Xiong, Zhiwei Hu, Chang&#8208;Yang Kuo, F Q Chang, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Zhenya Li, Wen&#8208;Jie Bian, Jing Wang, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Linjuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bifunctional Iron&#8208;Nickel Oxygen Reduction/Oxygen Evolution Catalyst for High&#8208;Performance Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409161</link>
      <description>Zhengfan Chen, Weiyi Cheng, Kecheng Cao, Jin Meng, Sarra Rahali, Soressa Abera Chala, Elnaz Ebrahimi, Nana Ma, Rongji Liu, Keseven Lakshmanan, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Chun&#8208;Chi Cheung, Haojian Luo, Yongkang Wang, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang, Carsten Streb, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404832755

                Abstract Efficient and robust electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial for fuel cells, metal&#8208;air batteries, and other energy technologies. Here, a highly stable, efficient bifunctional OER/ORR electrocatalyst (FeNi&#8208;NC@MWCNTs) is reported and demonstrated its integration and robust performance in an aqueous Zinc&#8211;air battery (ZAB). The catalyst is based on neighboring iron/nickel sites (FeNiN 6 ) which are atomically dispersed on porous nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon particles. The particles are wrapped in electrically conductive multi&#8208;walled carbon nanotubes for enhanced electrical conductivity. Electrocatalytic analyses show high OER and ORR performance (OER/ORR voltage difference = 0.69 V). Catalyst integration in a ZAB results in excellent performance metrics, including an open circuit voltage of 1.44 V, a specific capacity of 782 mAh g &#8722;1 (at j = 15 mA cm &#8722;2 ), a peak power density of 218 mW cm &#8722;2 (at j = 260 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and long&#8208;term durability over 600 charge/discharge cycles. Combined experimental and theoretical (density functional theory) analyses provide an in&#8208;depth understanding of the physical and electronic structure of the catalyst and the role of the FeNi dual atom reaction site. The study therefore provides critical insights into the structure and reactivity of high&#8208;performance bifunctional OER/ORR catalysts based on atomically dispersed non&#8208;critical metals.</description>
      <author>Zhengfan Chen, Weiyi Cheng, Kecheng Cao, Jin Meng, Sarra Rahali, Soressa Abera Chala, Elnaz Ebrahimi, Nana Ma, Rongji Liu, Keseven Lakshmanan, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Chun&#8208;Chi Cheung, Haojian Luo, Yongkang Wang, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang, Carsten Streb</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Electron Transport Propellant Mechanism of Oxygen Vacancy for Boosting Hydrogen Evolution Electrocatalysis in Alkaline Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409675</link>
      <description>Junheng Tang, Xiaobin Liu, Xuanyi Wang, Siqi Wu, Jiawei Zhu, Xinping Wang, Tianshi Wang, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404832767

                Abstract Currently, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline seawater still faces problems such as low catalyst activity and Cl &#8722; poisoning of active sites. In this work, an electron transfer facilitator of oxygen vacancies is introduced as a driving force for electronic transmission, which enhances the electron&#8208;metal&#8208;support interactions (EMSI) effect while introducing a charge protective layer, realizing killing two birds with one stone. In situ characterizations and density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrate that the EMSI effect enhances the H * transfer step at the interface. At the same time, due to oxygen vacancies for the enhanced EMSI, Ru forms an electron&#8208;rich layer, avoiding the poison of Cl &#8722; on active sites in seawater for HER. As a result, the Ru/Ni(OH) 2&#8208;x has an overpotential of only 156 mV at a current density of 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 in alkaline seawater. After assembling anion&#8208;exchange&#8208;membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWE), the Ru/Ni(OH) 2&#8208;x has a flat efficiency of &#8776;70% at different current densities, low energy consumption and price of per gallon gas equivalent (GGE) H 2 produced. Owning to the well Cl &#8722; tolerance, the catalyst also maintains long&#8208;term stability at 0.5 A cm &#8722;2 , indicating its great potential for industrial feasibility.</description>
      <author>Junheng Tang, Xiaobin Liu, Xuanyi Wang, Siqi Wu, Jiawei Zhu, Xinping Wang, Tianshi Wang, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Architectures by Hybridizing Ru Nanoparticles with Nitrogen/Oxygen Dual&#8208;doped Carbon Nanotubes for Advanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400571</link>
      <description>Yan Han, Yanhui Lu, Yu Xu, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404836439

                Developing highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts is critical for advancing hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) for hydrogen production. Herein, we report a facile approach to fabricating a hierarchical catalyst featuring ruthenium (Ru) nanoparticles uniformly integrated with nitrogen/oxygen co&#8208;doped carbon nanotube aerogels (Ru&#8208;NOCAs). Heteroatoms N and O&#8208;modified CNTs can result in a negatively charged surface to effectively trap Ru3+ ions. Ru&#8208;NOCAs exhibit a well&#8208;defined hierarchical morphology facilitated by the self&#8208;assembly of functional groups on the surface of CNTs, which enhances the interaction between Ru nanoparticles and CNTs. Due to the synergistic effect of hierarchical structure and strong interaction formation, Ru&#8208;NOCAs show excellent catalytic activity and stability. Ru&#8208;NOCAs catalyst demonstrates a remarkable overpotential of 41 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 with a Tafel slope of 57 mV dec&#8208;1 in 1 M KOH and an overpotential of 68 mV with a Tafel slope of 65.8 mV dec&#8208;1 in 0.5 M H2SO4. These results indicate superior catalytic efficiency and enhanced charge transfer kinetics compared to the control samples. This study highlights the effectiveness of incorporating hierarchical structures and tailored surface chemistries in electrocatalyst design, offering new avenues for optimizing HER performance and advancing hydrogen fuel technology.</description>
      <author>Yan Han, Yanhui Lu, Yu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying key intermediates for the oxygen evolution reaction on hematite using ab-initio molecular dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54796-9</link>
      <description>Shuai Xu, Jiarui Yang, Peixian Su, Li Wang, Xiaowei Yang, Zhaohui Zhou, Yuliang Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404849149

                Hematite is a well-known catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction on photoanodes in photoelectrochemical water-splitting cells. However, the knowledge of hematite-water interfaces and water oxidation mechanisms is still lacking, which limits improvements in photoelectrochemical water-splitting performance. Herein, we use the Fe-terminated hematite (0001) surface as a model and propose a comprehensive mechanism for the oxygen evolution reaction on both non-solvated and solvated surfaces. Key reaction intermediates are identified through ab initio molecular dynamics simulations at the density functional theory level with a Hubbard U correction. Several notable intermediates are proposed, and the effects of water solvent on these intermediates and the overall reaction mechanisms are suggested. The proposed mechanisms align well with experimental observations under photoelectrochemical water oxidation conditions. Additionally, we highlight the potential role of O2 desorption in the oxygen evolution reaction on hematite, as O2 adsorption may block reaction sites and increases surface hydrophobicity, leading to an unfavorable pathway for oxygen evolution. Hematite is a promising material for photoelectrochemical water splitting, but its mechanisms are not well understood. Here, the authors report a detailed mechanism, identifying key reaction intermediates and highlighting the influence of solvent water and oxygen desorption on the reaction pathways.</description>
      <author>Shuai Xu, Jiarui Yang, Peixian Su, Li Wang, Xiaowei Yang, Zhaohui Zhou, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54796-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MnO2 as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst with pseudocapacitive behavior for high-power rechargeable seawater batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114805</link>
      <description>Seohae Kim, Dowan Kim, Youngsik Kim, Jehee Park, Journal of Energy Storage. 106(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404856129

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seohae Kim, Dowan Kim, Youngsik Kim, Jehee Park</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b</link>
      <description>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404860375

                Understanding the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and Ir dissolution mechanisms in amorphous, hydrous iridium oxides (am-hydr-IrO x ) is hindered by the reliance on crystalline iridium oxide theoretical models to interpret its...</description>
      <author>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of the Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks Polymorphism on the Electrocatalytic Properties of CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; toward Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c08837</link>
      <description>Nuno Mendes, Antonio Lopes de Souto Neto, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Andr&#233; Luiz Menezes de Oliveira, Rafael A. Raimundo, Daniel A. Macedo, Fausthon Fred da Silva, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404862954

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nuno Mendes, Antonio Lopes de Souto Neto, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Andr&#233; Luiz Menezes de Oliveira, Rafael A. Raimundo, Daniel A. Macedo, Fausthon Fred da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c08837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Peroxide Electrosynthesis via Selective Oxygen Reduction Reactions Through Interfacial Reaction Microenvironment Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414490</link>
      <description>Qiang Tian, Lingyan Jing, Wenyi Wang, Xieshu Ye, Xiaoyan Chai, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Hengpan Yang, Chuanxin He, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404866412

                Abstract The electrochemical two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e &#8722; ORR) offers a compelling alternative for decentralized and on&#8208;site H 2 O 2 production compared to the conventional anthraquinone process. To advance this electrosynthesis system, there is growing interest in optimizing the interfacial reaction microenvironment to boost electrocatalytic performance. This review consolidates recent advancements in reaction microenvironment engineering for the selective electrocatalytic conversion of O 2 to H 2 O 2 . Starting with fundamental insights into interfacial electrocatalytic mechanisms, an overview of various strategies for constructing the favorable local reaction environment, including adjusting electrode wettability, enhancing mesoscale mass transfer, elevating local pH, incorporating electrolyte additives, and employing pulsed electrocatalysis techniques is provided. Alongside these regulation strategies, the corresponding analyses and technical remarks are also presented. Finally, a summary and outlook on critical challenges, suggesting future research directions to inspire microenvironment engineering and accelerate the practical application of H 2 O 2 electrosynthesis is delivered.</description>
      <author>Qiang Tian, Lingyan Jing, Wenyi Wang, Xieshu Ye, Xiaoyan Chai, Xue Zhang, Qi Hu, Hengpan Yang, Chuanxin He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414490</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Heterostructures Modulated by Oxyphilic Transition Metals for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110528</link>
      <description>Wenqing Guan, Chengxu Zhang, Yue Zhang, Yuebin Feng, Yunjie Mei, Qianglong Qi, Youjian Song, Jue Hu, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404870126

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqing Guan, Chengxu Zhang, Yue Zhang, Yuebin Feng, Yunjie Mei, Qianglong Qi, Youjian Song, Jue Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and performance of nickel/C based acidic oxygen evolution anode with polyphenol film</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.370</link>
      <description>Daxue Fu, S. Chen, Ji Shi, Qingli Xu, Junqing Wu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 97(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404874679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daxue Fu, S. Chen, Ji Shi, Qingli Xu, Junqing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.370</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ decoration of NiCo-thiophene based metal-organic framework on nickel foam as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235942</link>
      <description>Muhammad Salman, Hanli Qin, Yuming Zou, Zhenyuan Ji, Hu Zhou, Xiaoping Shen, Hongbo Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, P. Subramanian, Aihua Yuan, Journal of Power Sources. 629(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404876062

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Salman, Hanli Qin, Yuming Zou, Zhenyuan Ji, Hu Zhou, Xiaoping Shen, Hongbo Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, P. Subramanian, Aihua Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuSe nanoparticles anchored on polyaniline (PANI)matrix as highly efficient and durable electrocatalyst for robust oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06553-z</link>
      <description>Munaza sadiq, Eman Aldosari, Naseeb Ahmad, M. Aslam, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404876811

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munaza sadiq, Eman Aldosari, Naseeb Ahmad, M. Aslam</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06553-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Untangling Enhanced Performance Origin of Ca-Doped Laba1- X Ca X Co2o5+ &#916; Electrocatalysts Toward Intermediate-Temperature Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5039822</link>
      <description>Haibin Huo, Zixuan Tang, Tian Xia, Yingnan Dou, Qiang Li, Jingping Wang, Liping Sun, Li&#8208;Hua Huo, Hui Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404877796

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Huo, Zixuan Tang, Tian Xia, Yingnan Dou, Qiang Li, Jingping Wang, Liping Sun, Li&#8208;Hua Huo, Hui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5039822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting effect of ultrasonication on the oxygen evolution reaction during zinc electrowinning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ultsonch.2024.107183</link>
      <description>Guihong Han, Zhen Chen, N. Cui, Shuzhen Yang, Yanfang Huang, Bingbing Liu, Hu Sun, Ultrasonics Sonochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404878669

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guihong Han, Zhen Chen, N. Cui, Shuzhen Yang, Yanfang Huang, Bingbing Liu, Hu Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ultsonch.2024.107183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCoCe/NF Nanosheet Clusters for Alkaline Electrolyzed Water Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.111173</link>
      <description>Zandong Zhang, Wenfei Wang, Zhezhi Chen, Zuobo Yang, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, Materials Today Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404878997

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zandong Zhang, Wenfei Wang, Zhezhi Chen, Zuobo Yang, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.111173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881031

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881065

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881073

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881227

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881288

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881341

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881591

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881598

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrosion-Engineered Room-Temperature Deposition of NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/NiS/Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; at Nickel Foam: An Efficient Strategy and Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01627</link>
      <description>Marilia B. Dalla Benetta, Eithne Dempsey, Carmel B. Breslin, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404882261

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marilia B. Dalla Benetta, Eithne Dempsey, Carmel B. Breslin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping Ti into RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Accelerate Bridged&#8208;Oxygen&#8208;Assisted Deprotonation for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411709</link>
      <description>Wei Hu, Bolong Huang, Mingzi Sun, Jing Du, Yong Hai, Wen Yin, Xiaomei Wang, Wensheng Gao, Zhao Chun-Yang, Yinghong Yue, Zelong Li, Can Li, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404883582

                Abstract The development of efficient and durable electrocatalysts for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential for advancing renewable hydrogen energy technology. However, the slow deprotonation kinetics of oxo&#8208;intermediates, involving the four proton&#8208;coupled electron steps, hinder the acidic OER progress. Herein, a RuTiO x solid solution electrocatalyst is investigated, which features bridged oxygen (O bri ) sites that act as proton acceptors, accelerating the deprotonation of oxo&#8208;intermediates. Electrochemical tests, infrared spectroscopy, and density functional theory results reveal that the moderate proton adsorption energy on O bri sites facilitates fast deprotonation kinetics through the adsorbate evolution mechanism. This process effectively prevents the over&#8208;oxidation and deactivation of Ru sites caused by the lattice oxygen mechanism. Consequently, RuTiO x shows a low overpotential of 198 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 geo and performance exceeding 1400 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 geo with negligible deactivation. These insights into the OER mechanism and the structure&#8208;function relationship are crucial for the advancement of catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Wei Hu, Bolong Huang, Mingzi Sun, Jing Du, Yong Hai, Wen Yin, Xiaomei Wang, Wensheng Gao, Zhao Chun-Yang, Yinghong Yue, Zelong Li, Can Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/response1</link>
      <description>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404890679

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v3/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Density Functional Theory Study on the Electrocatalytic Performance of Defected Monolayer Vanadium Diselenide for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122669</link>
      <description>Rabia Hassan, Rehan Hassan, Fei Ma, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404893517

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rabia Hassan, Rehan Hassan, Fei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of RuO2/Ni-Co3O4 Heterostructures for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.246</link>
      <description>Bilal Zaman, Dongxu Jiao, Jinchang Fan, Dewen Wang, Huafeng Fan, Ming Gong, Shan Xu, Yanhua Liu, Muhammad Faizan, Xiaoqiang Cui, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404893565

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bilal Zaman, Dongxu Jiao, Jinchang Fan, Dewen Wang, Huafeng Fan, Ming Gong, Shan Xu, Yanhua Liu, Muhammad Faizan, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Unravelling the mechanistic complexity of the oxygen evolution reaction and Ir dissolution in highly dimensional amorphous hydrous iridium oxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404881326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marianne van der Merwe, Yonghyuk Lee, Enggar Wibowo, Tathiana Midori Kokumai, Anna Efimenko, Mauricio D. Arce, Catalina Jim&#233;nez, Benjamin Howchen, Rosario Suarez Anzorena, Ilaria Lucentini, Carlos Escudero, G&#246;tz Schuck, Zdravko Kochovski, Marco Favaro, David E. Starr, Karsten Reuter, Christoph Scheurer, Marcus B&#228;r, Raul Garcia&#8208;Diez</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02839b/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal synthesis of tungsten oxide photo/electrocatalysts: precursor-driven morphological tailoring and electrochemical performance for hydrogen evolution and oxygen reduction reaction application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-35607-6</link>
      <description>Rahul Sarma, Biraj Kumar Kakati, Environmental Science and Pollution Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404734191

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahul Sarma, Biraj Kumar Kakati</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-35607-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction Really Need To Be Suppressed in O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Tolerant CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electroreduction Catalyzed by DAE-BPy-CoPor and Co-TAPP?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02957</link>
      <description>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404771815

                This letter chooses DAE-BPy-CoPor [DAE, 1,2-bis(5'-formyl-2'-methylthien-3'-yl)cyclopentene; BPy, 2,2'-bipyridine-5,5'-dicarbaldehyde; and CoPor, two-dimensional cobalt porphyrin-based covalent organic framework] and Co-TAPP [10,15,20-tetrakis(4-aminophenyl)porphinatocobalt] as two model catalysts to investigate the effect of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in the O</description>
      <author>Pengfei Yuan, Chong Li, Jianan Zhang, Fei Wang, Xuebo Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Water Oxidation Catalysts: The Dominant Role of Surface Chemistry over Reconstruction Degree in Activity Promotion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01562-7</link>
      <description>Li An, Jianyi Li, Yuanmiao Sun, Jiamin Zhu, Justin Zhu Yeow Seow, Hong Zhang, Nan Zhang, Pinxian Xi, Zhichuan J. Xu, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Nano-Micro Letters. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404725533

                Water splitting hinges crucially on the availability of electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction. The surface reconstruction has been widely observed in perovskite catalysts, and the reconstruction degree has been often correlated with the activity enhancement. Here, a systematic study on the roles of Fe substitution in activation of perovskite LaNiO</description>
      <author>Li An, Jianyi Li, Yuanmiao Sun, Jiamin Zhu, Justin Zhu Yeow Seow, Hong Zhang, Nan Zhang, Pinxian Xi, Zhichuan J. Xu, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01562-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocomposites - Electrochemical Oxidation of Organic Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.47392/irjash.2024.047</link>
      <description>Sakshi Mokashi, A&#241;il Sharma, International Research Journal on Advanced Science Hub. 6(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404764652

                Electrochemical regeneration is very suitable approach for industrial effluents, but it suffers from low regeneration efficiency due to side reactions like oxygen evolution, as well as oxidation of the adsorbent. Utilizing PVA films through a solution casting method, incorporating varying concentrations of Cr&#8322;O&#8323; nanoparticles to evaluate their effects on the material properties .The measurement of the viscosity of the PVA- nanoparticle solution shows that the viscosity increases with the addition of Cr&#8322;O&#8323;, indicating that the viscosity is related to the interaction between the nanoparticles and PVA chains.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Mokashi, A&#241;il Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.47392/irjash.2024.047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;throughput screening of Co&#8208;Fe&#8208;Ni electrocatalysts for high&#8208;current&#8208;density water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401749</link>
      <description>Rajini P. Antony, Ridha Zerdoumi, Sascha Saddeler, Olga A. Krysiak, Lars Banko, Alfred Ludwig, Wolfgang Schuhmann, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404825531

                Developing oxygen evolution (OER) catalysts with opti&#173;mum composition and highly active catalytic centres is a challenge during electrode scale&#8208;up. We show a selection strategy for the optimum composition of Co&#8208;Fe&#8208;Ni catalyst systems through a scanning droplet cell&#8208;based high&#8208;throughput screening on thin&#8208;film materials libraries, followed by fabrication and testing of the selected compositions in form of catalyst&#8208;coated porous electrodes for the OER in alkaline media. The electrode with optimum composition (Co17Ni58Fe25_Ni foam) exhibits a high current density of 1 A cm&#8208;2 during water electrolysis at an operating potential of ~1.9 V.</description>
      <author>Rajini P. Antony, Ridha Zerdoumi, Sascha Saddeler, Olga A. Krysiak, Lars Banko, Alfred Ludwig, Wolfgang Schuhmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Nanocomposites in Covalent Organic Framework-Based Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14231907</link>
      <description>Haiping Zhou, Kechang Li, Qingqing Pan, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Rui Wang, Nanomaterials. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404756219

                In recent years, the development of high-performance electrocatalysts for energy conversion and environmental remediation has become a topic of great interest. Covalent organic frameworks (COFs), linked by covalent bonds, have emerged as promising materials in the field of electrocatalysis due to their well-defined structures, high specific surface areas, tunable pore structures, and excellent acid&#8211;base stability. However, the low conductivity of COF materials often limits their intrinsic electrocatalytic activity. To enhance the catalytic performance of COF-based catalysts, various nanomaterials are integrated into COFs to form composite catalysts. The stable and tunable porous structure of COFs provides an ideal platform for these nanomaterials, leading to improved electrocatalytic activity. Through rational design, COF-based composite electrocatalysts can achieve synergistic effects between nanomaterials and the COF carrier, enabling efficient targeted electrocatalysis. This review summarizes the applications of nanomaterial-incorporated COF-based catalysts in hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, oxygen reduction, carbon dioxide reduction, and nitrogen reduction. Additionally, it outlines design principles for COF-based composite electrocatalysis, focusing on structure&#8211;activity relationships and synergistic effects in COF composite nanomaterial electrocatalysts, as well as challenges and future perspectives for next-generation composite electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Haiping Zhou, Kechang Li, Qingqing Pan, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Rui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14231907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advancements in Co3O4-Based Composites for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/mi15121450</link>
      <description>Komal S. Wagh, Sagar M. Mane, Aviraj M. Teli, Jae Cheol Shin, Jaewoong Lee, Micromachines. 15(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404860884

                The pursuit of efficient and economical catalysts for water splitting, a critical step in hydrogen production, has gained momentum with the increasing demand for sustainable energy. Among the various electrocatalysts developed to date, cobalt oxide (Co3O4) has emerged as a promising candidate owing to its availability, stability, and catalytic activity. However, intrinsic limitations, including low catalytic activity and poor electrical conductivity, often hinder its effectiveness in electrocatalytic water splitting. To overcome these challenges, substantial efforts have focused on enhancing the electrocatalytic performance of Co3O4 by synthesizing composites with conductive materials, transition metals, carbon-based nanomaterials, and metal&#8211;organic frameworks. This review explores the recent advancements in Co3O4-based composites for the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction, emphasizing strategies such as nanostructuring, doping, hybridization, and surface modification to improve catalytic performance. Additionally, it examines the mechanisms driving the enhanced activity and stability of these composites while also discussing the future potential of Co3O4-based electrocatalysts for large-scale water-splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Komal S. Wagh, Sagar M. Mane, Aviraj M. Teli, Jae Cheol Shin, Jaewoong Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/mi15121450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intrinsic metal-support interactions break the activity-stability dilemma in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5208867/v1</link>
      <description>Ruitao Lv, Lingxi Zhou, Menghao Yang, Yihong Liu, Feiyu Kang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404776253

                Abstract Electrocatalysis plays a central role in clean energy conversion and sustainable technologies. However, the trade-off between activity and stability of electrocatalysts significantly hinders their practical applications, notably in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for producing hydrogen and solar fuels. Here we report a steam-assisted synthesis armed with machine learning screening of an integrated ruthenium-titanium-manganese electrode, featuring intrinsic metal-support interactions. These atomic-scale interactions with self-healing capabilities radically address the activity-stability dilemma across all pH levels. Consequently, our electrode achieved high mass activities, 48.5, 112.8 and 74.6 times those of benchmark ruthenium oxides in acidic, neutral and alkaline conditions, respectively; and stable operation for up to 3,000 hours, a multi-fold improvement in stability over the reported advanced catalysts. The breakthrough in activity-stability limitations highlights the potential of intrinsic metal-support interactions for enhancing electrolysis and other heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Ruitao Lv, Lingxi Zhou, Menghao Yang, Yihong Liu, Feiyu Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5208867/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Ruthenium&#8208;Cobalt Active Pair with Moderate Spacing for Enhanced Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409173</link>
      <description>Xiaoxia Chen, Meihuan Liu, C.Y. Ni, Yiwen Chen, Tianyu Liu, Shiyu Li, Hui Su, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404900015

                Abstract Ruthenium (Ru)&#8208;based catalysts have emerged as promising alternatives to Iridium (Ir) catalysts in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis cells due to their lower price and excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. However, their stability is compromised by generation of unstable high&#8208;valence Ru sites and oxygen vacancy in a lattice oxygen&#8208;mediated (LOM) pathway. Here, a low&#8208;load Ru site on a Barium (Ba)&#8208;doped Co 3 O 4 (RuBa x Co 3&#8211;x O 4 ) catalyst is developed with abundant Ruthenium&#9472;Cobalt (Ru&#9472;Co) pairs for enhanced acidic OER activity. The incorporation of Ba can efficiently modulate the lattice of Co 3 O 4 , creating Ru&#9472;Co active pairs with optimized spacing through compression stress. In situ characterizations exhibit contractive Ru&#9472;Co pairs that promote the rapid and direct coupling of * O&#9472;O * radicals, bypassing the sluggish * OOH species and avoiding the oxygen vacancies, which can trigger the oxide path mechanism (OPM) for an efficient and stable OER process. As a result, the designed catalyst delivers a low overpotential of 219 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and also demonstrates excellent stability, maintaining performance over 50 h of continuous operation at a larger current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . These findings highlight the potential of the RuBa x Co 3&#8208;x O 4 catalysts for durable and efficient OER applications.</description>
      <author>Xiaoxia Chen, Meihuan Liu, C.Y. Ni, Yiwen Chen, Tianyu Liu, Shiyu Li, Hui Su</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Proton&#8208;Mediated Synthesis of a High&#8208;Entropy Borate Library</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414067</link>
      <description>Da Liu, Peifang Guo, Qiangqiang Wang, Xingyu Ding, Yufei He, Jin Zhou, Dalin Sun, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404900244

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy compounds (HECs) provide extensive possibilities for exploring distinctive properties and potential applications. However, most HECs reported so far are synthesized by an arduous high&#8208;temperature treatment and special equipment, which is clearly not scalable for practical application. Here a scalable room&#8208;temperature solution synthetic strategy is reported for a library of high&#8208;entropy borates with arbitrary metal component numbers from 5 to 12 up to 3302 kinds in total and more than a hundred grams per operation within one minute. In conjunction with theoretical and in situ investigations, it is uncovered that the highly local concentration of protons at ethanol/aqueous interface is favorable to the creation of a stable thermodynamic microenvironment and a desirable kinetic miscibility reservoir, thus enabling a formation of single&#8208;phase borates. With the FeCoNiMoCu high&#8208;entropy borate, it is further shows that it functions as a highly active catalyst for catalytic oxygen evolution reaction. The work opens up opportunities for the scalable synthesis of HECs for energy storage and conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Da Liu, Peifang Guo, Qiangqiang Wang, Xingyu Ding, Yufei He, Jin Zhou, Dalin Sun, Hongge Pan, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress on layered double hydroxides-based electrocatalysts for electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837676408-00282</link>
      <description>Mohamed H. Elbakkay, S.I. El&#8208;Dek, Ahmed A. Farghali, Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404756818

                Replacing global depleting fossil fuels with sustainable energy sources that are affordable and environmentally-benign, is from the most pressing challenges for the future socio-economic developments. To that goal, electrochemical water splitting would provide green hydrogen fuel which is considered one of the most promising energy carriers. However, the viability of the process still hinges on the availability of robust earth-abundant electrocatalysts that catalyze the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In recent years, transition metal based layered double hydroxides (LDHs) electrocatalysts, with advantageous physio-chemical properties, can represent a promising outstanding research approaches to accelerate the sluggish electrochemical kinetics of these two half-reactions. Herein, we present brief explanations of the reaction mechanisms and the important parameters relating to the electrochemical water splitting along with the recent developments of different LDHs derived electrocatalysts towards the HER/OER performances. Furthermore, the innovative fabrication strategies of the LDHs systems and the subsequent evolution of the LDHs classes, including adopted modification strategies including cation/anion doping, defect engineering, exchanging interlayer anions, nanostructured morphology, designing hierarchical heterostructures or nanocomposites, etc. Finally, the current perspectives and challenges of some critical issues as well as the future opportunities for the developments of outstanding LDHs-based electrocatalysts for electrochemical water electrolysis are also provided.</description>
      <author>Mohamed H. Elbakkay, S.I. El&#8208;Dek, Ahmed A. Farghali</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837676408-00282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic mechanism for overall water splitting to produce sustainable hydrogen by 2D Janus MoSH monolayer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-024-00516-2</link>
      <description>Deobrat Singh, Nisha Singh, Yogesh Sonvane, npj 2D Materials and Applications. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404761563

                Abstract In the present work, we investigates the potential of two dimensional (2D) Janus MoSH monolayer as an electrocatalyst for overall water splitting using first-principles calculations. Our results shows that 2D Janus MoSH monolayer exhibits excellent structural stability and electronic properties, which are essential for efficient electrocatalysis. We find that the charge transfer mechanism between Mo and S atoms plays a crucial role in the electrocatalytic activity of 2D Janus MoSH monolayer. Due to the asymmetric structure of MoSH monolayer, it has intrinsic electric field with dipole moment of 0.24 D. Moreover, we demonstrate that 2D Janus MoSH monolayer exhibits high catalytic activity for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with overpotential 0.04 V and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with overpotential 0.11 V, making it a promising candidate for overall water splitting. Our findings have significant implications for the design and optimization of 2D monolayered materials for renewable energy production. By providing insights into the underlying mechanisms of HER and OER on 2D Janus MoSH monolayer, our study paves the way for the development of efficient and sustainable electrocatalysts for water splitting. We hope that current work will be helpful in understanding the electrocatalytic mechanism of 2D Janus MoSH monolayer and its potential applications in renewable energy production.</description>
      <author>Deobrat Singh, Nisha Singh, Yogesh Sonvane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41699-024-00516-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Lewis Base&#8208;Phosphate to Boost Neutral Seawater Splitting in Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202415143</link>
      <description>Mei Han, Li Wang, Jieshu Zhou, Kangning Liu, Ning Wang, Xihao Chen, Lei Zhu, Hongyan Liang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404867741

                Abstract Electrolysis of seawater using anion exchange membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWEs) under neutral conditions, is an attractive method for hydrogen production. Unfortunately, competitive anodic chlorine evolution reaction together with sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics caused by insufficient OH &#8722; , significantly limit the system's current density and operational stability. Herein, Lewis base phosphate (PO 4 3&#8722; ) is used as a proton acceptor to accelerate the cleavage of OH&#8722;H bonds, which facilitates the accumulation of *OH. NiFeP nanosheets grown on pretreated nickel foam (NiS&#8208;A) are used as the free&#8208;standing electrode. During the OER process, the pre&#8208;catalyst NiFeP spontaneously transforms into Lewis base&#8208;PO 4 3&#8722; decorated Ni(Fe)OOH. Experimental studies and density functional theory calculations reveal that Ni(Fe)OOH active phases adsorb H 2 O intermediates and synergize with the protophilic Lewis base PO 4 3&#8722; to favor the dissociation of water molecules (*H 2 O&#8594;*OH+H + +e &#8722; ), ensuring the timely supply of *OH in neutral media. Meanwhile, PO 4 3&#8722; also exhibits excellent ability to repel chloride ions in seawater splitting, achieving &#8776;98.2% oxygen Faradaic efficiency. The optimized NiFeP/NiS&#8208;A delivers a low overpotential (280 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and long&#8208;term OER durability (over 400 h at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Integrating NiFeP/NiS&#8208;A in a seawater&#8208;based AEMWE can achieve an industrially required current density of 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 (60 &#176;C) at 1.8 V and an operation stability over 220 h.</description>
      <author>Mei Han, Li Wang, Jieshu Zhou, Kangning Liu, Ning Wang, Xihao Chen, Lei Zhu, Hongyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202415143</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Water Splitting in Isoindigo&#8208;based Covalent Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419836</link>
      <description>Ali Trabolsi, Gobinda Das, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Fayrouz Abou Ibrahim, Areej Merhi, Huda N. Dirawi, Farah Benyettou, Akshaya Kumar Das, Thirumurugan Prakasam, Sabu Varghese, Sudhir Kumar Sharma, Serdal K&#305;rm&#305;z&#305;alt&#305;n, Ramesh Jagannathan, Felipe G&#225;ndara, Samer Aouad, Mark A. Olson, Subrata Kumar Kundu, Bilal R. Kaafarani, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404739555

                Developing a low&#8208;cost, robust, and high&#8208;performance electrocatalyst capable of efficiently performing both the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under both basic and acidic conditions is a major challenge. This area of research has attracted much attention in recent decades due to its importance in energy storage and conversion. Herein, we report the synthesis of two imine&#8208;linked isoindigo&#8208;based covalent organic networks. The combination of isoindigo dialdehyde with a planar triazine core, leads to the formation of thin, highly crystalline, planar 2D&#8208;nanosheets covalent organic framework (I&#8208;TTA COF), whereas its combination with ionic non&#8208;planar guanidinium core leads to an amorphous covalent organic polymer (I&#8208;TG COP) with a fibrous morphology. The sheet&#8208;like crystalline I&#8208;TTA COF shows better electrocatalytic activity compared to the amorphous fibrous I&#8208;TG COP. I&#8208;TTA exhibits a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at an overpotential of ~134 mV for HER (in 0.5 M H2SO4) and ~283 mV for OER (in 1 M KOH). The electrocatalytic activity of the I&#8208;TTA COF in the OER exceeds that of other metal&#8208;free COFs. The catalytic activity is maintained even after 24 hours of chronoamperometry and 500 cycles of cyclic voltammetry (CV) at high scan rates.</description>
      <author>Ali Trabolsi, Gobinda Das, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Fayrouz Abou Ibrahim, Areej Merhi, Huda N. Dirawi, Farah Benyettou, Akshaya Kumar Das, Thirumurugan Prakasam, Sabu Varghese, Sudhir Kumar Sharma, Serdal K&#305;rm&#305;z&#305;alt&#305;n, Ramesh Jagannathan, Felipe G&#225;ndara, Samer Aouad, Mark A. Olson, Subrata Kumar Kundu, Bilal R. Kaafarani</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Delocalized Ni Active Sites in Spinel Catalysts Enable Efficient Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421027</link>
      <description>Hui-Jian Zhang, Zi-Qiang Chen, Xiaotong Ye, Kang Xiao, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772457

                The urea oxidation reaction (UOR) has attracted much attention as an efficient alternative reaction to oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to its low required overpotential. Despite significant progress in efficient nickel&#8208;based catalysts, the fundamental issues regarding product selectivity control and dissociation mechanism during the UOR process have not been clarified. Here, we report that tuning the electron delocalization strength of Ni sites significantly affects the OH&#8208; binding sites, altering urea molecule dissociation patterns in alkaline systems. Using spinel NiCo2O4 as a model catalyst, the charge delocalization strength of nickel active centers is influenced by the degree of phosphorus&#8208;substituted anions. Specifically, complete phosphorus&#8208;substituted spinel enhances N2 selectivity to over 26.8% with a peak current density of 300 mA&#183;cm&#8208;2, while partial phosphorus&#8208;substituted spinel achieves a Faraday efficiency of 78.1% for liquid products (NOx&#8208;). Experiments and theory reveal that strong charge delocalization at Ni sites favors remote&#8208;site attack on urea molecules by hydroxide ions, whereas weak delocalization prefers nearby&#8208;site attack, enhancing UOR efficiency and suppressing OER in both pathways.</description>
      <author>Hui-Jian Zhang, Zi-Qiang Chen, Xiaotong Ye, Kang Xiao, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202421027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Delocalized Ni Active Sites in Spinel Catalysts Enable Efficient Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421027</link>
      <description>Hui-Jian Zhang, Zi-Qiang Chen, Xiaotong Ye, Kang Xiao, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404772608

                The urea oxidation reaction (UOR) has attracted much attention as an efficient alternative reaction to oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to its low required overpotential. Despite significant progress in efficient nickel&#8208;based catalysts, the fundamental issues regarding product selectivity control and dissociation mechanism during the UOR process have not been clarified. Here, we report that tuning the electron delocalization strength of Ni sites significantly affects the OH&#8208; binding sites, altering urea molecule dissociation patterns in alkaline systems. Using spinel NiCo2O4 as a model catalyst, the charge delocalization strength of nickel active centers is influenced by the degree of phosphorus&#8208;substituted anions. Specifically, complete phosphorus&#8208;substituted spinel enhances N2 selectivity to over 26.8% with a peak current density of 300 mA&#183;cm&#8208;2, while partial phosphorus&#8208;substituted spinel achieves a Faraday efficiency of 78.1% for liquid products (NOx&#8208;). Experiments and theory reveal that strong charge delocalization at Ni sites favors remote&#8208;site attack on urea molecules by hydroxide ions, whereas weak delocalization prefers nearby&#8208;site attack, enhancing UOR efficiency and suppressing OER in both pathways.</description>
      <author>Hui-Jian Zhang, Zi-Qiang Chen, Xiaotong Ye, Kang Xiao, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202421027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water dissociation on NiOOH in alkaline water electrolysis improves with increasing alkali metal cation size</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-db1l7</link>
      <description>Julia Gallenberger, Clara Gohlke, Marie Neumann, Anna K. Mechler, Jan P. Hofmann, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404855833

                The activity of nickel-based electrocatalysts towards the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is influenced by the presence of alkali metal cations in the electrolyte. Since the underlying mechanism is not fully resolved yet, we conducted a study combining Raman, FTIR, and photoelectron spectroscopies. We found that an improved OER activity correlates with structural changes of the catalyst. The cations are adsorbed in increasing amounts in the order Li+ &lt; Na+ &lt; K+ &lt; Cs+, opening the layers of the NiOOH layered double-hydroxide structure and promoting a transition from a more &#946;-like to a more &#947;-like NiOOH phase. In addition, the NiOOH surface gets increasingly deprotonated with increasing alkali cation size. We stabilized the activated catalyst materials in ultra-high vacuum and exposed them to controlled doses of H2O to analyse the catalyst-electrolyte interface in a quasi in-situ approach with photoelectron spectroscopy. Going from Li+ to Cs+, more OH groups are found on the surface after the exposure to H2O, demonstrating that such structural changes are facilitating the dissociation of H2O. As the dissociation of H2O is a crucial step in many OER mechanisms, its modified efficiency can be correlated with the observed trends in OER activity in LiOH, NaOH, KOH, and CsOH.</description>
      <author>Julia Gallenberger, Clara Gohlke, Marie Neumann, Anna K. Mechler, Jan P. Hofmann</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-db1l7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline&#8208;Amorphous Interface&#8208;Triggered Electron Redistribution on Copper(II) Sulfide@Metal (Ni, Co, and Fe) Oxyhydroxides for Ultra&#8208;Efficient Overall Water/Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403657</link>
      <description>Peng Gu, Yidong Song, Yihe Fan, Xin Meng, Lei Zhu, Guofeng Wang, Zhouguanwei Li, Heyuan Sun, Ziyu Zhao, Jinlong Zou, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404900237

                Abstract Rearranging the electronic orbitals of metal sites through interface engineering is the breakthrough for achieving high efficiencies in hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) on bimetallic catalysts. Here, via a multistep liquid&#8208;phase synthesis strategy, the crystalline&#8208;amorphous (c&#8208;a) interface is built by coating amorphous oxyhydroxide layer on the surface of crystallized copper(II) sulfide (CuS@MOOH, M = iron (Fe), cobalt (Co) and nickel (Ni)) with an internal cavity. For HER, c&#8208;a interface facilitates the electron filling of the 3d orbitals of Cu, thereby enhancing the coordination between Cu sites (Cu 2+ /Cu + ) and *H and reducing the energy barrier for *H adsorption. For OER, c&#8208;a interface triggers electronic rearrangement in the 3d orbitals of M sites, prompting electron transition from the t2g orbitals to the eg orbitals to achieve a half&#8208;filled state, optimizing the oxygen&#8208;intermediates adsorption on M sites (M 3+ /M 4+ ). Among CuS@MOOH, the as&#8208;marked CuS@CoOOH&#8208;6 exhibits the best activities with ultra&#8208;low overpotentials of 62 mV (HER) and 136 mV (OER). Only 1.52 V is sufficient to power the electrolyzer with CuS@CoOOH&#8208;6&#8208;based cathode/anode, maintaining a ultra&#8208;stable efficiency (96.9 %) over 72 h. Notably, CuS@CoOOH&#8208;6 also exhibits impressive activity/durability for natural seawater electrolysis. This study enhances understanding of the properties and electronic structure of the c&#8208;a interface for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Peng Gu, Yidong Song, Yihe Fan, Xin Meng, Lei Zhu, Guofeng Wang, Zhouguanwei Li, Heyuan Sun, Ziyu Zhao, Jinlong Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ELECTROCHEMICAL DEPOSITION OF NANOCRYSTALLINE NICKEL&#8211;CERIUM DIOXIDE COMPOSITE FROM A DEEP EUTECTIC SOLVENT TO FABRICATE ELECTROCATALYSTS FOR HYDROGEN ENERGY</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37827/ntsh.chem.2024.75.161</link>
      <description>V. S. Protsenko, O.D. Sukhatskyi, T.E. Butyrina, Proceedings of the Shevchenko Scientific Society Series &#1057;hemical sciences. 2024(75)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404892819

                This study reports the patterns of electroplating a composite coating containing phases of nanocrystalline metallic nickel and cerium dioxide from an electrolyte based on a new generation of ionic liquids, deep eutectic solvents (DESs). Currently, the use of DESs is an extremely promising direction for the electrochemical deposition of electrocatalytic coatings for electrochemical energy, particularly for "green" hydrogen energy. The electrolyte for deposition contained a liquid eutectic mixture of choline chloride and urea (the so-called "reline", a typical representative of DESs), in which nickel (II) chloride (0.1 mol/dm&#179;) and cerium (III) chloride (0.2&#8211;0.4 mol/dm3) were dissolved. According to the results of energy-dispersive X-ray analysis and XRD investigations, the composite coating contains approximately 12&#8211;16 at.% cerium, presumably in the form of cerium dioxide. A reaction scheme for the formation of the composite nanocoating, which includes a combination of chemical and electrochemical stages, is proposed. It was found that the incorporation of cerium oxide leads to a significant increase in electrocatalytic activity (compared to nickel coating) in the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction and anodic oxygen evolution and urea oxidation reactions. It is hypothesized that the observed enhancement in electrocatalytic effect is due to the formation of additional active catalytic sites on the surface containing cerium in different oxidation states (e.g., Ce(+4)/Ce(+3)), which can act as electron carriers in both cathodic and anodic reactions. A significant advantage of this composite is its bifunctionality as an electrocatalyst, meaning it can be used for both cathodic and anodic processes. The obtained results can be used in the development of new high-efficiency processes for the electrochemical synthesis of "green" hydrogen.</description>
      <author>V. S. Protsenko, O.D. Sukhatskyi, T.E. Butyrina</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37827/ntsh.chem.2024.75.161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material sustainability evaluation of electrocatalysts in early-stage development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ft8zt</link>
      <description>Lisa Heymann, Andrea Schreiber, Christian Pithan, Christoph Baeumer, Felix Gunkel, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404729679

                Sustainable energy materials for energy storage applications are crucial for a reliable energy transition. However, evaluating material sustainability in early stages of energy material research is a big challenge, as it is difficult to predict the final industrial process and supply chain of the investigated material. In this work we showcase that a sustainability evaluation can already be conducted in the early stage of electrocatalyst research. We provide a case study of two highly active alkaline oxygen evolution catalysts La0.6Sr0.4CoO3-&#948; and La0.6Ca0.4FeO3-&#948; with a thin film model catalyst approach. For the sustainability evaluation, we consider the material criticality, compare precursor prices, conduct an environmental impact analysis of the precursors based on life cycle assessment and provide a qualitative discourse for social impacts of raw material extraction. We find that La0.6Ca0.4FeO3-&#948; has a reduced environmental footprint, smaller precursor supply risk and 10 times lower precursor price compared to La0.6Sr0.4CoO3-&#948;. However, for both perovskites the high environmental impact and high supply risk of lanthanum is of immediate concern towards larger scale application purposes. Sustainability evaluation in the early stages of energy material research can be a great chance to develop new material selection strategies leveraging sustainability in later stages of materials research for the energy transition.</description>
      <author>Lisa Heymann, Andrea Schreiber, Christian Pithan, Christoph Baeumer, Felix Gunkel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-ft8zt</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Magnetic Heterostructures with Synergistic Regulation of Charge&#8208;Transfer and Spin&#8208;Ordering for Enhanced Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409842</link>
      <description>Chongyan Hao, Yang Wu, Xiaobo Zheng, Yumeng Du, Yameng Fan, Wei Kong Pang, Anton Tadich, Shujun Zhang, Thomas Frauenheim, Tianyi Ma, Xiaoning Li, Zhenxiang Cheng, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404722349

                Abstract The design of heterojunctions offers a crucial solution for energy conversion and storage challenges, but current research predominantly focuses on charge transfer benefits, often neglecting spin attribute regulation despite the increasing recognition of spin&#8208;sensitivity in many chemical reactions. In this study, a novel magnetic heterostructure, CoFe 2 O 4 @CoFeMo 3 O 8 , is designed to simultaneously modulate charge and spin characteristics, and systematically elucidated their synergistic impact on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Experimental results and density functional theory calculations confirmed that the magnetic heterostructure exhibits both charge transfer and spin polarization. It is found that the charge&#8208;transfer behavior enhances conductivity and adsorption ability through band structure regulation. Meanwhile, magnetically polarized electrons promote triplet O 2 generation and accelerate electron transport via spin&#8208;selective pathways. Moreover, the heterostructure's effective response to external alternating magnetic fields further amplifies the spin&#8208;dependent effect and introduces a magnetothermal effect, locally heating the active sites through spin flip, thereby boosting catalytic activity. Consequently, the OER activity of the magnetic heterostructure is improved by 83.8 times at 1.5 V compared to its individual components. This magnetic heterojunction strategy presents a promising avenue for advanced catalysis through synergistic regulating of charge&#8208;transfer and spin&#8208;ordering.</description>
      <author>Chongyan Hao, Yang Wu, Xiaobo Zheng, Yumeng Du, Yameng Fan, Wei Kong Pang, Anton Tadich, Shujun Zhang, Thomas Frauenheim, Tianyi Ma, Xiaoning Li, Zhenxiang Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202409842</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteroatom-Doped Carbon Allotropes in Water-Splitting Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/bk-2024-1491.ch007</link>
      <description>Abhisek Majumdar, Tran Khoa Dang, Deepanshu Malhotra, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, ACS symposium series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404751796

                Water-splitting technology is crucial for generating green hydrogen energy, a sustainable and clean fuel source that can significantly decrease reliance on fossil fuels and reduce greenhouse gas emissions, thereby helping to mitigate the global energy crisis. Renewable energy sources are expected to significantly replace fossil fuels, contributing to lowering greenhouse gas releases and helping to mitigate the energy crisis. The water-splitting process for generating green hydrogen energy is acknowledged as a promising approach toward achieving carbon neutrality. In this context, the attributes and features of electrocatalysts have a crucial part in shaping the reaction activity and selectivity of both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) processes involved in the water-splitting process. In addition to traditional noble-metal-based catalysts, carbon-based materials like carbon nanotubes (CNTs), graphene, and porous carbons have proven effective for catalyzing these reactions. A highly effective strategy to enhance their electrical, physical, and chemical characteristics involves doping them with heteroatoms like nitrogen (N), sulfur (S), phosphorus (P), boron (B), and transition metals. These materials, renowned for their exceptional characteristics, have been extensively researched in both the academic and industrial sectors for diverse applications, like energy conversion and storage technologies. This chapter comprehensively reviews notable advancements in the progress of heteroatom-doped carbon allotropes materials and their utilization in overall water splitting, highlighting different synthesis methods and strategies like templating strategy, hydrothermal/solvothermal synthesis, chemical vapour deposition (CVD), and high-temperature annealing aimed at achieving heteroatom-doped carbon allotrope materials with diverse types and quantities of dopants (both metallic and non-metallic), as well as multi-atoms. Additionally, the discussion underlines the structural and morphological characteristics that elucidate the structure-property relationship and improvements in the physicochemical features of heteroatom-doped carbon allotropes. It explores how heteroatom doping enhances different properties, such as conductivity, and optimizes surface adsorption for various reaction intermediates, as evidenced by density functional theory (DFT) calculations. Finally, the chapter explores recent promising studies of heteroatom-doped carbon allotropes with excellent catalytic performance and reveals their future prospects for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Abhisek Majumdar, Tran Khoa Dang, Deepanshu Malhotra, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/bk-2024-1491.ch007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The changes of oxygen extraction fraction in different types of lesions in multiple sclerosis: A cross-sectional and follow-up study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/1051</link>
      <description>Yan Xie, Wenzhen Zhu, Proceedings on CD-ROM - International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine. Scientific Meeting and Exhibition/Proceedings of the International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, Scientific Meeting and Exhibition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404748184

                Motivation: Multiple sclerosis (MS) lesions with different pathologic conditions could be distinguished by MRI. There may be differences in oxygen metabolism in different types of lesions. Goal(s): To explore the oxygen metabolism of different types of lesions in MS patients by oxygen extraction fraction (OEF) both cross-sectionally and longitudinally. Approach: The OEF map was reconstructed from a 3D multi-echo gradient echo scan. White matter lesions were classified into four types based on contrast-enhanced T1WI and quantitative susceptibility mapping. Results: There were differences in OEF among different types of MS lesions. The OEF in the lesion and the lesion type may change as time progresses. Impact: This study revealed tissue damage and oxygen metabolism level in different types of MS lesions. The OEF may contribute to further understanding of the pathological mechanisms in MS lesion evolution.</description>
      <author>Yan Xie, Wenzhen Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/1051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co nanoparticles encapsulated in N-doped carbon nanotube materials derived from new metal-organic frameworks for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07187e</link>
      <description>Jieling Zhang, Weiran Suo, Yu Han, Yiwen Cao, Yi Xu, Mengying Wang, Zuozhong Liang, Yuan Wang, Haoquan Zheng, Rui Cao, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404731116

                Bifunctional electrocatalysts used for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER) are of great significance for metal-air batteries. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs), after undergoing a high-temperature calcination process, emerge as promising precursors...</description>
      <author>Jieling Zhang, Weiran Suo, Yu Han, Yiwen Cao, Yi Xu, Mengying Wang, Zuozhong Liang, Yuan Wang, Haoquan Zheng, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07187e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decadal oscillations in the ocean&#8217;s largest oxygen-deficient zone</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adk4965</link>
      <description>Nicolas Duprey, Alan Foreman, Jos&#233; D. Carriquiry, C.D. Charles, Sara C. Sanchez, Hubert Vonhof, Florian Rubach, Renate Rabenstein, M. R&#246;hr, H&#233;ctor Reyes&#8208;Bonilla, Dario Marconi, Daniel M. Sigman, Gerald H. Haug, Alfredo Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Garc&#237;a, Science. 386(6725)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404835461

                The impact of global warming on the ocean&#8217;s oxygen-deficient zones (ODZs) is uncertain, partly because of a lack of data on past changes. We report monthly resolved records of coral skeleton&#8211;bound nitrogen isotopes (CS-&#948; 15 N) to reconstruct denitrification in the Eastern Tropical North Pacific (ETNP) ODZ over the last 80 years. The data indicate strong decadal variation in ETNP denitrification, with maxima during the cool North Pacific phase of Pacific Decadal Variability. The maxima in denitrification (and thus oxygen deficiency) were likely due to stronger upwelling that enhanced productivity leading to greater oxygen demand in the thermocline. Prior findings of multidecadal-to-centennial ODZ trends were likely biased by this variability. ODZ evolution over the next century will depend on how global warming interacts with the decadal oscillations.</description>
      <author>Nicolas Duprey, Alan Foreman, Jos&#233; D. Carriquiry, C.D. Charles, Sara C. Sanchez, Hubert Vonhof, Florian Rubach, Renate Rabenstein, M. R&#246;hr, H&#233;ctor Reyes&#8208;Bonilla, Dario Marconi, Daniel M. Sigman, Gerald H. Haug, Alfredo Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Garc&#237;a</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adk4965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen&#8208;blocking properties of HfB&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;MoSi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;SiC coating by CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20266</link>
      <description>Sheng Zhang, Ji Xiang, Yuexing Chen, Peipei Wang, Ph. V. Kiryukhantsev&#8208;Korneev, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;&#1096;&#1086;&#1074;, Ji Shi, Xuanru Ren, Xueqin Kang, Baojing Zhang, Ping Zhang, Leihua Xu, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404691021

                Abstract To alleviate the destructive alteration of the glass layer surface caused by gas evolution during the oxygen&#8208;blocking process of the HfB 2 &#8208;MoSi 2 &#8208;SiC coating, CeO 2 was incorporated to modify HfB 2 &#8208;MoSi 2 &#8208;SiC coating, and the anti&#8208;oxidation mechanism at 1700&#176;C in air was investigated. Compared with the unmodified HfB 2 &#8208;MoSi 2 &#8208;SiC coating, the addition of the refractory CeO 2 to the Hf&#8208;B&#8208;Si&#8208;O system leads to the formation of a stable Hf&#8208;Ce&#8208;B&#8208;Si&#8208;O complex phase glass, which substantially enhances the viscosity, stability, and self&#8208;healing sealing properties of the glass layer. The introduction of 0.75 vol.% CeO 2 significantly lowers the oxidative activity of the HfB 2 &#8208;MoSi 2 &#8208;SiC coating, boosting its average protective efficiency to 99.96% and reducing the maximal oxygen permeability by 43.48%, thus exhibiting superior oxygen&#8208;blocking performance. However, excessive addition of CeO 2 leads to an overabundance of oxygen release through its distinctive oxygen vacancy mechanism, which accelerates the formation of Hf&#8208;oxides, resulting in excessive viscosity on the coating surface and leaving oxidation defects unrepaired.</description>
      <author>Sheng Zhang, Ji Xiang, Yuexing Chen, Peipei Wang, Ph. V. Kiryukhantsev&#8208;Korneev, &#1045;. &#1040;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1074;&#1072;&#1096;&#1086;&#1074;, Ji Shi, Xuanru Ren, Xueqin Kang, Baojing Zhang, Ping Zhang, Leihua Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.20266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Microstructural Evolution and Mechanical Properties of Boron-Doped Ti35Zr30V10Nb25 Refractory High-Entropy Alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14121029</link>
      <description>Xinggang Wang, Meng Sun, Jiaxin Liu, Xueqing Liu, Weibin Jiang, Xianping Wang, Q.F. Fang, Crystals. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404755203

                The addition of oxygen or nitrogen in refractory high-entropy alloys (HEAs) has been widely reported, but studies on boron-doped HEAs have mainly focused on the segregation of boron elements at grain boundaries. The changes in the microstructure and mechanical properties in TiZrNb-based HEAs remain enigmatic. In this work, boron-doped Ti35Zr30V10Nb25 (Ti35-xB) refractory HEAs were designed to elucidate their microstructural evolution and mechanical properties. Unlike oxygen and nitrogen, trace amounts of boron addition result in the formation of borides, and boron exhibits a strong repulsion towards Zr, leading to Zr-depleted borides. Borides distributed along the grain boundaries refine the grain size and dendritic structure. The borides and structural refinement effect enhance the strain-hardening capacity and uniform elongation, resulting in an over 15% uniform elongation for Ti35-0.25B.</description>
      <author>Xinggang Wang, Meng Sun, Jiaxin Liu, Xueqing Liu, Weibin Jiang, Xianping Wang, Q.F. Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14121029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solving coupled non-linear schr&#246;dinger equations via quantum imaginary time evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1140/epjs/s11734-024-01384-z</link>
      <description>Yang Hong Li, Jim Al-Khalili, P. D. Stevenson, The European Physical Journal Special Topics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404681499

                Abstract Coupled non-linear Schr&#246;dinger equations are crucial in describing dynamics of many-particle systems. We present a quantum imaginary time evolution (ITE) algorithm as a solution to such equations in the case of nuclear Hartree-Fock approach. Under a simplified Skyrme interaction model, we calculate the ground state energy of an oxygen-16 nucleus and demonstrate that the result is in agreement with the classical ITE algorithm. We examine bottlenecks and deficiencies in the quantum algorithm and suggest possible improvements.</description>
      <author>Yang Hong Li, Jim Al-Khalili, P. D. Stevenson</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1140/epjs/s11734-024-01384-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation of High-Altitude Plants to Harsh Environments: Application of Phenotypic-Variation-Related Methods and Multi-Omics Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252312666</link>
      <description>Kai&#8208;Lu Zhang, Ya-Nan Leng, Ruirui Hao, Wenyao Zhang, Hongfei Li, Mo&#8208;Xian Chen, Fu&#8208;Yuan Zhu, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 25(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404724114

                High-altitude plants face extreme environments such as low temperature, low oxygen, low nutrient levels, and strong ultraviolet radiation, causing them to adopt complex adaptation mechanisms. Phenotypic variation is the core manifestation of ecological adaptation and evolution. Many plants have developed a series of adaptive strategies through long-term natural selection and evolution, enabling them to survive and reproduce under such harsh conditions. This article reviews the techniques and methods used in recent years to study the adaptive evolution of high-altitude plants, including transplantation techniques, genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and metabolomics techniques, and their applications in high-altitude plant adaptive evolution. Transplantation technology focuses on phenotypic variation, which refers to natural variations in morphological, physiological, and biochemical characteristics, exploring their key roles in nutrient utilization, photosynthesis optimization, and stress-resistance protection. Multiple omics technologies, including genomics, transcriptomics, proteomics, and metabolomics, have revealed genes, regulatory pathways, and metabolic networks associated with phenotypic variations at the genetic and molecular levels. At the same time, the limitations and deficiencies of current technologies used to study plant adaptation to high-altitude environments were discussed. In addition, we propose future improvements to existing technologies and advocate for the integration of different technologies at multiple levels to study the molecular mechanisms of plant adaptation to high-altitude environments, thus providing insights for future research in this field.</description>
      <author>Kai&#8208;Lu Zhang, Ya-Nan Leng, Ruirui Hao, Wenyao Zhang, Hongfei Li, Mo&#8208;Xian Chen, Fu&#8208;Yuan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252312666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interglacial dust, ocean fertilisation and Neoproterozoic earth oxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/dep2.323</link>
      <description>Leandro G. DaSilva, Peir K. Pufahl, No&#235;l P. James, The Depositional Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404855918

                Abstract Feedback processes that drove Earth's second major increase in ocean&#8211;atmosphere oxygen levels during the Neoproterozoic are poorly constrained. Variability in seawater redox over geological timescales is commonly linked to changes in the biogeochemical cycling of P and thus the rate of primary production and generation of photosynthetic oxygen. In the modern surface ocean, an important source of bioessential P and micronutrients (Fe, Cu, Co, Zn, Mo, Cr and Ni) is aeolian dust derived from deserts and arid, post&#8208;glacial landscapes. It is interpreted herein that glacial retreat following the Sturtian ( ca 717 to 660 Ma) and Marinoan ( ca 650 to 635 Ma) snowball glaciations provided copious dust to the global ocean. Correlation of interglacial siltstone successions in palaeogeographical context suggests that such dust accumulation was diachronous and concentrated in the palaeo&#8208;horse latitudes (30&#176; N and 30&#176; S). Delivery of this dust from continents is likely reflected in the steep increase in global radiogenic Sr isotope values ( 87 Sr/ 86 Sr) in post&#8208;Sturtian carbonates, and changes in the &#948; 18 O signatures of Cryogenian zircons derived from subducted marine sediments. Accumulation of sedimentary organic matter also peaked during interglacial periods, suggesting a causal link between glaciation, aeolian dust and primary production. This relationship implies windblown dust was an important source of P and micronutrients for an evolving biological pump that stimulated primary production, enhanced burial of organic carbon and increased ocean&#8211;atmosphere oxygen concentrations. Thus, delivery of aeolian dust to the global ocean was likely critical for sustaining Earth's second major increase in oxygen. Sequestration of atmospheric CO 2 in organic&#8208;rich siltstones and shales is also interpreted to have been an important negative feedback process, which together with silicate weathering, prevented runaway greenhouse conditions during interglacial periods. The oxygen produced by this aeolian marine biological pump may have helped pave the way for the evolution of multicellular animals in the Ediacaran.</description>
      <author>Leandro G. DaSilva, Peir K. Pufahl, No&#235;l P. James</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/dep2.323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post covid Follow up on Diabetic Patient</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.70921/medev.v30i1.893</link>
      <description>Dana Diana Romanescu, Corina Beiu&#537;anu, A. Maghiar, Alionka Bostan, Cociuban C. L. Micula, Iulia Codru&#355;a Macovei, Erika Bimb&#243;-Szuhai, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404831402

                Aim and objectives: This study aimed to explore insulin necessity in hospitalized patients with non-insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus (DM) for the first six months after COVID-19 infection. A pro-inflammatory and pro-coagulative status probably contribute to the risk of worse outcomes in diabetes. Material and Methods: A number of 78 non-insulin necessitate diabetic patients with COVID-19 infection which needed oxygen therapy were included in the research. There were collected parameters routinely assessed to detect the possible predictors of diabetic patient evolution in SARS-CoV-2 infection. Results: The evolution of insulin necessity for 78 patients with non-insulin-dependent DM at admission was towards transformation into insulin-dependent DM at 6 months after discharge in 30 cases (38.5%), while the rest of the patients remained on oral antidiabetic drugs (48 patients, 61.5%). Conclusions: At hospitalized diabetic patient with covid-19 infection under corticotherapy, statistically significant differences were noted in HbA1c and aPTT level at 3 and 6 months after discharge.</description>
      <author>Dana Diana Romanescu, Corina Beiu&#537;anu, A. Maghiar, Alionka Bostan, Cociuban C. L. Micula, Iulia Codru&#355;a Macovei, Erika Bimb&#243;-Szuhai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.70921/medev.v30i1.893</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Oxygen Concentrations on the Development of Fires in Ventilation Limited Environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2885/1/012057</link>
      <description>Ayaan Lakhani, Alexander DiPaola, Peter Senez, Elizabeth J. Weckman, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2885(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404854290

                Abstract Large-scale fire tests at the University of Waterloo compare behaviour of a Canadian non-fire retardant faux leather couch and a UK fire-retardant faux leather couch of the same construction under ventilation limited conditions. Results reveal that both fuel loads reach maximum, but different, mass loss rates at minimum oxygen concentration in the environment. Following this, they document the rapid decay in fuel mass loss rate with consequent decrease in temperature through the burn structure. Time-varying volatile organic compounds and carbon monoxide data show preferential increase in concentration as combustion efficiency decreases. The paper adds novel time varying, simultaneously collected fuel mass, temperature and concentration data with aim to provide new insight into the full evolution of compartment fires through transition from early growth to ventilation limited conditions and subsequent fire decay.</description>
      <author>Ayaan Lakhani, Alexander DiPaola, Peter Senez, Elizabeth J. Weckman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2885/1/012057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pore Types and Dolomite Reservoir Genesis of the Fifth Member of the Ordovician Majiagou Formation in the Central and Eastern Ordos Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app142310976</link>
      <description>Shilei Chen, Rongji Dai, Shunshe Luo, Applied Sciences. 14(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404715881

                The Ordovician dolomite in the Ordos Basin is an important natural gas reservoir. Exploring dolomite genesis and the factors influencing reservoir characteristics is essential for deep carbonate rock exploration. This study offers a comprehensive analysis of dolomite evolution using methods such as thin-section petrography, isotope analysis, and trace and rare earth elements. The analysis shows that: Based on petrographic observations of the Majiagou Formation in the study area, the dolomite in the study area can be divided into residual oolitic dolomite of synsedimentary or metasomatic origin, micritic dolomite of secondary metasomatism or recrystallization origin, powder crystal dolomite, and fine crystal dolomite. Reservoir pores mainly develop intergranular pores, mold pores, dissolved pores, and fractures. Combined with the characteristics of major elements, trace elements, carbon and oxygen isotopes, rare earth elements, and inclusions in the study area, it can be concluded that the fifth member dolomite of the Majiagou Formation is of shallow&#8211;medium burial origin. The diagenetic evolution sequence from the penecontemporaneous period to the middle&#8211;deep burial period in the study area is penecontemporaneous dolomite, anhydrite dissolution &#8594; seepage silt filling, freshwater dolomite, calcite, and gypsum filling, pressure solution compaction, calcite partial dissolution &#8594; gypsum filling, karst cave, buried hydrothermal dolomite, dolomite partial dissolution &#8594; calcite complete dissolution, pore dissolution expansion, and quartz pyrite filling. In the early stage of compaction and pressure solution, the primary pores are rapidly reduced, and in the later stage, sutures are generated to provide channels for reservoir fluid migration. The recrystallization reduces the porosity during the middle&#8211;deep burial period.</description>
      <author>Shilei Chen, Rongji Dai, Shunshe Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app142310976</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observations of Molecular CN toward S-type Asymptotic Giant Branch Stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ad8ba6</link>
      <description>Yanan Feng, Xiaohu Li, Xiaofeng Yang, T. J. Millar, R. Szczerba, Sheng&#8208;Li Qin, Xue-Jian Jiang, Donghui Quan, Juan Tuo, Zhenzhen Miao, Sheng&#8208;Yuan Liu, Xiang Liu, The Astronomical Journal. 168(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404696113

                Abstract S-type asymptotic giant branch (AGB) stars are defined by their carbon-to-oxygen (C/O) ratio approaching unity. However, observations of circumstellar molecules in these stars are limited and challenging. In this study, we used the James Clerk Maxwell Telescope to search for cyanide (CN) in 12 selected S-type AGB stars, with only 4 of these stars displaying CN spectral line signals. The column density and fractional abundance of CN were calculated assuming local thermodynamic equilibrium, and the average CN-to-hydrogen-cyanide (HCN) abundance ratio of the four sources is about 0.036. We investigate, for the first time, the relationship between CN and HCN fractional abundances in all types of AGB stars, finding that the ratio is similar in O-rich and S-type stars, while those in C-rich stars are quite different. This result supports the idea that the level of HCN photodissociation plays a crucial role in determining the CN abundance in the circumstellar envelopes of AGB stars at various stages of their evolution.</description>
      <author>Yanan Feng, Xiaohu Li, Xiaofeng Yang, T. J. Millar, R. Szczerba, Sheng&#8208;Li Qin, Xue-Jian Jiang, Donghui Quan, Juan Tuo, Zhenzhen Miao, Sheng&#8208;Yuan Liu, Xiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ad8ba6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MULTI-ECHO FUNCTIONAL IMAGING ON AN ULTRA HIGH-PERFORMANCE HEAD-ONLY GRADIENT SYSTEM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/5122</link>
      <description>Gail Kohls, Nastaren Abad, Heidi Morris, Mauren Hood, J. Kevin DeMarco, Thomas Foo, Proceedings on CD-ROM - International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine. Scientific Meeting and Exhibition/Proceedings of the International Society for Magnetic Resonance in Medicine, Scientific Meeting and Exhibition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404743435

                Motivation: This abstract focuses on educating on how high-gradient MRI systems can utilize the multi-echo functional MRI (ME-fMRI) techniques. Goal(s): We explain the blood-oxygen-level-dependent (BOLD) signal technique and how additional echoes can improve the signal fidelity. Approach: The ME-fMRI, using three or more echoes allow for the pixelwise T2* decay to be modeled, and as BOLD contrast is a function of T2* evolution over time, an experiment sampling the voxel-wise T2* signal decay can be used to separate BOLD from artifact signal constituents. Results: Gradient systems with ultra-rapid slew rates (&amp;gt; 400 T/m/s) allow ME-fMRI to reduce artefacts from flow, motion, and susceptibility effects. Impact: MRI systems with ultra-high gradient systems can reduce artefacts from flow, motion, and susceptibility effects in the BOLD contrast technique using an ME-fMRI technique with three or more echoes to improve fidelity of fMRI.</description>
      <author>Gail Kohls, Nastaren Abad, Heidi Morris, Mauren Hood, J. Kevin DeMarco, Thomas Foo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58530/2024/5122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fundamental understanding of voltage decay in Li-rich Mn-based layered oxides cathode materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43673-024-00138-2</link>
      <description>Huixian Xie, Jia&#8208;Cheng Xiao, Hongyi Chen, Boyang Zhang, Kwun Nam Hui, Shanqing Zhang, C.S. Liu, Dong Luo, Zhan Lin, AAPPS bulletin. 34(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404703159

                Abstract To satisfy the needs of modern intelligent society for power supplies with long-endurance ability, Li-rich Mn-based layered oxides (LRMOs) are receiving much attention because of their ultrahigh capacity. However, their real-world implementation is hindered by the serious voltage decay, which results in a continuous decrease in energy density. The understanding on voltage decay still remains a mystery due to the complicated hybrid cationic-anionic redox and the serious surface-interface reactions in LRMOs. Moreover, some of the mechanisms are occasionally contradictory, indicating that the origin of voltage decay is still unclear. As a result, none of the innovative strategies proposed on the basis of mechanisms has effectively alleviated the problem of voltage decay, and voltage decay becomes a long-term distress of LRMOs. Therefore, it is particularly crucial to sort out the mutual relation of various mechanisms, which helps to go back to the source of voltage decay. In this review, we summarize the current mechanisms of voltage decay as structural evolution and oxygen chemistry, and attempt to trace the origin of voltage decay for LRMOs. In addition, we discuss how current researches address the issue with generalized guidance in designing appropriate strategies based on mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Huixian Xie, Jia&#8208;Cheng Xiao, Hongyi Chen, Boyang Zhang, Kwun Nam Hui, Shanqing Zhang, C.S. Liu, Dong Luo, Zhan Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43673-024-00138-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular basis of the phosphorothioation-sensing antiphage defense system IscS&#8211;DndBCDE&#8211;DndI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkae1133</link>
      <description>Yaqian Tang, Dan Wu, Yueying Zhang, Xuan Liu, Hui Chu, Qian Tan, Lixu Jiang, Shi Chen, Geng Wu, Lianrong Wang, Nucleic Acids Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404837068

                Abstract Phosphorothioation serves as a DNA backbone modification mechanism, wherein a sulfur atom substitutes the nonbridging oxygen atom within the phosphodiester, facilitated by the gene products of dndABCDE or sspABCD. The combination of dndABCDE with dndFGH forms a bona fide defense system, where the DndFGH protein complex exhibits DNA nickase and DNA translocase activities to prevent phage invasion. In this study, we identified that dndI, co-transcribed with dndFGH, can independently couple with iscS-dndBCDE as an anti-phage defense system. Moreover, we resolved the crystal structure of DndI from Salmonella at a resolution of 3.10 &#197;. We discovered that its residue Y25, residing within a hydrophobic region of DndI, is involved in phosphorothioate (PT) sensing. Upon sensing PT modifications at 5&#8242;-GPSAAC-3&#8242;/5&#8242;-GPSTTC-3&#8242;, the ATPase activity of DndI is stimulated, which subsequently triggers a conformational transition, facilitating the dissociation of DndI from self-DNA, thereby allowing DndI to avoid cleaving self-DNA while restricting PT-deficient phage DNA. This research broadens the knowledge of the mechanistic diversity underlying PT-based defense systems and highlights their complexity in the course of evolution.</description>
      <author>Yaqian Tang, Dan Wu, Yueying Zhang, Xuan Liu, Hui Chu, Qian Tan, Lixu Jiang, Shi Chen, Geng Wu, Lianrong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/nar/gkae1133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New-to-nature CO2-dependent acetyl-CoA assimilation enabled by an engineered B12-dependent acyl-CoA mutase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53762-9</link>
      <description>Helena Schulz-Mirbach, Philipp Wichmann, Ari Satanowski, H. Meusel, Tong Wu, Maren Nattermann, Simon Burgener, Nicole Paczia, Arren Bar&#8208;Even, Tobias J. Erb, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404716791

                Abstract Acetyl-CoA is a key metabolic intermediate and the product of various natural and synthetic one-carbon (C1) assimilation pathways. While an efficient conversion of acetyl-CoA into other central metabolites, such as pyruvate, is imperative for high biomass yields, available aerobic pathways typically release previously fixed carbon in the form of CO 2 . To overcome this loss of carbon, we develop a new-to-nature pathway, the Lcm module, in this study. The Lcm module provides a direct link between acetyl-CoA and pyruvate, is shorter than any other oxygen-tolerant route and notably fixes CO 2 , instead of releasing it. The Lcm module relies on the new-to-nature activity of a coenzyme B 12 -dependent mutase for the conversion of 3-hydroxypropionyl-CoA into lactyl-CoA. We demonstrate Lcm activity of the scaffold enzyme 2-hydroxyisobutyryl-CoA mutase from Bacillus massiliosenegalensis , and further improve catalytic efficiency 10-fold by combining in vivo targeted hypermutation and adaptive evolution in an engineered Escherichia coli selection strain. Finally, in a proof-of-principle, we demonstrate the complete Lcm module in vitro. Overall, our work demonstrates a synthetic CO 2 -incorporating acetyl-CoA assimilation route that expands the metabolic solution space of central carbon metabolism, providing options for synthetic biology and metabolic engineering.</description>
      <author>Helena Schulz-Mirbach, Philipp Wichmann, Ari Satanowski, H. Meusel, Tong Wu, Maren Nattermann, Simon Burgener, Nicole Paczia, Arren Bar&#8208;Even, Tobias J. Erb</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53762-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Oxygen Redox Activity by Local Chemical Disorder toward Robust Co&#8208;Free Li&#8208;Rich Cathode with High Voltage Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414443</link>
      <description>Hongfei Zheng, Mengjian Fan, Chenying Zhang, Wei He, Guiyang Gao, Yuanyuan Liu, Laisen Wang, Qingshui Xie, Dong&#8208;Liang Peng, Jun L&#252;, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404774764

                Abstract Despite extensive investigation on the lattice oxygen redox (LOR) in Li&#8208;rich cathodes, significant challenges remain in utilizing LOR activity without compromising structural and electrochemical stability. Related breakthroughs are hindered by the lack of understanding regarding how different LOR activity influences the structural evolution and electrochemical stability, and what is the optimal LOR activity. Herein, the degree of LOR activity is successfully regulated from 22% to 92% in Co&#8208;free Li&#8208;rich cathodes (Li 1+x Mn 0.62 Ni 0.18 O 2 ) by controlling local chemical disorder, and the relationship between LOR activity and cycling stability is revealed. Conventional consensus is challenged by new findings that the over&#8208;suppressive LOR activity also undermines electrochemical/structural stability, and even causes more severe voltage fading compared to cases with excessive LOR. However, their failure mechanisms related to lattice strain present different characteristics. Based on the established understanding, the appropriate LOR activation is necessary to balance the maximum reversible LOR activity and good stability, and the optimal degree is identified as 86% in Li 1.18 Mn 0.62 Ni 0.18 O 2 (LR&#8208;78). LR&#8208;78 exhibits remarkable voltage retention of 96% after 400 cycles at 1 C, and superior high&#8208;rate cyclability without capacity decay within 600 cycles at 5 C. These findings significantly broaden the understanding of LOR mechanisms and provide critical guidance for designing durable LOR&#8208;based cathodes.</description>
      <author>Hongfei Zheng, Mengjian Fan, Chenying Zhang, Wei He, Guiyang Gao, Yuanyuan Liu, Laisen Wang, Qingshui Xie, Dong&#8208;Liang Peng, Jun L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation on Crystallization of CaO&#8208;Al&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;B&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;BaO Slag Using Differential Scanning Calorimeter and In Situ High&#8208;Temperature Raman Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400697</link>
      <description>Yong Lin, Francis Gyakwaa, Tommi Kokkonen, Riku Mattila, Baijun Yan, Timo Fabritius, Qifeng Shu, steel research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404891934

                CaO&#8208;Al 2 O 3 &#8208;B 2 O 3 &#8208;based slag is among the most promising &#8220;nonreactive&#8221; mold fluxes for continuous casting of high&#8208;aluminum steel. However, CaO&#8208;Al 2 O 3 &#8208;B 2 O 3 &#8208;based slag system exhibits a stronger crystallization ability compared to traditional mold fluxes. Herein, calcium oxide in CaO&#8208;Al 2 O 3 &#8208;10%B 2 O 3 slag is partially replaced by the same mass of barium oxide (5 and 10 mass%) to adjust the crystallization ability. The crystallization of glassy slags is then investigated using a differential scanning calorimeter and their crystallization kinetics are analyzed using the Matusita&#8211;Sakka model. The structural evolution of glassy slags from room temperature to 1200 &#176;C is also investigated using in situ Raman spectroscopy. The kinetic analysis shows that the crystallization process of CaO&#8208;Al 2 O 3 &#8208;B 2 O 3 &#8208;BaO glassy slags follows the surface crystallization mechanism. The predominant crystalline products are calcium monoaluminate (CaAl 2 O 4 ) and calcium borate (Ca 3 (BO 3 ) 2 ). The partial replacement of calcium oxide by barium oxide inhibits the growth of CaAl 2 O 4 in the slag by increasing the activation energy of crystal growth. The high&#8208;temperature Raman spectroscopy study shows that the band between 700 and 900 cm &#8722;1 gets weaker relative to the band between 450 and 650 cm &#8722;1 at high temperatures. This indicates the strengthening of bending vibration of Al&#8208;O&#8208;Al, which is consistent with the precipitation of CaAl 2 O 4 with full oxygen bridging.</description>
      <author>Yong Lin, Francis Gyakwaa, Tommi Kokkonen, Riku Mattila, Baijun Yan, Timo Fabritius, Qifeng Shu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/srin.202400697</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidative/Nitrosative Stress and Brain Involvement in Sepsis: A Relationship Supported by Immunohistochemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina60121949</link>
      <description>Giuseppe Bertozzi, Michela Ferrara, Mariagrazia Calvano, Natascha Pascale, Aldo Di Fazio, Medicina. 60(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404718285

                Background and Objectives: A large amount of recent evidence suggests that cellular inability to consume oxygen could play a notable part in promoting sepsis as a consequence of mitochondrial dysfunction and oxidative stress. The latter could, in fact, represent a fundamental stage in the evolution of the &#8220;natural history&#8221; of sepsis. Following a study previously conducted by the same working group on heart samples, the present research project aims to evaluate, through an immunohistochemical study, the existence and/or extent of oxidative stress in the brains of subjects who died due to sepsis and define, after reviewing the literature, its contribution to the septic process to support the use of medications aimed at correcting redox anomalies in the management of septic patients. Materials and Methods: 10 cases of subjects who died in healthcare facilities with ante-mortem clinical-laboratory signs that allowed the diagnosis of septic shock were selected as case studies, and 1 case of a subject who died immediately following a road traffic accident was used as a negative control. Samples of the cerebral cortex were then taken, fixed in formalin, and subjected to sections on which an immunohistochemical study was performed using anti-NOX-2, NT, iNOS, and 8-OHdG antibodies. Results: The results emerging from the present study demonstrate that despite a variable expressivity for the NT, iNOS, and NOX2 markers, the brain samples demonstrated univocal and high positivity for the 8-OHdG marker. Conclusions: This would allow us to hypothesize how, regardless of the mechanism of production of ROS and NOS (iNOS or NOX2 mediated) and the pathophysiological mechanisms that are triggered during sepsis, oxidative damage to DNA represents the event to which this whole process leads and, in fact, in the literature, is directly correlated to sepsis-dependent mortality. Neurons, conversely, appear to be more sensitive to oxidative stress because of a low number of protective or scavenger molecules (catalase, glutathione peroxidase, GSH, or vitamin E). Therefore, despite reduced production, the manifestation of the damage remains high. This evidence, together with that of the previous study, can only support the introduction of substances with an antioxidant function in the guidelines for the treatment of sepsis.</description>
      <author>Giuseppe Bertozzi, Michela Ferrara, Mariagrazia Calvano, Natascha Pascale, Aldo Di Fazio</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/medicina60121949</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two mixed-valent cerium oxo clusters: synthesis, structure, and self-assembly</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1507834</link>
      <description>Yuan Gao, Yang Zhang, Zhe Han, Chunhui Wang, Lei Zhang, Jieshan Qiu, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404897473

                Studies on cerium oxo clusters (CeOCs) are not only significant for understanding the redox and hydrolysis behaviors of Ce(III/IV) ions but also crucial for the rational synthesis of novel clusters and nanoceria with specific Ce(III)/Ce(IV) ratios. Here, two sets of reactions were conducted using cerium nitrate and H 2 O 2 -oxidized cerium nitrate, resulting in the formation of two distinct mixed-valent CeOCs [Ce III 4 Ce IV 10 O 14 (OH) 2 (PhCO 2 ) 22 (DMF) 6 ] (Ce 14 ) and [Ce III 2 Ce IV 22 O 28 (OH) 8 (PhCO 2 ) 30 (DMF) 4 ] (Ce 24C ). These two clusters exhibit different structures and Ce(III)/Ce(IV) ratios, demonstrating the critical role of cerium oxidation states and the occurrence of redox reactions in cluster formation. Ce 14 is the first tetradecanuclear CeOC with a novel structure, whereas Ce 24C differed in its Ce(III)/Ce(IV) ratio, protonation levels of O atoms, and ligands from previously reported 24-nuclear CeOCs. Furthermore, various techniques were employed to investigate the formation process of these two clusters. X-ray photoelectron spectra (XPS) revealed that the white precipitates formed during the preparation of Ce 14 contain Ce(III) ions, while the reddish-brown precipitates formed during the preparation of Ce 24C contain a mixture of Ce(III) and Ce(IV) ions. These two precipitations were individually dissolved in N,N-Dimethylformamide (DMF). The evolution of solution color and ultraviolet-visible (UV-Vis) spectra over time revealed the gradual oxidation of partial Ce(III) ions by oxygen in the solution of the white precipitation. As Ce(IV) ions increased in this solution, time-resolved small angle X-ray scattering (SAXS) data demonstrated the self-assembly of the Ce 14 clusters after 4 days. In contrast, SAXS data and UV-Vis spectra revealed the rapid assembly of Ce 24C clusters within 2 h due to the initial coexistence of Ce(IV) and Ce(III) ions in the DMF solution of the reddish-brown precipitation. The continued reduction of partial Ce(IV) ions in this solution does not affect Ce 24C clusters&#8217; formation and stability. Our studies expand the family of CeOCs and enhance our understanding of the effects of cerium&#8217;s oxidation states on cluster formation.</description>
      <author>Yuan Gao, Yang Zhang, Zhe Han, Chunhui Wang, Lei Zhang, Jieshan Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1507834</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
