<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2024 01:08:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the high-entropy perovskite as efficient and reliable electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02680b</link>
      <description>Ruirui Wei, Gaoliang Fu, Hui Qi, Hewei Liu, RSC advances. 14(26)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399411629

                This work reports a high-entropy perovskite La 0.3 Sr 0.7 (CrMnFeCoNi) 0.2 O 3 as a high-performance OER electrocatalyst. Sr doping induces the formation of higher-valence Cr 6+ , Mn 4+ , Fe 4+ , Co 4+ and Ni 3+ responsible for the excellent OER activity.</description>
      <author>Ruirui Wei, Gaoliang Fu, Hui Qi, Hewei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02680b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational designing NiVO3@CoNi-MOF heterostructures on activated carbon cloth for high-performance asymmetric supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.044</link>
      <description>Sheng Qin, Jianying Liang, Shuang Luo, Jiangshan Feng, Pengfei Xu, Kang Liu, Jien Li, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399421162

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sheng Qin, Jianying Liang, Shuang Luo, Jiangshan Feng, Pengfei Xu, Kang Liu, Jien Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge engineering in black phosphorene with tunable electronic structures as efficient oxygen evolution electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2024.116013</link>
      <description>Huating Liu, Zongyu Huang, Hui Qiao, Xiang Qi, Physica. E, Low-dimensional systems and nanostructures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399424024

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huating Liu, Zongyu Huang, Hui Qiao, Xiang Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.physe.2024.116013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g</link>
      <description>Chao Shuai, Chunyang Kong, Y.S. Li, Liang Zhang, Qi Chen, Zunli Mo, RSC advances. 14(26)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399432345

                3D flower-like bimetallic MOF (F-Ni1Co4-BTC) was successfully designed and synthesized and exhibited excellent OER activity. Moreover, fixed on the surface of a carbon cloth, F-Ni1Co4-BTC realized high OER activity and long-term durability.</description>
      <author>Chao Shuai, Chunyang Kong, Y.S. Li, Liang Zhang, Qi Chen, Zunli Mo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrospun carbon nanofiber&#8208;supported V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; with enriched oxygen vacancies as a free&#8208;standing high&#8208;rate anode for an all&#8208;vanadium&#8208;based full battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.517</link>
      <description>Qi Lai, Baocai Yin, Dou Yu, Qing Zhang, Yingmei Zhu, Yingkui Yang, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399436653

                Abstract Synergistic regulation of hierarchical nanostructures and defect engineering is effective in accelerating electron and ion transport for metal oxide electrodes. Herein, carbon nanofiber&#8208;supported V 2 O 3 with enriched oxygen vacancies (OV&#8208;V 2 O 3 @CNF) was fabricated using the facile electrospinning method, followed by thermal reduction. Differing from the traditional particles embedded within carbon nanofibers or irregularly distributed between carbon nanofibers, the free&#8208;standing OV&#8208;V 2 O 3 @CNF allows for V 2 O 3 nanosheets to grow vertically on one&#8208;dimensional (1D) carbon nanofibers, enabling abundant active sites, shortened ion diffusion pathway, continuous electron transport, and robust structural stability. Meanwhile, density functional theory calculations confirmed that the oxygen vacancies can promote intrinsic electron conductivity and reduce ion diffusion energy barrier. Consequently, the OV&#8208;V 2 O 3 @CNF anode delivers a large reversible capacity of 812 mAh g &#8722;1 at 0.1 A g &#8722;1 , superior rate capability (405 mAh g &#8722;1 at 5 A g &#8722;1 ), and long cycle life (378 mAh g &#8722;1 at 5 A g &#8722;1 after 1000 cycles). Moreover, an all&#8208;vanadium full battery (V 2 O 5 //OV&#8208;V 2 O 3 @CNF) was assembled using an OV&#8208;V 2 O 3 @CNF anode and a V 2 O 5 cathode, which outputs a working voltage of 2.5 V with high energy density and power density, suggesting promising practical application. This work offers fresh perspectives on constructing hierarchical 1D nanofiber electrodes by combining defect engineering and electrospinning technology.</description>
      <author>Qi Lai, Baocai Yin, Dou Yu, Qing Zhang, Yingmei Zhu, Yingkui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of pH&#8208;universal electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.555</link>
      <description>Jingwen Lin, Qianqian Wang, Zhenyun Zhao, Dongliang Chen, Rumin Liu, Zhizhen Ye, Bin L&#252;, Bin Yang, Jianguo Lu, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399436717

                Abstract The path to searching for sustainable energy has never stopped since the depletion of fossil fuels can lead to serious environmental pollution and energy shortages. Using water electrolysis to produce hydrogen has been proven to be a prioritized approach for green resource production. It is highly crucial to explore inexpensive and high&#8208;performance electrocatalysts for accelerating hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and apply them to industrial cases on a large scale. Here, we summarize the different mechanisms of HER in different pH settings and review recent advances in non&#8208;noble&#8208;metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Then, based on the previous efforts, we discuss several universal strategies for designing pH&#8208;independent catalysts and show directions for the future design of pH&#8208;universal catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jingwen Lin, Qianqian Wang, Zhenyun Zhao, Dongliang Chen, Rumin Liu, Zhizhen Ye, Bin L&#252;, Bin Yang, Jianguo Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Craved Ni3S2&#8211;Sm2O3 heterojunction with enhanced electrocatalytic stability and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00411-y</link>
      <description>Razan A. Alshgari, Jafar Hussain Shah, S. Noor Mohammad, Ome Parkash Kumar, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Han-guk seramik hakoeji/Han'gug se'la'mig haghoeji. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399439988

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Razan A. Alshgari, Jafar Hussain Shah, S. Noor Mohammad, Ome Parkash Kumar, Abdul Ghafoor Abid</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00411-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyrolysis-free coupling strategy to synthesize two-dimensional oxygen reaction electrocatalysts for rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152909</link>
      <description>Pengfei Xie, Hao Hu, Lingzhe Fang, Xiaohua Yu, Ju Rong, Xiaoyi Qiu, Xiaofeng Wu, Tao Li, Minhua Shao, Jin&#8208;Cheng Li, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399446733

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pengfei Xie, Hao Hu, Lingzhe Fang, Xiaohua Yu, Ju Rong, Xiaoyi Qiu, Xiaofeng Wu, Tao Li, Minhua Shao, Jin&#8208;Cheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152909</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Stability of Boron Modified NiFe Hydroxide for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01186d</link>
      <description>Yewon Hong, Juhyung Choi, Juhyung Choi, Juhyung Choi, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399452068

                The introduction of non-metal elements including boron has been identified as a significant means to enhance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance in NiFe-based catalysts. To understand the catalytic activity and...</description>
      <author>Yewon Hong, Juhyung Choi, Juhyung Choi, Juhyung Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01186d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399455932

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399455934

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399455937

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399456113

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399456174

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Oxidation Kinetics Through Electronic Structure Regulation of MnCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4.5&lt;/sub&gt;@Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; p&#8211;n Junction for Urea&#8208;Assisted Electrocatalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311548</link>
      <description>Sangeeta Adhikari, Stephan N. Steinmann, Maheswari Arunachalam, Soon Hyung Kang, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399462204

                Abstract A promising strategy to boost electrocatalytic performance is via assembly of hetero&#8208;nanostructured electrocatalysts that delivers the essential specific surface area and also active sites by lowering the reaction barrier. However, the challenges associated with the intricate designs and mechanisms remain underexplored. Therefore, the present study constructs a p&#8211;n junction in a free&#8208;standing MnCo 2 O 4.5 @Ni 3 S 2 on Ni&#8208;Foam. The space&#8208;charge region's electrical characteristics is dramatically altered by the formed p&#8211;n junction, which enhances the electron transfer process for urea&#8208;assisted electrocatalytic water splitting (UOR). The optimal MnCo 2 O 4.5 @Ni 3 S 2 electrocatalyst results in greater oxygen evolution reactivity (OER) than pure systems, delivering an overpotential of only 240 mV. Remarkably, upon employing as UOR electrode the required potential decreases to 30 mV. The impressive performance of the designed catalyst is attributed to the enhanced electrical conductivity, greater number of electrochemical active sites, and improved redox activity due to the junction interface formed between p&#8208;MnCo 2 O 4.5 and n&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 . There are strong indications that the in situ formed extreme&#8208;surface NiOOH, starting from Ni 3 S 2, boosts the electrocatalytic activity, i.e., the electrochemical surface reconstruction generates the active species. In conclusion, this work presents a high&#8208;performance p&#8211;n junction design for broad use, together with a viable and affordable UOR electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Sangeeta Adhikari, Stephan N. Steinmann, Maheswari Arunachalam, Soon Hyung Kang, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen&#8208;tolerant CO2 Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400659</link>
      <description>Hongfei Zhu, Hui Guo, Rong Cao, Yuan&#8208;Biao Huang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399465290

                The electrochemical carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR) to generate high&#8208;value products is considered to be a promising approach to reduce the atmospheric concentration of CO2. However, the pure CO2 gas is generally required in the most of the reported CO2RR system, which brings tedious capture and separation procedures and high cost. The utilization of realistic CO2 emission directly such as flue gas for the CO2RR is highly desirable. However, the gas impurities in the real CO2 sources such as oxygen could seriously affect the activity and selectivity of the CO2RR. This concept summarizes the recently reported works about CO2RR studies in the presence of O2 and highlights the physical and chemical strategies to boost CO2 electroreduction performance. We further discuss the implications of these strategies for future progress in this emerging field.</description>
      <author>Hongfei Zhu, Hui Guo, Rong Cao, Yuan&#8208;Biao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru nanocrystals modified porous FeOOH nanostructures with open 3D interconnected architecture supported on NiFe foam as high&#8208;performance electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction and electrocatalytic urea oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.056</link>
      <description>Peng Zhao, Qiancheng Liu, Xulin Yang, Sudong Yang, Chen Lin, Jing Zhu, Qian Zhang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399470562

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Zhao, Qiancheng Liu, Xulin Yang, Sudong Yang, Chen Lin, Jing Zhu, Qian Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.056</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waste tobacco-derived N, P dual-doped porous carbon loaded with heterostructured CoFe/CoFe2O4 nanoparticles for efficient oxygen electrocatalysis and Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.112945</link>
      <description>Yang Feng, Qing Kong, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Ruoxin Wu, Xian&#8208;Wei Lv, Feng Xu, Zhong&#8722;Yong Yuan, Materials research bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399490548

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Feng, Qing Kong, Jin&#8208;Tao Ren, Ruoxin Wu, Xian&#8208;Wei Lv, Feng Xu, Zhong&#8722;Yong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.112945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZIF&#8208;Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@ZIF&#8208;Derived Urchin&#8208;Like Hierarchically Porous Carbon as Efficient Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/open.202400057</link>
      <description>Lingling Zhang, Xiaokang Wang, Chong Gong, Wanying Sun, Zihan Lu, ChemistryOpen. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399490831

                Abstract Co 3 O 4 nanoparticles were sandwiched into interlayers between ZIF&#8208;8 and ZIF&#8208;67 to form ZIF&#8208;Co 3 O 4 @ZIF precursors. Pyrolysis of ZIF&#8208;Co 3 O 4 @ZIF yielded an urchin&#8208;like hierarchically porous carbon (Co@CNT/NC), the thorns of which were carbon nanotubes embedded Co nanoparticles. With large specific surface area and hierarchically porous structure, as&#8208;prepared Co@CNT/NC exhibited excellent bifunctional oxygen electrocatalytic performances. It has good ORR performance with E 1/2 of 0.85 V, which exceeds the Pt/C half&#8208;wave potential (E 1/2 =0.83 V). In addition, Co@CNT/NC has an OER performance close to that of RuO 2 . To further demonstrate the effect of Co modifying on the properties, the samples were subjected to acid washing treatment. Co&#8208;based nanoparticles were proved to After acid washing, there was obvious loss of Co particles in Co@CNT/NC, resulting in poor oxygen electrocatalysis. So, the pyrolysis products of ZIF&#8208;8&#8208;Co 3 O 4 @ZIF&#8208;67 retained large specific surface area and porous structure can be retained, and on the other hand, the carbon tube structure and original polyhedron framework. Besides, existence of Co nanoparticle@carbon nanotube provided more active sites and improved the ORR and OER performances.</description>
      <author>Lingling Zhang, Xiaokang Wang, Chong Gong, Wanying Sun, Zihan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/open.202400057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mechanism of Enhanced Electrocatalytic Water Splitting on S-Doped NiFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/Ni-Fe Alloy@Copper Foams</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad5683</link>
      <description>Wenbin Wang, Wenbin Wang, Wenbin Wang, Wenbin Wang, Wenbin Wang, Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399518641

                Abstract The development of bifunctional catalysts with subtle structures, high efficiencies and good durabilities for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is crucial for overall water splitting. In this work, a multicomponent S-doped NiFe2O4/Ni-Fe micronano flower electrocatalyst was synthesized rapidly on foam copper using a simple one-step constant current electrodeposition method. The introduction of S leads to the transformation of the microsphere structure of the Ni-Fe alloy into a cauliflower-like morphology and induces changes in the surface electronic structure, significantly enhancing the catalytic performance for the HER and OER. The S-NiFe2O4/Ni-Fe alloy/CF showed low overpotentials of 220 mV and 66 mV at 10 mA cm-2 in 1.0 M KOH for the OER and HER, respectively. High durability OER and HER performances were demonstrated through 60 h of chronopotentiometry and 6000 CV cycles test. Excellent overall water splitting electrocatalytic activity was observed in the S-NiFe2O4/Ni-Fe alloy/CF&#8214;S-NiFe2O4/Ni-Fe alloy/CF two-electrode system. In particular, active-phase NiOOH, a highly active substance for OER, can be controllably formed in the reaction process owing to the nanoflower structure of multi-layer sulfur which slows down the dissolution of NiFe2O4/Ni-Fe alloy. These results suggest that this composite structure is a promising bifunctional electrocatalyst.&amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Wenbin Wang, Wenbin Wang, Wenbin Wang, Wenbin Wang, Wenbin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad5683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lanthanide-regulating Ru-O covalency optimizes acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49281-2</link>
      <description>L&#252; Li, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Gengwei Zhang, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Gengwei Zhang, Yingjun Tan, Yingjun Tan, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Yingjun Tan, Gengwei Zhang, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399539823

                Abstract Precisely modulating the Ru-O covalency in RuO x for enhanced stability in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis is highly desired. However, transition metals with d -valence electrons, which were doped into or alloyed with RuO x , are inherently susceptible to the influence of coordination environment, making it challenging to modulate the Ru-O covalency in a precise and continuous manner. Here, we first deduce that the introduction of lanthanide with gradually changing electronic configurations can continuously modulate the Ru-O covalency owing to the shielding effect of 5 s /5 p orbitals. Theoretical calculations confirm that the durability of Ln-RuO x following a volcanic trend as a function of Ru-O covalency. Among various Ln-RuO x , Er-RuO x is identified as the optimal catalyst and possesses a stability 35.5 times higher than that of RuO 2 . Particularly, the Er-RuO x -based device requires only 1.837 V to reach 3 A cm &#8722;2 and shows a long-term stability at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for 100 h with a degradation rate of mere 37 &#956;V h &#8722;1 .</description>
      <author>L&#252; Li, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Gengwei Zhang, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Gengwei Zhang, Yingjun Tan, Yingjun Tan, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu, Yingjun Tan, Gengwei Zhang, Youxing Liu, Youxing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49281-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Prediction and Experimental Verification of IrO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Supported on Titanium Nitride for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02936</link>
      <description>Xue Han, Tianyou Mou, A. T. M. N. Islam, Sinwoo Kang, Qiaowan Chang, Zhenghui Xie, Xinbing Zhao, Kotaro Sasaki, Jos&#233; A. Rodr&#237;guez, Ping Liu, Jingguang G. Chen, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399546622

                Reducing iridium (Ir) catalyst loading for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical strategy for large-scale hydrogen production via proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis. However, simultaneously achieving high activity, long-term stability, and reduced material cost remains challenging. To address this challenge, we develop a framework by combining density functional theory (DFT) prediction using model surfaces and proof-of-concept experimental verification using thin films and nanoparticles. DFT results predict that oxidized Ir monolayers over titanium nitride (IrO</description>
      <author>Xue Han, Tianyou Mou, A. T. M. N. Islam, Sinwoo Kang, Qiaowan Chang, Zhenghui Xie, Xinbing Zhao, Kotaro Sasaki, Jos&#233; A. Rodr&#237;guez, Ping Liu, Jingguang G. Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Invoking Interfacial Engineering Boosts Structural Stability Empowering Exceptional Cyclability of Ni&#8208;Rich Cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405628</link>
      <description>Youqi Chu, Yongbiao Mu, Huan Gu, Yan Hu, Xianbin Wei, Lingfeng Zou, Can Yu, Xianglong Xu, Shaowei Kang, Kang Li, Meisheng Han, Qing Zhang, Lin Zeng, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399552458

                Abstract The cycling stability of LiNi 0.8 Co 0.1 Mn 0.1 O 2 under high voltages is hindered by the occurrence of hybrid anion&#8208; and cation&#8208;redox processes, leading to oxygen escape and uncontrolled phase collapse. In this study, we propose an interfacial engineering strategy involving a straightforward mechanical ball milling and low&#8208;temperature calcination, employing a Se&#8208;doped and FeSe 2 &amp;Fe 2 O 3 &#8208;modified approach to design a stable Ni&#8208;rich cathode. Se 2&#8722; are selectively adsorbed within oxygen vacancies to form O&#8208;TM&#8208;Se bond, effectively stabilizing lattice oxygen, and preventing structural distortion. Simultaneously, the Se&#8208;NCM811//FeSe 2 //Fe 2 O 3 self&#8208;assembled electric field is activated, improving interfacial charge transfer and coupling. Furthermore, FeSe 2 accelerates Li + diffusion and reacts with oxygen to form Fe 2 O 3 and SeO 2 . The Fe 2 O 3 coating mitigates HF erosion and acts as an electrostatic shield layer, limiting the outward migration of oxygen anions. Impressively, the modified materials exhibit significantly improved electrochemical performance, with a capacity retention of 79.7% after 500 cycles at 1C under 4.5 V. Furthermore, it provides an extraordinary capacity retention of 94.6% in 3 &#8211; 4.25 V after 550 cycles in pouch&#8208;type full battery. This dual&#8208;modification approach demonstrates its feasibility and opens new perspectives for the development of stable lithium&#8208;ion batteries operating at high voltages. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Youqi Chu, Yongbiao Mu, Huan Gu, Yan Hu, Xianbin Wei, Lingfeng Zou, Can Yu, Xianglong Xu, Shaowei Kang, Kang Li, Meisheng Han, Qing Zhang, Lin Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable energy transitions?  1 technology focus: Porous organic polymers for a POM-based oxygen evolution catalyst + 1 framework proposal: Situated green chemistries</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4399553182</link>
      <description>E. Quadrelli, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399553182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. Quadrelli</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4399553182</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A fibrous Ir-doped NiFeOx on two-dimensional materials for high efficiency oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118424</link>
      <description>Yadi Zhu, Chunxiang Liu, Hanlu Zhang, Zhimin Zhou, Yunbo Jiang, Teng Wang, Yuzhou Liu, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399555998

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yadi Zhu, Chunxiang Liu, Hanlu Zhang, Zhimin Zhou, Yunbo Jiang, Teng Wang, Yuzhou Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Strain with Stabilized Oxygen Vacancies Boosts Ceria for Robust Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Outperforming Benchmark Pt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405970</link>
      <description>Xiao Jing Liu, Shuaichong Wei, Shuyi Cao, Yongguang Zhang, Wei Xue, Yanji Wang, Guihua Li, Jingde Li, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399556115

                Abstract Earth&#8208;abundant metal oxides are usually considered as stable but catalytically inert towards hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to their unfavorable hydrogen intermediate adsorption performance. Herein, a heavy rare earth (Y) and transition metal (Co) dual&#8208;doping induced lattice strain and oxygen vacancy stabilization strategy is proposed to boost CeO 2 towards robust alkaline HER. The induced lattice compression and increased oxygen vacancy (O v ) concentration in CeO 2 synergistically improve the water dissociation on O v and sequential hydrogen adsorption at activated O v &#8208;neighboring sites, leading to significantly enhanced HER kinetics. Meanwhile, Y doping offers stabilization effect on O v by its stronger Y&#8722;O bonding over Ce&#8722;O, which endows the catalyst with excellent stability. The Y,Co&#8208;CeO 2 electrocatalyst exhibits an ultra&#8208;low HER overpotential (27 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and Tafel slope (48 mV dec &#8722;1 ), outperforming the benchmark Pt electrocatalyst. Moreover, the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer incorporated with Y,Co&#8208;CeO 2 achieves excellent stability of 500 h under 600 mA cm &#8722;2 . This synergistic lattice strain and oxygen vacancy stabilization strategy sheds new light on the rational development of efficient and stable oxide&#8208;based HER electrocatalysts. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Xiao Jing Liu, Shuaichong Wei, Shuyi Cao, Yongguang Zhang, Wei Xue, Yanji Wang, Guihua Li, Jingde Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction of Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper-based Oxides in Nonreactive Environments and Under Electrochemical Conditions for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.06.108</link>
      <description>Hainan Sun, Junxiong Zhang, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399559390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hainan Sun, Junxiong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.06.108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ transformation from metal-organic framework into iridium-iron hollow hexagonal rod to promote oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160510</link>
      <description>Y.J. Wang, Yanyan Du, Weiping Zhu, Yijie Gao, Rongjie Zhang, Qiang Jiao, Duan Bin, Hongbo Lu, Cunwang Ge, Beibei Yang, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399561140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y.J. Wang, Yanyan Du, Weiping Zhu, Yijie Gao, Rongjie Zhang, Qiang Jiao, Duan Bin, Hongbo Lu, Cunwang Ge, Beibei Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Altering electronic structure of nickel foam supported CoNi-based oxide through Al ions modulation for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.057</link>
      <description>M. Rabbani, Jing&#8208;Huo Chen, Yan&#8208;Xin Duan, Rong&#8208;Chao Cui, Xiaoze Du, Zhong-Yi Liu, Muhammad Imran Anwar, Zaiba Zafar, Xinzheng Yue, Journal of colloid and interface science. 673(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399562915

                No abstract</description>
      <author>M. Rabbani, Jing&#8208;Huo Chen, Yan&#8208;Xin Duan, Rong&#8208;Chao Cui, Xiaoze Du, Zhong-Yi Liu, Muhammad Imran Anwar, Zaiba Zafar, Xinzheng Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Break the Activity&#8208;Stability Conundrum in Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis: Mechanistic Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400567</link>
      <description>Tobias Binninger, Genevieve C. Moss, Ziba Shabir Hussein Somjee Rajan, Rhiyaad Mohamed, Michael Eikerling, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399563374

                Abstract Technically viable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) must be both active and stable under the harsh conditions at an electrolyser anode. While numerous highly active metal&#8208;oxide catalysts have been identified, only very few are sufficiently stable, with iridium oxides being the most prominent. In this perspective, we draw insights from OER mechanisms to circumvent the activity&#8208;stability conundrum generally plaguing the development of OER catalysts. In the commonly considered OER mechanisms, one or several metal&#8208;oxygen (M&#8722;O) bonds are required to be broken along the OER pathway, providing a mechanistic link between the OER and oxide decomposition. However, a recently discovered mechanism on crystalline iridium dioxide provides a new OER pathway without M&#8722;O bond breakages, thus enabling the combination of sufficient activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Tobias Binninger, Genevieve C. Moss, Ziba Shabir Hussein Somjee Rajan, Rhiyaad Mohamed, Michael Eikerling</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and oxygen evolution reaction performance of Ni-supported catalysts based on steam-exploded poplar</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15376/biores.19.3.4886-4898</link>
      <description>Jing Yuan, Xiaofei Li, Feifan Wu, Peng Cheng, Haitao Yang, Bioresources. 19(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399565772

                Using renewable steam-exploded poplar (SEP) as carbon source, nickel metal doped carbon hybrid materials were designed to synthesize catalysts (Ni/SEP) with certain oxygen evolution reaction (OER) properties and were compared with nickel catalysts supported on metal organic framework structure (ZIF67-Ni). The roles of SEP support in Ni-based catalyst were considered. Scanning electron microscope (SEM) images confirmed that the fiber could better hinder the aggregation of metal particles. Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR) indicated the presence of surface OH groups after the reduction process. X-ray diffraction (XRD) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analyses confirmed the major form of metallic Ni in the resulting Ni catalysts. Carbon materials as carriers, the synergetic effect of Ni-doped, and carbon carrier played an important role in facilitating the kinetics of OER, which was similar to the carrier of metal-organic frame material. Notably, the Ni/SEP (11.3 mF/cm-2) and ZIF67-Ni (37.2 mF/cm-2) with better OER performance exhibited a smaller double layer capacitances (Cdl), suggesting the intrinsic OER catalytic activity of the Ni/SEP and ZIF67-Ni were much higher in comparison to the ZIF67-Ni/SEP. Moreover, the inferior performance of Ni/SEP further indicated that the synergistic effect between carbon and Ni/NiO contributes to the enhanced OER activity.</description>
      <author>Jing Yuan, Xiaofei Li, Feifan Wu, Peng Cheng, Haitao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15376/biores.19.3.4886-4898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Data&#8208;Driven Descriptors for Establishing the Structure&#8208;Activity Relationship of Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks Toward Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409449</link>
      <description>Jian Zhou, Liang Xu, Huiyu Gai, N. Xu, Zhichu Ren, Xianbiao Hou, Zongkun Chen, Zhongkang Han, Debalaya Sarker, Sergey V. Levchenko, Minghua Huang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399575217

                The development of readily accessible and interpretable descriptors is pivotal yet challenging in the rational design of metal&#8208;organic framework (MOF) catalysts. This study presents a straightforward and physically interpretable activity descriptor for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), derived from a dataset of bimetallic Ni&#8208;based MOFs. Through an artificial&#8208;intelligence (AI) data&#8208;mining subgroup discovery (SGD) approach, a combination of the d&#8208;band center and number of missing electrons in eg states of Ni, as well as the first ionization energy and number of electrons in eg states of the substituents, is revealed as a gene of a superior OER catalyst. The found descriptor, obtained from the AI analysis of a dataset of MOFs containing 3&#8208;5d transition metals and 13 organic linkers, has been demonstrated to facilitate in&#8208;depth understanding of structure&#8211;activity relationship at the molecular orbital level. The descriptor is validated experimentally for 11 Ni&#8208;based MOFs. Combining SGD with physical insights and experimental verification, our work offers a highly efficient approach for screening MOF&#8208;based OER catalysts, simultaneously providing comprehensive understanding of the catalytic mechanism.</description>
      <author>Jian Zhou, Liang Xu, Huiyu Gai, N. Xu, Zhichu Ren, Xianbiao Hou, Zongkun Chen, Zhongkang Han, Debalaya Sarker, Sergey V. Levchenko, Minghua Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface&#8208;Engineered NiFe/Ni&#8208;S Nanoparticles for Reliable Alkaline Oxygen Production at Industrial Current: A Sulfur Source Confinement Strategy (Small 24/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202470187</link>
      <description>Bin Chen, Tao Liu, Junfeng Zhang, Shichao Zhao, Runfei Yue, Sipu Wang, Lianqin Wang, Zhihao Chen, Yingjie Feng, Jun Huang, Yan Yin, Michael D. Guiver, Small. 20(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399576420

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Chen, Tao Liu, Junfeng Zhang, Shichao Zhao, Runfei Yue, Sipu Wang, Lianqin Wang, Zhihao Chen, Yingjie Feng, Jun Huang, Yan Yin, Michael D. Guiver</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202470187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facilitating active NiOOH formation via Mo doping towards high-efficiency oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00314d</link>
      <description>Liuqing Wang, Jinsheng Li, Qinglei Meng, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Xing Wei, Jianbing Zhu, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399577346

                The insufficient performance of non-noble metal catalysts in alkaline media is a prominent issue that limits the widespread adoption of electrocatalytic water splitting. In this study, we present an efficient...</description>
      <author>Liuqing Wang, Jinsheng Li, Qinglei Meng, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Xing Wei, Jianbing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00314d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greenly Synthesized CoPBA@PANI as a Proficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Its Green Sustainability Assessments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01023</link>
      <description>Krishnan Umapathy, Murugan Muthamildevi, Dhanasingh Thiruvengadam, Murugan Vijayarangan, K. Rajan, Jayaraman Jayabharathi, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399578292

                Water electrolysis is a key factor to generate mobile and sustainable energy sources for H</description>
      <author>Krishnan Umapathy, Murugan Muthamildevi, Dhanasingh Thiruvengadam, Murugan Vijayarangan, K. Rajan, Jayaraman Jayabharathi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the influence of oxygen-functionalized graphene nanosheets as an efficient multifunctional material for supercapacitor and electrocatalytic water splitting applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111293</link>
      <description>G. Karthik, P. Rosaiah, Munirah D. Albaqami, Nunna Guru Prakash, Tae Jo Ko, Diamond and related materials. 147(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399581653

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. Karthik, P. Rosaiah, Munirah D. Albaqami, Nunna Guru Prakash, Tae Jo Ko</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn-doped RuO2 as superior pH-universal electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.087</link>
      <description>Xuan Dong, Yang-Yang Wang, Jintao Wang, Yiqiang Sun, Cheng&#8208;Yan Xu, Cuncheng Li, Lifeng Hang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 73(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399581867

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuan Dong, Yang-Yang Wang, Jintao Wang, Yiqiang Sun, Cheng&#8208;Yan Xu, Cuncheng Li, Lifeng Hang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Functional Groups Regulate Cobalt&#8208;Porphyrin Molecular Electrocatalyst for Acidic H2O2 Electrosynthesis at Industrial&#8208;Level Current</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407163</link>
      <description>Y. L. Chen, Cheng Zhang, Yubin Chen, Haijun Zhao, Yuda Wang, Zhouying Yue, Qiansen Wang, Jun Li, Meng Gu, Qingqing Cheng, Hui Yang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399582041

                Electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) based on proton exchange membrane (PEM) reactor represents a promising approach to industrial&#8208;level H2O2 production, while it is hampered by the lack of high&#8208;efficiency electrocatalysts in acidic medium. Herein, we present a strategy for the specific oxygen functional group (OFG) regulation to promote the H2O2 selectivity up to 92% in acid on cobalt&#8208;porphyrin molecular assembled with reduced graphene oxide. In&#8208;situ X&#8208;ray adsorption spectroscopy, in&#8208;situ Raman spectroscopy and Kelvin probe force microscopy combined with theoretical calculation unravel that different OFGs exert distinctive regulation effects on the electronic structure of Co center through either remote (carboxyl and epoxy) or vicinal (hydroxyl) interaction manners, thus leading to the opposite influences on the promotion in 2e&#8208; ORR selectivity. As a consequence, the PEM electrolyzer integrated with the optimized catalyst can continuously and stably produce the high&#8208;concentration of ca. 7 wt% pure H2O2 aqueous solution at 400 mA cm&#8208;2 over 200 h with a cell voltage as low as ca. 2.1 V, suggesting the application potential in industrial&#8208;scale H2O2 electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Y. L. Chen, Cheng Zhang, Yubin Chen, Haijun Zhao, Yuda Wang, Zhouying Yue, Qiansen Wang, Jun Li, Meng Gu, Qingqing Cheng, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amphiphilic Polymer Electrolyte Blocking Lattice Oxygen Evolution from High&#8208;Voltage Nickel&#8208;rich Cathodes for Ultra&#8208;Thermal Stabile Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407024</link>
      <description>Jialiang Chen, Yan Lin, Bo Li, Hao Ren, Linchen Zhang, Yuanyuan Sun, Siyu Zhang, Xinchao Shang, Weidong Zhou, Mingbo Wu, Zhongtao Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399582079

                Ni&#8208;rich cathodes have been intensively adopted in Li&#8208;ion batteries to pursuit high energy density, which still suffering irreversible degradation at high voltage. Some unstable lattice O2&#8208; species in Ni&#8208;rich cathodes would be oxidized to singlet oxygen 1O2 and released at high volt, which lead to irreversible phase transfer from the layered rhombohedral (R) phase to a spinel&#8208;like (S) phase. To overcome the issue, the amphiphilic copolymers (UMA&#8208;Fx) electrolyte were prepared by linking hydrophobic C&#8208;F side chains with hydrophilic subunits, which could self&#8208;assemble on Ni&#8208;rich cathode surface and convert to stable cathode&#8211;electrolyte interphase layer. Thereafter, the oxygen releasing of polymer coated cathode was obviously depressed and substituted by the Co oxidation (Co3+&#8594;Co4+) at high volt (&gt;4.2V), which could suppressed irreversible phase transfer and improve cycling stability. Moreover, the amphiphilic polymer electrolyte was also stable with Li anode and had high ion conductivity. Therefore, the NCM811//UMA&#8208;F6//Li pouch cell exhibited outstanding energy density (362.97 Wh/kg) and durability (cycled 200 times at 4.7V), which could be stalely cycled even at 120&#8451; without short circuits or explosions.</description>
      <author>Jialiang Chen, Yan Lin, Bo Li, Hao Ren, Linchen Zhang, Yuanyuan Sun, Siyu Zhang, Xinchao Shang, Weidong Zhou, Mingbo Wu, Zhongtao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-vacancy-rich Ru nanoclusters doped NiCo metal-organic framework for driving overall water electrolysis and supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234851</link>
      <description>Qi Ling, Kui Yan, Ziwei Zhao, Zihan Zhou, Zhaoqi Sun, Lei Yang, Miao Zhang, Journal of power sources. 613(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399582132

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Ling, Kui Yan, Ziwei Zhao, Zihan Zhou, Zhaoqi Sun, Lei Yang, Miao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Electrical-Field-Enhanced Corrosion Endows Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Fe/NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide Nanosheets with High-Rate Oxygen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02075</link>
      <description>Wei Zhao, Ke Wang, Shuo Yang, Huxiao Wang, Denghui Zhang, Zhenyuan Zhang, Haoyu Wang, Tianyi Kou, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399582699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Zhao, Ke Wang, Shuo Yang, Huxiao Wang, Denghui Zhang, Zhenyuan Zhang, Haoyu Wang, Tianyi Kou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sn-doped cobalt&#8211;iron hydroxide nanoarrays for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution in oilfield wastewater systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.105</link>
      <description>Zhaoxiang Qi, Jianzhao Cao, Zhi&#8208;Rong Zhong, Ying Qu, Wei Peng, Yahong Xie, International journal of hydrogen energy. 73(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399584000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaoxiang Qi, Jianzhao Cao, Zhi&#8208;Rong Zhong, Ying Qu, Wei Peng, Yahong Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial nanoparticles of Co2P/Co3Fe7 encapsulated in N-doped carbon nanotubes as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101626</link>
      <description>Ailing Feng, Liang Liu, Peitao Liu, Yanqing Zu, Fengbo Han, Xiaodong Li, Shijiu Ding, Yanan Chen, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399589130

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ailing Feng, Liang Liu, Peitao Liu, Yanqing Zu, Fengbo Han, Xiaodong Li, Shijiu Ding, Yanan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101626</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts: controlled synthesis and dynamic mechanism in electrochemical oxygen evolution substitution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02786-7</link>
      <description>Qi Zhao, Rong Z. Gan, Yuping Ran, Qibin Ma, Wenwen Chen, Yuexin Guo, Yan Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Rare metals/Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399594567

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Zhao, Rong Z. Gan, Yuping Ran, Qibin Ma, Wenwen Chen, Yuexin Guo, Yan Zhang, Dingsheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02786-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe layered double hydroxide nanosheets self assembled and etched by phosphotungstic acid for the enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112143</link>
      <description>Xiangbing Zhu, Minghe Du, Haijun Deng, Bo Liu, Jieyu Chen, Shengping Wang, Huixi Li, Chunjie Yan, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399595631

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangbing Zhu, Minghe Du, Haijun Deng, Bo Liu, Jieyu Chen, Shengping Wang, Huixi Li, Chunjie Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112143</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxide-Encapsulated Ruthenium Oxide Catalysts for Selective Oxygen Evolution in Unbuffered pH-Neutral Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00839</link>
      <description>Daniela Bushiri, Amanda F. Baxter, Onaolapo Odunjo, Daniela V. Fraga Alvarez, Yong Yuan, Jingguang G. Chen, Daniel V. Esposito, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399600390

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniela Bushiri, Amanda F. Baxter, Onaolapo Odunjo, Daniela V. Fraga Alvarez, Yong Yuan, Jingguang G. Chen, Daniel V. Esposito</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Adjustable Heterointerface for Enhancing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Performances of RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@CoMnO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00778</link>
      <description>Jinyang Zhang, Hongye Qin, Xuejie Cao, Jia Wang, Rongpeng Ma, Xiaojie Chen, Wei Xia, Guangliang Lin, Lifang Jiao, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399601289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinyang Zhang, Hongye Qin, Xuejie Cao, Jia Wang, Rongpeng Ma, Xiaojie Chen, Wei Xia, Guangliang Lin, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure engineering of cobaltous sulfide for high-efficient pH-universal hydrogen evolution/alkaline oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.124</link>
      <description>Danhua Jiao, Wenhui L&#252;, Xiaodong Cai, Qunliang Song, Weiwei Xu, Rongrong Wang, Qianqian Wang, Liangliang Xu, Qizhao Wang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 74(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399613334

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Danhua Jiao, Wenhui L&#252;, Xiaodong Cai, Qunliang Song, Weiwei Xu, Rongrong Wang, Qianqian Wang, Liangliang Xu, Qizhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.06.124</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergetic engineering of ZnS/In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Te&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; heterostructure for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14823</link>
      <description>Asma A. Alothman, Ome Parkash Kumar, Muhammad Nadeem Madni, Imran Ahmad, S. Noor Mohammad, Shahroz Saleem, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, International journal of applied ceramic technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399616127

                Abstract The potential of electrochemical water splitting to tackle energy and environmental issues has garnered substantial interest. In the present work, an effective ZnS/In 2 Te 3 has been constructed by hydrothermal support on a stainless&#8208;steel strip and explored for oxygen evolution. The addition of ZnS modifies the band structure of In 2 Te 3 and enhances its specific conductivity and capacitance on an intrinsic level, making rapid ion transportation. The optimized ZnS/In 2 Te 3 displayed efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance with an overpotential of 228 mV and a Tafel slope of 111 mV dec &#8722;1 with cyclic activity up to 1000 cycles in 1 M KOH solution. ZnS/In 2 Te 3 has a large surface area (28 m 3 g &#8722;1 ) and a charge capacitance of (.037 mF), according to studies using Brunauer&#8211;Emmett&#8211;Teller and double&#8208;layer capacitance. Combining several strategies improves overall electrochemical performance of ZnS/In 2 Te 3 , making it a promising option for use in state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art OER.</description>
      <author>Asma A. Alothman, Ome Parkash Kumar, Muhammad Nadeem Madni, Imran Ahmad, S. Noor Mohammad, Shahroz Saleem, Abdul Ghafoor Abid</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction by controlled assembly of Co3O4 nanorods on TiB2 nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104619</link>
      <description>Mruthyunjayachari Chattanahalli Devendrachari, Ramasubba Reddy Palem, Ganesh Shimoga, Yong Hae Heo, Seok&#8208;Han Lee, Harish Makri Nimbegondi Kotresh, Sang&#8208;Youn Kim, Dong&#8208;Soo Choi, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399617308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mruthyunjayachari Chattanahalli Devendrachari, Ramasubba Reddy Palem, Ganesh Shimoga, Yong Hae Heo, Seok&#8208;Han Lee, Harish Makri Nimbegondi Kotresh, Sang&#8208;Youn Kim, Dong&#8208;Soo Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing A Z-Scheme Heterojunction Of Oxygen-Deficient Wo3-X And G-C3n4 For Superior Photocatalytic Evolution of H2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4863873</link>
      <description>Fengyun Su, Mengzhen Tian, Hailong Cao, Zhishuai Wang, Qiang Zhao, Hui Xie, Yezhen Zhang, Xiaoli Jin, Xin Li, Zhengdao Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399624471

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengyun Su, Mengzhen Tian, Hailong Cao, Zhishuai Wang, Qiang Zhao, Hui Xie, Yezhen Zhang, Xiaoli Jin, Xin Li, Zhengdao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4863873</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave&#8208;Assisted ultrafast Synthesis of Bimetallic Nickel&#8208;Cobalt Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Application in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401644</link>
      <description>Christoph Janiak, Thi Hai Yen Beglau, Yanyan Fei, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399630320

                A series of monometallic Ni&#8208;, Co&#8208; and Zn&#8208;MOFs and bimetallic NiCo&#8208;, NiZn&#8208; and CoZn&#8208;MOFs M2(BDC)2DABCO and (M,M&#8217;)2(BDC)2DABCO, respectively, with the same pillar and layer linkers 4&#8208;diazabicyclo[2.2.2]octane (DABCO) and benzene&#8208;1,4&#8208;dicarboxylate (BDC) were prepared through a fast microwave&#8208;assisted thermal conversion synthesis method within only 12 min. In the bimetallic MOFs the ratio M:M&#8217; was 4:1. The mono&#8208; and bimetallic MOFs were selected to systematically explore the catalytic&#8208;activity of their derived metal oxide/hydroxides for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The NiCoMOF exhibits superior catalytic activity for the OER with the lowest overpotentials of 301 mV and Tafel slopes of 42 mV dec&#8722;1 on a glassy carbon electrode in 1 mol L&#8211;1 KOH electrolyte at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. In addition, NiCoMOF was in situ grown in just 25 min by the MW synthesis on the surface of nickel foam (NF) where overpotentials of 313 and 328 mV at current densities of 50 and 300 mA cm&#8211;2, respectively, were delivered and superior long&#8208;term stability for practical OER application. The low Tafel slope of 27 mV dec&#8722;1, as well as a low reaction resistance from electrochemical impedance spectroscopy measurement (Rfar = 2 &#937;), confirm the excellent OER performance of this NiCoMOF/NF composite.</description>
      <author>Christoph Janiak, Thi Hai Yen Beglau, Yanyan Fei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Challenges in the determination of reactive oxygen species evolving during membrane water electrolysis for in situ ozone production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105623</link>
      <description>Roman Grimmig, Philipp Gillemot, Axel Kretschmer, Klaus G&#252;nther, Helmut Baltruschat, Steffen Witzleben, Journal of water process engineering. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399636276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Roman Grimmig, Philipp Gillemot, Axel Kretschmer, Klaus G&#252;nther, Helmut Baltruschat, Steffen Witzleben</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jwpe.2024.105623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Entropy Spinel Oxide (AlCrCoNiFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;)O as Highly Active Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03807</link>
      <description>Pouria Dadvari, Wei-Hsuan Hung, Kuan-Wen Wang, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399647005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pouria Dadvari, Wei-Hsuan Hung, Kuan-Wen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c03807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Entropy Materials for Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003391388-11</link>
      <description>Bhagyashri B. Kamble, Arun Karmakar, Subrata Kundu, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399537582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bhagyashri B. Kamble, Arun Karmakar, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003391388-11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis of Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Iron Oxide Nanomaterials Synthesized with Camellia sinensis Extract</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21577/0103-5053.20240101</link>
      <description>Sebasti&#227;o do Amaral Machado, Ana Lu&#237;sa Silva, Ana Paula Almeida de Souza, D. R. S&#225;nchez, M. Alzamora, Jefferson S. de Gois, Nak&#233;dia M. F. Carvalho, Journal of the Brazilian Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399574443

                The generation of clean, zero-carbon, and renewable energy is a challenge for the development of a sustainable and egalitarian society. Hydrogen gas can be produced by water electrolysis and has been claimed as the most promising option to replace fossil fuels. The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the most energetically demanding step of the water splitting and requires the use of electrocatalysts to overcome the kinetic barrier. Iron oxide nanomaterials have been emerging as a low-cost and Earth-abundant OER electrocatalysts. The synthesis of iron oxide assisted by plant extract is an eco-friendly approach to obtain nanomaterials with unique properties. Herein, we investigated iron oxide synthesized with the assistance of Camellia sinensis extract, under different experimental conditions towards oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysis. Pure phases of iron oxide were obtained, ferrihydrite and maghemite showed overpotentials of 460 and 480 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 , respectively. After calcination, hematite was formed and the overpotential was raised to 610 and 810 mV, respectively. The lower overpotential of the amorphous materials could be related to the lower electron transfer resistance and faster reaction rate. On the other hand, the calcinated materials presented higher specific activity, stability and higher Faradaic efficiency.</description>
      <author>Sebasti&#227;o do Amaral Machado, Ana Lu&#237;sa Silva, Ana Paula Almeida de Souza, D. R. S&#225;nchez, M. Alzamora, Jefferson S. de Gois, Nak&#233;dia M. F. Carvalho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21577/0103-5053.20240101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of Oxygen Evolution in a Thermally Stratified Reservoir Under Climate Warming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4862732</link>
      <description>Baosong Ma, Feifei Dong, Wenqi Peng, Xiaobo Liu, Aiping Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399580839

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baosong Ma, Feifei Dong, Wenqi Peng, Xiaobo Liu, Aiping Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4862732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review of Advancements in Theoretical Simulation of Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Single-Atom Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100876</link>
      <description>Ninggui Ma, Yu Xiong, Yuhang Wang, Yaqin Zhang, Qianqian Wang, Shuang Luo, Jingbo Zhao, Changxiong Huang, Fan Jiang, Materials today sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399458462

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ninggui Ma, Yu Xiong, Yuhang Wang, Yaqin Zhang, Qianqian Wang, Shuang Luo, Jingbo Zhao, Changxiong Huang, Fan Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100876</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect-rich CoFeCu Alloy Nanoflowers for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134532</link>
      <description>Jiawen Wang, Zhipeng Gu, Yong Huang, Fuxi Bao, Yan Liang, Colloids and surfaces. A, Physicochemical and engineering aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399620328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawen Wang, Zhipeng Gu, Yong Huang, Fuxi Bao, Yan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Enriched Amorphous Transition Metal Ternary Oxides toward Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00716</link>
      <description>Qianyun Bai, Da Li, Xiaoxiao Yan, Peifang Guo, Xingyu Ding, Kang Xiang, Xin Tu, Y. P. Guo, Renbing Wu, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399577908

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianyun Bai, Da Li, Xiaoxiao Yan, Peifang Guo, Xingyu Ding, Kang Xiang, Xin Tu, Y. P. Guo, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interpretable Data&#8208;Driven Descriptors for Establishing the Structure&#8208;Activity Relationship of Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks Toward Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409449</link>
      <description>Jian Zhou, Liang Xu, Huiyu Gai, Ning Xu, Zhichu Ren, Xianbiao Hou, Zongkun Chen, Zhongkang Han, Debalaya Sarker, Sergey V. Levchenko, Minghua Huang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399575024

                The development of readily accessible and interpretable descriptors is pivotal yet challenging in the rational design of metal&#8208;organic framework (MOF) catalysts. This study presents a straightforward and physically interpretable activity descriptor for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), derived from a dataset of bimetallic Ni&#8208;based MOFs. Through an artificial&#8208;intelligence (AI) data&#8208;mining subgroup discovery (SGD) approach, a combination of the d&#8208;band center and number of missing electrons in eg states of Ni, as well as the first ionization energy and number of electrons in eg states of the substituents, is revealed as a gene of a superior OER catalyst. The found descriptor, obtained from the AI analysis of a dataset of MOFs containing 3&#8208;5d transition metals and 13 organic linkers, has been demonstrated to facilitate in&#8208;depth understanding of structure&#8211;activity relationship at the molecular orbital level. The descriptor is validated experimentally for 11 Ni&#8208;based MOFs. Combining SGD with physical insights and experimental verification, our work offers a highly efficient approach for screening MOF&#8208;based OER catalysts, simultaneously providing comprehensive understanding of the catalytic mechanism.</description>
      <author>Jian Zhou, Liang Xu, Huiyu Gai, Ning Xu, Zhichu Ren, Xianbiao Hou, Zongkun Chen, Zhongkang Han, Debalaya Sarker, Sergey V. Levchenko, Minghua Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-etching of carbon nanofiber surface and subsequent Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C thin film coating for enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2024.140412</link>
      <description>Jun Maruyama, Shohei Maruyama, Setsuko Shibuya, Yoshiyuki Nonoguchi, Zyun Siroma, Thin solid films. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399552391

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Maruyama, Shohei Maruyama, Setsuko Shibuya, Yoshiyuki Nonoguchi, Zyun Siroma</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2024.140412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amphiphilic Polymer Electrolyte Blocking Lattice Oxygen Evolution from High&#8208;Voltage Nickel&#8208;rich Cathodes for Ultra&#8208;Thermal Stabile Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407024</link>
      <description>Jialiang Chen, Yan Lin, Qiang Li, Hao Ren, Linchen Zhang, Yi Sun, Siyu Zhang, Xinchao Shang, Weidong Zhou, Mingbo Wu, Zhongtao Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399581620

                Ni&#8208;rich cathodes have been intensively adopted in Li&#8208;ion batteries to pursuit high energy density, which still suffering irreversible degradation at high voltage. Some unstable lattice O2&#8208; species in Ni&#8208;rich cathodes would be oxidized to singlet oxygen 1O2 and released at high volt, which lead to irreversible phase transfer from the layered rhombohedral (R) phase to a spinel&#8208;like (S) phase. To overcome the issue, the amphiphilic copolymers (UMA&#8208;Fx) electrolyte were prepared by linking hydrophobic C&#8208;F side chains with hydrophilic subunits, which could self&#8208;assemble on Ni&#8208;rich cathode surface and convert to stable cathode&#8211;electrolyte interphase layer. Thereafter, the oxygen releasing of polymer coated cathode was obviously depressed and substituted by the Co oxidation (Co3+&#8594;Co4+) at high volt (&gt;4.2V), which could suppressed irreversible phase transfer and improve cycling stability. Moreover, the amphiphilic polymer electrolyte was also stable with Li anode and had high ion conductivity. Therefore, the NCM811//UMA&#8208;F6//Li pouch cell exhibited outstanding energy density (362.97 Wh/kg) and durability (cycled 200 times at 4.7V), which could be stalely cycled even at 120&#8451; without short circuits or explosions.</description>
      <author>Jialiang Chen, Yan Lin, Qiang Li, Hao Ren, Linchen Zhang, Yi Sun, Siyu Zhang, Xinchao Shang, Weidong Zhou, Mingbo Wu, Zhongtao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Evolution and Electronic Properties of Anionic Plutonium-Doped Oxygen Clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4855417</link>
      <description>Zaifu Jiang, Pingping Fu, Shuguang Jin, Panlong Kong, Jie Zhang, Hanqing Lu, Cheng Lu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399520536

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zaifu Jiang, Pingping Fu, Shuguang Jin, Panlong Kong, Jie Zhang, Hanqing Lu, Cheng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4855417</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice oxygen evolution in rutile Ru&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e367" altimg="si69.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&#8722;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;Ni&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" display="inline" id="d1e379" altimg="si70.svg"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow/&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt;O&lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/&#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144567</link>
      <description>Adrian Frandsen, Kate&#345;ina Macounov&#225;, Jan Rossmeisl, Petr Krtil, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399544974

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adrian Frandsen, Kate&#345;ina Macounov&#225;, Jan Rossmeisl, Petr Krtil</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel thiophene-linked metalloporphyrin conjugated polymer: highly efficient trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and oxygen reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02463j</link>
      <description>Sheng L&#252;, Jackie Y. Ying, Tiancun Liu, Qianqian Wang, Min Guo, Qi Shen, Qing Li, Wu Yong, Yafei Zhao, Yu Zhang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399596293

                Searching for highly efficient, stable and cost-effective trifunctional catalysts capable of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is vital to the advancement of...</description>
      <author>Sheng L&#252;, Jackie Y. Ying, Tiancun Liu, Qianqian Wang, Min Guo, Qi Shen, Qing Li, Wu Yong, Yafei Zhao, Yu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02463j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-cobalt oxide nanoparticles as superior electrocatalysts for enhanced coupling hydrogen evolution and selective ethanol oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03259d</link>
      <description>Yihe Zhang, Rong Liu, Yi Ma, Ning Jian, Hui-Yan Pan, Yongliang Liu, Jie Deng, Luming Li, Qing Shao, Canhuang Li, Junshan Li, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399506220

                The selective oxidation of organic small molecule not only promotes cathodic hydrogen production, but also acts as an alternative reaction to the anodic oxygen evolution reaction of electrolytic water, producing...</description>
      <author>Yihe Zhang, Rong Liu, Yi Ma, Ning Jian, Hui-Yan Pan, Yongliang Liu, Jie Deng, Luming Li, Qing Shao, Canhuang Li, Junshan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03259d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination of Ti3+ and Ni3+ to promote the electrocatalytic OER properties of SrTiO3@TiO2 heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00258j</link>
      <description>Yongqiang Bi, Zifeng Zhao, Jianhua Qian, Liang Chen, Chengjiao Duan, Sustainable energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399516839

                Limited current and overpotential are critical factors for efficient hydrogen production through photoelectrochemical water oxidation. To enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), transition metals (Ni, Co, Cu) are doped into...</description>
      <author>Yongqiang Bi, Zifeng Zhao, Jianhua Qian, Liang Chen, Chengjiao Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00258j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique Multi&#8208;Hetero&#8208;Interface Engineering of Fe&#8208;doped Co&#8208;LDH@MoS2&#8208;Ni3S2 Nanoflower&#8208;Based Electrocatalyst for Overall Water&#8208;Splitting: An Experimental and Theoretical Investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400821</link>
      <description>Ujjwal Phadikar, Gopal Sanyal, Srijib Das, Aniruddha Kundu, Chinmoy Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Tapas Kuila, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399602222

                Herein, a self&#8208;supported, robust, and noble&#8208;metal&#8208;free 3D hierarchical interface&#8208;rich Fe&#8208;doped Co&#8208;LDH@MoS2&#8208;Ni3S2/NF heterostructure electrocatalyst has been prepared through a controllable two&#8208;step hydrothermal process. The resultant electrode shows low overpotential of &#8275;95 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), &#8275;220 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the two&#8208;electrode system requires only a cell voltage of &#8275;1.54 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 current density, respectively. Extensive ab initio calculations were carried out to find out the overpotential for HER, orbital interaction through the determination of electron density of states and quantification of charge transfer by Bader charge analysis. The computed overpotential matched closely with the experimental data. The superior HER performance of the tri&#8208;layer is enhanced due to the charge transfer (1.7444e) to Fe&#8208;doped Co&#8208;LDH from Ni3S2&#8208;MoS2 hybrid. This research strategy paves an effective pathway for affordable green H2 production and future efficient non&#8208;precious bifunctional electrocatalyst design for overall water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Ujjwal Phadikar, Gopal Sanyal, Srijib Das, Aniruddha Kundu, Chinmoy Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Tapas Kuila</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined Growth of Highly Ordered Metal Atomic Arrays for Seawater Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406043</link>
      <description>Yang Gao, Yurui Xue, Siao Chen, Yaming Zheng, Siyi Chen, Xuchen Zheng, Feng He, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399653521

                Metal atom catalysts have been among the most important research objects due to their specific physical and chemical properties. However, precise control of the anchoring of metal atoms is still challenging to achieve. Cobalt and iridium atomic arrays formed sequentially ordered stable arrays in graphdiyne (GDY) triangular cavities depending on their intrinsic chemical properties and interactions. The success of this method was attributed to multifunctional integration of GDY, enabling selective growth from one to several atoms and various atomic densities. The bimetallic atom arrays show several advantages resulting from reducibility of acetylene bonds, space limiting effect, incomplete charge transfer between GDY and metal atoms, and sp&#8208;C hybridized triple bond skeleton. This well&#8208;designed system exhibits unprecedented oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance with a mass activity of 2.6 A mgcat.&#8211;1 at a low overpotential of 300 mV, which is 216.6 times higher than the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art IrO2 catalyst, and long&#8208;term stability.</description>
      <author>Yang Gao, Yurui Xue, Siao Chen, Yaming Zheng, Siyi Chen, Xuchen Zheng, Feng He, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confined Growth of Highly Ordered Metal Atomic Arrays for Seawater Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406043</link>
      <description>Yang Gao, Yurui Xue, Siao Chen, Yaming Zheng, Si&#8208;Yi Chen, Xuchen Zheng, Feng He, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399653584

                Metal atom catalysts have been among the most important research objects due to their specific physical and chemical properties. However, precise control of the anchoring of metal atoms is still challenging to achieve. Cobalt and iridium atomic arrays formed sequentially ordered stable arrays in graphdiyne (GDY) triangular cavities depending on their intrinsic chemical properties and interactions. The success of this method was attributed to multifunctional integration of GDY, enabling selective growth from one to several atoms and various atomic densities. The bimetallic atom arrays show several advantages resulting from reducibility of acetylene bonds, space limiting effect, incomplete charge transfer between GDY and metal atoms, and sp&#8208;C hybridized triple bond skeleton. This well&#8208;designed system exhibits unprecedented oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance with a mass activity of 2.6 A mgcat.&#8211;1 at a low overpotential of 300 mV, which is 216.6 times higher than the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art IrO2 catalyst, and long&#8208;term stability.</description>
      <author>Yang Gao, Yurui Xue, Siao Chen, Yaming Zheng, Si&#8208;Yi Chen, Xuchen Zheng, Feng He, Changshui Huang, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Efficient Hydrogen Production: Nucleophilic Oxidation Reactions Coupled with Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404806</link>
      <description>Peng Wang, Jie Zheng, Xin Xue, Yuqing Zhang, Qingshan Shi, Yong Wan, Seeram Ramakrishna, Jun Zhang, Liyang Zhu, Tokihiko Yokoshima, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yun&#8208;Ze Long, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399480524

                Electrocatalytic water splitting driven by sustainable energy is a clean and promising water-chemical fuel conversion technology for the production of high purity green hydrogen. However, the sluggish kinetics of anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) pose challenges for large-scale hydrogen production, limiting its efficiency and safety. Recently, the anodic OER has been replaced by a nucleophilic oxidation reaction (NOR) with biomass as the substrate and coupled with hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), which has attracted great interest. Anode NOR offers faster kinetics, generates high-value products, and reduces energy consumption. By coupling NOR with hydrogen evolution reaction, hydrogen production efficiency can be enhanced while yielding high-value oxidation products or degrading pollutants. Therefore, NOR-coupled HER hydrogen production is another new green electrolytic hydrogen production strategy after electrolytic water hydrogen production, which is of great significance for realizing sustainable energy development and global decarbonization. This review explores the potential of nucleophilic oxidation reactions as an alternative to OER and delves into NOR mechanisms, guiding future research in NOR-coupled hydrogen production. It assesses different NOR-coupled production methods, analyzing reaction pathways and catalyst effects. Furthermore, it evaluates the role of electrolyzers in industrialized NOR-coupled hydrogen production and discusses future prospects and challenges. This comprehensive review aims to advance efficient and economical large-scale hydrogen production. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Peng Wang, Jie Zheng, Xin Xue, Yuqing Zhang, Qingshan Shi, Yong Wan, Seeram Ramakrishna, Jun Zhang, Liyang Zhu, Tokihiko Yokoshima, Yusuke Yamauchi, Yun&#8208;Ze Long</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Universal Coulombic Efficiency Compensation Strategy for Zinc&#8208;based Flow Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202406366</link>
      <description>Shiqiang Huang, Mengxiao Li, Yuxi Song, Shibo Xi, Chao Wu, Zhi Wei Javier Ang, Qing Wang, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399601496

                Abstract Alkaline zinc&#8208;iron flow batteries (AZIFBs) are well suited for energy storage because of their good safety, high cell voltage, and low cost. However, the occurrence of irreversible anodic parasitic reactions results in a diminished coulombic efficiency (CE), unbalanced charge state of catholyte/anolyte and subsequently, a poor cycling performance. Here, we report a universal CE compensation strategy centered around the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on the cathodic side. This strategy aims to equalize the charge state of the [Fe(CN) 6 ] 3&#8208;/4&#8722; &#8208;based catholyte and counteract pH fluctuations. The OER process can be implemented either directly on the electrode through electrochemical reaction or in an external catalytic reactor column via a redox&#8208;mediated process. This innovative approach effectively mitigates the gradual accumulation of [Fe(CN) 6 ] 3&#8722; in discharged catholyte and [Zn(OH) 4 ] 2&#8722; in charged anolyte by consuming the extra OH &#8722; during continuous cycling process. As a result, AZIFBs demonstrated exceptional cycling performance with an extremely low capacity fading rate of 0.0128%/day (or 0.0005%/cycle) over 600 cycles at 80% state of charge (SOC). The proposed CE compensation strategy not only provides an effective way to address the CE loss issue for AZIFBs but can also be applied to diverse battery technologies encountering CE loss caused by water/oxygen&#8208;induced parasitic reactions. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Shiqiang Huang, Mengxiao Li, Yuxi Song, Shibo Xi, Chao Wu, Zhi Wei Javier Ang, Qing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202406366</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single&#8208;crystal&#8208;to&#8208;single&#8208;crystal transformation of a two&#8208;dimensional noninterpenetrated layer to a microporous three&#8208;dimensional fourfold interpenetrated MOF triggered by DMF</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7590</link>
      <description>Pei&#8208;Pei Huang, Tung&#8208;Chuan Wu, Meng&#8208;Qi Tuo, Hui&#8208;Bin Pan, Si&#8208;Yu Yue, Pei Huang, Y.K. Gao, Jiu&#8208;Fu Lu, Ling&#8208;Xia Jin, Applied organometallic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399590029

                We have demonstrated a single&#8208;crystal&#8208;to&#8208;single&#8208;crystal (SCSC) transformation from a two&#8208;dimensional noninterpenetrated layer to a microporous three&#8208;dimensional fourfold interpenetrated MOF. The centrosymmetric [Co 2 (&#956; 2 &#8208;OH)(EIBA) 3 ] n ( SNUT&#8208;25 ) transforms into a microporous [Co(EIBA) 2 ] n ( SNUT&#8208;26 ), which is triggered by the reaction time with DMF that acts as a structure&#8208;directing agent (HEIBA = 4&#8208;(2&#8208;ethyl&#8208;1H&#8208;imidazol&#8208;1&#8208;yl)benzoic acid; DMF = N,N&#8242;&#8208;dimethylformamide). Despite the distinct structure and coordination arrangements of SNUT&#8208;25 in contrast to SNUT&#8208;26 , both Co&#8208;MOFs were synthesized using the same ligand. Fascinatingly, upon introducing a specific quantity of DMF combined with a negligible proportion of nitric acid, SNUT&#8208;25 will progressively and completely transform into SNUT&#8208;26 . Under the synergistic induction of solvent molecules and temperature, SNUT&#8208;25 changed from the original two&#8208;dimensional layered structure to the three&#8208;dimensional pore structure of SNUT&#8208;26 . In addition, SNUT&#8208;25 and SNUT&#8208;26 are efficient photocatalysts for the degradation of organic dye methyl blue (MB) under visible light irradiation. Surprisingly, the degradation rates of both SNUT&#8208;25 and SNUT&#8208;26 can reach over 96%. In addition, SNUT&#8208;25 and SNUT&#8208;26 also exhibited high electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Pei&#8208;Pei Huang, Tung&#8208;Chuan Wu, Meng&#8208;Qi Tuo, Hui&#8208;Bin Pan, Si&#8208;Yu Yue, Pei Huang, Y.K. Gao, Jiu&#8208;Fu Lu, Ling&#8208;Xia Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy&#8208;Controlled CuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;/N,Se Co&#8208;Doped Porous Carbon via Plasma&#8208;Treatment for Enhanced Electro&#8208;Reduction of Nitrate to Green Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403253</link>
      <description>Junbeom Maeng, Daehee Jang, Jungseub Ha, Junhyuk Ji, Jong Heo, Yeji Park, Subin Kim, Won Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399540364

                Abstract The electrochemical nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) is of significance in regards of environmentally friendly issues and green ammonia production. However, relatively low performance with a competitive hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is a challenge to overcome for the NO 3 RR. In this study, oxygen vacancy&#8208;controlled copper oxide (CuO x ) catalysts through a plasma treatment are successfully prepared and supported on high surface area porous carbon that are co&#8208;doped with N, Se species for its enhanced electrochemical properties. The oxygen vacancy&#8208;increased CuO x catalyst supported on the N,Se co&#8208;doped porous carbon (CuO x &#8208;H/NSePC) exhibited the highest NO 3 RR performance with faradaic efficiency (FE) of 87.2% and yield of 7.9 mg cm &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 for the ammonia production, representing significant enhancements of FE and ammonia yield as compared to the un&#8208;doped or the oxygen vacancy&#8208;decreased catalysts. This high performance should be attributed to a significant increase in the catalytic active sites with facilitated energetics from strategies of doping the catalytic materials and weakening the N&#9472;O bonding strength for the adsorption of NO 3 &#8722; ions on the modulated oxygen vacancies. This results show a promise that co&#8208;doping of heteroatoms and regulating of oxygen vacancies can be key factors for performance enhancement, suggesting new guidelines for effective catalyst design of NO 3 RR.</description>
      <author>Junbeom Maeng, Daehee Jang, Jungseub Ha, Junhyuk Ji, Jong Heo, Yeji Park, Subin Kim, Won Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MANGANESE BIOCATALYSIS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.58532/v3becs4p2ch1</link>
      <description>Gopinath Mavankal, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399586664

                Manganese, a 3d transition metal, with variable oxidation states(-3 to +7) is ubiquitous in earth&#8217;s crust, has low toxicity, and as a catalyst in cyanobacterial photosynthesis accumulated oxygen in the ocean which gradually escaped into the atmosphere displacing methane sometime between 2.4 &#8211; 2.1 billion years ago1. Cyanobacteria evolved from an anaerobic environment to produce oxygen which wiped out much of anaerobic life and gave rise to aerobic metabolism. Manganese thus plays a central role in evolution. Biophysical and biochemical studies of manganese as biocatalysts is described from a chemical and biological perspective in this chapter. The dissertation work done by the author dictates the choices in this chapter that are thus more like vignettes considering the vast amount of ongoing work in the area of Manganese bio catalysis. Manganese as a catalyst that produces hydrogen from water might turn out to be the key to a carbon neutral green economy of the future.</description>
      <author>Gopinath Mavankal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.58532/v3becs4p2ch1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Nitrogen Doped Barium Zirconate Using Density
  Functional Theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2406.05749</link>
      <description>Izhar Ahmad, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399555088

                Using density functional theory (DFT), this work explores barium zirconate doped with nitrogen. In addition, we used density functional theory (DFT) to study the BaZrO$_3$'s electrical, optical, and structural properties, and we found that the BaZrO$_3$ has intrinsic vacancy defects by employing the supercell approach. Integrating testability into hardware devices is the goal of testing design, an approach to integrated circuit design that draws on density functional theory. This technology simplifies production testing and implementation. The study strategy incorporates the following methods: LSDA+U, Exchange Correlation Approximations, Hohenberg Kohn Theorem, and Local Spin Density Approximation. We tracked the evolution of barium zirconate's protonic, nitrogen ionic, and electronic conductivities using Density Functional Theory (DFT). We found low electrical conductivity despite the fact that nitrogen doping successfully lowered energy barriers for oxygen and proton ion migration. The conductivity of barium zirconate increased in proportion to the supercell's nitrogen content. Furthermore, we investigated the local arrangements of octahedral sites in Pm3m cubic frameworks and utilized Density Functional Theory to dope BaZrO$_3$. Nitrogen doping caused a lot of changes to oxygen sites, revealing three groups of oxygen atoms with different structural properties.</description>
      <author>Izhar Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2406.05749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Implications of Thermal Hydrodynamic Atmospheric Escape on the TRAPPIST-1 Planets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/psj/ad4454</link>
      <description>Megan T. Gialluca, Rory Barnes, Victoria Meadows, Rodolfo Garc&#237;a, Jessica Birky, Eric Agol, &#152;The &#156;planetary science journal. 5(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399540498

                Abstract JWST observations of the seven-planet TRAPPIST-1 system will provide an excellent opportunity to test outcomes of stellar-driven evolution of terrestrial planetary atmospheres, including atmospheric escape, ocean loss, and abiotic oxygen production. While most previous studies use a single luminosity evolution for the host star, we incorporate observational uncertainties in stellar mass, luminosity evolution, system age, and planetary parameters to statistically explore the plausible range of planetary atmospheric escape outcomes. We present probabilistic distributions of total water loss and oxygen production as a function of initial water content, for planets with initially pure water atmospheres and no interior&#8211;atmosphere exchange. We find that the interior planets are desiccated for initial water contents below 50 Earth oceans. For TRAPPIST-1e, f, g, and h, we report maximum water-loss ranges of    8.0   &#8722; 0.9   + 1.3    ,    4.8   &#8722; 0.4   + 0.6    ,    3.4   &#8722; 0.3   + 0.3    , and    0.8   &#8722; 0.1   + 0.2    Earth oceans, respectively, with corresponding maximum oxygen retention of    1290   &#8722; 75   + 75    ,    800   &#8722; 40   + 40    ,    560   &#8722; 25   + 30    , and    90   &#8722; 10   + 10    bars. We explore statistical constraints on initial water content imposed by current water content, which could inform evolutionary history and planet formation. If TRAPPIST-1b is airless while TRAPPIST-1c possesses a tenuous oxygen atmosphere, as initial JWST observations suggest, then our models predict an initial surface water content of 8.2     &#8722; 1.0   + 1.5    Earth oceans for these worlds, leading to the outer planets retaining &gt;1.5 Earth oceans after entering the habitable zone. Even if TRAPPIST-1c is airless, surface water on the outer planets would not be precluded.</description>
      <author>Megan T. Gialluca, Rory Barnes, Victoria Meadows, Rodolfo Garc&#237;a, Jessica Birky, Eric Agol</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/psj/ad4454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the Surface Wettability of Vertically Oriented Multilayer Graphene Sheets Deposited by Plasma Technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14121023</link>
      <description>Domen Paul, Rok Zaplotnik, Gregor Primc, Alenka Vesel, Miran Mozeti&#269;, Nanomaterials. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399633344

                Carbon deposits consisting of vertically oriented multilayer graphene sheets on metallic foils represent an interesting alternative to activated carbon in electrical and electrochemical devices such as super-capacitors because of the superior electrical conductivity of graphene and huge surface&#8211;mass ratio. The graphene sheets were deposited on cobalt foils by plasma-enhanced chemical vapor deposition using propane as the carbon precursor. Plasma was sustained by an inductively coupled radiofrequency discharge in the H mode at a power of 500 W and a propane pressure of 17 Pa. The precursor effectively dissociated in plasma conditions and enabled the growth of porous films consisting of multilayer graphene sheets. The deposition rate varied with time and peaked at 100 nm/s. The evolution of surface wettability was determined by the sessile drop method. The untreated substrates were moderately hydrophobic at a water contact angle of about 110&#176;. The contact angle dropped to about 50&#176; after plasma treatment for less than a second and increased monotonously thereafter. The maximal contact angle of 130&#176; appeared at a treatment time of about 30 s. Thereafter, it slowly decreased, with a prolonged deposition time. The evolution of the wettability was explained by surface composition and morphology. A brief treatment with oxygen plasma enabled a super-hydrophilic surface finish of the films consisting of multilayer graphene sheets.</description>
      <author>Domen Paul, Rok Zaplotnik, Gregor Primc, Alenka Vesel, Miran Mozeti&#269;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14121023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Convergent genetic adaptation in human tumors developed under systemic hypoxia and in populations living at high altitudes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.06.10.594693</link>
      <description>Carlota Arenillas, Jose Ruiz-Cantador, Luc&#237;a Celada, Bruna Calsina, Eduardo Garc&#237;a&#8208;Galea, Debabrata Datta, Roberta Fasani, Ana Bel&#233;n Moreno-C&#225;rdenas, Juan J. Alba-Linares, Berta Miranda, &#193;ngel M Mart&#237;nez-Montes, Cristina &#193;lvarez Escol&#225;, Beatriz Lecumberri, Elvira Ana Gonzalez Garcia, Shahida K Flores, Emmanuel Esquivel, Yanli Ding, Rita Maria Regojo Zapata, Jos&#233; Juan Pozo&#8208;Kreilinger, Carmela Iglesias, Trisha Dwight, Christopher A. Muir, Amelia Oleaga Alday, Mar&#237;a Elvira Garrido-Lestache Rodr&#237;guez-Monte, M Jesus Del Cerro, Isaac Martinez-Bendayan, Delmar Muniz Louren&#231;o, Maria Adelaide Albergaria Pereira, Nelly Burnichon, Alexandre Buffet, Craig S. Broberg, Paxton V. Dickson, Mario F. Fraga, Jos&#233; Lu&#237;s Llorente, Joaqu&#237;n Rueda Soriano, Francisco Buend&#237;a Fuentes, S. P. A. Toledo, Roderick Clifton&#8208;Bligh, Rodrigo Dienstmann, Joaquim Capdevila i Capdevila, Anne-Paule Gimenez-Roqueplo, Judith Favier, Donate Weghorn, Paolo Nuciforo, William Young, Alexander R. Opotowsky, Anand Vaidya, Irina Bancos, Mercedes Robledo, Anna Caster&#224;s, Laura Dos&#8208;Subir&#224;, Mar&#237;a Dolores Chiara, Igor Adameyko, Patricia L. M. Dahia, Rodrigo A. Toledo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399555446

                EPAS1HIF2a is the primary gene implicated in systemic hypoxia adaptation. Conversely, aberrantly activated EPAS1HIF2a acts as a tumor driver against which anti-tumor therapeutics are proven effective. We elucidated connections between adaptation to systemic hypoxia in high-altitude populations, such as Tibetans and Sherpas, and human tumors. Similar to the accelerated adaptability observed in high-altitude populations via genetic introgression, tumors from patients with hypoxia since birth exhibited impaired DNA repair and increased mutation burden. As in high-altitude dwellers, EPAS1HIF2a genetic variants were positively selected within sympathetic tumors developed under hypoxia, with a consistently high frequency of 90%. Bulk and single-cell RNA sequencing followed by in vitro studies have shown that hypoxia and EPAS1HIF2a gain-of-function tumor mutations induce COX4i2 expression and impair mitochondrial respiration, indicating that decreased cellular oxygen consumption may confer a proliferative advantage in hypoxia. Analyzing medical data from a patient cohort with hypoxia since birth who developed/did not develop tumors revealed tissue-specific and time-dependent tumorigenic effects of systemic hypoxia, which is limited to oxygen-sensitive and responsive cells, particularly during the postnatal period. This study supports connections between the EPAS1HIF2a genetic adaptation in human tumors developed under systemic hypoxia to populations living in high altitudes. The genetic adaptations in populations to different stressors can be explored further to understand tumorigenesis and tumor evolution.</description>
      <author>Carlota Arenillas, Jose Ruiz-Cantador, Luc&#237;a Celada, Bruna Calsina, Eduardo Garc&#237;a&#8208;Galea, Debabrata Datta, Roberta Fasani, Ana Bel&#233;n Moreno-C&#225;rdenas, Juan J. Alba-Linares, Berta Miranda, &#193;ngel M Mart&#237;nez-Montes, Cristina &#193;lvarez Escol&#225;, Beatriz Lecumberri, Elvira Ana Gonzalez Garcia, Shahida K Flores, Emmanuel Esquivel, Yanli Ding, Rita Maria Regojo Zapata, Jos&#233; Juan Pozo&#8208;Kreilinger, Carmela Iglesias, Trisha Dwight, Christopher A. Muir, Amelia Oleaga Alday, Mar&#237;a Elvira Garrido-Lestache Rodr&#237;guez-Monte, M Jesus Del Cerro, Isaac Martinez-Bendayan, Delmar Muniz Louren&#231;o, Maria Adelaide Albergaria Pereira, Nelly Burnichon, Alexandre Buffet, Craig S. Broberg, Paxton V. Dickson, Mario F. Fraga, Jos&#233; Lu&#237;s Llorente, Joaqu&#237;n Rueda Soriano, Francisco Buend&#237;a Fuentes, S. P. A. Toledo, Roderick Clifton&#8208;Bligh, Rodrigo Dienstmann, Joaquim Capdevila i Capdevila, Anne-Paule Gimenez-Roqueplo, Judith Favier, Donate Weghorn, Paolo Nuciforo, William Young, Alexander R. Opotowsky, Anand Vaidya, Irina Bancos, Mercedes Robledo, Anna Caster&#224;s, Laura Dos&#8208;Subir&#224;, Mar&#237;a Dolores Chiara, Igor Adameyko, Patricia L. M. Dahia, Rodrigo A. Toledo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.06.10.594693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic understanding of speciated oxide growth in high entropy alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49243-8</link>
      <description>Bharat Gwalani, Andrew Martin, Elizabeth J. Kautz, Boyu Guo, Sten Lambeets, Matthew J. Olszta, Anil K. Battu, Aniruddha Malakar, Feipeng Yang, Jinghua Guo, Suntharampillai Thevuthasan, Ruipeng Li, Aram Amassian, Martin Thuo, Arun Devaraj, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399570275

                Abstract Complex multi-element alloys are gaining prominence for structural applications, supplementing steels, and superalloys. Understanding the impact of each element on alloy surfaces due to oxidation is vital in maintaining material integrity. This study investigates oxidation mechanisms in these alloys using a model five-element equiatomic CoCrFeNiMn alloy, in a controlled oxygen environment. The oxidation-induced surface changes correlate with each element&#8217;s interactive tendencies with the environment, guided by thermodynamics. Initial oxidation stages follow atomic size and redox potential, with the latter becoming dominant over time, causing composition inversion. The study employs in-situ atom probe tomography, transmission electron microscopy, and X-ray absorption near-edge structure techniques to elucidate the oxidation process and surface oxide structure evolution. Our findings deconvolute the mechanism for compositional and structural changes in the oxide film and will pave the way for a predictive design of complex alloys with improved resistance to oxidation under extreme conditions.</description>
      <author>Bharat Gwalani, Andrew Martin, Elizabeth J. Kautz, Boyu Guo, Sten Lambeets, Matthew J. Olszta, Anil K. Battu, Aniruddha Malakar, Feipeng Yang, Jinghua Guo, Suntharampillai Thevuthasan, Ruipeng Li, Aram Amassian, Martin Thuo, Arun Devaraj</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49243-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Population-specific responses to pollution exposure suggest local adaptation of invasive red swamp crayfish Procambarus clarkii along the Mediterranean French coastline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-33775-z</link>
      <description>Marie-Catherine Raffalli, Ana Mar&#237;a Boj&#243;rquez-S&#225;nchez, Jehan&#8208;Herv&#233; Lignot, Diana Mart&#237;nez-Alarc&#243;n, Environmental science and pollution research international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399611979

                Abstract Anthropogenic stressors can have an impact in a broad range of physiological processes and can be a major selective force leading to rapid evolution and local population adaptation. In this study, three populations of the invasive crayfish Procambarus clarkii were investigated. They are geographically separated for at least 20 years, and live in different abiotic environments: a freshwater inland lake (Salagou lake) with no major anthropogenic influence and two other coastal wetlands regularly polluted by pesticides along the Mediterranean coast (Camargue region and Bages-Sigean lagoon). Collected adults were genetically characterized using the mitochondrial COI gene and haplotype frequencies were analyzed for genetic variability within and between populations. Results revealed a higher genetic diversity for these invasive populations than any previous report in France, with more than seven different haplotypes in a single population. The contrasting genetic diversity between the Camargue and the other two populations suggest different times and sources of introduction. To identify differences in key physiological responses between these populations, individuals from each population were maintained in controlled conditions. Data on oxygen consumption rates indicate that the Salagou and Bages-Sigean populations possess a high inter-individual variability compared to the Camargue population. The low individual variability of oxygen consumption and low genetic diversity suggest a specific local adaptation for the Camargue population. Population-specific responses were identified when individuals were exposed to a pesticide cocktail containing azoxystrobin and oxadiazon at sublethal concentrations. The Salagou population was the only one with altered hydro-osmotic balance due to pollutant exposure and a change in protease activity in the hepatopancreas. These results revealed different phenotypic responses suggesting local adaptations at the population level.</description>
      <author>Marie-Catherine Raffalli, Ana Mar&#237;a Boj&#243;rquez-S&#225;nchez, Jehan&#8208;Herv&#233; Lignot, Diana Mart&#237;nez-Alarc&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-33775-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blood vessels in a dish: the evolution, challenges, and potential of vascularized tissues and organoids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2024.1336910</link>
      <description>Peter N. Nwokoye, Oscar J. Abilez, Frontiers in cardiovascular medicine. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399628691

                Vascular pathologies are prevalent in a broad spectrum of diseases, necessitating a deeper understanding of vascular biology, particularly in overcoming the oxygen and nutrient diffusion limit in tissue constructs. The evolution of vascularized tissues signifies a convergence of multiple scientific disciplines, encompassing the differentiation of human pluripotent stem cells (hPSCs) into vascular cells, the development of advanced three-dimensional (3D) bioprinting techniques, and the refinement of bioinks. These technologies are instrumental in creating intricate vascular networks essential for tissue viability, especially in thick, complex constructs. This review provides broad perspectives on the past, current state, and advancements in key areas, including the differentiation of hPSCs into specific vascular lineages, the potential and challenges of 3D bioprinting methods, and the role of innovative bioinks mimicking the native extracellular matrix. We also explore the integration of biophysical cues in vascularized tissues in vitro , highlighting their importance in stimulating vessel maturation and functionality. In this review, we aim to synthesize these diverse yet interconnected domains, offering a broad, multidisciplinary perspective on tissue vascularization. Advancements in this field will help address the global organ shortage and transform patient care.</description>
      <author>Peter N. Nwokoye, Oscar J. Abilez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fcvm.2024.1336910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geochemistry of forty&#8208;one eclogitic and pyroxenitic mantle xenoliths from the Central Slave Craton, Canada (Ekati Diamond Mine)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/gdj3.258</link>
      <description>Dorrit E. Jacob, Agnes Fung, Geoscience data journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399532353

                Abstract This article describes a novel dataset on non&#8208;diamondiferous eclogite and garnet pyroxenite xenoliths from four kimberlite pipes of the Ekati Diamond Mine (Central Slave Craton, Canada). Xenoliths brought to the surface by kimberlite eruptions are direct sources of information on the composition and evolution of the Earth's mantle. Eclogite and garnet pyroxenite xenoliths, specifically, are testimony of subduction into, and metasomatism of, the mantle beneath cratons. Furthermore, these rocks are major hosts for diamond and thus an important part of the deep carbon cycle. The sample suite consists of 41 small xenoliths (2&#8211;5 cm) recovered from drill cores. The dataset includes major and trace element concentrations for garnet, clinopyroxene and ilmenite, as well as stable oxygen isotope compositions of garnets. Strontium and neodymium isotopic compositions are reported for garnet and clinopyroxene for four samples which were large enough to allow for analysis. Overall, this dataset significantly expands and complements existing datasets on diamondiferous and non&#8208;diamondiferous xenoliths from the Slave Craton in Canada, furthering our understanding of the composition of the Slave subcratonic lithosphere. The dataset includes several samples with rare mineral assemblages, including an olivine&#8208;bearing eclogite as well as ilmenite and apatite&#8208;bearing garnet&#8208;pyroxenites, and thus provides data shedding light on rarely reported compositional nuances in xenolith suites found in kimberlites.</description>
      <author>Dorrit E. Jacob, Agnes Fung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/gdj3.258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced electrocatalysts for fuel cells: Evolution of active sites and synergistic properties of catalysts and carrier materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20230052</link>
      <description>Zhijie Kong, Jianghua Wu, Zhijuan Liu, Dafeng Yan, Zhi Peng Wu, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, Exploration. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399516623

                Abstract Proton exchange&#8208;membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) is a clean and efficient type of energy storage device. However, the sluggish reaction rate of the cathode oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) has been a significant problem in its development. This review reports the recent progress of advanced electrocatalysts focusing on the interface/surface electronic structure and exploring the synergistic relationship of precious&#8208;based and non&#8208;precious metal&#8208;based catalysts and support materials. The support materials contain non&#8208;metal (C/N/Si, etc.) and metal&#8208;based structures, which have demonstrated a crucial role in the synergistic enhancement of electrocatalytic properties, especially for high&#8208;temperature fuel cell systems. To improve the strong interaction, some exciting synergistic strategies by doping and coating heterogeneous elements or connecting polymeric ligands containing carbon and nitrogen were also shown herein. Besides the typical role of the crystal surface, phase structure, lattice strain, etc., the evolution of structure&#8208;performance relations was also highlighted in real&#8208;time tests. The advanced in situ characterization techniques were also reviewed to emphasize the accurate structure&#8208;performance relations. Finally, the challenge and prospect for developing the ORR electrocatalysts were concluded for commercial applications in low&#8208; and high&#8208;temperature fuel cell systems.</description>
      <author>Zhijie Kong, Jianghua Wu, Zhijuan Liu, Dafeng Yan, Zhi Peng Wu, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/exp.20230052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Schottky/Z&#8208;Scheme Hybrid for Augmented Photocatalytic H2 and H2O2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400496</link>
      <description>Lopamudra Acharya, Lijarani Biswal, Bhagyashree Priyadarshini Mishra, Sarmistha Das, Srabani Dash, Kulamani Parida, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399577835

                The prodigious employment of fossil fuels to conquer the global energy demand is becoming a dreadful threat to the human society. This predicament is appealing for a potent photocatalyst that can generate alternate energy sources via solar to chemical energy conversion. With this interest, we have fabricated a ternary heterostructure of Ti3C2 nanosheet modified g&#8208;C3N4/Bi2O3 (MCNRBO) Z&#8208;scheme photocatalyst through self&#8208;assembly process. The morphological analysis clearly evidenced the close interfacial interaction between g&#8208;C3N4 nanorod, Bi2O3 and Ti3C2 nanosheets. The oxygen vacancy created on Bi2O3 surface, as suggested by XPS and EPR analysis, supported the Z&#8208;scheme heterojunction formation between g&#8208;C3N4 nanorod and Bi2O3 nanosheets. The collaborative effect of Z&#8208;scheme and Schottky junction significantly reduced charge transfer resistance promoting separation efficiency of excitons as indicated from PL and EIS analysis. The potential of MCNRBO towards photocatalytic application was investigated by H2O2 and H2 evolution reaction. A superior photocatalytic H2O2 and H2 production rate for MCNRBO is observed, which are respectively around 5 and 18 folds higher as compared to pristine CNR nanorod. The present work encourages for the development of a noble, eco&#8208;benign and immensely efficient dual heterojunction based photocatalyst, which can acts as saviour of human society from energy crisis.</description>
      <author>Lopamudra Acharya, Lijarani Biswal, Bhagyashree Priyadarshini Mishra, Sarmistha Das, Srabani Dash, Kulamani Parida</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlating Substrate Reactivity at Electrified Interfaces with the Electrolyte Structure in Synthetically Relevant Organic Solvent/Water Mixtures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05538</link>
      <description>Florian Dorchies, Alessandra Serva, Astrid Sidos, Laurent J. Michot, Micha&#235;l Deschamps, Mathieu Salanne, Alexis Grimaud, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399585117

                Optimizing electrosynthetic reactions requires fine tuning of a vast chemical space, including charge transfer at electrocatalyst/electrode surfaces, engineering of mass transport limitations, and complex interactions of reactants and products with their environment. Hybrid electrolytes, in which supporting salt ions and substrates are dissolved in a binary mixture of organic solvent and water, represent a new piece of this complex puzzle as they offer a unique opportunity to harness water as the oxygen or proton source in electrosynthesis. In this work, we demonstrate that modulating water-organic solvent interactions drastically impacts the solvation properties of hybrid electrolytes. Combining various spectroscopies with synchrotron small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS) and force field-based molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, we show that the size and composition of aqueous domains forming in hybrid electrolytes can be controlled. We demonstrate that water is more reactive for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in aqueous domains than when strongly interacting with solvent molecules, which originates from a change in reaction kinetics rather than a thermodynamic effect. We exemplify novel opportunities arising from this new knowledge for optimizing electrosynthetic reactions in hybrid electrolytes. For reactions proceeding first via the activation of water, fine tuning of aqueous domains impacts the kinetics and potentially the selectivity of the reaction. Instead, for organic substrates reacting prior to water, aqueous domains have no impact on the reaction kinetics, while selectivity may be affected. We believe that such a fine comprehension of solvation properties of hybrid electrolytes can be transposed to numerous electrosynthetic reactions.</description>
      <author>Florian Dorchies, Alessandra Serva, Astrid Sidos, Laurent J. Michot, Micha&#235;l Deschamps, Mathieu Salanne, Alexis Grimaud</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05538</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A time series analysis of transparent exopolymer particle distributions and C:N stoichiometry in the subtropical North Pacific: a key process in net community production and preformed nitrate anomalies?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1416</link>
      <description>Kieran Curran, Tracy A. Villareal, Robert T. Letscher, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399581860

                Abstract. Within the oligotrophic subtropical oceans, summertime DIC drawdown despite nutrient limitation in surface waters and subsurface oxygen consumption in the absence of Redfieldian stoichiometric nitrate release are two phenomena still awaiting a full mechanistic characterization. The distribution, intensity and seasonality of these phenomena are identified with preformed nitrate as a tracer, where negative preformed nitrate (NPN) anomalies below the euphotic zone correspond to oxygen consumption without Redfieldian NO3- release, and positive performed nitrate (PPN) anomalies found within the upper 100 m occur where O2 is produced without stoichiometric NO3- drawdown. Many processes that may contribute to these anomalies including N2 fixation, non-Redfieldian DOM cycling, vertically migrating phytoplankton, heterotrophic NO3- uptake and vertical NO3- injection events have been measured or modelled, yet generally cannot fully account for the magnitudes of preformed nitrate anomalies and excess DIC drawdown observed in many oligotrophic subtropical waters. One other candidate process that may contribute to both phenomena is the formation of carbon-rich transparent exopolymer particles (TEP) and Coomassie-stainable particles (CSP) from dissolved organic precursors in surface waters and their subsequent remineralization below the subsurface chlorophyll maximum (SCM). However, few data exist to quantify exopolymer production and vertical distributions in oligotrophic oceans over an annual cycle, which is necessary to understand their potential role in the evolution of seasonal preformed nitrate anomalies and DIC drawdown. To investigate the significance of exopolymer formation and export to North Pacific subtropical gyre biogeochemistry, we undertook a multi-year time-series (Jan 2020 &#8211; Sep 2022) analysis of TEP, CSP and total dissolved polysaccharides concentrations at Station ALOHA (22&#176; 45&#8217;,158&#176; W), and along a transect from 22&#176; 45&#8217; to 31&#176; N to measure latitudinal variability in June 2021. Exopolymer C:N stoichiometry at Station ALOHA varied between 16.4 &#8211; 34.3, with values being more carbon-rich in summer; ratios were higher (32&#8211;38) toward the gyre centre at 31&#176; N. TEP concentrations were consistently elevated in surface waters through Spring&#8211;Autumn (4&#8211;8 &#181;M C after carbon conversion) at Station ALOHA with lower concentrations (~1.5&#8211;3 &#181;M C) and more uniform vertical distribution during winter, indicating that TEP accumulated in surface waters may vertically sink and be exported with winter mixing. The accumulation of TEP in surface waters through Spring&#8211;Autumn and its subsequent export may account for 6.5&#8211;20 % of net community production (NCP), helping reduce the estimated imbalance of N supply and N demand at this site to &lt;10 %. The upper ocean TEP cycle may explain 22&#8211;67 % of the observed PPN/NPN anomalies, helping to close the C, N, and O2 budgets at station ALOHA, while leaving room for significant contributions from other processes such as vertically migrating phytoplankton and heterotrophic nitrate uptake to be further validated. These results suggest that exopolymer production and cycling may be more important to open ocean carbon biogeochemistry than previously expected, with considerable seasonality and spatial variability influenced by physical processes and phytoplankton activity.</description>
      <author>Kieran Curran, Tracy A. Villareal, Robert T. Letscher</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relating Macroscopic PET Radiomics Features to Microscopic Tumor Phenotypes Using a Stochastic Mathematical Model of Cellular Metabolism and Proliferation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers16122215</link>
      <description>Hailey S. H. Ahn, Yas Oloumi Yazdi, Brennan J. Wadsworth, Kevin L. Bennewith, Arman Rahmim, Ivan S. Klyuzhin, Cancers. 16(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399603768

                Cancers can manifest large variations in tumor phenotypes due to genetic and microenvironmental factors, which has motivated the development of quantitative radiomics-based image analysis with the aim to robustly classify tumor phenotypes in vivo. Positron emission tomography (PET) imaging can be particularly helpful in elucidating the metabolic profiles of tumors. However, the relatively low resolution, high noise, and limited PET data availability make it difficult to study the relationship between the microenvironment properties and metabolic tumor phenotype as seen on the images. Most of previously proposed digital PET phantoms of tumors are static, have an over-simplified morphology, and lack the link to cellular biology that ultimately governs the tumor evolution. In this work, we propose a novel method to investigate the relationship between microscopic tumor parameters and PET image characteristics based on the computational simulation of tumor growth. We use a hybrid, multiscale, stochastic mathematical model of cellular metabolism and proliferation to generate simulated cross-sections of tumors in vascularized normal tissue on a microscopic level. The generated longitudinal tumor growth sequences are converted to PET images with realistic resolution and noise. By changing the biological parameters of the model, such as the blood vessel density and conditions for necrosis, distinct tumor phenotypes can be obtained. The simulated cellular maps were compared to real histology slides of SiHa and WiDr xenografts imaged with Hoechst 33342 and pimonidazole. As an example application of the proposed method, we simulated six tumor phenotypes that contain various amounts of hypoxic and necrotic regions induced by a lack of oxygen and glucose, including phenotypes that are distinct on the microscopic level but visually similar in PET images. We computed 22 standardized Haralick texture features for each phenotype, and identified the features that could best discriminate the phenotypes with varying image noise levels. We demonstrated that &#8220;cluster shade&#8221; and &#8220;difference entropy&#8221; are the most effective and noise-resilient features for microscopic phenotype discrimination. Longitudinal analysis of the simulated tumor growth showed that radiomics analysis can be beneficial even in small lesions with a diameter of 3.5&#8211;4 resolution units, corresponding to 8.7&#8211;10.0 mm in modern PET scanners. Certain radiomics features were shown to change non-monotonically with tumor growth, which has implications for feature selection for tracking disease progression and therapy response.</description>
      <author>Hailey S. H. Ahn, Yas Oloumi Yazdi, Brennan J. Wadsworth, Kevin L. Bennewith, Arman Rahmim, Ivan S. Klyuzhin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cancers16122215</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
