<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 01:26:04 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-embedded TiO2-x with rich Ru-Ti bonds and triggered oxygen vacancies for boosted and sustained hydrogen oxidation and evolution electrocatalysis in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157669</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Cong, Mengling Liu, Luyun Chen, Y. Q. Qi, Limin Zhang, Qiuping Zhao, Chunlei Li, Haibin Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. 501(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404454064

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Cong, Mengling Liu, Luyun Chen, Y. Q. Qi, Limin Zhang, Qiuping Zhao, Chunlei Li, Haibin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Two&#8208;Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Electrochemical Glycerol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416178</link>
      <description>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404455598

                Electrochemical glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) is a promising candidate to couple with cathodic reaction, like hydrogen evolution reaction, to produce high&#8208;value product with less energy consumption. Two&#8208;dimensional conjugated metal&#8208;organic frameworks (2D c&#8208;MOFs), comprising square&#8208;planar metal&#8208;coordination motifs (e.g., MO4, M(NH)4, MS4), are notable for their programable active sites, intrinsic charge transport, and excellent stability, making them promising catalyst candidates for GOR. Here, we introduce a novel class of 2D c&#8208;MOFs electrocatalysts, M2[NiPcS8] (M=Co/Ni/Cu), which are synthesized via coordination of octathiolphthalocyaninato nickel (NiPc(SH)8) with various metal centers. Due to a fast kinetic and high activity of CoS4 sites for GOR, the electrocatalytic tests demonstrate that Co2[NiPcS8] supported on carbon paper displays a low GOR potential of 1.35 V vs. RHE at 10 mA cm&#8208;2, significantly reducing the overall water&#8208;electrolysis&#8208;voltage reduction by 0.27 V from oxygen evolution reaction to GOR, thereby outperforming Ni2[NiPcS8] and Cu2[NiPcS8]. Additionally, we have determined that the GOR activity of CoX4 linkage sites varies with different heteroatoms, following an experimentally and theoretically confirmed activity order of CoS4&gt;CoO4&gt;Co(NH)4. The GOR performance of Co2[NiPcS8] not only demonstrate superior performance among non&#8208;noble metal complex, but also provides critical insights on designing high&#8208;performance MOF electrocatalysts upon optimizing the electronic environment of active sites.</description>
      <author>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe Hydroxide Nanopheres for Enhanced Alkaline Splitting and Seawater Oxidation:Anion Doping Effects of Fluorine and Carbonate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403628</link>
      <description>Tingting Zheng, Junyu Shi, Dandan Wang, Yulin Min, Qunjie Xu, Qiaoxia Li, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404458249

                Green hydrogen production can be achieved through electrolysis of fresh water or the use of renewable energy to electrolyze seawater. However, due to the low activity and poor stability of oxygen evolution reaction catalysts, direct electrolysis of alkaline seawater faces significant challenges. Herein, The catalyst F&#8208;CoFe(OH)&#8208;CO3/NF with three&#8208;dimensional nanosphere structure was prepared, The introduction of CO32&#8208; into the intermediate layer of CoFe Hydroxide improves the corrosion resistance of alkaline electrolyte and the doping of F&#8208; is to design three&#8208;dimensional layered nanostructures, increase the active site, and accelerate the diffusion of the electrolyte. By in situ Raman analysis, partial oxidation of CoFe hydroxide to CoFe (oxy)hydroxide as the active center can accelerating the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;related intermediates. In 1M KOH, it requires overpotentials of 210 mV and 251mV to drive current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8208;2, respectively. And it remained stable at the current density of 100 mA cm&#8208;2 for 120 h in 1M KOH. F&#8208;CoFe(OH)&#8208;CO3/NF can also catalyzes the decomposition of electrolytic seawater. Compared with hydroxide, anion&#8208;doped carbonate hydroxide is more efficient and stable in electrolyte solution, which is of great importance for the development of a new stable electrocatalyst for water decomposition.</description>
      <author>Tingting Zheng, Junyu Shi, Dandan Wang, Yulin Min, Qunjie Xu, Qiaoxia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Lattice Oxygen in Nitrogen-Doped High-Entropy Oxide Nanosheets for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05997</link>
      <description>Shengqin Guan, Baoen Xu, Xingbo Yu, Yong&#8208;Hong Ye, Yuting Liu, Taotao Guan, Yang Yu, Jiali Gao, Kaixi Li, Jianlong Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404459898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengqin Guan, Baoen Xu, Xingbo Yu, Yong&#8208;Hong Ye, Yuting Liu, Taotao Guan, Yang Yu, Jiali Gao, Kaixi Li, Jianlong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05997</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isomorphous Cobalt Coordination Frameworks: Enhancing Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction through Coordinated Solvent Variations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.4c00890</link>
      <description>Anjana Chanthapally, Anagha Yatheendran, N. Sandhyarani, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404466198

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key electrochemical redox reaction involved in metal&#8211;air batteries and water-splitting devices. Reducing the energy barrier of these reactions accentuates the necessity in designing competent electrocatalysts. There is an urgent demand for affordable and durable catalysts utilizing non-noble metals, specifically Ni, Co, and Fe, for the OER. In this context, three following cobalt(II) coordination frameworks based on a pyridyl carboxylic acid ligand were synthesized: [Co3(&#956;3-OH)(PCA)4(DMF)2(H2O)](NO3)&#183;DMF&#183;3H2O (1), [Co3(&#956;3-OH)(PCA)4(EtOH)3](NO3)&#183;3EtOH&#183;3H2O (2), and [Co3(&#956;3-OH)(PCA)4(DMA)2(H2O)] (ClO4)&#183;DMA&#183;H2O) (3) using a solvothermal method. The single-crystal diffraction studies confirm the similarity in the three-center cobalt secondary building unit (SBU) and the final 3D topology. These frameworks are investigated as potential catalysts for the OER under alkaline (1 M KOH) conditions. Compound 1 shows extraordinary OER activity demonstrating an overpotential value of 0.37 V at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 78.9 mV. The alternation in the coordination sphere resulting from the difference in coordinated solvent emerges as an intriguing reason contributing to the exceptional activity of a coordination network. The effective electronic modulation within the cobalt trinuclear center induced by the changes in the coordination sphere has lowered the free energy barrier for the desorption of the oxygen produced. This work emphasizes the significant influence and effect of the coordination environment in catalytic activity, serving as a template for designing advanced electrocatalysts that are free from noble metals.</description>
      <author>Anjana Chanthapally, Anagha Yatheendran, N. Sandhyarani</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.4c00890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of Network&#8208;Like 1D/2D (NHCNT/Ni&#9472;MOF) Hybrid Nanoarchitecture for Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401492</link>
      <description>Mrunal Bhosale, Nagaraj Murugan, Yoong Ahm Kim, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, Tae Hwan Oh, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404473833

                Here, integrated functional components into a hybrid heterostructure via highly stabilized network-like interconnected electronic nanoarchitecture of 1D N-doped holey-carbon nanotube (NHCNT) with 2D nickel&#9472;metal-organic framework (Ni&#9472;MOF) nanosheets are developed as high-performance electrocatalyst for overall water splitting. The NHCNT promoting electron transport pathways in electrocatalyst, and formation of holes in nanotubes further enables excellent diffusion of ions for promoting the overall reaction rate. An excellent combination of 1D/2D structure of NHCNT/Ni&#9472;MOF-4 electrocatalyst exhibits excellent oxygen evolution reaction (&#951;</description>
      <author>Mrunal Bhosale, Nagaraj Murugan, Yoong Ahm Kim, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, Tae Hwan Oh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Action of Co-Doped MoS2 Nanosheets on Directional Piezoelectric Catalytic Generation of Reactive Oxygen Species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemproc2024015003</link>
      <description>Win Thi Yein, Dongsu Kim, Qun Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404486316

                Molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) with single- and odd-numbered layers is a novel piezocatalyst, and its piezocatalytic molecular oxygen activation is considered a promising and low-cost strategy for environmental remediation. In this study, the odd-numbered layers of Co-doped MoS2 ultrathin nanosheets were successfully fabricated, which decomposed tetracycline by 99.8% in 15 min through shaking vibration. Moreover, to verify the enhanced piezoelectric catalytic activity of MoS2 via the doping effect, molecular oxygen activation properties were predicted through DFT calculation and monitored by generated reactive oxygen species (ROS) evolution. In addition, the primary reactive species responsible for the degradation of tetracycline pollutants were also investigated in detail.</description>
      <author>Win Thi Yein, Dongsu Kim, Qun Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemproc2024015003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of heterostructured ZnCo2O4@Ni-MOF electrode for the asymmetric supercapacitor and electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145371</link>
      <description>Gita B. Bhanuse, Sanath Kumar, Chung-Jen Chien, Yen&#8208;Pei Fu, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404489081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gita B. Bhanuse, Sanath Kumar, Chung-Jen Chien, Yen&#8208;Pei Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145371</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Oxygen Self-Sufficiency System Enables Singlet Oxygen Production for Water Decontamination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestwater.4c00848</link>
      <description>Zhou Zhou, Yingang Xue, Xia Xu, Wenhao Hu, Yu Wu, Min Shen, Xuefeng Liu, ACS ES&amp;T Water. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404494616

                Electrochemical advanced oxidation process represents a promising strategy for water decontamination, but the parasitic anodic side oxygen evolution reaction always causes a low energy utilization efficiency. In this study, we address this limitation of developing an electrocatalytic oxygen self-sufficiency system. This system established an integrated electrocatalytic process that ran solely on O2 produced by anodic oxygen evolution, followed by transformation of O2 into H2O2 at the nanoconfined Fe2O3 cathode, which then led to the generation of 1O2. The performance of water decontamination was evaluated using tetracycline (TC), bisphenol A (BPA), and perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) as model emerging contaminants. When anodic polarization was applied at 2.0 V vs the standard hydrogen electrode, the removal of TC, BPA, and PFOA with a flow rate of 10 mL min&#8211;1 could reach 90.1%, 92.1%, and 62.2%, respectively. Electron spin resonance and radical quenching results indicated 1O2 as the main reactive oxygen species for TC and BPA decomposition, whereas PFOA decomposition was contributed by direct electron transfer. The intermediate toxicity was predicted to be reduced, and the excellent anti-interference ability of this system was proved in actual water. These findings suggest a reagent-free and oxygen-dependent sustainable system for water decontamination.</description>
      <author>Zhou Zhou, Yingang Xue, Xia Xu, Wenhao Hu, Yu Wu, Min Shen, Xuefeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsestwater.4c00848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeNi-Based Aerogels Containing FeNi3 Nanoclusters Embedded with a Crystalline&#8211;Amorphous Heterojunction as High-Efficiency Oxygen Evolution Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225429</link>
      <description>Tao Li, Jiahui Chen, Zihao Song, Shujie Zhong, Wei Ma, Molecules. 29(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404497521

                In green hydrogen production via water electrolysis, catalysts with multiscale nanostructures synthesized by compositing micro-heterojunctions and nanoporous structures exhibit excellent electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Moreover, they are the most promising non-noble metal catalysts. Herein, FeNi-based aerogels with a three-dimensional nanoporous structure and amorphous matrix embedded with FeNi3 nanoclusters were synthesized via wet chemical reduction coprecipitation. The FeNi3 nanoclusters and the FeNi-based amorphous matrix formed a crystalline&#8211;amorphous heterojunction. These aerogels exhibited excellent OER performance and electrocatalytic stability in alkaline electrolytes. In 1 mol/L of KOH electrolyte, the as-synthesized aerogel exhibited an overpotential of 262 mV at a current density of 20 mA cm&#8722;2 with a Tafel slope of only 46 mV dec&#8722;1. It also demonstrated excellent stability during a 12 h chronopotentiometry test.</description>
      <author>Tao Li, Jiahui Chen, Zihao Song, Shujie Zhong, Wei Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-MOF-derived core-shell CoP@Co3O4 nanoparticle loaded N-doped graphene: An efficient catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07696f</link>
      <description>Xian-Chen Meng, Jian Luan, Lei Zhu, Yuhao Sheng, Fu-Yu Guo, Peng Zheng, Wen-Long Duan, Wen&#8208;Ze Li, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404499262

                Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) and their derivatives have multiple advantages, such as controlled morphology and uniform distribution of elements, which can be served as a kind of excellent electrocatalyst. It is...</description>
      <author>Xian-Chen Meng, Jian Luan, Lei Zhu, Yuhao Sheng, Fu-Yu Guo, Peng Zheng, Wen-Long Duan, Wen&#8208;Ze Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07696f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the performance of ultrathin bimetallic Co&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;1&#8722;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanosheets for pseudocapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06846g</link>
      <description>Pallavi B. Jagdale, Sayali Ashok Patil, A. J. Pathak, Mukaddar Sk, Ranjit Thapa, Amanda Sfeir, S&#233;bastien Royer, Akshaya K. Samal, Manav Saxena, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404500794

                Bimetallic Co&#8211;Ni hydroxide nanosheets for pseudocapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Pallavi B. Jagdale, Sayali Ashok Patil, A. J. Pathak, Mukaddar Sk, Ranjit Thapa, Amanda Sfeir, S&#233;bastien Royer, Akshaya K. Samal, Manav Saxena</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06846g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating the effect of oxygen vacancies on the OER activity of LaNiO3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-40vsz</link>
      <description>Chuanmu Tian, Danni Wang, Kelvin H. L. Zhang, Jan P. Hofmann, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404506579

                In this work, we have investigated the effect of oxygen vacancies on the surface composition, electronic structure and OER performance of LaNiO3. The results show that the OER performance of LaNiO3 can be improved both by lowering the oxygen partial pressure during film growth or annealing the thin film in H2 atmosphere. X-ray photoemission spectroscopy (XPS) shows a significant increase in La ratio on the LaNiO3 surface after the introduction of oxygen defects, especially after H2 treatment where Ni/La reaches 3.5:1. The presence of oxygen vacancies leads to the aggregation of Ni on the surface of LaNiO3, which plays a crucial role in enhancing the OER performance of LaNiO3. In addition, the OER activity of both LaNiO3 and oxygen vacancy rich LaNiO3 decreases upon cyclic voltammetry (CV) between +1.0 V and +1.5 V vs. RHE with proceeding cycle numbers. XPS results reveal that the CV treatments lead to the decrease of Ni concentration at the LaNiO3 surface, which is an important factor for the decrease in the OER performance of LaNiO3 as well as oxygen vacancy rich LaNiO3.</description>
      <author>Chuanmu Tian, Danni Wang, Kelvin H. L. Zhang, Jan P. Hofmann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-40vsz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Mutual&#8208;Constraint of Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis via Direct O&lt;i&gt;&#9472;&lt;/i&gt;O Coupling on High&#8208;Valence Ir Single&#8208;Atom on MnO&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412950</link>
      <description>Ziyi Yang, Fayuan Lai, Qianjiang Mao, Chong Liu, Shengjie Peng, Xiangfeng Liu, Tianran Zhang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404506748

                Abstract Insufficient bifunctional activity of electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the major obstruction to the application of rechargeable metal&#8211;air batteries. The primary reason is the mutual constraint of ORR and OER mechanism, involving the same oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and demonstrating the scaling limitations of the adsorption energies. Herein, it is reported a high&#8208;valence Ir single atom anchored on manganese oxide (Ir SA &#8208;MnO x ) bifunctional catalyst showing independent pathways for ORR and OER, i.e., associated 4e &#8722; pathway on high&#8208;valence Ir site for ORR and a novel chemical&#8208;activated concerted mechanism for OER, where a distinct spontaneous chemical activation process triggers direct O &#9472; O coupling. The Ir SA &#8208;MnO x therefore delivers outstanding bifunctional activities with remarkably low potential difference (0.635 V) between OER potential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and ORR half&#8208;wave potential in alkaline solution. This work breaks the scaling limitations and provides a new avenue to design efficient and multifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Ziyi Yang, Fayuan Lai, Qianjiang Mao, Chong Liu, Shengjie Peng, Xiangfeng Liu, Tianran Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412950</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Se&#8208;Doped CoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructures on Multiwalled Carbon Nanotubes as Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407049</link>
      <description>Y.&#8208;B. Jiang, Xuguang An, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Feng Wang, Abdukader Abdukayum, Qingquan Kong, Sanshuang Gao, Guangzhi Hu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404507176

                Abstract The use of efficient and affordable non&#8208;precious metal catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions is vital for replacing and widely implementing new energy sources. Nevertheless, improving the catalytic performance of these non&#8208;precious&#8208;metal bifunctional electrocatalysts continues to be a major challenge. In this article, an optimized Se&#8208;incorporated bulk CoS 2 @MoS 2 heterostructure grown on the surface of carbon nanotubes is reported. The resulting Se&#8208;CoS 2 @MoS 2 /CNTs exhibit robust bifunctional electrocatalytic performance, with low overpotentials of 85 and 240 mV @ 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 for HER and OER, respectively. The materials exhibit superior long&#8208;term stability of over 145 h, surpassing most electrocatalysts of similar type. This enhanced performance is attributed to the synergistic effect at the interface between the MoS 2 and CoS 2 phases, abundant active sites, and high active surface area, which collectively improves the electron&#8208;transfer efficiency during the reaction process. Furthermore, the incorporation of the amorphous state of Se into the heterostructure yields a change in the crystallinity of the heterostructure in the electronic structure, which optimizes the adsorption and activation energy barriers of the catalytic intermediate. This study thus presents a promising approach to regulating anion doping in bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Y.&#8208;B. Jiang, Xuguang An, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Feng Wang, Abdukader Abdukayum, Qingquan Kong, Sanshuang Gao, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXene Electrocatalysts: Transformative Approaches in Hydrogen Production with Alternative Anode Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407120</link>
      <description>Sreenisa Sundarraj, Neshanth Vadivel, Arun Prasad Murthy, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Myong Yong Choi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404507611

                Abstract Water electrolyzer is crucial for producing clean hydrogen, but the traditional approach faces challenges owing to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) slow kinetics at the anode. Hybrid water splitting replaces the OER with the oxidation of an organic molecule to enhance hydrogen production along with value&#8208;added products. The scarcity of affordable and highly effective catalysts remains a major challenge. MXene, a 2D nanomaterial, has gained substantial attention for its enviable properties, for instance high conductivity, hydrophilicity, and substantial surface area. This review discusses experimental methods for synthesizing MXene and MXene&#8208;based nanocomposites. Furthermore, the small molecules oxidation such as benzyl alcohol, methanol, ethanol, urea, hydrazine, furfural, and formic acid as alternatives to the oxygen evolution reaction is examined. Finally, an understanding of imminent research and the development of MXene&#8208;associated materials in electrocatalytic applications are presented.</description>
      <author>Sreenisa Sundarraj, Neshanth Vadivel, Arun Prasad Murthy, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Dual Potential of the MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@VS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocomposite as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02504</link>
      <description>Joshi Anju, Levna Chacko, T. Sruthi, P Gopika, Vincent Mathew, P. M. Aneesh, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404513241

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Joshi Anju, Levna Chacko, T. Sruthi, P Gopika, Vincent Mathew, P. M. Aneesh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02504</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of Ultrasonically Treated Nickel Electrodes in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoes.2024.100884</link>
      <description>Yang Xiao-ling, Weijuan Zhang, Jiaoling Li Lanhuang, International Journal of Electrochemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404515412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Xiao-ling, Weijuan Zhang, Jiaoling Li Lanhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijoes.2024.100884</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retraction notice to "Enhanced the electrochemical performance of mesh nano composite based on Co3O4/MoSOX for oxygen evolution reaction: Recent development" [Int J Hydrogen Energy 47 (6) (2022) 3556&#8211;3567, 33874]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.352</link>
      <description>Abdul Qayoom Mugheri, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404515441

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Qayoom Mugheri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aqueous Exfoliated 2D Cobalt-Iron-Layered Double Hydroxide Nanosheets: Effect of Co:Fe Ratio on Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135793</link>
      <description>Shraddha A. Pawar, Shweta V. Talekar, Prashant D. Sawant, Vikas V. Magdum, Shirin P. Kulkarni, Yogesh M. Chitare, C.D. Lokhande, Hemraj M. Yadav, Jayavant L. Gunjakar, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404516706

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shraddha A. Pawar, Shweta V. Talekar, Prashant D. Sawant, Vikas V. Magdum, Shirin P. Kulkarni, Yogesh M. Chitare, C.D. Lokhande, Hemraj M. Yadav, Jayavant L. Gunjakar</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Improvement of Thermodynamics and Kinetics of BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanode via CuI for Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03658</link>
      <description>Yuan Guan, Zheng Shen, Xinyi Gu, Dayu Wu, Shaomang Wang, Zhongyu Li, Shicheng Yan, Zhigang Zou, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404516991

                The preparation of durable and efficient photoanodes for photoelectrochemical water oxidation is of great importance in promoting the development of green hydrogen production and artificial photosynthesis. Here, n-type BiVO4 was combined with p-type CuI to construct a CuI/BiVO4 (CIB-1) p&#8211;n heterojunction photoanode. The composite photoanode effectively overcame the drawbacks of BiVO4, such as low separation and injection efficiency of photogenerated electron&#8211;hole pairs. As a result, the CIB-1 had the highest photocurrent density of 1.98 mA cm&#8211;2, which was 2.5 times higher than pure BiVO4 with 0.79 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.23 V (vs RHE) under AM 1.5G light irradiation. The CIB-1 had a lower Tafel slope of 23.2 mV decade&#8211;1 compared to 47.9 mV decade&#8211;1 for BiVO4, so the water oxidation kinetics was remarkably advanced over CuI/BiVO4. Based on DFT calculations, the OER overpotential of 0.480 V for CuI/BiVO4 was significantly lower than that of 1.546 V for BiVO4 due to the lower free energy from OH&#8211; to oxygen over CuI/BiVO4 compared to BiVO4.</description>
      <author>Yuan Guan, Zheng Shen, Xinyi Gu, Dayu Wu, Shaomang Wang, Zhongyu Li, Shicheng Yan, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic coordination polymers synthesized from pyrazine dicarboxylic acid serve as efficient electrocatalysts for enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113579</link>
      <description>Jia Du, Xueguo Liu, Bingke Li, Kenan Sun, Kexin Huang, Lixuan Chen, Yiming Wu, Fule Li, Yifan Yang, Yuming Song, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404517398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Du, Xueguo Liu, Bingke Li, Kenan Sun, Kexin Huang, Lixuan Chen, Yiming Wu, Fule Li, Yifan Yang, Yuming Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heteroatom Engineering in Earth-Abundant Cobalt Electrocatalyst for Energy-Saving Hydrogen Evolution Coupling with Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11228</link>
      <description>Siyuan Tang, Zhipeng Zhang, Quanjiang Lv, Xueqing Pan, Jianling Dong, Luyu Liu, Yangyang Wan, Jian Han, Fuzhan Song, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404522598

                The development of multifunctional electrocatalysts with high performance for electrocatalyzing urea oxidation-assisted water splitting is of great significance for energy-saving hydrogen production. In this work, we demonstrate a novel heteroatom engineering strategy for development of B-doped Co as a multifunctional electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and urea oxidation reaction (UOR). Density functional theory (DFT) results suggest that a B dopant can efficiently adjust the electron reconstruction of the exposure of Co sites nearby and facilitate electron transfer, resulting in an optimal d-band center along with a lower Gibbs free energy barrier. Ultimately, the obtained B&#8211;Co exhibits pH-universal HER properties in various electrolytes. A highly efficient HER performance with overpotentials as low as 27, 163, and 430 mV to &#8722;10, &#8722;100, and &#8722;500 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH, respectively, is observed for the B&#8211;Co electrode. More importantly, the UOR-assisted electrolyzer only requires a voltage input of 1.55 V to produce the current densities of 50 mA cm&#8211;2, resulting in a 200 mV saving-energy potential compared to water electrolysis, demonstrating its high efficiency of hydrogen production in industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Siyuan Tang, Zhipeng Zhang, Quanjiang Lv, Xueqing Pan, Jianling Dong, Luyu Liu, Yangyang Wan, Jian Han, Fuzhan Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urchin-Like Assembled Iron-Doped Nickel Cobalt Oxide Nanorods Anchored on Nitrogen and Sulfur Co-Doped Reduced Graphene Oxide for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5026161</link>
      <description>N. Durga Sri, T. Maiyalagan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404527549

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. Durga Sri, T. Maiyalagan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5026161</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel N-doped biomass carbon spheres loaded with In-Situ grown FeCo layered double hydroxide for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.126</link>
      <description>Chong Cai, Lin Hao, Danhua Sun, Zitong Chen, Hongyuan Yan, Yufan Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 680(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404529046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chong Cai, Lin Hao, Danhua Sun, Zitong Chen, Hongyuan Yan, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-doped graphene encapsulated FeNi core-shell with S defect for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04244a</link>
      <description>Rumeng Feng, Lu Chen, Liping Huang, Haihong Wu, Yuanyu Ge, Jiani Xu, Min Zeng, Wenyao Li, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404533025

                The synergistic effect between the transition metal sulfide alloy core, the N-doped graphene shell, and the internal interfacial potential serves to regulate the electronic structure and facilitate electron transfer. We...</description>
      <author>Rumeng Feng, Lu Chen, Liping Huang, Haihong Wu, Yuanyu Ge, Jiani Xu, Min Zeng, Wenyao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04244a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable Heteroassembly of 2D CoNi LDH and Ti3C2 Nanosheets with Enhanced Electrocatalytic Activity for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03679d</link>
      <description>Xueyi Lu, Lulu Jia, Minchen Hou, Xuemin Wu, Chang Ni, Gaofei Xiao, Renzhi Ma, Xia Lu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404533126

                The sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are bottlenecks to develop hydrogen energy based on water electrolysis, which can be significantly improved using high performance catalyst. In this context,...</description>
      <author>Xueyi Lu, Lulu Jia, Minchen Hou, Xuemin Wu, Chang Ni, Gaofei Xiao, Renzhi Ma, Xia Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03679d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Ni-Cu-Fe Trimetallic Selenides on Nickel Foam for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5027612</link>
      <description>Mingda Che, Xinrong Zhao, Yaqiong Gong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404535751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingda Che, Xinrong Zhao, Yaqiong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5027612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applicable Descriptors under Weak Metal&#8208;Oxygen d&#8208;p Interaction for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419718</link>
      <description>Fangshi Fan, Bohan Lei, Xiaomin Song, Jiayuan Liang, Weiwei Cai, Yu Lin Zhong, Yongjun Wu, Ningzhong Bao, Lingjie Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404540082

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role in water electrolysis and renewable energy conversion processes. Descriptors are utilized to elucidate the structure&#8208;performance relationships of OER catalytic materials, yet each descriptor exhibits specificity to particular systems. Currently, there is a lack of effective descriptors to describe the relationship between electronic structure and OER performance in ionic systems. This study reveals for the first time that widely used OER descriptors, the d&#8208;band center and charge transfer energy, are limited in their effectiveness for oxide systems dominated by ionic bonds, in which ionic interactions significantly enhance or suppress the catalytic activity. Furthermore, composite descriptors tailored for ionic systems are proposed, with findings extended to complex multi&#8208;component and high&#8208;entropy oxides. The results indicate that the metal d&#8208;band unoccupied states parameter and the active states parameter can serve as effective OER descriptors for ionic catalytic materials. This work addresses the gap in OER descriptors for ionic systems, offering a new theoretical foundation and guidance for the development of efficient OER catalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Fangshi Fan, Bohan Lei, Xiaomin Song, Jiayuan Liang, Weiwei Cai, Yu Lin Zhong, Yongjun Wu, Ningzhong Bao, Lingjie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applicable Descriptors under Weak Metal&#8208;Oxygen d&#8208;p Interaction for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419718</link>
      <description>Fangshi Fan, Bohan Lei, Xiaomin Song, Jiayuan Liang, Weiwei Cai, Yu Lin Zhong, Yongjun Wu, Ningzhong Bao, Lingjie Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404540122

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role in water electrolysis and renewable energy conversion processes. Descriptors are utilized to elucidate the structure&#8208;performance relationships of OER catalytic materials, yet each descriptor exhibits specificity to particular systems. Currently, there is a lack of effective descriptors to describe the relationship between electronic structure and OER performance in ionic systems. This study reveals for the first time that widely used OER descriptors, the d&#8208;band center and charge transfer energy, are limited in their effectiveness for oxide systems dominated by ionic bonds, in which ionic interactions significantly enhance or suppress the catalytic activity. Furthermore, composite descriptors tailored for ionic systems are proposed, with findings extended to complex multi&#8208;component and high&#8208;entropy oxides. The results indicate that the metal d&#8208;band unoccupied states parameter and the active states parameter can serve as effective OER descriptors for ionic catalytic materials. This work addresses the gap in OER descriptors for ionic systems, offering a new theoretical foundation and guidance for the development of efficient OER catalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Fangshi Fan, Bohan Lei, Xiaomin Song, Jiayuan Liang, Weiwei Cai, Yu Lin Zhong, Yongjun Wu, Ningzhong Bao, Lingjie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phytic acid-assisted rapid electrochemical reconstruction for efficient oxygen evolution reaction at high current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.258</link>
      <description>Y. Z. Qu, Yun Wu, Yijie Zhang, Qiang Zhao, Jinping Li, Guang Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 95(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404540775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y. Z. Qu, Yun Wu, Yijie Zhang, Qiang Zhao, Jinping Li, Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous interface engineering to enhance oxygen electrocatalytic activity for rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02213k</link>
      <description>Taotao Li, Yu-Rui Ji, Yongfu Wu, Peng&#8208;Fei Wang, Zonglin Liu, Jie Shu, Ting&#8208;Feng Yi, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404543143

                Co/CoO heterojunctions embedded in N-doped hollow carbon nanospheres coupled with multiple active sites promote the electron transfer of oxygen-related intermediates and modulate surface engineering promoting ORR/OER activity.</description>
      <author>Taotao Li, Yu-Rui Ji, Yongfu Wu, Peng&#8208;Fei Wang, Zonglin Liu, Jie Shu, Ting&#8208;Feng Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02213k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconfiguration and activation induced by characteristic migration of transition metal-ions between interfaces of high-entropy oxygen evolution catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g</link>
      <description>Wei Zuo, Zhenhang Xu, Jun Qian, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao, Materials Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404546198

                The tremendous potential of high entropy alloys (HEA) in the electrocatalysis of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is constantly revealed, but there are still many issues worth discussing how to build...</description>
      <author>Wei Zuo, Zhenhang Xu, Jun Qian, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Cobalt-doped Ni3S2@NiFe-LDH Heterojunction with Enhanced Local Electric Field for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06830k</link>
      <description>Jie Wu, An&#8208;Chi Huang, Wen Cao, Xuehui Gao, Zhongwei Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404551182

                Alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER), involving a four-electron transfer process, is characterized by high overpotential and extremely sluggish reaction kinetics, posing a significant challenge for catalyst design. Herein, a strategy...</description>
      <author>Jie Wu, An&#8208;Chi Huang, Wen Cao, Xuehui Gao, Zhongwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06830k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Water Splitting Electrocatalysts through Computational Insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05117c</link>
      <description>Mingcheng Zhang, Yu-Chang Hou, Yuzhu Jiang, Xin Ni, Yanfei Wang, Xiaoxin Zou, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404551239

                Electrocatalytic water splitting is vital for the sustainable production of green hydrogen. Electrocatalysts, including those for the hydrogen evolution reaction at the cathode and the oxygen evolution reaction at the...</description>
      <author>Mingcheng Zhang, Yu-Chang Hou, Yuzhu Jiang, Xin Ni, Yanfei Wang, Xiaoxin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05117c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>L-Arginine-assisted cobalt hydroxide as an Efficacious electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.202</link>
      <description>Simi Thomas, Bhuvaneswari Thasma Subramanian, R. Anjali, Shyaam Srirangadhamu Yuvaraj, Devika Manoj, V.M. Biju, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 95(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404552219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simi Thomas, Bhuvaneswari Thasma Subramanian, R. Anjali, Shyaam Srirangadhamu Yuvaraj, Devika Manoj, V.M. Biju</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Evolution Enhancement of Oxalate-Based Nickel&#8211;Iron MOF through Bipyridine Coordinated Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04133</link>
      <description>Yashu Liu, Xuan Hao, Cheng Tang, Zehang Li, Shilin Wu, Shan Qiao, Hongbo Zhou, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404560924

                The catalytic performance of oxalate-based Ni&#8211;Fe metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) was investigated via a coordination strategy. The bidentate chelating ligand 2,2&#8242;-bpy (2,2&#8242;-bipyridine), was utilized to improve the catalytic kinetics under ambient conditions. The results revealed that a MOF-to-MOF transformation including the formation of [M(2,2&#8242;-bpy)n]2/3+ (M = Ni/Fe, n = 1&#8211;3) could boost alkaline OER, giving an impressive ultralow overpotential of 220 mV at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 in a 1 M KOH solution, surpassing the performance of control group activity of oxalate-based Ni&#8211;Fe MOF. However, excessive addition of the ligand had a negative effect, leading to decreased activity. Further investigation revealed the double role of 2,2&#8242;-bpy: Both promote and suppress catalytic reactions. The catalytic mechanism was then discussed, highlighting the potential of secondary ligands to effectively fine-tune the catalytic behavior of these materials.</description>
      <author>Yashu Liu, Xuan Hao, Cheng Tang, Zehang Li, Shilin Wu, Shan Qiao, Hongbo Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoZn-based high entropy alloy catalysts enabled dual activation and stabilization in alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq6758</link>
      <description>Yunjie Mei, J. X. Chen, Qi Wang, Y.. Guo, Hanwen Liu, W. Shi, Lin Cheng, Yifei Yuan, Yuhua Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Yonggang Yao, Science Advances. 10(47)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404563910

                It remains a grand challenge to develop electrocatalysts with simultaneously high activity, long durability, and low cost for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), originating from two competing reaction pathways and often trade-off performances. The adsorbed evolution mechanism (AEM) suffers from sluggish kinetics due to a linear scaling relationship, while the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) causes unstable structures due to lattice oxygen escape. We propose a MoZnFeCoNi high-entropy alloy (HEA) incorporating AEM-promoter Mo and LOM-active Zn to achieve dual activation and stabilization for efficient and durable OER. Density functional theory and chemical probe experiments confirmed dual-mechanism activation, with representative Co-Co &#8224; -Mo sites facilitating AEM and Zn-O &#8224; -Ni sites enhancing LOM, resulting in an ultralow OER overpotential (&#951; 10 = 221 mV). The multielement interaction, high-entropy structure, and carbon network notably enhance structural stability for durable catalysis (&gt;1500 hours at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Our work offers a viable approach to concurrently enhance OER activity and stability by designing HEA catalysts to enable dual-mechanism synergy.</description>
      <author>Yunjie Mei, J. X. Chen, Qi Wang, Y.. Guo, Hanwen Liu, W. Shi, Lin Cheng, Yifei Yuan, Yuhua Wang, Bao Yu Xia, Yonggang Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq6758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomass derived amino acid assisted synthesis of FeNi layered double hydroxide for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113574</link>
      <description>S. M. Abu Nayem, Yuda Prima Hardianto, Abubakar Dahiru Shuaibu, Syed Shaheen Shah, Santa Islam, Mohammad A. Jafar Mazumder, Md. Abdul Aziz, A. J. Saleh Ahammad, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404565151

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. M. Abu Nayem, Yuda Prima Hardianto, Abubakar Dahiru Shuaibu, Syed Shaheen Shah, Santa Islam, Mohammad A. Jafar Mazumder, Md. Abdul Aziz, A. J. Saleh Ahammad</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of bifunctional MOF-based composite electrocatalysts promoting oxygen evolution reaction and glucose oxidation reaction and its kinetic deciphering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101601</link>
      <description>Hongmei Yuan, Changyu Weng, Xinghua Zhang, Lungang Chen, Qi Zhang, Longlong Ma, Jianguo Liu, Materials Today Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404565325

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongmei Yuan, Changyu Weng, Xinghua Zhang, Lungang Chen, Qi Zhang, Longlong Ma, Jianguo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of BiVO4 photoanode surface oxygen evolution kinetics via Ni-Fe-ZIF derived bimetallic NiFeOx co-catalyst for water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120965</link>
      <description>Dongbo Xu, Xiaoying Gao, Gui Zhang, Yulong Duan, Yihuan Li, Xianghai Meng, Na Gao, Weidong Shi, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404565683

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongbo Xu, Xiaoying Gao, Gui Zhang, Yulong Duan, Yihuan Li, Xianghai Meng, Na Gao, Weidong Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the spin configuration by topochemical transformation for optimized intermediates adsorption ability in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60140-3</link>
      <description>Jinchang Xu, Yongqi Jian, Guang-Qiang Yu, Wanli Liang, Xiashi Zhu, Muzi Yang, Jian Chen, Fangyan Xie, Yanshuo Jin, Nan Wang, Xi&#8208;Bo Li, Hui Meng, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404565943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinchang Xu, Yongqi Jian, Guang-Qiang Yu, Wanli Liang, Xiashi Zhu, Muzi Yang, Jian Chen, Fangyan Xie, Yanshuo Jin, Nan Wang, Xi&#8208;Bo Li, Hui Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60140-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress of anionic vacancies in electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60157-9</link>
      <description>Yanan Xia, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Junheng Tang, Xiaobin Liu, Zhenyu Xiao, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang, CHINESE JOURNAL OF CATALYSIS (CHINESE VERSION). 66(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404565982

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Xia, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Junheng Tang, Xiaobin Liu, Zhenyu Xiao, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60157-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Identification of Electrocatalyst Layer Generated on Lead Electrode under Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145388</link>
      <description>Naoto Todoroki, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404566071

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naoto Todoroki</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triggering the Dual-Metal-Site Lattice Oxygen Mechanism with In Situ-Generated Mn&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; Sites for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14338</link>
      <description>Jianyun Liu, Tanyuan Wang, Mingzi Sun, Mengyi Liao, Li Wang, Shuxia Liu, Hao Shi, Yang Liu, Yue Shen, Ruiguo Cao, Yunhui Huang, Bolong Huang, Qing Li, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404578003

                The development of high-performance non-Ir/Ru catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acid is critical for the applications of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). Here, we report a new kind of heterostructure catalyst by loading 5.8% Ag nanoparticles on MnO nanorods (Ag/MnO) for acidic OER. The as-prepared Ag/MnO requires only an overpotential of 196 mV for the OER at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and operates in a PEMWE for over 300 h at a current density of 200 mA cm&#8211;2, representing one of the best non-Ir/Ru OER catalysts. Operando X-ray absorption spectroscopy confirms that the introduction of trace Ag can promote the generation of highly active Mn3+&#8211;O sites with oxygen vacancies at a low voltage, leading to a dual-metal-site lattice oxygen-mediated pathway with faster kinetics than the adsorbate evolution mechanism. Theoretical calculations indicate that the trace Ag promotes the overlap between the d orbitals of Mn and the s, p orbitals of O, thereby activating the lattice oxygen and reducing the OER energy barrier. The dissolution of Mn is also suppressed by Ag due to the increased energy for vacancy formation of Mn, where the stability number reaches a high value of 3058, supporting improved structural stability.</description>
      <author>Jianyun Liu, Tanyuan Wang, Mingzi Sun, Mengyi Liao, Li Wang, Shuxia Liu, Hao Shi, Yang Liu, Yue Shen, Ruiguo Cao, Yunhui Huang, Bolong Huang, Qing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Properties and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Performance of a Medium-Entropy Metal Nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02059</link>
      <description>Huashuai Hu, Xiaohui Yan, Li Wang, Congling Yin, J. Paul Attfield, Minghui Yang, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404578267

                The advancement of highly efficient and durable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential for advancing sustainable hydrogen energy technologies. In this study, we synthesized a novel medium-entropy metal nitride (MEMN), FeCoNiZnN, with an antiperovskite structure through a solid-phase reaction method. FeCoNiZnN displays ferromagnetism above 350 K and demonstrates exceptional OER performance with a specific activity 141 times greater than that of Co3ZnN, with an overpotential of only 301 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, comparable to that of commercial RuO2 catalysts, and exhibits superior durability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the enhanced catalytic performance is due to optimized electronic properties and improved d-band centers, which enhance the adsorption of oxygen intermediates and reduce the free energy barriers at the rate-determining step. This study highlights the potential of MEMNs in developing advanced magnetic materials and novel electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Huashuai Hu, Xiaohui Yan, Li Wang, Congling Yin, J. Paul Attfield, Minghui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Engineering of NiCoP Sites via N, Ru Dual Doping for Bifunctional Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03879</link>
      <description>Meng Zhou, Wenzhi Jia, Tian Tian, Yuhan Ye, Jianping Zhou, Jian Tian, Guoxiang Pan, Bin He, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404578577

                Exploiting highly effective electrocatalysts is a challenge for boosting the overall efficiency of water splitting. Herein, we present a nitrogen and ruthenium dual-doping strategy to tailor the electronic structures of NiCoP(N, Ru&#8211;NiCoP), creating high-performance bifunctional electrodes for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The dual-doping approach is favorable for electronic interactions within the NiCoP and CoP, yielding a near-zero Gibbs free energy for H adsorption. Consequently, the optimized N, Ru&#8211;NiCoP electrodes exhibit exceptional bifunctional activities, with overpotentials of 53 and 405 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 for the HER and OER, respectively. Notably, their performance surpasses that of commercial Pt/C and RuO2 catalysts at large current densities, demonstrating their potential for industrial water splitting applications. Moreover, the overall water-splitting device achieves a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 with a driving voltage of only 1.54 V. This work provides an effective heteroatom doping strategy to develop low-cost and highly active electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Meng Zhou, Wenzhi Jia, Tian Tian, Yuhan Ye, Jianping Zhou, Jian Tian, Guoxiang Pan, Bin He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03879</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface reconstruction of Co(OH)2 nanosheets through an in-situ PBA etching and sulfuration strategy for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114709</link>
      <description>Changhong Diao, Xin Chang, Xinyao Ding, Ruibai Cang, Mingyi Zhang, Molecular Catalysis. 570(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404580308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Changhong Diao, Xin Chang, Xinyao Ding, Ruibai Cang, Mingyi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur-doped FeCoNiOx nanosheets improve their catalytic oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.286</link>
      <description>Yanghanqi Li, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Jie Li, Zhengying Wu, Caiqin Wang, Yukou Du, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 95(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404580457

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanghanqi Li, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Jie Li, Zhengying Wu, Caiqin Wang, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Reconfiguration and activation induced by characteristic migration of transition metal-ions between interfaces of high-entropy oxygen evolution catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Wei Zuo, Zhenhang Xu, Jun Qian, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Zuo, Zhenhang Xu, Jun Qian, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Reconfiguration and activation induced by characteristic migration of transition metal-ions between interfaces of high-entropy oxygen evolution catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582617

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Reconfiguration and activation induced by characteristic migration of transition metal-ions between interfaces of high-entropy oxygen evolution catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582652

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Reconfiguration and activation induced by characteristic migration of transition metal-ions between interfaces of high-entropy oxygen evolution catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582658

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Reconfiguration and activation induced by characteristic migration of transition metal-ions between interfaces of high-entropy oxygen evolution catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582667

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Joule Heating with Vibration Ball Milling for Synthesizing Carbon-Supported Ni&lt;sub&gt;100&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles Achieving Efficient Oxygen Evolution and Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00591</link>
      <description>Li Zhang, Mengyuan Ma, Zhenya Hu, Hui Liu, Dong Chen, Shaonan Tian, Lin Xu, Guozhu Chen, Jun Yang, ACS Applied Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Zhang, Mengyuan Ma, Zhenya Hu, Hui Liu, Dong Chen, Shaonan Tian, Lin Xu, Guozhu Chen, Jun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Amorphous Cu(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/ZIF-67 as Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysts for Anion-Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03641</link>
      <description>In Tae Kim, Seunghun Lee, Sung Jun Lee, Jun Seok Ha, Seo Hyun Park, Hyunsoo Jin, Woo&#8208;Jae Lee, Bong Kyun Kang, Hyunju Lee, Young Do Kim, Yoo Sei Park, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404589618

                The anion-exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEM electrolyzer) is an advanced technology for the sustainable production of green hydrogen. However, its commercialization has been hindered by its relatively low performance, which necessitates the use of platinum group metal (PGM)-based electrocatalysts. Herein, we address this challenge by developing a composite material consisting of non-PGM-based amorphous Cu(OH)2 and ZIF-67. The abundant defects in amorphous Cu(OH)2 and the modification of the electronic structure, induced by the strong interaction between ZIF-67 and Cu(OH)2, significantly enhance the catalytic performance of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The AEM electrolyzer equipped with Cu(OH)2@ZIF-100 demonstrates a higher performance (1.75 Vcell at 1.0 A/cm2) compared to those using RuO2 (1.784 Vcell at 1.0 A/cm2) by reducing mass transport losses within the AEM electrolyzer.</description>
      <author>In Tae Kim, Seunghun Lee, Sung Jun Lee, Jun Seok Ha, Seo Hyun Park, Hyunsoo Jin, Woo&#8208;Jae Lee, Bong Kyun Kang, Hyunju Lee, Young Do Kim, Yoo Sei Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Delocalized Polarizations in Metal Oxide Electrodes with Conducting Polymers for Efficient and Durable Water&#8208;Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401881</link>
      <description>Hyun&#8208;Ji Oh, Ji-Woo Park, Jae&#8208;Hong Choi, Young&#8208;Wan Ju, Changmin Kim, Jeeyoung Shin, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404602234

                Oxygen evolution reaction is a pivotal anodic reaction for electrolysis, however, it remains the obstacle from its sluggish reaction kinetics originating from multiple electron transfer pathways at electrochemical interfaces. Especially, it remains a challenge to achieve stable operation at elevated current densities as electrodes suffer oxidative environment in corrosive conditions. Herein, we report that the conducting polymer polypyrrole electrodeposited Pr0.7Sr0.3CoO3 perovskite oxides for durable oxygen evolution electrodes. We found that the conducting polymer electrodeposited oxides exhibited a highly durable electrochemical oxygen evolution performance maintaining &gt;99% of initial activities during the accelerated durability test. Meanwhile, bare metal oxides presented significant performance drops (&lt;6% of initial activities) over the consecutive 20,000 accelerated durability test. High&#8208;resolution transmission electron microscope images identified the maintenance of high crystallinity of the heterostructure, suggesting that the electrodeposited pPy clusters can effectively delocalize highly polarized electrodes preventing material corrosion. The overall water electrolysis experiments further demonstrated that the heterostructure showed excellent stability at the high current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 over 700 hours. This marks the first report of the delocalized polarization benefiting from conducting polymers for durable oxygen evolution for perovskite oxides, suggesting great potential for scalable water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Hyun&#8208;Ji Oh, Ji-Woo Park, Jae&#8208;Hong Choi, Young&#8208;Wan Ju, Changmin Kim, Jeeyoung Shin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Oriented Dual&#8208;Interface Built&#8208;in Electric Fields of Robust Pd&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;Ta&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&#945; Bifunctional Electrocatalysis for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418211</link>
      <description>Jun L&#252;, Kai Huang, Hongdae Lee, Sheng-Yang Huang, Hao Fu, Kai Wang, Sixiao Liu, Donghyun Min, Cheng Lian, Ho Seok Park, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404602516

                Abstract It is imperative yet challenging for developing highly efficient multifunctional electrocatalysts for future sustainable energy pursuits. Herein, dual&#8208;interface reinforced reverse orientation of built&#8208;in electric fields (BIEFs) is reported in Pd 1 Mo 1 Ta 2 O&#945; in&#8208;plane heterostructure, where amorphous Ta 2 O 5 and PdO &#948; particles are confined to PdMo nanosheet, for robust bifunctional electrocatalysts of rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries. The as&#8208;synthesized electrocatalyst (Pd 1 Mo 1 Ta 2 O&#945;) exhibits remarkable catalytic activity toward oxygen reduction (E on = 0.95 V, E 1/2 = 0.81 V) and oxygen evolution (&#951; 10 = 401 mV) reactions with high kinetics and operational stability. These enhanced bifunctional electrocatalytic activities of Pd 1 Mo 1 Ta 2 O&#945; are attributed to the synergistic collaboration of dual&#8208;interface BIEFs, where PdMo || PdO &#948; initiating BIEF 1 orientation is parallel to OER external electric field (ExEF) and Ta 2 O 5 || PdO &#948; /PdMo initiating BIEF 2 orientation is parallel to ORR ExEF. In particular, the rechargeable zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB) with the as&#8208;designed Pd 1 Mo 1 Ta 2 O&#945; electrocatalysts delivers a high specific capacity of 1050 mAh g &#8722;1 and stable voltage profiles over 800 cycles. Therefore, this work provides the structural and interfacial designs of bifunctional electrocatalysts with the reverse oriented BIEFs that synergistically enhance intrinsic catalytic activity and electronic transport for both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Jun L&#252;, Kai Huang, Hongdae Lee, Sheng-Yang Huang, Hao Fu, Kai Wang, Sixiao Liu, Donghyun Min, Cheng Lian, Ho Seok Park</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain&#8208;Engineered Ir Shell Enhances Activity and Stability of Ir&#8208;Ru Catalysts for Water Electrolysis: An Operando Wide&#8208;Angle X&#8208;Ray Scattering Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403738</link>
      <description>Tom&#225;&#353; Hrbek, Peter K&#250;&#353;, Jakub Drnec, Marta Mirolo, Hridya Nedumkulam, Isaac Martens, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404602548

                Abstract Ir&#8208;Ru alloys with high Ru content serve as stable and highly active catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers (PEM&#8208;WEs), enabling efficient operation with low Ir loadings (150 &#181;g cm &#8722; 2 ). Despite this, the mechanisms behind their enhanced stability remain unclear. In this study, operando Wide&#8208;Angle X&#8208;ray Scattering (WAXS) and ex situ techniques are utilized to investigate the structural evolution of these magnetron&#8208;sputtered alloys during a PEM&#8208;WE operation. The findings reveal that Ru leaches from the surface upon potential application, forming a dynamic Ir&#8208;Ru@IrO x core&#8208;shell structure. The Ir shell, strained by the Ir&#8208;Ru core, maintains a lower oxidation state than pure Ir catalyst, leading to superior catalytic activity and stability. Remarkably, the Ir&#8208;Ru 25:75 catalyst demonstrates better stability over Ir&#8208;Ru 50:50, despite its higher Ru content, due to the better protection of the subsurface Ir and Ru from oxidation and dissolution. This study not only clarifies the performance&#8208;enhancing mechanisms of Ir&#8208;Ru catalysts but also suggests that other, more economical materials, such as Co or Ti, could serve as effective cores in Ir&#8208;M systems, offering a pathway to more cost&#8208;effective catalysts for PEM&#8208;WE applications.</description>
      <author>Tom&#225;&#353; Hrbek, Peter K&#250;&#353;, Jakub Drnec, Marta Mirolo, Hridya Nedumkulam, Isaac Martens, Jaroslava Nov&#225;kov&#225;, Tom&#225;&#353; &#352;k&#225;la, Iva Matol&#305;&#769;nov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Bonding of Lattice N Activates Metal Ni to Achieve Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411526</link>
      <description>Nian-Dan Zhao, Wei Luo, Sijun Li, Hua Wang, Yini Mao, Yimin Jiang, Wenbin Wang, Ming Li, Wei&#8208;Fang Su, Rongxing He, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404611968

                Abstract Developing efficient and robust free&#8208;standing electrocatalysts for overall water splitting is a promising but challenging task. Herein, the N&#8208;incorporated Ni nanosheets non&#8208;fully encapsulated by N&#8208;doped carbon (NC) layer are fabricated (N&#9472;Ni&#169;NC). The introduction of N not only regulates the size of nanosheets in N&#9472;Ni&#169;NC but also promotes the electrochemical activity of metal Ni. Experimental and theoretical results reveal that strong bonding of the lattice N activates the inert metal Ni by promoting charge transfer between Ni and N. In addition, the upward shift of the d&#8208;band center induced by lattice N enhances the adsorption of intermediates, thereby making Ni as a new OER active site together with C. This strategy of generating Ni and C dual active sites by introducing lattice N greatly accelerates oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics, resulting in excellent electrocatalytic performance of N&#9472;Ni&#169;NC. At the current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , the overpotentials of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and OER are 27 and 206 mV, respectively, and the cell voltage for overall water splitting only needs 1.47 V. This work offers a unique heteroatom activation approach for designing free&#8208;standing electrodes with high activity.</description>
      <author>Nian-Dan Zhao, Wei Luo, Sijun Li, Hua Wang, Yini Mao, Yimin Jiang, Wenbin Wang, Ming Li, Wei&#8208;Fang Su, Rongxing He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Excess Hydrogen Output via Concurrent Electrochemical and Chemical Redox Reactions on P&#8208;Doped Co&#8208;Based Catalysts with Electron Manipulation and Kinetic Regulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406288</link>
      <description>Yue Yao, Menghui Qi, Liang Chen, Enlai Hu, Haotian Cai, Defa Gu, Li Wang, Yuanjing Cui, Guodong Qian, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404617882

                Abstract Electrolytic hydrogen production is of great significance in energy conversion and sustainable development. Traditional electrolytic water splitting confronts high anode voltage with oxygen generation and the amount of hydrogen produced at cathode depends entirely on the quantity of electric charge input. Herein, excess hydrogen output can be achieved by constructing a spontaneous hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR) coupled hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) system. For the hydrazine oxidation&#8208;assisted electrolyzer in this work, both the external input electrons and the electrons produced by spontaneous chemical redox reaction can reduce water, producing more hydrogen than traditional electrolytic water splitting system. The ultrafast kinetics of bifunctional P&#8208;doped Co&#8208;based catalysts plays a key role in the spontaneous feature of HzOR/HER redox reaction and low working voltage of hydrazine oxidation&#8208;assisted electrolyzer (12 mV@100 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Theoretical calculation results and ex situ/in situ spectra demonstrate that doped P could optimize electronic structure, regulate adsorption energy of intermediates, and thus endows catalysts with ultrafast kinetics. This work provides a new pathway for the development of spontaneous oxidation&#8208;assisted hydrogen production, to achieve excess hydrogen output via concurrent electrochemical and chemical redox reactions.</description>
      <author>Yue Yao, Menghui Qi, Liang Chen, Enlai Hu, Haotian Cai, Defa Gu, Li Wang, Yuanjing Cui, Guodong Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Perovskite Oxides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Structures, Mechanisms, and Strategies for Performance Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416705</link>
      <description>Xiong Sun, Ying Yuan, Shuzhi Liu, Hongqing Zhao, Suqiang Yao, Sun Yuying, Shouxin Zhang, Yijiang Liu, Zhiqun Lin, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404618145

                Abstract Perovskite&#8208;type oxides are widely employed as oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts due to their tunable composition, diverse structure, abundant natural reserves, remarkable stability, and low cost. The intrinsic OER electrocatalytic activity of these perovskite oxides is generally enhanced by improving conductivity, increasing specific surface area, and optimizing the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates. This is achieved through rationally designed strategies, including compositional engineering, defect engineering, hybridization, and surface regulation. In this review, recent advances in perovskite oxides for OER are summarized, with a focus on exploring structure&#8208;performance relationships. This review provides a brief introduction to the application of perovskite oxides in OER, followed by the classification and characteristics of these perovskite oxides. The primary OER catalytic mechanisms, and well&#8208;established activity descriptors are discussed. The key strategies are concentrated for enhancing OER activity, including composition engineering, defect engineering, hybridization, and surface reconstruction. Finally, the challenges and opportunities in developing high&#8208;performance perovskite oxides as OER electrocatalysts are presented.</description>
      <author>Xiong Sun, Ying Yuan, Shuzhi Liu, Hongqing Zhao, Suqiang Yao, Sun Yuying, Shouxin Zhang, Yijiang Liu, Zhiqun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416705</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering for Improved Large&#8208;Current Oxygen Evolution via Partial Phosphorization of Ce&#8208;MOF/NiCo&#8208;MOF Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408897</link>
      <description>Dan Li&#250;, Xuewen Xia, Xue&#8208;Qiang Zhang, Fei Wang, Tao Li, Ya Gao, Shujuan Wang, Zhongya Pang, Yu Xing, Guangshi Li, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Shen Hu, Ji Li, Xionggang Lu, Xingli Zou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404618356

                Abstract Interface engineering for electrocatalysts has proven to be an effective method for modulating electrocatalytic properties, yet a more efficient and straightforward strategy to construct a valid heterointerface for further enhancing interface effects is urgently needed for boosting oxygen evolution reactions (OER) at large current. Herein, a closely compacted heterostructure combining NiCo&#8208;metal&#8208;organic framework (MOF) and Ce&#8208;MOF is in situ formed through a one&#8208;step hydrothermal treatment, and partial phosphorization is employed to further enhance the interface effect between the newly formed urchin&#8208;shaped NiCoP shells and hexagonal rod&#8208;like Ce&#8208;MOF cores on nickel foam (NiCoP/Ce&#8208;MOF@NF). Experimental and theoretical results indicate that the heterogeneous NiCoP/Ce&#8208;MOF@NF, characterized by a more intensive interface rather than a simple physical mixture, generates an OER&#8208;beneficial electronic structure, significantly facilitates charge transfer and reaction kinetics, and creates a synergistically stable structure. The optimal NiCoP/Ce&#8208;MOF@NF exhibits remarkable electrocatalytic activity for OER, achieving an ultralow overpotential of 268 mV at a current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 , and also delivers satisfactory large&#8208;current stability of up to 120 h. This work offers a novel approach for designing heterogeneous catalysts with strong interface effects for potential applications in industrial water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Dan Li&#250;, Xuewen Xia, Xue&#8208;Qiang Zhang, Fei Wang, Tao Li, Ya Gao, Shujuan Wang, Zhongya Pang, Yu Xing, Guangshi Li, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Shen Hu, Ji Li, Xionggang Lu, Xingli Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rare-Earth Elements Doped NiFe-MOFs as Efficient and Robust Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Both Alkaline Freshwater and Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06574c</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Jing Wang, Jiahui Xian, Runan Xiang, Guangqin Li, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404619733

                Based on the target of carbon neutrality, it is very important to explore highly active and durable electrocatalysts for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here,...</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Jing Wang, Jiahui Xian, Runan Xiang, Guangqin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc06574c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Chalcogenide&#8208;Derived NiFe2O4 as Highly Efficient and Stable Anode for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403198</link>
      <description>Husileng Lee, Guoheng Ding, Linqin Wang, Licheng Sun, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404619914

                Developing low&#8208;cost, highly active, and durable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrodes is one of the critical scientific issues for anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEM&#8208;WE). Herein, we report a vacancy&#8208;rich and alkali&#8208;stable NiFe2O4&#8208;type electrode (named as NiFeOx&#8208;350&#8208;Ov), derived from the chemical&#8208;vapor deposited precursor NiFeSexSy&#8208;350, as an efficient and robust anode material. The obtained electrode affords current densities of 100 and 500 mA cm&#8722;2 at overpotentials of 245 and 270 mV, respectively, and displays excellent long&#8208;term durability sustaining 1.0 A cm&#8722;2 at least for 1000 h. When coupled with Ni4Mo/MoO2/NF as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst, the resulting platinum group metal (PGM)&#8208;free single&#8208;cell AEM&#8208;WE exhibits a cell voltage of 1.71 V at the current density of 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 at 80 &#176;C and long&#8208;term durability during a current&#8208;cycling test between 0.5 and 1.0 A cm&#8722;2 over 150 h at 60 &#176;C. This work highlights a unique reconstruction strategy for preparing highly active and durable OER catalysts used in PGM&#8208;free AEM&#8208;WE.</description>
      <author>Husileng Lee, Guoheng Ding, Linqin Wang, Licheng Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Zhang, Xuanyu Zhou, Kongliang Luo, Yaning Fan, Chuandong He, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404620648

                Developing efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts was urgent for producing clean hydrogen energy. High-entropy oxides (HEOs) have become a focus of interest, were widely used for OER. HEOs would...</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Zhang, Xuanyu Zhou, Kongliang Luo, Yaning Fan, Chuandong He, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological&#8203; Evolution and Crystal Plane Effects of Spinel Nico2o4 Catalyst on Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030028</link>
      <description>Qimei Liang, Yihui Liu, Yan Dong, Liuyang Bai, Hui Kang, Chao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404621038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qimei Liang, Yihui Liu, Yan Dong, Liuyang Bai, Hui Kang, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameterization and quantification of two key operando physio-chemical descriptors for water-assisted electro-catalytic organic oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54318-7</link>
      <description>Bailin Tian, Fangyuan Wang, Pan Ran, Luhan Dai, Jing Wang, Yuxia Sun, Zhangyan Mu, Yamei Sun, Lingyu Tang, William A. Goddard, Mengning Ding, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404623942

                Electro-selective-oxidation using water as a green oxygen source demonstrates promising potential towards efficient and sustainable chemical upgrading. However, surface micro-kinetics regarding co-adsorption and reaction between organic and oxygen intermediates remain unclear. Here we systematically study the electro-oxidation of aldehydes, alcohols, and amines on Co/Ni-oxyhydroxides with multiple characterizations. Utilizing Fourier transformed alternating current voltammetry (FTacV) measurements, we show the identification and quantification of two key operando parameters (&#916;Iharmonics/IOER and &#916;Vharmonics) that can be fundamentally linked to the altered surface coverage ( $$\Delta {\theta }_{{{{{\rm{OH}}}}}^{*}}/{\theta }_{{{{{\rm{OH}}}}}^{*}}^{{{{\rm{OER}}}}}$$ ) and the changes in adsorption energy of vital oxygenated intermediates ( $${\Delta G}_{{{{\rm{OH}}}}*}^{{{{\rm{EOOR}}}}}-{\Delta G}_{{{{\rm{OH}}}}*}^{{{{\rm{OER}}}}}$$ ), under the influence of organic adsorption/oxidation. Mechanistic analysis based on these descriptors reveals distinct optimal oxyhydroxide surface states for each organics, and elucidates the critical catalyst design principles: balancing organic and M3+&#948;&#8722;OH* coverages and fine-tuning &#916;G for key elementary steps, e.g., via precise modulation of chemical compositions, crystallinity, defects, electronic structures, and/or surface bimolecular interactions. Water-assisted electro-catalytic selective oxidation is promising for sustainable production of value-added chemicals. Here the authors quantify two key physio-chemical parameters for efficient mechanistic investigation and rational catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Bailin Tian, Fangyuan Wang, Pan Ran, Luhan Dai, Jing Wang, Yuxia Sun, Zhangyan Mu, Yamei Sun, Lingyu Tang, William A. Goddard, Mengning Ding</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54318-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A dual-phase PtNiCuMnMo high-entropy alloy as high-performance electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161865</link>
      <description>Fang Miao, Tongheng Wang, Zhiyuan Jing, Bin Zhang, Jun Wang, Tao Gu, Zhijie Yan, Xiubing Liang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404626182

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fang Miao, Tongheng Wang, Zhiyuan Jing, Bin Zhang, Jun Wang, Tao Gu, Zhijie Yan, Xiubing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilizing Cationic Vacancy Defects to Switch Oxygen Evolution Mechanisms on Atomically Dispersed Ru for Enhanced Acidic Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124845</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Deshuai Yang, Zhen Yang, Lili Wang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404628614

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Deshuai Yang, Zhen Yang, Lili Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous amorphous high entropy oxide coated dimensionally stable anode for oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161882</link>
      <description>Wushuai Dai, Lei Wang, Keyi Li, Wei Wang, Yunlong Bai, Feng Xie, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wushuai Dai, Lei Wang, Keyi Li, Wei Wang, Yunlong Bai, Feng Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress in advanced design of iridium&#8208;based and ruthenium&#8208;based perovskite catalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.79</link>
      <description>Yuqing Cheng, Yibo Wang, Zhaoping Shi, Hongxiang Wu, Jiahao Yang, Jing Ni, Ming Yang, Ziang Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631203

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is of great importance for the production of green hydrogen. The large&#8208;scale implementation of PEMWE, however, is seriously impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode, which results in considerable overpotential and thus the decreased energy conversion efficiency. To overcome this problem, researchers have extensively explored efficient anode catalysts that possess high activity and prolonged stability. Up to now, Ir&#8208;based and Ru&#8208;based catalysts are considered to be the most efficient candidates. Especially perovskite&#8208;based catalysts have received intensive attention due to their distinctive structures and exceptional OER catalytic performance. To further promote their practical application, considerable research efforts are devoted to structural engineering toward enhanced activity and stability. In this paper, a review of the research progress on the advanced design of Ir&#8208; and Ru&#8208;based perovskite catalysts is presented, with a focus on phase engineering, doping/substitution, morphology control, and compositing with other materials for perovskite catalysts as well as some preparation methods commonly used. It also summarizes the challenges and opportunities concerning perovskite&#8208;based catalysts in current research, yielding further comprehension of the pertinent preparation and scrutiny of perovskite catalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Cheng, Yibo Wang, Zhaoping Shi, Hongxiang Wu, Jiahao Yang, Jing Ni, Ming Yang, Ziang Wang, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.79</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of electrochromic band-shifts in the Soret region induced by the formation of TyrD, TyrZ, and QA- in Photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.21.624785</link>
      <description>Alain Boussac, Takumi Noguchi, A. William Rutherford, Julien Sell&#233;s, Miwa Sugiura, Stefania Viola, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631459

                The effects of TyrD, TyrZ, and QA- radical formation on the absorption spectrum in the Soret region were studied in Mn-depleted Photosystem II at pH 8.6 (in order to be in the TyrD state after the dark adaptation). Flash-induced difference spectra were recorded in several PSII samples from i) Thermosynechococcus vestitus (formerly T. elongatus), ii) Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803, iii) Chroococcidiopsis thermalis PCC7203 grown under far-red light, and iv) Acaryochloris marina. In the case of T. vestitus, mutants D1/H198Q, D1/T1789H, D2/I178H and D2/Y160F, with PsbA1/Q130 instead of PsbA3/E130, were also studied for possible contributions from PD1, ChlD1, ChlD2 and PheD1, respectively. For a possible contribution from PD2, the D2/H197A mutant was studied in S. 6803. While PD1 is clearly the species whose spectrum is blue shifted by ~ 3 nm in the presence of QA-, as already well documented in the literature, the species whose spectra are shifted upon the formation of TyrD, and TyrZ remain to be clearly identified as they appear different from PD1, PD2, PheD1, ChlD1 and ChlD2 as concluded by the lack of different light-induced difference spectra in the mutants listed above. Although we cannot rule out too weak effect taking into account the accuracy of the experiments, it is proposed that other pigments are involved as antenna Chl and/or Car near the reaction center. Additionally, it is shown that, i) there is no proton release into the bulk upon the oxidation of TyrD at pH 8.6, and ii) the rearrangement of the electrostatic environment of the pigments involved in the light-induced different spectra in the samples studied upon the formation TyrD, TyrZ, and QA- likely occur differently on a kinetic and structural point of views.</description>
      <author>Alain Boussac, Takumi Noguchi, A. William Rutherford, Julien Sell&#233;s, Miwa Sugiura, Stefania Viola</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.21.624785</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Electronic Correlations in Ruthenium Oxides for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00068</link>
      <description>Xianbing Miao, Jingda Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Shiming Zhou, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404632938

                Elucidating the electronic factors dominating the adsorption properties of transition-metal oxides is essential to construct highly efficient oxygen-evolving catalysts for hydrogen production by water splitting but remains a great challenge. Electron correlation from on-site Coulomb repulsion (U) among d-electrons is generally believed to significantly affect the electronic structure of these materials; however, it has long been neglected in studying their adsorption properties. Here, by choosing ruthenium oxide as a model system, we demonstrate the role of electron correlation on the electrocatalytic activity toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Our density functional theory plus U calculations on rutile RuO2 reveal that the electron correlation can tune the adsorption energies for oxygenated intermediate and optimize them after the metallic oxide being a Mott insulator upon increasing U. By regulating the RuO6 octahedral network, we constructed and synthesized a series of strongly correlated ruthenium oxides, where the Mott insulating ones indeed exhibit a superior OER performance to the metallic RuO2. Our work builds a bridge between the electrochemistry and Mott physics for transition-metal oxides, opening a new avenue for designing advanced catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xianbing Miao, Jingda Zhang, Zhenpeng Hu, Shiming Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Ru nanoclusters in tandem with single atoms on oxygen-vacancy regulated CeO2 for anion exchange membrane seawater-splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.017</link>
      <description>Yan Wang, Jing Li, Pengfei Yang, Hongdong Li, Guangrui Xu, Yunmei Du, Caixia Li, Wei Jin, Tianyi Ma, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404633981

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Wang, Jing Li, Pengfei Yang, Hongdong Li, Guangrui Xu, Yunmei Du, Caixia Li, Wei Jin, Tianyi Ma, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.11.017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and application of a liquid metal ball-supported layered double hydroxide core&#8211;shell structure as highly efficient catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction in rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157924</link>
      <description>Liqing Qiao, Wenwei Liu, Na Du, Ying Wang, Yankun Li, Haijun Wu, Zhonghua Bao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404634694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liqing Qiao, Wenwei Liu, Na Du, Ying Wang, Yankun Li, Haijun Wu, Zhonghua Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electron Donation from Carbon Support Enhances the Activity and Stability of Ultrasmall Ruo2 Nanoparticles in Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030506</link>
      <description>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luo Huang, Lixia Ma, Jie Yang, Jianghao Kang, Yu Chen, Junqing Yan, Yunpeng Fang, Li Deng, Ruibin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5030506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic modulation of CoFe sites for advanced bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100470</link>
      <description>Ju-Hong Zhou, Hui Zhao, Ping Han, Ruizi Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Xiaoxia Mao, Konglin Wu, Shengjue Deng, Wenxiang He, Binbin Jiang, Chinese Journal of Structural Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635846

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ju-Hong Zhou, Hui Zhao, Ping Han, Ruizi Wang, Shouxin Zhang, Xiaoxia Mao, Konglin Wu, Shengjue Deng, Wenxiang He, Binbin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100470</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An oxycarbide-derived-carbon supported nickel ferrite/copper tungstate ternary composite for enhanced electrocatalytic activity towards the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02688h</link>
      <description>Kumar Sanket, Uttam Kumar, Indrajit Sinha, Shantanu K. Behera, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404637944

                This work integrates a unique porous carbon with a binary heterostructured NiFe 2 O 4 /CuWO 4 composite to enhance electrocatalytic activity towards the oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Kumar Sanket, Uttam Kumar, Indrajit Sinha, Shantanu K. Behera</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02688h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution on Flexible Catalysts Based on Nickel&#8211;Iron Coatings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120843</link>
      <description>Dmytro Shyshkin, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Dijana &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Zita Sukackien&#279;, J&#363;rat&#279; Vai&#269;i&#363;nien&#279;, Birut&#279; &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;-Stanynien&#279;, Antanas Nacys, Eugenijus Norkus, Catalysts. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404639176

                The electrolysis of water is one of low-cost green hydrogen production technologies. The main challenge regarding this technology is designing and developing low-cost and high-activity catalysts. Herein, we present a strategy to fabricate flexible electrocatalysts based on nickel&#8211;iron (NiFe) alloy coatings. NiFe coatings were plated on the flexible copper-coated polyimide surface (Cu/PI) using the low-cost and straightforward electroless metal-plating method, with morpholine borane as a reducing agent. It was found that Ni90Fe10, Ni80Fe20, Ni60Fe40, and Ni30Fe70 coatings were deposited on the Cu/PI surface; then, the concentration of Fe2+ in the plating solution was 0.5, 1, 5, and 10 mM, respectively. The morphology, structure, and composition of NixFey/Cu/PI catalysts have been examined using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and inductively coupled plasma&#8211;optical emission spectroscopy (ICP-OES), whereas their activity has been investigated for hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions in 1 M KOH using linear sweep voltammetry (LSVs). It was found that the Ni80Fe20/Cu/PI catalyst exhibited the lowest overpotential value of &#8722;202.7 mV for the HER, obtaining a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 compared to Ni90Fe10/Cu/PI (&#8722;211.9 mV), Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI (&#8722;276.3 mV), Ni30Fe70/Cu/PI (&#8722;278.4 mV), and Ni (&#8722;303.4 mV). On the other hand, the lowest OER overpotential (344.7 mV) was observed for the Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI catalyst, obtaining a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 compared to the Ni35Fe65 (369.9 mV), Ni80Fe20 (450.2 mV), and Ni90Fe10 (454.2 mV) coatings, and Ni (532.1 mV). The developed Ni60Fe40/Cu/PI catalyst exhibit a cell potential of 1.85 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The obtained catalysts seem to be suitable flexible catalysts for HER and OER in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Dmytro Shyshkin, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Dijana &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Zita Sukackien&#279;, J&#363;rat&#279; Vai&#269;i&#363;nien&#279;, Birut&#279; &#352;imk&#363;nait&#279;-Stanynien&#279;, Antanas Nacys, Eugenijus Norkus</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14120843</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404647545

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404647569

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O&#9472;O Radical Coupling in Ultrathin Reconstructed Co6.8Se8 Nanosheets for Effective Oxygen Evolution and Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419083</link>
      <description>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Chengyuan Dong, Xiaohui Peng, Yousef Ibraheem, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Laura Simonelli, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Yizhong Lu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404651304

                Designing ultrathin transition metal electrocatalysts with optimal surface chemistry state is crucial for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the structure&#8208;dependent electrochemical performance and the underlying catalytic mechanisms are still not clearly distinguished. Herein, we synthesize ultrathin Co6.8Se8 nanosheets (NSs) with subnanometer thickness by incorporating catalytically inactive selenium (Se) into ultrathin Co(OH)2, thereby switching the OER reaction pathway from adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) to oxide path mechanism (OPM). The prepared ultrathin Co6.8Se8 NSs exhibit an overpotential of 253 mV at 10 mA/cm2, outperforming the mostly reported Co&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Advanced operando synchrotron spectroscopies and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy reveal the ultrathin Co6.8Se8 NSs, whose surface is reconstructed into Se&#8208;doped Co(OH)2 during the OER process, could trigger direct O*&#8208;O* radical coupling rather than OOH* intermediates within AEM pathway thus lowering the energy input. Density functional theory calculations confirm that Co6.8Se8 NSs with shorter Co&#8208;Co bond length and stable Co&#8208;Se bond could optimize the rate&#8208;determining step barrier via OPM pathway. Besides, rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries based on Co6.8Se8 NSs exhibit excellent stability for more than 500 h of continuous charge&#8208;discharge cycles at 4 mA/cm2. The present study highlights the structural&#8208;dependent switch of OER pathways and provides valuable insights for further development of ultrathin OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Chengyuan Dong, Xiaohui Peng, Yousef Ibraheem, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Laura Simonelli, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Yizhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>O&#9472;O Radical Coupling in Ultrathin Reconstructed Co6.8Se8 Nanosheets for Effective Oxygen Evolution and Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419083</link>
      <description>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Chengyuan Dong, Xiaohui Peng, Yousef Ibraheem, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Laura Simonelli, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Yizhong Lu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404651398

                Designing ultrathin transition metal electrocatalysts with optimal surface chemistry state is crucial for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the structure&#8208;dependent electrochemical performance and the underlying catalytic mechanisms are still not clearly distinguished. Herein, we synthesize ultrathin Co6.8Se8 nanosheets (NSs) with subnanometer thickness by incorporating catalytically inactive selenium (Se) into ultrathin Co(OH)2, thereby switching the OER reaction pathway from adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) to oxide path mechanism (OPM). The prepared ultrathin Co6.8Se8 NSs exhibit an overpotential of 253 mV at 10 mA/cm2, outperforming the mostly reported Co&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Advanced operando synchrotron spectroscopies and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy reveal the ultrathin Co6.8Se8 NSs, whose surface is reconstructed into Se&#8208;doped Co(OH)2 during the OER process, could trigger direct O*&#8208;O* radical coupling rather than OOH* intermediates within AEM pathway thus lowering the energy input. Density functional theory calculations confirm that Co6.8Se8 NSs with shorter Co&#8208;Co bond length and stable Co&#8208;Se bond could optimize the rate&#8208;determining step barrier via OPM pathway. Besides, rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries based on Co6.8Se8 NSs exhibit excellent stability for more than 500 h of continuous charge&#8208;discharge cycles at 4 mA/cm2. The present study highlights the structural&#8208;dependent switch of OER pathways and provides valuable insights for further development of ultrathin OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Chengyuan Dong, Xiaohui Peng, Yousef Ibraheem, Oleg A. Usoltsev, Laura Simonelli, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Yizhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CRADA: Development and Commercialization of a Nanosegrated Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2172/2478157</link>
      <description>Xiong Peng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404652091

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiong Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2172/2478157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404653580

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404653843

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "High entropy spinel oxide (Ni0.2Co0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2Mg0.2)Fe2O4 nanofibers for efficient oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404653928

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06051b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orientation-modulated oxygen evolution reaction in epitaxial SrRuO3 films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05379f</link>
      <description>Shencheng Pan, Lianjin Wei, Junlong Xie, Zhenjie Lu, Jiajia Yuan, Tian Tang, Leichao Meng, Xin Wang, Junwu Zhu, Yongsheng Fu, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404542725

                The SrRuO3 films were grown on SrTiO3 using a lattice matching strategy. Scanning electrochemical microscopy imaged local oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, exploring the relationship between micro-area activity and the...</description>
      <author>Shencheng Pan, Lianjin Wei, Junlong Xie, Zhenjie Lu, Jiajia Yuan, Tian Tang, Leichao Meng, Xin Wang, Junwu Zhu, Yongsheng Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05379f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distorted MO6 octahedral unit on the activity and stability for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04992f</link>
      <description>Huaixin Yang, Xin Ning, W. B. Yan, Hua Gui Yang, Haiyang Yuan, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404635654

                Metal oxides have garnered significant attention in oxygen evolution reaction (OER), where the distorted MO6 octahedral unit has a marked impact on their performance. This study introduces the distortion coefficient...</description>
      <author>Huaixin Yang, Xin Ning, W. B. Yan, Hua Gui Yang, Haiyang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04992f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening on azafullerene-supported bifunctional single-atom catalysts for oxygen evolution and reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03608e</link>
      <description>Mo Xiong, Tao Yang, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404503126

                Developing efficient bifunctional catalysts toward both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains challenging. Herein, we systematically explored the catalytic activity of single-atom catalysts (SACs) for OER...</description>
      <author>Mo Xiong, Tao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03608e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe/Co bimetallic borides with modified electronic structure for Efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161893</link>
      <description>Shuai Wan, Lihong Bao, Yuyang Zong, Jiayu Xiao, Jiaru He, Xinyu Gao, Sheng Wang, Ruguang Ma, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631327

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Wan, Lihong Bao, Yuyang Zong, Jiayu Xiao, Jiaru He, Xinyu Gao, Sheng Wang, Ruguang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161893</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and kinetic analysis of the oxygen evolution reaction on TiO2 (100) and (101) surfaces: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122654</link>
      <description>Felipe Marinho Fernandes, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, M&#225;rcio Soares Pereira, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva, Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404642081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Felipe Marinho Fernandes, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, M&#225;rcio Soares Pereira, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susc.2024.122654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Reconfiguration and activation induced by characteristic migration of transition metal-ions between interfaces of high-entropy oxygen evolution catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404582706

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00772g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Similarity between oxygen evolution in photosystem II and oxygen reduction in cytochrome c oxidase via proton coupled electron transfers. A unified view of the oxygenic life from four electron oxidation&#8211;reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43630-024-00648-w</link>
      <description>K. Yamaguchi, Koichi Miyagawa, Mitsuo Shoji, Hiroshi Isobe, Takashi Kawakami, Photochemical &amp; Photobiological Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404611030

                Abstract Basic concepts and theoretical foundations of broken symmetry (BS) and post BS methods for strongly correlated electron systems (SCES) such as electron-transfer (ET) diradical, multi-center polyradicals with spin frustration are described systematically to elucidate structures, bonding and reactivity of the high-valent transition metal oxo bonds in metalloenzymes: photosystem II (PSII) and cytochrome c oxidase (C c O). BS hybrid DFT (HDFT) and DLPNO coupled-cluster (CC) SD(T 0 ) computations are performed to elucidate electronic and spin states of CaMn 4 O x cluster in the key step for oxygen evolution, namely S 4 [S 3 with Mn(IV) = O + Tyr161-O radical] state of PSII and P M [Fe(IV) = O + HO-Cu(II) + Tyr161-O radical] step for oxygen reduction in C c O. The cycle of water oxidation catalyzed by the CaMn 4 O x cluster in PSII and the cycle of oxygen reduction catalyzed by the Cu A -Fe a -Fe a3 -Cu B cluster in C c O are examined on the theoretical grounds, elucidating similar concerted and/or stepwise proton transfer coupled electron transfer (PT-ET) processes for the four-electron oxidation in PSII and four-electron reduction in C c O. Interplay between theory and experiments have revealed that three electrons in the metal sites and one electron in tyrosine radical site are characteristic for PT-ET in these biological redox reaction systems, indicating no necessity of harmful Mn(V) = O and Fe(V) = O bonds with strong oxyl-radical character. Implications of the computational results are discussed in relation to design of artificial systems consisted of earth abundant transition metals for water oxidation. Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>K. Yamaguchi, Koichi Miyagawa, Mitsuo Shoji, Hiroshi Isobe, Takashi Kawakami</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43630-024-00648-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;High performance graphene oxide/NiAl2O4 directly grown on carbon cloth hybrid for oxygen evolution reaction&#8221; [Int. J. Hydrogen Energy 47, Issue 81, (22 September 2022), 34299&#8211;34311]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.087</link>
      <description>Salma Aman, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Rabia Yasmin Khosa, KhaledA. Elsayed, Khaled H. Mahmoud, T.A. Taha, Muhammad Suleman Waheed, Muhammad Abdullah, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 95(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404572387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Salma Aman, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Rabia Yasmin Khosa, KhaledA. Elsayed, Khaled H. Mahmoud, T.A. Taha, Muhammad Suleman Waheed, Muhammad Abdullah</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retraction notice to "Promoting highly dispersed Co3O4 nanoparticles onto polyethyne unraveling the catalytic mechanism with stable catalytic activity for oxygen evolution reaction: From fundamentals to applications" [Int J Hydrogen Energy 46 (71) (2021) 35261&#8211;35270, 33170]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.350</link>
      <description>Abdul Qayoom Mugheri, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404515459

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Qayoom Mugheri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchoring ZnIn2S4 nanosheets on oxygen-vacancy NiMoOx nanorods for efficient photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130608</link>
      <description>Meng Liu, Jie Xiong, Delong Kong, H. Liu, WU Hong-wei, Fengli Li, Hengyu Hu, Dengfeng Wang, Xiangwei Guo, Yingying Jiao, Zhiming Zhang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404517433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meng Liu, Jie Xiong, Delong Kong, H. Liu, WU Hong-wei, Fengli Li, Hengyu Hu, Dengfeng Wang, Xiangwei Guo, Yingying Jiao, Zhiming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.130608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput screening of the oxygen reduction/evolution reactions catalyst supported on covalent organic framework doped by main group metal using a constant potential method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.210</link>
      <description>Yu Jin, Daoxiong Wu, Wenjun Xiao, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Jinshun Bi, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Yaqiong Su, Xuefei Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 94(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404524547

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Jin, Daoxiong Wu, Wenjun Xiao, Gang Wang, Degui Wang, Jinshun Bi, Mingqiang Liu, Wu Yan, Abuduwayiti Aierken, Xuan Chen, Yaqiong Su, Xuefei Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.210</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in noble-metal-free bifunctional oxygen electrode catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00551a</link>
      <description>Hengqi Liu, Rui Xiong, Shengyu Ma, Ran Wang, Zhiguo Liu, Tai Yao, Bo Song, Energy Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404486799

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial reactions in a range of energy storage. However, the sluggish rate of these oxidation electrode reactions and the...</description>
      <author>Hengqi Liu, Rui Xiong, Shengyu Ma, Ran Wang, Zhiguo Liu, Tai Yao, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00551a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically engineered layer of &#947;-NiOOH with FeOOH on nickel foam for durable OER catalysis for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00538d</link>
      <description>Sreekanth Narayanaru, Hidenori Kuroki, Takanori Tamaki, Gopinathan M. Anilkumar, Takeo Yamaguchi, RSC Sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404503374

                An efficient and durable oxygen evolution reaction catalyst is essential for the advancement of anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Here we report a simple, rapid, and cost-effective two-step electrochemical synthesis...</description>
      <author>Sreekanth Narayanaru, Hidenori Kuroki, Takanori Tamaki, Gopinathan M. Anilkumar, Takeo Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4su00538d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrocatalytic glucose oxidation coupled water electrolysis driven by the Ni-foam supported Ni-P nanowire arrays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06649a</link>
      <description>Hezhen Lou, Yikai Yang, Xiuming Bu, Haoxin Fan, Duo Weng, Jian Zhang, Wei Gao, Dan Wen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404533401

                Using the thermodynamically favorable glucose oxidation reaction (GOR) to replace oxygen evolution reaction (OER) not only enables energy-efficient hydrogen production but also yields high-value products for water electrolysis. Herein, self-supported...</description>
      <author>Hezhen Lou, Yikai Yang, Xiuming Bu, Haoxin Fan, Duo Weng, Jian Zhang, Wei Gao, Dan Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06649a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Hydroxide&#8211;Organic Framework Mediated Structural Reengineering Enables Efficient NiFe Interaction for Robust Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c04815</link>
      <description>Hanxiao Liao, Kejun Chen, Xiaorong He, Jiaxin Tong, Xuanzhi Liu, Pengfei Tan, Xueyi Guo, Yongjin Ma, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404535109

                NiFe layered double hydroxide (NiFe LDH) derived oxyhydroxides are promising electrocatalysts for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, NiFe LDH with a stable metal-oxygen-metal (M-O-M) structure suffers from inadequate NiFe interaction, leading to undesirable activity and stability. Herein, we develop a NiFe hydroxide-organic framework (NiFe HOF) via modification of NiFe LDH with an organic linker to break the structural constraint of M-O-M and thus boost the OER. NiFe HOF with reconfigurable metal sites facilitates structural reengineering under the OER condition to form abundant NiFe interaction and prolonged M-O bonds, stimulating lattice oxygen mechanism. Therefore, NiFe HOF shows a distinctly decreased overpotential at 50 mA cm</description>
      <author>Hanxiao Liao, Kejun Chen, Xiaorong He, Jiaxin Tong, Xuanzhi Liu, Pengfei Tan, Xueyi Guo, Yongjin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c04815</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MXenes for Energy Storage Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003465768</link>
      <description>Muhammad Rafique, Muhammad Bilal Tahir, Saira Anwar, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404534259

                MXenes for Energy Storage Applications focuses on two-dimensional transition metal carbides and nitrides (MXenes), covering the structure, precursors, types of compositions, and unique properties of MXenes. It highlights various promising applications of MXenes-based materials across different energy fields, such as catalysis and energy conversion, including hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, supercapacitors, batteries, and so forth. This book provides advanced solutions for all the issues and challenges related to energy storage and conversion: It covers a large range of MXenes from their basics to the advancements and their energy applications. It provides a detailed description of the structures, precursors, types of compositions, and unique properties of MXenes. It discusses synthesis techniques of MXenes along with their pros and cons. It summarizes the promising energy applications, including catalysis and electrochemical reactions for hydrogen production to batteries. It briefly explains recent progress, challenges, and practical limitations with proposed solutions. This book is aimed at researchers and graduate students in materials science, chemical engineering, and nanomaterials.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Rafique, Muhammad Bilal Tahir, Saira Anwar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003465768</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Water Splitting via Metal&#8211;Support Redox Interaction in Ce&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;M&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; (M = Co, Ni, Cu)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04683</link>
      <description>Saraswati Roy, Sounak Roy, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404468202

                The efficiency of electrochemical water splitting is constrained by the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which suffers from high energy barriers, sluggish kinetics, and significant overpotential. Designing affordable and efficient electrocatalysts for the OER remains a key goal for advancing the hydrogen economy, with transitional metals like Co, Ni, and Cu gaining significant attention as promising alternatives due to their redox properties, abundance, and economy. The oxidation step of Mn+ &#8594; M(n+1)+ (M = Co, Ni, Cu) is the key intermediate step that produces the active species (M-OOH) formation, and thereby lowers the energy barrier and enhances the kinetics of the OER. However, the oxidation of Mn+ &#8594; M(n+1)+ creates charge-transfer orbitals near the Fermi energy level, which is fundamentally challenging. In this study, through structural and surface analyses, we demonstrate that the highly reducible CeO2 support in the Ce1&#8211;xMxO2&#8722;&#948; solid-solution effectively facilitates the Mn+ &#8594; M(n+1)+ oxidation process and the evolution of lattice oxygen during the OER. Among the three transition metals, the presence of the Ni3+ species along with the surface oxygen vacancy promoted the formation of -OOH surface intermediates and maximized the OER activity in Ce0.95Ni0.05O2&#8722;&#948; catalyst.</description>
      <author>Saraswati Roy, Sounak Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic coupling effect and anionic modulation of CoFeLDH@MXene for triggered and sustained alkaline water/seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401295</link>
      <description>Xiaojie Zhang, Sol-Ji Song, Mengfen Xia, Yi Feng, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404474349

                The application of seawater splitting is crucial for hydrogen production; therefore, efficient electrocatalysts are necessary to prevent chlorine evolution and severe corrosion. A synergistic method is employed on CoFe LDH by integrating a conductive Ti3C2Tx MXene layer and subsequently applying anionic modulation. Robust metal-substrate interaction along with subsequent phosphidation facilitates efficient electron transfer and optimises the electronic structure of Co and Fe sites. The CoFe-P-1000@Ti3C2Tx/CC demonstrates commendable electrochemical performance, requiring overpotentials of 106.6 mV and 276 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at 10 mA cm-2 in 1M KOH electrolyte, while 292 mV is necessary for OER in a simulated seawater electrolyte (1 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl). Furthermore, the CoFe-P-1000@Ti3C2Tx/CC exhibits an encouraging cell voltage of 1.59 V (j = 10 mA cm-2) for comprehensive alkaline seawater splitting, maintaining exceptional stability for over 50 hours.</description>
      <author>Xiaojie Zhang, Sol-Ji Song, Mengfen Xia, Yi Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202401295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sputtering induced the architecture of &#8220;needle mushroom&#8221; shaped Cu2O&#8211;NiCo2O4 heterostructure with novel morphology and abundant interface for high-efficiency electrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221991</link>
      <description>Kai Chen, Jaehong Park, Sunny Yadav, Gyu-Cheol Kim, Dung Van Dao, Periyayya Uthirakumar, In&#8208;Hwan Lee, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404474155

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is widely recognized as a bottleneck in the kinetics and activity of decomposition water. Unique geometric design and compositional regulation are important technologies for achieving significant activity and excellent kinetics, but they continue to face obstacles in reaction thermodynamics and kinetic response. Here, a "needle mushroom" shaped Cu2O-NiCo2O4 heterostructure with abundant active sites and optimized conductivity that is grown on the Nickel-foam (NF) (labeled as Cu2O-NiCo2O4/NF-2) is prepared using advanced magnetron sputtering strategies for electrochemical water oxidation. Based on the excellent geometric advantages and efficient charge transfer capabilities, the catalyst of Cu2O-NiCo2O4/NF-2 shows superior electrocatalytic activity (low overpotential) and kinetics (low electrochemical impedance) compared with nanoneedle shaped Cu2O-NiCo2O4/NF-1 and NiCo2O4/NF for OER in alkaline medium. This work demonstrates a practical and economical strategy toward the fabrication of ternary transition metal oxides for water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Kai Chen, Jaehong Park, Sunny Yadav, Gyu-Cheol Kim, Dung Van Dao, Periyayya Uthirakumar, In&#8208;Hwan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221991</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Performance and Kinetic Behavior of Anion&#8208;Intercalated Borate&#8208;Based NiFe LDH in Alkaline OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400457</link>
      <description>Maike Berger, Alexandra Markus, Stefan Palkovits, Regina Palkovits, ChemElectroChem. 11(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404505818

                Abstract The synthesis of hydrogen via water electrolysis is an important step towards resolving the energy crisis and impeding global warming, as hydrogen can be used as a green energy carrier. The oxygen evolution as one half&#8208;cell reaction (OER) is currently limiting efficient water splitting due to kinetic inhibition as well as a complex mechanism, causing a large overpotential. Nickel&#8208;iron layered double hydroxides (LDH) were found to be suitable OER catalysts, as they are cost effective, stable and highly active. This work focuses on the intercalation of different organic and inorganic borates into the LDH interlayers to study their influence on OER. Besides activity and stability measurements, three borate candidates were chosen for a kinetic study, including steady&#8208;state Tafel analysis and reaction order plots. It was found that the Bockris pathway with the second step as rate&#8208;determining step was predominant for all three catalysts. Of all candidates, the intercalation of borate resulted in the highest performance, which was associated with a high reducibility affecting the active metal sites.</description>
      <author>Maike Berger, Alexandra Markus, Stefan Palkovits, Regina Palkovits</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lateral size dependence of photoconductivity in TMD networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-648x/ad965a</link>
      <description>Daniel Olaya-Cortes, Liliana Ramos-Moreno, Tomas Rubio Cruz, Juan Pablo Pablo Pab&#243;n Londo&#241;o, Yenny Hern&#225;ndez, Journal of Physics Condensed Matter. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404623680

                Abstract Photoconductivity is an important feature of semiconductors that finds major attention in the fields of solar cells, hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions, and photodetectors. This feature involves a change of density of charge carriers induced by light, which is dependent on the generation of light-induced carriers and the recombination of excitons. This phenomenon has been observed in transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) since 2010; however, when printing such materials on flexible substrates, they form networks that would exhibit distinct transport characteristics compared to isolated TMDs crystals. In this work, TMD nanosheets are printed by vacuum filtering and their photoconductivity was measured by using a xenon lamp inside an obscure chamber. Molybdenum disulfide-based devices show higher responsivity as compared with tungsten disulfide devices, which is attributed to an increased light absorption and hydroxyl groups attached to the surface of the MoS$_2$ networks that enhance the photoconductivity by increasing the carrier lifetimes. Furthermore, the responsivity of the devices behaves similarly to the conductivity, which is modeled as networks of pairs of nanosheets and junctions through percolative paths. Finally, this is the first report that shows that the response time of the devices increases with lateral size.</description>
      <author>Daniel Olaya-Cortes, Liliana Ramos-Moreno, Tomas Rubio Cruz, Juan Pablo Pablo Pab&#243;n Londo&#241;o, Yenny Hern&#225;ndez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-648x/ad965a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical insights on potential-dependent oxidation behaviors and antioxidant strategies of MXenes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54455-z</link>
      <description>Yumiao Tian, Peng&#8208;Fei Hou, H.Y. Zhang, Yu Xie, Gang Chen, Quan Li, Fei Du, Aleksandra Vojvodi&#263;, Jianzhong Wu, Xing Meng, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404573035

                Significant efforts have been devoted to investigating the oxidation of MXenes in various environments. However, the underlying mechanism of MXene oxidation and its dependence on the electrode potential remain poorly understood. Here we show the oxidation behavior of MXenes under the working conditions of electrochemical processes in terms of kinetics and thermodynamics by using constant-potential ab initio simulations. The theoretical results indicate that the potential effects can be attributed to the nucleophilic attack of water molecules on metal atoms, similar to that taking place in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction. Building upon these findings, we deduced the oxidation potential of the common MXenes, and proposed antioxidant strategies for MXene. Finally, we demonstrated that MBenes, the boron analogs of MXenes, may undergo a similar nucleophilic attack in water and inferred that molecule-induced Walden inversion is widely present in material reconstructions. This work contributes to a fundamental understanding MXene stability at the atomic level, and promotes the transition in materials discovery from trial-and-error synthesis to rational design. MXenes are two-dimensional materials with promising applications, but their oxidation mechanisms under electrochemical conditions are poorly understood. Here, the authors use theoretical simulations to investigate how the oxidation of MXenes is influenced by the electrode potential.</description>
      <author>Yumiao Tian, Peng&#8208;Fei Hou, H.Y. Zhang, Yu Xie, Gang Chen, Quan Li, Fei Du, Aleksandra Vojvodi&#263;, Jianzhong Wu, Xing Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54455-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bismuth sensitized iron oxide on exfoliated graphene oxide (Bi&#8211;Fe2O3@GO) for oxygen evaluation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s11671-024-04146-x</link>
      <description>Akhtar Munir, Shaheer Jamal, Humaira Yasmeen Gondal, Javed Iqbal, Aamir Hussain, Alex Aziz, Muhammad Shahid Nisar, Muhammad Zubair, Abdul Momin, Ali Haider, Discover Nano. 19(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404643210

                Electrochemical water splitting is a promising approach towards a sustainable and renewable energy source. However, the demand for high anodic potential and sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) restrict the efficiency and feasibility of the water-splitting process. In this quest, transition metal oxides and alloys are considered potential candidates owing to their natural occurrence and high redox potential for OER. However, many associated challenges in their use are still there to be addressed. Here, we designed a new class of bismuth-doped iron oxide on exfoliated graphene oxide by optimizing the metal loading on the conductive support to facilitate the flow of charge during catalysis. The catalytic ability of the synthesized Bi-doped nanocomposites was evaluated in activating the OER under extreme alkaline conditions (1 MKOH). On screening different combinations, 20Bi&#8211;Fe2O3@GO was identified as the most efficient and sustainable electrocatalyst even under harsh operating conditions, with an onset potential of 1.48 V and a Tafel slope of 65 mV/dec. The current study offers a new class of Bi-doped electrocatalysts, where the precise doping of Bi and the optimized loading of metal was found the key to achieving low onset potential and high current density to initiate OER.</description>
      <author>Akhtar Munir, Shaheer Jamal, Humaira Yasmeen Gondal, Javed Iqbal, Aamir Hussain, Alex Aziz, Muhammad Shahid Nisar, Muhammad Zubair, Abdul Momin, Ali Haider</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s11671-024-04146-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multihybridization for Enhancing Fe&#8208;Ni Bimetal Electrocatalyst in Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403464</link>
      <description>Hongyan Zhang, Hao Zhou, Hua Wang, Yikai Wang, Xuehan Yang, Dan Wu, Yuan Pan, Maoshuai He, Wenxian Wei, Tao Yang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404590423

                Abstract Water electrolysis holds the promise of transforming electric&#8208;power into hydrogen energy through a carbon free process and its widespread application highly depends on anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) efficiency. Transition metal&#8208;based OER catalysts meet the requirements of long&#8208;term development for cost effectiveness, and their performance can be improved by a variety of band electronic structure modulating methods. Herein, a multihybridization strategy is proposed, i.e., p&#8208;d, s&#8208;sp , and d&#8208;d hybridization are emphasized together, which guides the design of an effective vanadium (V), boron (B)&#8208;FeNiP catalyst. Density functional theory analysis reveals the existence of multihybridization and the difference between Fe and Ni in terms of hybridization strength, band configuration, and interfacial charge transfer. Specially, Fe and Ni sites are simultaneously optimized to their highest performance upon the dual B, V incorporation. As a result, the VB&#8208;FeNiP catalyst displays outstanding OER performance, regarding a Tafel slope of 57.64 mV dec &#8722;1 , an overpotential of 175 mV at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , and exceptional stability. Here the synergistic effect of multihybridization in the design of transition metal&#8208;based catalysts is highlighted and the work in pursuit of effective way based on regulating band configuration to developing high performance OER catalysts would be evoked.</description>
      <author>Hongyan Zhang, Hao Zhou, Hua Wang, Yikai Wang, Xuehan Yang, Dan Wu, Yuan Pan, Maoshuai He, Wenxian Wei, Tao Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Two&#8208;Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Electrochemical Glycerol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416178</link>
      <description>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404458317

                Electrochemical glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) is a promising candidate to couple with cathodic reaction, like hydrogen evolution reaction, to produce high&#8208;value product with less energy consumption. Two&#8208;dimensional conjugated metal&#8208;organic frameworks (2D c&#8208;MOFs), comprising square&#8208;planar metal&#8208;coordination motifs (e.g., MO4, M(NH)4, MS4), are notable for their programable active sites, intrinsic charge transport, and excellent stability, making them promising catalyst candidates for GOR. Here, we introduce a novel class of 2D c&#8208;MOFs electrocatalysts, M2[NiPcS8] (M=Co/Ni/Cu), which are synthesized via coordination of octathiolphthalocyaninato nickel (NiPc(SH)8) with various metal centers. Due to a fast kinetic and high activity of CoS4 sites for GOR, the electrocatalytic tests demonstrate that Co2[NiPcS8] supported on carbon paper displays a low GOR potential of 1.35 V vs. RHE at 10 mA cm&#8208;2, significantly reducing the overall water&#8208;electrolysis&#8208;voltage reduction by 0.27 V from oxygen evolution reaction to GOR, thereby outperforming Ni2[NiPcS8] and Cu2[NiPcS8]. Additionally, we have determined that the GOR activity of CoX4 linkage sites varies with different heteroatoms, following an experimentally and theoretically confirmed activity order of CoS4&gt;CoO4&gt;Co(NH)4. The GOR performance of Co2[NiPcS8] not only demonstrate superior performance among non&#8208;noble metal complex, but also provides critical insights on designing high&#8208;performance MOF electrocatalysts upon optimizing the electronic environment of active sites.</description>
      <author>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screened d&#8208;p Orbital Hybridization in Turing Structure of Confined Nickel for Sulfion Oxidation Accelerated Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419572</link>
      <description>Yin Zhu, Shao Wang, Yanxu Chen, Yangyang Zhang, Yafei Feng, Genqiang Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404568505

                The sulfion oxidation reaction (SOR) could offer an energy&#8208;efficient and tech&#8208;economically favorable alternative to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for H2 production. Transition metal (TM) based catalysts have been considered promising candidates for SOR but suffer from limited activity due to the excessive bond strength from TM&#8208;S2&#8208; d&#8208;p orbit coupling. Herein, we propose a feasible strategy of screening direct d&#8208;p orbit hybridization between TM and S2&#8208; by constructing the Turing structure composed of lamellar stacking carbon&#8208;confined nickel nanosheets. The optimized p&#8208;p orbit coupling between electron&#8208;injected carbon and S2&#8208; enables exceptional catalytic activity and stability for sulfion degradation and energy&#8208;efficient yet value&#8208;added H2 production. Specifically, it achieves a current density of 500 mA cm&#8208;2 at an ultralow potential of 0.67 V vs. RHE for alkaline SOR. Theoretical calculations indicate that the electron transfer from Ni imparts metallicity and a higher p&#8208;band center to carbon shells, thereby contributing to optimized p&#8208;p orbit hybridization and a thermodynamically favorable stepwise sulfion degradation. Practically, a two&#8208;electrode flow cell achieves an industrial current density of 1 Acm&#8208;2 at an unprecedented low voltage of 0.91 V while maintaining stability for over 300 hours, and exhibits high productivities of 3.83 and 0.32 kgh&#8208;1m&#8208;2 for sulfur and H2, respectively.</description>
      <author>Yin Zhu, Shao Wang, Yanxu Chen, Yangyang Zhang, Yafei Feng, Genqiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screened d&#8208;p Orbital Hybridization in Turing Structure of Confined Nickel for Sulfion Oxidation Accelerated Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419572</link>
      <description>Yin Zhu, Shao Wang, Yanxu Chen, Yangyang Zhang, Yafei Feng, Genqiang Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404568296

                The sulfion oxidation reaction (SOR) could offer an energy&#8208;efficient and tech&#8208;economically favorable alternative to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for H2 production. Transition metal (TM) based catalysts have been considered promising candidates for SOR but suffer from limited activity due to the excessive bond strength from TM&#8208;S2&#8208; d&#8208;p orbit coupling. Herein, we propose a feasible strategy of screening direct d&#8208;p orbit hybridization between TM and S2&#8208; by constructing the Turing structure composed of lamellar stacking carbon&#8208;confined nickel nanosheets. The optimized p&#8208;p orbit coupling between electron&#8208;injected carbon and S2&#8208; enables exceptional catalytic activity and stability for sulfion degradation and energy&#8208;efficient yet value&#8208;added H2 production. Specifically, it achieves a current density of 500 mA cm&#8208;2 at an ultralow potential of 0.67 V vs. RHE for alkaline SOR. Theoretical calculations indicate that the electron transfer from Ni imparts metallicity and a higher p&#8208;band center to carbon shells, thereby contributing to optimized p&#8208;p orbit hybridization and a thermodynamically favorable stepwise sulfion degradation. Practically, a two&#8208;electrode flow cell achieves an industrial current density of 1 Acm&#8208;2 at an unprecedented low voltage of 0.91 V while maintaining stability for over 300 hours, and exhibits high productivities of 3.83 and 0.32 kgh&#8208;1m&#8208;2 for sulfur and H2, respectively.</description>
      <author>Yin Zhu, Shao Wang, Yanxu Chen, Yangyang Zhang, Yafei Feng, Genqiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Molybdate Oxyanion Boosts Self-Optimization and Self-Healing on the NiMoFe Heterostructure for Water Splitting in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05108</link>
      <description>Qing Zhang, Wei Xiao, Jia Shi, Jing Lei, Qi Xiao, Hong Qun Luo, Nian Bing Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404609586

                NiMo-based alloys and NiFe layered double hydroxides (NiFe-LDHs) are the most promising nonprecious-metal electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER) under alkaline conditions. However, the ready leaching of Mo and Fe during electrolysis may cause dynamic variation of the surface composition and structure of the catalysts. Here, we developed a NiMoFe heterostructure consisting of NiMoFe alloy and MoO42&#8211;-intercalated NiFe-LDH (NiMoFe HI), which enables self-optimization of HER and self-healing of OER through the dynamic exchange of MoO42&#8211; species. During the HER process, the leaching and readsorption of MoO42&#8211; optimizes the electronic structure of NiFe-LDH, facilitating H2O adsorption and dissociation. Simultaneously, the repulsion of OH&#8211; by accumulated MoO42&#8211; in the electric double layer can more rapidly drive the transfer kinetics of *OH + e &#8652; OH&#8211; to promote the desorption of *OH from the active sites, thus continuously enhancing the HER activity. During the OER process, the dynamic equilibrium of MoO42&#8211; facilitates the readsorption of active Fe(OH)x species on the NiFeOOH surface and reduces the energy barrier of the OER rate-determining step, achieving self-healing of the OER activity. Benefiting from the self-optimization and self-healing properties for HER and OER, NiMoFe LDH exhibits promising performance in alkaline water splitting, with a low cell voltage of 1.528 V at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 and stable operation at a high current density of 100 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 for 150 h.</description>
      <author>Qing Zhang, Wei Xiao, Jia Shi, Jing Lei, Qi Xiao, Hong Qun Luo, Nian Bing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalysts in Focus</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.33540/2690</link>
      <description>Thimo Sander Jacobs, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404579679

                The catalytic conversion of CO2 into value-added chemical building blocks is a crucial process towards a more sustainable society. The performance of the catalysts for this conversion process can be tracked using analytical methods, including spectroscopy and microscopy, which can aid towards a better understanding and optimization of these catalyst materials. The length scales of importance for a catalytic reaction vary over multiple orders of magnitude, where each length scale provides additional physicochemical insights into the functioning of the catalyst. Consequently, spectroscopy and microscopy methods need to be applied to this variety of length scales. In this PhD Thesis, we show the development and application of two spectroscopic methods to probe the local temperature and reaction intermediates, namely luminescence thermometry and Raman spectroscopy, at a spatial resolution of 1 &#181;m2 and temporal resolution of seconds. The results described in the different chapters provide a methodological view on the application of these analytical methods and showcase spatially resolved information on the catalytic performance. We optimized the lanthanide-based luminescent thermometer to have optimal signal strength, resulting in low temperature uncertainties. The thermometer particles were used to study the temperature change in two processes: 1) the thermocatalytic CO2 hydrogenation reaction and 2) the electrocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions. We found significant temperature increase upon the introduction of the reactant gasses CO2 and H2 during process 1 due to exothermic reactions at the catalyst surface, as well as temperature variations as a function of current density and electrolyte composition in process 2. Furthermore, the reaction intermediates of the CO2 hydrogenation reaction were studied with plasmonic substrates, for which we provided more robust and homogeneous alternatives based on a combination of atomic layer deposition and lithography. Further progress can be made in the combination of the two analytical methods, as well as more efficient designs of operando reactor cells. This PhD Thesis can be used as a guideline for spatiotemporal spectroscopic studies during catalytic reactions to map out local effects such as temperature and reaction intermediates.</description>
      <author>Thimo Sander Jacobs</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.33540/2690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancies and Ti&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; In-Gap Defects Dictate Photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Generation in BaTiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02142</link>
      <description>Sujana Chandrappa, P. S. Sankara Rama Krishnan, Stephen Nagaraju Myakala, Sreekanth Perumbilavil, C. S. Suchand Sandeep, Murukeshan Vadakke Matham, Dominik Eder, Alexey Cherevan, Dharmapura H. K. Murthy, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404577106

                Ubiquitous oxygen vacancies and mutually correlated Ti3+ defects in ABO3-type perovskite titanate, such as BaTiO3 (BTO), critically impact optoelectronic properties. However, rationally tuning such defects via synthesis routes and obtaining insights into their impact on photocatalytic H2 generation is limited. Herein, the effect of heating as-synthesized BTO in an H2 atmosphere at 400 &#176;C for an hour on the photocatalytic activity is investigated. Such post-synthesis modification did not induce changes in the bulk properties of BTO, such as crystalline phase and optical properties. However, the photocatalytic H2 evolution activity under ultraviolet light decreased by &#8776;1.8 times after the H2 reduction treatment. Under visible light (&#955; &gt; 400 nm) that majorly populates in-gap defects, virtually no photocatalytic activity was observed in BTO after being subjected to the H2 reduction process. This observation is attributed to an enhancement in the density of electron-trapping Ti3+ and oxygen vacancies, revealed via complementary microscopic and spectroscopic tools. Insights from nonlinear optical measurement revealed the location of such electron-trapping in-gap states to be &#8776;0.8 eV below the conduction band of BTO. Results show how vulnerable these defects can be toward reduction treatment with 5% H2 for an hour and its crucial impact on the photocatalytic H2 evolution efficiency. Hence, elucidating the inherent nature of defects and controlling them should be considered as a key parameter in photocatalyst design.</description>
      <author>Sujana Chandrappa, P. S. Sankara Rama Krishnan, Stephen Nagaraju Myakala, Sreekanth Perumbilavil, C. S. Suchand Sandeep, Murukeshan Vadakke Matham, Dominik Eder, Alexey Cherevan, Dharmapura H. K. Murthy</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electro&#8208;Oxidative Extraction of Methanol from Lignin Using a Three&#8208;Dimensional Graphite Anode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400464</link>
      <description>Zhongqiang Xiong, Kazuyo Kobayashi, A. Miyawaki, Shinya Teranishi, Yoshiharu Sawada, Takashi Hibino, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404511861

                Abstract This paper reports an electrochemical approach that uses lignin as a resource for renewable and sustainable methanol production. The aromatic rings of lignin have methoxy substituents, which can be oxidatively demethylated to methanol by active oxygen produced at the anode. A graphite electrode fabricated in a sponge form provided sufficient reaction space for the lignin feedstock, efficiently generated active oxygen species from water, and considerably suppressed the overoxidation of methanol to carbon dioxide. As a result, the methanol yield reached approximately 70 % at a temperature of 75 &#176;C, atmospheric pressure, and anode potential of +0.57 V. Another advantage of this technique is that hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) occurred at the cathode and the cathode potential was held at approximately &#8722;0.5 V during the HER. Therefore, the cell voltage required for lignin electrolysis was 1.1 V or lower, which means that hydrogen as well as methanol was produced under mild conditions.</description>
      <author>Zhongqiang Xiong, Kazuyo Kobayashi, A. Miyawaki, Shinya Teranishi, Yoshiharu Sawada, Takashi Hibino</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerium Dioxide&#8208;Induced Abundant Cu+/Cu0 Sites for Electrocatalytic Reduction of Carbon Dioxide to C2+ Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402097</link>
      <description>Yuwen Wang, Jiajun Wang, Shuang Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Jin Lin, Lanlan Feng, Demeng Kong, Chenxi Zhang, Yajuan Wei, Jingbo Zhang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404474958

                In recent years, the electrochemical reduction of carbon dioxide (CO2RR) has made many advances in C2+ production. Cu+/Cu0 site is beneficial for C&#8208;C coupling process, but the oxidation state of copper cannot be well maintained during the reaction process, resulting in a decrease in catalyst activity. Based on this consideration, in this work, transition metal oxide CeO2 with a hollow cube structure and oxygen vacancies was introduced to stabilize and increase Cu+/Cu0 active sites (Ce1Cu2). The catalyst exhibits excellent CO2RR performance, with FEC2+ achieving 73.52% and jC2+ &gt; 280 mA/cm2 at 1.26 V (vs. RHE). Ethanol is the main C2+ product and FEethanol reaches 39% at 1.26 V. The experimental results indicate that the presence of CeO2 provides a large number of oxygen vacancies and forming Cu+&#8208;O2&#8208;&#8208;Ce4+ structure by the strong interaction of CeO2 and Cu NPs. The structure of Cu+&#8208;O2&#8208;&#8208;Ce4+ and abundant oxygen vacancies lay a good foundation for the CO2 adsorption. Moreover, it increases the content of Cu+/Cu0 sites, effectively inhibiting hydrogen evolution reaction, promoting the C&#8208;C coupling interaction, thereby facilitating the generation of C2+ products. The DFT theoretical calculation further demonstrates that Ce1Cu2 is more inclined towards the ethanol pathway, confirming its high selectivity for ethanol.</description>
      <author>Yuwen Wang, Jiajun Wang, Shuang Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Jin Lin, Lanlan Feng, Demeng Kong, Chenxi Zhang, Yajuan Wei, Jingbo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202402097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Depositional Architecture and Diagenetic Evolution in the Jurassic Carbonates, Trans Indus Ranges, NW Himalayas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min14111170</link>
      <description>Muhammad Jamil, Ihsan Ullah, Hamad ur Rahim, I. Khan, Wahid Abbas, Mohib ur Rehman, Alidu Rashid, Muhammad Umar, Asad Ali, Numair Ahmed Siddiqui, Minerals. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404486903

                The evolution of Jurassic carbonates is globally significant for understanding the depositional framework, diagenetic phases and sedimentary characteristics of shallow marine shelf deposits. For this purpose, two outcrop sections of the Jurassic carbonates with a road distance of 121 km in the Trans Indus Ranges, NW Himalayas, were included in this study. Geological fieldwork was conducted for sedimentological data, and representative samples were collected for microfacies analysis and diagenetic evolution complemented by carbon and oxygen isotope analysis. Results show that eight microfacies were identified in both sections where mudstone microfacies was only present in the Chichali section, whereas wackestone and packstone facies widely existed in both sections. The diagenetic evolution interpreted that dolomitization and stylolization were pronounced in the Paniala section, while micritization and calcite cementation were prevalent in the Chichali section. The interpreted depositional setting implies the wide range from supratidal to outer ramp shallow marine for the Chichali section, suggesting a wide range and relatively deeper environment, alongside merely intertidal to middle ramp settings for Paniala section. Diagenetic evolution suggests marine to meteoric influence in the Chichali section, while burial and uplift phases were dominant in the Paniala section. The diagenetic events were also validated by the isotopic analysis, where most of the samples with values up to &#8722;4&#8240; VPDB &#948;18O, corresponding to a carbon isotope range of up to +4&#8240;, were interpreted as the burial phase of diagenesis; meanwhile, a few samples with &#8722;2 &#948;13C and &#8722;7&#8240; VPDB &#948;18O isotope signatures were marked as meteoric influx in the Paniala section. This study indicates the diversity of the depositional environment and diagenetic heterogeneity by integration of thin sections using isotope data, which are quite applicable to shallow marine carbonates.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Jamil, Ihsan Ullah, Hamad ur Rahim, I. Khan, Wahid Abbas, Mohib ur Rehman, Alidu Rashid, Muhammad Umar, Asad Ali, Numair Ahmed Siddiqui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min14111170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dharwar Stratigraphy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17491/jgsi/1972/130110</link>
      <description>R. Srinivasan, B. Sreenivas, Journal of the Geological Society of India. 13(1)] 1972. https://openalex.org/W4404507496

                Abstract Reconsideration of the stratigraphy of the Dharwars of Mysore State in the light of new data suggests that they are Paleoproterozoic and overlie Charnockites of Archean age. Classification of Dharwars based on tectonomagmatic and atmospheric evolution leads to a four fold divison. Pregeosynclinal shelf stage iS represented by two cycles of platformal sedimentation and magmatism; the earlier, under oxygen deficient conditions, on mafic platforms built by subaerial lavas, Is represented by Bababudan Series, and the latter under oxygenic conditions accompained by alkaline ultramafic intrusions gave rise to Dodguni Series. The geosynclinal Stage represented by pillow-Iava-greywacke-Iron ore deposition (third cycle of magmatism and sedimentation) constitutes the Grey trapRambennur Series. Early tectonic plagioclase granites-Champion gneisses syntectonic migmatites-Peninsular gneisses and late to post-tectonic alkali metasomatic granites Closepet granites (fourth, fifth and sixth magmatic cycles) developed during the folding and metamorphism of Dharwar geosynclinal pile. The inversion of geosyncline witnessed apogeosynclinal molasse red bed Sedimentation (fourth cycle of sedimentation) represented by G. R. Series. Paleoproterozoic epidiorites and post-Paleoproterozoic dolerites cratonised the area.</description>
      <author>R. Srinivasan, B. Sreenivas</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 1972 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17491/jgsi/1972/130110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogenase structural evolution across Earth s history</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.18.623660</link>
      <description>Bruno Cuevas-Zuvir&#237;a, Franka Detemple, Kaustubh Amritkar, Amanda K. Garcia, Lance C. Seefeldt, Oliver Einsle, Bet&#252;l Ka&#231;ar, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404493480

                Life on Earth is more than 3.5 billion years old nearly as old as the age of the planet. Over this vast expanse of time, life and its biomolecules adapted to and triggered profound changes to the Earth s environment. Certain critical enzymes evolved early in the history of life and have persisted through planetary extremes. While sequence data is widely used to trace evolutionary trajectories, enzyme structure remains an underexplored resource for understanding how proteins evolve over long timescales. Here, we implement an integrated approach to study nitrogenase, an ancient, globally critical enzyme essential for nitrogen fixation. Despite the ecological diversity of its host microbes, nitrogenase has strict functional limitations, including extreme oxygen sensitivity, energy requirements and substrate availability. By combining phylogenetics, ancestral sequence reconstruction, protein crystallography and deep learning based structural prediction, we resurrected three billion years of nitrogenase structural history. We present the first effort to predict all extant and ancestral structures along the evolutionary tree of an enzyme and present a total of 5000 structures. Our approach lays the foundation for reconstructing key structural constraints that influence protein evolution and studying ancient enzyme evolution in the light of phylogenetic and environmental change.</description>
      <author>Bruno Cuevas-Zuvir&#237;a, Franka Detemple, Kaustubh Amritkar, Amanda K. Garcia, Lance C. Seefeldt, Oliver Einsle, Bet&#252;l Ka&#231;ar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.18.623660</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evidence for Type Ib/c Origin of the Supernova Remnant G292.0+1.8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad7e17</link>
      <description>Takuto Narita, Hiroyuki Uchida, Jacco Vink, Satoru Katsuda, Hideyuki Umeda, Takashi Yoshida, Toshiki Sato, Kai Matsunaga, Takeshi Go Tsuru, The Astrophysical Journal. 976(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404509264

                Abstract Circumstellar material (CSM) produced by mass loss from massive stars (&#8819;10 M &#8857; ) through strong stellar winds or binary stripping provides rich information for understanding progenitors of core-collapse supernova remnants. In this paper we present a grating spectroscopy of a Galactic SNR G292.0+1.8, which is claimed to be a Type Ib/c remnant in a binary system according to recent studies. If G292.0+1.8 had experienced a strong mass-loss via binary interactions before its explosion, an oxygen-rich material produced in the He-burning layer is expected to be observed in the central belt-like structure formed by shock-heated CSM. Using the Reflection Grating Spectrometer onboard XMM-Newton, we detect N vii Ly &#945; line (0.50 keV) for the first time in G292.0+1.8 and find that the abundance ratio of nitrogen to oxygen is significantly lower (N/O = 0.5 &#177; 0.1) than the solar value. This low N/O suggests that the progenitor of G292.0+1.8 experienced strong mass-loss and ended up as a Wolf&#8211;Rayet star exposing the He-burning layer at the presupernova. Comparing our result and the evolution models of single stars and binaries, we conclude that the progenitor of G292.0+1.8 experienced strong enough mass-loss to occur a Type Ib/c supernova. Our finding is another crucial piece of evidence for a stripped-envelope supernova such as Type Ib/c as the origin of G292.0+1.8.</description>
      <author>Takuto Narita, Hiroyuki Uchida, Jacco Vink, Satoru Katsuda, Hideyuki Umeda, Takashi Yoshida, Toshiki Sato, Kai Matsunaga, Takeshi Go Tsuru</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad7e17</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary tracks of binary neutron star progenitors across cosmic times</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450422</link>
      <description>Cl&#233;ment Pellouin, Irina Dvorkin, L&#233;onard Lehoucq, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404562516

                Recent discoveries of gravitational wave sources have advanced our knowledge about the formation of compact object binaries. At present, many questions about the stellar origins of binary neutron stars remain open. In this work, we explore the evolution of binary neutron star progenitors with the population synthesis code COSMIC. We identify three dominant evolutionary tracks to form neutron star binaries that merge within the age of the Universe: a scenario that includes a common envelope phase between the first neutron star and its companion, a scenario with almost equal-mass progenitors that evolve quasi-simultaneously and feature a double-core common envelope, and a scenario involving the accretion-induced collapse of an oxygen-neon white dwarf into a neutron star. We show that the distribution of time delays between stellar formation and binary neutron star merger at a given progenitor metallicity does not follow a power law but instead features a complex structure that reflects the progenitor properties and the relative contribution of each evolutionary track. We also explore the evolution of the merger rate density with redshift, and we show that the scenario involving the accretion-induced collapse could be dominant at high redshifts. These results can have important implications for the study of the chemical enrichment of galaxies in r-process elements produced in kilonovae and of short gamma-ray burst offsets in their host galaxies.</description>
      <author>Cl&#233;ment Pellouin, Irina Dvorkin, L&#233;onard Lehoucq</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards The Upscaling Of ODS Steels: STARS ROUTE&#174;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59499/wp225381791</link>
      <description>N. Ord&#225;s, M. Rold&#225;n, E. Le&#243;n, T. Leguey, Evelin Cardozo, I. Iturriza, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4404482132

                14Cr-2W-0.3Ti-0.3Y2O3 Oxide Dispersion Strengthened (ODS) Ferritic Stainless Steels are promising candidates for structural components in future nuclear systems. Their outstanding properties are attributed to an ultrafine microstructure and a very stable dispersion of Y-Ti-O oxide nanoparticles (NPs).The STARS Route&#174; developed to produce ODS alloys avoids the need for mechanical alloying to dissolve the oxide-former elements in the matrix and relies on Ceit&#8217;s capability to introduce them during gas atomization as oversaturated solid solution. Warm rolling after HIPing introduces a high density of dislocations, preferential nucleation sites. Final annealing heat treatment precipitates the NPs through an internal oxidation process: the metastable oxides formed at the surface of powder particles after atomization dissociate, and oxygen, Ti and Y diffuse towards the dislocations, where they precipitate as Y-Ti-O nano-oxides.This work shows the microstructural evolution of ODS steels obtained with the STARS Route&#174;, and the role of process parameters on mechanical properties.</description>
      <author>N. Ord&#225;s, M. Rold&#225;n, E. Le&#243;n, T. Leguey, Evelin Cardozo, I. Iturriza</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59499/wp225381791</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Type Ia supernovae</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.09740</link>
      <description>S. Blondin, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404569008

                Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) correspond to the thermonuclear explosion of a carbon-oxygen white dwarf (C-O WD) star in a binary system, triggered by the accretion of material from another star, or the merger/collision with a secondary WD. Their phenomenal luminosity -- several billion times that of the sun -- has motivated their use as cosmological distance indicators and led to the discovery of the accelerated expansion of the universe. SNe Ia are also the main producers of iron and hence play a fundamental role in the chemical evolution of galaxies. While recent observations have confirmed the basic theoretical picture of an exploding C-O WD star whose luminosity is powered by the radioactive decay of $^{56}$Ni, a number of uncertainties remain concerning the nature of the binary companion and the explosion mechanism. Several lines of evidence point towards the existence of multiple progenitor channels in order to explain the full range of the observed diversity. A complete physical understanding of these energetic stellar explosions remains a long-lasting goal of modern astrophysics.</description>
      <author>S. Blondin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.09740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Protection and Dielectric Properties of Borosilicate Coatings for SiCf/SiC Composites Under High-Temperature Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14111456</link>
      <description>Xiaohui Dong, Lianyi Wang, Ruiying Luo, Guoteng Zhang, Jinsen Wang, Xiaotian Yang, Huiyong Yang, Juntong Huang, Coatings. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404484033

                Currently, oxidation of SiCf/SiC composites in harsh environments such as high temperatures has become a key challenge for their application in high-temperature structural wave-absorbing materials. In this study, borosilicate glass (BSZ) coatings were prepared using the thermal nitrogen&#8211;oxygen process. The evolution of mechanical and coating microwave dielectric properties of the composites with and without BSZ coatings after oxidation at 1100 &#176;C, 1200 &#176;C, 1300 &#176;C and 1400 &#176;C was investigated. The results showed that the mechanical strength of the BSZ-coated SiCf/SiC specimens remains virtually unchanged, with a remarkable strength retention rate of 94%. The exceptional oxidation resistance of these coatings can be attributed to the formation of self-healing oxides and the reinforcing &#8220;pinning&#8221; effect of ZrSiO4. With an increase in oxidation temperature, the dielectric properties of the oxidized coatings are determined by the intrinsic properties of the generators and the porosity. Overall, these features highlight the potential of borosilicate coatings in the field of electromagnetic wave-absorbing composites, and the current work establishes a correlation between the oxidized microscopic properties of the coatings and the dielectric properties.</description>
      <author>Xiaohui Dong, Lianyi Wang, Ruiying Luo, Guoteng Zhang, Jinsen Wang, Xiaotian Yang, Huiyong Yang, Juntong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14111456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moir&#233; polar vortex, flat bands, and Lieb lattice in twisted bilayer BaTiO &lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq0293</link>
      <description>Seungjun Lee, D. J. P. de Sousa, Bharat Jalan, Tony Low, Science Advances. 10(47)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404563471

                Through first-principles calculations based on density functional theory, we investigate the crystal and electronic structures of twisted bilayer BaTiO 3 . Our findings reveal that large stacking fault energy leads to a chiral in-plane vortex pattern that was recently observed in experiments. We also found nonzero out-of-plane local dipole moments, indicating that the strong interlayer interaction might offer a promising strategy to stabilize ferroelectric order in the two-dimensional limit. The vortex pattern in the twisted BaTiO 3 bilayer supports localized electronic states with quasi-flat bands, associated with the interlayer hybridization of oxygen p z orbitals. We found that the associated bandwidth reaches a minimum at &#8764;19 &#8728; twisting, configuring the largest magic angle in moir&#233; systems reported so far. Further, the moir&#233; vortex pattern bears a notable resemblance to two interpenetrating Lieb lattices and the corresponding tight-binding model provides a comprehensive description of the evolution the moir&#233; bands with twist angle and reveals the topological nature.</description>
      <author>Seungjun Lee, D. J. P. de Sousa, Bharat Jalan, Tony Low</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq0293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling of hydrogen release during electrolysis of alkaline solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202459201010</link>
      <description>V Yu Chebakova, E3S Web of Conferences. 592(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404545702

                Electrochemical processes of electrolysis of solutions belong to heterogeneous processes, their most intensive development and flow occurs at the interface, namely at the contact line between the metal electrode and the liquid electrolyte. The paper describes an algorithm for solving the objective of calculating hydrogen evolution during electrolysis of alkaline electrolyte in one-dimensional approximation. This numerical algorithm makes it possible to predict the hydrogen yield, to find the rates of constants in electrode processes, as well as we calculate the concentrations of substances involved in electrode processes and their spatial distribution. The algorithm consists of two blocks. The first block is an independent objective to find rate constants of processes. Kinetic objectives make it possible to find rate constants of near-electrode processes and to estimate contributions of near-electrode processes. The second block is the solution of initial-boundary and boundary value objectives in the &#8220;one-dimensional&#8221; approximation. The difference schemes for solving these objectives are constructed by the integrointerpolation method on a uniform grid, and an explicit difference scheme is used for solving the initial-boundary objectives of the charged particle balance. Calculation of the amount of separated gas showed good convergence both at the cathode (hydrogen) and at the anode (oxygen). The calculation of the spatial ones showed characteristic gradients, i.e., rather qualitative convergence.</description>
      <author>V Yu Chebakova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202459201010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distinct immune responses to HIV and CMV in Hofbauer cells across gestation highlight evolving placental immune dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.21.624730</link>
      <description>Viviane Schuch, Daniel J. Hossack, Tiffany Hailstorks, Rana Chakraborty, Erica L. Johnson, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404629620

                Placental immune responses to Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) and Human Cytomegalovirus (CMV) vary across gestational stages and may influence postnatal outcomes. This study investigates the innate immunity of Hofbauer cells from placentae obtained at early/mid-gestation (18-21.6 weeks) and term (&gt;37 weeks). RNA sequencing and cytokine profiling reveal that early/mid-gestation HCs exhibit heightened differential gene expression responses compared to term HCs, indicating a distinct transcriptional activity in early pregnancy. Significant overlap in gene expression profiles of early/mid-gestation cells in response to CMV and HIV suggest similar innate immune responses, while term cells exhibit distinct patterns, reflecting the temporal evolution of placental immunity. Integration with the Human Protein Atlas database reveals more placental-specific differentially expressed genes in early/mid-gestation HCs exposed to HIV and CMV compared to term cells. Functional analysis reveals downregulation of pathways related to oxygen stress, estrogen response, and KRAS signalling pathway in early/mid-gestation HCs, with HIV uniquely upregulating reactive oxygen species and CMV uniquely disrupting WNT &#946;-Catenin signalling. In term HCs, CMV exposure upregulates antiviral interferon (IFN) signaling and inflammatory pathways. Co-expression analysis highlights distinct molecular pathway enrichments across gestation, particularly with upregulation of IFN signalling and disruption of lipid metabolism in term CMV-exposed HCs. Cytokine profiling shows enhanced expression of GM-CSF, IFN-&#947;, and Th2-associated cytokines in early/mid-gestation HCs, indicating heightened immune responsiveness. These findings reveal the dynamic nature of placental immunity and underscore the need for targeted interventions to address unique immune and metabolic disruptions caused by viral infections at distinct stages of pregnancy to improve fetal and infant health outcomes.</description>
      <author>Viviane Schuch, Daniel J. Hossack, Tiffany Hailstorks, Rana Chakraborty, Erica L. Johnson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.21.624730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genomic Insights into Tibetan Sheep Adaptation to Different Altitude Environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252212394</link>
      <description>Wentao Zhang, Chao Yuan, Xuejiao An, Tingting Guo, Caihong Wei, Zengkui Lu, Jianbin Liu, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 25(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404504755

                In recent years, research has gradually uncovered the mechanisms of animal adaptation to hypoxic conditions in different altitude environments, particularly at the genomic level. However, past genomic studies on high-altitude adaptation have often not delved deeply into the differences between varying altitude levels. This study conducted whole-genome sequencing on 60 Tibetan sheep (Medium Altitude Group (MA): 20 Tao sheep (TS) at 2887 m, High Altitude Group (HA): 20 OuLa sheep (OL) at 3501 m, and Ultra-High Altitude Group (UA): 20 AWang sheep (AW) at 4643 m) from different regions of the Tibetan Plateau in China to assess their responses under varying conditions. Population genetic structure analysis revealed that the three groups are genetically independent, but the TS and OL groups have experienced gene flow with other northern Chinese sheep due to geographical factors. Selection signal analysis identified FGF10, MMP14, SLC25A51, NDUFB8, ALAS1, PRMT1, PRMT5, and HIF1AN as genes associated with ultra-high-altitude hypoxia adaptation, while HMOX2, SEMA4G, SLC16A2, SLC22A17, and BCL2L2 were linked to high-altitude hypoxia adaptation. Functional analysis showed that ultra-high-altitude adaptation genes tend to influence physiological mechanisms directly affecting oxygen uptake, such as lung development, angiogenesis, and red blood cell formation. In contrast, high-altitude adaptation genes are more inclined to regulate mitochondrial DNA replication, iron homeostasis, and calcium signaling pathways to maintain cellular function. Additionally, the functions of shared genes further support the adaptive capacity of Tibetan sheep across a broad geographic range, indicating that these genes offer significant selective advantages in coping with oxygen scarcity. In summary, this study not only reveals the genetic basis of Tibetan sheep adaptation to different altitudinal conditions but also highlights the differences in gene regulation between ultra-high- and high-altitude adaptations. These findings offer new insights into the adaptive evolution of animals in extreme environments and provide a reference for exploring adaptation mechanisms in other species under hypoxic conditions.</description>
      <author>Wentao Zhang, Chao Yuan, Xuejiao An, Tingting Guo, Caihong Wei, Zengkui Lu, Jianbin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms252212394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasensitive Solar-Blind Phototransistor Based on ZnO/&#946;-Ga&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunctions Fabricated Via Zinc-Induced Low-Temperature Dual-Crystallization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphotonics.4c01487</link>
      <description>Gang Shi, Qiandong Zhuang, Yuhang Liu, Jiao Xu, Teng Yun, Dengji Guo, Xujin Wang, Sudong Wu, ACS Photonics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404539645

                Crystalline Ga2O3 is a desirable candidate for high-performance solar-blind photodetectors (SBPDs) owing to its intrinsic merits, such as an ultrawide bandgap (&#8764;4.9 eV) and high chemical stability. However, Ga2O3-based SBPDs fabricated using conventional methods often suffer from high crystallization temperatures exceeding 750 &#176;C. Herein, we propose a zinc-induced low-temperature dual-crystallization method for facile fabrication of high-performance n-ZnO/n-&#946;-Ga2O3 heterostructures by annealing a sputtered Zn/a-Ga2O3 bilayer (5 nm/15 nm) at 500 &#176;C in air. The structural evolution and crystallization mechanism of n&#8211;n heterojunctions were explored using cross-sectional high-resolution transmission electron microscopy and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Benefiting synergistically from the significantly reduced oxygen vacancies as well as the high mobility of the n-ZnO derived from zinc oxidation, the back-gated phototransistors based on this heterojunction exhibited outstanding and balanced optoelectronic performance, with an ultrahigh responsivity of 7.4 &#215; 104 A/W, an ultrafast rise time of 8.0 ms, a photo-to-dark current ratio of 2.4 &#215; 107, and a detectivity of 2.8 &#215; 1015 Jones. This study presents a novel approach for low-cost fabrication of high-quality ZnO/Ga2O3 heterojunctions, revealing a promising pathway for achieving high-performance heterojunction optoelectronic devices.</description>
      <author>Gang Shi, Qiandong Zhuang, Yuhang Liu, Jiao Xu, Teng Yun, Dengji Guo, Xujin Wang, Sudong Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsphotonics.4c01487</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swimming kinematics of deep&#8208;sea fishes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jfb.15989</link>
      <description>Brett H. Woodworth, Jessica Palmeri, Patrick Flannery, Lydia Fregosi, Cassandra M. Donatelli, Mackenzie E. Gerringer, Journal of Fish Biology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404512811

                Abstract Although the deep oceans represent Earth's largest habitat, the challenges of studying deep&#8208;sea organisms in situ have limited our understanding of adaptation, ecology, and behaviour in these important ecosystems. One fundamental trait of fishes that remains largely unexplored in the deep ocean is swimming, a vital process for movement, migration, and dispersal in marine habitats. Deep&#8208;sea conditions such as temperature, pressure, and food availability could each impact the speed and efficiency of swimming in fishes. To investigate swimming kinematics of fishes with increasing depth, we analysed in situ video of bony fishes across a 6000&#8208;m depth gradient. We compared open&#8208;source videos of fishes from National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Ocean Exploration with tank&#8208;based recordings of shallow&#8208;water relatives from Puget Sound, Washington, USA to understand how both habitat depth and phylogeny influence swimming in fishes. We analysed kinematics in four dominant demersal fish groups, the orders Anguilliformes, Gadiformes, Ophidiiformes, and Perciformes. Deep&#8208;sea fishes swam consistently slowly. Swimming kinematics varied across temperature, oxygen, body elongation, and depth. These results suggest that swimming kinematics do not change linearly with increasing habitat depth in fishes and that the impacts of deep&#8208;sea conditions such as low temperatures, high pressures, and low nutrient availability on swimming behaviour need to be considered independently of one another. These findings provide insight into the evolution of fish form and function in the deep ocean.</description>
      <author>Brett H. Woodworth, Jessica Palmeri, Patrick Flannery, Lydia Fregosi, Cassandra M. Donatelli, Mackenzie E. Gerringer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jfb.15989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geochemistry of Granite-Greenstone Terrain of South India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17491/jgsi/1974/150404</link>
      <description>B. Sreenivas, R. Srinivasan, Journal of the Geological Society of India. 15(4)] 1974. https://openalex.org/W4404504862

                Abstract A critical evaluation of the available major and trace element data on rocks of the granite-greenstone belts or South India leads to the following inferences: Barrovian and Abukuma facies series of metamorphism are recognizable in the terrain. Rocks of peridotitic and basaltic komatiite affinities occur in the pre-Dharwar and early Dharwar ultramafic-mafic sequence. The bulk of the greenstones are island arc tholeiites with a strong calc-alkaline affinity. The presence of detrital pyrites in the oldest conglomerates, and the occurrence of red beds in the topmost Dharwar sequence, indicate that an oxygenic atmosphere evolved through the Dharwar times. The pre-Dharwar granitoids were probably tonalitic, and through time, alkali fractionation gave rise to the Champion gneisses, Peninsular gneisses and Closepet granites. The available data are inadequate to elucidate the fractionation pattern of the granitic crust of Peninsular India. Pyrolite and eclogite mantle are invoked for tectonomagmatic events during the pre-Dharwar and Dharwar times, respectively. Convection, and eclogite sinkers, are proposed as alternative geodynamic models. From the geochemical evolution, it is contended that the granite-greenstone belts of Peninsular India represent a more evolved crustal condition as compared to the Archaean granite greenstone belts of South Africa and Western Australia. Obviously, the granite-greenstone belts of all the shield areas, did not evolve simultaneously.</description>
      <author>B. Sreenivas, R. Srinivasan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 1974 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17491/jgsi/1974/150404</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geochemistry of Precambrian Carbonatite Complexes of India: Present Status of, and Gaps in our Knowledge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17491/jgsi/1974/150411</link>
      <description>G.R. Udas, Journal of the Geological Society of India. 15(4)] 1974. https://openalex.org/W4404504933

                Abstract Carbonatites of Precambrian age occur at Newania and Mundwara in Rajasthan, Sevathur and Hogenakal in Tamil Nadu, Kunavaram in Andhra Pradesh, and KolJegal in Karnataka. The Newania carbonatite is 959&#177;24 m.y. old (K-Ar age of an alkali amphibole), and the Sevathur carbonatite is 720&#177;30 m.y. old (K-Ar age of a biotite). Although comprehensive geochemical studies involving major, minor, and trace elements and carbon, oxygen and strontium isotopes have been undertaken on the 37.5&#177;2.5 m.y. old Eocene carbonatite complex at Amba Dongar, Gujarat, geochemical studies on the Precambrian carbonatites of India have been confined only to routine determinations of selected elements like Sr, Ba, Y, Ce, La, Nb, Zr, Th, Mn, Ti, F and P to demonstrate their carbonatitic affinites. Except for two K-Ar ages, and for some limited trace element data, no attempts have been made to elucidate the chronologie and petrogenetic evolution of these Precambrian carbonatites by the application of Rb-Sr, K-Ar, and U-Pb geochronometry, critical element ratios, stable and radiogenic isotope abundances, and geothermometry. Basic researches aimed at formulating geochemical criteria for locating commercially exploitable economic Precambrian carbonatite complexes are yet to be initiated in India.</description>
      <author>G.R. Udas</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 1974 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17491/jgsi/1974/150411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterisation of Five Natural Magnetite Reference Materials for &lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Iron Isotope Measurement with Application to Magmatic Ni&#8208;Cu Sulfide Mineralisation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ggr.12592</link>
      <description>Yantong Feng, Wen Zhang, Yawen Bao, Xianli Zeng, Hong Liu, Tao Luo, Zhaochu Hu, Mingjie Zhang, Li Wang, Yang Yan, Shengjiang Liu, Geostandards and Geoanalytical Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404454998

                Iron isotope ratios in magnetite have been widely used to reveal critical geological and biological processes. Laser ablation multi&#8208;collector inductively coupled plasma&#8208;mass spectrometry (LA&#8208;MC&#8208;ICP&#8208;MS) is ideally suited for measurement of Fe isotope ratios, however the lack of suitable reference materials poses a significant challenge for in situ Fe isotopic measurements in magnetites. In this study, five high&#8208;quality natural magnetite crystals were characterised for Fe isotope ratios using solution nebulisation (SN)&#8208;MC&#8208;ICP&#8208;MS and LA&#8208;MC&#8208;ICP&#8208;MS. The effects of LA&#8208;MC&#8208;ICP&#8208;MS analytical conditions were investigated to obtain precise and accurate Fe isotope ratios. The yielded intermediate measurement precisions for the &#948; 56 Fe values in the five investigated magnetites were &#177; 0.05&#8211;0.06&#8240; (2 s ) using SN&#8208;MC&#8208;ICP&#8208;MS and &#177; 0.08&#8211;0.14&#8240; (2 s ) using LA&#8208;MC&#8208;ICP&#8208;MS. Magnetites with homogeneous Fe isotopic compositions in hand&#8208;specimen measurements and microanalysis can serve as potential reference materials for in situ Fe isotopic measurement. Furthermore, the Fe isotope ratios in the magnetites from the Jinchuan Ni&#8208;Cu&#8208;PGE sulfide deposit were measured using LA&#8208;MC&#8208;ICP&#8208;MS with natural magnetite as the bracketing calibrator. The increase in the Fe isotopic composition with magmatic sulfide evolution was primarily dominated by oxygen fugacity ( f O 2 ) and hydrothermal fluids. This finding implies that the Fe isotopic composition of magnetite can serve as a potential geochemical indicator of magmatic Ni&#8208;Cu sulfide mineralisation.</description>
      <author>Yantong Feng, Wen Zhang, Yawen Bao, Xianli Zeng, Hong Liu, Tao Luo, Zhaochu Hu, Mingjie Zhang, Li Wang, Yang Yan, Shengjiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ggr.12592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cosmic-ray-induced chemical processes in CH3OH, CH3NH2 and CH3OH:CH3NH2 ices. Conventional and novel IR spectroscopic analysis with VIZSLA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202452170</link>
      <description>Barbara Keresztes, S&#225;ndor G&#243;bi, Anita Schneiker, G&#225;bor Bazs&#243;, Gy&#246;rgy Tarczay, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404610085

                Icy mantles on interstellar dust grains are considered key contributors to the chemical complexity of the interstellar medium (ISM). Gas-phase molecules in the ISM can adsorb onto these icy surfaces, where chemical reactions can be induced by ultraviolet (UV) or cosmic ray (CR) irradiation. The resulting molecules can subsequently desorb, thereby altering the composition of the gas phase in the ISM. Therefore, studying astrochemically relevant reactions within ices is essential for advancing our understanding of astrochemistry. We conducted experiments with pure methanol (CH OH), pure methylamine (CH NH ), and CH OH:CH NH ices. To simulate CR effects, ices were irradiated with 5 keV electrons. We integrated the advantages of ice experiments and noble gas matrix experiments by performing two distinct investigations on each sample. During temperature-programmed desorption (TPD), chemical changes in the ice samples were monitored using Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy. Simultaneously, the desorbing molecules were trapped in an Ar matrix. This TPD-matrix-isolation (TPD-MI) redeposition process enabled FTIR spectroscopic identification of the desorbed species. The results obtained from experiments with CH OH and CH NH ices are consistent with previous studies. Additionally, the TPD-MI redeposition process enabled the identification of several species previously not detected clearly and directly in pure CH OH or CH NH ices, including molecules such as HCOOH, HCN, and CH CHNH. Our experiments with CH OH:CH NH mixtures revealed the formation of several nitrogen- and oxygen-containing organic species (CH NHCH OH, NH CH OH, NH CH CH OH, and HNCO), which are potential precursors to prebiotic molecules in the ISM. Therefore, these experiments provide valuable insights into the chemical evolution in space.</description>
      <author>Barbara Keresztes, S&#225;ndor G&#243;bi, Anita Schneiker, G&#225;bor Bazs&#243;, Gy&#246;rgy Tarczay</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202452170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum: Seasonal intensification of oxygen minimum zone: linking Godavari River discharge to fall hypoxia in the Bay of Bengal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1523183</link>
      <description>K. S. Sreejith, V. V. S. S. Sarma, P. Sreenivas, F. Feba, Ibrahim Hoteit, Karumuri Ashok, Frontiers in Marine Science. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404494464

                The Eastern Tropical Pacific (ETP), Arabian Sea (AS), and Bay of Bengal (BoB) are recognized for hosting the most intense oxygen minimum zones (OMZs), characterized by severe hypoxia at intermediate depths (Gilly et al., 2013; McCreary et al., 2013). The formation of these OMZs is attributed to a complex interplay of physical and biogeochemical processes, many of which exhibit commonalities across all three basins. Enhanced primary productivity in surface waters fosters organic matter export to deeper layers. This organic matter undergoes intensified decomposition at intermediate depths, leading to oxygen depletion through microbial respiration (Breitburg et al., 2018; Gilly et al., 2013; Paulmier and Ruiz-Pino, 2009; Pennington et al., 2006). Furthermore, sluggish circulation patterns within these basins limit the advection of oxygen-rich waters into the OMZ, and weak vertical mixing restricts oxygen replenishment from the surface (Breitburg et al., 2018; Gilly et al., 2013; Paulmier and Ruiz-Pino, 2009; McCreary et al., 2013).The Bay of Bengal oxygen minimum zone (BoB-OMZ) deviates from the typical pattern observed in the ETP and AS despite sharing common drivers for OMZ formation (Gilly et al., 2013; McCreary et al., 2013). This disparity underscores the significant influence of regional factors on the BoB-OMZ's characteristics. A key distinction lies in the primary mechanism responsible for its persistence. Microbial processes such as denitrification and anammox are crucial for oxygen consumption in the ETP and AS (Rao et al., 1994; Gilly et al., 2013; Kalvelage et al., 2013; Castro-Gonz&#225;lez et al., 2014). In contrast, the BoB-OMZ primarily owes its existence to intense salinity stratification (Paulmier and Ruiz-Pino, 2009; Sarma et al., 2018; Udaya Bhaskar et al., 2021). This stratification effectively traps oxygen-depleted waters, hindering vertical mixing and oxygen replenishment from the surface. Cyclonic eddies further influence the intensity and distribution of the BoB-OMZ (Sarma et al., 2018). Interestingly, anticyclonic eddies can sporadically ventilate the BoB-OMZ with oxygen-rich surface waters, leading to temporary weakening and spatial heterogeneity of the hypoxic zone (Sarma and Udaya Bhaskar, 2018). These contrasting mechanisms, absent in the ETP and AS, contribute to the BoB-OMZ's weaker overall intensity and dynamic nature.The intensity and extent of the BoB-OMZ exhibit significant spatial and temporal variations. In the northern BoB, influenced by major river discharge from the Ganges and Brahmaputra rivers, the summer monsoon and post-monsoon seasons see intensified salinity stratification, leading to a more pronounced OMZ (Howden and Murtugudde, 2001; Jana et al., 2015; Udaya Bhaskar et al., 2021; Sarma et al., 2016). This stratification traps oxygen-depleted waters, hindering vertical mixing and oxygen replenishment. Additionally, the cross-shelf transport of organic matter from the western BoB fuels microbial decomposition, resulting in a stronger OMZ compared to the eastern region (Udaya Bhaskar et al., 2021). Recent studies suggest the possibility of even more intense OMZ formation in the northwestern BoB during winter (Bristow et al., 2017), potentially due to enhanced nutrient input from rivers or atmospheric deposition. However, Sridevi and Sarma (2021) propose that these intense episodes might be transient features caused by eddies. Biogeochemically, the BoB-OMZ is considered weaker compared to other regions. This can be attributed to factors such as weak upwelling, limited primary productivity, and rapid sinking of organic carbon to the deep sea, reducing the availability of organic matter for microbial oxygen consumption (Rao et al., 1994; Ittekkot et al., 1991; Naqvi et al., 1996; Ramaiah et al., 2010; McCreary et al., 2013). Furthermore, several studies suggest that riverine nutrients are rapidly consumed within a limited distance (20 km) from the coast, restricting their contribution to offshore OMZ intensification (Howden and Murtugudde, 2001; Sarma et al., 2018).The Godavari River, India's third-longest fluvial system (1,465 km), is driven by the monsoon cycle, resulting in concentrated discharge from July to September (Central Water Commission, 2019). This peak discharge coincides with the BoB's highest riverine input, contrasting with the dominance of tidal processes in other seasons (Howden and Murtugudde, 2001; Sarma et al., 2010). While the influence of major rivers such as the Ganges and Brahmaputra on the northern BoB-OMZ is well-established (Jana et al., 2015; Udaya Bhaskar et al., 2021), the annual impact of medium-sized rivers such as the Godavari remains less explored. This study addresses this knowledge gap by investigating the annual cycle of Godavari River discharge (GRD), its potential effects on local coastal primary productivity, and its contribution to the development of a seasonal OMZ near the river mouth. The following section outlines the methodology and details the datasets employed. Section 3 presents our findings on the seasonal evolution of the BoB- OMZ, the biogeochemistry in the river mouth region, and the potential mechanisms driving the intense OMZs observed near the Godavari. Finally, section 4 provides a comprehensive summary and concluding remarks. The GRD data utilized in this study were obtained from the Dowleiswaram barrage, located approximately 50 km upstream of the river's confluence with the BoB. This barrage serves as the final major infrastructure point along the Godavari's course, regulating the downstream flow of freshwater into the BoB. Daily measurements of water released from the Dowleiswaram barrage provided a high- resolution record of GRD variations. These daily values were subsequently aggregated to generate monthly mean time series data spanning 29 years (1990-2018). The use of Dowleiswaram barrage discharge as a proxy for total GRD into the BoB is justified due to several factors. First, the barrage captures the vast majority of the Godavari's freshwater input, as evidenced by minimal tributaries downstream. Second, the relatively short distance (50 km) between the barrage and the BoB minimizes potential losses through evaporation or tributary inputs. This time series data of mean monthly GRD serve as a key foundation for our investigation of the river's influence on coastal BoB dynamics. Due to confidentiality restrictions, the GRD data used in this study were not publicly available. The data was obtained from Superintending Engineer, Irrigation Circle, Dhavaleswaram, Rajamahendravaram, Andhra Pradesh (https://irrigationap.cgg.gov.in/wrd/home; scicbowlm@gmail.com).This study leverages Biogeochemical-Argo (BGC-ARGO) data, a critical component of the Global Ocean Observing System (Notarstefano, 2020), to provide high-resolution in situ station observations in the vicinity of the Godavari River mouth. Within the extensive BGC-ARGO network, we identified two floats (2902264 and 2902193) strategically positioned within the plume of low-saline GRD. The precise locations of these floats are presented in Figure 1, along with their temporal and location information in Table 1 and Supplementary Tables S1, S2. These two floats provided individual quality-controlled profiles of various oceanographic parameters. Float 2902193 completed 184 data cycles, with three profiles (cycles 49, 59, and 71) acquired within the vicinity of the GRD region through the fall to early winter (mid-September to December). Float 2902264 completed 268 cycles, with three profiles (cycles 41, 44, and 60) in the GRD region through the fall to the winter months (mid-October to January). Both floats were stationed outside the GRD region for the remaining data cycles. Consequently, only the three profiles acquired within the GRD region, as outlined above, were utilized for the analysis of dissolved oxygen (DO), chlorophyll-a (Chl-a) concentration, and particle backscattering coefficient information at 700 nm (bb700) in this study. The DO measurements offer insights into potential oxygen depletion associated with enhanced organic matter decomposition driven by the GRD influx. Chl-a, a proxy for phytoplankton biomass, acts as a marker of primary productivity potentially stimulated by nutrient enrichment from the river discharge. Finally, the particle backscattering coefficient serves as an indicator of the presence and type of suspended particles, including phytoplankton and non-living organic matter, which the GRD dynamics can influence. By scrutinizing these critical variables from the strategically located BGC-ARGO floats, we aim to provide robust observational evidence to confirm and refine our understanding of the Godavari River's impact on the biogeochemical dynamics of the coastal BoB region. We obtained BGC-ARGO data from https:// biogeochemical-argo.org/data-access.php. To gain further insights into potential spatial biogeochemical responses to the GRD, we also drew upon complementary datasets from the Ocean Colour Climate Change Initiative (OC-CCI) (https://www.oceancolour.org/browser/index.php?product=chlor_ a&amp;page=0.=monthly&amp;version=1&amp;limit=24&amp;from=2002- 01-01&amp;to=2016-01-01&amp;mode=download#results). This fresh initiative provides a robust, merged Level 3 product for monthly mean Chl-a concentrations from 2002 to 2016. This valuable resource utilizes satellite observations from diverse sensors, including Medium Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer (MERIS), Sea-viewing Wide Field-of-view Sensor (SeaWiFS), Moderate Resolution Imaging Spectroradiometer (MODIS)-Aqua, and Visible Infrared Imaging Radiometer Suite (VIIRS), seamlessly combined to offer a comprehensive and spatially extensive view of phytoplankton biomass across the global ocean (Sathyendranath et al., 2019). The 4 km spatial resolution of the OC-CCI Chl-a data strikes a balance between capturing local dynamics near the Godavari estuary and providing regional context for the observed patterns. To further elucidate the potential impact of GRD on primary productivity, we also leverage monthly mean net primary productivity (NPP) data obtained from the same OC-CCI website for the same timeframe (2002-2016) (https://www.oceancolour.org/browser/index.php?product=pp&amp;page=0&amp;limit=24&amp;from=2002-01-01&amp;to=2016-01- 01&amp;mode=browse#results). NPP is estimated using the Ocean Production from the Absorption of Light (OPAL) model. This model builds upon the framework originally proposed by Marra et al. (2003). NPP is integrated over the euphotic zone and expressed in grams of carbon per square meter of sea surface (g C m-2). Four key satellite-derived inputs that are assimilated into OPAL are surface Chl- a concentration, sea surface temperature, photosynthetically active radiation reaching the ocean surface, and the absorption coefficient of colored dissolved organic matter. A detailed description of the NPP calculations is available in O'Reilly (2017). This dataset provides a valuable quantitative estimate of the rate at which organic matter is produced by Chl-a-rich phytoplankton biomass within the coastal BoB region. By analyzing the co-variation between Chl-a, and NPP, we aim to gain insights into the potential stimulation of primary productivity by nutrient enrichment associated with the GRD. The World Ocean Atlas 2018 (WOA18) serves as a cornerstone resource for this study, providing a comprehensive set of objectively analyzed climatological fields for the world ocean (https:// www.ncei.noaa.gov/access/world-ocean-atlas-2018/). These fields, derived from in-situ measurements, encompass various oceanographic parameters at standard depth levels across different grid resolutions (5&#176; &#215; 5&#176;, 1&#176; &#215; 1&#176;, and 0.25&#176; &#215; 0.25&#176;). Specifically, the data includes annual, seasonal, and monthly climatologies of temperature, salinity, DO, phosphate, silicate, and nitrate. The annual and seasonal climatologies extend to an impressive depth of 5,500 m, encompassing 102 distinct vertical levels. However, for monthly climatologies, the data extends only up to 1,500 m (57 vertical levels), still providing valuable insights into the temporal dynamics of near-surface ocean processes. Additionally, the chemical parameters (such as DO, phosphate, silicate, and nitrate) are available only on a 5&#176; &#215; 5&#176; and a 1&#176; &#215; 1&#176; horizontal resolution. This choice balances the need for a detailed spatial resolution within the coastal BoB region with the data availability and reliability constraints inherent in monthly climatologies. In this study, we used the monthly climatological salinity (Zweng et al., 2018) on a 0.25&#176; &#215; 0.25&#176; grid, and dissolved oxygen (Garcia et al., 2019) at a 1&#176; &#215; 1&#176; resolution. By leveraging this robust and authoritative dataset, we aim to gain valuable insights into the spatiotemporal patterns of dissolved oxygen and their potential association with the influence of GRD. The monthly mean horizontal and vertical current data (2000-2020) from the Global Ocean Data Assimilation System (GODAS) developed by the National Centre for Environmental Prediction (NCEP) is used to elucidate the seasonal dynamics of coastal circulation and upwelling near the Godavari River mouth. This advanced reanalysis product (replacing Reanalysis 6) serves as the initial oceanic state for the NCEP's Climate Forecast System (Saha et al., 2006). The GODAS is forced by the momentum flux, heat flux, and freshwater flux. It utilizes a quasi-global configuration of the Geophysical Fluid Dynamics Laboratory (GFDL) MOM.v3 model, encompassing the critical coastal zone with high-resolution grids (1&#176; x 1&#176;, enhanced to 1/3&#176; near the equator) and 40 vertical levels (10 m resolution in the upper 200 m). Leveraging these capabilities of the GODAS data (https:// www.cpc.ncep.noaa.gov/products/GODAS/), we estimated the divergence and upwelling of the GRD region. The divergence field represents the net flow of fluid into or out of a specific region and is calculated as the sum of the partial derivatives of the horizontal velocity components (u and v) with respect to x and y, respectively. Positive divergence leads to upwelling as surface water is drawn away, allowing deeper water to rise and replace it.The monthly distribution of the various physical and biogeochemical fields near the GRD region displays interesting signatures (Supplementary Figures S1&#8211;S4). Since a detailed analysis of each month will be too descriptive, we focus on January, April, July, and October to examine the evolution of various fields in the boreal seasons of winter, spring, summer, and fall, respectively. GRD exhibits a strong seasonality driven by the Southwest Monsoon (SWM) season. Monthly climatology (Figure 2A) reveals a peak discharge exceeding 4700 m3.s-1 in August, coinciding with peak SWM rainfall. Subsequently, GRD declines through September, October, and November, becoming negligible by December. Surface salinity distribution (Figure 2B) generally shows a freshening trend during fall due to the equatorward movement of the West India Coastal Current (WICC) transporting low-salinity waters from the northern BoB. Interestingly, GRD also contributes significantly to this freshening during the SWM season, causing a decrease in over 2 practical salinity units (psu) near the river mouth compared to the pre- monsoon values. From summer to winter, salinity becomes the dominant factor controlling near-surface density stratification. This stratification results in a shallow mixed layer and the formation of a thick barrier layer. The shallow mixed layer restricts the exchange of air-sea fluxes, while the barrier layer suppresses mass and energy exchange between the surface layers and the deeper ocean interior. In short, though the relative contribution of fresh water from GRD is negligible compared to other rivers (Sarma et al., 2016), it has the potential to impact the physical and biogeochemical state of the BoB, especially near the Godavari River mouth region. GRD profoundly amplifies spatiotemporal Chl-a dynamics in the BoB during the SWM season (Figure 2C). Pre-monsoon and winter months are characterized by Chl-a concentrations lingering well below 0.4 mg.m-3, indicative of quiescent phytoplankton growth. In stark contrast, the SWM season ushers in a vibrant pulse of primary productivity, propelling Chl-a to peak values exceeding 2.2 mg.m-3 within a significantly expanded spatial footprint encompassing regions up to 83&#176;E around the river mouth (Figure 2C). This pronounced Chl-a bloom intricately mirrors the fluctuations in GRD, diminishing in intensity as the monsoon recedes. The riverine influx of nutrients orchestrates this dramatic seasonal spectacle, directly fueling phytoplankton proliferation and consequently boosting regional NPP, as depicted in Figure 2D. NPP exhibits a gradual ascent from April that culminates at the onset of SWM, and surges beyond 1000 mgC.m-2 by July. However, with the waning of the monsoon and subsequent decline in GRD, NPP undergoes a steep drop, leaving the river mouth region with markedly reduced productivity by October. Thus, the annual peak in GRD serves as a potent force, not only inducing vertical stratification but also transforming the BoB into a highly productive ecosystem during the SWM season. The thriving phytoplankton blooms fueled by enhanced nutrients from the Godavari River are projected to contribute to a significant suspension of organic matter in subsurface BoB waters. To gain insights into this process, we utilized particle backscatter data from two BGC-ARGO floats (2902264 and 2902193) deployed near the river mouth (Figure 1). These floats offered three individual profiles spanning the SWM to winter seasons, allowing us to analyze the organic matter dynamics across contrasting productivity regimes. Details of the data acquisition and processing are provided in Table 1. The BGC-ARGO float 2902264 revealed a pronounced peak in particle backscatter (&gt;0.002 m-1), coinciding with elevated Chl-a concentrations (&gt;3.5 mg m-3) at depths between 30 and 50 m in October 2018 (Figures 1A, B). This peak, located at a depth of 40-50 m, suggests a substantial abundance of organic matter during peak productivity. By November, the intensity of the particle backscatter peak diminished to 0.00165 m-1 at 39 m, accompanied by a reduction in Chl-a to 1.5 mg.m-3 at 37 m. This decline implied a weakening of organic matter abundance as productivity decreased. Notably, while the extreme particle backscatter peaks were absent by January 2019, Chl-a exhibited a secondary peak at 48 m, albeit with a lower magnitude (&lt;0.8 mg.m- 3). This suggests a potential decoupling between Chl-a and organic particle suspension during this period. Data from BGC-ARGO float 2902193 qualitatively support the observed patterns from float 2902264 (Figures 1C, D) in the upper 80 m of the water column. The highest values for both particle backscatter (&gt;0.003 m-1) and Chl-a (&gt;3.5 mg.m-3) were observed during November 2016 (late fall/early winter season) at depths between 25 and 40 m. The peak particle backscatter (&gt;0.003 m-1) occurred at 38 m, while the peak Chl-a (&gt;3.5 mg.m-3) was slightly shallower at 28 m. These elevated values suggest an enhanced production and possible export of organic matter during the fall, following the peak productivity of the SWM. However, the September 2016 data showed lower particle backscatter (&lt;0.0028 m-1) and significantly reduced Chl-a (&lt;1.9 mg.m-3), indicating weaker organic matter suspension preceding the fall peak. Interestingly, while December 2016 exhibited the highest particle backscatter value (&gt;0.0032 m-1) between 85 and 95 m, Chl-a concentrations remained very low (&lt;1 mg.m-3) at depths between 30 and 80 m. This discrepancy suggests a potential decoupling between particle export and phytoplankton biomass at deeper depths during this period. Thus, our analysis of the BGC-ARGO data from both floats indicates a seasonal pattern of enhanced Chl-a inducing an elevated particle backscatter underneath it, along with increased organic matter abundance near the Godavari River mouth region, particularly at depths between 25 and 55 m during the fall season. Furthermore, this abundance appears to be linked to elevated Chl-a and NPP during the preceding SWM season.Hence, GRD significantly impacts the river mouth region during the SWM season through a multifaceted interplay of stratification, primary productivity, and organic matter abundance. The pronounced stratification resulting from a shallow mixed layer and a thick barrier layer generated by GRD restricts vertical mixing, potentially minimizing DO transport from the surface to subsurface layers. Simultaneously, the riverine influx of nutrients fuels phytoplankton growth, leading to enhanced Chl-a concentrations and culminating in elevated NPP. This primary productivity surge drives organic matter export into subsurface layers, potentially capable of influencing DO distribution through microbial decomposition processes. In conclusion, the combined effects of altered stratification, intensified primary productivity at the surface, and organic matter sinking into subsurface layers during the post-SWM season are likely to significantly modify the DO distribution (both horizontal and vertical) near the Godavari River mouth region. The region near the Godavari River mouth lies within the BoB- OMZ, a persistent feature characterized by year-round hypoxic conditions at intermediate depths (200-1,000 m). This section focuses on the potential impact of enhanced organic matter sinking during the SWM and early fall seasons on the distribution of DO and the dynamics (intensity and upper limit) of the BoB-OMZ in the Godavari River mouth region. Analysis of DO profiles from BGC-ARGO floats near the Godavari River mouth reveals the presence of an OMZ (DO within 0-0.5 ml.l-1) between 50 to 800 m (average depth levels), with a dynamic response to seasonal changes in organic matter input (Figure 3). Both floats exhibit a shoaling and intensification of the OMZ during the fall season, indicating a potential influence of riverine flow on DO consumption. At float 2902264, the upper limit of the OMZ deepened from 40-45 m in October 2018 (DO ~ 0 ml.l-1) to 50m in November (DO ~ 0.2 ml.l-1) and to 100 m by January 2019 (DO ~0.5 ml.l-1) (Figure 3A). This pattern suggests a gradual deepening of the OMZ as surface productivity declined and oxygen consumption in subsurface layers for microbial respiration reduced. Float 2902193 exhibited a similar trend, with the upper OMZ boundary at 35-40 m in November 2016 (following the SWM with a DO of ~ 0 ml.l-1), which was as deep as 75 m in September (pre-SWM with a DO of ~ 0.2 ml.l-1) and further down to 105 m in December (with a DO of ~ 0.2 ml.l-1) (Figure 3B). These observations collectively suggest a significant shoaling and intensification of the OMZ near the Godavari River mouth during the fall season. Thus, the enhanced Chl-a and particle backscatter (between 25 and 55 m depth) during the fall season driven by GRD (Figure 1) coincides with shoaling and intensification of the OMZ near the Godavari River mouth. This provides strong evidence for the potential impact of high organic matter sinking on the dynamics of the BoB-OMZ. The limited availability of BGC-ARGO observations in the GRD region restricts our ability to investigate the seasonal evolution of DO. Therefore, we turn to the objectively analyzed WOA18 DO data, despite its coastal data gap. WOA18 offers sufficient coverage (&gt;80% data availability) for a 63-year period (1955-2017), enabling seasonal analysis of various ocean fields. Figures 4A&#8211;D display the vertical distribution of DO (surface to 500 m) in the BoB near GRD (16.8&#176;N) during different seasons, derived from WOA18. High DO concentrations (&gt;4-5 ml.l-1) characterize the basin's surface layers (~0-80 m) year-round. Below this, the OMZ prevails, with its upper boundary primarily residing between 80-200 m, exhibiting seasonal and spatial variations. Winter and spring months reveal similar spatial patterns of the OMZ (Figures 4A, B), with its upper limit confined between 80-110 m depth. A pronounced OMZ (DO &lt; 0.3 ml.l-1) persists below 500 m throughout these seasons. Summer (July) exhibits distinct spatial patterns from the previous two seasons (Figure 4C). Except for a narrow depth range (200-250 m, 92.5-93.5&#176;E), DO levels below the mixed layer generally remain above 0.2 ml.l-1. Additionally, the OMZ upper boundary in the western basin deepens to 110-130 m. The fall season witnesses the most profound OMZ expansion and intensification near the western basin, where the Godavari River discharges (Figure 4D). DO levels below 0.1 ml.l-1 appear between 60-175 m in this region, a stark contrast to summer values of 1-1.5 ml.l-1 (Figure 4C). The shoaling and intensification of the OMZ at subsurface depths (40-200 m) near the Godavari River mouth, evident in the BGC- ARGO and WOA18 data during fall, necessitates further investigation. To validate this localized phenomenon, we delved deeper into the seasonal evolution of DO within this critical depth range (40-200 m) in the western BoB (Figures 4E&#8211;H). Winter reveals a clear influx of highly oxygenated water from the southern BoB (Figure 4E), aided by the prevailing ocean current system (Figure 2B). This influx maintains sufficient DO (&gt;1 ml.l-1) in the western BoB throughout winter and spring (Figures 4E, F). Even in summer (July) (Figure 4G), subsurface DO (averaged over 40-200 m) near the Godavari River mouth remains moderate, exceeding 1.2 ml.l-1. However, a dramatic shift occurs in the fall (October) as the region transforms into an oxygen-depleted zone (&lt;0.5 ml.l-1) (Figure 4H). This stark contrast highlights the dynamic seasonal cycle of subsurface DO in the western BoB. While oxygenated waters prevail near the Godavari delta basin during winter, spring, and summer, a localized and intense OMZ establishes itself near the river mouth during fall. Thus, coinciding with the retreat of the SWM season, the confluence of increased organic matter input from the Godavari River and enhanced stratification likely contributes to the generation of an intense and shallow subsurface OMZ (40-200 m) near the river mouth. The genesis and dynamics of the pronounced subsurface OMZ observed near the GRD region after the retreat of the SWM season are likely influenced by a complex interplay of physical and biogeochemical factors. In this section, we focus on analyzing other processes such as surface ocean circulation and divergence in the western BoB near the GRD region (Figure 5) using GODAS data, recognizing their crucial role in upwelling and associated biogeochemical processes influencing OMZ dynamics. The surface circulation in the western BoB exhibits distinct seasonal patterns near the Godavari River mouth, playing a crucial role in regional upwelling and potentially influencing the observed OMZ dynamics. The pre-Southwest Monsoon and SWM seasons are characterized by strong northward coastal currents and an eastward current across the BoB, as shown in Figures 5B, C, respectively. Additionally, during the SWM season, south-westerly winds induce positive divergence along the western BoB coast, favoring coastal upwelling (Figure 5C). Following the retreat of the SWM season, the strong monsoon currents subside, and southward- moving coastal currents dominate the western BoB (Figure 5D). This shift creates favorable conditions for upwelling near the GRD region and northwards, indicated by positive surface divergence (Figure 5D). Winter (January) sees a further weakening of the southward current, and positive divergence persists near the GRD region, suggesting continued upwelling potential (Figure 5A). Thus the oceanic region near the GRD experiences favorable conditions for upwelling throughout the SWM, fall, and late winter periods due to the combined influence of surface currents and divergence. This sustained upwelling could potentially contribute to the observed surge in chlorophyll-a (Chl-a), NPP, and the subsequent intensification and vertical expansion (shoaling) of the OMZ observed after the retreat of the SWM season. To provide insights into the interplay between GRD and upwelling in shaping dissolved DO and OMZ dynamics in the BoB, we selected two geographically distinct study regions. Box A (82-84&#176;E, 15.5-17&#176;N) lies directly at the Godavari River mouth, maximizing its exposure to GRD influence and benefiting from favorable upwelling conditions during the SWM season. In contrast, Box B (84-86&#176;E, 17-18.5&#176;N), located slightly north, experiences minimized GRD influence while retaining similar upwelling conditions during the SWM season. This strategic selection allows for a comparative analysis, disentangling the individual and combined effects of GRD and upwelling on DO and OMZ dynamics. Figure 6 represents the seasonal evolution of vertical velocity (GODAS data), and those of Chl-a (OC-CCI data), NPP (OC-CCI), and depth-averaged (40-200 m) dissolved oxygen (WOA18 data) in these two selected oceanic regions. The analysis unfolds similar qualitative patterns for vertical velocity (upwelling) in both boxes. In both the oceanic regions, upwelling increases with the emergence of the SWM season and starts declining with its withdrawal. In comparison, Box A records higher values for upwelling than Box B (Figure 6A). The highest upwelling was recorded in July in both boxes, 0.72&#215;10-5 m.s-1 in Box A and 0.58&#215;10-5 m.s-1 in Box B. The increase in upwelling during the SWM season clearly reflects the seasonal evolution of Chl-a in Box A, whereas Box B shows a slight decreasing trend from June to July, although it maintained an overall increasing trend during the SWM season (Figure 6B). Both the regions reflected mild Chl-a values during rest of the year. In comparison, Chl-a blooms in Box A (0.8-0.9 mg.m-3) were almost twice as intense as Box B (0.4-0.5 mg.m-3) during the SWM season. NPP also showed a similar seasonal signature (Figure 6C). Both boxes highlighted an increasing trend in NPP during the SWM season and showed similar patterns during the rest of the year. Similar to the Chl-a distribution, Box A recorded very high (&gt; 1100 mgC.m-3) NPP distribution compared to Box B (&lt; 850 mgC.m-3) during the SWM season. The rise in Chl- a and NPP during the SWM season significantly impacted seasonal DO fluctuations in both study regions (Figure 6D). While DO exhibited a mildly increasing trend in both boxes during late winter and pre-monsoon, it displayed a substantial decline with the onset of the SWM season. In Box A, DO plummeted from 3 ml.l-1 in May to a critical low of 0.1 ml.l-1 in October (fall), representing a drastic decrease of 2.9 ml.l-1. In contrast, Box B experienced a smaller decline, with DO decreasing from 2.2 ml.l-1 in June to an average of 0.55 ml.l-1 during fall (September-November), representing a decrease of 1.75 ml.l-1. In conclusion, it is evident that SWM- driven biogeochemical activity was significantly enhanced in Box A, directly influenced by GRD, leading to pronounced oxygen consumption during fall. This comparative analysis highlights the crucial role of GRD in shaping DO and OMZ dynamics in the BoB. This study delves into the profound biogeochemical impact of GRD in the BoB, with a particular focus on the region near the river mouth. Our key finding is the intriguing presence of an intense and shallow OMZ within the subsurface (40-200 m) depths near the Godavari River mouth during the post-monsoon season which has hardly been mentioned previously. Notably, this phenomenon differs from the conventional intermediate-depth BoB-OMZ prevalent in the basin (McCreary et al., 2013). The temporal evolution of this shallow OMZ was elucidated through data from two BGC-ARGO floats located close to the river discharge region. Their observations revealed a clear intensification and shoaling of the OMZ during fall. To unveil the spatial extent and context of this phenomenon, we leveraged the broader coverage of WOA18 data, facilitating comparisons with other crucial variables. Furthermore, to disentangle the relative influence of GRD and upwelling on OMZ dynamics, we conducted a comparative analysis in two geographically distinct locations. This comparative analysis proved the pivotal role of GRD in shaping the biogeochemical environment near the river mouth. Despite both regions experiencing similar upwelling patterns, the area directly influenced by GRD exhibited significantly higher Chl-a blooms, enhanced NPP during the SWM season, and a more pronounced oxygen consumption during fall. These observations strongly suggest that the extensive nutrient influx from GRD fuels increased primary productivity, leading to enhanced organic matter suspension and subsequent oxygen depletion in the subsurface layers, culminating in the observed intense and shallow OMZ. Our findings paint a compelling picture of the substantial influence of GRD on BoB biogeochemistry, particularly in the vicinity of the river mouth. Briefly, during the SWM season, the influx of nutrients from GRD, combined with enhanced coastal upwelling, creates favorable conditions for phytoplankton blooms. These blooms, peaking in August and September, are characterized by high Chl-a concentrations and lead to a surge in NPP. However, this elevated productivity comes with a subsequent cost. As the blooms senesce and decompose by fall, an elevation in suspended organic matter at the subsurface depths (40-200 m) develops. This organic matter fuels the activity of heterotrophic microbial communities, leading to intense oxygen consumption through respiration. This microbial respiration, coupled with the reduced atmospheric oxygen supply due to strong stratification, drives the shoaling and intensification of the OMZ off the Godavari River mouth. Understanding and quantifying these impacts are crucial for various reasons. First, alterations in GRD can directly affect primary productivity and food webs in the coastal zone. Second, changes in the OMZ's intensity can influence the release of greenhouse gases such as CO2 and N2O, potentially impacting global climate change. Finally, understanding the dynamic interplay between riverine inputs, upwelling, and biogeochemical processes is critical for predicting and managing the future state of the BoB ecosystem. In summary, although the discharge of the Godavari River is negligible compared to other rivers flowing into the BoB, GRD plays a pivotal role in shaping the biogeochemistry of the bay, with profound impacts on primary productivity, oxygen dynamics, and greenhouse gas emissions. Further research is needed to fully understand the intricate interactions between GRD, upwelling, and biogeochemical processes, and to predict the consequences of future alterations in riverine inputs on this vital ecosystem. It should, however, be noted that the interpretations derived from our analysis are subject to the limited temporal and spatial sample extent, which precludes us from any statistical significance test of the results. We are in the process of initiating a few high-resolution sensitivity experiments with the ocean model that will be 15-20 years long. The outputs will enable us to quantify the contributions of each parameter separately.</description>
      <author>K. S. Sreejith, V. V. S. S. Sarma, P. Sreenivas, F. Feba, Ibrahim Hoteit, Karumuri Ashok</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1523183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The synergy of transformation of isomorphous phyllosilicate structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17308/kcmf.2024.26/11944</link>
      <description>A. G. Chetverikova, &#1042;. &#1053;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1082;&#1072;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, O. N. Kanygina, Mikhail M. Seregin, A. A. Yudin, &#1050;&#1086;&#1085;&#1076;&#1077;&#1085;&#1089;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1089;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1099; &#1080; &#1084;&#1077;&#1078;&#1092;&#1072;&#1079;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1075;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1094;&#1099;. 26(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404554998

                The article presents an analysis of the synergy of structural transformations of phyllosilicates subjected to high temperatures and microwave radiation in terms of the destruction and formation of crystal structures. Studying the synergy of transformations of crystal structures is essential for the development of new materials and technologies, because it helps to create materials with unique properties, which cannot be obtained when using the same factors separately. The material used in the study was a polymineral complex, which contained quartz, montmorillonite, kaolinite, chlorite, paragonite, and iron oxides (listed from the largest to the smallest mass fraction). The methods used in the study allowed us to assess the structural transformations. Averaged structural formulas of the studied phyllosilicates were calculated using the oxygen method combined with a recalculation method based on the results of a microprobe analysis. Differential thermal analysis demonstrated a synergistic effect of high temperature and microwave fields registered as a decrease inthe temperature gradient of the ceramics and initiation of the sintering process at lower temperatures and with greater intensity. All the treated samples contained the amorphous phase in significant concentrations: from 15 to 25 vol. %. Half of the three-layer phyllosilicates (chlorite and montmorillonite) were destroyed by the microwave field. Kaolinite and paragonite practically did not react to external factors. The synergistic effect was the most obvious in the structural transformations of silicon and iron oxides. Our experiments demonstrated for the first time the mechanism of formation of magnetite and hematite crystals from X-ray amorphous iron-containing films covering the particles of clay minerals. The use of the MW field and the resulting dehydration led to the formation of crystals of nuclei of iron oxides. The following high-temperature processes activated an increase in aggregated iron (magnetite and hematite). The X-ray diffraction analysis determined the presence of a synergistic effect in the evolution of structures, which could not be identified by means of IR-spectroscopy. The EPR spectroscopy allowed us to register the states of rare irregular cells with foreign paramagnetic atoms. The shift of the foreign Fe3+ from the geometric centers of octahedral crystal cells towards the minima of potential energy caused by the Jahn-Teller effect decreased the potential energy of the crystal lattice. At the same time, some chemical bonds forming the crystal cellbecame stronger, while others weakened</description>
      <author>A. G. Chetverikova, &#1042;. &#1053;. &#1052;&#1072;&#1082;&#1072;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;, O. N. Kanygina, Mikhail M. Seregin, A. A. Yudin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17308/kcmf.2024.26/11944</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Extreme Low-mass End of the Mass&#8211;Metallicity Relation at z &#8764; 7</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ad8dc9</link>
      <description>Iryna Chemerynska, Hakim Atek, Pratika Dayal, Lukas J. Furtak, Robert Feldmann, Jenny E. Greene, Michael V. Maseda, Themiya Nanayakkara, Pascal A. Oesch, Seiji Fujimoto, Ivo Labb&#233;, Rachel Bezanson, Gabriel Brammer, Sam E. Cutler, Joel Leja, Richard Pan, Sedona H. Price, Bingjie Wang, John R. Weaver, Katherine E. Whitaker, The Astrophysical Journal Letters. 976(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404482455

                Abstract The mass&#8211;metallicity relation provides crucial insights into the baryon cycle in galaxies and strong constraints on galaxy formation models. We use JWST NIRSpec observations from the UNCOVER program to measure the gas-phase metallicity in a sample of eight galaxies during the epoch of reionization at z = 6&#8211;8. Thanks to the strong lensing of the galaxy cluster Abell 2744, we are able to probe extremely low stellar masses between 10 6 and 10 8 M &#8857; . Using strong-line diagnostics and the most recent JWST calibrations, we derive extremely low oxygen abundances in the range of 12 + log(O/H) = 6.7&#8211;7.8. By combining this sample with more massive galaxies at similar redshifts, we derive a best-fit relation of 12 + log(O/H) =  &#8722;   0.076   &#8722; 0.03   + 0.03   &#215;   ( log (   M   &#8902;   ) )   2   +   1.61   &#8722; 0.52   + 0.52    &#215;  log (   M   &#8902;   ) &#8722;   0.26   &#8722; 0.10   + 0.10    , which becomes steeper than determinations at z &#8764; 3&#8211;6 toward low-mass galaxies. Our results show a clear redshift evolution in the overall normalization of the relation, galaxies at higher redshift having significantly lower metallicities at a given mass. A comparison with theoretical models provides important constraints on which physical processes, such as metal mixing, star formation or feedback recipes, are important in reproducing the observations. Additionally, these galaxies exhibit star formation rates that are higher by a factor of a few to tens compared to extrapolated relations at similar redshifts or theoretical predictions of main-sequence galaxies, pointing to a recent burst of star formation. All these observations are indicative of the highly stochastic star formation and interstellar medium enrichment expected in these low-mass systems, suggesting that feedback mechanisms in high- z dwarf galaxies might be different from those in place at higher masses.</description>
      <author>Iryna Chemerynska, Hakim Atek, Pratika Dayal, Lukas J. Furtak, Robert Feldmann, Jenny E. Greene, Michael V. Maseda, Themiya Nanayakkara, Pascal A. Oesch, Seiji Fujimoto, Ivo Labb&#233;, Rachel Bezanson, Gabriel Brammer, Sam E. Cutler, Joel Leja, Richard Pan, Sedona H. Price, Bingjie Wang, John R. Weaver, Katherine E. Whitaker</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ad8dc9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metagenomic analysis sheds light on the mixotrophic lifestyle of bacterial phylum &lt;i&gt;Zhuqueibacterota&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/imt2.249</link>
      <description>Zheng&#8208;Han Lian, Nimaichand Salam, Sha Tan, Yang Yuan, Meng&#8208;Meng Li, Yu&#8208;Xian Li, Ze&#8208;Tao Liu, Chao&#8208;Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yu&#8208;Ting OuYang, Caiyu Lu, Jingyi Zhang, Ying Chen, Le&#8208;Bin Chen, Zhen&#8208;Hao Luo, Bin Ma, Zheng&#8208;Shuang Hua, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Wen&#8208;Jun Li, Lan Liu, iMeta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404650498

                Zhuqueibacterota is a novel bacterial phylum proposed based on hot spring metagenomes and public metagenome-assembled genomes, classified within the Fibrobacterota-Chlorobiota-Bacteroidota superphylum. This globally distributed phylum consists of one class and five orders, with the majority of its members being facultative anaerobes. Notably, the order Zhuqueibacterales utilizes hydrogen as an electron donor for carbon fixation through the Calvin Benson Bassham cycle. Phylogenetic and metabolic analyses reveal the phylum's key role in the carbon cycle, with frequent horizontal gene transfer events influencing its evolutionary trajectory. To the editor, The candidate phylum KSB1 has been identified as anaerobic heterotrophic bacterium and detected in various environments. However, little known about its diversity, ecology, and evolutionary history. In this study, we analyzed 30 new metagenome-assembled genomes (MAGs) from the Tengchong hot spring and 45 public MAGs. Phylogenetic analyses based on the draft genome and 16S rRNA gene indicate they form a distinct group within the Fibrobacterota-Chlorobiota-Bacteroidota (FCB) superphylum, and thus we propose their classification as a new phylum, herein Zhuqueibacterota, which contain five orders and one class. Members of Zhuqueibacterota are globally distributed and likely facultative anaerobes, with one order exhibiting autotrophy via the Calvin Benson Bassham (CBB) cycle by using hydrogen as an electron donor. Metabolic predictions at the community level suggest that Zhuqueibacterota play a significant role in the carbon fixation of hot spring. Ancestral state reconstruction points to frequent horizontal gene transfer (HGT) events throughout Zhuqueibacterota evolution. Facultative anaerobic traits appear to be ancestral, with some lineage losing hydrogen oxidation capabilities while acquiring carbon fixation capabilities through HGT in Zhuqueibacterales. These results shed light on diversity, ecological roles, and evolutionary history of Zhuqueibacterota, highlighting their significance in the carbon cycle. The earth harbors a huge biodiversity of eukaryotic and prokaryotic microorganisms. However, only a small portion of bacteria is culturable under laboratory conditions and most bacterial phyla have no cultured members. The candidate bacterial phylum KSB1, as one of the uncultured phyla, was first identified in sulfur-rich marine sediments, and now was recognized for its broad ecological adaptability [1]. In estuary sediments, genome studies revealed its capacity for carbohydrate metabolism and &#946;-oxidation [2]. KSB1 members from hydrothermal sediment possess genes encoding benzylsuccinate synthase and alkylsuccinate synthase, suggesting a role in anaerobic hydrocarbon degradation [3]. In wetland sediments, KSB1 MAGs encode enzymes such as isopropanol dehydrogenase, phosphotransbutyrylase, and butyrate kinase, further highlighting their ecological versatility. Notably, KSB1 was also recovered from metagenomic data of hot spring, indicating KSB1 may harbor new functional niches that allow it to grow in the extreme environment. In addition, although nearly 100 MAGs of KSB1 have been reconstructed from various environments, the limited number of high-quality genomes hinders the ability to understand the ecological roles and metabolism of KSB1. Thus, more comprehensive research is needed to explore their metabolic pathways and evolutionary history. To address this, we collected available KSB1 genomes from public database and extracted new MAGs from hot spring samples. Our study significantly expands the genomic diversity of KSB1, clarify the phylogenetic relationships, and revealing its facultative anaerobic lifestyle and carbon fixation potential via the CBB cycle. We hereby designate this phylum as Zhuqueibacterota. Continuous sampling of hot springs in Tengchong County, Yunnan province, China, has been conducted for metagenomic studies since 2016, and 30 high-quality MAGs (Table S1) assigned to KSB1 were reconstructed from 16 metagenomes of hot springs. In total, 75 high-quality KSB1 MAGs were used to construct phylogenetic trees, including 45 genomes (Table S2) downloaded from GenBank. A maximum-likelihood tree, employing Bac120 marker sets from genome taxonomy database (GTDB), revealed that KSB1 forms a monophyletic clade within the FCB superphylum [4], and clearly separated from other phyla (Figure S1A). Phylogenetic tree based on 16S rRNA gene further supports the classification of KSB1 as a distinct phylum taxon in the domain Bacteria under the kingdom Psuedomonadati [5] (Figure S1B). To resolve the phylogenetic affiliations within phylum Zhuqueibacterota, we constructed a maximum likelihood tree with a concatenated set of single-copy marker genes. Previous analyses identified four clades within KSB1 [1]; however, our phylogenetic analysis revealed five distinct groups, corresponding to five orders of the undescribed phylum KSB1 in GTDB r214 (Figure 1A) and clarified that clade II (GTDB taxonomy: p__JdFR-76) is not part of KSB1 but a sister phylum. Average amino acid identity (AAI, 95%&#8211;100% for same species) [6], and average nucleotide identity (ANI, 95%&#8211;100% for same species) (Table S3, Figure S2) were used to classify the novel lineage on the species, which were consistent with the GTDB classification. In addition, phylogenomic tree and GTDB toolkit (GTDB-Tk) (Tables S1 and S2) based analyses were performed to classify the novel lineage on genus levels and higher taxonomic ranks. Finally, we identified 1 class, 5 orders, 14 families, 27 genera, and 40 species from the 75 MAGs (Table S4), including 9 novel species from our own 30 MAGs. Following the recommendations for defining species and higher ranks of not-yet-cultured bacteria using MAGs as type material [6, 7], we proposed the name Zhuqueibacterota phyl. nov. for the KSB1 with five orders: Zhuqueibacterales (O1), Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), Thermofontimicrobiales (O4), and Oceanimicrobiales (O5). Using 16S rRNA gene sequences as queries in the IMNGS platform, Zhuqueibacterota was detected across six biotopes: aquatic, sediment, soil, hydrothermal vents, animal- and plant-associated environments (Figure 1B). The phylum is particularly prevalent in soil and biofilm samples, where it constitutes 3%&#8211;10% of biofilm-associated communities (Table S5), suggesting that biofilms may serve as a protective niche for these bacteria. Zhuqueibacterales (O1), the most widely distributed order (Figure 1C), was found in diverse environments. Residuimicrobiales (O2) and Oleimicrobiales (O3) were predominantly detected in hydrothermal vents and sediment, and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4) was enriched in marine environments. Despite limited data for Oceanimicrobiales (O5), Zhuqueibacterota's broad ecological presence (Figure 1C) highlights its adaptability across various habitats, emphasizing its ecological significance. Previous studies suggested that Zhuqueibacterota is enriched in anoxic environments [1], leading to the hypothesis of an anaerobic lifestyle. In our study, genes associated with anaerobic metabolism, such as acetyl-CoA synthetase (acs), phosphate acetyltransferase (pta), acetate kinase (ack), aldehyde dehydrogenase (aldh), and alcohol dehydrogenase (adh), were detected across all clades of Zhuqueibacterota (Table S6), suggesting they may have the ability to produce ethanol through fermentation [8]. Additionally, we identified the Rnf complexes [9] were widely distributed among Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Phylogenetic analysis of the rnfABCDEG operon indicated that they clustered with anaerobic microorganisms (Figure S3), further suggesting the potential anaerobic lifestyle of Residuimicrobiales (O2), Oleimicrobiales (O3), and Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Remarkably, Zhuqueibacterota harbored cydAB genes, encoding the cytochrome bd ubiquinol oxidase, which provides an O2-directed respiratory chain under low-oxygen conditions. The coxABC genes [10] were identified in all MAGs of the Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5), as well as in three MAGs of the Residuimicrobiales (O2) and two MAGs of the Thermofontimicrobiales (O4). Additionally, we observed that several MAGs from Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) encoded the aerobic aa3-type cytochrome c oxidase [10]. However, the genes of complete pathways for oxidative phosphorylation were just widely distributed in Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5). These findings suggest that members of Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) may have the ability to utilize oxygen as a terminal electron acceptor. Considering these observations, we propose that members of Zhuqueibacterales (O1) and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) are more likely facultative anaerobes, rather than being obligate anaerobes. Through metabolic reconstruction, all Zhuqueibacterota orders contain complete genes for glycolysis, gluconeogenesis, and pentose phosphate pathways (Figure 1D). MAGs assigned to the Zhuqueibacterales (O1), Thermofontimicrobiales (O4), and Oceanimicrobiales (O5) harbor the complete gene sets for the TCA cycle. We also identified a diverse array of carbohydrate-active enzymes (CAZymes) among the 75 MAGs, including 79 glycoside hydrolases (GHs), 10 glycosyl transferases (GTs), 10 carbohydrate esterases (CEs), 8 polysaccharide lyases (PLs), and 10 carbohydrate-binding modules (CBMs) (Table S7). Interestingly, the gene encoding the large subunit of ribulose-1,5-bisphosphate carboxylase/oxygenase (RuBisCO) was identified in 35 MAGs of Zhuqueibacterales (O1). Phylogenetic analysis revealed that the RuBisCO large subunit (rbcL) gene belongs to form I group (Figure 2A), which plays a crucial role in carbon fixation via the CBB cycle [11]. Moreover, genes encoding RuBisCO small subunit (rbcS), phosphoribulokinase (PRK), transketolase (TKT), fructose-1,6-bisphosphate aldolase (FBPA), fructose-1,6-bisphosphatase (FBPase), and ribulose-5-phosphate 3-epimerase (RuPE) were found near the rbcL gene cluster (Figure 2B). Based on these observations, we hypothesize that members of Zhuqueibacterota possess the capability for carbon fixation via the CBB cycle. Notably, the absence of sedoheptulose-1,7-bisphosphatase (SBPase) and the presence of transaldolase (TAL) suggest that Zhuqueibacterota uses the transaldolase-variant of the CBB cycle [12, 13]. Carbon fixation via the CBB cycle requires significant energy and reducing equivalents, and hydrogen is a critical energy source in terrestrial hot springs [14] and hydrothermal vents [15]. Numerous prokaryotes can utilize H2 and CO2 as their energy and carbon source [16]. In our study, genes annotated to encode hydrogenases were present in Zhuqueibacterota, and the phylogenetic analyses of hydrogenases revealed five different clades ([Ni&#8211;Fe] group 1d, 3b-3d, and [Fe&#8211;Fe] group) (Figure S4). In Zhuqueibacterales (O1) MAGs, especially those containing CBB gene cluster, we identified two types of hydrogenases (Figure 2C). The [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1d hydrogenase, a membrane-bound hydrogenase, transfers electrons from H2 to the respiratory chain via membrane-connected cytochromes [17] (Figure S4). Additionally, the cytosolic [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 3b hydrogenase transfers electrons generated by H2 oxidation to NAD+ [18], which serves as a reducing equivalent, for carbon fixation or for ATP production through the respiratory chain [17]. The biosynthesis and maturation of [Ni&#8211;Fe] hydrogenase are catalyzed by six Hyp proteins (hypABCDEF) [19]. The co-localization of hydrogenase maturation proteins, [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1 d and 3b hydrogenases (Figure 2C) indicate that Zhuqueibacterales (O1) likely utilizes hydrogen as an energy source for carbon fixation. The CBB cycle operates aerobically [20], and both the [Ni&#8211;Fe]-group 1d and 3b hydrogenases exhibit O2 tolerance, maintaining hydrogen oxidation even in the presence of oxygen. This further supports the hypothesis that Zhuqueibacterota is facultative anaerobic mixotrophy. Utilizing METABOLIC v4.0, we constructed a community metabolic network comprising with 186 medium/high-quality MAGs (completeness &gt;50% and contamination &lt;6%) derived from JZ2 hot spring (JZ2_202007). Despite being represented by only two MAGs, Zhuqueibacterota exhibited the highest relative abundance (15.48%). It contributed to 24 metabolic processes, with a relative contribution exceeding 25% (Figure S5, Table S8). Notably, Zhuqueibacterota dominated carbon fixation via the CBB cycle, with the highest contribution (57.9%) among all microbial taxa (Table S8). These findings suggest that Zhuqueibacterota, with its chemolithoautotrophic capabilities, plays a vital role in this ecosystem. To decipher the evolutionary histories of the Zhuqueibacterota, we predicted gene gain and loss events mapping onto a Bayesian tree showed that contemporary Zhuqueibacterota harbor more gene families over time (Figure 2D, Figure S6), with 71% of HGT events occurred within Zhuqueibacterales (O1), mostly from hot spring-associated MAGs. HGT played a major role in genome diversity, despite the common trend of genome reduction in hot spring environments. The ancestral Zhuqueibacterota likely possessed hydrogenase, with later loss events leading to the loss of this hydrogen utilization capability in some lineages. The cydAB gene (Figure 2E, Table S9) for high oxygen stress response was acquired early, while the coxABC gene was independently acquired by different lineages (Figure 2E, Table S9). Anaerobic fermentation-related genes were lost at multiple evolutionary nodes, potentially contributing to metabolic diversity, indicating that the ancestors of Zhuqueibacterota were facultative anaerobic bacteria. Genes related to the CBB cycle, such as rbcL, rbcS, and PRK, were acquired gradually. Over time, Zhuqueibacterota inhabiting thermal environments gained the ability for carbon fixation via the CBB cycle. In this study, we have expanded our understanding of the uncultured phylum KSB1, herein Zhuqueibacterota, by utilizing high-quality genomes to explore its diversity and function. Our analysis indicated that Zhuqueibacterota has clear functional differentiation, and distinct environmental preferences among its clades. Notably, this phylum represents a group of facultative anaerobic chemoautotrophs, which play a pivotal role in sustaining microbial communities in hot springs. Ancestral state reconstructions suggest the facultative anaerobic lifestyle of their ancestor, while carbon fixation capabilities probably evolved through HGT. Overall, this study provides new insights into the ecological functions of Zhuqueibacterota and open avenues for further research. Moreover, the findings indicate the possibility of isolating and purifying members of this phylum using the hydrogen-oxidizing autotrophic enrichment system. Zheng-Han Lian: Writing&#8212;review and editing; writing&#8212;original draft; software. Nimaichand Salam: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis; data curation; investigation. Sha Tan: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; visualization. Yang Yuan: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; visualization. Meng-Meng Li: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; resources. Yu-Xian Li: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software. Ze-Tao Liu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; data curation. Chao-Jian Hu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; methodology. Ai-Ping Lv: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis. Yu-Ting OuYang: Writing&#8212;review and editing; validation. Cai-Yu Lu: Writing&#8212;review and editing; formal analysis. Jing-Yi Zhang: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization. Ying Chen: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; data curation. Le-Bin Chen: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software; resources. Zhen-Hao Luo: Writing&#8212;review and editing; resources; validation. Bin Ma: Writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software. Zheng-Shuang Hua: Writing&#8212;review and editing; software. Jian-Yu Jiao: Supervision; writing&#8212;review and editing; writing&#8212;original draft; software; funding acquisition. Wen-Jun Li: Supervision; writing&#8212;review and editing; funding acquisition; project administration; resources. Lan Liu: Supervision; writing&#8212;original draft; writing&#8212;review and editing; visualization; software; validation; funding acquisition; project administration; data curation; resources. This research received financial support from the Key R&amp;D Program of Zhejiang Province (2023C02004, 2023C020015), the Key-Area Research and Development Program of Guangdong Province (2022B0202110001), the National Natural Science Foundation of China (Grants No. 92251302, 32200010, 32300001, 32200007, and 32370011), the National Science and Technology Fundamental Resources Investigation Program of China (2021FY100900), and the Fundamental Research Funds for the Universities (Nos. 23ptpy11, 23ptpy136, and 23ptpy137). We extend our sincere appreciation to the staff at Yunnan Tengchong Volcano for their invaluable assistance and gracious permission granted for sample collection. Special thanks are due to Dr. Chih-Min Chang from Guangdong Magigene Biotechnology Co., Ltd., China, for his expert guidance and support throughout the data analysis process. The authors declare no conflicts of interest. No animals or humans were involved in this study. The MAGs discussed in this research have been archived in the GenBank database under the BioProject ID PRJNA895542 (https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/bioproject/PRJNA895542/). Accession numbers for each individual MAG are detailed in Table S1. The data and scripts used are saved in GitHub https://github.com/lianzhh-pub/Code_for_iMeta2024. Supplementary materials (methods, figures, tables, graphical abstract, slides, videos, Chinese translated version, and updated materials) may be found in the online DOI or iMeta Science http://www.imeta.science/. The data that supports the findings of this study are available in the supplementary material of this article. Figure S1. Phylogeny of Zhuqueibacterota. Figure S2. The ANI/AAI heatmap of all pairwise comparisons. Figure S3. The phylogenetic tree based on concatenated alignment of Rnf complex genes. Figure S4. Phylogenetic trees and classification of hydrogenases and metabolic model of hydrogen-oxidizing bacteria. Figure S5. Microbial contribution to carbon, nitrogen, and sulfur cycling in hot spring. Figure S6. Ancestral genome content reconstruction using COUNT software. Figure S7. Phylogenetic tree of nosZ gene. Figure S8. Variation and correlation of genome size and GC content across orders of Zhuqueibacterota. Figure S9. Plot of Principal Coordinates Analysis (PCoA) based on functional traits of Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S1. General genomic features of Candidate Division KSB1 genomes from hot spring. Table S2. Genomic overview of Candidate Division KSB1 reference genome. Table S3. ANI/AAI values for each genome pair. Table S4. Brief nomenclature of Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S5. Global distribution and relative abundances of the Zhuqueibacterota. Table S6. List of genes in the metabolic model of Zhuqueibacterota. Table S7. CAZyme statistics for Zhuqueibacterota MAGs. Table S8. The MW-score for JZ2 hot spring metagenomic dataset. Table S9. Gene gain and loss events detected at key nodes. Please note: The publisher is not responsible for the content or functionality of any supporting information supplied by the authors. Any queries (other than missing content) should be directed to the corresponding author for the article.</description>
      <author>Zheng&#8208;Han Lian, Nimaichand Salam, Sha Tan, Yang Yuan, Meng&#8208;Meng Li, Yu&#8208;Xian Li, Ze&#8208;Tao Liu, Chao&#8208;Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yu&#8208;Ting OuYang, Caiyu Lu, Jingyi Zhang, Ying Chen, Le&#8208;Bin Chen, Zhen&#8208;Hao Luo, Bin Ma, Zheng&#8208;Shuang Hua, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Wen&#8208;Jun Li, Lan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/imt2.249</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eLife Assessment: Spatial and temporal coordination of Duox/TrpA1/Dh31 and IMD pathways is required for the efficient elimination of pathogenic bacteria in the intestine of Drosophila larvae</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.98716.3.sa0</link>
      <description>Bruno Lemaitre, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404631782

                Full text Figures and data Peer review Side by side eLife Assessment This article describes a novel mechanism allows Drosophila to combat enteric pathogens while also preserving the beneficial indigenous microbiota. The authors provide compelling evidence that oral infection of Drosophila larvae by pathogenic bacteria activate a valve that traps the intruders in the anterior midgut, allowing them to be killed by antimicrobial peptides. This is an important finding revealing a new mechanism of host defense in the gut of insects. https://doi.org/10.7554/eLife.98716.3.sa0 Significance of the findings: Important: Findings that have theoretical or practical implications beyond a single subfield Landmark Fundamental Important Valuable Useful Strength of evidence: Compelling: Evidence that features methods, data and analyses more rigorous than the current state-of-the-art Exceptional Compelling Convincing Solid Incomplete Inadequate During the peer-review process the editor and reviewers write an eLife Assessment that summarises the significance of the findings reported in the article (on a scale ranging from landmark to useful) and the strength of the evidence (on a scale ranging from exceptional to inadequate). Learn more about eLife Assessments Abstract Introduction Results Discussion Materials and methods Data availability References Article and author information Metrics Abstract Multiple gut antimicrobial mechanisms are coordinated in space and time to efficiently fight foodborne pathogens. In Drosophila melanogaster, production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and antimicrobial peptides (AMPs) together with intestinal cell renewal play a key role in eliminating gut microbes. A complementary mechanism would be to isolate and treat pathogenic bacteria while allowing colonization by commensals. Using real-time imaging to follow the fate of ingested bacteria, we demonstrate that while commensal Lactiplantibacillus plantarum freely circulate within the intestinal lumen, pathogenic strains such as Erwinia carotovora or Bacillus thuringiensis, are blocked in the anterior midgut where they are rapidly eliminated by antimicrobial peptides. This sequestration of pathogenic bacteria in the anterior midgut requires the Duox enzyme in enterocytes, and both TrpA1 and Dh31 in enteroendocrine cells. Supplementing larval food with hCGRP, the human homolog of Dh31, is sufficient to block the bacteria, suggesting the existence of a conserved mechanism. While the immune deficiency (IMD) pathway is essential for eliminating the trapped bacteria, it is dispensable for the blockage. Genetic manipulations impairing bacterial compartmentalization result in abnormal colonization of posterior midgut regions by pathogenic bacteria. Despite a functional IMD pathway, this ectopic colonization leads to bacterial proliferation and larval death, demonstrating the critical role of bacteria anterior sequestration in larval defense. Our study reveals a temporal orchestration during which pathogenic bacteria, but not innocuous, are confined in the anterior part of the midgut in which they are eliminated in an IMD-pathway-dependent manner. Introduction One of the key avenues by which bacterial pathogens infiltrate a host is through the ingestion of contaminated food. Following the entry of bacteria in the intestine, the host defense mechanisms will operate in a temporal manner, with mechanical and constitutive chemical barriers serving as the first line of defense, followed by inducible mechanisms involving the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS), the transcription, translation, and secretion of antimicrobial peptides (AMPs) as well as inter-organ signaling to cope with possible upcoming stages of infection. This temporality is evident between innate and adaptive immunity, with the former considered the primary defense line that contains and combats the threat while preparing the more subtle adaptive response. To focus on deciphering innate immune processes, the insect Drosophila melanogaster has been widely and successfully used (Neyen et al., 2014; Younes et al., 2020). This model has made it possible to establish the chronology of the events involved in the defense against pathogenic bacteria. In Drosophila, as in all metazoans, a layer made of mucus, completed with a peritrophic membrane in insect midguts, protects the intestine lining from direct contact with pathogens (Hegedus et al., 2009; Lemaitre and Miguel-Aliaga, 2013; Pelaseyed et al., 2014). In adult Drosophila, a conserved immune response involving the production of ROS by Duox (dual oxidase) enzyme in enterocytes (ECs) is triggered in the intestine as early as 30 min after ingesting pathogenic bacteria. ROS directly damage bacterial membranes (Benguettat et al., 2018; Ha et al., 2009; Ha et al., 2005; Lee et al., 2013) but also exert an indirect effect in adults by triggering visceral spasms through the host detection of ROS mediated by the TrpA1 nociceptor and subsequent secretion of diuretic hormone 31 (Dh31) by enteroendocrine cells (EECs; Benguettat et al., 2018; Du et al., 2016a). Dh31 then binds its receptor on visceral muscles, triggering contractions that expedite bacterial elimination (Benguettat et al., 2018). This pathway seems to be conserved during evolution as TrpA1 is a Drosophila homolog of TRP receptors that respond to noxious conditions (Ogawa et al., 2016) and Dh31 is the Drosophila homolog of the mammalian CGRP (Guo et al., 2022; N&#228;ssel and Zandawala, 2019). In parallel, the immune deficiency (IMD) innate immune pathway is activated following bacterial peptidoglycan detection, leading to the transcription of AMP encoding genes and to the subsequent secretion of the peptides that kill bacteria (Capo et al., 2019). Previous study has explored the dynamics of food transit involving intestinal valves and Dh31 in the context of Drosophila larvae (LaJeunesse et al., 2010). Additionally, the perturbed circulation of bacteria within the intestine has not been documented in the literature though some specific localization of commensal and pathogenic bacteria along the intestine have been observed in insects (Basset et al., 2000; Bosco-Drayon et al., 2012; Lanan et al., 2016; Nardi et al., 2016; Ramond et al., 2021; Yao et al., 2022). However, the intricate interplay between the sequestration of bacteria in specific gut regions and their subsequent elimination has remained unexplored. In our study, we leveraged a novel real-time experimental system designed specifically for Drosophila larvae, enabling us to meticulously trace the journey and ultimate fate of pathogenic bacteria ingested alongside food. This approach has allowed us to shed light on the complex mechanisms underpinning bacterial management within the larval gut, contributing a significant advancement to our understanding of host-pathogen interactions at the intestinal level. We characterized a new mechanism implicated in the blockage and elimination of pathogenic bacteria in the anterior part of the midgut. We demonstrated that this confinement is regulated by the ROS/TrpA1/Dh31 axis. Our results delineate a model in which bacterial trapping arises from ROS production in the intestinal lumen in response to pathogenic bacteria. These ROS compounds interact with TrpA1 in Dh31-expressing EECs located between the anterior and middle midgut, leading to Dh31 secretion and subsequent bacterial compartmentalization, suggesting the closure of a valve, a midgut junction structure proposed by LaJeunesse et al., 2010. Interestingly, we found that we can ectopically induce the trapping of fluorescent particles or innocuous bacteria using human CGRP that replaces Dh31. Our findings also highlight the central role of this blockage, which acts first allowing sufficient time for the subsequent eradication of blocked pathogens by the IMD pathway and its downstream effectors. Collectively, our data unravel a finely tuned coordination between the ROS/TrpA1/Dh31 axis and the IMD pathway, enabling an effective bactericidal action of AMPs. Results Bacterial confinement in the anterior part of larval intestine The translucency of Drosophila larvae allows for live studies of immune defense components and their coordination in eradicating pathogenic bacteria. In our prior work, we revealed a modified food transit in larvae exposed to the Gram-negative opportunistic bacterium Erwinia carotovora carotovora (Ecc15), a process that involved TrpA1 (Keita et al., 2017). Using blue food dye, we tracked the presence of food in the intestinal lumen and observed that larval guts were blue without bacterial contaminants, while in the presence of Ecc15, they appeared clearer (Keita et al., 2017). Such a strategy was already used to delineate whether oral infection by Pseudomonas entomophila could modulate food transit (Liehl et al., 2006). However, our previous assay with Ecc15 was limited to 1 hr post-ingestion and using a food dye, not directly moenitoring the fate of the ingested bacteria over the time. We therefore designed a new protocol allowing to film the fate of fluorescent bacteria once ingested by the larvae. Animals are fed for 1 hr with food contaminated with fluorescent bacteria to investigate the localization of these pathogens within the intestinal tract. Following this feeding period, the animals were transferred to a wet chamber devoid of food. This setup allowed us to monitor the positional dynamics of the bacteria within the intestine over time, without further food intake influencing the observations. We principally tested three different fluorescent bacteria: Ecc15-GFP (Ecc, an opportunistic Gram-negative bacterium), Bacillus thuringiensis-GFP (Bt, an opportunistic Gram-positive bacterium), and Lactiplantibacillus plantarum-GFP (Lp, a commensal Gram-positive bacterium). After 1 hr of feeding on contaminated media, Ecc and Bt were concentrated in the anterior midgut (Videos 1 and 2). The location of the bacteria specifically in the anterior part of the intestine following 1 hr exposure was confirmed when individuals from populations were imaged and counted (Figure 1A). The consistently defined limits of the area containing bacteria in the anterior part of the gut across our observations strongly indicate the presence of a physical boundary. This reproducibility contrasts with what would be expected if the cessation of food intake was responsible for halting bacterial progression, which would likely result in more variable bacterial distributions within the intestine among individual subjects (Figure 1A). Remarkably, with animals fed 1 hr with Ecc or Bt and transferred in a wet chamber, tracking the GFP signal over time revealed that it remained in the anterior part of the larva and began to fade 6 hr after ingestion (Videos 1 and 2; Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 1A and B). This fading suggests the elimination of the bacteria, while the larva continued to exhibit active movements. This pattern was observed for both Ecc and Bt. Interestingly, the blockage is reversible and may depend upon the presence or status of the trapped bacteria. Indeed, if fluorescent dextran polymers are co incubated with Ecc, both bacteria and dextran are blocked in the anterior part of the intestine and following bacteria-associated fluorescence disappearance, the dextran is released in the posterior part (Video 3). However, unlike the opportunistic bacteria Ecc and Bt, a food mixture contaminated with Lp led to the bacteria being present in the posterior compartment of the larval midgut after 1 hr of feeding and remained there throughout the 16 hr duration of our observation (Video 4, Figure 1A and Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 1C; Storelli et al., 2018). To better characterize the blockage phenomenon, we counted the ratio of larvae with trapped GFP-bacteria 1 hr post feeding. Importantly, in all our experiments, approximately 20% of larvae displayed an absence of fluorescent bacteria within the intestinal lumen. Notably, this proportion remained consistent across different bacterial strains used to contaminate the food, indicating that the specific compartmentalization of pathogenic bacteria we observed is not related to a global food-intake cessation. Instead, these findings suggest the deployment of a targeted sequestration mechanism. Focusing on animals containing fluorescent bacteria, we found that while less than 10% of the larvae had Lp blocked in the anterior part of the intestine, more than 80% of the larvae had Ecc and Bt bacteria localized in the anterior part of the midgut (Figure 1A and B). We completed our observation of the posterior location of non-pathogenic bacteria with another harmless species, the OP50 strain of Escherichia coli (Eco). Less than 20% of the animals fed a mixture containing Eco showed a blocking phenotype. The portion of the intestine containing the fluorescent bacteria is delimited posteriorly by an extensive turn, a region that was suggested to act like a valve (LaJeunesse et al., 2010). Importantly, the blockage of pathogenic bacteria (Ecc and Bt) in the anterior part of the intestine was confirmed using D. melanogaster larvae with different genetic backgrounds (Figure 1C). To confirm our findings, we dissected the intestines of larvae that had ingested the bacteria. Our analysis confirmed that Ecc and Bt were predominantly located in the anterior part of the intestines, whereas Lp was not, supporting our initial observations (Figure 1&#8212;figure supplement 2). Our data collectively indicate that pathogenic bacteria, such as Ecc and Bt, are spatially confined to the anterior part of the larval midgut before their disappearance. In contrast, the commensal bacterium Lp or the innocuous Eco line we used are distributed throughout the midgut, persisting principally in the posterior part. Figure 1 with 2 supplements see all Download asset Open asset Contrary to Lp or Eco, Ecc or Bt bacteria are found exclusively in the anterior part of the gut. (A) Pictures to illustrate the position of the green fluorescence of control (CantonS) L3 stage larvae as a group (upper panel) or individual (lower panel) after having been fed 1 hr with a media containing yeast and GFP-producing bacteria (Ecc or Bt or Lp). The white asterisk indicates the anterior part of the animal. The white arrow indicates the posterior limit of the area containing the fluorescent bacteria. Below the pictures are schematics representing larvae, their gut, and the relative position of the GFP-producing bacteria in green. Scale bar is 1 mm. (B) Graphic representing the blockage ratio for CantonS (ctrl) L3 larvae exposed during 1 hr to a mixture composed of yeast and fluorescent bacteria: Lp or Escherichia coli (Eco) or Ecc or Bt. The ratio of control larvae with a distinguishable green fluorescence only in the upper part of the intestine, considered as blocked bacteria, is represented. The ratio is calculated as: x larvae with bacteria exclusively in the anterior part of the gut / (x larvae with bacteria exclusively in the anterior part of the gut +y larvae with bacteria all along the gut). Larvae with no distinguishable fluorescence were considered as non-eaters and discarded from the quantifications. The ratio of larvae with no distinguishable fluorescence was not influenced by the different conditions we tested. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 30 animals per condition and trial. **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. (C) Blockage ratio for L3 larvae of w1, Oregon or w1118 isogenized genotypes fed during various times with a mixture combining yeast with Lp, Ecc, or Bt. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 100 animals in total. The 0 symbol indicates an absence of blockage, **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. Video 1 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Ecc is blocked in the anterior part of the larval intestine then vanishes. Live imaging during 12 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Ecc fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018385.v2. Video 2 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Bt is blocked in the anterior part of the larval intestine then vanishes. Live imaging during 12 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Bt fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018427.v2. Video 3 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Dextran-TexasRed is concomitantly blocked Fluorescent Bt in the anterior part of the larval intestine then released posteriorly following bacterial clearance. Live imaging during 6 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Bt fluorescent bacteria and Dextran-Texas-Red then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. The anterior part of the larvae is at the bottom right. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.26355076.v1. Video 4 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Lp is not blocked in the anterior part of the larval intestine and persists in the posterior midgut. Live imaging during 10 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Lp fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018442.v2. The anterior intestinal confinement of pathogenic bacteria is dose-specific and occurs rapidly We hypothesized that the bacterial localization specifically in the anterior part of the larval intestine was an active host response and might be dependent on the bacterial dose. To test this, we exposed larvae to varying concentrations of Ecc and Bt and measured the blockage ratio. We found that a concentration of 2.109 Ecc bacteria per ml was sufficient to induce the bacterial compartmentalization, whereas for Bt, a concentration of 4.1010 Bt bacteria per ml was required (Figure 2A). Interestingly, following over time the intoxication of control larvae with a Bt concentration of 1.1010 bacteria per ml instead of 4.1010 Bt bacteria per ml revealed that bacteria were not sequestered in the anterior part of the intestine but reached the posterior part (Video 5). Nonetheless, the fluorescence remained weak likely due to the low amount of bacteria and we could even observed an excretion of bacteria. For all subsequent experiments, we used 4.1010 bacteria per ml. Figure 2 with 1 supplement see all Download asset Open asset Bacterial blockage is dose-dependent, occurs in less than 30 min, and does not involve a group effect. (A) Blockage ratio for control L3 larvae fed 1 hr with a mixture combining yeast with different concentrations of fluorescent Ecc or Bt, concentrations are in number of bacteria per ml. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 18 animals per condition and trial. **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. (B) Representative images of control larvae fed during 30 min. with Bt. Scale bar is 1 mm. (C) Blockage ratio for control L3 larvae fed during various times with a mixture combining yeast with Ecc or Bt. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 20 animals per condition and trial. ns indicates values with differences not statistically significant, **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. (D) Blockage ratio for control L3 larvae fed 1 hr as individual animals or as groups of 10 or &gt;40 with a mixture combining yeast with a constant concentration of Ecc or Bt (4.1010 bacteria per ml). Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with the exact number of animals indicated per condition and trial. ns indicates values with differences not statistically significant, Fischer exact t-test. See the source data file for details. Video 5 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Bt at a low concentration is not blocked in the anterior part of the larval intestine, persists in the posterior midgut and the larva does not die. Live imaging during 10 hr of a L3 control larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Bt fluorescent bacteria (1.1010 bacteria per ml instead of 4.1010) then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.26355196.v1. In previous contamination assays, we arbitrary used a 1 hr time point to assess the phenotype. However, observations of bacterial blockage occurring within minutes suggested that this response does not require de novo protein synthesis by the host. Shorter exposure times revealed that Ecc was blocked in the anterior part of the intestine within 15 min, while Bt showed a similar pattern beginning at 15 min and completing by 30 min (Figure 2B and C). Based on these results, we defined 1 hr as our standard exposure time of larvae with bacterial contaminated food. In addition, we performed longer continuous feeding with Ecc (20 hr) to assay whether the blockage would still be present. We observed that while most of the larvae continuously exposed to the contaminated mixture tend to flee and do not contain fluorescent bacteria in their intestine, the ones with detectable fluorescence were blocking the bacteria (Figure 2&#8212;figure supplement 1). Our assays typically involved groups of approximately 50 larvae to observe population-level phenomena. Recent studies have suggested that larval behavior can be influenced by group dynamics (Dombrovski et al., 2019; Dombrovski et al., 2017; Louis and de Polavieja, 2017; Mast et al., 2014). To determine whether group size affects the bacterial confinement, we exposed groups of varying sizes to Bt or Ecc and measured the blockage ratio. The phenomenon proved robust even with a single larva exposed to contaminated food, indicating that the response was not influenced by group size under our experimental conditions (Figure 2D). Based on these findings, for all subsequent experiments, we standardized the conditions using 4.1010 bacteria per ml, a 1 hr exposure time, and groups of at least 20 larvae. Host TrpA1 and Dh31 are crucial for the blockage phenotype In our previous study reporting an altered food transit for larvae exposed to a food contaminated with Ecc (Keita et al., 2017), we identified the gene TrpA1 as essential for the host response. The TrpA1 protein, a member of the TRP channel family, facilitates Ca2 +entry into cells at temperatures over 25 &#176;C or upon exposure to chemicals such as ROS (Du et al., 2016b; Gu et al., 2019; Guntur et al., 2015). This channel, involved in nociception (Lapointe and Altier, 2011), has been linked to intestinal muscle activity in adult Drosophila following Ecc exposure (Du et al., 2016a) and in response to ROS production by the host (Benguettat et al., 2018). We examined the role of TrpA1 during the larval response to contaminated food using TrpA11 homozygous viable mutant in the experimental setup with fluorescent Lp, Ecc, or Bt bacteria. In these mutant larvae, while the localization of Lp in the posterior midgut remained unchanged, Ecc and Bt were found in the posterior midgut following a 1 hr intoxication and the fluorescence does not fade (Figure 3A and B, Video 6 and Figure 3&#8212;figure supplement 1A). This observation underscores that TrpA1 is necessary for the blockage of pathogenic bacteria in the anterior midgut and suggests that the disappearance of the fluorescence observed for pathogenic bacteria within the intestine of control animals may be due to bacteria being killed rather than fading of GFP or plasmid loss. Considering previous reports on visceral contraction in adult Drosophila linked to ROS production, detection by TrpA1, and Dh31 secretion to expel bacteria (Benguettat et al., 2018; Du et al., 2016a), we wondered whether a similar ROS/TrpA1/Dh31 signaling axis is necessary in larvae to block pathogenic bacteria in the anterior midgut. Indeed, the bacterial blockage we observed might involve muscle contractions related to food contamination. Thus, we tested the blockage ratio of Dh31KG09001 homozygous viable mutants exposed to Lp, Bt, or Ecc bacteria. In contrast to control animals, where fewer than 20% of larvae exhibited Ecc or Bt in the posterior section of the intestine, for more than 60% of Dh31KG09001 mutant larvae, the pathogenic bacteria Bt or Ecc were localized in the posterior midgut confirming Dh31's crucial role in this mechanism (Figure 3A and B, Video 7 and Figure 3&#8212;figure supplement 1B). The localization of Lp was not affected (Figure 3B). Figure 3 with 2 supplements see all Download asset Open asset The bacterial blockage necessitates Duox in enterocytes, the TrpA1 channel and Dh31 in Pros + cells. (A) Pictures to illustrate the localization of the fluorescent bacteria within the intestine of control (ctrl), TrpA11 or Dh31KG09001 L3 larvae after having been fed 1 hr with a mixture of yeast and Ecc. Scale bar is 1 mm. (B) Blockage ratio for control (ctrl) L3 larvae or mutants for TrpA11 or Dh31KG09001 fed 1 hr with a mixture combining yeast and Lp or Ecc or Bt or fluorescent Dextran with or without hCGRP hormone. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 30 animals per condition and trial. 0 indicates an absence of blockage. **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. (C) Pictures to illustrate the localization of the fluorescence within the intestine of control L3 larvae after having been fed 1 hr with a mixture of yeast and fluorescent Dextran with or without hCGRP hormone. Below the pictures are schematics representing larvae, their gut, and the relative position of the fluorescence in green. Scale bar is 1 mm. (D) Blockage ratio for animals expressing RNA interference constructions directed against Duox mRNA or Dh31 mRNA, ubiquitously (Da-Gal4), in enterocytes (Mex-Gal4) or in enteroendocrine cells (Pros-Gal4) and then fed 1 hr with a mixture combining yeast and Ecc or Bt. Shown is the average blockage ratio with a 95% confidence interval from at least three independent assays with at least 30 animals per condition and trial. ns indicates values with differences not statistically significant, **** indicates p&lt;0.0001, Fisher exact t-test. See the source data file for details. Video 6 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Ecc is not blocked in the anterior part of the TrpA1 mutant larval intestine and persists in the posterior midgut. Live imaging during 10 hr of a L3 TrpA1 mutant larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Ecc fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber. https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018463.v1. Video 7 Download asset This video cannot be played in place because your browser does support HTML5 video. You may still download the video for offline viewing. Download as MPEG-4 Download as WebM Download as Ogg Fluorescent Ecc is not blocked in the anterior part of the Dh31 mutant larval intestine and persists in the posterior midgut. Live imaging during 10 hr of a L3 Dh31 mutant larva previously fed 1 hr with a food containing Ecc fluorescent bacteria then transferred on a glass slide in a wet chamber.https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.25018472.v1. Given the possibility that the compartmentalization of pathogens we observed might be driven by bacterial virulence factors, we aimed to further investigate the underlying mechanism. To discern whether this phenomenon was specific to pathogenic bacteria or could extend to non-pathogenic entities, we conducted experiments to determine if abiotic particles or non-virulent bacteria could also be ectopically sequestered within the gut. The human Calcitonin Gene-Related Peptide (hCGRP) is the functional homolog of Dh31. Indeed, hCGRP has been shown to promote visceral muscle contractions in adult flies (Benguettat et al., 2018). To investigate whether the bacterial confinement could be triggered without pathogenic bacteria in response to a hormone, we exposed larvae to either Lp or Dextran-FITC in the presence of hCGRP. While Lp and Dextran-FITC were normally distributed throughout the midgut, adding hCGRP to the food induced a significant blockage (Figure 3</description>
      <author>Bruno Lemaitre</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.98716.3.sa0</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
