<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 01:21:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction through improved lattice oxygen activity via carbon dots incorporation into MOFs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.133</link>
      <description>Zi Kang Tang, Delun Chen, Weiwei Li, Hai Li, Jinchun Tu, Xiaolin Zhang, Bingrong Wang, Rentong Yu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 685(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406569124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zi Kang Tang, Delun Chen, Weiwei Li, Hai Li, Jinchun Tu, Xiaolin Zhang, Bingrong Wang, Rentong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ growth of Ni2.86Te2 and Mo6Te8 telluride catalysts on foam NiMo substrates for enhanced oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</link>
      <description>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406570335

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Yang, Wenbin Wang, Sha Deng, QIANMAO JI, Yunlong Guo, Tao Long</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational construction and design of bimetallic Co-Ni species by pulsed laser irradiation for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118011</link>
      <description>Wenzhe Cao, Xiaohui Ren, Ying Wen, Tian Zhang, W.Y. Chu, Zhaoyang Liu, Haoran Zou, Qianying Guo, Rongsheng Chen, Feng Ma, Hongwei Ni, Materials Science and Engineering B. 314(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406583868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenzhe Cao, Xiaohui Ren, Ying Wen, Tian Zhang, W.Y. Chu, Zhaoyang Liu, Haoran Zou, Qianying Guo, Rongsheng Chen, Feng Ma, Hongwei Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2025.118011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridinic-N-enriched mesoporous carbon coated carbon cloth for efficient oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162444</link>
      <description>Y.S. Li, Chi Li, Qing Zhou, Yongfu Lian, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406586469

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Y.S. Li, Chi Li, Qing Zhou, Yongfu Lian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Steel mesh coated Cobalt Tungstate Microflowers as Efficient Binder-Free Electrode Materials for Supercapacitors and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112579</link>
      <description>Neha C. Patil, Umesh V. Shembade, Mayuri G. Magadum, Jaywant V. Mane, Dnyandevo N. Zambare, Tanaji R. Bhosale, A.V. Moholkar, Sandeep B. Wategaonkar, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406590900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Neha C. Patil, Umesh V. Shembade, Mayuri G. Magadum, Jaywant V. Mane, Dnyandevo N. Zambare, Tanaji R. Bhosale, A.V. Moholkar, Sandeep B. Wategaonkar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial amine-assisted electrodeposition of superhydrophilic/superaerophobic metal hydroxides for robust oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2483-8</link>
      <description>Qing Chen, Keyu Wang, Shiyi Li, Yixing Wang, Linfeng Lei, Minghui Zhu, Linzhou Zhuang, Zhi Xu, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406591464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Chen, Keyu Wang, Shiyi Li, Yixing Wang, Linfeng Lei, Minghui Zhu, Linzhou Zhuang, Zhi Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2483-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium&#8208;Doped NiBP Micro&#8208;Sphere Electrocatalysts for Green Hydrogen Production under Industrial Operational Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401939</link>
      <description>Md Ahasan Habib, Shusen Lin, Sumiya Akter Dristy, Mehedi Hasan Joni, Rutuja Mandavkar, Jae&#8208;Hun Jeong, Jihoon Lee, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406593946

                Abstract Wide spread adaptation of green hydrogen can help to mitigate the serious climate issues, increasing global energy demands and the development of advanced electrocatalysts robust under industrial conditions is one of the key technological challenges. Herein, chromium&#8208;doped nickel&#8208;boride&#8208;phosphide (Cr/NiBP) micro sphere (MS) electrocatalyst is demonstrated via a two&#8208;step hydrothermal approach along with post&#8208;annealing. The Cr/NiBP MS demonstrates low hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evaluation reaction over potentials of 78 and 250 mV at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH, out performing most of the reported catalysts. The Cr/NiBP &#449; Cr/NiBP exhibits only 1.54 V at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH and surpasses the benchmark of RuO 2 (+) &#449; Pt/C (&#8722;) up to 2000 mA cm &#8722;2 , which sets it as one of the best bifunctional electrocatalysts. Impressively, it maintains stable performance for over 240 h at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in 6 m KOH at 60&#176;C, demonstrating rapid response, anti&#8208;corrosion resistance, and robust structural integrity to meet the industrial operational conditions. Further, Cr/NiBP &#449; Pt/C exhibits a super&#8208;low cell&#8208;voltage of 2.25 V at 2000 mA cm &#8722;2 . The small amount of Cr atoms incorporation can significantly enhance active sites and intrinsic properties, accelerating water dissociation and rapid intermediate formation.</description>
      <author>Md Ahasan Habib, Shusen Lin, Sumiya Akter Dristy, Mehedi Hasan Joni, Rutuja Mandavkar, Jae&#8208;Hun Jeong, Jihoon Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401939</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridinic&#8208;N Seized Co in Biphasic Nanoarchitecture for Reversible Oxygen Electrocatalysis Enabling Longevous (&amp;gt;1200 h) Aqueous and Dual&#8208;Anion Kosmotropic Electrolyte Stabilized High Power Quasisolid&#8208;State Zn&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401874</link>
      <description>Srijib Das, Saikat Bolar, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, A. J. Pathak, Ranjit Thapa, Ujjwal Phadikar, Haradhan Kolya, Chun&#8211;Won Kang, Tapas Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Aniruddha Kundu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406593979

                Abstract Integration of different active sites by heterostructure engineering is pivotal to optimize the intrinsic activities of an oxygen electrocatalyst and much needed to enhance the performance of rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, a biphasic nanoarchitecture encased in in situ grown N&#8208;doped graphitic carbon (MnO/Co&#8208;NGC) with heterointerfacial sites are constructed. The density functional theory model reveals formation of lattice oxygen bridged heterostructure with pyridinic nitrogen atoms anchored Co species, which facilitate adsorption of oxygen intermediates. Consequently, the well&#8208;designed catalyst with accessible active sites, abundant oxygen vacant sites, and heterointerfacial coupling effects, simultaneously accelerate the electron/mass transfer and thus promotes the trifunctional electrocatalysis. The assembled aqueous ZAB delivers maximum power density of &#8776;268 mW cm &#8722;2 and a specific capacity of 797.8 mAh g zn &#8722;1 along with excellent rechargeability and extremely small voltage gap decay rate of 0.0007 V h &#8722;1 . Further, the fabricated quasisolid&#8208;state ZAB owns a remarkable power density of 163 mW cm &#8722;2 and long cycle life, outperforming the benchmark air&#8208;electrode and many recent reports, underlining its robustness and suitability for practical utilization in diverse portable applications.</description>
      <author>Srijib Das, Saikat Bolar, Erakulan E. Siddharthan, A. J. Pathak, Ranjit Thapa, Ujjwal Phadikar, Haradhan Kolya, Chun&#8211;Won Kang, Tapas Kuila, Naresh Chandra Murmu, Aniruddha Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Carbon nanotube directed synthesis of blue TiO2 with oxygen vacancy for sonocatalytic H2 production&#8221; [Renew. Energy, (241), March 2025, 122379]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122446</link>
      <description>Huaqiang Zhuang, Xiangge Wang, Miaoling Huang, Xiao&#8208;Bing Lian, Xiaobin Liu, Xiaoyang Pan, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406596751

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaqiang Zhuang, Xiangge Wang, Miaoling Huang, Xiao&#8208;Bing Lian, Xiaobin Liu, Xiaoyang Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating design of tunable CuCo2O4@NiMnO3 heterostructure towards superior oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06645-w</link>
      <description>Adel El&#8208;marghany, Muhammad Khalil, Abdul Wahab Haroon, Fawad Ahmad, Ome Parkash Kumar, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem, Zobia Siddique, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406598016

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adel El&#8208;marghany, Muhammad Khalil, Abdul Wahab Haroon, Fawad Ahmad, Ome Parkash Kumar, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem, Zobia Siddique</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06645-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cucurbit[&lt;i&gt;n&lt;/i&gt;]uril-Derived Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution, Oxygen Reduction, and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17510</link>
      <description>Nan Jiang, Yirong Cao, Hang Cong, Qingmei Ge, Wenfeng Zhao, Bo You, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406605909

                Various sustainable energy conversion techniques like water electrolyzers, fuel cells, and metal-air battery devices are promising to alleviate the issues in fossil fuel consumption. However, their broad employment has been mainly inhibited by the lack of advanced electrocatalysts to accelerate the sluggish kinetics of the three involved half-reactions including oxygen evolution reaction (OER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Recent advances have witnessed the cucurbit[n]uril (CB[n])-directed strategy as a prominent tool to develop high performance electrocatalysts with either OER, ORR, or HER activities. In this review, the recent progress on CB[n]-derived electrocatalysts ranging from molecular complexes to heterogeneous nanostructures and single-atoms for the three half-reactions are reviewed, and future opportunities are discussed. A concise introduction to the fundamentals of CB[n]s regarding their synthesis, structure, and chemistry is given first. Subsequently, the systematic summary of CB[n]-derived electrocatalysts and their performance for the OER/ORR/HER are discussed in detail, with a specific emphasis on correlating their structure and activities by combining diverse physiochemical characterizations, electrochemical experiments, and theory simulations. Finally, a brief conclusion and perspective for future opportunities regarding CB[n]-derived electrocatalysts for many other electrocatalytic applications are proposed.</description>
      <author>Nan Jiang, Yirong Cao, Hang Cong, Qingmei Ge, Wenfeng Zhao, Bo You</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c17510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homologous metal-organic complexes reconstructed oxy-hydroxide heterostructures as efficient oxygen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.181</link>
      <description>Yuting Chen, Haikuo Lan, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Kang Liu, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406606851

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuting Chen, Haikuo Lan, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Kang Liu, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General design of self-supported Co-Ni/nitrogen-doped carbon nanotubes array for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.159</link>
      <description>Mengfei Mou, Yameng Wang, Wenjie Yu, Huimin Jiang, Shuo Zhang, Yanchao Zhao, Jingyun Ma, Liting Yan, Xiang-Jun Kong, Xuebo Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406606893

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengfei Mou, Yameng Wang, Wenjie Yu, Huimin Jiang, Shuo Zhang, Yanchao Zhao, Jingyun Ma, Liting Yan, Xiang-Jun Kong, Xuebo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of NiFe alloy foams at high oxygen evolution reaction rates using a dry anode setup in alkaline environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236245</link>
      <description>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406609398

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Coated CeO2-CoFe Core-Shell electrocatalysts derived from Prussian blue analogues for high-performance oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131699</link>
      <description>Huu Thang Nguyen, Kimin Chae, Deng&#8208;Guang Yu, Nguyen Anh Thu Tran, Tran Minh Khoi, Jin Goo Kim, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Younghyun Cho, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615373

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huu Thang Nguyen, Kimin Chae, Deng&#8208;Guang Yu, Nguyen Anh Thu Tran, Tran Minh Khoi, Jin Goo Kim, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Younghyun Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2025.131699</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formamide-Assisted Synthesis of Phosphate-Intercalated Ni(Oh)2/Niooh Electrode for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5104122</link>
      <description>Yuexiang Li, Qiang Li, Shaoqin Peng, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615628

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuexiang Li, Qiang Li, Shaoqin Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5104122</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational synthesis of MOF-Derived Cobalt-Based binary selenides nanocrystals for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162479</link>
      <description>Faozia Nasser Al-Shaibah, Muhammad Arif Ibrahim, Aymen S. Abu Hatab, Ahmed Abotaleb, Alessandro Sinopoli, Atef Zekri, Yahia H. Ahmad, Siham Y. Al-Qaradawi, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406616868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faozia Nasser Al-Shaibah, Muhammad Arif Ibrahim, Aymen S. Abu Hatab, Ahmed Abotaleb, Alessandro Sinopoli, Atef Zekri, Yahia H. Ahmad, Siham Y. Al-Qaradawi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the local S coordination environment on Ru single atoms to boost the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04706k</link>
      <description>Yiling Ran, Rong Z. Gan, Qin Zhao, Quanlei Ma, Yijing Liao, Yinwei Li, Yi Wang, Yanwei Wang, Yan Zhang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406617530

                A single atom Ru-NiS 2 catalyst with a controlled S-coordination environment for OER was prepared by a simple atom capture strategy. Fine-tuned local S coordination environment can optimize the electronic structure of Ru active sites.</description>
      <author>Yiling Ran, Rong Z. Gan, Qin Zhao, Quanlei Ma, Yijing Liao, Yinwei Li, Yi Wang, Yanwei Wang, Yan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04706k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;Layered Double Hydroxide Heterostructures as Efficient Alkaline Water Splitting (Photo)Electro&#8208;catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409097</link>
      <description>Kayvan Moradi, Maysam Ashrafi, Abdollah Salimi, Marko Melander, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406617906

                Abstract Designing cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts with fast reaction kinetics and high stability is an outstanding challenge in green hydrogen generation through overall water splitting (OWS). Layered double hydroxide (LDH) heterostructure materials are promising candidates to catalyze both oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the two OWS half&#8208;cell reactions. This work develops a facile hydrothermal route to synthesiz hierarchical heterostructure MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;LDH and MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH electrocatalysts, which exhibit extremely good OER and HER performance as witnessed by their low IR&#8208;corrected overpotentials of 156 and 61 mV with at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 under light assistance. The MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH&#8208;MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;LDH OWS cell achieves a low cell voltage of 1.46V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 during light&#8208;assisted water electrolysis. Both materials exhibited exceptional stability under industrially relevant HER and OER conditions, maintaining a current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 with minimal alterations in their potential and performance. The experimental and computational results demonstrate that doping the LDH matrix with high&#8208;valence Mo atoms and MoS 2 quantum dots improves the electrocatalytic activity by 1) enhancing electron transfer, 2) making the electrocatalyst metallic, 3) increasing the number of active sites, 4) lowering the thermodynamic overpotential, and 5) changing the OER mechanism. Overall, this work develops a facile synthesis method to design highly active and stable MoS 2 @NiFeCo&#8208;Mo(doped)&#8208;LDH heterostructure electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Kayvan Moradi, Maysam Ashrafi, Abdollah Salimi, Marko Melander</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-tunable cobalt borides with amorphous shell toward highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236255</link>
      <description>Yuxin Gao, Xiaowei Yang, Yuyang Zong, Lihong Bao, Ruguang Ma, Jijun Zhao, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406618795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxin Gao, Xiaowei Yang, Yuyang Zong, Lihong Bao, Ruguang Ma, Jijun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrostatic and Electronic Effects on Doped Nickel Oxide Nanofilms for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14493</link>
      <description>Ina &#216;str&#248;m, Marco Favaro, Moein Seyfouri, Patrick A. Burr, Bram Hoex, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406632531

                An ideal water-splitting electrocatalyst is inexpensive, abundant, highly active, stable, selective, and durable. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the main bottleneck for H2 production with a complex and not fully resolved mechanism, slow kinetics, and high overpotential. Nickel oxide-based catalysts (NiOx) are highly active and cheaper than precious metal catalysts. However, rigorous catalyst tests and DFT calculations are still needed to rationally optimize NiOx catalysts. In this work, we combine plasma-enhanced atomic layer deposition (PE-ALD) and density functional theory (DFT) to address the role of dopants in promoting NiOx OER activity. Ultrathin films of NiOx doped with Zn2+, Al3+, and Sn4+ presented improved intrinsic activity, stability, and durability for the OER. The results show a low to high catalytic performance of ZnNiOx &lt; NiOx &lt; AlNiOx &lt; SnNiOx, which we attribute to an increase in the concentration of valence band (VB) holes combined with conduction band (CB) electron conductivity, characterized by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The influence of doping on the electronic structure and catalytic activity was investigated using advanced characterization techniques and density functional theory (DFT) calculations (PEB0/pob-TZVP). DFT complements the experimental results, showing that the dopant charge states and orbital hybridization enhance the OER by improving the charge carrier concentration and mobility, thus allowing optimal binding energies and charge dynamics and delocalization. Our findings demonstrate the potential of PE-ALD-doped nanofilms NiOx and DFT to rationally design and develop catalysts for sustainable energy applications.</description>
      <author>Ina &#216;str&#248;m, Marco Favaro, Moein Seyfouri, Patrick A. Burr, Bram Hoex</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver-decorated titanium dioxide micro-tablets as a photocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00990-w</link>
      <description>Liszulfah Roza, Gerald Ensang Timuda, Elvy Rahmi Mawarnis, Rany Miranti, Abdul Wafi, Toto Sudiro, Nono Darsono, Sudiyarmanto, Mahfujur Rahman, Emergent Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406637806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liszulfah Roza, Gerald Ensang Timuda, Elvy Rahmi Mawarnis, Rany Miranti, Abdul Wafi, Toto Sudiro, Nono Darsono, Sudiyarmanto, Mahfujur Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00990-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Investigation of Sr Segregation Effects on the High-temperature Oxygen Evolution Reaction Rate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee05056h</link>
      <description>Weicheng Feng, Geng Zou, Tianfu Liu, Rongtan Li, Jingcheng Yu, Yige Guo, Qingxue Liu, Xiaomin Zhang, Junhu Wang, Na Ta, Mingrun Li, Peng Zhang, Xingzhong Cao, Runsheng Yu, Yuefeng Song, M. Liu, Guoxiong Wang, Xinhe Bao, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406641499

                While the effects of Sr segregation on the performance and stability of perovskite electrodes in solid oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs) have been widely studied, most attention has been focused on...</description>
      <author>Weicheng Feng, Geng Zou, Tianfu Liu, Rongtan Li, Jingcheng Yu, Yige Guo, Qingxue Liu, Xiaomin Zhang, Junhu Wang, Na Ta, Mingrun Li, Peng Zhang, Xingzhong Cao, Runsheng Yu, Yuefeng Song, M. Liu, Guoxiong Wang, Xinhe Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee05056h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced oxygen evolution catalysis: SnS&#8322; and MoS&#8322; decorated titania nanostructures in alkaline electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.204</link>
      <description>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Youngae Lee, Sadanand Pandey, Younghwan Im, Mohammad Altaf, Misook Kang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 105(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406641511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Youngae Lee, Sadanand Pandey, Younghwan Im, Mohammad Altaf, Misook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Significantly Improved Electrocatalytic Activity of Pr1.1ba0.9co2o5+ &#916; Induced by Ba-Site Sr Doping Toward Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5106619</link>
      <description>Enhui Hou, Xiang Li, Jingping Wang, Tian Xia, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406641514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enhui Hou, Xiang Li, Jingping Wang, Tian Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5106619</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DNA Origami-Assembled Gold Nanobipyramid Dimer Electrocatalyst for Ultrahigh Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05951</link>
      <description>Charanleen Kaur, Imtiaz Ahmed, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Tapasi Sen, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406645211

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Charanleen Kaur, Imtiaz Ahmed, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Tapasi Sen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c05951</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a hybrid electrocatalyst by impregnating the CuS/CdFe2O4 composite heterostructure into the carbon nanofiber network for improved electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.126988</link>
      <description>N. Ch. Ramgopal, Nipa Roy, Gedi Sreedevi, Salh Alhammadi, Razan A. Alshgari, Mohammed Sheikh Saleh Mushab, K. Prasad, Sai Kumar Arla, Sang Woo Joo, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406661431

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. Ch. Ramgopal, Nipa Roy, Gedi Sreedevi, Salh Alhammadi, Razan A. Alshgari, Mohammed Sheikh Saleh Mushab, K. Prasad, Sai Kumar Arla, Sang Woo Joo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2025.126988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous carbon nanosheets integrated with graphene-wrapped CoO and CoNx as efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.170</link>
      <description>Chang Ma, Binji Zhu, Yue Wang, Shuwen Ma, Jingli Shi, Xiangwu Zhang, Yan Song, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406661536

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chang Ma, Binji Zhu, Yue Wang, Shuwen Ma, Jingli Shi, Xiangwu Zhang, Yan Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.170</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3d Core-Shell Structured Nico2o4 Nanoneedle Array Encased in N-Doped Carbon for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Electrocatalytic Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5106177</link>
      <description>Na Li, Jiawei Yang, Runduo Zhang, Yaxuan Wei, Kun Yang, Xiaoqiang Du, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406661622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Li, Jiawei Yang, Runduo Zhang, Yaxuan Wei, Kun Yang, Xiaoqiang Du</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5106177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin Magnetic Effect Activate Dual Site Intramolecular O&#9472;O Bridging for Nickel&#8208;Iron Hydroxide Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202415525</link>
      <description>Haohai Dong, Lanke Luo, Shaobing Zhou, Lin Chen, Xinyu Wu, Yitao Yang, Zhensheng Liao, Fu Liao, Ming Chen, Yuxin Zhu, Peiyuan Su, Haomin Jiang, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin, Qingsong Hua, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406664421

                Abstract The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) involves the recombination of diamagnetic hydroxyl (OH) or water (H 2 O) into the paramagnetic triplet state of oxygen (O 2 ). The spin conservation of oxygen intermediates plays a crucial role in OER, however, research on spin dynamics during the catalytic process remains in its early stages. Herein, &#946; &#8208;Ni(OH) 2 and Fe&#8208;doped &#946; &#8208;Ni(OH) 2 (Ni 5 Fe 1 (OH) 2 ) are utilized as model catalysts to understand the mechanism of spin magnetic effects at iron (III) sites during OER. Combined with magnetic characterization, it is founded that the introduction of Fe transforms the antiferromagnetic Ni(OH) 2 into a ferromagnetic material. Testing the magnetic response of the catalyst under an external magnetic field, the OER activity of Ni 5 Fe 1 (OH) 2 is significantly enhanced in comparison to Ni(OH) 2 . This improvement is likely due to the introduction of iron sites, which promote spin magnetic effects and enhance reaction kinetics, thereby increasing catalytic efficiency. Combining experimental and theoretical characterization, it is discovered that the iron sites accelerate the formation of heterogeneous dual&#8208;site O&#9472;O bridging, represented as &#9472;Ni&#9472;O&#9472;O&#9472;Fe&#9472;, thereby effectively enhancing the kinetics of the OER reaction. This study provides a magnetic perspective on the structure&#8208;function relationship of magnetic iron&#8208;based catalysts and has significant implications for the design of new catalysts.</description>
      <author>Haohai Dong, Lanke Luo, Shaobing Zhou, Lin Chen, Xinyu Wu, Yitao Yang, Zhensheng Liao, Fu Liao, Ming Chen, Yuxin Zhu, Peiyuan Su, Haomin Jiang, Zemin Sun, Liu Lin, Qingsong Hua</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202415525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptive Morphing of Hydroxyl Groups on Covalency Competing Spinel Oxides Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07014</link>
      <description>Jiali Gou, Xin Lei, Bifa Ji, Shanshan Zhang, Yongping Zheng, Yongbing Tang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406668219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Gou, Xin Lei, Bifa Ji, Shanshan Zhang, Yongping Zheng, Yongbing Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe, Co, N-doped composite as an efficient catalyst for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102531</link>
      <description>Junyuan Zhang, Jingjing Chen, Jing Yi, Xiaolong Xu, Changyu Liu, Jianbo Jia, Materials Today Chemistry. 44(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406669422

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junyuan Zhang, Jingjing Chen, Jing Yi, Xiaolong Xu, Changyu Liu, Jianbo Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2025.102531</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of IrCu/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; hybrid nanostructures and their enhanced catalytic properties toward oxygen evolution reaction under both acidic and alkaline conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt03079f</link>
      <description>Xiaomei Xu, Taekyung Yu, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406669837

                IrCu/Co 3 O 4 hybrid nanostructures were prepared under mild conditions using NaBH 4 through an anti-solvent crystallization method.</description>
      <author>Xiaomei Xu, Taekyung Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt03079f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Molybdenum-Doped Cobalt-Iron Layered Double Hydroxide Hollow Nanorods Via a &#8216;One-Stone-Two-Birds&#8217; Strategy for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5105624</link>
      <description>Lingyu Kong, Ningzhao Shang, Tingyu Zhang, Ming Su, Yufan Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406677032

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingyu Kong, Ningzhao Shang, Tingyu Zhang, Ming Su, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5105624</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Induced Crystal-Amorphous Interface in Nife Ldh Catalyst for Enhanced Oer Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5105606</link>
      <description>Yiwang Chen, Jun Guo, Buming Chen, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406677034

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yiwang Chen, Jun Guo, Buming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5105606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron phosphide microwires based on-chip electrocatalytic oxygen evolution microdevice</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2025.111859</link>
      <description>Hongwei Su, Qingguo Chi, Hongtao Li, Alei Li, Yunlei Zhong, Xu Zhang, Lin Geng, Shuai Liu, Liuqi Dong, Xiaohang Pan, Lin Wang, Lixing Kang, iScience. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406681688

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongwei Su, Qingguo Chi, Hongtao Li, Alei Li, Yunlei Zhong, Xu Zhang, Lin Geng, Shuai Liu, Liuqi Dong, Xiaohang Pan, Lin Wang, Lixing Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.isci.2025.111859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guided Heterostructure Growth of CoFe LDH on Ti&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; MXene for Durably High Oxygen Evolution Activity (Small 3/2025)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202570016</link>
      <description>Jiali Sheng, Jiahui Kang, Pan Jiang, Kristoffer Meinander, Xiaodan Hong, Hua Jiang, Nonappa Nonappa, Olli Ikkala, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Bo Peng, Zhong&#8208;Peng Lv, Small. 21(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406693393

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiali Sheng, Jiahui Kang, Pan Jiang, Kristoffer Meinander, Xiaodan Hong, Hua Jiang, Nonappa Nonappa, Olli Ikkala, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Bo Peng, Zhong&#8208;Peng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202570016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isomerization of Covalent Organic Frameworks for Efficiently Activating Molecular Oxygen and Promoting Hydrogen Peroxide Photosynthesis (Small 3/2025)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202570017</link>
      <description>Wenjiao Wang, Rui Zhang, Hongqi Chu, Zhen Zhan, Qi Huang, Zhenzi Li, Xuepeng Wang, Fu&#8208;Quan Bai, Wei Zhou, Small. 21(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406693408

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjiao Wang, Rui Zhang, Hongqi Chu, Zhen Zhan, Qi Huang, Zhenzi Li, Xuepeng Wang, Fu&#8208;Quan Bai, Wei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202570017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d</link>
      <description>Li Liao, Rui Wang, Zerong Zhang, Jianfeng Zhang, Shibin Huang, Wenhao Xie, Y. Wang, Ming Xue, Qianrong Fang, Shilun Qiu, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406695542

                The development of covalent organic frameworks (COFs) as bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), coupled with precise control over their active sites, is...</description>
      <author>Li Liao, Rui Wang, Zerong Zhang, Jianfeng Zhang, Shibin Huang, Wenhao Xie, Y. Wang, Ming Xue, Qianrong Fang, Shilun Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Confining Surface Oxygen Redox in Double Perovskites for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404560</link>
      <description>Natasha Hales, Jinzhen Huang, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Ivano E. Castelli, Radim Skoup&#253;, Adam H. Clark, Micha&#322; Andrzejewski, Nicola Casati, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706492

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;based double perovskites AA&#8242;BB&#8242;O 6 are an underexplored class of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, in which B&#8208;site substitution is used to tune electronic and structural properties. BaSrNiWO 6 , with a B&#8208;site comprised of alternating Ni and W, exhibits high oxygen evolution activity, attributed to the evolution of a highly OER active surface phase. The redox transformation of Ni 2+ (3d 8 ) to Ni 3+ (3d 7 ) combined with partial W dissolution into the electrolyte from the linear Ni(3d)&#8208;O(2p)&#8208;W(5d) chains drives an in situ reconstruction of the surface to an amorphized, NiO&#8208;like layer, promoting oxygen redox in the OER mechanism. However, the high valence W 6+ (5d 0 ) acts as a stabilizing electronic influence in the bulk, preventing the mobilization of lattice oxygen which is bound in highly covalent W&#9472;O bonds. It is proposed that the surface generated during the OER can support a lattice oxygen evolution mechanism (LOEM) in which oxygen vacancies are created and preferentially refilled by electrolytic OH &#8722; , while bulk O species remain stable. This surface LOEM (sLOEM) allows BaSrNiWO 6 to retain structural integrity during OER catalysis. With a Tafel slope of 45 mV dec &#8722;1 in 0.1 m KOH, BaSrNiWO 6 illustrates the potential of Ni&#8208;based double perovskites to offer both OER efficiency and bulk stability in alkaline electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Natasha Hales, Jinzhen Huang, Benjamin H. Sj&#248;lin, &#193;lvaro Garc&#237;a-Padilla, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Ivano E. Castelli, Radim Skoup&#253;, Adam H. Clark, Micha&#322; Andrzejewski, Nicola Casati, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202404560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Side Reaction Turned Positive: Synchronous OER Manipulating the Electrocatalytic Properties of Anodic Electrodeposited Lead Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410556</link>
      <description>Hua Guo, Xinyuan Li, Mingtao Li, Yang Liu, Wei Yan, Hao Xu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706719

                Abstract The preparation and modification of porous electrodes are an important component of the new generation electrochemical oxidation technology. Rapid preparation of porous electrodes can be easily achieved by synchronous oxygen bubble electrodeposition. However, according to the reaction mechanism of lead dioxide anodic electrodeposition, there is bound to be a competitive reaction of adsorbed hydroxyl radicals in the oxygen bubble template method, which means that synchronous OER impacts both the surface morphology and potentially the crystalline structure of the metal oxides. Clarifying the comprehensive influence of synchronous OER on the morphology and microstructure of the coating is important. In this work, the electrodeposition process of porous lead dioxide coating is regulated by the way of linear potential increase and realized the rapid preparation of high&#8208;performance porous lead dioxide coating within 40 s. The morphology and microstructure, electrical, and electrochemical properties are characterized, combined with theoretical calculation and orthogonal analysis, to investigate the regulatory mechanism of the rapid growth of the porous lead dioxide by the electric potential. It is demonstrated that synchronous OER confers porous morphology and a large number of defects to the coating in situ, and enhancing the electrocatalytic oxidation performance of the electrode.</description>
      <author>Hua Guo, Xinyuan Li, Mingtao Li, Yang Liu, Wei Yan, Hao Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Distortions Promoting the In-Depth Reconstruction of Ni-Based Electrocatalysts with Enriched Oxygen Vacancies for the Electrochemical Oxidation of 5-Hydroxymethylfurfural toward 2,5-Furandicarboxylic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03764</link>
      <description>Y KOU, Fanan Wang, Yun Lin, Di Liu, Qian Wang, Yan Zhang, Wenting Wen, Junhong Huang, Rengui Weng, Gang Xu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406708098

                The electrocatalytic 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation reaction (HMFOR) toward 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) has been considered a promising approach for the substitution of the energy-consuming and hazardous oxygen evolution reaction and for the valorization of renewable biomass. However, it is limited by the susceptibility of HMF to the oxidative environment and requires efficient electrocatalysts. Herein, a NiMo complex (NiMo-N) is provided as the precatalyst for the HMFOR, exhibiting favorable performances with a current density of 450 mA&#183;cm-2 achieved at an anodic potential of 1.4 V vs RHE (similarly hereinafter) with 50 mmol/L (mM) HMF and over 95% HMF conversion and FDCA FE for at least five cycles. Combined with quasi situ and in situ analysis, it is confirmed that the extensive lattice distortions in the precatalyst facilitate the in-depth reconstruction, increasing the accessible Ni sites and defective oxygen vacancies (Ov), which would promptly convert to high-valence Ni and active O species during the reaction. The improved performance is then attributed to the incorporation of the improved chemisorption and dehydrogenation ability of HMF by the as-evolved active sites.</description>
      <author>Y KOU, Fanan Wang, Yun Lin, Di Liu, Qian Wang, Yan Zhang, Wenting Wen, Junhong Huang, Rengui Weng, Gang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-Situ Phosphorus Doping Derived P-Metal-N Coordination Configuration to Boost the Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5108001</link>
      <description>Zhenlu Zhao, Zeqi Wu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406716107

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhenlu Zhao, Zeqi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5108001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Single-Crystal Cobalt Carbonate Hydroxide via Surface Fe Doping and Facet Dependence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03018</link>
      <description>Shenghua Ye, Zhi&#8208;Jun Ou, Weibin Chen, Shuyuan Wu, D. Xiao, Jie Zhang, Lirong Zheng, Wenda Chen, Yuanguo Xu, Yongliang Li, Xiangzhong Ren, Xiaoping Ouyang, Xueqing Yan, Jianhong Liu, Qianling Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406716855

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical half-reaction in water splitting and metal&#8211;air cells. The sensitivity of the OER to the composition and structure of the electrocatalyst presents a significant challenge in elucidating the structure&#8211;property relationship. In this study, highly stable single-crystal cobalt carbonate hydroxide [Co2(OH)2CO3, CoCH] was used as a model to investigate the correlations among structure, composition, and reactivity. Single-crystal CoCH nanowires (denoted as CoCH NWs) and Fe-doped CoCH nanowires (denoted as Fe-CoCH NWs) with an exposed (210) facet and Fe-doped CoCH nanosheets (denoted as Fe-CoCH NSs) with an exposed (2&#8211;13) facet were synthesized using electrochemical and one-step hydrothermal strategies, respectively. Their OER activity decreased in the following order: Fe-CoCH NWs &gt; Fe-CoCH NSs &gt; CoCH NWs. Theoretical investigation suggested that the doped Fe sites serve as active sites, and the crystal-facet dependence can finely adjust the 3d configuration of Fe sites, resulting in the optimal adsorption strengths and energy barriers for potential-determining steps on the (210) facet of CoCH. This renders the as-prepared Fe-CoCH NWs as some of the most promising Co-based OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shenghua Ye, Zhi&#8208;Jun Ou, Weibin Chen, Shuyuan Wu, D. Xiao, Jie Zhang, Lirong Zheng, Wenda Chen, Yuanguo Xu, Yongliang Li, Xiangzhong Ren, Xiaoping Ouyang, Xueqing Yan, Jianhong Liu, Qianling Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ identification and dynamic transformation of FeOOH with different phases for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109319</link>
      <description>Ze&#8208;Feng Xu, Chuan-Wu Chen, Ya&#8208;Nan Jing, Da-Qiang Liu, Leilei Li, Xing-Liang Yin, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 190(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406725386

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ze&#8208;Feng Xu, Chuan-Wu Chen, Ya&#8208;Nan Jing, Da-Qiang Liu, Leilei Li, Xing-Liang Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2025.109319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese doped Ni-MOF derived porous carbon-based bifunctional oxygen electrode catalyst for metal air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130448</link>
      <description>Naseem Iqbal, Rabia Ahmad, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Nadia Shahzad, Muhammad Imran Shahzad, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406739276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naseem Iqbal, Rabia Ahmad, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Nadia Shahzad, Muhammad Imran Shahzad</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2025.130448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating oxygen-vacancy of IrOx@Ti via controllably partial pressures by magnetron sputtering for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162525</link>
      <description>Shurong Zhang, Lei Yu, Feng Guo, Xinghua Ma, Bo Gao, Jin Wang, Xiaoye Du, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741645

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shurong Zhang, Lei Yu, Feng Guo, Xinghua Ma, Bo Gao, Jin Wang, Xiaoye Du</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GC-DFT simulation of coverage and potential effect for oxygen evolution reaction on RuO2-based electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</link>
      <description>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741776

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Ge, Suiqin Li, Jingnan Zheng, Xing Zhong, Shibin Wang, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115968</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT, molecular docking, antimicrobial activity, dye degradation, and oxygen evolution reaction of functionalized chitosan integrated eudragit-stannous selenide nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105907</link>
      <description>Areej Fatima, Misbah Naz, Adnan Ali, Iram Shahzadi, Anwar Ul-Ham&#305;d, Hameed Ullah, Ghafar Ali, Sawaira Moeen, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Muhammad Ikram, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406741955

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Areej Fatima, Misbah Naz, Adnan Ali, Iram Shahzadi, Anwar Ul-Ham&#305;d, Hameed Ullah, Ghafar Ali, Sawaira Moeen, Salah M. El&#8208;Bahy, Muhammad Ikram</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2025.105907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Regulation of High-Entropy Perovskite Oxides through Hole Doping for Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20338</link>
      <description>Gaoliang Fu, Ruipeng Hou, Li Sun, Huili Liu, Yaru Wei, Ruixue Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Shouren Zhang, Baocheng Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406747925

                Due to the high configuration entropy, unique atomic arrangement, and electronic structures, high-entropy materials are being actively pursued as bifunctional catalysts for both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in rechargeable zinc-air batteries (ZABs). However, a relevant strategy to enhance the catalytic activity of high-entropy materials is still lacking. Herein, a hole doping strategy has been employed to enable the high-entropy perovskite La(Cr0.2Mn0.2Fe0.2Co0.2Ni0.2)O3 to effectively catalyze the ORR and OER. Hole doping experiments rely on the substitution of Sr2+ for La3+. The optimized La0.7Sr0.3(Cr0.2Mn0.2Fe0.2Co0.2Ni0.2)O3 displays remarkable activity for the ORR and the OER, with a low potential difference of 0.880 V between the half-wave potential of the ORR and the OER potential at 10 mA cm-2, exceeding the majority of perovskite bifunctional catalysts. Further analysis of the electronic structures reveals that hole doping could regulate the eg-orbital filling of the transition-metal cations in high-entropy perovskites to an ideal position and thereby generate many highly active sites to promote the redox activity of oxygen. The assembled rechargeable ZAB with the targeted high-entropy perovskite as the cathode affords a specific capacity of 774.5 mAh gZn-1 under 10 mA cm-2 and durability for a period of 300 cycles, comparable to that of the 20%Pt/C + RuO2 ZAB. This work offers an important approach for the advancement of efficient high-entropy perovskites for ZABs.</description>
      <author>Gaoliang Fu, Ruipeng Hou, Li Sun, Huili Liu, Yaru Wei, Ruixue Wei, Xiangyu Meng, Shouren Zhang, Baocheng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical screening of multifunctional single-atom catalysts supported by VS2 monolayer for the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115098</link>
      <description>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang, Computational and Theoretical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406748597

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liang-Cai Ma, Peng Yuan, Yin-Yin Hou, Hao Li, Haijuan Wang, Jian&#8208;Min Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2025.115098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Role of Functional Groups of Terephthalate in Enhancing the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Nickel&#8211;Organic Framework Nanoarrays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04958</link>
      <description>Chong Lin, Shun Wang, Xuetong Zhang, Bin Xiao, Yepeng Zeng, Li Huang, Fei Luo, K Liu, Jingyang Tian, Min Li, Minghui Cao, Yong Qian, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406750293

                The platelike nickel-terephthalate-type metal-organic framework nanoarrays (Ni-BDC NAs) on carbon cloth are obtained by employing agaric-like Ni(OH)2 NAs as sacrificial templates. The microenvironment of Ni-BDC NAs is modulated by various neighboring functional groups (-NH2, -NO2, and -Br) on the carboxylate ligand, exerting minimal destructive effects on the structure and morphology of Ni-BDC NAs. The electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) of Ni-BDC-NH2 NAs, Ni-BDC-NO2 NAs, and Ni-BDC-Br NAs exhibited a significant enhancement compared to that of Ni-BDC NAs alone, as evidenced by both experimental and theoretical assessments. The presence of neighboring groups exerts a positive influence on the electronic coupling between Ni and O atoms, thereby facilitating the thermodynamically favorable formation of *O intermediates on Ni sites and accelerating the kinetics of the OER. The findings presented here provide valuable insights for the design and utilization of carboxylic acid molecules with functional group effects, enhancing the activity of the OER across diverse Ni centers.</description>
      <author>Chong Lin, Shun Wang, Xuetong Zhang, Bin Xiao, Yepeng Zeng, Li Huang, Fei Luo, K Liu, Jingyang Tian, Min Li, Minghui Cao, Yong Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Li Liao, Rui Wang, Zerong Zhang, Jianfeng Zhang, Shibin Huang, Wenhao Xie, Y. Wang, Ming Xue, Qianrong Fang, Shilun Qiu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406750356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Liao, Rui Wang, Zerong Zhang, Jianfeng Zhang, Shibin Huang, Wenhao Xie, Y. Wang, Ming Xue, Qianrong Fang, Shilun Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced NiCo2O4 /ZnO-CuO/NF composite for high-performance asymmetric supercapacitor and efficient oxygen evolution reaction applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-025-01238-9</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Shusheel Kumar, Aneela Tahira, Adeel Liaquat Bhatti, Zaheer Ahmed Ujjan, Mansab Ali Jakhrani, Umair Aftab, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Ayman Nafady, Elmuez A. Dawi, M&#233;lanie Emo, Brigitte Vigolo, Antonia Infantes&#8208;Molina, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, Advanced Composites and Hybrid Materials. 8(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406755914

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Shusheel Kumar, Aneela Tahira, Adeel Liaquat Bhatti, Zaheer Ahmed Ujjan, Mansab Ali Jakhrani, Umair Aftab, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Ayman Nafady, Elmuez A. Dawi, M&#233;lanie Emo, Brigitte Vigolo, Antonia Infantes&#8208;Molina, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42114-025-01238-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Imaging of the Surface Termination and Reconstruction of Low and High Index Iridium Oxide Surfaces and Insights into Their Facet-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Activities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16908</link>
      <description>Yinping Wei, Wenshuo Li, Yangfan Shao, Ziqiang Wang, Hongda Du, Jia Li, Lin Gan, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406756155

                Resolving the atomic surface structure, particularly surface termination or reconstruction, is essential for understanding the catalytic properties of metal oxides. Although rutile phase iridium dioxide (IrO2) is the state-of-the-art electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water splitting, the atomic-level surface structures of IrO2 remain largely unexplored, limiting our understanding of its facet-dependent OER activities. Herein, we perform aberration-corrected integrated differential phase contrast scanning transmission electron microscopy of the low- and high-index surface structures of spindle-shaped IrO2 nanorods and reveal distinct surface terminations and/or reconstructions on different surfaces. Notably, the (110) surface shows a predominantly top-/bridge-oxygen termination and high structural stability without obvious surface reconstruction. In contrast, the (001) and (101) surfaces, where all surface Ir atoms are coordinatively unsaturated, undergo significant reconstruction. Additionally, a high-index (321) surface composed of (110) terraces is identified and exhibits a distinct [IrO] surface termination, indicating a weaker binding energy between Ir with O. Density functional theory calculations reveals weakened oxygen-binding energies on both the reconstructed (101) surface and the high-index (321) surface, predicting substantially lower limiting OER overpotentials compared to the (110) surface. These findings provide an important structural basis for understanding the OER activities of IrO2 surfaces.</description>
      <author>Yinping Wei, Wenshuo Li, Yangfan Shao, Ziqiang Wang, Hongda Du, Jia Li, Lin Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Nanoscale Characterization Reveals Fe Doping of Ni Oxide Enhances Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Fragmentation and Formation of Dual Active Sites.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419521</link>
      <description>Yunchang Liang, Sof&#237;a O. Parreiras, Seunghwa Lee, Karla Banjac, Victor Boureau, Jos&#233; M. Gallego, Xile Hu, David &#201;cija, &#8234;Magal&#237; Lingenfelder, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406757208

                Efficient catalytic water splitting demands advanced catalysts to improve the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Earth&#8208;abundant transition metal oxides show promising OER activity in alkaline media. However, most experimental information available is either from post&#8208;mortem studies or in&#8208;situ space&#8208;averaged X&#8208;ray techniques in the micrometer range. Therefore, the composition of the active centers under operando conditions is still under debate. In this work, we combine nanoscopic and spectroscopic measurements on the hydroxylation of molecular beam epitaxy (MBE)&#8208;prepared Ni and NiFe oxides nanoislands with operando local investigations of Ni and NiFe hydroxide electrocatalysts under OER conditions to reveal the nature of the active centers in 2D OER catalysts. Our results reveal that Fe doping increases the active surface area by island fragmentation, and boosts the intrinsic activity by creating optimized active centers consisting of both Ni and Fe atoms. In addition, our findings show that operando characterization at the nanoscale is crucial to reveal the dynamic nature of the interface of 2D catalysts under reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Yunchang Liang, Sof&#237;a O. Parreiras, Seunghwa Lee, Karla Banjac, Victor Boureau, Jos&#233; M. Gallego, Xile Hu, David &#201;cija, &#8234;Magal&#237; Lingenfelder</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Nanoscale Characterization Reveals Fe Doping of Ni Oxide Enhances Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Fragmentation and Formation of Dual Active Sites.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419521</link>
      <description>Yunchang Liang, Sof&#237;a O. Parreiras, Seunghwa Lee, Karla Banjac, Victor Boureau, Jos&#233; M. Gallego, Xile Hu, David &#201;cija, &#8234;Magal&#237; Lingenfelder, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406757974

                Efficient catalytic water splitting demands advanced catalysts to improve the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Earth&#8208;abundant transition metal oxides show promising OER activity in alkaline media. However, most experimental information available is either from post&#8208;mortem studies or in&#8208;situ space&#8208;averaged X&#8208;ray techniques in the micrometer range. Therefore, the composition of the active centers under operando conditions is still under debate. In this work, we combine nanoscopic and spectroscopic measurements on the hydroxylation of molecular beam epitaxy (MBE)&#8208;prepared Ni and NiFe oxides nanoislands with operando local investigations of Ni and NiFe hydroxide electrocatalysts under OER conditions to reveal the nature of the active centers in 2D OER catalysts. Our results reveal that Fe doping increases the active surface area by island fragmentation, and boosts the intrinsic activity by creating optimized active centers consisting of both Ni and Fe atoms. In addition, our findings show that operando characterization at the nanoscale is crucial to reveal the dynamic nature of the interface of 2D catalysts under reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Yunchang Liang, Sof&#237;a O. Parreiras, Seunghwa Lee, Karla Banjac, Victor Boureau, Jos&#233; M. Gallego, Xile Hu, David &#201;cija, &#8234;Magal&#237; Lingenfelder</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419521</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;One Stone, Two Birds&#8221;: Multi&#8208;Element Doping Induced Crystallinity Modulation for Large Current Density Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202422889</link>
      <description>Yuhang Yuan, Yifan Yang, Guanglei Liu, Ming&#8208;Wei Chang, Zhu Liu, Kaichun Gao, Huiling Zheng, Mingxin Ye, Jianfeng Shen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406760281

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a critical role in water splitting, which can directly determine the energy consumption of hydrogen production. However, the poor stability of catalysts at large current density inhibits their industrial application. Therefore, the development of efficient catalysts with industry&#8208;relevant activities still faces great challenges. Herein, a one&#8208;step corrosion strategy is reported for the preparation of multi&#8208;element low&#8208;crystal transition metal hydroxide (denoted as NiFeCrMnCo&#8208;c). Density functional theory calculation indicates that multi&#8208;element doping strategy improves the conductivity of the catalyst and reduces the energy barrier in the catalytic process. Only 259 and 303 mV overpotentials are required to achieve the anodic current densities of 100 and 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 respectively, and it can work at the anodic current density of 50 and 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for 300 h without apparent attenuation. Furthermore, when it is self&#8208;assembled as an anion exchange membrane electrolyzer, it requires only 1.72 V at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for industrial water splitting and operates stably for 100 h at 60 &#176;C, which can meet the requirements of industrial hydrogen production. The design of the OER catalysts with simple preparation, high activity, and high current density provides a new perspective for practical industrial water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Yuan, Yifan Yang, Guanglei Liu, Ming&#8208;Wei Chang, Zhu Liu, Kaichun Gao, Huiling Zheng, Mingxin Ye, Jianfeng Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202422889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of Ternary Layered Double Hydroxides by Tuning All Three Cations&#8217; Electronic Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15030177</link>
      <description>Gayi Nyongombe, M. M&#226;aza, Mohamed Siaj, M.S. Dhlamini, Nanomaterials. 15(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406761142

                The pursuit of efficient and sustainable hydrogen production is essential in the fight against climate change. One important method for achieving this is the electrolysis of water, particularly through the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Recent studies indicate that trimetallic layered double hydroxides (LDHs) can enhance OER performance compared to bimetallic LDHs. This improvement occurs because the third cation alters the electronic structures of the other two cations, thereby increasing the intermediates&#8217; binding energies and enhancing electrical conductivity. This study proposes an approach enabling the modulation of the electronic structures of all three cations involved in the synthesis of the trimetallic LDHs. It suggested intercalating sodium dodecyl sulfate (SDS) into the interlayer of the trimetallic NiFe-La-LDH. A successful intercalation of SDS has been confirmed through the XRD, FT-IR, EDS, and XPS. This has expanded the interlayer distance which was beneficial for the electrical conductivity. Furthermore, SDS generated sulphur, which modulated the electronic structures of all three cations enriching the active sites and improving electrical conductivity and OER performance compared to its counterparts. This approach is beneficial: 1. The interlayer can be further enlarged by using different doping ratios of SDS. 2. Sulphur can enrich the active sites and improve the OER performance.</description>
      <author>Gayi Nyongombe, M. M&#226;aza, Mohamed Siaj, M.S. Dhlamini</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano15030177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Dual Active Sites in Ru&#8208;doped FeMn&#8208;MOF&#8208;74 for Efficient Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202500149</link>
      <description>Wenting Sun, Jinqi Hu, Yongbing Lou, Jinxi Chen, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406763300

                The design of well&#8208;engineered bifunctional electrocatalysts is crucial for achieving durable and efficient performance in overall water splitting. In this study, Ru&#8208;doped FeMn&#8208;MOF&#8208;74 itself has Ru sites and generates FeMnOOH under catalytic conditions, forming dual active sites for overall water splitting. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrate that the Ru dopants exhibit optimized binding strength for H* and enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance. Moreover, the Mn sites within FeMnOOH lower the energy barrier for the rate&#8208;determining step (from O* to OOH*), serving as the active centre for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The incorporation of Ru significantly improves the electron transfer properties of FeMn&#8208;MOF&#8208;74 and enhances its water adsorption capacity, synergistically boosting its bifunctional activity. This strategy of designing dual active sites provides new insights into the development of bifunctional metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) for efficient overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Wenting Sun, Jinqi Hu, Yongbing Lou, Jinxi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202500149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic synthesis of pure H2O2 from crossover oxygen through a porous proton exchange membrane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100088</link>
      <description>Kazuma Enomoto, Takuya Okazaki, Kosuke Beppu, Fumiaki Amano, Materials Today Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406765638

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kazuma Enomoto, Takuya Okazaki, Kosuke Beppu, Fumiaki Amano</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcata.2025.100088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium Substitution Within Ruthenium Oxide Aerogels Enables High Activity Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15020116</link>
      <description>Jesus Adame-Solorio, Samuel W. Kimmel, Kathleen O. Bailey, Christopher P. Rhodes, Crystals. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406768633

                Acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts that provide high activity, lower costs, and long-term stability are needed for the wide-scale adoption of proton-exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolyzers for generating hydrogen through electrochemical water splitting. We report the effects of chromium substitution and temperature treatments on the structure, OER activity, and electrochemical stability of ruthenium oxide (RuO2) aerogel OER electrocatalysts. RuO2 and Cr-substituted RuO2 aerogels (Ru0.6Cr0.4O2) were synthesized using sol&#8211;gel chemistry and then thermally treated at different temperatures. Introducing chromium into the synthesis increased the surface area (7&#8211;11 times higher) and pore volume (5&#8211;6 times higher) relative to RuO2 aerogels. X-ray diffraction analysis is consistent with s that Cr was substituted into the rutile RuO2 structure. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy showed that trivalent Cr substitution altered the surface electronic structure and ratio of surface hydroxides. The specific capacitance values of Cr-substituted RuO2 aerogels were consistent with charge storage within a hydrous surface. Cr-substituted RuO2 aerogels exhibited 26 times the OER mass activity and 3.5 times the OER specific activity of RuO2 aerogels. Electrochemical stability tests show that Cr-substituted RuO2 aerogels exhibit similar stability to commercial RuO2. Understanding how metal substituents can be used to alter OER activity and stability furthers our ability to obtain highly active, durable, and lower-cost OER electrocatalysts for PEM electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Jesus Adame-Solorio, Samuel W. Kimmel, Kathleen O. Bailey, Christopher P. Rhodes</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst15020116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>W&#8208;mediated electron accumulation in Ru&#8208;O&#8208;W motifs enables ultra&#8208;stable oxygen evolution reaction in acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422707</link>
      <description>Chunzhong Li, Kai Zhou, Heng Liu, Zhongliang Liu, Xiaoning Li, Nana Wang, Mingyue Wang, Tianrui Xue, Yongjun Shen, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406773897

                The development of efficient and durable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is crucial for advancing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) technology, especially in the pursuit of non&#8208;iridium alternatives. Herein, we report a Zn, W co&#8208;doping Ru3Zn0.85W0.15Ox (RZW) ternary oxide catalyst that exhibits a low overpotential of 200 mV and remarkable stability for over 4000 hours at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.1 M HClO4. The incorporation of highly electronegative W facilitates the efficient capture of electrons released from the sacrificial Zn species during OER, and subsequently mediated to Ru sites. The observed enhancement in electron density within the stable Ru&#8208;O&#8208;W motifs substantially improve the anti&#8208;overoxidation properties of the Ru active sites. Our findings highlight the importance of strategic metal doping in modulating the electronic structure of OER catalysts during operation, thereby facilitating the development of practical and long&#8208;lasting water electrolysis technologies.</description>
      <author>Chunzhong Li, Kai Zhou, Heng Liu, Zhongliang Liu, Xiaoning Li, Nana Wang, Mingyue Wang, Tianrui Xue, Yongjun Shen, Hao Li, Huihui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>W&#8208;mediated electron accumulation in Ru&#8208;O&#8208;W motifs enables ultra&#8208;stable oxygen evolution reaction in acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422707</link>
      <description>Chunzhong Li, Kai Zhou, Heng Liu, Zhongliang Liu, Xiaoning Li, Nana Wang, Mingyue Wang, Tianrui Xue, Yongjun Shen, Hao Li, Huihui Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406773955

                The development of efficient and durable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is crucial for advancing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) technology, especially in the pursuit of non&#8208;iridium alternatives. Herein, we report a Zn, W co&#8208;doping Ru3Zn0.85W0.15Ox (RZW) ternary oxide catalyst that exhibits a low overpotential of 200 mV and remarkable stability for over 4000 hours at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.1 M HClO4. The incorporation of highly electronegative W facilitates the efficient capture of electrons released from the sacrificial Zn species during OER, and subsequently mediated to Ru sites. The observed enhancement in electron density within the stable Ru&#8208;O&#8208;W motifs substantially improve the anti&#8208;overoxidation properties of the Ru active sites. Our findings highlight the importance of strategic metal doping in modulating the electronic structure of OER catalysts during operation, thereby facilitating the development of practical and long&#8208;lasting water electrolysis technologies.</description>
      <author>Chunzhong Li, Kai Zhou, Heng Liu, Zhongliang Liu, Xiaoning Li, Nana Wang, Mingyue Wang, Tianrui Xue, Yongjun Shen, Hao Li, Huihui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte engineering towards efficient oxygen evolution electrodes with enhanced catalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134438</link>
      <description>Zhilin Zhang, Chenyang Cai, Yutao Hua, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Xinchuan Du, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao, Fuel. 388(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406780323

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhilin Zhang, Chenyang Cai, Yutao Hua, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Xinchuan Du, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial properties of gold and cobalt oxyhydroxide in plasmon-mediated oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46569/47429k58s</link>
      <description>Janet Zhen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406722969

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Janet Zhen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46569/47429k58s</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Investigations of the Au and NiOOH Interface in the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46569/7w62fj62g</link>
      <description>Guoqing Guan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406723328

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guoqing Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46569/7w62fj62g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406750049

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406750268

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406750364

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406750703

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of Oxygen Evolution Efficiency and Suppression of Side Reaction of Lithium Air Battery based on Metal Halide Electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53619/kobs.2024.12.4.2.137</link>
      <description>Juhyoung Kim, Dongwook Kim, Journal of the Korean Battery Society. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406780674

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juhyoung Kim, Dongwook Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53619/kobs.2024.12.4.2.137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Stacking Faults in Fe2B Induces a High-Performance Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010089</link>
      <description>Haoyu Li, Xin Liu, Xiaoyan Liu, Jian Cao, Lili Yang, Huilian Liu, Pinwen Zhu, Qiang Zhou, Xingbin Zhao, Yanli Chen, Maobin Wei, Qiang Tao, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406669871

                Fe2B is a potentially promising electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to its excellent electronic conductivity, which is superior to that of traditional oxide catalysts. However, the activity of Fe2B is still not satisfactory. In this study, meta-stable microstructure stacking faults (SFs) were incorporated into Fe2B through a one-step high-pressure and high-temperature (HPHT) method. Pressure suppressed atomic diffusion but formed SFs when the grain grew. Fe2B with SFs exhibited remarkable OER activity, with low overpotential values of only 269 and 344 mV required to reach current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively; because of the presence of SFs, the overpotential for the OER was reduced to only 67.7% of that of Fe2B without SFs at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Theoretical and experimental investigations confirmed that these SFs regulate the d-band center of Fe2B toward the Fermi level, optimizing the catalytic site activity. Furthermore, SFs reduced the charge transfer between Fe atoms and boron (B) atoms, increasing the number of free electrons in the structure and thereby increasing conductivity. Finally, this study suggests a strategy to construct microstructures in crystals, providing new insights into designing excellent catalysts via microstructure engineering.</description>
      <author>Haoyu Li, Xin Liu, Xiaoyan Liu, Jian Cao, Lili Yang, Huilian Liu, Pinwen Zhu, Qiang Zhou, Xingbin Zhao, Yanli Chen, Maobin Wei, Qiang Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mg-Evaporation Induced Amorphous Multi-Principal Element Alloys for Advanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110686</link>
      <description>Jianghong Zhang, Yu Lu, Mingzhen Xiu, Jiuyang Xia, H. Denny Kamaruddin, Liang Yu, Ke Li, Kang Huang, Bowei Zhang, Bowen Huang, Junsheng Wu, Yizhong Huang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406603583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianghong Zhang, Yu Lu, Mingzhen Xiu, Jiuyang Xia, H. Denny Kamaruddin, Liang Yu, Ke Li, Kang Huang, Bowei Zhang, Bowen Huang, Junsheng Wu, Yizhong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2025.110686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Heterogeneous Surface/Interface Reconstruction of Nickel Molybdate Nanofiber by In Situ Prussian Blue Analogs Etching Strategy for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12882</link>
      <description>Xinyao Ding, Lirong Zhang, Peng Yu, Ruibai Cang, Mingyi Zhang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406733316

                Bimetallic oxides are promising electrocatalysts due to their rich composition, facile synthesis, and favorable stability under oxidizing conditions. This paper innovatively proposes a strategy aimed at constructing a one&#8208;dimensional heterostructure (Fe&#8211;NiO/NiMoO 4 nanoparticles/nanofibers). The strategy commences with the meticulous treatment of NiMoO 4 nanofibers, utilizing in situ etching techniques to induce the formation of Prussian Blue Analog compounds. In this process, [Fe(CN) 6 ] 3&#8722; anions react with the NiMoO 4 host layer to form a steady NiFe PBA. Subsequently, the surface/interface reconstituted NiMoO 4 nanofibers undergo direct oxidation, leading to a reconfiguration of the surface structure and the formation of a unique Fe&#8211;NiO/NiMoO 4 one&#8208;dimensional heterostructure. The catalyst showed markedly enhanced electrocatalytic performance for the oxygen evolution reaction. Density functional theory results reveal that the incorporation of Fe as a dopant dramatically reduces the Gibbs free energy associated with the rate&#8208;determining step in the oxygen evolution reaction pathway. This pivotal transformation directly lowers the activation energy barrier, thereby significantly enhancing electron transfer efficiency.</description>
      <author>Xinyao Ding, Lirong Zhang, Peng Yu, Ruibai Cang, Mingyi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12882</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological and surface chemical composition disorder induced efficient oxygen evolution and supercapacitor processes into Co3O4 nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112577</link>
      <description>Abdul Jaleel Laghari, Umair Aftab, Huma Shaikh, Antonia Infantes&#8208;Molina, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406580798

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Jaleel Laghari, Umair Aftab, Huma Shaikh, Antonia Infantes&#8208;Molina, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2025.112577</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron doping boosts the catalytic activity of Pd single-atom catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction of lithium peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2025.115433</link>
      <description>Luhong Chen, Qiang Ke, Xueling Lei, Journal of Energy Storage. 111(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406573720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luhong Chen, Qiang Ke, Xueling Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2025.115433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degree of span control to determine the impact of different mechanisms and limiting steps: Oxygen evolution reaction over Co3O4(001) as a case study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115970</link>
      <description>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406732898

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2025.115970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Shell Thickness on the Oxygen Evolution Activity of Core@shell Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01784</link>
      <description>Iryna Makarchuk, Benjamin Rotonnelli, Lisa Royer, Simon Hettler, Jean&#8208;Jacques Gallet, Fabrice Bournel, Julie Guehl, Amandine Brige, Andrea Zitolo, Gw&#233;na&#235;lle K&#233;rangu&#233;ven, Antoine Bonnefont, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Elena R. Savinova, Tristan Asset, Beno&#238;t P. Pichon, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406702474

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Iryna Makarchuk, Benjamin Rotonnelli, Lisa Royer, Simon Hettler, Jean&#8208;Jacques Gallet, Fabrice Bournel, Julie Guehl, Amandine Brige, Andrea Zitolo, Gw&#233;na&#235;lle K&#233;rangu&#233;ven, Antoine Bonnefont, Ra&#250;l Arenal, Elena R. Savinova, Tristan Asset, Beno&#238;t P. Pichon</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c01784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient chromium-based transition metal nitrides catalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115385</link>
      <description>Muhammad Faizan, Humaira A. Bibi, Erum Aamir, Roheen Saeed, Sieh Kiong Tiong, Hua Song, Renewable and Sustainable Energy Reviews. 212(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406605754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Faizan, Humaira A. Bibi, Erum Aamir, Roheen Saeed, Sieh Kiong Tiong, Hua Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rser.2025.115385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Three-dimensional porphyrin-based covalent organic frameworks as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406750446

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi03018d/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ethane Oxidative Dehydrogenation over TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and M/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts: Unraveling the Surface Structure Evolution, Oxygen Species Type, and Role of Doped Metal in Tuning Catalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07213</link>
      <description>Mifeng Xue, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406708054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mifeng Xue, Baojun Wang, Maohong Fan, Lixia Ling, Riguang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c07213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique hierarchical NiFe-LDH/Ni/NiCo2S4 heterostructure arrays on nickel foam for the improvement of overall water splitting activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr05248j</link>
      <description>Xiong Gong, Jian Zhou, Xianya Liu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406624608

                The development of environmental-friend, high-efficiency, good stability, earth-abundant and non-precious metal-based electro-catalysts with the fast kinetics and low overpotential of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is...</description>
      <author>Xiong Gong, Jian Zhou, Xianya Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr05248j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom Tungsten Doping Induced Chemical-electrochemical Coupled Pathway on Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Enables Efficient Urea Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee05340k</link>
      <description>Lebin Cai, Haoyun Bai, Jilong Li, Feng Xie, Kang Jiang, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Hui Pan, Yongwen Tan, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406702468

                Electrocatalytic urea oxidation reaction (UOR) has emerged as a promising alternative to oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for wastewater recycling and energy recovery. However, traditional UOR pathway on NiOOH surface faces...</description>
      <author>Lebin Cai, Haoyun Bai, Jilong Li, Feng Xie, Kang Jiang, Ying&#8208;Rui Lu, Hui Pan, Yongwen Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee05340k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secondary Coordination Effects of Adjacent Metal Center in Metal&#8211;Nitrogen-Carbon Improve Scaling Relation of Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03285</link>
      <description>Ke Ye, Yulan Han, Min Hu, P. Hu, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406614507

                Heterogenous single-atom catalysts (SACs) are reminiscent of homogeneous catalysts because of the similarity of structural motif of active sites, showing the potential of using the advantage of homogeneous catalysts to tackle challenges in hetereogenous catalysis. In heterogeneous oxygen electrocatalysis, the homogeneity of adsorption patterns of reaction intermediates leads to scaling relationships that limit their activities. In contrast, homogeneous catalysts can circumvent such limits by selectively altering the adsorption of intermediates through secondary coordination effects (SCEs). This inspired us to explore potential SCEs in metal&#8211;nitrogen-carbon (M&#8211;N-C), a promising type of oxygen evolution electrocatalyst. We introduced SCEs with a neighboring metal site that can modulate the adsorption strengths of oxygen-containing intermediates. First-principles calculations show that the second site in the heteronuclear duo four-nitrogen-coordinated metal center can induce SCEs that selectively stabilize the OOH intermediate but with minor effects on the OH intermediate and, thereby, disrupt the scaling relation between oxygen species and eventually increase the catalytic activity in oxygen evolution reactions. Additionally, the activity of oxygen reduction reaction of selected M&#8211;N-C is also enhanced by such SCE. Our computational work underscored the critical role SCEs can have in shaping activities of SACs, particularly in favorably altering scaling relationships, and demonstrated its potential to address catalytic challenges in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Ke Ye, Yulan Han, Min Hu, P. Hu, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of dopants in mitigating the chemo&#8208;mechanical degradation of Ni&#8208;rich cathode: A critical review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.92</link>
      <description>Imesha Rambukwella, Hanisha Ponnuru, Cheng Yan, EcoEnergy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406619840

                Abstract Ni&#8208;rich cathodes are more promising candidates to the increasing demand for high capacity and the ability to operate at high voltages. However, the high Ni content creates a trade&#8208;off between energy density and cycling stability, mainly caused by the chemo&#8208;mechanical degradation. Oxygen evolution, cation mixing, rock salt formation, phase transition, and crack formation contribute to the degradation process. To overcome this problem, strategies such as doping, surface coating, and core&#8208;shell structures have been employed. The advantage of doping is to engineer the cathode surface, structure, and particle morphology simultaneously. This review aims to summarize recent advances in understanding chemo&#8208;mechanical degradation mechanism and the role of different dopants in enhancing the thermal stability and overall electrochemical performance. The pinning and pillaring effects of dopants on suppressing oxygen evolution, cation mixing, and phase transition are introduced. It is found that the higher ionic radii enable dopants to reside on cathode particles, preserving the particle surface and refining particle morphology to suppress crack formation. Finally, the effect of doping on Li ion diffusion, rate capability, and long&#8208;term stability are discussed.</description>
      <author>Imesha Rambukwella, Hanisha Ponnuru, Cheng Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ece2.92</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Unconventional Seawater Acceleration Effect Enables High&#8208;Spin Cobalt Sites for Industrial&#8208;Level Seawater Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419626</link>
      <description>Yuntong Sun, Y Li, Liming Dai, Nicole L. D. Sui, Wenjun Fan, Yingtang Zhou, Junwu Zhu, Jong&#8208;Min Lee, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406760332

                Abstract Catalytic seawater electrolysis is a valuable renewable energy generation process. However, it is restricted by the intricate and corrosive ionic nature of seawater which hinders oxygen evolution reaction (OER), one of the reactions governing seawater electrolysis. Herein, we introduce an effective approach that not only withstands, but also harnesses the potential of complex ions in seawater to enhance the efficiency and durability of OER. Unlike conventional strategies that address adverse effects through catalyst surface modification, we found that seawater actively facilitates the reconstruction of catalysts with high&#8208;spin sites. In situ characterizations suggest that the selective adsorption of Cl &#8722; from seawater on high&#8208;spin Co sites in alkaline seawater accelerates catalyst reconstruction, contributing to the rapid formation of high&#8208;valence Co, which enhances OER activity. The resulting reconstructed wrinkled nanosheets also create additional active Co sites and accelerate electrolyte transport. As a result, we achieve an overpotential as low as 377 mV at a current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 , showcasing nearly 100% oxygen evolution efficiency in alkaline seawater. Notably, our approach achieves a remarkable current density of 2.13 A cm &#8722;2 prior to the onset of the chlorine evolution reaction, underscoring its potential for efficient and sustainable seawater electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Yuntong Sun, Y Li, Liming Dai, Nicole L. D. Sui, Wenjun Fan, Yingtang Zhou, Junwu Zhu, Jong&#8208;Min Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419626</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing electrocatalytic performance of RuO2-based catalysts: mechanistic insights, strategic approaches, and recent advances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/adad9f</link>
      <description>Binod Raj K C, D. Kumar, Bishnu Prasad Bastakoti, Journal of Physics Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406749323

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting presents the ultimate potential of hydrogen and oxygen production; however, regulating the rate and efficiency of water splitting is highly dependent on the accessibility of extremely efficient electrode materials for slow performance kinetics and large overpotential of both oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Ruthenium oxide (RuO2) based materials display high performance for OER and HER because of their capacity to bind oxygen, eminent catalytic activity, low cost compared to other precious metals, and stability in a wide pH range. However, there is still much space to promote the OER and HER activity and stability of RuO2 to fulfill the necessity for practical applications in water splitting. Different researchers applied multiple approaches that boosted the catalytic performance of RuO2-based electrocatalysts toward overall water splitting. Herein, this review provides a comprehensive overview of recent advancements in RuO2-based materials in the field of water electrolysis for the generation of alternative energies. It gives a general description of water splitting in acidic and alkaline settings, including reaction mechanisms as well as common evaluation elements for the catalytic function of the materials. Most of the review reported based on RuO2 materials are only focused on OER performance but this review highlighted comprehensive ideas on different strategies like morphology design, electronic structure, electrolytes, and optimizing both electrocatalytic HER and OER functioning of RuO2-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Binod Raj K C, D. Kumar, Bishnu Prasad Bastakoti</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/adad9f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuCu Nanorod Arrays Synergistically Promote Efficient Water-Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010098</link>
      <description>Tao Chen, Xiangkai Kong, Qiangchun Liu, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406698375

                In the realm of green hydrogen energy, utilizing ruthenium (Ru) as a precious metal electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) instead of platinum (Pt/C) is an excellent choice. Unfortunately, there are not enough active sites or electronic structures on a single Ru-based catalyst to significantly improve the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Therefore, creating bifunctional water electrolysis catalysts that are stable and highly active in a variety of media continues to be a major challenge. The study describes a new method for creating an electrocatalyst (RuCuCl/NF-2) by using Ru to regulate an inert CuCl precursor. The enhanced mass transfer performance of the distinctive coral structure and the synergistic effect of RuCu emphasize its excellent water electrolysis activity, which is based on the self-assembly of Cu nanoparticles into a conical membrane structure. Overtaking the commercial benchmark Pt/C (~38 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2), the RuCuCl/NF-2 displays HER activity (~25 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2) in 1M KOH. This sheds light on how to create more sophisticated bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Chen, Xiangkai Kong, Qiangchun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distinct Promotion of PEC Water Oxidation of Ta&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;/&#945;-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/Co&#8211;Ni PBA via Coupling Ni 3d with O 2p</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c05042</link>
      <description>Yuan Guan, Qiankun Deng, Dayu Wu, Shaomang Wang, Zhongyu Li, Shicheng Yan, Zhigang Zou, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406764969

                The development of robust and effective photoanodes is crucial for photoelectrochemical hydrogen production via total water splitting. Herein, the Ta2O5/&#945;-Fe2O3/Co-Ni PBA (TFPB-1) photoanode was constructed by the compositing n-type Ta2O5 and n-type &#945;-Fe2O3 followed by the deposition of p-type Co-Ni PBA. The IPCE of TFPB-1 was increased to 35.4% compared to 13.9% for Ta2O5 owing to the significantly improved light absorption efficiency, carrier separation efficiency and injection efficiency. The TFPB-1 achieved a current density of 2.78 mA cm-2 at 1.23 V (vs RHE), which was around 18.5 times that of Ta2O5. The OER overpotential over TFPB-1 was reduced to 0.59 V compared to 1.13 V for Ta2O5, resulting in a substantial reduction in the free energy of PEC water oxidation over TFPB-1. As a result, TFPB-1 exhibited remarkably enhanced photoelectrocatalytic activity for oxygen evolution through water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Yuan Guan, Qiankun Deng, Dayu Wu, Shaomang Wang, Zhongyu Li, Shicheng Yan, Zhigang Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c05042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiny Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@Hollow Carbon Spheres&#9472;Polyacrylonitrile/Carbon Black Fiber-Based Bifunctional Air Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04378</link>
      <description>Yongsong Tan, Xiaorong Shi, Weiyi Han, Dajiang Kuang, Chaoxia Wang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406781419

                In the realm of zinc-air batteries, high bifunctional catalytic efficacy is intimately tied to the evaluation of catalysts. Consequently, the pursuit of proficient bifunctional catalysts that can efficiently catalyze both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a paramount objective in this research area. In this study, the spiny cobalt tetroxide (Co3O4) encapsulated hollow carbon spheres (HCSs) are constructed by anchoring Co3O4 onto HCS via hydrothermal or annealing treatment. The strategic interface design of the HCS encourages an abundance of sites while simultaneously facilitating the proliferation of spiny Co3O4, offering an expansive surface area and abundant active sites. The surface active Co3+ ions and the induction of surface oxygen vacancies in spiny Co3O4 encapsulated HCS endow it with outstanding bifunctional catalytic activity and stability. After spray-coating and subsequent annealing of the spiny Co3O4 encapsulated HCS catalyst on the flexible carbon-based polyacrylonitrile (PAN) nanofiber support, the spiny Co3O4 encapsulated HCS-PAN/carbon black (C) 800 air electrode is successfully integrated. Moreover, the optimized spiny Co3O4 encapsulated HCS-PAN/C 800 air electrode displays a decreased potential difference (&#916;E) of 0.77 V for catalyzing the ORR and OER performance. This work introduces a promising candidate approach for exploring innovative bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts, targeting enhanced efficiency in portable energy storage applications.</description>
      <author>Yongsong Tan, Xiaorong Shi, Weiyi Han, Dajiang Kuang, Chaoxia Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c04378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Performance and Durability of Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries Utilizing W&#8208;Doped Cobalt Pentlandite Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419515</link>
      <description>Ning Liu, Zhijian Peng, Jiaming Sun, Ye Tian, Lefu Mei, Guocheng Lv, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Junying Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406766719

                Abstract The design of cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts is critical for advancing sustainable energy technologies, particularly for key reactions like the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in water electrolyzers and metal&#8211;air batteries. Cobalt pentlandite (CNFS) has emerged as a promising candidate, offering high conductivity, stability, and the advantage of using abundant elements. In this study, density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that tungsten (W) doping in CNFS, combined with an increased concentration of sulfur vacancies, can effectively shift the d&#8208;band center downward enhancing metal&#8208;sulfur orbital hybridization. These modifications facilitate the desorption of oxygen intermediate while maintaining structural integrity. Additionally, the engineering of this material with a hollow architecture further increases active site exposure, significantly improving catalytic activity. As a result of this multifaceted approach, the W&#8208;doped CNFS catalyst achieves a remarkably low OER overpotential of 241 mV at 50 mA cm&#8315; 2 , alongside enhanced ORR activity. Furthermore, the catalyst demonstrates excellent performance in rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs), achieving a peak power density of 100 mW cm&#8315; 2 and sustaining over 650 h of cycling at 4 mA cm&#8315; 2 . Overall, this study presents a viable strategy for improving ZAB performance and reducing costs by utilizing efficient and cost&#8208;effective metal sulfides with a cobalt pentlandite structure.</description>
      <author>Ning Liu, Zhijian Peng, Jiaming Sun, Ye Tian, Lefu Mei, Guocheng Lv, Ren He, Andreu Cabot, Junying Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrids of Deep HOMO Organic Cyanoacrylic Acid Dyes and Graphene Nanomaterials for Water Splitting Photoanodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18020463</link>
      <description>Alejandro Ans&#243;n&#8208;Casaos, Ana M. Benito, Wolfgang K. Maser, J. Orduna, Bel&#233;n Villacampa, Mar&#237;a&#8208;Jes&#250;s Blesa, Materials. 18(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406615496

                Dye-sensitization is a promising strategy to improve the light absorption and photoactivity abilities of wide-bandgap semiconductors, like TiO2. For effective water-splitting photoanodes with no sacrificial agents, the electrochemical potential of the dye must exceed the thermodynamic threshold needed for the oxygen evolution reaction. This study investigates two promising organic cyanoacrylic dyes, designed to meet that criterion by means of theoretical calculations. Both yellow-colored dyes were synthesized and characterized by optical and photoelectrochemical techniques, demonstrating strong light absorption in the visible region, suitable experimental reduction potentials, and adsorption from the organic solvent onto mesoporous TiO2 layers. In addition, to promote immobilization in aqueous electrolytes, the dyes were hybridized with graphene oxide or multi-walled carbon nanotubes. Photoelectrochemical analysis of the dye-sensitized photoelectrodes demonstrated efficient charge transfer from the dyes to the TiO2 photoanode under simulated solar light. While the starting photocurrent notably surpassed the blank TiO2, a subsequent decay points to kinetic obstacles that still need to be overcome.</description>
      <author>Alejandro Ans&#243;n&#8208;Casaos, Ana M. Benito, Wolfgang K. Maser, J. Orduna, Bel&#233;n Villacampa, Mar&#237;a&#8208;Jes&#250;s Blesa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma18020463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical deposition of bimetallic sulfides on novel BDD electrode for bifunctional alkaline seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-87104-6</link>
      <description>Mingxu Li, Genjie Chu, Jiyun Gao, Xiaolei Ye, Ming Hou, Shenghui Guo, Yunchuan Li, Ziqi Zhou, Yang Li, Pascal Briois, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406690346

                Seawater electrolysis is an ideal technology for obtaining clean energy&#8212;green hydrogen. Developing efficient bifunctional catalysts is crucial for hydrogen production through direct seawater electrolysis. Currently, metal substrates loaded with active catalysts are widely employed as electrodes for seawater electrolysis. However, the challenge of metal corrosion cannot be ignored. In this work, the boron-doped diamond (BDD) with excellent corrosion resistance was explored as a substrate for loading active catalysts in seawater electrolysis. A step-by-step electrodeposition method was used to fabricate the FeCoS/Ni/BDD electrode, effectively addressing the poor adhesion of the FeCoS active layer to the BDD substrate. The resulting electrode demonstrated interesting bifunctional catalytic performance, achieving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) overpotentials of 425 mV and 360 mV, respectively, in alkaline simulated seawater (1 M KOH and 3.5 wt% NaCl) at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722; 2. Furthermore, by increasing the KOH concentration in the alkaline simulated seawater to 3 M, the OER and HER overpotentials of the electrode significantly decreased to 383 and 300 mV, respectively. This work offers a novel approach for utilizing BDD substrates in the design of corrosion-resistant electrodes for alkaline seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Mingxu Li, Genjie Chu, Jiyun Gao, Xiaolei Ye, Ming Hou, Shenghui Guo, Yunchuan Li, Ziqi Zhou, Yang Li, Pascal Briois</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-025-87104-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring P-(Fe,V)-Codoped Metastable-Phase &#946;-NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Improving the Performance of Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02233</link>
      <description>Yuxuan Kong, Qingqing Guo, Dengke Xiong, Ning Chai, Qiao Jiang, Tianyu Chen, Fei&#8208;Yan Yi, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406740393

                It is especially essential to develop high-performance and low-cost nonprecious metal catalysts for large-scale hydrogen production. A large number of electrochemical catalysts composited by transition metal centers has been reported; however, it is still a great challenge to design and manipulate target electrocatalysts to realize high overall water-splitting activity at the atomic level. Herein, we develop totally new P-(Fe,V)-codoped metastable-phase &#946;-NiMoO4. As an electrocatalyst, it can realize oxygen evolution at only 163 mV and hydrogen evolution at only 44 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2. It, as both an anode and a cathode, is fabricated into a cell for overall water splitting, which has an ultralow voltage value of 1.48 V to drive a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and can remain stable for at least 100 h. In the target electrode, the P element plays three important roles: (1) it can stabilize the metastable-phase structure of &#946;-NiMoO4; (2) it can further optimize the electronic structure; and (3) it can provide more active sites. The synergistic effect for multimetal centers with different redox couples is key for the great improvement of catalytic activity. The related mechanism is discussed in detail.</description>
      <author>Yuxuan Kong, Qingqing Guo, Dengke Xiong, Ning Chai, Qiao Jiang, Tianyu Chen, Fei&#8208;Yan Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Spray Combustion Enabling Hierarchical Porous Carbon-Supported FeCoNi Alloy Catalyst for Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c19069</link>
      <description>Hongrui Huang, Qianqian Liang, Guangchao Li, Huajun Guo, Zhixing Wang, Guochun Yan, Xinhai Li, Hui Duan, Jiexi Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406708075

                Rechargeable Zn-air batteries (RZABs) are poised for industrial application, yet they require low-cost, high-performance catalysts that efficiently facilitate both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The pivotal challenge lies in designing multimetal active sites and optimizing the carbon skeleton structure to modulate catalyst activity. In this study, we introduce a novel hierarchical porous carbon-supported FeCoNi bifunctional catalyst, synthesized via a spray combustion method. The carbon, derived from sucrose, was tailored into a hierarchical porous morphology through etching with NO3- ions and NaCl, thereby significantly increasing the surface area for the interaction of the O2 and electrolyte interaction. The in situ formation of FeCoNi alloy nanoparticles ensures their uniform dispersion and anchoring, facilitating electron transport. The strong interaction and charge transfer at the heterogeneous FeCoNi alloy interfaces, along with nitrogen doping, which enhances the OER/ORR activity, endow the FeCoNi/N-PC catalyst with exceptional bifunctional catalytic properties, characterized by an activity parameter of 0.73 V. Furthermore, the RZAB assembled with this catalyst demonstrates outstanding cycling stability and reversibility, with a minimal round-trip efficiency decay of 7.6% over 1380 cycles (460 h) at 10 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Hongrui Huang, Qianqian Liang, Guangchao Li, Huajun Guo, Zhixing Wang, Guochun Yan, Xinhai Li, Hui Duan, Jiexi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c19069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Layered Oxide Cathodes Based on Universal Surface Residual Alkali Conversion Chemistry for Rechargeable Secondary Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417540</link>
      <description>Yi&#8208;Feng Liu, Hanxiao Liu, Yan&#8208;Fang Zhu, Hongrui Wang, Jiayang Li, Yong&#8208;Chun Li, Haiyan Hu, Zhenguo Wu, Xiaodong Guo, Yao Xiao, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406766859

                Abstract Layered transition metal oxides (LTMOs) are attractive cathode candidates for rechargeable secondary batteries because of their high theoretical capacity. Unfortunately, LTMOs suffer from severe capacity attenuation, voltage decay, and sluggish kinetics, resulting from irreversible lattice oxygen evolution and unstable cathode&#8208;electrolyte interface. Besides, LTMOs accumulate surface residual alkali species, like hydroxides and carbonates, during synthesis, limiting their practical application. Herein, a universal strategy is suggested to in situ convert surface residual alkali into a stable polymer coating layer for LTMOs, thus turning wastes into treasure. The formation process of polymer coating involves NH 4 F treatment to consume residual alkali, then utilizing generated fluorides to induce the ring&#8208;opening polymerization of tetrahydrofuran. Implementing this strategy to Li&#8208;rich Mn&#8208;based cathode materials (LRM) results in a notable reduction in voltage hysteresis, along with enhanced kinetics and cycling stability in lithium&#8208;ion batteries. With this layer of encapsulation, surface lattice oxygen release and layered&#8208;to&#8208;spinel phase transition of LRM are significantly alleviated with minimal mechanical degradation and surface parasitic reactions. Such strategy can also be applied to air&#8208;sensitive sodium&#8208;rich LTMOs in sodium&#8208;ion batteries, which showcases superior universality. This work might provide a promising solution to overcome residual alkali and interfacial instability issues for LTMOs in practical application.</description>
      <author>Yi&#8208;Feng Liu, Hanxiao Liu, Yan&#8208;Fang Zhu, Hongrui Wang, Jiayang Li, Yong&#8208;Chun Li, Haiyan Hu, Zhenguo Wu, Xiaodong Guo, Yao Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The prediction of X2B6 monolayers with ultrahigh carrier mobility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fphy.2024.1534301</link>
      <description>Xuesen Du, Zhaoming Huang, Frontiers in Physics. 12(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406628409

                Two-dimensional (2D) materials present novel electronic and catalytic performances, showing a promising application as nano-device. In this investigation, a family of 2D material, X 2 B 6 (X = K, Na and Rb), is predicted with puckered crystal structure by elemental mutation method. The dynamic and thermal stability of the X 2 B 6 monolayer is addressed. The anisotropic mechanical properties of the X 2 B 6 monolayer is obtained by the Young&#8217;s modulus (296&#8211;406 N/m) and the Poisson&#8217;s ratio (0.36&#8211;0.35). Interestingly, the K 2 B 6 and Rb 2 B 6 monolayers demonstrate a metallic band structure, while the Na 2 B 6 monolayer is a semiconductor with an ultra-narrow bandgap only about 0.42 eV. Then, the ultra-high electron mobility in the Na 2 B 6 monolayer is calculated as about 9942 cm 2 .V &#8722;1 .s &#8722;1 , and the excellent optical performance of the Na 2 B 6 monolayer is also addressed. More importantly, the advantageous catalytic activity in hydrogen evolution reduction (HER) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER) is explored in these X 2 B 6 monolayers. Our work suggests a theoretical guidance to use the X 2 B 6 monolayer as a high-speed electronic devices and highly efficient catalyst.</description>
      <author>Xuesen Du, Zhaoming Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fphy.2024.1534301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst&#8208;Anchored 3D Framework Electrodes: A Breakthrough in Large&#8208;Scale Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ppsc.202400226</link>
      <description>Samruddhi V. Chauhan, Kinjal K. Joshi, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh, Particle &amp; Particle Systems Characterization. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406628653

                Abstract The idea of grid&#8208;scale hydrogen production by water electrolysis has been made possible by developing catalyst&#8208;anchored three&#8208;dimensional (3D) foam&#8208;based electrodes. Catalytic performance in hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions is improved by incorporating catalyst in 3D interlinked porous architecture, which enhances electrical conductivity and speeds up the discharge of gas bubbles. The detailed study on the role&#8208;play of 3D frameworks in energy generation is explained in this article. The review also focuses on the recent development in utilizing these 3D substrates in the field of electrochemistry. Furthermore, it is imperative to enhance their compatibility with renewable energy systems and high&#8208;temperature electrolysis for the sustainable production of hydrogen. Therefore, this review briefly explores the innovative design of self&#8208;supported 3D framework electrodes using heterostructures and doping techniques to develop stable, durable, and efficient electrocatalysts. These catalysts aim to provide near&#8208;zero overpotential, high selectivity, and long&#8208;term stability for hydrogen production through water electrolysis, paving the way for commercial&#8208;scale green energy production. 3D foam&#8208;based electrodes can emerge as a key technology in the field of electrochemistry.</description>
      <author>Samruddhi V. Chauhan, Kinjal K. Joshi, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ppsc.202400226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-throughput calculations of two-dimensional auxetic $M_4X_8$ with
  magnetism, electrocatalysis, and alkali metal battery applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.11242</link>
      <description>Haidi Wang, Xu Li, Weiduo Zhu, Zhao Chen, Zhongjun Li, Xiaofeng Liu, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406734960

                Two-dimensional (2D) materials with multifunctional properties, such as negative Poisson's ratio (NPR), magnetism, catalysis, and energy storage capabilities, are of significant interest for advanced applications in flexible electronics, spintronics, catalysis, and lithium-ion batteries. However, the discovery of such materials, particularly in low-dimensional forms, remains a challenge. In this study, we perform high-throughput density-functional theory (DFT) calculations to explore a new class of 2D V-shaped monolayers with remarkable physicochemical properties. Among 18 stable $M_4X_8$ (M = transition metal; X = halogen) compounds, we identify 9 auxetic monolayers, with \ce{Pd4I8} standing out for its exceptionally high NPR of -0.798. Notably, 4 of these materials exhibit half semiconductor properties, while 5 others are bipolar magnetic semiconductors, offering a unique combination of electronic and magnetic behavior. Additionally, these materials demonstrate promising catalytic activity for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) and show potential as anodes for rechargeable metal-ion batteries, particularly in alkali-ion systems. This work not only expands the family of 2D NPR materials but also introduces new candidates with multifunctional capabilities for a wide range of applications in nanoelectronics, catalysis, and energy storage.</description>
      <author>Haidi Wang, Xu Li, Weiduo Zhu, Zhao Chen, Zhongjun Li, Xiaofeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.11242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strain Engineering of Ru&#8211;Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;Ni Nanoalloy Encapsulated with Carbon Nanotubes for Efficient Anion and Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420517</link>
      <description>Abhisek Majumdar, Tran Khoa Dang, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406706028

                Abstract Alloying atomically dispersed noble metals with earth&#8208;abundant transition metal nanoparticles (NPs) presents a promising approach to enhance the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water electrolysis. However, the challenge remains of reducing the size of the NPs without sacrificing high activity and durability. In this study, Ru&#8211;Co 2 Ni nanoalloy particles (NAPs) encapsulated in nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes (NCNTs) are introduced, forming a core&#8208;shell electrocatalyst (Ru&#8211;Co 2 Ni@NCNT). This design leverages Ru site optimization, CNT density control, strain engineering, efficient water dissociation, and outstanding bubble release dynamics within the core&#8208;shell structure. These factors significantly improve catalytic performance with low overpotentials of 35 and 57 mV overpotential in 1.0 m KOH and 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 solutions, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that while Ru sites serve as active sites, they also modify the electronic structure of Co and Ni, optimizing their hydrogen adsorption energies and improving HER efficiency. The Ru&#8211;Co 2 Ni@NCNT catalyst is successfully integrated into both anion exchange membrane (AEM) and proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzers, demonstrating stable operation at 0.5 A cm &#8722;2 for 500 h, underscoring its potential for efficient and durable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Abhisek Majumdar, Tran Khoa Dang, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyper-Cross-Linked Polymer-Derived Carbon-Coated Fe&#8211;Ni Alloy/CNT as a Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03361</link>
      <description>Arindam Modak, Ankita Phutela, Aniruddha Kundu, Srijib Das, Vidha Bhasin, D. Bhattacharyya, Saswata Bhattacharya, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406722932

                The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are considered to be the most important processes in metal&#8211;air batteries and regenerative fuel cell devices. Metal&#8211;organic polymers are attracting interest as promising precursors of advanced metal/carbon electrocatalysts because of their hierarchical porous structure along with the integrated metal&#8211;carbon framework. We developed carbon-coated CNTs with Ni/Fe and Cu/Fe as active sites. Experimental observations from X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and X-ray absorption analysis suggest that C@CNT[Ni] outperforms C@CNT[Cu] in the ORR and OER, which is further supported by density functional theory calculations. C@CNT[Ni] exhibits a higher onset potential (0.99 V vs RHE) and a smaller Tafel slope (40.2 mV decade&#8211;1) compared to those of C@CNT/[Cu] in an alkaline electrolyte (0.94 V vs RHE and 46.5 mV decade&#8211;1, respectively). Such circumstances are attributed to the alloying effect between Ni and Fe in C@CNT[Ni], in contrast to the existing copper iron oxide phase in C@CNT/[Cu]. It is noteworthy that C@CNT[Ni] also displayed an improved OER, demanding its bifunctional property. As a proof of concept, C@CNT[Ni] was utilized in zinc&#8211;air batteries, which shows a high energy efficiency of &#8764;60%, a small charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap of 0.78 V, and excellent cycling performance (&#8764;120 h) at 5 mA cm&#8211;2 and 25 &#176;C. This protocol expands the utility of novel metal&#8211;organic hyper-cross-linked polymer-derived bimetallic electrocatalysts for clean energy research.</description>
      <author>Arindam Modak, Ankita Phutela, Aniruddha Kundu, Srijib Das, Vidha Bhasin, D. Bhattacharyya, Saswata Bhattacharya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c03361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studies on the Electrochemical Behavior of Sulfite on Incoloy 800 in a Neutral Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app15031144</link>
      <description>Mihaela-Alexandra L&#259;bo&#537;el, Andrea Kellenberger, Mircea Lauren&#539;iu Dan, Nataliia Rudenko, George-Daniel Dima, Nicolae Vaszilcsin, Applied Sciences. 15(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406756465

                Avoiding atmospheric pollution with sulfur dioxide is generally achieved by its absorption from combustion gases in alkaline solutions and conversion to sulfites. Afterwards, sulfites can be transformed into neutral and environmentally safe chemicals by oxidation to sulfates. The oxidation of sulfites to sulfates can also be carried out in a cell in which the fuel will be sulfite ions. In this way, in addition to the beneficial effect of neutralizing large quantities of sulfite waste, electrical energy is also obtained. This is one of the reasons why study of the anodic oxidation of sulfite to sulfate on various electrode materials was necessary. Given the sensitivity of electrode materials in the presence of sulfur compounds, in our research we approached the study of sulfite oxidation on the Incoloy 800 anode in neutral solution (1 mol L&#8722;1 Na2SO4). In this research, the results obtained in the study of the kinetic parameters of the anodic process as a function of the sulfite concentration (10&#8722;1, 0.5, and 1 mol L&#8722;1), using linear voltammetry, are presented. The appreciable values of the exchange current density (3.4, 3.0, and 2.6 A m&#8722;2) show that Incoloy 800 has a significant catalytic effect in the anodic oxidation of sulfite. Chronoamperometric studies have shown that the anodic oxidation of sulfite is controlled by the mass transfer of sulfite ions from the bulk solution to the electrode surface. According to the chronocoulometric diagrams, it can be appreciated that, up to anodic potentials of +1.50 V, sulfite oxidation occurs on the electrode, while at more positive potentials, the oxygen evolution reaction is the main process. Electrochemical impedance data provide evidence of a chemical reaction coupled with electron transfer, which was modeled using a Gerischer impedance. At high sulfite concentrations, the charge transfer resistance (Rct) decreases by a factor of 10, indicating that the sulfite oxidation reaction is fast at sufficiently positive potentials. On the other hand, the passivation tendency of stainless steels upon anodic polarization gives them a high corrosion resistance, so that Incoloy 800 can be a viable option as an anode material for sulfite/oxygen (air) fuel cells.</description>
      <author>Mihaela-Alexandra L&#259;bo&#537;el, Andrea Kellenberger, Mircea Lauren&#539;iu Dan, Nataliia Rudenko, George-Daniel Dima, Nicolae Vaszilcsin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app15031144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Partially Substituted La for Sm in Sm&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;NiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;: An Efficient Electrocatalyst Towards Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405118</link>
      <description>Reena Parihar, Prakhar Mishra, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Narendra Kumar Singh, ChemistrySelect. 10(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406694906

                Abstract Perovskite&#8208;type oxides having composition La x Sm 0.8&#8722; x Sr 0.2 NiO 3 (0 &#8804; x &#8804; 0.6) were explored for their ability to act as facilitators for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. Synthesis of the materials was conducted through a sol&#8208;gel procedure via malic acid. The materials underwent advanced physicochemical characterization utilizing techniques, namely transmission electron microscope (TEM), scanning electron microscope/energy dispersive X&#8208;ray spectroscopy (SEM/EDS), inductively coupled plasma &#8211; mass spectrometry (ICP&#8208;MS) and X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD). These analyses provided crucial details about the material&#8217;s particle size, surface morphology/chemical composition and crystalline structure, opening up exciting possibilities for their diverse applications. From TEM analysis, the average particle size of the oxide materials has been estimated and found to be 5.9 nm for Sm 0.8 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 and 4.8 nm for La 0.6 Sm 0.2 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 . The particle size of the oxide material decreases when La was partially substituted for Sm in Sm 0.8 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 . Cyclic voltammetry and Tafel plot were observed for the electrochemical analysis in 1 M KOH (25 &#176;C). An investigation on the anodic polarization of oxides revealed an increased electrocatalytic activity when La was partially substituted for Sm in Sm 0.8 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 . La 0.6 Sm 0.2 Sr 0.2 NiO 3 was found to be most active at 800 mV with a current density, j = 184.1 mA/cm 2 . The Tafel experiment was conducted in 1M KOH at varying temperatures to determine thermodynamic properties like standard electrochemical energy of activation (), standard enthalpy of activation (&#916; H &#176; # ), and standard entropy of activation (&#916; S &#176; # ).</description>
      <author>Reena Parihar, Prakhar Mishra, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Narendra Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Interior Structure and Thermal Evolution of Super-Earth GJ
  486b</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.09963</link>
      <description>Chandan Sahu, Liton Majumdar, Sudipta Mridha, H. Anantha Krishna, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406603967

                Recent ground- and space-based surveys have shown that planets between Earth and Neptune in size, known as "super-Earths," are among the most frequently found planets in the Galaxy. Although the JWST era has provided high-quality atmospheric data on several such super-Earths, modeling tools are crucial for understanding their unobservable interiors. Consequently, interior studies represent the next essential step in gaining a comprehensive understanding of this class of exoplanets. This study investigates the interior structure, thermal evolution, and atmospheric dynamics of the super-Earth GJ 486b using SERPINT, a 1-D self-consistent coupled interior structure and evolution model, aiming to understand the planet's thermal evolution based on an Earth-like structure. Our results indicate that GJ 486b's core is approximately 1.34 times larger than Earth's, with a core pressure of about 1171 GPa. The thermal evolution model predicts that the planet's mantle cools and solidifies over approximately 0.93 million years. As the magma ocean cools, water is released from the melt, forming a water-rich atmosphere during early solidification. Photolysis of water vapor and subsequent hydrogen escape lead to oxygen accumulation, forming a water- and oxygen-rich secondary atmosphere. Future high-sensitivity JWST observations, with improved wavelength coverage and the detection of additional trace gases, will enable a detailed analysis of the planet's atmospheric composition, providing crucial insights into the interior, surface, and subsurface properties of GJ 486b.</description>
      <author>Chandan Sahu, Liton Majumdar, Sudipta Mridha, H. Anantha Krishna</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.09963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial carbon oxidation in seawater below the hypoxic threshold</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-82438-z</link>
      <description>Sarah Wolf, Clare Jayawickrama, Craig A. Carlson, Curtis Deutsch, Edward W. Davis, Benjamin N. Daniels, Francis Chan, Stephen J. Giovannoni, Scientific Reports. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406695513

                Global oxygen minimum zones (OMZs) often reach hypoxia but seldom reach anoxia. Recently it was reported that Michaelis Menten constants (Km) of oxidative enzymes are orders of magnitude higher than respiratory Km values, and in the Hypoxic Barrier Hypothesis it was proposed that, in ecosystems experiencing falling oxygen, oxygenase enzyme activities become oxygen-limited long before respiration. We conducted a mesocosm experiment with a phytoplankton bloom as an organic carbon source and controlled dissolved oxygen (DO) concentrations in the dark to determine whether hypoxia slows carbon oxidation and oxygen decline. Total oxygen utilization (TOU) in hypoxic treatment (ca. 7.1 &#181;M O2) was 21.7% lower than the oxic treatment (ca. 245.1 &#181;M O2) over the first 43 days of the experiment. In addition, following the restoration of fully oxic conditions to the hypoxic treatment, TOU accelerated, demonstrating that oxidative processes are sensitive to DO concentrations found in large volumes of the ocean. Microbial amplicon-based community composition diverged between oxic treatments, indicating a specialized microbiome that included Thioglobaceae (SUP05 Gammaproteobacteria), OM190 (Planctomycetota), ABY1 (Patescibacteria), and SAR86 subclade D2472, thrived in the hypoxic treatment, while the genus Candidatus Actinomarina and SAR11 alphaproteobacteria were sharply inhibited. Our findings support the hypothesis that oxygenase kinetics might slow the progression of ocean deoxygenation in oxygen-poor regions and be a factor in the evolution of microbial taxa adapted to hypoxic environments.</description>
      <author>Sarah Wolf, Clare Jayawickrama, Craig A. Carlson, Curtis Deutsch, Edward W. Davis, Benjamin N. Daniels, Francis Chan, Stephen J. Giovannoni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-82438-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Densely populated macrocyclic dicobalt sites in ladder polymers for low-overpotential oxygen reduction catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56066-8</link>
      <description>Zhen Zhang, Zhenyu Xing, Xianglin Luo, Chong Cheng, Xikui Liu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406686912

                Dual-atom catalysts featuring synergetic dinuclear active sites, have the potential of breaking the linear scaling relationship of the well-established single-atom catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction; however, the design of dual-atom catalysts with rationalized local microenvironment for high activity and selectivity remains a great challenge. Here we design a bisalphen ladder polymer with well-defined densely populated binuclear cobalt sites on Ketjenblack substrates. The strong electron coupling effect between the fully-conjugated ladder structure and carbon substrates enhances the electron transfer between the cobalt center and oxygen intermediates, inducing the low-to-high spin transition for the 3d electron of Co(II). In situ techniques and theoretical calculations reveal the dynamic evolution of Co2N4O2 active sites and reaction intermediates. In alkaline conditions, the catalyst exhibits impressive oxygen reduction reaction activity featuring an onset potential of 1.10 V and a half-wave potential of 1.00 V, insignificant decay after 30,000 cycles, pushing the overpotential boundaries of ORR electrocatalysis to a low level. This work provides a platform for designing efficient dual-atom catalysts with well-defined coordination and electronic structures in energy conversion technologies. Designing dual-atom catalysts with high activity and selectivity for oxygen reduction reactions is a challenging task. Here, the authors report a bisalphen ladder polymer with densely populated binuclear cobalt sites on Ketjenblack substrates, which improves oxygen reduction performance and stability.</description>
      <author>Zhen Zhang, Zhenyu Xing, Xianglin Luo, Chong Cheng, Xikui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-56066-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aerobic hydrocarbon oxidation in a novel archaeal lineage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5714735/v1</link>
      <description>Andy O Leu, Ben J. Woodcroft, Simon Jon McIlroy, Gene W. Tyson, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406690330

                Abstract Over the last decade, there has been significant advances in our understanding of anaerobic hydrocarbon oxidation in Archaea. While Bacteria are known to oxidise hydrocarbons aerobically, no aerobic hydrocarbon oxidation pathway has been found in Archaea. Here, we report the first aerobic hydrocarbon oxidizing archaeon in a novel order of the Syntropharchaeia. This order is represented by six metagenome-assembled genomes (MAGs) spanning three genera that are found in terrestrial and marine ecosystems. Our analysis revealed that MAGs belonging to one newly defined genus, Candidatus &#8216;Aerovita&#8217;, encode a bacterial copper monooxygenase complex with homology to bacterial hydrocarbon monooxygenases. The presence of other oxygen-dependent enzymes, such as haem-copper oxygen reductase, and the absence of the Wood-Ljungdahl pathway, indicate an aerobic lifestyle for the Ca. &#8216;Aerovita&#8217; lineage. These findings support horizontal gene transfer between archaeal and bacterial domains facilitating the evolution of aerobic hydrocarbon-oxidizing archaea.</description>
      <author>Andy O Leu, Ben J. Woodcroft, Simon Jon McIlroy, Gene W. Tyson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5714735/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Primordial Biochemicals Within Coacervate-Like Droplets and the Origins of Life</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/v17020146</link>
      <description>George B. Stefano, Richard M. Kream, Viruses. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406768670

                An organism is considered &#8220;alive&#8221; if it can grow, reproduce, respond to external stimuli, metabolize nutrients, and maintain stability. By this definition, both mitochondria and viruses exhibit the key characteristics of independent life. In addition to their capacity for self-replication under specifically defined conditions, both mitochondria and viruses can communicate via shared biochemical elements, alter cellular energy metabolism, and adapt to their local environment. To explain this phenomenon, we hypothesize that early viral prototype species evolved from ubiquitous environmental DNA and gained the capacity for self-replication within coacervate-like liquid droplets. The high mutation rates experienced in this environment streamlined their acquisition of standard genetic codes and adaptation to a diverse set of host environments. Similarly, mitochondria, eukaryotic intracellular organelles that generate energy and resolve oxygen toxicity, originally evolved from an infectious bacterial species and maintain their capacity for active functionality within the extracellular space. Thus, while mitochondria contribute profoundly to eukaryotic cellular homeostasis, their capacity for freestanding existence may lead to functional disruptions over time, notably, the overproduction of reactive oxygen species, a phenomenon strongly linked to aging-related disorders. Overall, a more in-depth understanding of the full extent of the evolution of both viruses and mitochondria from primordial precursors may lead to novel insights and therapeutic strategies to address neurodegenerative processes and promote healthy aging.</description>
      <author>George B. Stefano, Richard M. Kream</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/v17020146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparison Study of the Synergistic Influence of Discrepancy in Exothermic Behavior of Polyacrylonitrile&#8208;Based Precursor Fibers and the Continuous Gradient Pre&#8208;Oxidation Condition on Stabilization Structure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/app.56672</link>
      <description>Yong Liu, Peipei Guo, Zongwei Guo, Shengtao Dai, Honglong Li, Lei Shang, Yuhui Ao, Journal of Applied Polymer Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406776935

                ABSTRACT The synergistic influence of discrepancy in exothermic behavior of two types of polyacrylonitrile&#8208;based precursor fibers (labeled as fiber A and B) and the continuous gradient pre&#8208;oxidation conditions on stabilization structure were studied. The evolution and development process of skin&#8208;core structure at different stabilization stages and corresponding influencing factors was clarified. Results showed fiber A had gentle exothermic behavior, smaller exothermic rates, and weaker heat flow, while fiber B had faster exothermic rates and concentrated heat flow, especially at stabilization later stage. Stabilization behaviors revealed that the cyclization index (Ic), oxidation index (Io), dehydrogenation index (Id), aromatization index (AI), X&#8208;ray stabilization index, O elements, and bulk density increased with proceeds of pre&#8208;oxidation. The relationship between the aromatization cross&#8208;linked structure, bulk density, and chemical structure indicated that cyclization, dehydrogenation, and oxidation reactions jointly promoted the formation of aromatization cross&#8208;linked conjugated lamellar structure. Under the same pre&#8208;oxidation conditions, the stabilization degree of fiber B was much higher than that of fiber A. Meanwhile, a more serious inhomogeneous structure appeared at the early stage and further deteriorated at a later stage, which is related to its concentrated exothermic behavior, locally high temperature in the core and nonuniform oxygen distribution in the radial direction. These factors become the internal factors that affect the formation and development of skin&#8208;core structure. By adjusting temperature and gradient distribution as well as shortening time, the skin&#8208;core structure disappeared without compromising the stabilization degree. The formation of the skin&#8208;core structure was controlled by chemical reactions at early stage but by double diffusion and locally high temperature in the core at the later stage. In order to promoted oxygen diffusion, the Ic, Io, and AI values at the initial stage should be controlled below 0.8%, 0.36%, and 32%, respectively. The principles, reasons, and regulatory mechanisms for optimizing the stabilization structure and set proper pre&#8208;oxidation procedures were provided.</description>
      <author>Yong Liu, Peipei Guo, Zongwei Guo, Shengtao Dai, Honglong Li, Lei Shang, Yuhui Ao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/app.56672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling the Solar Transition Region: Effects of Spatial Resolution on
  the Atmospheric Structure, Emission and Non-Equilibrium Ionization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.11237</link>
      <description>Takuma Matsumoto, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406734956

                The solar transition region (TR) is a narrow interface between the chromosphere and corona, where emitted radiation contains critical information pertinent to coronal heating processes. We conducted 2-dimensional radiation magnetohydrodynamics simulations using adaptive mesh refinement to spatially resolve the fine structure of the TR while simultaneously capturing the larger-scale dynamics originating from surface convection. The time evolution of ionization fractions for oxygen ions is computed alongside the simulations. A minimum grid size of 1.25 km is achieved in the TR, enabling adequate resolution of the upper TR (log$_{10}T \gtrsim$ 5), although the lower TR (log$_{10}T \lesssim$ 5) remains under-resolved. Doppler shifts and nonthermal widths synthesized from TR lines exhibit convergence with grid sizes as coarse as 40 km, though some discrepancies persist between our results and observed TR line properties. A notable enhancement in emission from \ion{O}{6} lines, converging at a grid size of 2.5 km, shows an intensity 1.2 times that expected under ionization equilibrium, attributable to shock interactions with the TR. While model refinements are still required, our ability to resolve the TR offers critical insights into TR line characteristics arising from non-equilibrium ionization states, advancing our understanding of the coronal heating problem.</description>
      <author>Takuma Matsumoto</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.11237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photothermal&#8208;Catalyzed Hydrogen Peroxide Production Enabled by Gold&#8208;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420941</link>
      <description>Ping Wu, Fangming Du, Qiang Xue, Hanxi Li, Ming&#8208;Chen Fu, Xukai Zhou, Feng Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406618009

                Abstract Gold catalysts are extensively utilized in photothermal processes that rely on localized surface plasmon resonance effects. However, the development of novel gold(I)&#8208;organic frameworks that function as highly efficient photothermal catalysts for the production of hydrogen peroxide from water and oxygen presents a fascinating and challenging research opportunity. Herein, three gold(I) cyclic trinuclear complexes (Au&#8208;CTCs) based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) are prepared, exhibiting good photothermal conversion efficiency and H 2 O 2 evolution rates. Utilizing the optimized Au&#8208;TFPT, the production rates of H&#8322;O&#8322; can reach as high as 51,987 &#181; m g&#8315;&#185; h&#8315;&#185;, surpassing the performance of most reported metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs), even with the use of sacrificial agents to accelerate the reaction. The thermal&#8208;assisted photocatalytic mechanism is comprehensively studied by transient photocurrent response, electrochemical impedance, electron paramagnetic resonance, rotating ring disk electrode test, catalytic performance and among others, demonstrating thermal energy can enhance the mobility of photogenerated carriers and apparent quantum yield, regulate the reactive species ratio and H 2 O 2 selectivity, reduce the apparent activation energy of photocatalysis, and improve mass transfer rates, thereby accelerating the reaction process. This study offers new insights into the thermal&#8208;assisted photocatalytic production of H 2 O 2 .</description>
      <author>Ping Wu, Fangming Du, Qiang Xue, Hanxi Li, Ming&#8208;Chen Fu, Xukai Zhou, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Local Adaptation in the Exploited Native Marine Mussel Mytilus chilensis: Genomic Evidence from a Reciprocal Transplant Experiment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms26030931</link>
      <description>Marco Y&#233;venes, Gonzalo Gajardo, Cristian Gallardo&#8208;Esc&#225;rate, International Journal of Molecular Sciences. 26(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406761717

                Local adaptations are important in evolution as they drive population divergence and preserve standing genetic diversity essential for resilience under climate change and human impacts. Protecting locally adapted populations is essential for aquaculture species. However, high larval connectivity and frequent translocations challenge this in Chilean blue mussel (Mytilus chilensis) aquaculture, a world-class industry in Chilo&#233; Island. This study examined local adaptations in two ecologically distinct natural beds, Cocham&#243; (northernmost inner sea of Chilo&#233;) and Yaldad (southernmost tip), through a 91-day reciprocal transplant experiment and genomic evidence. Cocham&#243; mussels grew faster in their native environment (0.015 g/day) than Yaldad (0.004 g/day), though growth declined upon transplantation. Mussels transplanted within and between beds displayed distinctive adaptive transcriptomic responses, with differentially expressed genes involved with immune function, osmoregulation, metabolism, and cellular balance. Additionally, 58 known outlier SNPs mapped over the species&#8217; genome sequence were linked with adaptive genes involved with osmoregulation, oxidative stress, and oxygen management, revealing selection-targeted specific genome regions. This study highlights how translocations affect the adaptive genomic response of M. chilensis and the impact of local environments in counterbalancing its genetic connectivity, concluding that the genomic differences in natural beds should be monitored and conserved for sustainable aquaculture practices.</description>
      <author>Marco Y&#233;venes, Gonzalo Gajardo, Cristian Gallardo&#8208;Esc&#225;rate</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms26030931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retina-Inspired Flexible Visual Synaptic Device for Dynamic Image Processing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16378</link>
      <description>Yuhang Ji, Meng Yao, Xueli Geng, Jiacheng Sun, Qin Gao, Hao Yin, Juan Gao, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang, Mei Wang, Zhisong Xiao, Yuyan Wang, Anping Huang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406695418

                Exploiting biomimetic perception of invisible spectra in flexible artificial human vision systems (HVSs) is crucial for real-time dynamic information processing. Nevertheless, the fast processing of motion objects in natural environments poses a challenge, necessitating that these artificial HVSs simultaneously have swift photoresponse and nonvolatile memory. Here, inspired by the human retina, we propose a flexible UV neuromorphic visual synaptic device (NeuVSD) based on GaOx@GaN-composited nanowires for dynamic visual perception. Benefiting from the combined action of oxygen adsorption kinetics on the GaOx shell and photoelectronic excitation in the GaN core, the NeuVSD can achieve rapid photoresponse and long-term plasticity simultaneously, a feature that surpasses traditional devices based on persistent photoconductivity mechanisms. Beyond the optoelectronic synaptic plasticity, the flexible NeuVSD on the PET/PI substrate exhibits good performance stability after 1000 bending cycles, profiting from the high adaptability of nanowires. Furthermore, target recognition and motion detection with weak light intensities are achieved through the establishment of neuromorphic visual neural networks, relying on dynamic exposures and edge information processing, respectively. Real-time edge detection can still be realized under a 40% noise factor and effectively remove the noise background. The flexible NeuVSD array-based artificial visual system can enhance the capability of dynamic visual information processing in low-light and high-noise conditions, thereby fostering the evolution of in-sensor computing and artificial intelligence.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Ji, Meng Yao, Xueli Geng, Jiacheng Sun, Qin Gao, Hao Yin, Juan Gao, Ru&#8208;Zhi Wang, Mei Wang, Zhisong Xiao, Yuyan Wang, Anping Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16378</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MUSE observations of V1425 Aql reveal an arc-shaped nova shell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.09780</link>
      <description>L. Celed&#243;n, C. Tappert, L. Schmidtobreick, F. Selman, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406603723

                Nova shells are the remnants of a nova eruption in a cataclysmic variable system. By studying their geometry we can better understand the physical mechanisms that shape them during the nova eruption. A nova shell that challenges our current understanding of these processes is the shell observed around V1425 Aql. It has at least two different components: an inner and symmetric shell, and an outer and asymmetric shell, with the latter expanding faster than the former. The physical reason behind the asymmetric ejecta is not clear. We aim to characterize the properties and differences between these two components to understand the origin behind the unusual shape. We acquired MUSE data to study the spatial position and kinematics of the expanding gas across the shell. Our analysis includes channel maps, position-velocity diagrams, and the reconstruction of the 3D geometry of the nova shell. Several emission lines are detected within the MUSE wavelength coverage, including but not limited to Balmer, Oxygen, Nitrogen, and Helium lines. There are significant differences in the spectra of the inner and outer shells, with the latter being observed only in forbidden transitions, while the inner shows a mix of forbidden and allowed ones. Our analysis reveals that the outer shell has a geometry consistent with an arc-shaped structure that partially encircles the more spherical inner shell. Within the inner shell, clumpy structures start to be noticeable in the lines of H$\alpha$+[Nii]. We have constrained the geometry of the outer shell to an arc-shaped structure, although the physical reason behind its origin is still eluding us. Further monitoring of the evolution of both shells in this object might help to clarify the mechanism behind this unusual configuration.</description>
      <author>L. Celed&#243;n, C. Tappert, L. Schmidtobreick, F. Selman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.09780</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on Numerical Simulation and Interpretation Method of Water Injection Well Temperature Field Based on DTS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr13010274</link>
      <description>S. Shi, Junfeng Liu, Xiaogang Li, Chao Sun, Lei Tong, Processes. 13(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406628875

                Traditional water injection profile monitoring primarily relies on methods such as isotope tracers and oxygen activation. Conventional resistive temperature instruments, which are drag-measured, are highly sensitive to production interference and can only capture the transient temperature response of the wellbore at a single depth. As a result, the temperature data obtained from well temperature logging has certain limitations. Using DTS (Distributed Temperature Sensing) for pre-and post-well opening and shut-in water injection profile testing, along with quantitative analysis of water absorption, addresses the limitations of traditional well temperature logging, which typically offers only qualitative insights. However, the interpretation of DTS data still requires further refinement to improve its alignment with actual conditions. In this study, COMSOL software 6.1 was used to simulate the temperature distribution within the downhole temperature field, both spatially and temporally. The Sobol method was employed to analyze the influence of fluid flow rate and rock thermal conductivity on the temperature field. The results indicated that the fluid flow rate in the wellbore has a more significant impact and is the primary controlling factor of the downhole temperature field. Based on actual field conditions and the forward simulation results, the differential evolution algorithm was applied to invert and interpret the water injection profile. The inversion results showed minimal error, confirming the feasibility of this approach. It is helpful to interpret the well temperature profile measured by the distributed fiber optic temperature sensor, which is helpful to improve the ability of well temperature logging to identify the output profile, which has important academic value and practical significance for the development of water injection wells.</description>
      <author>S. Shi, Junfeng Liu, Xiaogang Li, Chao Sun, Lei Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr13010274</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition and Mineralogical Features of Ultramafic Rocks of Eastern Part of Southern Kraka Massif (South Urals)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18599/grs.2024.4.9</link>
      <description>D. E. Saveliev, Ainur Biembetov, Timur Denisovich Shabutdinov, Aidar Alfridovich Samigullin, Ruslan Azatovich Gataullin, Georesursy. 26(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406600873

                The paper presents new data on the structure and composition of ultramafic rocks in the eastern part of the South Kraka massif. It is shown that the studied area is composed predominantly of spinel peridotites, among which the main role belongs to lherzolites with a low content of clinopyroxene (2&#8211;5%) and harzburgites, among which lens-shaped and bandshaped inclusions of monomineral olivine rocks &#8211; dunites &#8211; are quite often observed. The leading role in the structure of the rocks belongs to high-Mg olivine (Fo 87-94 ), a secondary role (2016). Nature of the lithospheric mantle beneath the Arabian Shield and genesis of Al-spinel micropods: Evidence from the mantle xenoliths of Harrat is played by high-Mg orthopyroxene (enstatite) and Ca-Mg clinopyroxene diopside. Rare minerals of the mantle stage are amphibole and plagioclase. A typical accessory mineral of ultramafic rocks is spinel, the composition of which varies from high-Al in lherzolites (Cr# = 0.16&#8211;0.3), to moderate-Al in harzburgites (Cr# = 0.3&#8211;0.55) and to high-Cr in dunites (Cr# = 0.6&#8211;0.85). Of the rare accessory minerals in the rocks, the following were identified: native copper, pentlandite, awaruite and PGM (laurite, irarsite, Os-Ir-Ru-alloys). The section of mantle ultramafic rocks of the Sargan Range completed its high-temperature evolution to the levels of the plagioclase peridotite facies, partly in the transition zone from spinel to plagioclase facies. An assessment of oxygen fugacity allows us to speak about more reducing conditions for the formation of rocks of the studied area compared to other similar formations of upper mantle origin and allows us to classify the studied ultramafic rocks as moderately depleted restites of the upper mantle under the riftogenic structure of the Paleo-Ural basin. The geochemical specialization of PGM also indicates a restite origin of ultramafic rocks. At the stage of cooling and tectonic transformations in the crust, ultramafic rocks underwent serpentinization.</description>
      <author>D. E. Saveliev, Ainur Biembetov, Timur Denisovich Shabutdinov, Aidar Alfridovich Samigullin, Ruslan Azatovich Gataullin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18599/grs.2024.4.9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>REBELS-IFU: Evidence for metal-rich massive galaxies at z~6-8</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.10559</link>
      <description>Lucie E. Rowland, Mauro Stefanon, R. J. Bouwens, Jacqueline Hodge, Hiddo Algera, Rebecca Fisher, Pratika Dayal, A. Pallottini, Dan Stark, K. E. Heintz, M. Aravena, R. A. A. Bowler, Karin Cescon, Ryan Endsley, Andrea Ferrara, Valentino Gonz&#225;lez, Luca Graziani, Cindy Gulis, Thomas Herard-Demanche, Hanae Inami, A. Laza-Ramos, Ivana van Leeuwen, I. De Looze, Themiya Nanayakkara, Pascal A. Oesch, Katherine Ormerod, Nina S. Sartorio, Sander Schouws, Renske Smit, Laura Sommovigo, Sune Toft, John R. Weaver, P. van der Werf, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406695599

                Metallicity is a crucial tracer of galaxy evolution, providing insights into gas accretion, star formation, and feedback. At high redshift, these processes reveal how early galaxies assembled and enriched their interstellar medium. In this work, we present rest-frame optical spectroscopy of 12 massive ($\log(M_*/\mathrm{M_{\odot}})&gt;9$) galaxies at $z\sim 6$-$8$ from the REBELS ALMA large program, observed with JWST NIRSpec/IFU in the prism mode. These observations span emission lines from [OII]$\lambda$3727,9 to [SII]$\lambda$6716,31, providing key information on nebular dust attenuation, ionisation states, and chemical abundances. We find lower O32 ratios (average $\sim3.7$) and [OIII]$\lambda$5007 equivalent widths (average ${EW_{[OIII]}}\sim390$\AA) than are generally found in existing large spectroscopic surveys at $z&gt;6$, indicating less extreme ionising conditions. Strong-line diagnostics suggest that these systems are some of the most metal-rich galaxies observed at $z&gt;6$ (average $Z_{\mathrm{gas}}\sim 0.4 Z_{\odot}$), including sources with near-solar oxygen abundances, in line with their high stellar masses (average $\log{M_*/\mathrm{M_{\odot}}}\sim9.5$). Supplementing with literature sources at lower masses, we investigate the mass-metallicity and fundamental metallicity relations (MZR and FMR, respectively) over a 4 dex stellar mass range at $63$ studies.</description>
      <author>Lucie E. Rowland, Mauro Stefanon, R. J. Bouwens, Jacqueline Hodge, Hiddo Algera, Rebecca Fisher, Pratika Dayal, A. Pallottini, Dan Stark, K. E. Heintz, M. Aravena, R. A. A. Bowler, Karin Cescon, Ryan Endsley, Andrea Ferrara, Valentino Gonz&#225;lez, Luca Graziani, Cindy Gulis, Thomas Herard-Demanche, Hanae Inami, A. Laza-Ramos, Ivana van Leeuwen, I. De Looze, Themiya Nanayakkara, Pascal A. Oesch, Katherine Ormerod, Nina S. Sartorio, Sander Schouws, Renske Smit, Laura Sommovigo, Sune Toft, John R. Weaver, P. van der Werf</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.10559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Exercise Capacity in Paediatric Cystic Fibrosis: A Modern Era Perspective</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1183/23120541.00971-2024</link>
      <description>Ren&#233; Gaupmann, Laura St&#246;ger, Klara Schmidthaler, Bianca Pauger, B. Mersi, Alexandra Gr&#225;f, Zsolt Sz&#233;pfalusi, Sabine Renner, Eleonora Dehlink, Saskia Gruber, ERJ Open Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406780472

                Background Maintaining good cardiopulmonary fitness is crucial for global health in Cystic Fibrosis (CF), but there is limited knowledge about the longitudinal evolution of fitness measures at young ages, particularly with recent therapeutic advances. We investigated trends in exercise test outcomes in young people with CF (PwCF) and how they are influenced by elexacaftor/tezacaftor/ivacaftor (ETI) and the COVID-19 pandemic. Methods 70 young PwCF (12 to 20 years) were included in this retrospective observational single-centre study. We reviewed 177 symptom-limited surveillance cardiopulmonary exercise tests (CPET) conducted on a cycle ergometer between 2010 and 2024. Longitudinal trends in peak oxygen uptake (VO 2peak ), maximal workload, and ventilation were analysed using linear mixed models, separately for periods before and after the COVID-19 pandemic onset and ETI introduction. Results In ETI-na&#239;ve PwCF, VO 2peak was lower, and the increase from 12 to 20 years was smaller than predicted by validated reference data (p&lt;0.001). Forty PwCF started ETI during the observational period with 46/103 tests performed under ETI (median therapy duration 1.6 years, range: 0.4&#8211;3.9). After ETI introduction, VO 2peak improved significantly, while ventilation and maximal workload were not relevantly affected. ETI approval coincided with the COVID-19 pandemic, during which a steeper decline of VO 2peak in ETI-na&#239;ve PwCF was observed. However, this potential confounder did not significantly impact the overall longitudinal improvement in VO 2peak trajectory following ETI introduction (p&lt;0.05). Conclusion The longitudinal trend in VO 2peak progression from adolescence to young adulthood is impaired in PwCF, but the initiation of ETI can have a positive impact on this trajectory.</description>
      <author>Ren&#233; Gaupmann, Laura St&#246;ger, Klara Schmidthaler, Bianca Pauger, B. Mersi, Alexandra Gr&#225;f, Zsolt Sz&#233;pfalusi, Sabine Renner, Eleonora Dehlink, Saskia Gruber</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1183/23120541.00971-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A responsabilidade do estado por danos marinhos em atividades governamentais</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.11606/t.2.2023.tde-23082023-154716</link>
      <description>Marcos Soares Cust&#243;dio, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4406627140

                The role of the State in the exercise of typical state activity in the face of international responsibility and sovereignty.The thesis aims to analyze the theme of international responsibility of the State in the exercise of empire activity.In the work, contextualizes the theme, relating it to the new challenges of DIMA and the protection of the marine environment.Discusses the sea and its importance for life, as a source of food and in the production of spare oxygen, in addition to its use for various human activities, especially in the transport of goods, in general, and oil, to demonstrate the importance of this study.It addresses the sea strips.It is a division for legal purposes, behold, the sea, in the general sense, understand the oceans and seas, is unique, thus only having the objective of establishing territoriality, sovereignty and sovereignty rights.This study is important for a better understanding of the attribution of the international responsibility of the State.Briefly, the territorial sea, the contiguous zone, the exclusive economic zone, the continental shelf, the high sea and the Area are analyzed.Several conventions of importance to the DIMA and to the Law of the Sea are analyzed about their implications to the State when using ships in the exercise of governmental activity or warships.As a rule, the various conventions addressed are important in the protective system of the marine environment, but have reservations regarding the application to warships or that are at the service of the State in carrying out typical activity, constituting true immunity to states when exercising empire activity.Among the conventions analyzed, we highlight the OILPOL Convention, 1954; the Convention on Intervention in the High Seas in Cases of Oil Pollution Casualties, 1969; the International Convention on Civil Liability for Oil Pollution Damage, 1969; the SOLAS Convention, 1974, and the ISPS, IMDG, ISM and HSC Codes; the MARPOL 73/78 Convention and theMontego Bay Convention, among others.Issues related to sovereignty and international accountability are addressed: current studies and projects related to the theme.In relation to sovereignty, the objective is to punctuate its evolution to the current times and the change of its nature, no longer seen as an obstacle to the responsability of the State but as an institute to assign responsibilities.At work, we seek to bring several institutes that can assist in the international responsability of the State more effectively or that there is greater commitment to the protective system of the marine environment, such as cooperation; the possible application of proportionality and reasonableness, although they are institutes of internal law focused on the application of principles of constitutional law; emphasis on the principles of prevention and precaution, as mitigating possible responsability; valuing soft law and sources of international law; a reading of the application of human rights from the perspective of environmental protection and the analysis of rhetoric in DIMA.And, finally, the conclusion whether or not there is the international responsibility of the state for the act of empire.The development of the work will have as main approach method the dialectic, in order to identify possible contradictions between conventions and principles of DIMA.Inductive, deductive, hypothetical-deductive and systemic methods will also be used.</description>
      <author>Marcos Soares Cust&#243;dio</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.11606/t.2.2023.tde-23082023-154716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parameter optimization of membrane mlectrode assembly in Fuel Cell based on improved differential evolution algorithm: biomechanical stress and strain considerations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62617/mcb1035</link>
      <description>Ting Lu, Yan Liu, Molecular &amp; cellular biomechanics. 22(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406713223

                The membrane electrode assembly in a proton exchange membrane fuel cell (PEMFC) functions as the electrochemical reaction region, where the generated electric current relies on the diffusion of reactant gases and electron conduction. Drawing inspiration from biomechanics, this study embarked on constructing a database of PEMFC performance data. Similar to how biomechanical studies use advanced imaging and sensing techniques to map the internal workings of organisms, three-dimensional computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations were employed to capture the intricate fluid and gas behaviors within the fuel cell. The data was then used to train data-driven surrogate models based on artificial neural network (ANN) and improved differential evolution for rapid prediction and optimization. When considering the biomechanical aspects, we analyze the mechanical stresses and strains that occur within the membrane electrode assembly during operation. These biomechanical factors can affect the durability and performance of the fuel cell. The gas diffusion layer (GDL) is similar to the pore structure in biological tissues. The pore structure of biological organisms, such as bones, not only ensures the diffusion and transport of nutrients, but also provides space for the attachment of cells to maintain the growth and metabolism of bones. The optimization results revealed that the pores of the GDL, just like the pores of biological tissues, affect the diffusion efficiency of the reactant gases (similar to nutrients) to the catalytic layer, and an appropriate porosity ensures the supply of the reactants required for the electrochemical reactions inside the cell, and improves the PEMFC performance of the cell. By utilizing the random forest algorithm (RF) to conduct feature importance evaluation, we can gain further understanding and interpretation of the factors influencing coupling relationships. The researchers successfully identified the optimal values of GDL porosity and thickness, resulting in an 8.75% increase in power density and significant improvement in oxygen distribution uniformity. To validate the effectiveness and accuracy of the optimization, the optimized structural parameters were incorporated into CFD simulations. The validation results demonstrated close alignment between the optimized model's performance and actual values, confirming the efficacy and reliability of the optimization framework. Overall, this data-driven optimization approach provides an effective tool for multi-variable optimization of complex systems and holds significant importance in enhancing the performance and power density of PEMFC, while also taking into account the biomechanical factors that influence its long-term operation and stability.</description>
      <author>Ting Lu, Yan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62617/mcb1035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>12-Hydroxy-Lauric Acid Tethered Self-Assembled Heterochiral Diphenylalanine-Based Mechanoresponsive and Proteolytically Stable Hydrogel: A Dual Player for Handling Cancer and Bacterial Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01438</link>
      <description>Rishabh Ahuja, Manju Singh, Anita DuttKonar, ACS Applied Bio Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406668429

                Deciphering the most promising strategy for the evolution of cancer patient management remains a multifaceted, challenging affair to date. Additionally, such approaches often lead to microbial infections as side effects, probably due to the compromised immunity of the patients undergoing such treatment. Distinctly, this work delineates a rational combinatorial strategy harnessing stereogenic harmony in the diphenylalanine fragment, tethering it to an amphiphile 12-hydroxy-lauric acid at the N-terminus (compounds I-III) such that a potential therapeutic could be extracted out from the series. Aligned to the goal, the cytotoxic properties and cell viability of the compounds were investigated using two distinct cell lines: MCF-7 (human breast cancer cell) and HEK 293 (human embryonic kidney). Our rigorous investigations revealed that compounds I-III exhibited substantial cytotoxic impact on the MCF7 cell line. But from a pool of three constructs, compound III (12-hydroxy-lauric acid -d-Phe-l-Phe-OH) showed better selectivity toward cancerous MCF7 over normal HEK 293 in comparison to others, backed by computational calculations. Henceforth, it was fished out from the series and used for its elaborate anticancer activities using cell reactive oxygen species generation, DNA fragmentation, and caspase-dependent gene expression employing extrinsic and intrinsic apoptotic factors as well as inflammatory biomarkers, namely, TNF-&#945; and IL1-&#946;. We anticipated that compound III, possessing mechanoresponsiveness and a nanofibrillar network, could be administered in patients with injections because of its shear-thinning properties. Moreover, the optimum partition coefficient of compound III might have allowed the scaffold to penetrate the cellular membranes and form a dilactate complex (compound VI) when exposed to the accumulated lactates/lactic acids, a common phenomenon observed within the hypoxic cancerous tumor cores, in accordance with the Warburg mechanism, thereby evading the cytotoxicity within normal cells. Besides, the supramolecular &#946;-sheets of compound III manifest substantial antimicrobial efficacy against the common pathogens, two Gram-positive bacteria, S. aureus and B. subtilis, two Gram-negative bacteria, E. coli and P. aeruginosa, and a fungus, C. albicans, along with proteolytic stability and high mechanical strength at physiological pH. Overall, we speculate that the discovery of these multifunctional bioinspired materials holds future promise as preferential therapeutics for the remediation of immune-susceptible cancer patients, afflicted by microbial infections arising alone or as side effects of chemotherapeutic medications.</description>
      <author>Rishabh Ahuja, Manju Singh, Anita DuttKonar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c01438</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
