<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 01:04:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Synthesis Strategies for Binary MO2 (M = V, Sn, Ti, Zr, Hf) High-Entropy Oxides as Superior Catalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jeurceramsoc.2024.05.041</link>
      <description>Ziyaad Aytuna, Aman Bhardwaj, Michael Wilhelm, David Patrun, Thomas Fischer, Rajendra Prasad Sharma, Kousik Papakollu, Ravi Kumar, Sanjay Mathur, Journal of the European Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397001259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyaad Aytuna, Aman Bhardwaj, Michael Wilhelm, David Patrun, Thomas Fischer, Rajendra Prasad Sharma, Kousik Papakollu, Ravi Kumar, Sanjay Mathur</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jeurceramsoc.2024.05.041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;b&gt;Electrochemical fabrication of multiple crystalline-amorphous heterogeneous single-atom electrocatalysts for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction&lt;/b&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02457e</link>
      <description>Naiqing Zhang, Pei Pan, Xuewen Xia, Shujuan Wang, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Ji Li, Xin Yu, Xionggang Lu, Xingli Zou, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397003504

                Constructing multiple nanosized heterogeneous structures with in-situ optimized coordination environment for dispersing and stabilizing noble metal single atoms (SAs) is a highly effective strategy for high-efficiency utilization of SAs and...</description>
      <author>Naiqing Zhang, Pei Pan, Xuewen Xia, Shujuan Wang, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Ji Li, Xin Yu, Xionggang Lu, Xingli Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02457e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir-RuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles on WO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Ultrafine Nanowires As Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01516</link>
      <description>Xinyi Li, Zihan Gu, Junfang Cheng, Guozhu Zhang, Fenghua Zheng, Jiao Huang, Jinliang Xu, Guanghua Wei, Junliang Zhang, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397003677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyi Li, Zihan Gu, Junfang Cheng, Guozhu Zhang, Fenghua Zheng, Jiao Huang, Jinliang Xu, Guanghua Wei, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancies enhanced photo-fenton-like catalytic degradation of rhodamine B by electrochemical synthesized &#945;-Fe2O3 nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112563</link>
      <description>Asiyat Magomedova, &#1040;.&#1041;. &#1048;&#1089;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, Farid Orudzhev, Inorganic chemistry communications/Inorganic chemistry communications (Online). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397008714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asiyat Magomedova, &#1040;.&#1041;. &#1048;&#1089;&#1072;&#1077;&#1074;, Farid Orudzhev</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Stability and Activity of Transition Metal Chalcogenides: Development of Carbon-Based Hydrochar Supported Nickel-Cobalt Selenide Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/11301.0003ecst</link>
      <description>Patricia Isabel Soriano, Gio Jerson Almonte, Chris Ivan Sungcang, Joelma Perez, Angelo Earvin Sy Choi, Joseph R. Ortenero, ECS transactions. 113(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397011918

                Transition metal chalcogenides (TMCs) have been utilized as cost-effective alternatives for noble metal electrocatalysts, exhibiting comparable activity in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Nickel-cobalt selenide (NiCoSe) is a TMC exhibiting significant potential in reducing the overpotential of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). A carbon-based hydrochar support is used as a scaffold for depositing NiCoSe, ensuring the dispersion and stability of the synthesized electrocatalyst. This work develops a NiCoSe/hydrochar electrocatalyst to enhance the stability and activity of the TMC towards OER. Various compositions of nickel-cobalt selenide (NiCoSe 2 , Ni 0.85 Co 0.85 Se, and Ni 0.6 Co 0.4 Se 2 ) with a chitin-based hydrochar support are synthesized. The electrocatalytic activity is determined using cyclic voltammetry (CV) and linear sweep voltammetry using a three-electrode set-up. NiCoSe 2 has the lowest overpotential at 179.3 mV and a Tafel slope of 163.4 mV-dec -1 . This highlights the enhanced performance of NiCoSe 2 compared to other compositions.</description>
      <author>Patricia Isabel Soriano, Gio Jerson Almonte, Chris Ivan Sungcang, Joelma Perez, Angelo Earvin Sy Choi, Joseph R. Ortenero</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/11301.0003ecst</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Oxygen Vacancies in La&lt;sub&gt;0.4&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.6&lt;/sub&gt;FeO&lt;sub&gt;3-&#948; &lt;/sub&gt; Perovskite Oxide Nanoparticles for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/11310.0003ecst</link>
      <description>Geletu Qing, Jingyi Chen, ECS transactions. 113(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397011973

                Oxygen vacancies are important factors to tune the performance of oxide catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, it remains challenging how to control the concentration of the oxygen vacancies and decouple their effects on OER from other factors. In this work, we use a specific composition/phase La 0.4 Sr 0.6 FeO 3- d perovskite oxide as an example to tailor the oxygen vacancies of their nanoparticulate using a modified molten salt synthesis and ozone treatment. The OER performance of the resulting La 0.4 Sr 0.6 FeO 3- d nanoparticles with different degree of oxygen vacancies ranging from 0 to 25% are compared. The OER reactivity increases with increased oxygen vacancies in the materials, but the change is nonlinear. The OER stability, on the other hand, has a bimodal distribution. The activities of fully oxidized sample and the most oxygen-deficient sample degrade slower than the two samples in the middle. The results suggest that it is feasible to design catalysts with oxygen vacancy to be the most OER active and stable. Further investigation into the oxygen vacancy &#8211; active site relation would offer guiding principle to design and synthesize high OER performance oxide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Geletu Qing, Jingyi Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/11310.0003ecst</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysts Achieved by Axial Ligands Modulation on Two-Dimensional Porphyrin Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01235f</link>
      <description>Tianze Xu, Tianyang Liu, Yu Jing, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397014217

                Exploring efficient and low-cost oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions (ORR/OER) bifunctional catalysts is essential for the development of energy storage and conversion devices. Herein, enlightened by the experimentally synthesized...</description>
      <author>Tianze Xu, Tianyang Liu, Yu Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01235f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous hetero-structure iron/cobalt oxyhydroxide with atomic dispersed palladium for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124213</link>
      <description>Shuai Yang, Lu Lu, Peng Zhan, Zhihao Si, Leyi Chen, Yan Zhou, Peiyong Qin, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397024091

                The activity of iron oxyhydroxides (FeOOH) in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is limited by its poor conductivity and the high energy barrier in the rate-determining step. Herein, we report the immobilization of atomic dispersed Pd species on Co doped FeOOH, realizing the preparation of amorphous hetero-structure FeCoaOOH-Pdb. In the case of Co/Fe of 0.68 and Pd/Fe of 0.026, the coexisting structure of nanorods and nanospheres with appropriate oxygen vacancies and unsaturated active centers increases the number of active sites and enhances the intrinsic activity of the electrocatalyst. The density functional theory results uncover that the FeCo0.68OOH-Pd0.026 optimizes the binding energies of &#8270;O and &#8270;OOH, and accelerates the OER kinetics. The rationally designed FeCo0.68OOH-Pd0.026 exhibits excellent OER activity and reliability, manifesting a Tafel slope of 37.5 mV dec-1, a low overpotential of 265.1 mV at 10 mA cm-2, which has the potential to realize the large-scale implementation of water splitting.</description>
      <author>Shuai Yang, Lu Lu, Peng Zhan, Zhihao Si, Leyi Chen, Yan Zhou, Peiyong Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steric interaction of iridium sites towards efficient oxygen and hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152338</link>
      <description>Weibin Chen, Lei Li, Zhan Lin, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397024211

                Transition metal materials that loaded with trace of Iridium (Ir) are widely accepted as effective catalysts for oxygen evolution (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), in which the Ir atoms exposed on the surface can directly affect the electrocatalytic reaction. However, this neglects the Ir &#8211; Ir interaction of distinct locations, which may be benefit for the fine-tuning of electronic structure. Herein, we changed the locations (surface and inside) of Ir atoms in the cobalt oxide (Co3O4@NC), and investigated their alkaline OER and HER performances. Combined with X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and theoretical calculations, we infer that the steric interactions induced by the surface &#8211; internal Ir sites can weaken the Ir-O bond and optimize the adsorption of intermediates on catalyst surface with a negative shift of d-band center, enabling the surface-Ir sites with lower energy barrier for water dissociation and hydrogen adsorption for HER. Therefore, the as-prepared Irw-Co3O4@NC with surface &#8722; inside Ir distributions significantly improve the HER without degrading OER performance, with low overpotential of &#8722;173 / &#8722;71 mV for HER at &#8722;10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 in 0.1 M KOH / 1.0 M KOH, and 244 / 249 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 for OER.</description>
      <author>Weibin Chen, Lei Li, Zhan Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Novel Homological Approach for the Comprehensive Study of Nonstoichiometric Oxide with Exceptional Oxygen Mobility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4832906</link>
      <description>Marko I. Gongola, Rostislav Guskov, I. V. Kovalev, &#1052;. &#1055;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074;, A. P. Nemudry, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397028690

                Actual work devoted to the development of a homological approach for describing the kinetic properties of grossly nonstoichiometric oxides ABO3-&#948; with perovskite structure. The approach consists in considering such oxides having different oxygen stoichiometry 3-&#948; as chemical homologues involved in the same oxygen exchange reaction and forming a continuous series in &#948;. The proposed approach is considered using the oxide with exceptional oxygen mobility Ba0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3-&#948; (BSCF). The kinetic properties of BSCF were studied by new method of the oxygen partial pressure relaxation. The equilibrium properties of BSCF were reported earlier and obtained by original technique of the quasi-equilibrium oxygen release. The power law dependence of the kinetic parameters on the equilibrium oxygen partial pressure is considered as the consequence of linear free energy relationship similar to the Br&#248;nsted-Evans-Polanyi relation.</description>
      <author>Marko I. Gongola, Rostislav Guskov, I. V. Kovalev, &#1052;. &#1055;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074;, A. P. Nemudry</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4832906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy FeCoNiCuAlV sulfide as an efficient and reliable electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.186</link>
      <description>Yao Zhao, Jingbi You, Zhaoyu Wang, Guangyi Liu, Xiaojuan Huang, Mingyi Duan, Hangzhou Zhang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 70(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397030595

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yao Zhao, Jingbi You, Zhaoyu Wang, Guangyi Liu, Xiaojuan Huang, Mingyi Duan, Hangzhou Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Mn loaded FeCo-MOF and its composites with reduced graphene oxide as highly efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution and reduction reactions in metal-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.228</link>
      <description>Muhammad Mudassar Aslam, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Erum Pervaiz, Naseem Iqbal, Neelam Zaman, International journal of hydrogen energy. 70(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397031020

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Mudassar Aslam, Tayyaba N&#1086;&#1086;r, Erum Pervaiz, Naseem Iqbal, Neelam Zaman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni Nanoparticles Embedded in Multi-Channel Carbon Nanofibers: Self-Supporting Electrodes for Bifunctional Catalysis of Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174894</link>
      <description>Yaozu Liao, Tengteng Kang, Fanghuang Liu, Sicheng Zhou, Xinjuan Liu, Shuling Shen, Zhihong Tang, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397031624

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yaozu Liao, Tengteng Kang, Fanghuang Liu, Sicheng Zhou, Xinjuan Liu, Shuling Shen, Zhihong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Incorporation of Ag in Co9S8&#8208;Ni3S2 for Predominantly Enhanced Electrocatalytic Activities for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: A Combined Experimental and DFT Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400235</link>
      <description>Tsegaye Tadesse Tsega, Yuchi Zhang, Jiantao Zai, Foo Wah Low, Xuefeng Qian, ChemPlusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397042836

                Electrodeposition of abundant metals to fabricate efficient and durable electrodes play a viable role in advancing renewable electrochemical energy technologies. Herein, we deposit Co9S8&#8208;Ag&#8208;Ni3S2@NF onto nickel foam (NF) to form Co9S8&#8208;Ag&#8208;Ni3S2@NF as a highly efficient electrode for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The electrochemical investigation verifies that the Co9S8&#8208;Ag&#8208;Ni3S2@NF electrode exhibits superior electrocatalytic activity toward OER because of its nanoflowers' open&#8208;pore morphology, reduced overpotential (&#951;10 = 125 mV), smaller charge transfer resistance, long&#8208;term stability, and a synergistic effect between various components, which allows the reactants to be more easily absorbed and subsequently converted into gaseous products during the water electrolysis process. DFT calculation also reveals that the introduction of Ag (222) surface into the Co9S8 (440)&#8208;Ni3S2 (120) system increases the electronic density of states per unit cell of a system and significantly reduces the energy barriers of intermediates for OER, leading to enhanced electrocatalytic activity for OER. This study showcases the innovation of employing trimetallic nanomaterials immobilized on a conductive, continuous porous three&#8208;dimensional network formed on a nickel foam (NF) substrate as a highly efficient catalyst for OER.</description>
      <author>Tsegaye Tadesse Tsega, Yuchi Zhang, Jiantao Zai, Foo Wah Low, Xuefeng Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directional movement of electron induced by interfacial coupling in CuS@NiCo-LDHs for efficient alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160311</link>
      <description>Li Liu, Jing Mo, Jun Xu, Yangxi Liu, Ruoxi Yang, Xiaohui Yang, Xinguo Ma, Fu Wensheng, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397043610

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Liu, Jing Mo, Jun Xu, Yangxi Liu, Ruoxi Yang, Xiaohui Yang, Xinguo Ma, Fu Wensheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160311</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guanine-derived core-shell FeCo alloy confined in graphene-like N-doped carbon as efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174805</link>
      <description>Lin X, Longji Cui, Xueda Ding, Yiquan Chen, Qianyu Wei, Biao Huang, Zailai Xie, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397048603

                Maximization the synergistic effect of each component in transition metal-carbon complexes is expected to improve the bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis for rechargeable Zn-air batteries but is still challenging. Herein, nucleobase guanine is employed as a supramolecular precursor to generate the core (FeCo alloy)-shell (carbon) structure embedded in ultrathin graphene-like nitrogen-doped carbon nanosheets (FeCo@NCNSs) via a confinement pyrolysis strategy. Thanks to the generated core-shell structure and bimetallic synergistic effect, the as-prepared FeCo@NCNSs exhibits excellent electrochemical performance in both oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. As a result, when served as the bifunctional air electrode for a practical Zn-air battery, FeCo@NCNSs exhibits a higher open-circuit voltage (1.553 V) and peak power density (197.30 mW cm-2), as well as the greatly improved long-term cyclic stability compared to the noble metal benchmarks. This work provides a promising approach to integrate various active sites for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis and inspires the exploration of simple but efficient electrocatalysts for energy storage and conversion.</description>
      <author>Lin X, Longji Cui, Xueda Ding, Yiquan Chen, Qianyu Wei, Biao Huang, Zailai Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post-treatment induced anisotropic growth of MOF-derived surface modified heterogeneous catalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.119</link>
      <description>Yujin Cho, Komal Patil, Seyeon Cho, Mahendra R. Jadhav, Jin-Cheol Kim, Jihun Kim, Jongsung Park, International journal of hydrogen energy. 70(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397050258

                The advancement of electrocatalysts exhibiting outstanding performance in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), crucial for hydrogen production, holds immense significance in addressing energy shortages and mitigating environmental pollution. In this study, a novel approach to synthesizing Co-MOF (Metal-Organic Framework) directly immobilized onto a Ni foam substrate through hydrothermal synthesis is presented. In contrast to conventional methods employing powder-based synthesis with binders, our direct attachment method offers a unique and efficient means of creating robust Co-MOF at Ni foam (Co-MOF@NF) hybrid catalysts. Subsequently, a chemical reduction approach utilizing sodium borohydride was employed to introduce surface modification into the Co-MOF structure. The resulting material, sodium borohydride treated Co-MOF@NF (Red. 1 h Co-MOF@NF), exhibited a remarkable enhancement in OER activity compared to the pristine Co-MOF@NF sample. Notably, Red.1 h Co-MOF@NF demonstrated a substantially reduced overpotential of 235 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315;2, in contrast to the 300 mV overpotential required by the pristine Co-MOF@NF under the same conditions. Furthermore, the Red.1 h Co-MOF@NF catalyst displayed exceptional stability, sustaining a current density of 50 mA cm&#8315;2 for over 48 h, highlighting its promising potential for practical applications. The synergistic effects of direct hydrothermal attachment, surface modification, and improved OER performance make this study a significant contribution to the advancement of efficient and stable electrocatalysts for energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Yujin Cho, Komal Patil, Seyeon Cho, Mahendra R. Jadhav, Jin-Cheol Kim, Jihun Kim, Jongsung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabricating highly-active Ni3+ sites of spinel to enhance electrocatalysis oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.187</link>
      <description>Fangping Wang, Changliang Shan, Yuee Zhao, H.M. Yang, Yongfeng Zhang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397289971

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) suffers a complex four-electron process with sluggish kinetics, which severely hinders its practical application. In general, Ni-based spinel-structured materials have emerged as potential electrocatalysts for OER. However, fabricating surface with high efficient Ni3+ active sites for Ni-based spinel is thermodynamically unfavorable, which impedes the future development and application of Ni-based spinel. In this study, we have formulated a octahedral (Oh) sites doping route for the synthesis of a Ni3+-riched Ni(Co1.98Ni0.02)O4. The results demonstrate that the catalyst with high density of surface Ni3+ active sites exhibits an improved OER catalytic activity compared with NiCo2O4 and requires a low overpotential of 349 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Fangping Wang, Changliang Shan, Yuee Zhao, H.M. Yang, Yongfeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Azo chromophore functionalized polyesters; Synthesis, characterizations and applications for efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction and heavy metal ion detection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.138681</link>
      <description>Sumbal Jahan Ara, Kalsoom Fatima, Samina Qamar, Zareen Akhter, Journal of molecular structure. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397290640

                The current study focuses on the synthesis, characterization and investigation of the potential applications of azo chromophore functionalized polyesters and their composites with graphene derivatives. Employing the two-step diazotization coupling reaction, diazo diol monomers are synthesized. Subsequently, the azo polyesters are prepared via low-temperature solution polycondensation of the diazo diols with diacid chloride followed by the incorporation of graphene derivatives to obtain composite materials. Characterization techniques including Fourier transform Infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR), X-ray diffraction (XRD), Ultraviolet-Visible Diffuse reflectance spectroscopy (UV-Vis DRS) and Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) are employed to evaluate the chain structure, degree of crystallinity, optical properties and morphology. Further, their electrocatalytic activity towards the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and detection ability toward heavy metal ion was evaluated. The results demonstrate enhanced catalytic and detection capabilities attributed to synergistic interactions between polymer and graphene components. This study provides significant insights into the development of efficient polymer-graphene hybrid materials, with potential applications in green chemistry and environmental monitoring.</description>
      <author>Sumbal Jahan Ara, Kalsoom Fatima, Samina Qamar, Zareen Akhter</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molstruc.2024.138681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilization of MOF-derived Co3S4 nanoparticles via graphdiyne coating for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2956-9</link>
      <description>Mengyu Lu, Xin Zhao, Shifu Zhang, Hengxin Jian, Mei Wang, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Science China. Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398137601

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyu Lu, Xin Zhao, Shifu Zhang, Hengxin Jian, Mei Wang, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-2956-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrO2 Oxygen Evolution Catalysts Prepared by an Optimized Photodeposition Process on TiO2 Substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29102392</link>
      <description>Angeliki Banti, Christina Zafeiridou, Michail Charalampakis, Olga-Niki Spyridou, J. Georgieva, Vassili&#959;s Binas, Efrosyni Mitrousi, S. Sotiropoulos, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398140623

                Preparing high-performance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts with low precious metal loadings for water electrolysis applications (e.g., for green hydrogen production) is challenging and requires electrically conductive, high-surface-area, and stable support materials. Combining the properties of stable TiO2 with those of active iridium oxide, we synthesized highly active electrodes for OER in acidic media. TiO2 powders (both commercially available Degussa P-25&#174; and hydrothermally prepared in the laboratory from TiOSO4, either as received/prepared or following ammonolysis to be converted to titania black), were decorated with IrO2 by UV photodeposition from Ir(III) aqueous solutions of varied methanol scavenger concentrations. TEM, EDS, FESEM, XPS, and XRD measurements demonstrate that the optimized version of the photodeposition preparation method (i.e., with no added methanol) leads to direct deposition of well-dispersed IrO2 nanoparticles. The electroactive surface area and electrocatalytic performance towards OER of these catalysts have been evaluated by cyclic voltammetry (CV), Linear Sweep Voltammetry (LSV), and Electrochemical Impedance Spectroscopy (EIS) in 0.1 M HClO4 solutions. All TiO2-based catalysts exhibited better mass-specific (as well as intrinsic) OER activity than commercial unsupported IrO2, with the best of them (IrO2 on Degussa P-25&#174; &#932;iO2 and laboratory-made TiO2 black) showing 100 mAmgIr&#8722;1 at an overpotential of &#951; = 243 mV. Chronoamperometry (CA) experiments also proved good medium-term stability of the optimum IrO2/TiO2 electrodes during OER.</description>
      <author>Angeliki Banti, Christina Zafeiridou, Michail Charalampakis, Olga-Niki Spyridou, J. Georgieva, Vassili&#959;s Binas, Efrosyni Mitrousi, S. Sotiropoulos</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29102392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Urea-Assisted Natural Seawater Electrolysis in 3D Leaf-Like Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Nanosheet Arrays Using Metal Node Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04342</link>
      <description>Ngoc Quang Tran, Quang Minh Le, Trung Dinh Tran, Thuy&#8208;Kieu Truong, Jihong Yu, Lishan Peng, Thi Anh Le, T&#226;n L&#234; Ho&#224;ng &#272;o&#224;n, Bach Thang Phan, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398141676

                Metal node engineering, which can optimize the electronic structure and modulate the composition of poor electrically conductive metal&#8211;organic frameworks, is of great interest for electrochemical natural seawater splitting. However, the mechanism underlying the influence of mixed-metal nodes on electrocatalytic activities is still ambiguous. Herein, a strategic design is comprehensively demonstrated in which mixed Ni and Co metal redox-active centers are uniformly distributed within NH2&#8211;Fe-MIL-101 to obtain a synergistic effect for the overall enhancement of electrocatalytic activities. Three-dimensional mixed metallic MOF nanosheet arrays, consisting of three different metal nodes, were in situ grown on Ni foam as a highly active and stable bifunctional catalyst for urea-assisted natural seawater splitting. A well-defined NH2&#8211;NiCoFe-MIL-101 reaches 1.5 A cm&#8211;2 at 360 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and 0.6 A cm&#8211;2 at 295 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in freshwater, substantially higher than its bimetallic and monometallic counterparts. Moreover, the bifunctional NH2&#8211;NiCoFe-MIL-101 electrode exhibits eminent catalytic activity and stability in natural seawater-based electrolytes. Impressively, the two-electrode urea-assisted alkaline natural seawater electrolysis cell based on NH2&#8211;NiCoFe-MIL-101 needs only 1.56 mV to yield 100 mA cm&#8211;2, much lower than 1.78 V for alkaline natural seawater electrolysis cells and exhibits superior long-term stability at a current density of 80 mA cm&#8211;2 for 80 h.</description>
      <author>Ngoc Quang Tran, Quang Minh Le, Trung Dinh Tran, Thuy&#8208;Kieu Truong, Jihong Yu, Lishan Peng, Thi Anh Le, T&#226;n L&#234; Ho&#224;ng &#272;o&#224;n, Bach Thang Phan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration of TiO2/ZnIn2S4 p&#8208;n Heterojunction with Titanium Defects to Boost PEC Oxygen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400485</link>
      <description>Haipeng Wang, Guang&#8208;Ling Song, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398145326

                TiO2 is a widely used photoelectric conversion semiconductor material. However, due to its selective absorption of ultraviolet light and high recombination rate of photogenerated carriers, it exhibits poor photoelectrochemical water splitting performance. In this study, intrinsic defect titanium vacancy and semiconductor recombination agents ZnIn2S4 were introduced into an anodization&#8208;annealed TiO2 film (TiO2 NT) to enhance the photoanode activity. The activity&#8208;enhanced TiO2 photoanode (ZIS@TiO2 NT&#8208;EA) was characterized by surface analyses and photoelectrochemical measurements. The results indicated that the introduction of titanium vacancies into the TiO2 NT&#8208;EA changed its semiconductor type from n to p. After the ZnIn2S4 nanoparticles were loaded on the TiO2 NT&#8208;EA film, the carrier concentration of the ZIS@TiO2 NT&#8208;EA increased nearly 12 times than the pristine TiO2 NT. Due to the higher carrier separation efficiency resulting from the formation of p&#8208;n heterojunction, the photocurrent density of the ZIS@TiO2 NT&#8208;EA reached 3.89 mA cm&#8208;2 at 1.23 V vs. RHE, nearly 3 times higher than that of the original TiO2 NT. The maximum applied bias photon&#8208;to&#8208;current efficiency (ABPE) value of the ZIS@TiO2 NT EA reached 2.15% at 0.496 V vs. RHE, which is very competitive if compared with all the reported TiO2 film electrodes in the PEC water splitting application.</description>
      <author>Haipeng Wang, Guang&#8208;Ling Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin Crossover and Exchange Effects on Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyzed by Bimetallic Metal Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01091</link>
      <description>Guangsheng Liu, Fajun Xie, Xu Cai, Jingyun Ye, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398145641

                Bimetallic metal&#8211;organic frameworks (BMOFs) have shown a superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, attributed to the synergistic effects of dual metal sites. However, the significant role of these dual-metal synergies in the OER is not yet fully understood. In this study, we employed density functional theory to systematically investigate the OER performance of NiAl- and NiFe-based BMOFs by examining all possible spin states of each intermediate across diverse external potentials and pH environments. We found that the spin state featuring a shallow hole trap state and Ni ions with a higher oxidation state serve as strong oxidizing agents, promoting the OER. An external potential-induced spin crossover was observed in each intermediate, resulting in significant changes in the overall reaction and activation energies due to altered energy levels. Combining the constant potential method and the electrochemical nudged elastic band method, we mapped the minimum free energy barriers of the OER under varied external potential and pH by considering the spin crossover effect for both NiAl and NiFe BMOFs. The results showed that NiFe exhibits better OER thermodynamics and kinetics, which is in good agreement with experimentally measured OER polarization curves and Tafel plots. Moreover, we found that the improved OER kinetics of NiFe not only is attributed to lower barriers but also is a result of improved electrical conductivity arising from the synergistic effects of Ni&#8211;Fe dual-metal sites. Specifically, replacing the second metal Al with Fe leads to two significant outcomes: a reduction in both the band gap and the effective hole mass compared to NiAl, and the initiation of super- and double-exchange interactions within the Ni&#8211;F&#8211;Fe chain, thereby enhancing electron transfer and hopping and leading to the improved OER kinetics.</description>
      <author>Guangsheng Liu, Fajun Xie, Xu Cai, Jingyun Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving of the electrochemical performance of Acacia wood porous carbon/MnO2 nanocomposite as an advanced electrode for supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144459</link>
      <description>Hamouda Adam Hamouda, Anas Ramadan, Lachaacirc l Mokhtar, Suad Atitalla Ageeb, Magdy A. M. Ibrahim, Abir EM Ajab, Mohammed Bahreldin Hussein, Adriana Farah, Elfatih A. Hassan, Guofu Ma, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398146096

                Effective energy storage has now become increasingly critical as global energy demand has skyrocketed. Asymmetric supercapacitors using electrodes made of acacia wood-derived carbon doped with MnO2. A hydrothermal process was used to synthesize the AWPC/MnO2 composite. Techniques such as XRD, SEM, TEM, XPS, FTIR spectra, Ramman spectra, and N2 adsorption-desorption isotherms. We looked at the electrochemical properties of the materials we made in an electrolyte using cyclic voltammetry (CV), galvanostatic charge-discharge (GCD), and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). A hydrothermal synthesis approach is used to graft MnO2 wire-like nanostructures onto acacia wood-derived activated carbon. Good electrochemical performance is shown by the carbon/MnO2 hybrid composite electrode, which has high specific capacitances of 301 F g&#8722;1 at 500 mA s&#8722;1, low Tafel slope of 54 mV dec&#8722;1, which is attributed to the synergistic influences between MnO2 and waste biomass-produced carbon. Moreover, an asymmetric supercapacitor operating in the voltage range of 1.8 V and exhibiting a high energy density of 25 Wh kg&#8722;1 at a power density of 450 W kg&#8722;1 demonstrates the significant potential of the activated carbon/MnO2 composite generated from synthesized biomass. The AWPC/MnO2's oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity was checked to see how well the improved nanostructure could be used. The results offer a fresh perspective on the fabrication of electrochemical energy storage devices with outstanding performance.</description>
      <author>Hamouda Adam Hamouda, Anas Ramadan, Lachaacirc l Mokhtar, Suad Atitalla Ageeb, Magdy A. M. Ibrahim, Abir EM Ajab, Mohammed Bahreldin Hussein, Adriana Farah, Elfatih A. Hassan, Guofu Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144459</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supporting catalyst beat powder electrode for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction: cobalt-based catalyst as an example</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01627k</link>
      <description>He Zhao, Xiaoqiang Du, Xiaoshuang Zhang, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398150114

                The residuals have got little attention during the preparation process of the catalysts without binder by hydrothermal method. Employing Ni foam supported Co3O4 and CuCo2O4 materials for water oxidation reaction...</description>
      <author>He Zhao, Xiaoqiang Du, Xiaoshuang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01627k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stepwise Understanding on Hydrolysis Formation of the IrOx Nanoparticles as Highly Active Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00874-x</link>
      <description>Swapnil S. Karade, Raghunandan Sharma, Martin A.B. Hedegaard, Shuang Ma Andersen, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398156454

                Abstract In this study, we have investigated the synthesis of supported iridium oxide (IrO x ) nanoparticles (NPs) through hydrolysis in a surfactant-free aqueous bath as a possible route for the large-scale production of highly active electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic water electrolyzers. The process involves (i) formation of Ir-hydroxides complex from an Ir precursor in basic media followed by (ii) protonation in acidic media to form colloidal hydrated IrO x NPs and (iii) conversion and deposition of IrO x NPs on the surface of carbon or TiN support by probe sonication. The IrO x NPs produced through hydrolysis route form highly stable colloidal solution. Since it is essential to precipitate the catalyst NPs from the colloidal solution for their use in water electrolyzer electrode development, here, we investigate the optimal reaction conditions, e.g., pH, temperature, time, and presence of support, for efficient synthesis of the catalyst NPs. The reaction intermediates formed at different reaction steps are explored to get insights into the chemistry of the process. Under the optimal synthesis conditions, 100% precipitation of IrO x NPs was achieved. Further, the precipitated TiN supported IrO x NPs exhibited high OER activity, superior to that of the commercial benchmark IrO 2 electrocatalyst. The study provides a scalable synthesis route for highly active, low Ir-content OER electrocatalysts for acidic water electrolyzers. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Swapnil S. Karade, Raghunandan Sharma, Martin A.B. Hedegaard, Shuang Ma Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00874-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-generated oxygen radical species accelerate the alkaline oxygen-evolving reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.309</link>
      <description>Zhiqiang Hou, Shizhuan Zou, Xiaohui Fan, Xinru Li, Ying Wei, Peng Zhao, Faming Gao, Ke&#8208;Jing Huang, Qinfeng Rong, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398158878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiqiang Hou, Shizhuan Zou, Xiaohui Fan, Xinru Li, Ying Wei, Peng Zhao, Faming Gao, Ke&#8208;Jing Huang, Qinfeng Rong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accurately Modulating Binuclear Metal Nodes of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01254</link>
      <description>Huiling Huang, Lei Lei, Xin He, Jiaojiao Xin, Jin Huang, Zhong Zhang, Fu&#8208;Ping Huang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398160086

                The accurate manipulation of the species and locations of catalytic centers is crucial for regulating the catalytic activity of catalysts, which is essential for their efficient design and development. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) with coordinated metal sites are ideal materials for investigating the origin of catalytic activity. In this study, we present a Ni</description>
      <author>Huiling Huang, Lei Lei, Xin He, Jiaojiao Xin, Jin Huang, Zhong Zhang, Fu&#8208;Ping Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;Organic Skeleton-Derived P-CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@CN Nanoparticles Embedded with Nitrogen-Doped Carbon as Effective Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01518</link>
      <description>Huichun Kang, Bitao Su, Ziqiang Lei, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398160349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huichun Kang, Bitao Su, Ziqiang Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c01518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sonication-Induced Boladipeptide-Based Metallogel as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c18637</link>
      <description>Lalita Wagh, Devraj Singh, Vikash Kumar, Shrish Nath Upadhyay, Srimanta Pakhira, Apurba K. Das, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398161457

                Bioinspired, self-assembled hybrid materials show great potential in the field of energy conversion. Here, we have prepared a sonication-induced boladipeptide (HO-YF-AA-FY-OH (PBFY); AA = Adipic acid, F = l-phenylalanine, and Y = l-tyrosine) and an anchored, self-assembled nickel-based coordinated polymeric nanohybrid hydrogel (Ni-PBFY). The morphological studies of hydrogels PBFY and Ni-PBFY exhibit nanofibrillar network structures. XPS analysis has been used to study the self-assembled coordinated polymeric hydrogel Ni-PBFY-3, with the aim of identifying its chemical makeup and electronic state. XANES and EXAFS analyses have been used to examine the local electronic structure and coordination environment of Ni-PBFY-3. The xerogel of Ni-PBFY was used to fabricate the electrodes and is utilized in the OER (oxygen evolution reaction). The native hydrogel (PBFY) contains a gelator boladipeptide of 15.33 mg (20 mmol L</description>
      <author>Lalita Wagh, Devraj Singh, Vikash Kumar, Shrish Nath Upadhyay, Srimanta Pakhira, Apurba K. Das</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c18637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic modulation of the d-band center in Ni3S2 by selenium and iron for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.155</link>
      <description>Xu Song, Dongxu Jiao, Xiaowen Ruan, Zhaoyong Jin, Yu Qiu, Jinchang Fan, Lei Zhang, Weitao Zheng, Xiaoqiang Cui, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398164983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xu Song, Dongxu Jiao, Xiaowen Ruan, Zhaoyong Jin, Yu Qiu, Jinchang Fan, Lei Zhang, Weitao Zheng, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Surface Confinement of FeO Assists in the Generation of Singlet Oxygen and High&#8208;Valent Metal&#8208;Oxo Species for Enhanced Fenton&#8208;Like Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401970</link>
      <description>Guangfu Wang, Danlian Huang, Min Cheng, Lei Du, Sha Chen, Wei Zhou, Ruijin Li, Sai Li, Hai Huang, Wenbo Xu, Lin Tang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398169312

                Transition metal compounds (TMCs) have long been potential candidate catalysts in persulfate-based advanced oxidation process (PS-AOPs) due to their Fenton-like catalyze ability for radical generation. However, the mechanism involved in TMCs-catalyzed nonradical PS-AOPs remains obscure. Herein, the growth of FeO on the Fe</description>
      <author>Guangfu Wang, Danlian Huang, Min Cheng, Lei Du, Sha Chen, Wei Zhou, Ruijin Li, Sai Li, Hai Huang, Wenbo Xu, Lin Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401970</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly electrocatalytic activity of NixFey nanoporous for oxygen evolution reaction in water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.218</link>
      <description>Enkhjin Chuluunbat, Anh Ng&#7885;c Nguy&#7877;n, Oleksii Omelianovych, &#193;d&#225;m Sz&#225;niel, Liudmila L. Larina, Ho&#8208;Suk Choi, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398169891

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enkhjin Chuluunbat, Anh Ng&#7885;c Nguy&#7877;n, Oleksii Omelianovych, &#193;d&#225;m Sz&#225;niel, Liudmila L. Larina, Ho&#8208;Suk Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel High-Entropy FeCoNiMoZn-Layered Hydroxide as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14100889</link>
      <description>Zhihao Cheng, Xin Han, Liang Han, Jinfeng Zhang, Jie Liu, Zhong Wu, Cheng Zhong, Nanomaterials. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398170110

                The exploration of catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with high activity and acceptable price is essential for water splitting to hydrogen generation. High-entropy materials (HEMs) have aroused increasing interest in the field of electrocatalysis due to their unusual physicochemical properties. In this work, we reported a novel FeCoNiMoZn-OH high entropy hydroxide (HEH)/nickel foam (NF) synthesized by a facile pulsed electrochemical deposition method at room temperature. The FeCoNiMoZn-OH HEH displays a 3D porous nanosheet morphology and polycrystalline structure, which exhibits extraordinary OER activity in alkaline media, including much lower overpotential (248 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2) and Tafel slope (30 mV dec&#8722;1). Furthermore, FeCoNiMoZn-OH HEH demonstrates excellent OER catalytic stability. The enhanced catalytic performance of the FeCoNiMoZn-OH HEH primarily contributed to the porous morphology and the positive synergistic effect between Mo and Zn. This work provides a novel insight into the design of HEMs in catalytic application.</description>
      <author>Zhihao Cheng, Xin Han, Liang Han, Jinfeng Zhang, Jie Liu, Zhong Wu, Cheng Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14100889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafine Ir nanoparticles anchored on carbon nanotubles as efficient bifunctional oxygen catalysts for Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01465k</link>
      <description>J. Wang, Meiyan Ni, Jinjie Qian, Yifei Ge, C. Dong, Huagui Nie, Xuemei Zhou, Zhi Yang, Chemical communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398175924

                Ultrafine iridium particles anchored nitrogen-doped CNTs electrocatalyst is obtained from Ir(ppy)3 and CNTs using a simple annealing method, exhibiting high bifunctional oxygen catalysts for Zn-air battery. The synergistic effect, the...</description>
      <author>J. Wang, Meiyan Ni, Jinjie Qian, Yifei Ge, C. Dong, Huagui Nie, Xuemei Zhou, Zhi Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc01465k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical efficiency of carbon nanofiber/molybdenum oxide nanocomposites synthesized by electrospinning used in supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118368</link>
      <description>Alireza Chaji, Seyed Abdolkarim Sajjadi, Ghasem Barati Darband, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398177562

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Alireza Chaji, Seyed Abdolkarim Sajjadi, Ghasem Barati Darband</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lowering the kinetic barrier via enhancing electrophilicity of surface oxygen to boost acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100345</link>
      <description>Ling Tang, Yan Wan, Yangming Lin, Jiegou huaxue/Chinese journal of structural chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398177621

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ling Tang, Yan Wan, Yangming Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjsc.2024.100345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving asymmetric redox chemistry for oxygen evolution reaction through strong metal-support interactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.019</link>
      <description>Shihao Wang, Meiling Fan, Hongfei Pan, Jiahui Lyu, Jinsong Wu, Haolin Tang, Haining Zhang, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398177664

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shihao Wang, Meiling Fan, Hongfei Pan, Jiahui Lyu, Jinsong Wu, Haolin Tang, Haining Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of self-supported (NiCoZnCrFe)Se materials for supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.112914</link>
      <description>Xianrui Liu, Jinjuan Dong, H. Li, Ning Lv, Zhen Guo, Tianbao Li, Jun Luo, Materials research bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398185145

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianrui Liu, Jinjuan Dong, H. Li, Ning Lv, Zhen Guo, Tianbao Li, Jun Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.112914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Importance of Seox Formation in Nickel-Iron Selenides for Improving Oxygen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4836666</link>
      <description>Young&#8208;Il Jang, Seunghwa Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398188434

                ABSTRACT. There is a growing need to develop catalysts based on non-precious metals for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Among the various catalysts comprising multiple transition metals, nickel (Ni)-iron (Fe) selenides have gained considerable attention due to their promising catalytic activity, attributed to their distinct metal-like characteristics. Although a lot of studies have focused on the dissolution of selenium (Se) under alkaline OER conditions and its consequent in-situ reconstructing impact, little attention has been paid to the possible involvement of Se itself in OER. In this work, we focus on the small amounts of Se residues that remain after dissolution. Our findings suggest that the quantity of these residues directly influences the OER activity of the Fe active sites within NiFe selenides. These residues are presented on the surface in the form of SeOx.</description>
      <author>Young&#8208;Il Jang, Seunghwa Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4836666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemistry-assisted in-situ Regeneration of Oxygen Vacancies and Ti(III) Active Sites for Persistent Uranium Recovery at a Low Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121817</link>
      <description>Yanjing Wang, Chao Xie, Guangjin Wang, Fei Zhang, Zhaohui Xiao, JiaJia Wang, Yanyong Wang, Shuangyin Wang, Water research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398191166

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanjing Wang, Chao Xie, Guangjin Wang, Fei Zhang, Zhaohui Xiao, JiaJia Wang, Yanyong Wang, Shuangyin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of nanostructured MnCo2O4.5 with spheres and puffed rice balls-like structures as high-performance electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136696</link>
      <description>K. Prasad, T.V.M. Sreekanth, Kisoo Yoo, Jong&#8208;Hoon Kim, Materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398194054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Prasad, T.V.M. Sreekanth, Kisoo Yoo, Jong&#8208;Hoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance the Performance of OER Electrocatalyst via Synergistic Oxygen Vacancies and NiFe2O4-Phosphorene Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174949</link>
      <description>Yijie Mao, Xiao Wang, Jianxiang Wu, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Qing Xu, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398200746

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yijie Mao, Xiao Wang, Jianxiang Wu, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Qing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174949</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction activity of Iron (oxy) hydroxide by increasing reactive sites with morphology modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174911</link>
      <description>Harish S. Chavan, JeongEun Yoo, D Patil, Jiyoung Kim, Yongseon Choi, Ki&#8208;Young Lee, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398200773

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harish S. Chavan, JeongEun Yoo, D Patil, Jiyoung Kim, Yongseon Choi, Ki&#8208;Young Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174911</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Dependent Surface Restructuring on Nickel (Oxy)hydroxides: A Self-Activation Process for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02292</link>
      <description>Yunduo Yao, Guangxin Zhao, Xuyun Guo, Pei Xiong, Zhihang Xu, Longhai Zhang, C. P. Chen, Cunying Xu, Tai Wu, Y. L. Soo, Zhiming Cui, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Ye Zhu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398206347

                Unraveling the catalyst surface structure and behavior during reactions is essential for both mechanistic understanding and performance optimization. Here we report a phenomenon of facet-dependent surface restructuring intrinsic to &#946;-Ni(OH)2 catalysts during oxygen evolution reaction (OER), discovered by the correlative ex situ and operando characterization. The ex situ study after OER reveals &#946;-Ni(OH)2 restructuring at the edge facets to form nanoporous Ni1&#8211;xO, which is Ni deficient containing Ni3+ species. Operando liquid transmission electron microscopy (TEM) and Raman spectroscopy further identify the active role of the intermediate &#946;-NiOOH phase in both the OER catalysis and Ni1&#8211;xO formation, pinpointing the complete surface restructuring pathway. Such surface restructuring is shown to effectively increase the exposed active sites, accelerate Ni oxidation kinetics, and optimize *OH intermediate bonding energy toward fast OER kinetics, which leads to an extraordinary activity enhancement of &#8764;16-fold. Facilitated by such a self-activation process, the specially prepared &#946;-Ni(OH)2 with larger edge facets exhibits a 470-fold current enhancement than that of the benchmark IrO2, demonstrating a promising way to optimize metal-(oxy)hydroxide-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yunduo Yao, Guangxin Zhao, Xuyun Guo, Pei Xiong, Zhihang Xu, Longhai Zhang, C. P. Chen, Cunying Xu, Tai Wu, Y. L. Soo, Zhiming Cui, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Ye Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering oxygen-evolving catalysts for acidic water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0200438</link>
      <description>Xuan Minh Chau Ta, Th&#224;nh Tr&#7847;n&#8208;Ph&#250;, Thi Kim Anh Nguyen, Manjunath Chatti, Rahman Daiyan, Applied physics reviews. 11(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398206370

                The utilization of water electrolysis for green hydrogen (H2) production, powered by renewable energy, is a promising avenue for sustainable development. Proton-exchange-membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) stands out as one of the most efficient H2 production technologies. However, implementing it on an industrial scale faces substantial challenges, particularly regarding the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The OER, a critical process with inherently slow kinetics requiring additional potential, significantly influences overall water-splitting efficiency. Most OER electrocatalysts in PEMWE struggle with poor stability in harsh acidic environments at high oxidative potentials. While rare-earth metal oxides, such as iridium or ruthenium oxides, offer stability in commercial oxygen-evolving electrocatalysts (OECs), their use depends on achieving economically and sustainably viable operations. An alternative approach involves developing low- or non-noble metal-based OECs with sustaining high activity and long-term durability. Although such materials currently exhibit lower activity and stability than noble-based OECs, notable progress has been made in enhancing their performance. This review provides an overview of recent advancements in designing acidic-stable OECs based on low or without noble metal contents. It delves into the thermodynamics and degradation mechanisms of OECs in acidic media, evaluation parameters for activity and stability, strategies for developing active and acid-stable OECs, and the challenges and opportunities of acid water electrolysis. Through a detailed analysis of these aspects, the review aims to identify opportunities for engineering actively durable OECs.</description>
      <author>Xuan Minh Chau Ta, Th&#224;nh Tr&#7847;n&#8208;Ph&#250;, Thi Kim Anh Nguyen, Manjunath Chatti, Rahman Daiyan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0200438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Tellurate Nanorods and Nanoparticles for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00935</link>
      <description>Harishchandra Singh, Miska Veijola-Kara, Ekta Rani, Leticia S. Bezerra, Parisa Talebi, Hugo L. S. Santos, Akhilesh Kumar Patel, Marko Huttula, Pedro H. C. Camargo, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398206879

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harishchandra Singh, Miska Veijola-Kara, Ekta Rani, Leticia S. Bezerra, Parisa Talebi, Hugo L. S. Santos, Akhilesh Kumar Patel, Marko Huttula, Pedro H. C. Camargo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-derived MnCe3.67C6Permeable microflower: A robust electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.291</link>
      <description>Abdul Rasheed Rashid, Sumaira Manzoor, Monday Peter Ajisafe, Safyan Akram Khan, Bing Sun, &#350;enay Yal&#231;&#305;n, Huibin Qin, Suleyman I. Allakhverdiev, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398208043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Rasheed Rashid, Sumaira Manzoor, Monday Peter Ajisafe, Safyan Akram Khan, Bing Sun, &#350;enay Yal&#231;&#305;n, Huibin Qin, Suleyman I. Allakhverdiev</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten doped FeCoP&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles embedded into carbon for highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02326a</link>
      <description>Xinyao Quan, Jiajia Ma, Qian-Shuo Shao, Hao&#8208;Cong Li, Lingxiang Sun, Gui-Li Huang, Yan Su, Hong Zhang, Yuning Wang, Xiaoqing Wang, RSC advances. 14(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398209309

                Tungsten-doped bimetallic phosphide nanoparticles were embedded into carbon by ball milling and phosphorisation, which required only 264 and 310 mV overpotentials to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 current density for OER, respectively.</description>
      <author>Xinyao Quan, Jiajia Ma, Qian-Shuo Shao, Hao&#8208;Cong Li, Lingxiang Sun, Gui-Li Huang, Yan Su, Hong Zhang, Yuning Wang, Xiaoqing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02326a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-enabled fast exploration of stable and active single-atom catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59717/j.xinn-mater.2024.100072</link>
      <description>Woonghyeon Park, Juhwan Noh, Geun Ho Gu, Ga Eun Nam, Sang&#8208;Mun Jung, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Yousung Jung, &#152;The &#156;Innovation materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398211163

                &lt;p&gt;Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can convert renewable energy into hydrogen through water electrolysis. Identifying stable and active single-atom catalysts (SACs) for OER under acidic conditions holds great promise for developing cost-effective and efficient energy storage solutions, but challenging due to the vast number of potential material compositions and diverse surface morphologies. Here, to accelerate new discoveries, we present a high-throughput screening (HTS) framework that leverages the power of machine learning (ML) and density functional theory (DFT). The proposed framework includes an assessment of both the thermodynamic and electrochemical stability of support surfaces. In addition, the integration of ML and uncertainty quantification for predicting the binding energies dramatically reduces the computational cost (by over a factor of 10), facilitating the identification of catalytically active SACs. Following the proposed scheme, we suggest 14 new promising SACs for OER across the 795 binary oxide supports and 21 transition metal atom combinations. These catalysts are found to break the scaling relation due to the enhanced *OOH binding with the support, which arises from favorable hydrogen bonding interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Woonghyeon Park, Juhwan Noh, Geun Ho Gu, Ga Eun Nam, Sang&#8208;Mun Jung, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Yousung Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59717/j.xinn-mater.2024.100072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis by Coordination Engineering in Cobalt Phosphate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403310</link>
      <description>Jing Qi, Qizhen Chen, Mingxing Chen, Wei Zhang, Xinxin Shen, Jing Li, Enbo Shangguan, Rui Cao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398216358

                Abstract Understanding the structure&#8208;activity correlation is an important prerequisite for the rational design of high&#8208;efficiency electrocatalysts at the atomic level. However, the effect of coordination environment on electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains enigmatic. In this work, the regulation of proton transfer involved in water oxidation by coordination engineering based on Co 3 (PO 4 ) 2 and CoHPO 4 is reported. The HPO 4 2&#8722; anion has intermediate p K a value between Co(II)&#8208;H 2 O and Co(III)&#8208;H 2 O to be served as an appealing proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer (PCET) induction group. From theoretical calculations, the pH&#8208;dependent OER properties, deuterium kinetic isotope effects, operando electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) and Raman studies, the CoHPO 4 catalyst beneficially reduces the energy barrier of proton hopping and modulates the formation energy of high&#8208;valent Co species, thereby enhancing OER activity. This work demonstrates a promising strategy that involves tuning the local coordination environment to optimize PCET steps and electrocatalytic activities for electrochemical applications. In addition, the designed system offers a motif to understand the structure&#8208;efficiency relationship from those amino&#8208;acid residue with proton buffer ability in natural photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Jing Qi, Qizhen Chen, Mingxing Chen, Wei Zhang, Xinxin Shen, Jing Li, Enbo Shangguan, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atom-Decorated Transition Metal Oxides Nanomaterials for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00285g</link>
      <description>Chengzhang Li, Cheng&#8208;Zong Yuan, Lingxian Wang, Fengjie Wu, Xiaoguang Lei, Xiaomeng Zhang, An&#8208;Wu Xu, Materials chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398217996

                As one promising technology for highly pure hydrogen production under mild conditions, electrochemical water splitting has been garnering substantial interest, while its efficiency and rate are primarily restricted by the...</description>
      <author>Chengzhang Li, Cheng&#8208;Zong Yuan, Lingxian Wang, Fengjie Wu, Xiaoguang Lei, Xiaomeng Zhang, An&#8208;Wu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00285g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the effect of doping LaCoO3 in CoFe2O4 forming nanocomposite, towards Oxygen Evolution and Methanol Oxidation reactions in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i5.9153</link>
      <description>Reena Parihar, P. C. Mishra, Yamini Singh, Narendra Kumar Singh, Indian Journal of Chemistry. 63(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398222016

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Reena Parihar, P. C. Mishra, Yamini Singh, Narendra Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i5.9153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combustion Growth of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide for Efficient and Durable Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03766</link>
      <description>Zhe Yu, J. Gao, Min Jiang, Yanpeng Chen, Haifeng Yuan, Simeng Li, Jinxin Li, Dongxuan Guo, Mei Hong, Shihe Yang, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398222286

                NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH) with abundant heterostructures represents a state-of-the-art electrocatalyst for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, NiFe LDH/Fe2O3 nanosheet arrays have been fabricated by facile combustion of corrosion-engineered NiFe foam (NFF). The in situ grown, self-supported electrocatalyst exhibited a low overpotential of 248 mV for the OER at 50 mA cm&#8211;2, a small Tafel slope of 31 mV dec&#8211;1, and excellent durability over 100 h under the industrial benchmarking 500 mA cm&#8211;2 current density. A balanced Ni and Fe composition under optimal corrosion and combustion contributed to the desirable electrochemical properties. Comprehensive ex-situ analyses and operando characterizations including Fourier-transformed alternating current voltammetry (FTACV) and in situ Raman demonstrate the beneficial role of modulated interfacial electron transfer, dynamic atomic structural transformation to NiOOH, and the high-valence active metal sites. This study provides a low-cost and easy-to-expand way to synthesize efficient and durable electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhe Yu, J. Gao, Min Jiang, Yanpeng Chen, Haifeng Yuan, Simeng Li, Jinxin Li, Dongxuan Guo, Mei Hong, Shihe Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Como-Pom@If Nanoflower by Facile Room Temperature Etching as an Enhanced Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4837784</link>
      <description>Bo Li, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398225820

                Reasonable design and development of non-precious metal Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) electrocatalysts with high efficiency, low cost and stability are of great significance for electrocatalytic water splitting. The unique molecular structure and exceptional properties of polyoxometalates (POMs) have caught significant attention from the scientific community. Herein, CoMo-POM@IF nanoflowers has been successfully synthesized by facile etching iron foam (IF) at room temperature using polyoxometalates (POMs) as a precursor. POMs as a carbon-free metal-oxygen clusters with unique structural characteristics can be uniformly nucleated at room temperature, which can not only enable efficient green synthesis, but also provide a clear source of catalytic activity. CoMo-POM@IF catalysts with perfect nanoflake layer structure are obtained with the optimal reaction time, and the embedding of POM nanoparticles increased the surface roughness to expose more active sites. The embedding of POMs nanoparticles increases the surface roughness and electrochemically active area, showing great advantages in OER. An overpotential of 282 mV is measured at a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm-2 in 1 M KOH, showing long-term electrochemical stability. The green synthesis of POMs electrocatalyst provides great ideas for the development of room temperature oxygen evolution electrocatalyst and speeds up the development of OER electrocatalyst in the actual production.</description>
      <author>Bo Li, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4837784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo5/Nitrogen doped carbon as an efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for Zn&#8211;Air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118369</link>
      <description>Jingyu Wang, Tianai Zhang, Simin He, Chunwen Sun, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398236341

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingyu Wang, Tianai Zhang, Simin He, Chunwen Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and surface optimization of NiFeP-based heterostructure immobilized on carbon nanotube for boosting electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174957</link>
      <description>Qian Wang, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Xia Liu, Hui Ding, Li Zhang, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398239078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Wang, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Xia Liu, Hui Ding, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic &#8216;Gelectrodes&#8217; for Sustainable and Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-z9f59</link>
      <description>Anu Bovas, T. P. Radhakrishnan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398240909

                Development of cost-effective catalysts that provide low overpotentials and enhanced electrochemical kinetics is a critical goal of contemporary research on electrochemical water splitting and similar technologically significant processes. Translation to practical applications demands that they should also enable high current densities to be ex-tracted. A simple strategy of encapsulating the active electrocatalyst in hydrogel polymer matrices is shown to provide a solution in several respects, especially regarding the last criterion. The concept is illustrated using two examples of &#8216;gelectrodes&#8217; based on nanocomposites of cobalt oxyhydroxide and nickel-iron hydroxide with chitosan on nickel foam, and their efficient mediation of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Comparison with various control systems show that significantly lower overpotentials and higher current densities with extended temporal stability can be achieved with the gelectrodes; the cobalt oxyhydroxide - chitosan and nickel-iron hydroxide - chitosan systems provide stable current densities up to 1.6 - 1.7 A cm-2 for the OER with alkaline aqueous electrolyte. This simple design strategy is expected to open up a general route to technologically useful electrocatalyst performance.</description>
      <author>Anu Bovas, T. P. Radhakrishnan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-z9f59</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance of Nitrogen&#8208;Doped Carbon Nanoparticles Carrying FeNiCu as Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400830</link>
      <description>Qiao Guo, Rui Yuan, Yifei Zhao, Ying Yu, Jie Fu, Longsheng Cao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398242923

                Abstract Catalysts for zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) must be stable over long&#8208;term charging&#8208;discharging cycles and exhibit bifunctional catalytic activity. In this study, by doping nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (NC) materials with three metal atoms (Fe, Ni, and Cu), a single&#8208;atom&#8208;distributed FeNiCu&#8208;NC bifunctional catalyst is prepared. The catalyst includes Fe(Ni&#8208;doped)&#8208;N 4 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), Fe(Cu&#8208;doped)&#8208;N 4 for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and the NiCu&#8208;NC catalytic structure for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in the nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanoparticles. This single&#8208;atom distribution catalyst structure enhances the bifunctional catalytic activity. If a trimetallic single&#8208;atom catalyst is designed, it will surpass the typical bimetallic single&#8208;atom catcalyst. FeNiCu&#8208;NC exhibits outstanding performance as an electrocatalyst, with a half&#8208;wave potential ( E 1/2 ) of 0.876 V versus RHE, overpotential ( E j = 10 ) of 253 mV versus RHE at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a small potential gap ( &#916;E = 0.61 V). As the anode in a ZAB, FeNiCu&#8208;NC can undergo continuous charge&#8208;discharged cycles for 575 h without significant attenuation. This study presents a new method for achieving high&#8208;performance, low&#8208;cost ZABs via trimetallic single&#8208;atom doping.</description>
      <author>Qiao Guo, Rui Yuan, Yifei Zhao, Ying Yu, Jie Fu, Longsheng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inactive Ag Modification and Defect Engineering Optimization on Three-Dimensional Coral-Like High-Entropy Oxides to Trigger Effective Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4839860</link>
      <description>Bing Zhang, Ping Geng, Mengzhao Liu, Ming Cui, Weiming L&#252;, Weiming Yi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398243423

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Zhang, Ping Geng, Mengzhao Liu, Ming Cui, Weiming L&#252;, Weiming Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4839860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-Mn Pair-Site Triggers Key Oxygen Intermediate for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4839786</link>
      <description>Faming Gao, yuanzhe wang, Kuo Wei, Yanli Song, Adekunle Adedapo Obisanya, Heen Li, Jing Wang, Hongguan Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398244782

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faming Gao, yuanzhe wang, Kuo Wei, Yanli Song, Adekunle Adedapo Obisanya, Heen Li, Jing Wang, Hongguan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4839786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel layered cobalt oxide Ba2Co9O14 as an efficient and durable bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144450</link>
      <description>Dexuan Huang, Tong Liu, Aidong Xu, Jian Zhou, Yao Wang, Xiaoling Hu, Electrochimica acta. 494(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398247622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dexuan Huang, Tong Liu, Aidong Xu, Jian Zhou, Yao Wang, Xiaoling Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the Configuration Entropy of Layered Hydroxides Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4833203</link>
      <description>Da Li, Peifang Guo, Xiuping Yan, Yufei He, Renbing Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398249046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Da Li, Peifang Guo, Xiuping Yan, Yufei He, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4833203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rich oxygen vacancy and amorphous/crystalline ruthenium-doped CoCu -layered double hydroxide electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.169</link>
      <description>Yanan Wang, Li Jing, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Bo Liu, Yan Sun, Xianyu Chu, Chunbo Liu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398253008

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Wang, Li Jing, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Bo Liu, Yan Sun, Xianyu Chu, Chunbo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Engineering of Carbon Dots and Mn in Co&#8208;Based Phosphides for Highly Efficient Seawater Splitting at Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402478</link>
      <description>Tingting Fang, Xin Yu, Xu Han, Juan Gao, Yunlong Ma, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398253231

                Abstract Direct electrolysis of seawater to generate hydrogen is an attractive approach for storing renewable energy. However, direct seawater splitting suffers from low current density and limited operating stability, which severely hinders its industrialization. Herein, a promising strategy is reported to obtain a nano needle&#8208;like array catalyst&#8208;CDs&#8208;Mn&#8208;Co x P on nickel foam, in which the Mn&#9472;O&#9472;C bond tightly binds Mn, Carbon dots (CDs), and Co x P together. The coordination engineering of CDs and Mn not only effectively regulates the electronic structure of Co x P, but also endows the as&#8208;prepared catalyst with selectivity and marked long&#8208;term stability at ampere&#8208;level current density. Low overpotentials of 208 and 447 mV are required to achieve 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in simulated seawater, respectively. Cell potentials of 1.78 and 1.86 V are needed to reach 500 and 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline seawater along with excellent durability for 350 h. DFT studies have verified that the introduction of Mn and CDs effectively shifts the d&#8208;band center of Co&#8208;3d toward higher energy, thereby strengthening the adsorption of intermediates and enhancing the catalytic activity. This study sheds light on the development of highly effective and stable catalysts for large&#8208;scale seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Tingting Fang, Xin Yu, Xu Han, Juan Gao, Yunlong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing medium-entropy spinel oxide FeNiMnO4/CeO2 heterojunction as high-performance electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00770k</link>
      <description>Hao Wu, Zhichao Wang, Yuan Shi, Zexu Li, Dong Fan, Yilun Ren, Fengqi Li, Haifeng Bian, Cong Wang, Yurong Yang, Jimin Gu, Shaochun Tang, Yan Ma, Yu Deng, Xiangkang Meng, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398757676

                Medium-entropy oxides are commonly employed as electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in electrolysers aimed at producing sustainable hydrogen. However, the poor conductivity poses a significant obstacle to further...</description>
      <author>Hao Wu, Zhichao Wang, Yuan Shi, Zexu Li, Dong Fan, Yilun Ren, Fengqi Li, Haifeng Bian, Cong Wang, Yurong Yang, Jimin Gu, Shaochun Tang, Yan Ma, Yu Deng, Xiangkang Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00770k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Oxygen Evolution with Amine-Induced Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4834679</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhou, Wei Zi, Ziliang Kang, Hina Naz, Yashu Liu, Zhenyuan Ji, Guoxing Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398151937

                Developing of highly active electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution is one of the most important issues for water splitting. It is widely accepted that Fe sites can act as active centers for oxygen evolution in alkaline solution. Herein, an amine-mediated strategy was used to induce the reconstruction of nanoscale Prussian blue analogue. The nanoscale cubes of Prussian blue analogue can be etched by amine ligand, inducing the formation of hollow structure and small sized pieces. In the etching process, Fe-based species in situ preferentially loads on the surface of newly generated units, which can expose more iron sites and thus promotes the electrocatalytic performance for oxygen evolution. The optimized catalyst exhibits an incredibly low overpotential of 257 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm-2 and a small Tafel slope of 44.1 mV dec-1 with remarkable stability in alkaline solution. After OER operation, Ni-doped FeOOH with thin sheet-like structure was formed on the surface of catalyst particles. Density functional theory (DFT) calculation confirms the key role of Fe active sites in the OER process, and that the synergistic effect between Ni and Fe sites modulates the adsorption behavior of intermediates and so results in enhanced activity. This work provides an efficient strategy for advanced oxygen evolution catalysts towards electrochemical energy storage and conversion.</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhou, Wei Zi, Ziliang Kang, Hina Naz, Yashu Liu, Zhenyuan Ji, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4834679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Performed by a Long-Afterglow Material</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01382</link>
      <description>Yanfei Fan, Lijun Yan, Yujia Zhang, Xiu&#8208;Li Yang, Shizhao Si, Guanwei Cui, Xifeng Shi, Bo Tang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398131932

                A micron-sized long-afterglow material, Sr2MgSi2O7:Eu,Ce, was utilized to conduct the hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction, two half-reactions of water splitting, in the presence of sacrificial agents under both light and dark conditions for the first time. The as-synthesized Sr2MgSi2O7:Eu,Ce exhibited higher photocatalytic activity compared to that of the referenced Sr2MgSi2O7:Eu and Sr2MgSi2O7:Ce samples. Herein, in addition to benefiting from the long photogenerated carrier lifetime of long-afterglow materials, the higher photocatalytic activity was attributed to the conjugated electronic structure between Eu and Ce ions. This structure facilitates charge and energy transfer between them, leading to an enhanced photocatalytic efficiency. This research provides a new strategy for designing efficient long-afterglow material photocatalysts through the construction of conjugated electronic structures.</description>
      <author>Yanfei Fan, Lijun Yan, Yujia Zhang, Xiu&#8208;Li Yang, Shizhao Si, Guanwei Cui, Xifeng Shi, Bo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01382</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on fundamentals for designing stable ruthenium-based catalysts for the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60013-6</link>
      <description>Wangyan Gou, Yichen Wang, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398224626

                Clean and renewable energy is generally localized and intermittent. Thus, energy conversion and storage technologies are necessary to compensate for these shortcomings. Electrolytic water splitting presents a reliable and promising energy technology for producing high purity hydrogen (H2). Among the platinum metals, ruthenium (Ru) has gained significant attentions as it generally outperforms commercial catalysts in terms of activity at a more affordable price. Although great progress has been made in improving the catalytic activity of Ru-based catalysts, stability remains a major challenge hindering their practical applications. To this end, this review introduces the fundamentals of the stability over Ru-based catalysts for water splitting, including the reaction mechanisms of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), measurement methods and evaluation criteria, as well as deactivation mechanisms. Moreover, the up-to-date advances of representative strategies for improving HER and OER stability of Ru-based catalysts are further discussed with respect to specific design principles and underlying mechanisms. Ultimately, insights into the challenges and opportunities for Ru-based electrocatalysts are provided to promote the development of next-generation Ru-based catalysts with exceptional stability. This review aims at guiding the design and synthesis of superior catalysts, generating increased interest among researchers, and stimulating further advanced research.</description>
      <author>Wangyan Gou, Yichen Wang, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60013-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Alloy Catalysts of FeCoNiCuMo/C with High Stability for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174922</link>
      <description>Jiangtao Ma, Yujun Zhu, Kai Huang, Peng Wang, Dinghua Liu, Yupei Zhao, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398181354

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiangtao Ma, Yujun Zhu, Kai Huang, Peng Wang, Dinghua Liu, Yupei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and oxygen-evolution-reaction performance of sulphur-doped flower-like NiFe-based composites supported on biomass porous carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.2024.192.693</link>
      <description>Qihong Lou, Shan Zhong, Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, Digest Journal of Nanomaterials and Biostructures. 19(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398239346

                Hydrogen gas generated through water electrolysis can replace fossil fuels. Thus, developing cost-effective and efficient water-splitting electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction is highly important. Herein, biomass-porous-carbon-supported sulphur-doped flower-like NiFe-based alloy composites are prepared using an in situ impregnation&#8211;heat treatment technology. The spherical flower (diameter &#8776; 1 &#956;m, petal thickness &#8776; 20 nm) main components are Ni0.5Fe0.5 and Fe9Ni9S16. The 800 &#176;C heat-treated catalyst demonstrates outstanding catalytic performance in oxygen evolution reactions. At a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 , it exhibits a minimal overpotential of 298.62 mV</description>
      <author>Qihong Lou, Shan Zhong, Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.2024.192.693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-induced hollow binary metal-organic framework derived Fe-doped cobalt-carbon nanomaterials for oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.168</link>
      <description>Haitao Ni, Shaojie Xu, Rong Lin, Yi Ding, Jinjie Qian, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398249855

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haitao Ni, Shaojie Xu, Rong Lin, Yi Ding, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finely tuning Cobalt Valence in Co3O4 Lattice through Chromium Substitution: Regulating the charge transfer and oxygen vacancies for Oxygen Evolution and Methanol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100826</link>
      <description>Prakhar Mishra, Reena Parihar, Yamini Singh, Amritpal Singh Chaddha, Narendra Kumar Singh, Materials today sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397030834

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Prakhar Mishra, Reena Parihar, Yamini Singh, Amritpal Singh Chaddha, Narendra Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtsust.2024.100826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel catalysed and decorated CO2 laser induced graphene from bio-waste-derived thermoset polymer as a high-performance catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119275</link>
      <description>Suparna Saha, Shweta Hiwase, Sukanta K. Mondal, A. R. A. S. Deshmukh, Satishchandra Ogale, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398755838

                In this work, we examine carbonization of natural product derived thermoset polymer by CO2 laser-assisted direct-write transient pyrolysis process without and with the addition of nickel salt for possible catalytic intervention. We find that nickel indeed plays an interesting and crucial role in significantly enhancing the graphene content in the laser processed sample (Ni-LIG) retaining its few monolayer character. The unique and significant advantages of laser induced transient pyrolysis process are: a) it is a direct write process enabling in-process functionality patterning, if needed, b) it is highly energy economic because energy is localized and directed to the desired process zone, c) being a transient process it can be implemented under ambient conditions, and d) it creates distinctly different microstructure as compared to furnace annealing. It was further observed that upon incorporation of the Ni-(CH3COO)2.4H2O salt in the polymer the LIG process reduces it to Ni (111), which in turn catalyses the nucleation process and lowers the activation barrier for graphene formation by annealing the defects. Moreover, due to the very low lattice mismatch between Ni (111) and graphene facilitates its high growth quality. The concurrent decoration of Ni/NiO on graphene is also shown to promote water dissociation as well as adsorption of water oxidation intermediates. This leads to an impressive value of the overpotential for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at 10 mA/cm2 of only 290 mV in 1M KOH. Additionally, the catalytic capacity and structure remain stable after 30 h of continuous work in 1M KOH.</description>
      <author>Suparna Saha, Shweta Hiwase, Sukanta K. Mondal, A. R. A. S. Deshmukh, Satishchandra Ogale</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions by Using the V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CT&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;@Sm Nanocomposite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00993</link>
      <description>Eisha Mazhar, Irfan Ali, Saif Ullah Awan, Syed Rizwan, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398318329

                The rational design and advancement of highly efficient and readily available bifunctional electrocatalysts are crucial in pursuing renewable-energy-driven electrocatalytic water splitting as a potential strategy for clean hydrogen generation. Researchers have increasingly focused on transition-metal carbides (MXenes) in the past decade due to their distinctive properties, particularly their potential as cocatalysts in electrocatalytic systems. Herein, we have presented a method for surface modification of V2CTx MXene to create an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for water-splitting applications. The desired results are achieved through the intercalation of rare earth element Sm (samarium) with V2CTx MXene by the sonochemical method. The anchoring of samarium on the surface of two-dimensional MXene served as a conductive medium, and their extensive interfacial effects enabled the fast transportation of ions by creating short and conductive channels at the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface by exposing more active sites. The OER and HER electrocatalytic activity of the electrode material was investigated by using a 1.0 M KOH electrolyte. The results showed that the Sm@V2CTx nanocomposite (referred to as V1) exhibited exceptional performance for the OER with an overpotential of 350 mV (vs RHE) delivered at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 100 mV/dec. For HER, the system is capable of delivering an overpotential of 236 mV (vs RHE) and fast kinetics, having a Tafel slope of 88 mV/dec. Furthermore, it exhibits excellent stability for over 14 h. This research showcases the capability of earth-abundant MXene materials and the modification of their electrocatalytic activity to act as a foundation for creating a broad range of high-performance, environmentally sustainable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Eisha Mazhar, Irfan Ali, Saif Ullah Awan, Syed Rizwan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Spinel with Perovskite: Sr Substitution in the Perovskite Phase of CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;LaCoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocomposite for Oxygen Evolution and Methanol Oxidation in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400221</link>
      <description>Reena Parihar, P. C. Mishra, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Narendra Kumar Singh, Energy technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397290317

                CoFe 2 O 4 &#8211;La 1&#8722; x Sr x CoO 3 ( x = 0.2, 0.6, 0.8) composites have been synthesized using a two&#8208;step, low&#8208;temperature wet chemical approach that combines coprecipitation and sol&#8211;gel techniques. The composite materials have been physicochemically analyzed using Fourier&#8208;transform infrared spectroscopy, X&#8208;ray diffraction, and scanning electron microscope. The electrocatalytic properties of the composite materials have been assessed in terms of their performance in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) in alkaline medium. Cyclic voltammetry has been used for analyzing the redox behavior of the materials in 1 M KOH solution. The electrocatalytic activity of the materials has been assessed using anodic polarization curves on Ni substrate and the CoFe 2 O 4 &#8211;La 0.2 Sr 0.8 CoO 3 film electrode demonstrates excellent activity, with current densities of 11.1 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER and 47.4 mA cm &#8722;2 for MOR at 650 mV. Also, the CoFe 2 O 4 &#8211;La 0.2 Sr 0.8 CoO 3 film electrode has the maximum specific activity of 1.1 &#215; 10 3 mA cm &#8722;2 g &#8722;1 at 650 mV toward OER. The electrodes&#8217; stability has been assessed through chronoamperometric experiments and additional insight into the enhancement of electrocatalytic activity gained through the electrochemical surface area estimations using electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. From chronoamperometric experiment, it has been observed that the CoFe 2 O 4 &#8211;La 0.2 Sr 0.8 CoO 3 film electrode attains stability within 114 s with a current density of 108.7 mA cm &#8722;2 . Furthermore, the thermodynamic parameters, including the standard enthalpy of activation (&#916; H &#176; # ), standard entropy of activation (&#916; S &#176; # ), and standard electrochemical energy of activation (), have been estimated by anodic polarization curve recorded in KOH as well as KOH with CH 3 OH solutions at various temperatures.</description>
      <author>Reena Parihar, P. C. Mishra, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Narendra Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Oxygen in Evolution of Complexity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15750-9.00022-7</link>
      <description>Andrej Fabrizius, Thorsten Burmester, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398153054

                Oxygen had a profound effect on the evolution. In the beginning life on Earth emerged in an oxygen-free environment. Around 2.7 billion years ago, photosynthetic cyanobacteria started to produce oxygen. This caused a mass extinction of anaerobic organisms, except some bacteria that used oxygen for energy production. According to the endosymbiotic theory, the mitochondria of eukaryotes derive from such bacteria; the chloroplasts of plants are descendants of cyanobacteria. During the Cambrian "explosion" about 500 million years ago, rising oxygen levels enabled the evolution of complex animals. In later periods, fluctuations of atmospheric oxygen levels contributed to animal terrestrialization and mass extinction events, and facilitated the evolution of large insects and dinosaurs.</description>
      <author>Andrej Fabrizius, Thorsten Burmester</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-15750-9.00022-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction kinetics and photoluminescence studies of zinc stannate (ZnSnO3/Zn2SnO4) nanoparticles synthesized via &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" altimg="si12.svg" display="inline" id="d1e651"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;A&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;l&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;b&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;r&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;b&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;a&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;d&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;e&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;n&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;s&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;i&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml&#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2024.117427</link>
      <description>Vishwalinga Prasad B., H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, C. Ningappa, Daruka Prasad B, R. Sahana, K. Manjunatha, Sheng Yun Wu, K.N. Sridhar, Materials science and engineering. B, Solid-state materials for advanced technology/Materials science &amp; engineering. B, Solid-state materials for advanced technology. 305(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398159176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vishwalinga Prasad B., H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, C. Ningappa, Daruka Prasad B, R. Sahana, K. Manjunatha, Sheng Yun Wu, K.N. Sridhar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2024.117427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "The radical impact of oxygen on prokaryotic evolution&#8212;enzyme inhibition first, uninhibited essential biosyntheses second, aerobic respiration third"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397013932

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "The radical impact of oxygen on prokaryotic evolution&#8212;enzyme inhibition first, uninhibited essential biosyntheses second, aerobic respiration third"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397013788

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "The radical impact of oxygen on prokaryotic evolution&#8212;enzyme inhibition first, uninhibited essential biosyntheses second, aerobic respiration third"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397013830

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "The radical impact of oxygen on prokaryotic evolution&#8212;enzyme inhibition first, uninhibited essential biosyntheses second, aerobic respiration third"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Natalia Mrnjavac, Falk S. P. Nagies, Jessica L. E. Wimmer, Nils Kapust, Michael Knopp, Katharina Trost, Luca Modjewski, Nico Bremer, Marek Mentel, Mauro Degli Esposti, Itzhak Mizrahi, John F. Allen, William Martin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397013876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Natalia Mrnjavac, Falk S. P. Nagies, Jessica L. E. Wimmer, Nils Kapust, Michael Knopp, Katharina Trost, Luca Modjewski, Nico Bremer, Marek Mentel, Mauro Degli Esposti, Itzhak Mizrahi, John F. Allen, William Martin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "The radical impact of oxygen on prokaryotic evolution&#8212;enzyme inhibition first, uninhibited essential biosyntheses second, aerobic respiration third"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397013910

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "The radical impact of oxygen on prokaryotic evolution&#8212;enzyme inhibition first, uninhibited essential biosyntheses second, aerobic respiration third"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397013905

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/1873-3468.14906/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Investigation of Lattice Oxygen Loss from Preferentially Faceted Electrodeposited LiCoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Scanning Electrochemical Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4f22</link>
      <description>Abhiroop Mishra, Jiangli Lin, Beniamin Zahiri, Paul V. Braun, Joaqu&#237;n Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;L&#243;pez, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398199031

                Abstract Lattice oxygen loss from transition metal oxide cathodes in Li-ion batteries (LiBs) is a key factor responsible in their gradual capacity decline over time. Understanding and mitigating this phenomenon is crucial for the development of next-generation LiBs. The effect of various parameters on lattice oxygen loss, such as cathode chemical composition, has been studied extensively. However, there is a lack of experimental investigation into the lattice oxygen stability across different crystallographic facets within the same cathode composition. Here, we employed in situ scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM) to investigate oxygen evolution from preferentially faceted, electrodeposited LiCoO2 cathodes. Samples predominantly exposing the (003) basal planes and the (101), (102), (110) fast Li-ion diffusing facets exhibited oxygen evolution at potentials exceeding 3.5 V vs Li+/Li. Finite element simulations helped quantify the flux of oxygen evolution on the first charge cycle to 33&#177;5 pmol/cm2s for the basal plane and 37&#177;9 pmol/cm2s for the faceted samples at potentials above 4 V based on single spot measurements. However, spatially resolved measurements showed that faceted samples exhibited significant heterogeneity in their oxygen evolution, reaching twofold values compared to the basal plane samples at potentials beyond 4.5 V.</description>
      <author>Abhiroop Mishra, Jiangli Lin, Beniamin Zahiri, Paul V. Braun, Joaqu&#237;n Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4f22</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu&#8208;N Synergism Regulation to Enhance Anionic Redox Reversibility and Activity of Li&#8208; and Mn&#8208;Rich Layered Oxides Cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401645</link>
      <description>Zhijun Wu, C. T. Yan, Panyu Gao, Liaona She, Xin Zhang, Yue Lin, Guanglin Xia, Yongfeng Liu, Wenping Sun, Yinzhu Jiang, Yaxiong Yang, Mingxi Gao, Hongge Pan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398138897

                Anionic redox chemistry enables extraordinary capacity for Li- and Mn-rich layered oxides (LMROs) cathodes. Unfortunately, irreversible surface oxygen evolution evokes the pernicious phase transition, structural deterioration, and severe electrode-electrolyte interface side reaction with element dissolution, resulting in fast capacity and voltage fading of LMROs during cycling and hindering its commercialization. Herein, a redox couple strategy is proposed by utilizing copper phthalocyanine (CuPc) to address the irreversibility of anionic redox. The Cu-N synergistic effect of CuPc could not only inhibit surface oxygen evolution by reducing the peroxide ion O</description>
      <author>Zhijun Wu, C. T. Yan, Panyu Gao, Liaona She, Xin Zhang, Yue Lin, Guanglin Xia, Yongfeng Liu, Wenping Sun, Yinzhu Jiang, Yaxiong Yang, Mingxi Gao, Hongge Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside front cover</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90085e</link>
      <description>, Dalton transactions. 53(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398187595

                Co 3 O 4 /activated carbon nanocomposites as electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90085e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Bi-functional Oxide Electrode for Selective Oxidative C-C Cleavage of Glycerol to Formate and Synchronized Green Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00434e</link>
      <description>Arindam Saha, Vasantharadevi Murugiah, Ravi Ranjan, Inderjeet Chauhan, Kshirodra Kumar Patra, Himanshu Bajpai, Avishek Saha, Chinnakonda S. Gopinath, Sustainable energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398225373

                Alkaline water electrolysis is a mature method to produce green hydrogen, but it is at a significantly high cost due to the high overpotential for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However,...</description>
      <author>Arindam Saha, Vasantharadevi Murugiah, Ravi Ranjan, Inderjeet Chauhan, Kshirodra Kumar Patra, Himanshu Bajpai, Avishek Saha, Chinnakonda S. Gopinath</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00434e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treasure-Bowl Style Bifunctional Site in Cerium-Tungsten Hetero-Clusters for Superior Solar-Driven Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh00111g</link>
      <description>Pengliang Sun, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino, Fang Tan, Huanhuan Zhang, Qingquan Kong, Guangzhi Hu, Thomas W&#229;gberg, Materials horizons. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398211646

                Electrochemical water splitting powered by renewable energy sources hold potential for clean hydrogen production. However, there is still persistent challenges such as low solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency and sluggish oxygen evolution...</description>
      <author>Pengliang Sun, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino, Fang Tan, Huanhuan Zhang, Qingquan Kong, Guangzhi Hu, Thomas W&#229;gberg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh00111g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Potential of NiCo2O4 Nanocomposite: Morphology Modification via Urea Quantity, Hydrothermal and Calcination Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01581a</link>
      <description>Ataollah Niyati, Arianna Moranda, Juan F. Basb&#250;s, Ombretta Paladino, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398225747

                Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) electrocatalysts are critical in minimizing energy loss during the anodic four-electron transfer process that is required for water oxidation. Improving and selecting optimal non-nobel OER electrocatalysts...</description>
      <author>Ataollah Niyati, Arianna Moranda, Juan F. Basb&#250;s, Ombretta Paladino</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01581a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Materials for Green Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1339-4_16</link>
      <description>Nithin Chandran B.S., Anupma Thakur, Energy, environment, and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398151269

                Using green hydrogen as a clean energy carrier has gained unprecedented attention in the global pursuit of sustainable energy solutions. This chapter delves into the pivotal role that two-dimensional (2D) materials play in advancing the field of green hydrogen production. With a focus on electrocatalytic and photoelectrochemical processes, this chapter explores how 2D materials possess unique properties that enable efficient hydrogen evolution and oxygen evolution reactions, crucial steps in water splitting. The application landscape of 2D materials in green hydrogen production is then unveiled, covering their roles in electrocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution, as well as photoelectrochemical water splitting. The integration of 2D materials with renewable energy sources is explored, along with the technological challenges that must be overcome for successful implementation. The chapter culminates in a forward-looking analysis, outlining the emerging trends in 2D material research, computational modeling, stability enhancement, and economic feasibility. Through a blend of experimental insights and theoretical understanding, this chapter underscores the vital contribution of 2D materials to unlocking the potential of green hydrogen production. By shedding light on their remarkable catalytic properties and unveiling strategies for addressing challenges, this chapter serves as a springboard for researchers, policymakers, and industries invested in shaping a sustainable energy future.</description>
      <author>Nithin Chandran B.S., Anupma Thakur</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1339-4_16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Hematite Photoanodes for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting: The Impact of g&#8208;C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Supported Ni&#8208;CoP on Photogenerated Hole Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401298</link>
      <description>Mundo Yang, Louise I. Oldham, M&#225;ty&#225;s Dab&#243;czi, Yasmine Baghdadi, Junyi Cui, Daniele Benetti, W Zhang, James R. Durrant, Anna Hankin, Salvador Eslava, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397007907

                Abstract The increasing demand for clean hydrogen necessitates the rapid development of efficient photoanodes to catalyze the water oxidation half&#8208;reaction effectively. Here a strategy is introduced to fabricate photoanodes that synergistically combine and leverage the properties of porous Ti&#8208;doped hematite (Ti&#8208;Fe 2 O 3 ) and graphitic carbon nitride (g&#8208;C 3 N 4 ) nanosheets anchored with in situ grown Ni&#8208;doped CoP co&#8208;catalyst (Ni&#8208;CoP). The resulting hybrid photoanodes exhibit &gt;7 times higher photocurrent density at +1.23 V RHE compared with Ti&#8208;Fe 2 O 3 photoanodes. Comprehensive characterization techniques, including ambient photoemission spectroscopy, intensity&#8208;modulated photocurrent spectroscopy, and transient absorption spectroscopy complementarily reveal the key impact of g&#8208;C 3 N 4 in these composites with enhanced solar oxygen evolution reaction: The incorporation of g&#8208;C 3 N 4 leads to enhanced charge separation through a type&#8208;II heterojunction, thereby increasing the hole flux at the surface, and extending the charge carrier lifetime to the ms&#8208;s range needed for water oxidation. Additionally, g&#8208;C 3 N 4 facilitates efficient transfer of photogenerated holes to the fine Ni&#8208;CoP nanoparticles confined in the graphitic matrix for a boosted oxygen evolution reaction. These findings highlight the advantages of complex heterostructure photoanodes and demonstrate a new application of g&#8208;C 3 N 4 as a multifunctional support of co&#8208;catalysts for future photoanodes with enhanced performance.</description>
      <author>Mundo Yang, Louise I. Oldham, M&#225;ty&#225;s Dab&#243;czi, Yasmine Baghdadi, Junyi Cui, Daniele Benetti, W Zhang, James R. Durrant, Anna Hankin, Salvador Eslava</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401298</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating reaction pathway of ruthenium oxide with enhanced performance and stability toward acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101004</link>
      <description>Liqing Wu, Na Yao, Qinglei Meng, Hongnan Jia, Juan Zhu, Jianbing Zhu, Wei Luo, Chem catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398146519

                Developing RuO2-based electrocatalysts with high activity and stability for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is highly desirable but remains a challenge. More critically, strategies for rational manipulation of the reaction pathway of RuO2 from a kinetically favorable but unstable lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) pathway to an adsorption evolution mechanism (AEM) pathway are still elusive. Herein, we report the synthesis of Ce-doped RuO2 catalysts with the existence of oxygen vacancies (Ce-RuO2-x). Experimental results and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that Ru valence state is lowered with the formation of Ce-O-Ru local structure, and Ru-O covalency is decreased, which suppress the surface Ru demetallation and lattice oxygen loss, resulting in greatly enhanced durability toward acidic OER. Moreover, the synergistic effect between Ce-O-Ru local structure and oxygen vacancies can be conducive to the stabilization of OOH&#8727;, leading to a manipulated reaction pathway from LOM to AEM and reduced energy barrier of the rate-determining step.</description>
      <author>Liqing Wu, Na Yao, Qinglei Meng, Hongnan Jia, Juan Zhu, Jianbing Zhu, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalyst Interaction in Unitized Regenerative Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4e75</link>
      <description>Annabelle Maletzko, Eduardo Daniel Gomez Villa, Birgit Kintzel, H. Fietzek, Gordon Schmidt, J. Christen, Peter Veit, Philipp K&#252;hne, Aline Bornet, Matthias Arenz, Julia Melke, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398158906

                Abstract Unitized regenerative fuel cells have emerged as promising energy conversion and storage systems for various applications. However, in order to optimize their efficiency, it is crucial to enhance the performance of the bifunctional catalyst. This study aims to provide deeper insights into the electrochemical behavior and performance of the bifunctional catalyst. Several electrocatalysts were prepared and evaluated using rotating disc electrode measurements. The primary focus was placed on investigating the interaction between Pt, Ir, and the support material, antimony doped tin oxide (ATO), and their impact on the oxygen evolution reaction and oxygen reduction reaction. Among the analyzed catalysts, Pt black mixed with synthesized IrO2 supported on developed ATO exhibited the highest performance, considering the results from both the fuel cell and electrolyzer systems.</description>
      <author>Annabelle Maletzko, Eduardo Daniel Gomez Villa, Birgit Kintzel, H. Fietzek, Gordon Schmidt, J. Christen, Peter Veit, Philipp K&#252;hne, Aline Bornet, Matthias Arenz, Julia Melke</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4e75</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balance between Fe&lt;sup&gt;IV&lt;/sup&gt;&#8211;Ni&lt;sup&gt;IV&lt;/sup&gt; synergy and Lattice Oxygen Contribution for Accelerating Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01718</link>
      <description>Chao Jing, Lili Li, Y. Y. Chin, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Miaomiao Liu, Jing Zhou, Taotao Yuan, Xinan Zhou, Yifeng Wang, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Da&#8208;Wei Li, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Z. Hu, Linjuan Zhang, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398160514

                Hydrogen obtained from electrochemical water splitting is the most promising clean energy carrier, which is hindered by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Thus, the development of an efficient OER electrocatalyst using nonprecious 3d transition elements is desirable. Multielement synergistic effect and lattice oxygen oxidation are two well-known mechanisms to enhance the OER activity of catalysts. The latter is generally related to the high valence state of 3d transition elements leading to structural destabilization under the OER condition. We have found that Al doping in nanosheet Ni-Fe hydroxide exhibits 2-fold advantage: (1) a strong enhanced OER activity from 277 mV to 238 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Chao Jing, Lili Li, Y. Y. Chin, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Miaomiao Liu, Jing Zhou, Taotao Yuan, Xinan Zhou, Yifeng Wang, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Da&#8208;Wei Li, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Z. Hu, Linjuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01718</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rechargeable zinc-air battery with bifunctional electrocatalyst of copper oxide and graphene nanoplatelets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107760</link>
      <description>B&#225;rbara Antunes Cunha S&#225;, Tatiana Santos Andrade, Rafael Rodrigues de Souza, Antero Ricardo Santos Neto, Mariandry Rodr&#237;guez, Francisco G.E. Nogueira, M&#225;rcio C. Pereira, Electrochemistry communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398146912

                Rechargeable zinc-air batteries have been identified as promising technologies for energy storage. However, developing cost-effective electrocatalysts that can efficiently facilitate the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for their advancement. This work investigates synthesized electrocatalysts composed of graphene-Cu2O deposited on carbon cloth by doctor blading casting method as bifunctional electrodes in a rechargeable Zn-air battery. The battery integrated with graphene-Cu2O as the air-cathode electrocatalyst showed superior performance in terms of cycling stability compared to that without Cu2O. This enhanced performance is attributed to the reversibility of Cu+/Cu2+ species during the redox reactions facilitated by the high electrical conductivity of graphene. Therefore, the results suggest the potential of the synthesized electrodes for advancing the development of rechargeable Zn-air batteries.</description>
      <author>B&#225;rbara Antunes Cunha S&#225;, Tatiana Santos Andrade, Rafael Rodrigues de Souza, Antero Ricardo Santos Neto, Mariandry Rodr&#237;guez, Francisco G.E. Nogueira, M&#225;rcio C. Pereira</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107760</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress and perspective on electrocatalysis in neutral media: Mechanisms, materials, and advanced characterizations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/idm2.12172</link>
      <description>Fu-Shun Lai, Haochuan Shang, Yuechao Jiao, Xinyi Chen, Tianran Zhang, Xiangfeng Liu, Interdisciplinary materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398252762

                Abstract Electrocatalysis, which involves oxidation and reduction reactions with direct electron transfer, is essential for a variety of clean energy conversion devices. Currently, the vast majority of studies regarding electrocatalysis reactions focus on strong acidic or alkaline media because of the higher catalytic activity. Nevertheless, some inherent drawbacks, including the corrosive environment, expensive proton exchange membranes, and side effects, are still hard to break through. A sustainably promising way to overcome these shortcomings is to deploy neutral/near&#8208;neutral electrolytes for electrocatalysis reactions. Unfortunately, insufficient research in this area due to the lack of attention to related issues has slowed down the development process. In this review, we systematically review the catalytic reaction mechanisms, neutral electrolytes, electrocatalysts, and modification strategies carried out in neutral media on the three most common electrocatalytic reactions, that is, hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, and oxygen evolution reaction. Furthermore, the advanced characterization tools for guiding catalyst synthesis and mechanistic studies are also summarized. Eventually, we propose some challenges and perspectives on electrocatalysis reactions in neutral media and hope it will attract more research interest and provide guidance in neutral electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Fu-Shun Lai, Haochuan Shang, Yuechao Jiao, Xinyi Chen, Tianran Zhang, Xiangfeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/idm2.12172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Comprehensive Understanding of Intrinsic Contribution of Nickel Foam as a Conductive Substrate in Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4838947</link>
      <description>Umer Rashid, Youqi Zhu, Chuanbao Cao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398758006

                Using nickel foam as a substrate for electrocatalyst to report overpotential in a manuscript is a popular method in electrochemical testing or water-splitting i.e., the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, use of coated Nickel foam as substrate methodology is, in essence, not reasonable for studying the intrinsic chemistry difference of electrocatalysts. To assess water-splitting devices, Ni-foam is a valid substrate if nanoparticles are grown uniformly; however, when drop-casted ink methodology is used or there is inhomogeneous growth of nanoparticles, it becomes difficult to determine whether a particular electrocatalyst is intrinsically active or not. In order to gain a rational understanding of the electrochemical activity and overpotential findings of a specific catalyst, it is essential to recognize the limitations of Ni-foam on reflecting its intrinsic role in electrocatalytic activity. Ni-foam is therefore should not be preferred as a conductive substrate during electrochemical testing (ET). On the contrary, use of other neutral substrates like carbon fiber paper (CFP) and glassy carbon electrode (GCE) should be employed.</description>
      <author>Umer Rashid, Youqi Zhu, Chuanbao Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4838947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The synergistic effect of Ir and oxygen vacancies on Enhancing the OER performance of Surface-Reconstructed FeCo LDH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160310</link>
      <description>Xianjun Deng, Jinwei Chen, Qiuyan Chen, Yunzhe Zhou, Xinchi Liu, Jie Zhang, Gang Wang, Ruilin Wang, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397291958

                The modification of Ir or oxygen vacancies (Vo) is a strategy to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of heterogeneous nanocatalysts. However, it is crucial to further clarify the synergistic effect of Ir and Vo on the enhancement mechanism of OER performance after surface reconstruction. In this work, FeCo Layered double hydroxides (LDHs) co-modified by Ir and Vo were successfully prepared by the thermodynamically favorable galvanic replacement reaction. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy confirmed that the synergistic effect of Ir and Vo enhanced the charge transfer of FeCo LDHs. XPS spectra reveal robust interactions between Ir and FeCo LDHs. Density-functional theory further reveals that the low-oxygen-coordinated Ir (III) acts as an active site to optimize the OER rate-determining step energy barrier. As a result, Ir and Vo co-modified FeCo LDH requires only a 203 mV overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and, more importantly, operates stably at an industrial current density of 250 mA cm&#8722;2 for 312 h without degradation. This work provides new insights and avenues for understanding the enhanced performance mechanism of catalysts after surface reconstruction and for industrial scale-up production.</description>
      <author>Xianjun Deng, Jinwei Chen, Qiuyan Chen, Yunzhe Zhou, Xinchi Liu, Jie Zhang, Gang Wang, Ruilin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Molecule Oxidation Facilitated Seawater Splitting for Hydrogen Production: Opportunities and Challenges</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400258</link>
      <description>Jingwei Li, San Ping Jiang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398139264

                Direct seawater splitting is an environment&#8208;friendly and promising technology to replace freshwater electrolysis for hydrogen production. The challenge of seawater electrolysis lies in the competition between chloride oxidation reaction (CER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), as well as electrode corrosion and poisoning caused by chloride. Some small molecules have lower anodic electrocatalytic oxidation potentials compared to OER and CER, making them possible to substitute OER and/or CER in coupled electrolyzers not only to eliminate the electrode corrosion problem but also to significantly enhance the energy efficiency of seawater electrolysis. This article reviews the progress of such small molecule oxidation facilitated seawater electrolyzer. Starting with an overview of the key challenges in seawater electrolysis, this review introduces the fundamentals and advantages of the coupled seawater electrolyzers and discusses the strategies for anodic small molecule oxidation and cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction, including utilizing Cl&#8208; as a reactive medium, value&#8208;added chemical synthesis, pollutants electrooxidation, and optimizing electrolyzers. Finally, the challenges and prospects of small molecule oxidation facilitated seawater splitting are summarized, aiming to provide impetus for research and development on coupled seawater electrolysis technologies.</description>
      <author>Jingwei Li, San Ping Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mott&#8208;Schottky Construction Boosted Plasmon Thermal and Electronic Effects on the Ag/CoV&#8208;LDH Nanohybrids for Highly&#8208;efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202313057</link>
      <description>Xuyun Lu, Zhangyu Ma, Yu Chia Chang, S. C. Wang, Xiaoxuan Li, Dongdong Xu, Jianchun Bao, Ying Liu, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398131587

                Mott-Schottky construction and plasmon excitation represent two highly-efficient and closely-linked coping strategies to the high energy loss of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), but the combined effect has rarely been investigated. Herein, with Ag nanoparticles as electronic structure regulator and plasmon exciter, Ag/CoV-LDH@G nanohybrids (NHs) with Mott-Schottky heterojunction and notable plasmon effect are well-designed. Combining theoretical calculations with experiments, it was found that the Mott-Schottky construction modulates the Fermi level/energy band structure of CoV-LDH, which in turn leads to lowered d-band center (from -0.89 to -0.93), OER energy barrier (from 6.78 to 1.31 eV), and preeminent plasmon thermal/electronic effects. The thermal effect can offset the endothermic enthalpy change of OER, promote the deprotonation of *OOH, and accelerate electron transfer kinetics. Whereas the electronic effect can increase the density of charge carriers (from 0.70&#215;10</description>
      <author>Xuyun Lu, Zhangyu Ma, Yu Chia Chang, S. C. Wang, Xiaoxuan Li, Dongdong Xu, Jianchun Bao, Ying Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202313057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus Defect Mediated Electron Redistribution to Boost Anion Exchange Membrane&#8208;Based Alkaline Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400975</link>
      <description>Lili Guo, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Tong Cui, Jun Zhu, Yong Xia, Hailing Guo, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398134436

                Abstract It is of essential importance to design bifunctional electrocatalysts with excellent performance for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in seawater splitting. Herein, an approach for manipulating electron redistribution in NiCoP treated by P defect (P v ) engineering (NiCoP v @NF) is presented, exhibiting excellent catalytic activities and stability toward HER/OER in alkaline seawater solution. The P v reduces the surface electrooxidation reconfiguration energy barrier, making it easier to drive the local conversion of crystals to active oxy(hydroxide) in OER. In addition, the Ni site of NiCoP v and the Co site of NiCoOOH are the active sites for HER and OER processes, respectively. In situ generated PO 4 3&#8722; adsorbed on the catalyst surface causes spatial repulsion, preventing Cl &#8722; corrosion in seawater electrolysis. The seawater AEM electrolyzer using NiCoP v @NF couple achieves excellent performance of high activity (2.43 V at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and long&#8208;term durability (500 mA cm &#8722;2 over 110 h). The working efficiency of AEM in 1.0 M KOH is as high as 77.0% at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 with the price of per GGE H 2 as low as $ 0.87.</description>
      <author>Lili Guo, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Tong Cui, Jun Zhu, Yong Xia, Hailing Guo, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multifold nanotwin-enhanced catalytic activity of Ni-Zn-Cu for hydrazine oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174898</link>
      <description>Wei Xia, Tianyao Wang, Hongzhe Dai, Song Li, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397289293

                The hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR) plays a critical role in direct hydrazine fuel cells and presents a promising alternative to the kinetics-sluggish oxygen evolution reaction in water reduction. Engineering catalysts with high-density multifold nanotwin structures has emerged as a compelling strategy to enhance catalytic activity. However, the exploration of multifold nanotwins for HzOR applications remains absent. Herein, we report the successful synthesis of a porous Ni-Zn-Cu catalyst featuring high-density twofold and fivefold nanotwins. The Ni-Zn-Cu catalyst supported on Ni foam (Ni-Zn-Cu/Ni foam) exhibits exceptionally high catalytic activity and stability toward the HzOR, achieving a current density of 204.3 mA&#183;cm-2 at 0.0 V vs. RHE and retaining up to 89.1% after 20 hours of continuous electrolysis. Online mass spectrometer (MS) analysis indicates that the Ni-Zn-Cu coating facilitates N-N bond cleavage of N2H4. This study offers valuable insights into the development of multifold nanotwin catalysts for advancing HzOR applications.</description>
      <author>Wei Xia, Tianyao Wang, Hongzhe Dai, Song Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selectivity Study of Anodic Seawater Electrolysis Catalysts Using the Rotating Ring-Disc Electrode Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/11309.0003ecst</link>
      <description>Olivier Horner, El&#337;d Gyenge, David P. Wilkinson, ECS transactions. 113(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397011969

                Seawater Electrolysis is an exciting alternative to freshwater electrolysis; however, it suffers from a multitude of issues that must be resolved before the technology can be scaled. Corrosive hypochlorite forms at the anode of seawater electrolysis and can damage catalysts and electrolyzer components. Hypochlorite is unstable and can decay, particularly when exposed to heat and metal ions, which can lead to erroneously high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) selectivity conclusions, resulting in poor catalyst and electrolyzer component selection. In this study, we use the rotating ring-disc electrode technique to characterize the selectivity of IrO 2 , NiO, Co 3 O 4 , RuO 2 , Pt and PtRu electrocatalysts in situ at near-neutral pH (8.4) with linear scan voltammetry (LSV), potentiostatic and galvanostatic experiments. Our findings reveal that elevated temperatures are conducive to higher OER selectivity. Furthermore, when we increased the chloride concentration in the electrolyte with an IrO 2 catalyst, we observed that although the overall selectivity towards the OER reaction decreased, the OER current independently increased, indicating a synergistic relationship.</description>
      <author>Olivier Horner, El&#337;d Gyenge, David P. Wilkinson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/11309.0003ecst</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Pt dual atoms for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124214</link>
      <description>Pengfei Zhang, Mengyu Gan, Yanhui Song, Peizhi Liu, Hao&#8208;Jie Liang, Yongqing Shen, Bingshe Xu, Ting Liao, Junjie Guo, Ziqi Sun, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397048650

                While dual-atom catalysts benefiting from synergetic interatomic interactions have inspired the development of emerging catalysts, the role of atomic interactions on the catalytic selectivity and activity has yet to be clearly discovered. Herein, two-types of Pt dual-atom active sites, Pt dimers (2Pt) with an interatomic distance of 2.6 &#197; and Pt pairs (Pt2) at a distance of 0.9 &#197;, are fabricated by anchoring onto cationic vacancy-rich nickel-based hydroxide (Pt@NiFeCo-E). It reveals that 2Pt sites are favorable for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) while Pt2 sites are active towards oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The coexistence of two types of Pt dual atoms endows the bifunctional activity, which reached an overpotential of 14 mV@10 mA cm&#8722;2 for HER, an overpotential of 234 mV@100 mA cm&#8722;2 for OER, and an effective overall water splitting reaction (OWS) in alkaline at an overpotential of 1.42 V to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and at 100 mA cm&#8722;2 for 50 h. This work not only clarifies a new mechanism in manipulating the selectivity of dual-atom catalysts via controlling the interatomic distance, but also paves a pathway for designing novel high-efficient bifunctional catalysts.</description>
      <author>Pengfei Zhang, Mengyu Gan, Yanhui Song, Peizhi Liu, Hao&#8208;Jie Liang, Yongqing Shen, Bingshe Xu, Ting Liao, Junjie Guo, Ziqi Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom catalysts with anion center toward oxygen electrocatalysis based on the conductive 1T-HfTe2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115548</link>
      <description>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397292015

                Advancing efficient catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) or oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is imperative for commercializing emerging energy devices. Using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we propose doping different transition metal (TM) atoms to regulate the electronic structures of the two-dimensional 1T-HfTe2 monolayer to achieve bifunctional catalysis for the ORR/OER. Due to the small electronegativity of the Hf atom, we found the doped TMs can generally form anion centers by accepting abundant charges from the Hf interlayer. At the same time, the highly conductive 1T-HfTe2 contributes to the charge transfer between the active center and the reaction intermediates, rendering the designed SACs the tunable activity for the reactions. By comparing the theoretical overpotentials of ORR and OER on 15 single-atom catalysts (SACs), Pt-doped system exhibits excellent catalytic activity for both ORR and OER, outperforming the traditional Pt(1 1 1) and RuO2(1 1 0) catalysts. Based on the charge transfer mechanism, we clarified that the doped TM atoms act as a 'bridge' to transfer the electrons from the substrate to the reaction intermediates, thereby effectively contributing to the improvement of catalytic activity. In summary, our study shows that, by doping appropriate TM atoms, the intrinsic inert HfTe2 can be activated toward efficient ORR/OER. This could provide some guidance for the design of new two-dimensional ORR/OER bifunctional catalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous TiN-based ceramic electrode with N-modified Co-based Nanorods/TiN heterointerfaces for efficient overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234722</link>
      <description>Chuntian Tan, Haisen Huang, Feihong Wang, Nianwang Ke, Anding Huang, Wangzhong Tang, Luyuan Hao, Liangjun Yin, Xin Xu, Yuxi Xian, Simeon Agathopoulos, Journal of power sources. 610(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398154955

                The development of high-performance electrocatalytic electrodes for overall water splitting is a crucial issue to realize renewable hydrogen production. This paper presents the in situ growth of N-modified Co-based nanorods on porous TiN ceramic membranes using the hydrothermal method and thermal NH3 treatment, resulting in a novel self-supported electrocatalytic electrode with abundant heterointerfaces, denoted as NCTN-x-y (x: nitridation temperature; y: nitridation time). In the alkaline medium (1 M KOH), the NCTN-350-2 electrode displays the best hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity (&#414;10 = 66 mV), and the NCTN-250-3 electrode manifests the best oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance (&#414;10 = 270 mV). Accordingly, these two electrodes comprise an electrolyzer, which features a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at a low cell voltage of 1.63 V. The good electrocatalytic performance can be attributed to the abundant heterointerfaces formed between the porous TiN ceramic membrane and the N-modified Co-based nanorods, in conjunction with the hierarchical pore structure of the TiN ceramic membrane. Theoretical calculations identify that the construction of heterointerfaces modulates the electronic structure of active sites, thereby promoting the dissociation of H2O, optimizing the H* adsorption energy (&#916;GH*), and accelerating the reaction kinetics, which ultimately improve the electrocatalytic activity of electrode.</description>
      <author>Chuntian Tan, Haisen Huang, Feihong Wang, Nianwang Ke, Anding Huang, Wangzhong Tang, Luyuan Hao, Liangjun Yin, Xin Xu, Yuxi Xian, Simeon Agathopoulos</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;MOF&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;Derived Iron&#8208;Cobalt Phosphide Nanoframe as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12747</link>
      <description>Yanqi Yuan, Kun Wang, Boan Zhong, Dongkun Yu, Fei Ye, Jing Liu, Joydeep Dutta, Peng Zhang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398216964

                Transition metal phosphides (TMPs) have emerged as an alternative to precious metals as efficient and low&#8208;cost catalysts for water electrolysis. Elemental doping and morphology control are effective approaches to further improve the performance of TMPs. Herein, Fe&#8208;doped CoP nanoframes (Fe&#8208;CoP NFs) with specific open cage configuration were designed and synthesized. The unique nano&#8208;framework structured Fe&#8208;CoP material shows overpotentials of only 255 and 122 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), respectively, overwhelming most transition metal phosphides. For overall water splitting, the cell voltage is 1.65 V for Fe&#8208;CoP NFs at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , much superior to what is observed for the classical nanocubic structures. Fe&#8208;CoP NFs show no activity degradation up to 100 h which contrasts sharply with the rapidly decaying performance of noble metal catalyst reference. The superior electrocatalytic performance of Fe&#8208;CoP NFs due to abundant accessible active sites, reduced kinetic energy barrier, and preferable *O&#8208;containing intermediate adsorption is demonstrated through experimental observations and theoretical calculations. Our findings could provide a potential method for the preparation of multifunctional material with hollow structures and offer more hopeful prospects for obtaining efficient earth&#8208;abundant catalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yanqi Yuan, Kun Wang, Boan Zhong, Dongkun Yu, Fei Ye, Jing Liu, Joydeep Dutta, Peng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Performance Limitation of Liquid Alkaline Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4fe6</link>
      <description>Guanzhi Wang, Andrew W. Tricker, Jin Yi Lang, Jianxin Wang, Iryna V. Zenyuk, Di&#8208;Jia Liu, Rangachary Mukundan, Ping Xiong, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398243873

                Abstract Liquid alkaline water electrolyzers (LAWEs), being the most commercially mature electrolysis technology, play a pivotal role in large-scale hydrogen production. However, LAWEs suffer from low operational efficiency, primarily due to un-optimized electrode structure and chemical compositions. Thus, we investigated how various electrode configurations could impact LAWE performance. Our results show that Ni felt electrodes outperform the conventional Ni foam thanks to improved electrochemical active surface area (ECSA) and preferred electrode surface structure that minimizes the micro-gaps in between the electrode and separator. By comparing the stainless steel (SS) felt electrodes with Ni felt electrodes, SS not only shows better oxygen evolution reaction activity but also improved hydrogen evolution reaction activity, which is less studied in the literature. We also show that a bilayer structure with small pore radius facing the separator could further improve LAWE performance by further optimizing interfacial contact between electrode and separator. These findings enable LAWEs to sustain 2 A cm-2 at 2.2 V and operate steadily at 1 A cm-2 for nearly 600 h with negligible performance decay. Our studies establish criteria for selecting electrodes to achieve high-performance LAWE and, in turn, expedite the adoption of LAWEs in hydrogen production and the transition towards low-carbon economies.</description>
      <author>Guanzhi Wang, Andrew W. Tricker, Jin Yi Lang, Jianxin Wang, Iryna V. Zenyuk, Di&#8208;Jia Liu, Rangachary Mukundan, Ping Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4fe6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of Mo&#8208;doped Ni&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P/Fe&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;P&#8208;V Multiheterostructure for Efficient Dual&#8208;pH Hydrogen Evolution and Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400397</link>
      <description>Xiaodong Xu, Kun Guo, Ju&#8208;Feng Sun, Xinyue Yu, Xiangyang Miao, Wenbo Lu, Lifang Jiao, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398177340

                Abstract Developing highly effective transition metal&#8208;based bifunctional electrocatalysts remains a tremendously challenging task for large&#8208;scale overall water splitting. Herein, a multiheterostructured Mo&#8208;doped Ni 2 P/Fe x P electrocatalyst on NiFe foam with P vacancy (denoted as Mo&#9472;Ni 2 P/Fe x P&#8208;V/NFF) is developed to serve as an efficient dual&#8208;pH electrocatalyst. Due to the synergistic effect of multiple strategies (heteroatom doping, heterointerface, and P vacancy), the Mo&#9472;Ni 2 P/Fe x P&#8208;V/NFF possesses remarkable hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalytic activity in alkaline/acidic and excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, along with encouraging durability. The mechanisms of improved electrocatalytic activity combining multicharacterizations and density functional theory (DFT) calculations are elucidated. Specifically, X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure experimental analysis confirms that the Mo doping can optimize the electronic structure of electrocatalyst. In situ Raman spectroscopy demonstrates that the evolved oxyhydroxides are the real active substances for the OER. DFT calculations reveal that the conductivity of as&#8208;prepared samples can be enhanced through multiple strategy synergy. Moreover, in the HER process, multiple strategies can not only reduce the hydrogen binding energy to near zero but also enhance the H 2 O dissociation and *OH desorption. In the OER process, DFT calculations also verify that Mo doping and interface engineering can optimize the adsorption of the rate&#8208;determining step, achieving the lowest theoretical overpotential.</description>
      <author>Xiaodong Xu, Kun Guo, Ju&#8208;Feng Sun, Xinyue Yu, Xiangyang Miao, Wenbo Lu, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202400397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large-area ultrathin 2D Co(OH)2 nanosheets: A bifunctional electrode material for supercapacitor and water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101608</link>
      <description>Pallavi Bhaktapralhad Jagdale, Sayali Ashok Patil, Amanda Sfeir, Narad Barman, Asif Iqbal, S&#233;bastien Royer, Ranjit Thapa, Akshaya K. Samal, Debasis Ghosh, Manav Saxena, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398694170

                Ultrathin film of active materials having thickness &lt;5 nm emerged as a promising candidate for miniaturized energy storage and conversion devices. However, the small lateral size restricts its real device applications. Herein, we report large area, 2D, ultrathin (thickness: 4.3&#177;0.3 nm) Co(OH)2 nanosheets as bi-functional electrode material for supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction developed by Ionic layer epitaxy (ILE) method at the water-air interface. The symmetric supercapacitor device exhibited excellent volumetric capacitance of 2313 F cm-3 at 0.4 mA cm-2 current density. Additionally, it exhibited a remarkable volumetric energy density of 0.205 Wh cm-3 at a power density of 0.145 W cm-3, which is better than reported 2D electrode materials. Furthermore, the Co(OH)2 ultrathin-film electrodes showed improved OER electrocatalytic activity with low overpotential (&#414;10, 330 mV) and Tafel slope (47 mV dec-1). The structural and morphological investigations after long-term operations show substantial stability of the electrode material. The theoretical investigations of electronic structures, quantum capacitance, and free energy profiles for the OER mechanism corroborate the experimental results.</description>
      <author>Pallavi Bhaktapralhad Jagdale, Sayali Ashok Patil, Amanda Sfeir, Narad Barman, Asif Iqbal, S&#233;bastien Royer, Ranjit Thapa, Akshaya K. Samal, Debasis Ghosh, Manav Saxena</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long&#8208;Lasting Hybrid Seawater Electrolysis Enabled by Anodic Mass Transport Intensification for Energy&#8208;Saving Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407601</link>
      <description>Dongtong He, Pengju Yang, Kaizhou Yang, Jieshan Qiu, Zhiyu Wang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398236738

                Abstract Hybrid water electrolysis offers a groundbreaking approach to energy&#8208;saving hydrogen production by utilizing thermodynamically favorable and value&#8208;added reactions to replace sluggish anodic oxygen evolution in overall water splitting. However, numerous anodic processes generate intermediates or products incompatible with aqueous environments, thereby degrading anodic performance to limit the efficiency and durability of hybrid water electrolysis. Herein, this difficulty is addressed by applying anodic mass transport intensification in conjunction with catalyst engineering, realizing a long&#8208;lasting hybrid seawater electrolysis coupling sulfion oxidation reaction (SOR) for efficient hydrogen production below 1.2 V at an industrial&#8208;level current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . An exceptional longevity of 2000 h is achieved for the electrolysis by eliminating anode passivation by sulfur deposition during SOR, a general concern in the sulfur&#8208;involved industrial sector. This technology cut the electricity expense of hydrogen production to 2.80 kWh m &#8722;3 H 2 , undercutting alkaline water electrolysis by 34.9&#8211;51.1%. Simultaneously, fast upcycling of sulfion pollutants to value&#8208;added sulfur is achieved to add additional economic and environmental profits, enabling hydrogen production at a midpoint expense ($ 0.93) of the United States Department of Energy's 2026 target ($ 2.0) for the cost per gallon of gasoline&#8208;equivalent.</description>
      <author>Dongtong He, Pengju Yang, Kaizhou Yang, Jieshan Qiu, Zhiyu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vertically Oriented FeNiO Nanosheet Array for Urea and Water Electrolysis at Industrial-Scale Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00591</link>
      <description>Harsh K. Thakkar, Krishna H. Modi, Kinjal K. Joshi, Gopala Ram Bhadu, Sohel Siraj, Parikshit Sahatiya, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397022590

                In addressing the challenging quest for an efficient electrocatalyst in electrochemical water splitting, we demonstrate an Fe-doped NiO nanosheet array anchored on nickel foam synthesized via a two-step process. Demonstrating exceptional performance in an alkaline electrolyte, FeNiO catalysts exhibit the oxygen evolution reaction with a low potential of 1.52 V vs RHE and the urea oxidation reaction of 1.32 V vs RHE @ 10 mA/cm2. The bifunctional electrolyzer generates 10 mA/cm2 current at 1.95 V for water and 1.59 V for urea electrolysis at ambient temperature. Promisingly, the FeNiO catalyst based electrolyzer generates hydrogen at an industrial-scale current density of 400 mA/cm2 at a cell voltage of just 1.91 V in concentrated alkaline electrolyte and elevated temperature (80 &#176;C) due to the dimensionally stable and robust behavior of the self-supported catalyst. The activation energy for alkaline water electrolysis is found to be 52 kJ/mol. The present catalysts also demonstrate stable performance at 300 mA/cm2 in 4 M KOH electrolyte at 50 &#176;C for more than 20 h. The synergy induced by Fe doping into NiO activates catalytic sites, expediting charge transfer and reaction kinetics. The present research report highlights the potential of catalysts as a practical and cost-effective approach for green hydrogen production via water splitting.</description>
      <author>Harsh K. Thakkar, Krishna H. Modi, Kinjal K. Joshi, Gopala Ram Bhadu, Sohel Siraj, Parikshit Sahatiya, Pratik M. Pataniya, C.K. Sumesh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron&#8208;Induced Interstitial Effects Drive Water Oxidation on Ordered Ir&#8208;B Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407577</link>
      <description>Chen Ding, Ruohan Yu, Hongyu Zhao, Jixiang Jiao, Xueqin Mu, Jiaguo Yu, Shichun Mu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398173866

                Interstitial filling of light atoms strongly affects the electronic structure and adsorption properties of the parent catalyst due to ligand and ensemble effects. Different from the conventional doping and surface modification, constructing ordered intermetallic structures is more promising to overcome the dissolution and reconstruction of active sites through strong interactions generated by atomic periodic arrangement, achieving joint improvement in catalytic activity and stability. However, for tightly arranged metal lattices, such as iridium (Ir), obtaining ordered filling atoms and further unveiling their interstitial effects are still limited by highly activated processes. Herein, we report a high&#8208;temperature molten salt assisted strategy to form the intermetallic Ir&#8208;B compounds (IrB1.1) with ordered filling by light boron (B) atoms. The B residing in the interstitial lattice of Ir constitutes favorable adsorption surfaces through a donor&#8208;acceptor architecture, which has an optimal free energy uphill in rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), resulting in enhanced activity. Meanwhile, the strong coupling of Ir&#8208;B structural units suppresses the demetallation and reconstruction behavior of Ir, ensuring catalytic stability. Such B&#8208;induced interstitial effects endow IrB1.1 with higher OER performance than commercial IrO2, which is further validated in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs).</description>
      <author>Chen Ding, Ruohan Yu, Hongyu Zhao, Jixiang Jiao, Xueqin Mu, Jiaguo Yu, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407577</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron&#8208;Induced Interstitial Effects Drive Water Oxidation on Ordered Ir&#8208;B Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407577</link>
      <description>Ding Chen, Ruohan Yu, Hongyu Zhao, Jixiang Jiao, Xueqin Mu, Jiaguo Yu, Shichun Mu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398164613

                Interstitial filling of light atoms strongly affects the electronic structure and adsorption properties of the parent catalyst due to ligand and ensemble effects. Different from the conventional doping and surface modification, constructing ordered intermetallic structures is more promising to overcome the dissolution and reconstruction of active sites through strong interactions generated by atomic periodic arrangement, achieving joint improvement in catalytic activity and stability. However, for tightly arranged metal lattices, such as iridium (Ir), obtaining ordered filling atoms and further unveiling their interstitial effects are still limited by highly activated processes. Herein, we report a high-temperature molten salt assisted strategy to form the intermetallic Ir-B compounds (IrB1.1) with ordered filling by light boron (B) atoms. The B residing in the interstitial lattice of Ir constitutes favorable adsorption surfaces through a donor-acceptor architecture, which has an optimal free energy uphill in rate-determining step (RDS) of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), resulting in enhanced activity. Meanwhile, the strong coupling of Ir-B structural units suppresses the demetallation and reconstruction behavior of Ir, ensuring catalytic stability. Such B-induced interstitial effects endow IrB1.1 with higher OER performance than commercial IrO2, which is further validated in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs).</description>
      <author>Ding Chen, Ruohan Yu, Hongyu Zhao, Jixiang Jiao, Xueqin Mu, Jiaguo Yu, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407577</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Nickel&#8208;Based Materials from Spent NiMH Batteries for Electrochemical Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400135</link>
      <description>Ikhbayar Batsukh, Munkhbaatar Adiya, Lkhagvajav Sarantuya, G. Sevjidsuren, Mungunshagai Gansukh, Munkhbayar Batmunkh, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398209335

                Abstract In this work, we explored the recovering possibilities of nickel&#8208;based products from the cathode materials of spent nickel&#8208;metal hydride (NiMH) batteries collected from car repair centers in Mongolia. Specifically, nickel&#8208;based by&#8208;products such as metallic nickel, Ni microparticles, nickel oxide, nickel chloride, and betta&#8208;phase ( &#946; ) nickel hydroxide powders are successfully produced. X&#8208;ray diffraction patterns suggested that all samples show high crystallinity and phase purity. Ni microparticles were recovered using a chemical reduction method from a leachate solution prepared by dissolving the cathode of the spent NiMH battery in hydrochloric acid. Notably, &#946; &#8208;Ni(OH)&#8322; displayed two redox peaks in KOH electrolyte solution, suggesting that it has excellent electrochemical potential and can be reused for the fabrication of new NiMH batteries. To validate the electrochemical performances, we examined the catalytic activity of nickel microparticles as a catalyst for the degradation of Congo red (CR) dye and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The reduction reaction rate of CR dye in the presence of a nickel catalyst was 2.17&#215;10 &#8722;3 s &#8722;1 , significantly higher than the control experiment without a nickel catalyst. These results provide possible solutions for developing sustainable battery systems by recovering different nickel&#8208;based products from spent NiMH batteries.</description>
      <author>Ikhbayar Batsukh, Munkhbaatar Adiya, Lkhagvajav Sarantuya, G. Sevjidsuren, Mungunshagai Gansukh, Munkhbayar Batmunkh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Density Asymmetric Iron Dual-Atom Sites for Efficient and Ultra-Stable Electrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4217753/v1</link>
      <description>Wenxing Chen, Lili Zhang, Jianxiao Wang, Huishan Shang, Zhiyi Sun, Zihao Wei, Jingtao Wang, Yuanting Lei, Xiaochen Wang, Dan Wang, Yafei Zhao, Zhao-Yan Sun, Fang Zhang, Xiang Xu, Bing Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397021567

                Abstract Double-atom catalysts (DACs) have open up novel paradigms in the field of rapidly developing atomic catalysis because of their great potential to promote catalytic performances in various reaction systems. However, increasing the loading and extending the service life of metal active centers represents a grand challenge for the efficient utilization of DACs. Here, we rationally design asymmetric nitrogen, sulfur-coordinated diatomic iron centers on highly defective nitrogen-doped carbon nanosheets (denoted as A-Fe2S1N5/SNC, A: asymmetric), which possesses the atomic configuration of N2S1Fe-FeN3 moiety. The abundant defects and low-electronegativity heteroatoms in the carbon-based framework endow the A-Fe2S1N5/SNC with a high loading of 6.72 wt%. Furthermore, the A-Fe2S1N5/SNC demonstrates an ultra-low overpotential of 193 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at 10 mA cm&#8722; 2, outperforming the commercial RuO2 catalysts. In addition, the A-Fe2S1N5/SNC exhibits extraordinary stability, maintaining &gt; 97% activity for over 2000 hours during the OER process. This work provides a practical scheme for simultaneously balancing activity and stability of DACs toward electrocatalysis applications.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Chen, Lili Zhang, Jianxiao Wang, Huishan Shang, Zhiyi Sun, Zihao Wei, Jingtao Wang, Yuanting Lei, Xiaochen Wang, Dan Wang, Yafei Zhao, Zhao-Yan Sun, Fang Zhang, Xiang Xu, Bing Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4217753/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disinfection of Irrigation Water using Titanium Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/labqlv</link>
      <description>Geletu Qing, Mojtaba Abolhassani, Raheleh Daneshpour, Shelby L. Foster, Marty Matlock, Greg Thoma, Lauren F. Greenlee, Harvard Dataverse. None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4398746206

                The microbiological safety of irrigation water is critical to the prevention of fresh produce contamination with human pathogens. This work reports on the electrochemical disinfection of natural irrigation water using an undivided batch cell assembled with titanium (Ti) electrodes as both anode and cathode. Although Ti is considered an inactive electrode material for most applications due to the presence of an oxide film on the surface, we show here that it can efficiently catalyze the electrochemical oxidation of a few ppm of chloride ions in natural irrigation water to free chlorine species, which in turn enable fast disinfection. Disinfection experiments were performed by applying a polarity-reversing direct current between the two Ti electrodes. Compared to applying a polarity-constant direct current, the polarity-reversal technique effectively inhibited extensive oxidation of the Ti electrode surface as indicated by a lower oxide/hydroxide content on the electrode surface, thus providing excellent stability during electrolysis. The natural irrigation water was collected from the Waiahole Ditch Irrigation System in Hawaii. The naturally occurring concentration of chloride in the water was 1.84 mg/L and no other chemicals were added. E. coli K12 ER2738 was selected as a model bacterium to evaluate the electrochemical cell&#8217;s disinfection capability. The applied current density was varied between 0 mA/cm2 and 2 mA/cm2, and the half-period (T/2) of the polarity-reversing direct current was varied between 5 s and 60 s. The best disinfection performance was achieved at 2 mA/cm2 and T/2 = 10 s, requiring only 5 min of treatment for the complete disinfection of E. coli (4-log reduction). The trends in the concentration of free and total chlorine in the solution matched very well with those of the disinfection efficiency, suggesting that E. coli was inactivated by free chlorine species electrogenerated at the Ti electrodes. Hydrogen peroxide, short-lived oxidants, and direct electron transfer most likely had minor contributions to the disinfection process. The presence of a volcano-shaped dependence of the free and total chlorine concentration and disinfection efficiency on T/2 suggests that the chloride oxidation activity of the Ti electrode was closely related to the oxidation state (or the thickness of the oxide layer) of the electrode surface, i.e., there exists an optimal oxide layer thickness at which the Ti electrode shows the highest electrocatalytic activity toward chloride oxidation. During the disinfection experiment, disinfection byproducts (DBPs) of chlorate, bromodichloromethane, dibromochloromethane, and bromoform were not detected in the solution. Chloroform was first seen in the solution at 10 min (2.5 &#956;g/L), and then its concentration increased to 9.0 &#956;g/L at 20 min. These values are significantly lower than recommendations for drinking water, and the timeframe of chloroform production suggests a 5 min disinfection treatment avoids significant DBP formation. As a comparison, Pt/Ti electrodes prepared by electrodeposition showed negligible disinfection at 2 mA/cm2, but the disinfection efficiency increased dramatically at 4 mA/cm2 and 6 mA/cm2. This phenomenon was most likely due to the Pt catalyst&#8217;s high activity, readily catalyzing side reactions such as oxygen evolution and oxidation of organic matter in the natural irrigation water. The Ti electrodes consumed less electrical energy than the Pt/Ti electrodes because they needed a lower current density to achieve similar disinfection efficiency. The current work demonstrates that the Ti electrode electrochemical cell can provide an efficient, robust, and cost-effective solution to irrigation water disinfection, and thus is well suited for agriculture sector applications.</description>
      <author>Geletu Qing, Mojtaba Abolhassani, Raheleh Daneshpour, Shelby L. Foster, Marty Matlock, Greg Thoma, Lauren F. Greenlee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/labqlv</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Formation Mechanism of Reactive Oxygen Species in the Interface Reaction of SO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on Hematite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.3c10683</link>
      <description>Yongcheng Jia, Qingxia Ma, Liu Yuan, Chunyan Zhang, Tianzeng Chen, Peng Zhang, Biwu Chu, Hong He, Environmental science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398167158

                The interplay between sulfur and iron holds significant importance in their atmospheric cycle, yet a complete understanding of their coupling mechanism remains elusive. This investigation delves comprehensively into the evolution of reactive oxygen species (ROS) during the interfacial reactions involving sulfur dioxide (SO</description>
      <author>Yongcheng Jia, Qingxia Ma, Liu Yuan, Chunyan Zhang, Tianzeng Chen, Peng Zhang, Biwu Chu, Hong He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.3c10683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Devices for monitoring oenological processes: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.measurement.2024.114922</link>
      <description>Juan Jos&#233; Gallego-Mart&#237;nez, Eduardo Ca&#241;ete-Carmona, Andr&#233;s Gersnoviez, Mar&#237;a Brox, Juan J. S&#225;nchez-Gil, Cristian Mart&#237;n-Fern&#225;ndez, Juan J. Moreno, Measurement. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398146463

                Monitoring must be a basic element in oenological processes, assuring the oenologist's confidence in the supervision of the different processes. In this article, an analysis was carried out on all the works reported in the literature for the monitoring of different wine parameters in each phase. As described in the paper, artificial sensors have been developed to monitor the evolution of the fermentation and maceration phases. Similarly, in the ageing phase, other authors have developed different systems to monitor the evolution of the wine colour and oxygen. Within the particular case of biological ageing, not many developments have been found to control it. Given the scarcity of developments in this field, it would be necessary to propose a greater number of studies in this field.</description>
      <author>Juan Jos&#233; Gallego-Mart&#237;nez, Eduardo Ca&#241;ete-Carmona, Andr&#233;s Gersnoviez, Mar&#237;a Brox, Juan J. S&#225;nchez-Gil, Cristian Mart&#237;n-Fern&#225;ndez, Juan J. Moreno</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.measurement.2024.114922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and seasonal characteristics of organic vapors in urban Beijing: insights from Vocus-PTR measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1325</link>
      <description>Zhaojin An, Rujing Yin, Xinyan Zhao, Xiaoxiao Li, Ye Yuan, Jinxin Guo, Yuyang Li, X. Li, Dandan Li, Yaowei Li, Dongbin Wang, Chao Yan, Kebin He, Douglas R. Worsnop, Frank N. Keutsch, Jingkun Jiang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398219656

                Abstract. Understanding the compositions and evolution of atmospheric organic vapors is crucial for exploring their impact on air quality. However, the molecular and seasonal characteristics of organic vapors in urban areas, with complex anthropogenic emissions and high variability, remain inadequately understood. In this study, we conducted measurements in urban Beijing during 2021&#8211;2022 covering four seasons using a Vocus-PTR, an improved Proton Transfer Reaction-Mass Spectrometry (PTR-MS). During the measurement period, a total of 895 peaks are observed, and 543 of them can be assigned to formulas. The contribution of CxHyOz species is most significant, which compose up to 53.7 % of the number and 76.0 % of the mass of total organics. With enhanced sensitivity and mass resolution, various sub-ppt level species and organics with multiple oxygens (&#8805;3) were discovered. When counting the species number, 42.2 % of the organics measured are at sub-ppt level and 37.8 % of the species contain 3&#8211;8 oxygens. Organic vapors with multiple oxygens mainly consist of intermediate volatility and semi-volatile compounds, and many of them are found to be the multi-generational oxidation products of various volatile organic precursors. In summer, the fast photooxidation process generates organic vapors with multiple oxygens, and leads to an increase in both their concentration and proportion. While in other seasons, the variations of organic vapors with multiple oxygens are closely correlated with those of organic vapors with 1&#8211;2 oxygens, which could be heavily influenced by primary emissions. Organic vapors with low oxygen content (&#8804; 2 oxygens) are comparable to the results obtained by traditional PTR-MS measurements in both urban Beijing and neighboring regions.</description>
      <author>Zhaojin An, Rujing Yin, Xinyan Zhao, Xiaoxiao Li, Ye Yuan, Jinxin Guo, Yuyang Li, X. Li, Dandan Li, Yaowei Li, Dongbin Wang, Chao Yan, Kebin He, Douglas R. Worsnop, Frank N. Keutsch, Jingkun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emergence and evolution of heterocyte glycolipid biosynthesis enabled specialized nitrogen fixation in cyanobacteria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.17.594646</link>
      <description>Ruth P&#233;rez Gallego, F. A. Bastiaan von Meijenfeldt, Nicole J. Bale, Jaap S. Sinninghe Damst&#233;, Laura Villanueva, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397047626

                Paleontological and phylogenomic observations have shed light on the evolution of cyanobacteria. Nevertheless, the emergence of heterocytes, specialized cells for nitrogen fixation, remains unclear. Heterocytes are surrounded by heterocyte glycolipids (HGs), which contribute to protection of the nitrogenase enzyme from oxygen. Here, by comprehensive HG identification and screening of HG biosynthesis genes throughout cyanobacteria, we identify HG analogs produced by specific and distantly related non-heterocytous cyanobacteria. These structurally less complex molecules probably acted as precursors of HGs, suggesting that HGs arose after a genomic reorganization and expansion of ancestral biosynthetic machinery, enabling the rise of cyanobacterial heterocytes in an increasingly oxygenated atmosphere. Subsequently, HG chemical structure evolved convergently in response to environmental pressures. Our results open a new chapter in the potential use of diagenetic products of HGs and HG analogs as fossils for reconstructing the evolution of multicellularity and division of labor in cyanobacteria.</description>
      <author>Ruth P&#233;rez Gallego, F. A. Bastiaan von Meijenfeldt, Nicole J. Bale, Jaap S. Sinninghe Damst&#233;, Laura Villanueva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.17.594646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Realisation of a key step in the evolution of C4 photosynthesis in rice by genome editing.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.21.595093</link>
      <description>Jay Jethva, Florian Hahn, R. Giuliani, Niels Peeters, Asaph B. Cousins, Steven Kelly, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398175033

                C4 photosynthesis is a repeatedly evolved adaptation to photosynthesis that functions to reduce energy loss from photorespiration. The recurrent evolution of this adaptation is achieved through changes in the expression and localisation of several enzymes and transporters that are conventionally used in non-photosynthetic metabolism. These alterations result in the establishment of a biochemical CO2 pump that increases the concentration of CO2 around rubisco in a cellular environment where rubisco is protected from oxygen thus preventing the occurrence of photorespiration. A key step in the evolution of C4 photosynthesis is the change in subcellular localisation of carbonic anhydrase (CA) activity from the mesophyll cell chloroplast to the cytosol, where it catalyzes the first biochemical step of the C4 pathway. Here, we achieve this key step in C4 evolution in the C3 plant Oryza sativa (rice) using genome editing. We show that editing the chloroplast transit peptide of the primary CA isoform in the leaf results in relocalisation of leaf CA activity from the chloroplast to the cytosol. Through analysis of fluorescence induction kinetics in these CA relocalisation lines we uncover a role a new role for chloroplast CA in photosynthetic induction. We also reveal that relocalisation of CA activity to the cytosol causes no detectable perturbation to plant growth or leaf-level CO2 assimilation. Collectively, this work uncovers a novel role for chloroplast CA in C3 plants, and demonstrates that it is possible to achieve a key step in the evolution of C4 photosynthesis by genome editing.</description>
      <author>Jay Jethva, Florian Hahn, R. Giuliani, Niels Peeters, Asaph B. Cousins, Steven Kelly</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.21.595093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antibiotic Intermediates and Antibiotics Synergistically Promote the Development of Multiple Antibiotic Resistance in Antibiotic Production Wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4829342</link>
      <description>Ming Sun, Yanyan Zhang, B. Li, Xin Yuan, Jiane Zuo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397294331

                Antibiotic resistance (AR) is a major public health concern. Antibiotic intermediates (AIs) used in the production of semisynthetic antibiotics have the same bioactive structure as parent antibiotics and synthetic antibiotic production wastewater usually contains high concentrations of residual AIs; however, the effects of AIs and their interactive effects with antibiotics on the emergence of AR are unknown. In this study, antibiotic-sensitive E. coli K12 was exposed to five types of &#946;-lactam AIs and their parent antibiotic ampicillin to analyze their impact on the evolution of multiple AR. The results indicated that AI 6-APA inhibits bacterial growth and stimulates the production of reactive oxygen species, as well as induces AR and antibiotic persistence like the parent antibiotic AMP. Combined exposure to 6-APA and AMP synergistically stimulated the induction of multiple AR and antibiotic persistence. The resistance mutation frequency increased up to 6.1&#215;106-fold under combined exposure and the combination index reached 1326.5, indicating a strong synergy of 6-APA and AMP. Phenotypic and genotypic analyses revealed that these effects were associated with the overproduction of reactive oxygen species, enhanced stress response signatures, and activation of efflux pumps. These findings provide evidence and mechanistic insights into AR induction by AIs in antibiotic production wastewater.</description>
      <author>Ming Sun, Yanyan Zhang, B. Li, Xin Yuan, Jiane Zuo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4829342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A-type Tonian Granite in the Northwest of the Gavi&#227;o Block: Record of within-plate magmatism precursor to the continental rifting of the S&#227;o Francisco paleoplate?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsames.2024.104948</link>
      <description>Jos&#233; Alberto Rodrigues do Vale, Evilarde Carvalho Uch&#244;a Filho, Nilo Costa Pedrosa, Francisco Rubens de Sousa, Renato de Assis Barros, Ciro Duarte de Carvalho, Magno de S&#225; Freitas, Eduardo Soares de Rezende, Douglas Almeida Silveira, Journal of South American earth sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397048671

                The Early Tonian period in the S&#227;o Francisco Craton represents the development of an intracontinental rift across the northern and central Espinha&#231;o regions, playing a crucial role in understanding the tectonic evolution of the Neoproterozoic Period within this craton and its adjacent orogens. This rift is associated with the breakup of the S&#227;o Francisco paleoplate, marked by the formation of several rifts, some of which were aborted (e.g. Santo Onofre Rift), and magmatism associated. Field investigations, coupled with petrographic, lithogeochemical, and U-Pb geochronological data of the Serra do Meio Suite, elucidate key characteristics and offer significant insights into the Tonian tectonic evolution of the S&#227;o Francisco Craton and its relationship with Santo Onofre Rift. The suite comprises metagranitoids exhibiting a mineralogical composition spanning from alkali-feldspar granites to granites and its petrogenesis and tectonic characteristics reveal an alkaline to calc-alkalic signature, exhibiting extreme ferroan geochemistry and indications of moderate to high oxygen fugacity. Pressure estimations suggest low-pressure conditions during magma crystallization, implying shallow crustal emplacement. The suite's evolution involves complex petrogenetic processes, likely influenced by fractional crystallization and contamination by country rocks from a quartz-feldspathic crustal source, as well as a possible contribution from juvenile tholeiitic mantle sources associated with rift environments, showcasing a signature typical of A1-type granite. The U-Pb SHRIMP age, determined as 930 &#177; 2 Ma (MSWD = 0.34), is interpreted as the crystallization age of the rock and allows us to connect it to the opening of the Santo Onofre-Maca&#250;bas Rift in the S&#227;o Francisco Craton.</description>
      <author>Jos&#233; Alberto Rodrigues do Vale, Evilarde Carvalho Uch&#244;a Filho, Nilo Costa Pedrosa, Francisco Rubens de Sousa, Renato de Assis Barros, Ciro Duarte de Carvalho, Magno de S&#225; Freitas, Eduardo Soares de Rezende, Douglas Almeida Silveira</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jsames.2024.104948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Rechargeable Li&#8208;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Battery Performances by Tailoring Oxygen Defects on Li&#8208;Ni&#8208;Co&#8208;Mn Multi&#8208;Metal Oxide Catalysts Recycled from Spent Ternary Lithium&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402892</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Feng Ningning, Shuang Zhang, Yang Liu, Yapeng Zhang, Jing Du, Senlin Tian, Qun Zhao, Gang Yang, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397011778

                Abstract Rechargeable Li&#8208;CO 2 batteries are considered as a promising carbon&#8208;neutral energy storage technology owing to their ultra&#8208;high energy density and efficient CO 2 capture capability. However, the sluggish CO 2 reduction/evolution kinetics impedes their practical application, which leads to huge overpotentials and poor cyclability. Multi&#8208;element transit metal oxides (TMOs) are demonstrated as effective cathodic catalysts for Li&#8208;CO 2 batteries. But there are no reports on the integration of defect engineering on multi&#8208;element TMOs. Herein, the oxygen vacancy&#8208;bearing Li&#8208;Ni&#8208;Co&#8208;Mn multi&#8208;oxide (Re&#8208;NCM&#8208;H3) catalyst with the &#945; &#8208;NaFeO 2 &#8208;type structure is first fabricated by annealing the NiCoMn precursor that derived from spent ternary LiNi 0.8 Co 0.1 Mn 0.1 O 2 cathode, in H 2 at 300 &#176;C. As demonstrated by experimental results and theory calculations, the introduction of moderate oxygen vacancy has optimized electronic state near the Fermi level (E f ), eventually improving CO 2 adsorption and charge transfer. Therefore, the Li&#8208;CO 2 batteries with Re&#8208;NCM&#8208;H3 catalyst deliver a high capacity (11808.9 mAh g &#8722;1 ), a lower overpotential (1.54 V), as well as excellent stability over 216 cycles at 100 mA g &#8722;1 and 165 cycles at 400 mA g &#8722;1 . This study not only opens up a sustainable application of spent ternary cathode, but also validates the potential of multi&#8208;element TMO catalysts with oxygen defects for high&#8208;efficiency Li&#8208;CO 2 batteries.</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Feng Ningning, Shuang Zhang, Yang Liu, Yapeng Zhang, Jing Du, Senlin Tian, Qun Zhao, Gang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of the Tetragonal-Orthorhombic transition in polycrystalline
  YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_{6+\delta}$ samples during the oxidation process at constant
  temperature via thermogravimetry and differential thermometry analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.12650</link>
      <description>Lorenzo Gallo, C. Sobrero, J. Malarr&#305;&#769;a, Roberto F. Luccas, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398230212

                This work examines the oxygenation process of polycrystalline powder of YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_{6+\delta}$ superconductor material through constant temperature thermogravimetric analysis. Starting from completely deoxygenated samples ($\delta$ = 0), both the mass evolution in an oxygen atmosphere and a differential temperature value referenced to an inert sample (alumina powder) subjected to the same experimental conditions are recorded. The oxygenation process itself is identified as an exothermic process accompanied by a second also exothermic associated process. This second process is identified as the Tetragonal-Orthorhombic transition present in the material. Based on the obtained results, the structural phase diagram of the material is reconstructed. Issues of metastability of the structural phases, as well as the potential of the equipment used to obtain these results comparable to those obtained in large facilities, are discussed. Reinterpretations of previously discussed works in the literature are inferred.</description>
      <author>Lorenzo Gallo, C. Sobrero, J. Malarr&#305;&#769;a, Roberto F. Luccas</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.12650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic and biochemical impacts on the development of hypoxia in the Louisiana&#8211;Texas shelf &#8211; Part 1: roles of nutrient limitation and plankton community</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-2385-2024</link>
      <description>Yanda Ou, Z. George Xue, Biogeosciences. 21(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398217385

                Abstract. A three-dimensional coupled hydrodynamic&#8211;biogeochemical model with multiple nutrient and plankton functional groups was developed and adapted to the Gulf of Mexico to investigate the role of nutrients and the complexity of plankton community in dissolved oxygen (DO) dynamics. A 15-year hindcast was achieved covering the period of 2006&#8211;2020. Extensive model validation against in situ data demonstrates that the model was capable of reproducing vertical distributions of DO and spatial distributions of bottom DO concentration, as well as their interannual variations. The study demonstrates that bottom DO dynamics and hypoxia evolution are significantly influenced by both physical processes and local biochemistry, with sedimentary oxygen consumption and vertical diffusion identified as key contributors. Summer hydrodynamics play a critical role in nutrient distribution and limitation: a notable expansion of Si limitation was simulated when coastal currents shifted eastward or northward. This effect, especially pronounced on the western part of the Louisiana&#8211;Texas shelf, underscores the importance of nutrient limitation in shaping DO dynamics. The model identifies a bi-peak primary production pattern in spring and early summer, aligned with satellite chlorophyll a variations, attributed to the complexity of the plankton community and interactions among different plankton groups. Our findings emphasize the necessity of integrating sophisticated plankton community dynamics into biogeochemical models to understand primary production variability and its impact on bottom hypoxia.</description>
      <author>Yanda Ou, Z. George Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-2385-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat transfer and thermodynamic analysis of autothermal reactors by catalytic oxidation and steam-methanol reforming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/lckjue</link>
      <description>Junjie Chen, Harvard Dataverse. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4398632710

                Numerical simulations are carried out to understand the heat energy transport characteristics of an autothermal reactor by steam-methanol reforming on copper-based catalysts. Mathematical expressions are derived for the reactor system based upon the principles of chemical kinetics and fluid mechanics. Enthalpy analysis is performed and the evolution of energy in the reforming and oxidation processes is discussed in terms of reaction heat flux. The effects of different factors on the thermal behavior of the autothermal reactor is evaluated in order to fully describe the thermal energy change in the reactor. The objective of the present study is to understand the heat energy transport characteristics of microchannel reactors for hydrogen production by steam-methanol reforming on copper-based catalysts. Emphasis is placed on the effects of different factors on the thermal behavior of autothermal reactors. The results indicate that the heat required for the endothermic reforming reaction must pass through the wall of the tube. Minimal oxygen requirements serve to inhibit carbon formation in the catalyst bed. Small size and weight allow for rapid catalyst bed heat-up to operating temperatures which is a critical requirement for quick start capability necessary in most vehicle applications. The temperature within the hot spot can be increased or decreased respectively by increasing or decreasing respectively the amount of oxygen supplied to the mixture. Direct heating is of considerable advantage as it largely overcomes the problems encountered with reaction rates being limited by the rate of heat transfer through the tube wall. The intervening walls may be flat plates or cylindrical walls with heat transfer capabilities. The separation is often affected by an adsorption process after condensing out the steam from the shifted gas. Silicon is considered a good material for fabrication of microreactors due to the high strength of the silicon-silicon bonds which results in the chemical inertness and thermal stability of silicon.</description>
      <author>Junjie Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/lckjue</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Joining of silicon nitride ceramic to oxygen&#8208;free copper using Ag&#8211;Cu&#8211;TiH&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; filler</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.19921</link>
      <description>Liangliang Tang, Dongxu Yao, Yongfeng Xia, Jin Zhao, Ming Zhu, Yu&#8208;Ping Zeng, Journal of the American Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397039846

                Abstract Complex liquid&#8211;solid reactions occur during brazing. A deep understanding of brazing liquid evolution is therefore of important concern for the bonding between filler and substrates. The joining of gas&#8208;pressure&#8208;sintered silicon nitride (Si 3 N 4 ) ceramic to oxygen&#8208;free copper (OFC) foil was prepared using Ag&#8211;Cu&#8211;TiH 2 filler at 875&#176;C for 0.5 h. The effect of the Ag:Cu ratio on the interfacial microstructure and peeling strength of the joints was analyzed. The reaction of brazing liquid with Si 3 N 4 ceramic includes reactions with both the &#946;&#8208;Si 3 N 4 and the grain boundary phases (Y&#8211;Si&#8211;Mg&#8211;O&#8211;N). The resulting interfacial reaction products include TiN, Ti 5 Si 3 , and potential Cu 3 Ti 3 O. Based on the phase composition and three&#8208;dimensional morphology of the interfacial reaction products in the Si 3 N 4 ceramic/OFC foil joints, a model for the evolution of the brazing liquid as the reaction proceeds was proposed. Peeling test results indicated that the peeling strength of the joints rises unilaterally with the increase of the Ag:Cu ratio in the filler until reaching the peak value of 24.3 N/mm at the maximum Ag:Cu ratio of 90:10. The mechanisms of the joint peeling fracture were discussed in detail.</description>
      <author>Liangliang Tang, Dongxu Yao, Yongfeng Xia, Jin Zhao, Ming Zhu, Yu&#8208;Ping Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/jace.19921</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of electric field on bubble generation and dissolution characteristics in oil&#8211;paper insulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1049/hve2.12456</link>
      <description>Chaojie Yang, Tao Zhao, Yunpeng Liu, Jiajun Yang, Jiaxue Xu, Yingcong Xu, High voltage. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398261700

                Abstract The interturn paper insulation of oil&#8208;immersed power transformer windings, under the combined influence of electric fields, moisture, and conductor heating, will produce bubbles, which pose a significant threat to the insulation system. However, there is limited research on the characteristics of bubble evolution in oil&#8211;paper insulation under the influence of electric fields and the subsequent dissolution process. Based on the continuous observation of bubble size using electron microscopes, experimental and theoretical investigations into the formation and dissolution of bubbles under electric field conditions are presented. The effects of different field strengths on bubble evolution and dissolution characteristics were studied. The results showed that the electric field promoted both the generation and dissolution of bubbles, with a more pronounced effect observed at higher field strengths (below partial discharge (PD) inception electric field, hereafter referred to as PDIE). However, when the field strength exceeded PDIE, the bubbles tended to shrink and gradually increase in size. The changes in bubble volume were related to not only gas diffusion but also oxygen consumption and fault gases generation due to PD. A better understanding of the formation and dissolution characteristics of bubbles under varying field strengths is achieved. Furthermore, it also provides a reference for assessing the risk of bubble generation and conducting bubble&#8208;related fault diagnosis during the overload operation of oil&#8208;immersed power equipment.</description>
      <author>Chaojie Yang, Tao Zhao, Yunpeng Liu, Jiajun Yang, Jiaxue Xu, Yingcong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1049/hve2.12456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changeable Active Sites by Pr Doping CuSA&#8208;TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photocatalyst for Excellent Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202305779</link>
      <description>Baoye Zi, Hongshun Zheng, Tong Zhou, Qingjie Lu, Mingpeng Chen, B.L. Xiao, Yumin Zhang, Z. Q. Qiu, Huachuan Sun, Jianhong Zhao, Zhongbao Luo, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Zong&#8208;Yan Zhao, Qingju Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398136672

                Abstract Photocatalytic water splitting for clean hydrogen production has been a very attractive research field for decades. However, the insightful understanding of the actual active sites and their impact on catalytic performance is still ambiguous. Herein, a Pr&#8208;doped TiO 2 &#8208;supported Cu single atom (SA) photocatalyst is successfully synthesized (noted as Cu/Pr&#8208;TiO 2 ). It is found that Pr dopants passivate the formation of oxygen vacancies, promoting the density of photogenerated electrons on the CuSAs, and optimizing the electronic structure and H * adsorption behavior on the CuSA active sites. The photocatalytic hydrogen evolution rate of the obtained Cu/Pr&#8208;TiO 2 catalyst reaches 32.88 mmol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 , 2.3 times higher than the Cu/TiO 2 . Innovatively, the excellent catalytic activity and performance is attributed to the active sites change from O atoms to CuSAs after Pr doping is found. This work provides new insight for understanding the accurate roles of single atoms in photocatalytic water splitting.</description>
      <author>Baoye Zi, Hongshun Zheng, Tong Zhou, Qingjie Lu, Mingpeng Chen, B.L. Xiao, Yumin Zhang, Z. Q. Qiu, Huachuan Sun, Jianhong Zhao, Zhongbao Luo, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Zong&#8208;Yan Zhao, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202305779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West African Monsoon Dynamics and Its Control on the Stable Oxygen Isotopic Composition of Precipitation in the Late Cenozoic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024jd040748</link>
      <description>Daniel Boateng, Jeffrey N. A. Aryee, Michael Baidu, Frank H. Arthur, Sebastian G. Mutz, Journal of geophysical research. Atmospheres. 129(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398259253

                Abstract This study presents an overview of the Late Cenozoic evolution of the West African Monsoon (WAM), and the associated changes in atmospheric dynamics and oxygen isotopic composition of precipitation (&#948; 18 O p ). This evolution is established by using the high&#8208;resolution isotope&#8208;enabled GCM ECHAM5&#8208;wiso to simulate the climatic responses to paleoenvironmental changes during the Mid&#8208;Holocene (MH), Last Glacial Maximum (LGM), and Mid&#8208;Pliocene (MP). The simulated responses are compared to a set of GCM outputs from Paleoclimate Model Intercomparison Project Phase 4 (PMIP4) to assess the added value of a high resolution and model consistency across different time periods. Results show WAM magnitudes and pattern changes that are consistent with PMIP4 models and proxy reconstructions. ECHAM5&#8208;wiso estimates the highest WAM intensification in the MH, with a precipitation increase of up to 150 mm/month reaching 25&#176;N during the monsoon season. The WAM intensification in the MP estimated by ECHAM5&#8208;wiso (up to 80 mm/month) aligns with the mid&#8208;range of the PMIP4 estimates, while the LGM dryness magnitude matches most of the models. Despite an enhanced hydrological cycle in MP, MH simulations indicate a &#8764;50% precipitation increase and a greater northward extent of WAM than the MP simulations. Strengthened conditions of the WAM in the MH and MP result from a pronounced meridional temperature gradient driving low&#8208;level westerly, Sahel&#8208;Sahara vegetation expansion, and a northward shift of the Africa Easterly Jet. The simulated &#948; 18 O p values patterns and their relationship with temperature and precipitation are non&#8208;stationarity over time, emphasizing the implications of assuming stationarity in proxy reconstruction transfer functions.</description>
      <author>Daniel Boateng, Jeffrey N. A. Aryee, Michael Baidu, Frank H. Arthur, Sebastian G. Mutz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024jd040748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genomic Insights into Diving Adaptations of Extreme Pinniped Divers: A Comparative Study of Elephant and Weddell Seals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1152/physiol.2024.39.s1.2129</link>
      <description>Diana D. Moreno-Santill&#225;n, Jos&#233; Pablo V&#225;zquez&#8208;Medina, Allyson G. Hindle, Physiology. 39(S1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398175501

                Extreme pinniped divers are extraordinary models to study adaptations to hypoxia/reoxygenation events derived from extreme fluctuations in oxygen levels during deep diving. We analyzed the evolutionary adaptations of the Weddell seal ( Leptonychotes weddellii) and the Northern and Southern elephant seals ( Mirounga angustirostris and M. leonina), which have exceptional diving abilities, reaching depths of over 1000 meters for extended periods up to 90 minutes. To understand the molecular mechanisms underpinning these remarkable adaptations, we conducted a comprehensive comparative genomic analysis of thirteen pinniped species. Our gene family evolution analyses revealed a significant loss of function in genes involved in the enzymatic degradation of glutathione, an endogenous antioxidant that our functional analysis have previously shown to increase rapidly in response to hypoxia exposure in primary cells derived from extreme divers, likely to protect cells against oxidative damage. We also detected adaptive signatures in pathways involved in the optimization of mitochondrial respiration, energy metabolism, DNA repair and cardiovascular regulation in these extreme divers. Notably the Weddell seal exhibited more genes under positive selection compared to the Elephant seals, possibly reflecting adaptations to extreme environmental pressures. Pathways enriched in Weddell seals include those related to fat metabolism, oxidative damage against hydrogen peroxide and membrane lipid remodeling. Our analysis sheds light on the remarkable genomic adaptations that enable extreme pinniped divers to tolerate oxygen fluctuations associated with deep diving while offering valuable insights into their unique physiological and biochemical strategies for overcoming the challenges posed by hypoxia and reperfusion damage. NSF OPP 2020664. This is the full abstract presented at the American Physiology Summit 2024 meeting and is only available in HTML format. There are no additional versions or additional content available for this abstract. Physiology was not involved in the peer review process.</description>
      <author>Diana D. Moreno-Santill&#225;n, Jos&#233; Pablo V&#225;zquez&#8208;Medina, Allyson G. Hindle</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1152/physiol.2024.39.s1.2129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mycoplasma pneumoniae pneumonia &#8211; challenges related to diagnosis and treatment in children</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.37897/rjid.2024.1.12</link>
      <description>Nicoleta-Ana Tom&#537;a, Lorena Elena Meli&#539;, Tiberiu Popescu, Claudiu M&#259;rginean, Romanian Journal of Infectious Diseases. 27(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398186629

                Introduction. Pneumonia is a common infectious disease among children, very familiar to pediatricians and a major cause of hospitalization worldwide. Mycoplasma pneumoniae (M. pneumoniae) - atypical pathogen, is estimated to be responsible for approximately 30-40% of community-acquired pneumonias. The aim of the paper was to underline the diagnostic and treatment difficulties in a case of pneumonia with M. pneumoniae in a school-aged boy, with multiple presentations in the Emergency Service for respiratory difficulties. Material and method. We present the case of a 7 years and 10-month-old male patient, admitted to our clinic for wheezing, cough and dyspnea. Results. The clinical exam at admission pointed out influenced general status, wheezing, thoraco-abdominal swing, intercostal draft, sibilant and crackles, oxygen saturation 89%, tachycardia 134 beats/minute. The blood tests revealed mild leukocytosis, with neutrophilia, slightly increased inflammatory biomarkers. Considering the general status and the presence of functional respiratory syndrome, steroid and symptomatic anti-inflammatory treatment is initiated. However, the general condition remains stable, which required the widening of the spectrum of investigations with the performance of a chest CT noticing a pneumonic condensation with an air bronchogram located at the level of the right upper lobe. Considering the stationary respiratory functional syndrome and the radiological appearance of the pneumonia as well as the age, we performed serology for atypical germs and identified a positive titer of Ig M antibodies for M. pneumoniae by instituting Azithromycin po., but after 3 days, the evolution remains stationary, thus we changed the treatment with intravenous Levofloxacin, with a favorable subsequent evolution. Conclusions. Pneumonia with atypical pathogens such as M. pneumoniae is a well-defined and well-known pathology in the literature, but it still remains a condition that imposes multiple difficulties related to the diagnosis and therapeutic management of pediatric cases.</description>
      <author>Nicoleta-Ana Tom&#537;a, Lorena Elena Meli&#539;, Tiberiu Popescu, Claudiu M&#259;rginean</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.37897/rjid.2024.1.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depth-resolved Characterization of Meissner Screening Breakdown in Surface Treated Niobium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4402391/v1</link>
      <description>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. Andrew MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398268608

                Abstract We report direct measurements of the magnetic field screening at the limits of the Meissner phase for two superconducting Nb samples. The samples are processed with two different surface treatments that have been developed for superconducting radio-frequency cavity applications &#8212; a &#8220;baseline&#8221; treatment and an oxygen-doping (&#8220;O-doping&#8221; ) treatment. The measurements show: 1) that the screening length is significantly longer in the &#8220;O-doping&#8221; sample compared to the &#8220;baseline&#8221; sample; 2) that the screening length near the limits of the Meissner phase increases with applied field; 3) the evolution of the screening profile as the material transitions from the Meissner phase to the mixed phase; and 4) a demonstration of the absence of any screening profile for the highest applied field, indicative of the full flux entering the sample. Measurements are performed utilizing the &#946; -detected nuclear magnetic resonance (&#946; -NMR) technique that allows depth resolved studies of the local magnetic field within the first 100 nm of the surface. The study takes advantage of the &#946; -SRF beamline, a new facility at TRIUMF, Canada, where field levels up to 200 mT are available parallel to the sample surface to replicate radio frequency (RF) fields near the Meissner breakdown limits of Nb.</description>
      <author>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. Andrew MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4402391/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining of Arsenic-Based Small Molecules Geometrics Present in Cambridge Structural Database</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.142349</link>
      <description>pendra Nayek, Thripthi Nagesh Shenoy, Abdul Ajees Abdul Salam, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397010144

                Arsenic, ubiquitous in various industrial processes and consumer products, presents both essential functions and considerable toxicity risks, driving extensive research into safer applications. Our investigation, drawing from 7,182 arsenic-containing molecules in the Cambridge Structural Database (CSD), outlines their diverse bonding patterns. Notably, 51% of these molecules exhibit cyclic connections, while 49% display acyclic ones. Arsenic forms eight distinct bonding types with other elements, with significant interactions observed, particularly with phenyl rings. Top interactions involve carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, fluorine, sulfur, and arsenic itself. We meticulously evaluated average bond lengths under three conditions: without an R-factor cut-off, with R-factor &#8804; 0.075, and with R-factor &#8804; 0.05, supporting the credibility of our results. Comparative analysis with existing literature data enriches our understanding of arsenic's bonding behaviour. Our findings illuminate the structural attributes, molecular coordination, geometry, and bond lengths of arsenic with diverse atoms, enriching our comprehension of arsenic chemistry. These revelations not only offer a pathway for crafting innovative and safer arsenic-based compounds but also foster the evolution of arsenic detoxification mechanisms, tackling pivotal health and environmental challenges linked to arsenic exposure across different contexts.</description>
      <author>pendra Nayek, Thripthi Nagesh Shenoy, Abdul Ajees Abdul Salam</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.142349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin BiOCl-OV/CoAl-LDH S-scheme heterojunction for efficient photocatalytic peroxymonosulfate activation to boost Co (IV)=O generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121774</link>
      <description>Yi Zhong, Shiqing Ma, Daimei Chen, Yanmei Feng, Wenyang Zhang, Sijia Sun, Guocheng Lv, Weibin Zhang, Jin Z. Zhang, Sijia Sun, Water research. 258(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398155483

                Sustainable and rapid production of high-valent cobalt-oxo (Co(IV)=O) species for efficiently removing organic pollutants is challenging in permoxymonosulfate (PMS) based advanced-oxidation-processes (AOPs) due to the limitation of the high 3d-orbital electronic occupancy of Co and slow conversion from Co(III) to Co(II). Herein, S-scheme BiOCl-OV/CoAl-LDH heterojunction were constructed by ultrathin BiOCl with the oxygen-vacancy (OV) self-assembled with ultrathin CoAl-LDH. OV promoted the formation of charge transfer channel (Bi-O-Co bonds) at the interface of the heterojunction and reduced electron occupation of the Co 3d-orbital to facilitate the generation of Co(IV)=O in the BiOCl-OV/CoAl-LDH/PMS/Visible-light system. S-scheme heterojunction accelerated the photogenerated electrons to allow rapid conversion of Co(III) to Co(II), promoting the fast two-electron transfer from Co(II) to Co(IV)=O. Consequently, the developed BiOCl-OV/CoAl-LDH/PMS/Visible-light system showed excellent degradation efficiency for most of organic pollutions, and exhibited very high removal capability for the actual industrial wastewater. This study provides a new insight into the evolution of Co(IV)=O and the coordinative mechanism for photocatalysis and PMS activation.</description>
      <author>Yi Zhong, Shiqing Ma, Daimei Chen, Yanmei Feng, Wenyang Zhang, Sijia Sun, Guocheng Lv, Weibin Zhang, Jin Z. Zhang, Sijia Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121774</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoreduction of CO2 on Pd-In2O3: Synergistic optimization of progressive electron transfer via amorphous/crystalline Pd and oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152394</link>
      <description>Zhongming Wang, Hao Yuan, Siting Chen, Yong Jia, Lina Guo, Hong Wang, Wenxin Dai, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397289324

                The progressive transfer of photogenerated electrons between the catalyst components and reactants is of great significance for photocatalysis. Amorphous Pd (PdA) and oxygen vacancies (VOs) were simultaneously introduced in Pd-In2O3 exploiting hydrogen-induced amorphization effects; 0.6 wt% Pd-In2O3 exhibited a 4.5-fold increase in activity and a 3.2-fold higher selectivity toward CH3OH + CO (63.62 %) compared with In2O3. Multiple in situ techniques and theoretical calculations revealed that intercomponent electron transfer channels were established via various interface structures formed between PdA or crystalline Pd (PdC) and In2O3; PdA acted as electronic pump, facilitating the transfer and separation of photogenerated electrons, resulting in their subsequent enrichment on the surface of PdA. Simultaneously, PdA acted as electron-donating adsorption site for H2O, increasing the number of electrons received by H2O, further inhibiting the competitive adsorption of H2O and CO2 on VO sites, and promoting the hydrogen evolution reaction. Additionally, the electronic coupling between PdC and VOs could significantly decrease the electron-donating ability of VOs, reducing the number of electrons received by CO2, thus effectively regulating the degree of CO2 reduction. This study employs PdA/PdC and VOs to synergistic optimize the progressive transfer of photogenerated electrons, and presents a novel approach for elucidating the catalytic mechanism.</description>
      <author>Zhongming Wang, Hao Yuan, Siting Chen, Yong Jia, Lina Guo, Hong Wang, Wenxin Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The metallicity and carbon-to-oxygen ratio of the ultra-hot Jupiter
  WASP-76b from Gemini-S/IGRINS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.09769</link>
      <description>Megan Mansfield, Michael R. Line, Joost P. Wardenier, Matteo Brogi, Jacob L. Bean, Hayley Beltz, Peter Smith, Joseph A. Zalesky, Natasha E. Batalha, Eliza M.-R. Kempton, Benjamin T. Montet, James E. Owen, Peter Plavchan, Emily Rauscher, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397028229

                Measurements of the carbon-to-oxygen (C/O) ratios of exoplanet atmospheres can reveal details about their formation and evolution. Recently, high-resolution cross-correlation analysis has emerged as a method of precisely constraining the C/O ratios of hot Jupiter atmospheres. We present two transits of the ultra-hot Jupiter WASP-76b observed between 1.4-2.4 $\mu$m with Gemini-S/IGRINS. We detected the presence of H$_{2}$O, CO, and OH at signal-to-noise rations of 6.93, 6.47, and 3.90, respectively. We performed two retrievals on this data set. A free retrieval for abundances of these three species retrieved a volatile metallicity of $\left[\frac{\mathrm{C}+\mathrm{O}} {\mathrm{H}}\right]=-0.70^{+1.27}_{-0.93}$, consistent with the stellar value, and a super-solar carbon-to-oxygen ratio of C/O$=0.80^{+0.07}_{-0.11}$. We also ran a chemically self-consistent grid retrieval, which agreed with the free retrieval within $1\sigma$ but favored a slightly more sub-stellar metallicity and solar C/O ratio ($\left[\frac{\mathrm{C}+\mathrm{O}} {\mathrm{H}}\right]=-0.74^{+0.23}_{-0.17}$ and C/O$=0.59^{+0.13}_{-0.14}$). A variety of formation pathways may explain the composition of WASP-76b. Additionally, we found systemic ($V_{sys}$) and Keplerian ($K_{p}$) velocity offsets which were broadly consistent with expectations from 3D general circulation models of WASP-76b, with the exception of a redshifted $V_{sys}$ for H$_{2}$O. Future observations to measure the phase-dependent velocity offsets and limb differences at high resolution on WASP-76b will be necessary to understand the H$_{2}$O velocity shift. Finally, we find that the population of exoplanets with precisely constrained C/O ratios generally trends toward super-solar C/O ratios. More results from high-resolution observations or JWST will serve to further elucidate any population-level trends.</description>
      <author>Megan Mansfield, Michael R. Line, Joost P. Wardenier, Matteo Brogi, Jacob L. Bean, Hayley Beltz, Peter Smith, Joseph A. Zalesky, Natasha E. Batalha, Eliza M.-R. Kempton, Benjamin T. Montet, James E. Owen, Peter Plavchan, Emily Rauscher</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.09769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glance on Advancements and Innovations in Green Hydrogen Production Technologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1339-4_6</link>
      <description>Avesahemad S. N. Husainy, Vishal V. Patil, Omkar S. Chougule, Pramod Jadhav, Samir N. Momin, Sanmesh S. Shinde, Paramvir Singh, Energy, environment, and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398151144

                Hydrogen is being employed for more than only the typical industrial processes that involve creating ammonia, methanol, and refined petroleum. In recent years, there has been an increase in interest in the large-scale adoption of renewable energy-based power plants, as well as industrial and transportation uses, with a focus on manufacturing green hydrogen via the electrolysis process. Water electrolysis stands as a fundamental technique, involving the electrical decomposition of water into hydrogen and oxygen. Recent advances in alkaline water electrolysis have yielded impressive results, with energy efficiencies exceeding 70%. The photoelectrochemical water electrolysis, characterized by its proton-conductive membrane, demonstrates remarkable promise, boasting efficiency levels of up to 80%. Solid oxide cells represent a high-temperature option for hydrogen production, showcasing efficiencies above 70%. The burgeoning fields of photocatalytic and photoelectrochemical water splitting harness solar energy to drive the hydrogen evolution reaction. The results reveal that these technologies have achieved solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiencies of up to 18%. These diverse approaches offer versatile solutions for green hydrogen production, vital for decarburization efforts. They address the need for sustainable, environmentally friendly, and secure energy sources, aligning with economic, environmental, and social considerations. As continue to advance these methodologies, hydrogen's role in our energy landscape grows, promising a cleaner and more sustainable future.</description>
      <author>Avesahemad S. N. Husainy, Vishal V. Patil, Omkar S. Chougule, Pramod Jadhav, Samir N. Momin, Sanmesh S. Shinde, Paramvir Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-97-1339-4_6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regular study of lanthanide oxides for boosting photocatalytic hydrogen production on ZnIn2S4 photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174914</link>
      <description>Liang Geng, Wenjun Li, Mei Dong, Yueyan Fan, Yajie Li, Yang Li, Ruixue Huang, Yun Liu, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398147156

                Lanthanide oxides have potential advantages for photocatalytic hydrogen production. To systematically investigate the photocatalytic performance of lanthanide oxides on metal sulfides, a series of LnxOy/ZnIn2S4 (LnxOy/ZIS) were synthesized by hydrothermal method. Comprehensive characterization demonstrated that LnxOy synergistically improved the performance of ZnIn2S4 by extending light absorption, reducing contact interface resistance and enhancing carrier separation. The photocatalytic hydrogen evolution (PHE) rates of the LnxOy/ZIS photocatalysts were improved, which were 1.6 to 4.2 times higher than those of pure ZnIn2S4 (198.0 &#956;mol g-1 h-1). The PHE rates of LnxOy/ZIS decreased with increasing lanthanide atomic number, and when the lanthanides contained variable valence ions, the PHE rates of LnxOy/ZIS were superior to those of neighbouring lanthanides. The heterojunction formed by LnxOy and ZnIn2S4 effectively promoted carrier separation. Lanthanide ions with unoccupied 4 f orbital were more likely to accept electrons and served as a hydrogen adsorption site for further hydrogen reduction. Multivalent ions could also promote the migration of electrons and generate oxygen vacancies to inhibit the recombination of carriers. In conclusion, for ZnIn2S4, lanthanide oxides are promising candidates to improve the performance of PHE. This study provides guidance on the selection of appropriate lanthanide oxides for the construction of efficient sulphur-based heterojunction photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Liang Geng, Wenjun Li, Mei Dong, Yueyan Fan, Yajie Li, Yang Li, Ruixue Huang, Yun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174914</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The genome of &lt;i&gt;Lespedeza potaninii&lt;/i&gt; reveals biased subgenome evolution and drought adaptation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/plphys/kiae283</link>
      <description>Qi Yan, Pan Xu, Yunyue Xiao, L. Chen, Fan Wu, S.-M. Wang, F. Q. Guo, Zengqiang Duan, Jiyu Zhang, Plant physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397002691

                Abstract Lespedeza potaninii, a xerophytic subshrub belonging to the legume family, is native to the Tengger Desert and is highly adapted to drought. It has important ecological value due to its drought adaptability, but the underlying molecular mechanisms remain largely unknown. Here, we report a 1.24 Gb chromosome-scale assembly of the L. potaninii genome (contig N50=15.75 Mb). Our results indicate that L. potaninii underwent an allopolyploid event with two subgenomes, A and B, presenting asymmetric evolution and B subgenome dominance. We estimate that the two diploid progenitors of L. potaninii diverged around 3.6 MYA and merged around 1.0 MYA. We revealed that the expansion of hub genes associated with drought responses, such as the binding partner 1 of accelerated cell death 11 (ACD11) (BPA1), facilitated environmental adaptations of L. potaninii to desert habitats. We found a novel function of the BPA1 family in abiotic stress tolerance in addition to the known role in regulating the plant immune response, which could improve drought tolerance by positively regulating reactive oxygen species homeostasis in plants. We revealed that bZIP transcription factors could bind to the BPA1 promoter and activate its transcription. Our work fills the genomic data gap in the Lespedeza genus and the tribe Desmodieae, which should provide both theoretical support in the study of drought tolerance and in the molecular breeding of legume crops.</description>
      <author>Qi Yan, Pan Xu, Yunyue Xiao, L. Chen, Fan Wu, S.-M. Wang, F. Q. Guo, Zengqiang Duan, Jiyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/plphys/kiae283</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cable&#8208;Stayed Honeycomb Superstructure to Improve the Stability of Li&#8208;Rich Materials via Inhibiting Interlaminar Lattice Strain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404982</link>
      <description>Yunshan Jiang, Zhirong Liao, Fu&#8208;Da Yu, Ke Wang, Xin&#8208;yu Li, Xiawei Yang, Guoren Xu, Gang Sun, Yuanguang Xia, Wen Yin, Liang Deng, Linjie Zhao, Zhen Wang, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398247794

                Abstract In layered Li&#8208;rich materials, over stoichiometric Li forms an ordered occupation of LiTM6 in TM layer, showing a honeycomb superstructure along [001] direction. At the atomic scale, the instability of the superstructure at high voltage is the root cause of problems such as capacity/voltage decay of Li&#8208;rich materials. Here we report a Li&#8208;rich material with a high Li/Ni disorder, these interlayer Ni atoms locate above the honeycomb superstructure and share adjacent O coordination with honeycomb TM. These Ni&#8208;O bonds act as cable&#8208;stayed bridge to the honeycomb plane, and improve the high&#8208;voltage stability. The cable&#8208;stayed honeycomb superstructure is confirmed by in&#8208;situ X&#8208;ray diffraction to have a unique cell evolution mechanism that it can alleviate interlaminar lattice strain by promoting in&#8208;plane expansion along a&#8208;axis and inhibiting c&#8208;axis stretching. Electrochemical tests also demonstrate significantly improved long cycle performance after 500 cycles (86% for Li&#8208;rich/Li half cell and 82% for Li&#8208;rich/Si&#8208;C full cell) and reduced irreversible oxygen release. This work proves the feasibility of achieving outstanding stability of lithium&#8208;rich materials through superstructure regulation and provides new insights for the development of the next&#8208;generation high&#8208;energy&#8208;density cathodes. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Yunshan Jiang, Zhirong Liao, Fu&#8208;Da Yu, Ke Wang, Xin&#8208;yu Li, Xiawei Yang, Guoren Xu, Gang Sun, Yuanguang Xia, Wen Yin, Liang Deng, Linjie Zhao, Zhen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404982</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of pyrolysis and Computational Fluid Dynamics modeling of low metamorphic coal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/apj.3095</link>
      <description>Qiuli Zhang, Jun Li, Hai Xuan Wang, Jun Li Liu, Jun Zhou, Asia-Pacific journal of chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397022275

                Abstract This study explores the low&#8208;temperature pyrolysis kinetic of low metamorphic grade coal from Northern Shaanxi, utilizing Fourier transform infrared (FT&#8208;IR) spectroscopy to analyze the characteristics of various functional groups over a 293&#8211;1023 K temperature range. A kinetic model, correlating with the pyrolysis behaviors of these groups, was developed through thermal analysis kinetics. Computational fluid dynamics (CFD) technology simulated the furnace's flow dynamics, allowing an examination of the physical field alterations and functional group evolution during pyrolysis. Results showed that the pyrolysis kinetic functions for aromatic C&#8211;H, C=C, C&#8211;O, and &#8226;OH, along with temperature, pressure, and velocity fields, were successfully integrated into the simulation. This integration provided detailed insights into the temperature profile, pressure distribution, flow velocities, and functional group distribution in the furnace. Aliphatics, exhibiting the largest mass fraction and wide pyrolysis temperature range, and &#8226;OH radicals with the highest activation energy were concentrated in the furnace's pyrolysis zone center. C=C's distribution was influenced by aromatic C&#8211;H and aliphatics, showing a complementary pattern. The oxygen&#8208;containing groups C&#8211;O and C=O had similar pyrolysis mechanisms and uniform distribution. The functional groups' mass fractions were ranked from highest to lowest as follows: aliphatics &gt; &#8226;OH &gt; aromatic C&#8211;H &gt; C&#8211;O &gt; C=C &gt; C=O.</description>
      <author>Qiuli Zhang, Jun Li, Hai Xuan Wang, Jun Li Liu, Jun Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/apj.3095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ancient evolution of far-red light photoacclimation in cyanobacteria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.15.594131</link>
      <description>Laura A. Antonaru, Cecilia Rad&#8208;Men&#233;ndez, Susan Mbedi, Sarah Sparmann, M. A. Pope, Thomas Oliver, Shujie Wu, David H. Green, Muriel Gugger, Dennis J. N&#252;rnberg, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397292876

                Cyanobacteria oxygenated the atmosphere of early Earth and continue to be key players in global carbon and nitrogen cycles. A phylogenetically diverse subset of extant cyanobacteria can perform photosynthesis with far-red light through a process called far-red light photoacclimation, or FaRLiP. This phenotype is enabled by a cluster of ~20 genes, and involves the synthesis of red-shifted chlorophylls f and d, together with paralogues of the ubiquitous photosynthetic machinery used in visible light. The FaRLiP gene cluster is present in diverse, environmentally important cyanobacterial groups but its origin, evolutionary history, and connection to early biotic environments have remained unclear. This study takes advantage of the recent increase in (meta)genomic data to clarify this issue; sequence data mining, metagenomic assembly, and phylogenetic tree networks were used to recover more than 600 new FaRLiP gene sequences, corresponding to 52 new gene clusters. These data enable high-resolution phylogenetics and - by relying on multiple gene trees, together with gene arrangement conservation - support FaRLiP appearing early in cyanobacterial evolution. Sampling information shows that considerable FaRLiP diversity can be observed in microbialites to the present day, and the process may have been associated with microbial mats and stromatolite formation in the early Paleoproterozoic. The ancestral FaRLiP cluster was reconstructed, revealing a conserved intergenic regulatory sequence that has been maintained for billions of years. Taken together, our results indicate that oxygenic photosynthesis using far-red light may have played a significant role in Earth's early history.</description>
      <author>Laura A. Antonaru, Cecilia Rad&#8208;Men&#233;ndez, Susan Mbedi, Sarah Sparmann, M. A. Pope, Thomas Oliver, Shujie Wu, David H. Green, Muriel Gugger, Dennis J. N&#252;rnberg</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.15.594131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(Re)mind the gap: a hiatus in star formation history unveiled by APOGEE
  DR17</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.11025</link>
      <description>E. Spitoni, F. Matteucci, R. Gratton, B. Ratcliffe, I. Minchev, G. Cescutti, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398191615

                The analysis of several spectroscopic surveys indicates the presence of a bimodality between the disc stars in the abundance ratio space of [${\alpha}$/Fe] versus [Fe/H]. The two stellar groups are commonly referred to as the high-${\alpha}$ and low-${\alpha}$ sequences. Some models capable of reproducing such a bimodality, invoke the presence of a hiatus in the star formation history in our Galaxy, whereas other models explain the two sequences by means of stellar migration. Our aim is to show that the existence of the gap in the star formation rate between high-$\alpha$ and low-$\alpha$ is evident in the stars of APOGEE DR17, if one plots [Fe/$\alpha$] versus [$\alpha$/H], thus confirming previous suggestions by Gratton et al. (1996) and Fuhrmann (1998). Then we try to interpret the data by means of detailed chemical models. We compare the APOGEE DR17 red giant stars with the predictions of a detailed chemical evolution model based on the two-infall paradigm, taking also into account possible accretion of dwarf satellites. The APOGEE DR17 abundance ratios [Fe/$\alpha$] versus [$\alpha$/H] exhibit a sharp increase of [Fe/$\alpha$] at a nearly constant [$\alpha$/H] (where $\alpha$ elements considered are Mg, Si, O) during the transition between the two disc phases. This observation strongly supports the hypothesis that a hiatus in star formation occurred during this evolutionary phase. Notably, the most pronounced growth in the [Fe/$\alpha$] versus [$\alpha$/H] relation is observed for oxygen, as this element is exclusively synthesised in core-collapse supernovae. A chemical model predicting a stop in the star formation of a duration of roughly 3.5 Gyr, and where the high-$\alpha$ disc starts forming from pre-enriched gas by a previous encounter with a dwarf galaxy can well explain the observations.</description>
      <author>E. Spitoni, F. Matteucci, R. Gratton, B. Ratcliffe, I. Minchev, G. Cescutti</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.11025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the peroxiredoxin gene family: an antioxidant enzyme in the context of hypoxia-induced by aquatic mammals dives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1152/physiol.2024.39.s1.2571</link>
      <description>Giovanna Selleghin-Veiga, Mariana F. Nery, Physiology. 39(S1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398165205

                Peroxiredoxins are a group of antioxidant enzymes that play a crucial role in eliminating hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) produced during cellular metabolism. In conditions such as tissue ischemia/reperfusion, H 2 O 2 production is heightened. This scenario is recurrent in aquatic mammals, such as cetaceans and pinnipeds, when they perform breath-hold dives that lead to depletion of oxygen stores and cell hypoxia due to prolonged submersion. In such circumstances, peroxiredoxins are essential for regulating metabolism and preventing oxidative damage. Thus, our objective was to investigate evolutionary patterns of the peroxiredoxin gene family among aquatic mammalian species. Accordingly, we identified the number of ortholog and paralog genes among mammals, examining events of gene duplication, patterns of chromosomal distribution, and adaptive selection. We found that most subtypes of peroxiredoxins are characterized by single-copy genes with minimal missing data, with PRDX1, the most highly expressed subtype found in both the nucleus and cytoplasm, exhibiting an increase in gene copies in aquatic mammals, particularly in pinnipeds. The distribution of the copies was dispersed along the genome and the majority were retrocopies of the main coding sequence with little divergence among them. We also found evidence of positive selection in the PRDX3 gene, especially in a convergent mutation among two deepest-diving species, cuvier&#8217;s beaked whale and southern elephant seal in which the amino acid had radical physical-chemical property change, possibly affecting the protein function. These results suggest that the peroxiredoxin gene family has a role in the evolution of aquatic mammals by reducing oxidative damage intrinsic to diving behavior in these species. FAPESP - S&#227;o Paulo Research Foundation. This is the full abstract presented at the American Physiology Summit 2024 meeting and is only available in HTML format. There are no additional versions or additional content available for this abstract. Physiology was not involved in the peer review process.</description>
      <author>Giovanna Selleghin-Veiga, Mariana F. Nery</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1152/physiol.2024.39.s1.2571</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ediacaran marine animal forests and the ventilation of the oceans</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2024.04.059</link>
      <description>Susana Gutarra, Emily Mitchell, Frances S. Dunn, Brandt M. Gibson, Rachel A. Racicot, Simon A.F. Darroch, Imran A. Rahman, CB/Current biology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4397002791

                The rise of animals across the Ediacaran&#8211;Cambrian transition marked a step-change in the history of life, from a microbially dominated world to the complex macroscopic biosphere we see today.1Erwin D.H. Laflamme M. Tweedt S.M. Sperling E.A. Pisani D. Peterson K.J. The Cambrian Conundrum: early divergence and later ecological success in the early history of animals.Science. 2011; 334: 1091-1097Crossref PubMed Scopus (959) Google Scholar,2Droser M.L. Gehling J.G. The advent of animals: the view from the Ediacaran.Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2015; 112: 4865-4870Crossref PubMed Scopus (121) Google Scholar,3Droser M.L. Tarhan L.G. Gehling J.G. The rise of animals in a changing environment: global ecological innovation in the Late Ediacaran.Annu. Rev. Earth Planet Sci. 2017; 45: 593-617Crossref Scopus (119) Google Scholar While the importance of bioturbation and swimming in altering the structure and function of Earth systems is well established,4Butterfield N.J. Oxygen, animals and oceanic ventilation: an alternative view.Geobiology. 2009; 7: 1-7Crossref PubMed Scopus (220) Google Scholar,5Canfield D.E. Farquhar J. Animal evolution, bioturbation, and the sulfate concentration of the oceans.Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA. 2009; 106: 8123-8127Crossref PubMed Scopus (0) Google Scholar,6Butterfield N.J. Oxygen, animals and aquatic bioturbation: an updated account.Geobiology. 2018; 16: 3-16Crossref PubMed Scopus (41) Google Scholar the influence of epifaunal animals on the hydrodynamics of marine environments is not well understood. Of particular interest are the oldest "marine animal forests,"7Guizien K. Ghisalberti M. Living in the canopy of the animal forest: physical and biogeochemical aspects.in: Rossi S. Marine Animal Forests. Springer, 2017: 507-528Crossref Scopus (16) Google Scholar which comprise a diversity of sessile soft-bodied organisms dominated by the fractally branching rangeomorphs.8Clapham M.E. Narbonne G.M. Gehling J.G. Paleoecology of the oldest known animal communities: Ediacaran assemblages at Mistaken Point, Newfoundland.Paleobiology. 2003; 29: 527-544Crossref Google Scholar,9Mitchell E.G. Harris S. Kenchington C.G. Vixseboxse P. Roberts L. Clark C. Dennis A. Liu A.G. Wilby P.R. The importance of neutral over niche processes in structuring Ediacaran early animal communities.Ecol. Lett. 2019; 22: 2028-2038Crossref PubMed Scopus (32) Google Scholar Typified by fossil assemblages from the Ediacaran of Mistaken Point, Newfoundland,8Clapham M.E. Narbonne G.M. Gehling J.G. Paleoecology of the oldest known animal communities: Ediacaran assemblages at Mistaken Point, Newfoundland.Paleobiology. 2003; 29: 527-544Crossref Google Scholar,10Ghisalberti M. Gold D.A. Laflamme M. Clapham M.E. Narbonne G.M. Summons R.E. Johnston D.T. Jacobs D.K. Canopy flow analysis reveals the advantage of size in the oldest communities of multicellular eukaryotes.Curr. Biol. 2014; 24: 305-309Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (53) Google Scholar,11Matthews J.J. Liu A.G. Yang C. McIlroy D. Levell B. Condon D.J. A chronostratigraphic framework for the rise of the Ediacaran macrobiota: new constraints from Mistaken Point Ecological Reserve, Newfoundland.Geol. Soc. Am. Bull. 2021; 133: 612-624Crossref Scopus (55) Google Scholar these ancient communities might have played a pivotal role in structuring marine environments, similar to modern ecosystems,7Guizien K. Ghisalberti M. Living in the canopy of the animal forest: physical and biogeochemical aspects.in: Rossi S. Marine Animal Forests. Springer, 2017: 507-528Crossref Scopus (16) Google Scholar,12Rossi S. The destruction of the 'animal forests' in the oceans: towards an oversimplification of the benthic ecosystems.Ocean Coast Manag. 2013; 84: 77-85Crossref Scopus (105) Google Scholar,13Rossi S. Bramanti L. Gori A. Covadonga O. Animal forests of the world: an overview.in: Rossi S. Marine Animal Forests. Springer, 2017: 1-28Google Scholar but our understanding of how they impacted fluid flow in the water column is limited. Here, we use ecological modeling and computational flow simulations to explore how Ediacaran marine animal forests influenced their surrounding environment. Our results reveal how organism morphology and community structure and composition combined to impact vertical mixing of the surrounding water. We find that Mistaken Point communities were capable of generating high-mixing conditions, thereby likely promoting gas and nutrient transport within the "canopy." This mixing could have served to enhance local-scale oxygen concentrations and redistribute resources like dissolved organic carbon. Our work suggests that Ediacaran marine animal forests may have contributed to the ventilation of the oceans over 560 million years ago, well before the Cambrian explosion of animals.</description>
      <author>Susana Gutarra, Emily Mitchell, Frances S. Dunn, Brandt M. Gibson, Rachel A. Racicot, Simon A.F. Darroch, Imran A. Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cub.2024.04.059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage of diabetic retinopathy with blood antioxidants and gut microbiota in type two diabetes mellitus Saudi patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15406/aovs.2024.14.00457</link>
      <description>Rania Samir Fahmy, Advances in ophthalmology &amp; visual system. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398149045

                Background: The retina is a light-sensitive nerve layer located at the back of the eye that creates images of objects. These cells kept alive by getting oxygen and nutrients from tiny blood vessels in the eye. Retinopathy is a disease of the retina that is more prevalent in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients. Diabetic retinopathy is a leading cause of blindness because hyperglycemia weakens retinal capillaries, resulting in leakage of blood into the surrounding space. This bleeding can result in formation of scar tissue, which can cause traction retinal detachment and maculopathy. The development of a panel of blood biomarkers to monitor diabetic retinopathies is essential for both diagnosis and prognosis. Proteomics as a powerful tool for the analysis of complex mixtures of proteins and the identification of biomarkers can be of great importance. Purpose: To detect early nerve fiber layer changes around macula and optic disc in diabetic patients, and to correlate diabetic retinopathy with blood antioxidants and gut microbiota in T2DM in Saudi patients. Materials and Methods: In this cross-sectional case-control study, a total of 77 eyes of 39 subjects aged 40-60 years who did not have any history of eye injuries or eye diseases affecting fundus viewing, were recruited from King Saud University Campus and the department of ophthalmology in King Abdul Aziz university hospital in Riyadh. All subjects underwent full ophthalmic examination including Peripapillary retinal nerve fiber layer thickness and macular profile, Proteomic approach of collected overnight fasting plasma and Microbial stool examination. Results: The nerve fiber layer thickness around the optic disc was measured for all groups, and there was no statistically significant difference in all quadrants between groups. The total retinal thickness at the macular area was different among all groups and tends to increase in group 3 due to diabetic retinopathy. The macular thickness in the 4 quadrants revealed no statistical difference except in the inferior quadrant. Glutathione S transferase and lipid peroxides showed no significant difference between the three studied groups; vitamin C and Glutathione were surprisingly higher in controlled diabetic patients relative to controls. Moreover, over growth of bacteroids participated to the evolution of retinopathy in diabetic patients. Conclusion: As hyperglycemia and oxidative stress are implicated in the pathogenesis of diabetic retinopathy, the present study certified that the progressive damage can be delayed in controlled type 2 diabetic patients using different treatment modalities that subside oxidative stress.</description>
      <author>Rania Samir Fahmy</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15406/aovs.2024.14.00457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passivation of Bulk Defects in Halide Perovskites thin Films by Plasma Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.hopv.2024.116</link>
      <description>Ale&#353; Vlk, Robert Hlav&#225;&#269;, Lucie Landov&#225;, Julius A. Vida, Tom&#225;&#353; Homo&#318;a, A. Fejfar, Martin Ledinsk&#253;, Proceedings of the International Conference on Hybrid and Organic Photovoltaics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398149455

                Passivation of Bulk Defects in Halide Perovskites thin Films by Plasma TreatmentAle&#353; Vlk a, Robert Hlav&#225;&#269; a, Lucie Landov&#225; a, Julius Vida b, Tom&#225;&#353; Homola b, Anton&#237;n Fejfar a, Martin Ledinsk&#253; aa Institute of Physics of the Czech Academy of Sciences, Cukrovarnicka 10, 16200 Prague, Czech Republic.b Institute of Physics of the Czech Academy of Sciences, Cukrovarnicka 10, 16200 Prague, Czech Republic.International Conference on Hybrid and Organic PhotovoltaicsProceedings of International Conference on Hybrid and Organic Photovoltaics (HOPV24)Val&#232;ncia, Spain, 2024 May 12th - 15thOrganizer: Bruno EhrlerOral, Ale&#353; Vlk, presentation 116DOI: https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.hopv.2024.116Publication date: 6th February 2024Recombination of electrons and holes at the defect states of perovskite absorber limits the power conversion efficiency of the organic-inorganic halide perovskite solar cells. Recently, with the help of in-situ PL and GIWAXS measurements, we have shown that the defects are formed mainly at the grain boundaries and surface.1,2 Therefore, it is necessary to selectively passivate surface and grain boundaries. It was shown that the removal of thin surface layers using mechanical,3 or laser4 polishing may improve the performance of perovskite thin films and PCEs. In our work, we performed an initial study examining the effect of the DCSBD (the diffuse coplanar surface barrier discharge) plasma on perovskite thin films. The sample was placed in the vicinity of the plasma and exposed to the plasma for different duration. Using in-situ photoluminescence (PL) spectroscopy, we found that the exposure of perovskite surface to plasma in nitrogen atmosphere causes the removal of oxygen from perovskite film. We found that, at first, the PL intensity decreased significantly, which is caused by surface defects created by exposure to plasma. However, after this abrupt change, the plasma lines of singly ionized oxygen appear in the spectrum of the plasma, and the PL intensity increases until the oxygen is completely removed. This means that the removal of oxygen has a positive impact on defect densities in perovskite film. However, when completely removed, further exposure to plasma has only a negative impact. We believe this method could be an intermediate step before the deposition of a passivation layer on the perovskite. Additionally, the DCSBD plasma treatment is already used in different industrial applications and thus it is ready for use in large production lines. References:[1] Mrkyvkova, N.; Held, V.; N&#225;da&#382;dy, P.; Subair, R.; Majkova, E.; Jergel, M.; Vlk, A.; Ledinsky, M.; Kotl&#225;r, M.; Tian, J.; et al. Combined in Situ Photoluminescence and X-ray Scattering Reveals Defect Formation in Lead-Halide Perovskite Films. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2021, 12 (41), 10156&#8211;10162[2] Held, V.; Mrkyvkova, N.; N&#225;da&#382;dy, P.; Vegso, K.; Vlk, A.; Ledinsk&#253;, M.; Jergel, M.; Chumakov, A.; Roth, S. V.; Schreiber, F.; et al. Evolution of Structure and Optoelectronic Properties During Halide Perovskite Vapor Deposition. J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2022, 13 (51), 11905&#8211;11912.[3] Chen, S.; Liu, Y.; Xiao, X.; Yu, Z.; Deng, Y.; Dai, X.; Ni, Z.; Huang, J. Identifying the Soft Nature of Defective Perovskite Surface Layer and Its Removal Using a Facile Mechanical Approach. Joule 2020, 4 (12), 2661&#8211;2674.[4] Kedia, M.; Rai, M.; Phirke, H.; Aranda, C. A.; Das, C.; Chirvony, V.; Boehringer, S.; Kot, M.; Byranvand, M. M.; Flege, J. I.; et al. Light Makes Right: Laser Polishing for Surface Modification of Perovskite Solar Cells. ACS Energy Lett. 2023, 8 (6), 2603&#8211;2610.Acknowledgements:We acknowledge the use of the CzechNanoLab research infrastructure (LM2023051) and the CEPLANT research infrastructure (LM2023039) supported by the MEYS and project number 9F23003 supported by the MEYS. Furthermore, we acknowledge the support of Czech Science Foundation Project No. 24-11652S. &#169; FUNDACIO DE LA COMUNITAT VALENCIANA SCITOnanoGe is a prestigious brand of successful science conferences that are developed along the year in different areas of the world since 2009. Our worldwide conferences cover cutting-edge materials topics like perovskite solar cells, photovoltaics, optoelectronics, solar fuel conversion, surface science, catalysis and two-dimensional materials, among many others.MATSUSPreviously nanoGe Spring Meeting (NSM) and nanoGe Fall Meeting (NFM), MATSUS is a multiple symposia conference focused on a broad set of topics of advanced materials preparation, their fundamental properties, and their applications, in fields such as renewable energy, photovoltaics, lighting, semiconductor quantum dots, 2-D materials synthesis, charge carriers dynamics, microscopy and spectroscopy semiconductors fundamentals, etc.International Conference on Hybrid and Organic PhotovoltaicsInternational Conference on Hybrid and Organic Photovoltaics (HOPV) is celebrated yearly in May. The main topics are the development, function and modeling of materials and devices for hybrid and organic solar cells. The field is now dominated by perovskite solar cells but also other hybrid technologies, as organic solar cells, quantum dot solar cells, and dye-sensitized solar cells and their integration into devices for photoelectrochemical solar fuel production.Asia-Pacific International Conference on Perovskite, Organic Photovoltaics and OptoelectronicsThe main topics of the Asia-Pacific International Conference on Perovskite, Organic Photovoltaics and Optoelectronics (IPEROP) are discussed every year in Asia-Pacific for gathering the recent advances in the fields of material preparation, modeling and fabrication of perovskite and hybrid and organic materials. Photovoltaic devices are analyzed from fundamental physics and materials properties to a broad set of applications. The conference also covers the developments of perovskite optoelectronics, including light-emitting diodes, lasers, optical devices, nanophotonics, nonlinear optical properties, colloidal nanostructures, photophysics and light-matter coupling.International Conference on Perovskite Thin Film Photovoltaics Perovskite Photonics and OptoelectronicsThe International Conference on Perovskite Thin Film Photovoltaics Perovskite Photonics and Optoelectronics (NIPHO) is the best place to hear the latest developments in perovskite solar cells as well as on recent advances in the fields of perovskite light-emitting diodes, lasers, optical devices, nanophotonics, nonlinear optical properties, colloidal nanostructures, photophysics and light-matter coupling.</description>
      <author>Ale&#353; Vlk, Robert Hlav&#225;&#269;, Lucie Landov&#225;, Julius A. Vida, Tom&#225;&#353; Homo&#318;a, A. Fejfar, Martin Ledinsk&#253;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.hopv.2024.116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#2473 Renal failure in the emergency department: indications for emergency hemodialysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ndt/gfae069.1579</link>
      <description>Hana Hedhli, Raouf Hajji, Mouna Jemai, Sarra Jouini, Chaima Mahrsia, Safia Othmani, Nephrology, dialysis, transplantation/Nephrology dialysis transplantation. 39(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398233752

                Abstract Background and Aims kidney failure is a frequent reason for emergency department (ED) visits. Patients may require emergency hemodialysis and this situation may increases mortality risk. We set out to study the clinical relevance and biological characteristics of patients with renal failure presenting to the emergency department with an indication for emergency hemodialysis. Method A prospective observational study conducted in ED conducted over a 6-month period. Patients were included if they were 18 years or older and suffering from acute or chronic renal insufficiency defined by creatinine clearance (CrCL) calculated by MDRD&amp;lt;60 ml/min. Information is recorded on demographics, clinical profile, clinical presentation, laboratory, causes of for emergency hemodialysis and in-hospital complications. Results Eighty one patients were enrolled, among them 61.7% patients had an indication for emergency hemodialysis. Mean age was 61&#177; 12, sex-ratio=1,7. Sixty seven patients (82.7%) were known to have a chronic kidney failure and 17.3 % were discovered at the emergency department at the same hospitalisation period. Clinical profile (%): Anuric patients (11.1), preserved diuresis (40.7). Clinical presentation (%): deterioration of general condition (35.8), dyspnea and chest pain (21) and fever (17.3). Clinical examination showed a peripheral oxygen saturation between 70 and 100% with a mean of 94.81, a respiratory rhythm mean of 20 cycles/min, a systolic blood pressure mean of 134.61 mmHg and a diastolic blood pressure mean of 70 mmHg. biological exams showed that kalemia was between 2.4 and 8.6 and 45 of those patients had kalemia more or equal to 5.5. Twelve per cent of these patients had hyperkalemia signs on the electrocardiogram. The average were 28 mmol/l with a maximum of 83.3 mmol/l. Creatinine values were between 185 et 2620 &#956;mol/l with a median of 81. The value of Ph was between 7.04 and 7.53 with a median of 7.29 mm Hg. The value of HCO3- value was between 4.6 and 28.4 with a median of 14.2. Causes of emergency hemodialysis were acidosis in 12 cases, severe anemia with blood transfusion in 4 cases, hyperkalemia in 10 cases, acute pulmonary oedema in 5 cases and acute renal failure in 6 cases .the evolution of the patients was marked by improvement of 61.7% of the patients, only 3 of the 81 patients died during the hospitalization. Conclusion This study showed that the causes of emergency dialysis can be avoided by improving care and educating patients to improve the prognosis.</description>
      <author>Hana Hedhli, Raouf Hajji, Mouna Jemai, Sarra Jouini, Chaima Mahrsia, Safia Othmani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ndt/gfae069.1579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Evolution of a Zirconium Alloy for Use as Pressure Tubes in Indian Pressurized Heavy Water Reactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/9789815196771124010008</link>
      <description>R.N. Singh, A.K. Bind, Sunil Kumar S, A. Sarkar, S. Neogy, Theta Murty, BENTHAM SCIENCE PUBLISHERS eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398141306

                &amp;nbsp;In the early generation of the Indian 220 MWe pressurized heavy water reactor (PHWR220), Zr-2.5Nb pressure tubes (PT) were manufactured from doublemelted (DM) ingots. Later on, quadruple melted (QM) ingots were used to achieve enhanced performance. These pressure tubes were fabricated by hot extrusion followed by double pilgering with intermediate annealing and this fabrication route is designated as an old route (OR). These tubes have performed reasonably well. However, some of these tubes showed higher in-reactor deformation. Subsequently, both alloy chemistry and manufacturing practice were revisited and changes in alloy chemistry and ingot diameter, mode of hot working for breaking the cast structure and hot extrusion of billets with higher extrusion ratio and single pilgering steps have been employed. This route is designated as a new route (NR) and is being used for manufacturing pressure tubes for the current generation of 220MWe pressurized heavy water reactors. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Over the years, changes in Chlorine (Cl), Carbon (C), Phosphorous (P), Iron (Fe) and Hydrogen (H) specification and narrowing down the specification for Niobium (Nb) and Oxygen (O) have been implemented to exploit their beneficial effect on in-reactor deformation and hydrogen pickup. The changes in manufacturing practices had resulted in changes in microstructure and texture. In the old route (OR), pressure tube (PT) microstructure was characterized by the presence of discrete beta-phase precipitates along the interfaces of alpha lamellae while the new route (NR) pressure tube (PT) exhibits more continuous beta film and relatively coarser &#945; lamellae. In terms of crystallographic texture too, the new route (NR) pressure tubes (PTs) had higher FT values (in the order of 0.65) in comparison to old route (OR) pressure tubes (PTs) (FT~0.55 to 0.6).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Because of crystallographic and microstructural anisotropy, the tensile behavior of this material is also anisotropic with the transverse direction exhibiting higher flow stress and lower ductility at and below reactor operating temperatures. The transverse tensile strength of pressure tube (PTs) fabricated from new route (NR) is higher than that fabricated from old route (OR). The fracture toughness of pressure tubes (PT) manufactured from quadruple melted (QM) ingots are significantly higher than that of the pressure tubes (PTs) manufactured from double melted (DM) ingots, which is attributed to the deleterious effect of Chlorine (Cl), Carbon (C), Phosphorous (P) and their complexes. The variation in fracture toughness of pressure tubes (PTs) was evaluated as a function of temperature, hydrogen content and hydride orientation. The hydrided material exhibited a typical S curve showing lower-shelf, transition and upper shelf regimes. Delayed hydride cracking velocity and threshold stress intensity factor were determined as a function of temperature, direction of approach to test temperature and hydride orientation. Threshold stress for hydride reorientation (&#963;th) determined using ex-situ and in-situ methods between 250 and 300oC was observed to decrease with an increase in temperature. Thermal creep behavior was investigated for these tubes at 350, 400 and 450 &#176;C at different stress levels and comparison of the minimum creep rate and the rupture life is presented. This article describes the evolution of the alloy chemistry, microstructural features, texture and mechanical properties and hydride induced embrittlement of the pressure tubes (PTs) used in Indian pressurized heavy water reactor (PHWR) and life extension approaches. An attempt has been made to rationalize the observed properties in terms of alloy chemistry and microstructure.</description>
      <author>R.N. Singh, A.K. Bind, Sunil Kumar S, A. Sarkar, S. Neogy, Theta Murty</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/9789815196771124010008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SGLT2 inhibitors act as metabolic transducers to restore healthy nutrient deprivation and surplus signaling in the kidney</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.kint.2024.01.044</link>
      <description>Shinji Kume, Milton Packer, Kidney international. 105(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398135622

                In the healthy adult kidney, cellular homeostasis is maintained by the balance between nutrient surplus and nutrient deprivation signaling.1Packer M. Fetal reprogramming of nutrient surplus signaling, O-GlcNAcylation, and the evolution of CKD.J Am Soc Nephrol. 2023; 34: 1480-1491Crossref Scopus (3) Google Scholar The primary nutrient deprivation signals are sirtuin 1 (SIRT1) and adenosine monophosphate protein kinase (AMPK), which are activated by low intracellular levels of glucose and adenosine triphosphate (ATP) and by the oxidation-reduction state, and function to reduce oxidative stress and proinflammatory signaling, thus promoting cellular survival. The primary nutrient surplus signals are mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) and hypoxia-inducible factor-1&#945; (HIF-1&#945;), which are activated by high intracellular levels of glucose to enhance flux through glucose-driven anabolic pathways and to promote maladaptive tubular hypertrophy, oxidative stress, inflammation, fibrosis, and apoptosis. Typically, the balancing of nutrient deprivation and surplus pathways maintains kidney health, with nutrient deprivation signals being dominant, thereby ensuring a reduced level of cellular stress that promotes cellular survival, particularly in the proximal renal tubule and glomerular podocytes and mesangial cells. Chronic kidney disease is characterized by an increase in cellular glucose uptake, which triggers upregulation of nutrient surplus signaling (mTOR and HIF-1&#945;) and downregulation of nutrient deprivation signals (SIRT1 and AMPK).1Packer M. Fetal reprogramming of nutrient surplus signaling, O-GlcNAcylation, and the evolution of CKD.J Am Soc Nephrol. 2023; 34: 1480-1491Crossref Scopus (3) Google Scholar,2Packer M. Role of impaired nutrient and oxygen deprivation signaling and deficient autophagic flux in diabetic CKD development: implications for understanding the effects of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2-inhibitors.J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020; 31: 907-919Crossref PubMed Scopus (80) Google Scholar The convergent result is to enhance oxidative stress in the proximal tubule and the glomerulus, while promoting renal inflammation, apoptosis, and fibrosis. Activation of mTOR/HIF-1&#945; and increased flux through the pentose phosphate pathway directs glucose away from ATP production and toward anabolic pathways, thus driving proximal tubular cells into the cell cycle. However, under high-workload normoxic conditions, cells driven toward growth exhibit maladaptive dedifferentiation rather than tubular renewal, leading to renal structural and functional disarray.1Packer M. Fetal reprogramming of nutrient surplus signaling, O-GlcNAcylation, and the evolution of CKD.J Am Soc Nephrol. 2023; 34: 1480-1491Crossref Scopus (3) Google Scholar The activation of mTOR/HIF-1&#945; is particularly notable in the proximal renal tubule, where it drives the development of albuminuria and fibrosis in the renal cortex, and underlies the progression of chronic kidney disease.3Kogot-Levin A. Hinden L. Riahi Y. et al.Proximal tubule mTORC1 is a central player in the pathophysiology of diabetic nephropathy and its correction by SGLT2 inhibitors.Cell Rep. 2020; 32107954Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (68) Google Scholar Furthermore, the simultaneous suppression of SIRT1/AMPK signaling in the proximal tubule abrogates the ability of these nutrient deprivation signals to promote mitochondrial biogenesis and mitophagy, the housekeeping pathway that allows cells to dispose of dysfunctional mitochondria and, thereby, maintain ATP production.1Packer M. Fetal reprogramming of nutrient surplus signaling, O-GlcNAcylation, and the evolution of CKD.J Am Soc Nephrol. 2023; 34: 1480-1491Crossref Scopus (3) Google Scholar,2Packer M. Role of impaired nutrient and oxygen deprivation signaling and deficient autophagic flux in diabetic CKD development: implications for understanding the effects of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2-inhibitors.J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020; 31: 907-919Crossref PubMed Scopus (80) Google Scholar This sequence of events explains the exceptional degree of structural and functional mitochondrial abnormalities seen in the proximal tubule and glomerular podocytes in chronic kidney disease.4Packer M. Critical reanalysis of the mechanisms underlying the cardiorenal benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors and reaffirmation of the nutrient deprivation signaling/autophagy hypothesis.Circulation. 2022; 146: 1383-1405Crossref PubMed Scopus (136) Google Scholar Sodium-glucose cotransporter 2 (SGLT2) inhibitors act to block the transport of glucose into the proximal tubule, and they also trigger a system-wide state of fasting mimicry, which is characterized by enhanced gluconeogenesis and ketogenesis. Under healthy conditions, the proximal tubule is the second most important source of gluconeogenesis.2Packer M. Role of impaired nutrient and oxygen deprivation signaling and deficient autophagic flux in diabetic CKD development: implications for understanding the effects of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2-inhibitors.J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020; 31: 907-919Crossref PubMed Scopus (80) Google Scholar,4Packer M. Critical reanalysis of the mechanisms underlying the cardiorenal benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors and reaffirmation of the nutrient deprivation signaling/autophagy hypothesis.Circulation. 2022; 146: 1383-1405Crossref PubMed Scopus (136) Google Scholar This metabolic task is lost in chronic kidney disease, but it is restored by SGLT2 inhibitors through their ability to upregulate SIRT1 signaling, thus redirecting glucose away from anabolism, and promoting the oxidation of fatty acids and glucose to enhance the production of ATP. The ability to produce ATP action is facilitated by an effect of SIRT1 and AMPK to restore mitochondrial health through actions to reduce oxidative stress, enhance mitophagy, and augment mitochondrial biogenesis.4Packer M. Critical reanalysis of the mechanisms underlying the cardiorenal benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors and reaffirmation of the nutrient deprivation signaling/autophagy hypothesis.Circulation. 2022; 146: 1383-1405Crossref PubMed Scopus (136) Google Scholar At the same time, SGLT2 inhibitors suppress signaling through mTOR and HIF-1&#945;, further mitigating oxidative stress and acting to mute proinflammatory and profibrotic pathways in glomerular podocytes and mesangial cells and in the proximal tubule. There is considerable experimental evidence to support an effect of SGLT2 inhibitors to restore cytoprotective signaling as the primary mechanism underlying their renoprotective effects (Figure 1). Using single-cell RNA-sequencing analysis of the kidneys of diabetic mice, Wu et al.5Wu H. Gonzalez Villalobos R. Yao X. et al.Mapping the single-cell transcriptomic response of murine diabetic kidney disease to therapies.Cell Metab. 2022; 34: 1064-1078Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (67) Google Scholar demonstrated that SGLT2 inhibitors induce a state of fasting mimicry and hypoxia in the proximal renal tubule by restoring the splicing of master genes that are responsible for health cellular metabolism. Inoue et al.6Inoue M.K. Matsunaga Y. Nakatsu Y. et al.Possible involvement of normalized Pin1 expression level and AMPK activation in the molecular mechanisms underlying renal protective effects of SGLT2 inhibitors in mice.Diabetol Metab Syndr. 2019; 11: 57Crossref Scopus (45) Google Scholar showed that canagliflozin reduced mesangial cell proliferation and peritubular fibrosis; these effects were accompanied by increased AMPK phosphorylation, and the benefits of SGLT2 inhibition were abrogated by AMPK inhibition. Liu et al.7Liu X. Xu C. Xu L. et al.Empagliflozin improves diabetic renal tubular injury by alleviating mitochondrial fission via AMPK/SP1/PGAM5 pathway.Metabolism. 2020; 111154334Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF Scopus (61) Google Scholar reported that empagliflozin reduced oxidative stress, mitochondrial dysfunction, and apoptosis in proximal tubular cells exposed to high glucose; these effects were accompanied by upregulation of AMPK and were abrogated by AMPK inhibition. Using a similar model, Xu et al.8Xu J. Kitada M. Ogura Y. et al.Dapagliflozin restores impaired autophagy and suppresses inflammation in high glucose-treated HK-2 cells.Cells. 2021; 10: 1457Crossref PubMed Scopus (64) Google Scholar observed that dapagliflozin reduced proinflammatory signaling and increased AMPK phosphorylation; the benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors were eliminated by AMPK inhibition. Zhang et al.9Zhang Z. Ni L. Zhang L. et al.Empagliflozin regulates the AdipoR1/p-AMPK/p-ACC pathway to alleviate lipid deposition in diabetic nephropathy.Diabetes Metab Syndr Obes. 2021; 14: 227-240Crossref PubMed Scopus (25) Google Scholar showed that empagliflozin reduced interstitial fibrosis in murine diabetic nephropathy; this benefit was accompanied by increased AMPK phosphorylation and abolished by AMPK inhibition. Park et al.10Park C.H. Lee B. Han M. et al.Canagliflozin protects against cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury by AMPK-mediated autophagy in renal proximal tubular cells.Cell Death Discov. 2022; 8: 12Crossref Scopus (21) Google Scholar noted that canagliflozin increased cell viability and prevented cellular injury in HK2 proximal tubular cells exposed to cisplatin, and these benefits were abolished by AMPK inhibition. Yang et al.11Yang L. Liang B. Li J. et al.Dapagliflozin alleviates advanced glycation end product induced podocyte injury through AMPK/mTOR mediated autophagy pathway.Cell Signal. 2022; 90110206Crossref Scopus (25) Google Scholar showed that dapagliflozin reduced proinflammatory signaling and apoptosis in cultured podocytes exposed to advanced glycation end products; these effects were accompanied by increased AMPK phosphorylation and abrogated by AMPK inhibition. Importantly, in the reports by Xu et al.,8Xu J. Kitada M. Ogura Y. et al.Dapagliflozin restores impaired autophagy and suppresses inflammation in high glucose-treated HK-2 cells.Cells. 2021; 10: 1457Crossref PubMed Scopus (64) Google Scholar Park et al.10Park C.H. Lee B. Han M. et al.Canagliflozin protects against cisplatin-induced acute kidney injury by AMPK-mediated autophagy in renal proximal tubular cells.Cell Death Discov. 2022; 8: 12Crossref Scopus (21) Google Scholar and Yang et al.,11Yang L. Liang B. Li J. et al.Dapagliflozin alleviates advanced glycation end product induced podocyte injury through AMPK/mTOR mediated autophagy pathway.Cell Signal. 2022; 90110206Crossref Scopus (25) Google Scholar the favorable effects of SGLT2 inhibitors were also abolished by pharmacologic silencing of autophagic flux and mitophagy, thus identifying a key adaptive mechanism by which enhanced nutrient deprivation signaling might exert cytoprotective effects.4Packer M. Critical reanalysis of the mechanisms underlying the cardiorenal benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors and reaffirmation of the nutrient deprivation signaling/autophagy hypothesis.Circulation. 2022; 146: 1383-1405Crossref PubMed Scopus (136) Google Scholar These experiments demonstrating that the effects of SGLT2 inhibitors are mediated by upregulation of SIRT1 and AMPK are paralleled by experiments reporting that SGLT2 inhibitors suppress mTOR/HIF-1&#945; signaling. Li et al.12Li J. Liu H. Takagi S. et al.Renal protective effects of empagliflozin via inhibition of EMT and aberrant glycolysis in proximal tubules.JCI Insight. 2020; 5e129034Crossref Scopus (136) Google Scholar showed that high-glucose media induced endothelial-mesenchymal transition, which was accompanied by suppression of SIRT signaling, upregulation of HIF-1&#945;, and aberrant glycolysis. SGLT2 knockdown reversed these abnormalities and inhibited the mesenchymal transition of proximal tubular cells and neighboring endothelial cells. Kogot-Levin et al.3Kogot-Levin A. Hinden L. Riahi Y. et al.Proximal tubule mTORC1 is a central player in the pathophysiology of diabetic nephropathy and its correction by SGLT2 inhibitors.Cell Rep. 2020; 32107954Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (68) Google Scholar noted that dapagliflozin inhibited peritubular fibrosis and preserved glomerular function in a mouse model of diabetic nephropathy; these benefits were accompanied by suppression of mTOR activation, and the benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors were abolished by constitutive overactivation of mTOR. Tomita et al.13Tomita I. Kume S. Sugahara S. et al.SGLT2 inhibition mediates protection from diabetic kidney disease by promoting ketone body-induced mTORC1 inhibition.Cell Metab. 2020; 32: 404-419.e6Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (195) Google Scholar demonstrated the importance of mTOR suppression in several models of chronic kidney disease. Empaglifozin prevented podocyte and tubulointerstitial lesions while inhibiting mTOR signaling in nondiabetic chronic kidney disease produced in 5/6 nephrectomized mice. In proximal tubular cells of ApoE-deficient mice subjected to a high-fat diet, mTOR hyperactivation played a critical role in mediating the progression of chronic kidney disease, but this effect was abolished by empagliflozin. Interestingly, the favorable effects of empagliflozin were mimicked by 1,3-butanediol, a ketone body precursor, and the renoprotective effects of empagliflozin were prevented by knockout of 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl-coenzyme A synthase 2, the rate-limiting enzyme for ketogenesis. These observations suggested that ketone bodies produced by SGLT2 inhibitors as an effect of starvation mimicry may help to mediate their effects on nutrient surplus and nutrient deprivation signaling. Other investigators have also proposed that ketone bodies may function as metabolic signaling molecules (acting to upregulate SIRT1 and downregulate mTOR) rather than serving as an alternative fuel for the production of ATP.2Packer M. Role of impaired nutrient and oxygen deprivation signaling and deficient autophagic flux in diabetic CKD development: implications for understanding the effects of sodium-glucose cotransporter 2-inhibitors.J Am Soc Nephrol. 2020; 31: 907-919Crossref PubMed Scopus (80) Google Scholar,4Packer M. Critical reanalysis of the mechanisms underlying the cardiorenal benefits of SGLT2 inhibitors and reaffirmation of the nutrient deprivation signaling/autophagy hypothesis.Circulation. 2022; 146: 1383-1405Crossref PubMed Scopus (136) Google Scholar In fact, in the report by Tomita et al.,13Tomita I. Kume S. Sugahara S. et al.SGLT2 inhibition mediates protection from diabetic kidney disease by promoting ketone body-induced mTORC1 inhibition.Cell Metab. 2020; 32: 404-419.e6Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (195) Google Scholar the increase in proximal tubular ATP production following 1,3-butanediol was related to enhanced oxidation of long-chain fatty acids (rather than ketolysis), the expected result if restoration of cellular energetics was due to an improvement in mitochondrial function. Importantly, these effects have been demonstrated not only in animal models, but in cultured cells, which are not subject to hemodynamic perturbations. It is understood that many nephrologists believe that SGLT2 inhibitors exert renoprotective effects by increasing sodium delivery to the distal nephron and macula densa. The enhanced distal delivery of sodium has been hypothesized to increase distal tubular workload, leading to hypoxia at the corticomedullary junction. Furthermore, the augmented delivery to the macula densa might activate tubuloglomerular feedback and reduce intraglomerular filtration pressures, which has been proposed to slow the evolution of chronic kidney disease. However, the results of clinical and experimental studies do not support the pathophysiological importance of these hemodynamic changes. SGLT2 inhibitors do not produce renal medullary hypoxia in patients without diabetes14Zanchi A. Burnier M. Muller M.E. et al.Acute and chronic effects of SGLT2 inhibitor empagliflozin on renal oxygenation and blood pressure control in nondiabetic normotensive subjects: a randomized, placebo-controlled trial.J Am Heart Assoc. 2020; 9e016173Crossref Scopus (63) Google Scholar; instead, the source of increased erythropoietin production and erythrocytosis following SGLT2 inhibition appears to be the activation of SIRT1, which leads to increased expression of hypoxic-inducible factor-2&#945; and erythropoietin production, not only in the kidney but also in the liver. Furthermore, although alleviation of glomerular hyperfiltration might exert renoprotective effects in states of hyperfiltration (i.e., diabetes), patients with heart failure do not have glomerular hyperfiltration, but nevertheless, they show a reduction in major adverse renal outcomes with SGLT2 inhibitors in large-scale trials. Interestingly, the finding of a short-term decline in glomerular filtration rate following initiation of SGLT2 inhibitors may be explained by an effect of AMPK upregulation to enhance tubuloglomerular feedback rather than an effect on distal tubular sodium delivery.15Huang D.Y. Gao H. Boini K.M. et al.In vivo stimulation of AMP-activated protein kinase enhanced tubuloglomerular feedback but reduced tubular sodium transport during high dietary NaCl intake.Pflugers Arch. 2010; 460: 187-196Crossref Scopus (16) Google Scholar Taken together, there is a critical mass of experimental evidence that supports a renoprotective effect of SGLT2 inhibitors, which is mediated by upregulation of SIRT/1AMPK and downregulation of mTOR/HIF-1&#945; in the proximal tubule and in glomerular podocytes and mesangial cells. These drugs exert consistent effects to mute oxidative stress, restore mitochondrial health, mitigate proinflammatory and profibrotic signaling, and prevent cell death, thus maintaining the normal architecture and physiology of the kidney. Importantly, in numerous experimental studies, these renoprotective effects are abolished if SIRT1/AMPK/autophagy is silenced or if mTOR is overactivated. Therefore, SGLT2 inhibitors act as modulators of nutrient deprivation and nutrient surplus signaling to restore healthy proximal renal tubular homeostasis and metabolism. All the authors declared no competing interests. SGLT2 inhibitor: 2-way superstar in nephrology?Kidney InternationalVol. 105Issue 6PreviewShohei Ohtani became an amazing 2-way player in a modern-day game of baseball that basically never sees them, and he won his second American League most valuable player award unanimously in 2023. Full-Text PDF Kidney protective mechanisms of SGLT2 inhibitors: evidence for a hemodynamic effectKidney InternationalVol. 105Issue 6PreviewSodium-glucose cotransporter-2 (SGLT2) inhibitors were introduced a decade ago for the treatment of type 2 diabetes (T2D) and have emerged as a key therapy for the treatment of chronic kidney disease (CKD). In trials with primary kidney end points, SGLT2 inhibitors reduced the composite of kidney failure, kidney death, and doubling of serum creatinine by 28% to 39%.1 Benefits of this class of medication are independent of glycemic lowering, as glucose lowering with other drug classes has not been associated with similar improvements in kidney outcomes. Full-Text PDF</description>
      <author>Shinji Kume, Milton Packer</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.kint.2024.01.044</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
