<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 01:24:23 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the influence of deposited layers on Ti/RuO2 anodes to define the electroactivity of oxygen evolution and active chlorine reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118645</link>
      <description>Juan M. Sterling-Montealegre, Luis Norberto Ben&#237;tez, Ricardo E. Palma&#8208;Goyes, Rosa Mar&#237;a Luna-S&#225;nchez, Franklin Ferraro, Roberto Luis Palomino Resendiz, Selene Montserrat Garc&#237;a-Solares, Jorge Vazquez&#8208;Arenas, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402327121

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juan M. Sterling-Montealegre, Luis Norberto Ben&#237;tez, Ricardo E. Palma&#8208;Goyes, Rosa Mar&#237;a Luna-S&#225;nchez, Franklin Ferraro, Roberto Luis Palomino Resendiz, Selene Montserrat Garc&#237;a-Solares, Jorge Vazquez&#8208;Arenas</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe-spinel oxides with nitrogen-doped carbon quantum dots for enhanced oxygen evolution activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118632</link>
      <description>Xinping Yang, Q. T. Tao, Yan Zhang, Jingwen Liu, Jiwen Si, Weikun Ning, Yanbin Sun, Fagui Qiu, Wenqing Li, Shiding Miao, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402328148

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinping Yang, Q. T. Tao, Yan Zhang, Jingwen Liu, Jiwen Si, Weikun Ning, Yanbin Sun, Fagui Qiu, Wenqing Li, Shiding Miao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial regulation of CdIn2S4 and oxygen evolution cocatalyst for rapid hole extraction for photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.481</link>
      <description>Jiangchuan Liu, Yue Zhang, Shengkang Min, Yurong Ren, Changhai Liu, Zhidong Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 87(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402332153

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiangchuan Liu, Yue Zhang, Shengkang Min, Yurong Ren, Changhai Liu, Zhidong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Synthesis of CuO/MnAl2O4 nanocomposite as electrocatalysts for robust oxygen evolution reaction&#8221; [J. Phys. Chem. Solids Volume 193, October 2024, 112121]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112295</link>
      <description>Munaza sadiq, B.M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Khalid I. Hussein, Md Rezaul Karim, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402333018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munaza sadiq, B.M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Khalid I. Hussein, Md Rezaul Karim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Bimetallic Niru@Ti3c2tx Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution: The Impact of Mxene Content on Ru Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4949211</link>
      <description>Merve Buldu&#8208;Akturk, Thorsten Schultz, N. L. Sharma, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402337294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Merve Buldu&#8208;Akturk, Thorsten Schultz, N. L. Sharma, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4949211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the configuration entropy of layered hydroxides toward efficient oxygen evolution reaction for anion exchange membrane electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.08.008</link>
      <description>Da Liu, Peifang Guo, Xiaoxiao Yan, Yufei He, Renbing Wu, Materials Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402339642

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Da Liu, Peifang Guo, Xiaoxiao Yan, Yufei He, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.08.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinly-walled NiFe2O4 nanotubes derived from Ni, Fe, N-codoped carbon nanofibers toward oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solidstatesciences.2024.107691</link>
      <description>Zhan Tian, He Wang, Guoqiang Li, Hongrui Jia, Guoxin Zhang, Solid State Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402341259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhan Tian, He Wang, Guoqiang Li, Hongrui Jia, Guoxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solidstatesciences.2024.107691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of nickel-manganese based bimetallic hydroxide nanosheets for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2838/1/012002</link>
      <description>Shilin Li, Yuran Li, Yue Bian, Han Guo, Yifan Guo, You Long, Zhi Hong Lu, Guangxin Wang, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2838(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402357938

                Abstract This paper uses a common one-step hydrothermal method to prepare NiMn-LDH/NF (Layered Double Hydroxide, LDH) oxygen evolution catalyst with outstanding performance. The NiMn-LDH grows into a nanosheet array structure on nickel foam (NF) and it has a big surface area and exceptional ion transport function that could accelerate the diffusion rate of electrocatalytic products. It attempted to modulate the molar proportion of Ni and Mn to explore the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of the NiMn-LDH/NF catalysts. It was found that when Ni:Mn=4:1 (molar ratio, hereinafter), the nanosheets grew more densely and had better OER performance and stability. The electrochemical test results show that the Ni 4 Mn-LDH/NF catalyst exhibits an overvoltage of 341 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and the Tafel slope is only 98.99 mV dec &#8722;1 .</description>
      <author>Shilin Li, Yuran Li, Yue Bian, Han Guo, Yifan Guo, You Long, Zhi Hong Lu, Guangxin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2838/1/012002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salt-Flower-Shaped Fep-Cop for Highly Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4950897</link>
      <description>Leilei Li, Xue Jia, Xing-Liang Yin, Ze&#8208;Feng Xu, Chuan-Wu Chen, Ya&#8208;Nan Jing, D. Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402360029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leilei Li, Xue Jia, Xing-Liang Yin, Ze&#8208;Feng Xu, Chuan-Wu Chen, Ya&#8208;Nan Jing, D. Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4950897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advantages on mass transfer structure construction in transition metal&#8208;based cost&#8208;effective catalyst toward alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401166</link>
      <description>Xuehua Zhang, Li Zhang, Songlei Lv, Guodong Xu, Jiawei Shi, Jiehao Li, Weiwei Cai, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402373926

                The electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can be combined with various reactions to fabricate electrochemical energy conversion and storage devices while the slow kinetics and poor mass transfer capability at high current densities were the key constraints to its large&#8208;scale application. Therefore, this review primarily focuses on design and optimization of mass transfer structures of TM&#8208;metal&#8208;based OER catalysts. Nanostructuring, porous design, and the creation of hierarchical architectures have been applied during catalyst synthesis to enhance the surface area and accessibility, thereby improving mass transfer and catalytic OER efficiency. Strategies including doping, substrate invitation, soft/hard templating has been utilized to accelerate mass transfer as well as the ion/electron conduction efficiency for the overall improvement of OER performance of the catalysts. These developments underline the critical role of advanced material design in achieving high&#8208;performance OER catalysts and highlight the potential of TM&#8208;based materials in cost&#8208;effective and scalable applications.</description>
      <author>Xuehua Zhang, Li Zhang, Songlei Lv, Guodong Xu, Jiawei Shi, Jiehao Li, Weiwei Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Nanostructures of Iron Phthalocyanine Nanowires Coated on Nickel Foam as Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29174272</link>
      <description>Xianying Meng, Peng Yu, Mingyi Zhang, Molecules. 29(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402374762

                In this paper, iron phthalocyanine nanowires on a nickel foam (FePc@NF) composite catalyst were prepared by a facile solvothermal approach. The catalyst showed good electrochemical oxygen evolution performance. In 1.0 M KOH electrolyte, 289 mV low overpotential and 49.9 mV dec&#8722;1 Tafel slope were seen at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The excellent electrochemical performance comes from the homogeneous dispersion of phthalocyanine nanostructures on the surface of the nickel foam, which avoids the common agglomeration problem of such catalysts and provides a large number of active sites for the OER reaction, thus improving the catalytic performance of the system.</description>
      <author>Xianying Meng, Peng Yu, Mingyi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29174272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Sandwich&#8208;Type Porphyrinic MOF&#8208;Ruthenium&#8211;Nickel Foam Electrode for Boosting Overall Water Splitting via Self&#8208;Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401082</link>
      <description>Tingting Liu, Xinhui Yu, Yuanyuan Wu, Xianyu Chu, Wei Jiang, Bo Liu, Chunbo Liu, Guangbo Che, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402376525

                Abstract The rational construction of a hierarchical noble metal&#8211;metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) structure is anticipated to yield enduring and highly efficient performance in alkaline electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, a sandwich construction strategy is employed to enhance the stability, wherein active RutheniRu (Ru) nanosheets are incorporated onto nickel foam (NF) and subsequently covered with porphyrinic MOFs (PMOFs). In addition, activated PMOF&#8208;NiOOH&#8208;Ru 20 /NF&#8208;C/A electrodes are obtained by electrochemical self&#8208;reconstruction as cathode and anode, respectively. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrated that the resulting PMOF&#8208;NiOOH&#8208;Ru heterointerface effectively facilitated electron transfer, enhanced H 2 O adsorption capacity, and optimized &#916; G values for * H and * O to * OOH. Consequently, PMOF&#8208;NiOOH&#8208;Ru 20 /NF&#8208;C/A exhibited low overpotentials for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), accompanied by minimal Ru leakage. Furthermore, stable overall water splitting can be achieved with a low voltage of 1.456 V@10 mA cm &#8722;2 for over 120 h. Even when operated in simulated seawater, the prepared electrodes demonstrated similar activity and stability. This study contributes to a deeper understanding of the regulation mechanism for the performance and stability of active sites in the electrocatalytic self&#8208;reconstruction process.</description>
      <author>Tingting Liu, Xinhui Yu, Yuanyuan Wu, Xianyu Chu, Wei Jiang, Bo Liu, Chunbo Liu, Guangbo Che</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Role of Electrocatalysts Activation for Iron&#8208;Doped Ni Oxyhydroxide in Enhancing the Catalytic Performance of Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12827</link>
      <description>Jiyoung Kim, JeongEun Yoo, Kiyoung Lee, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377490

                Water electrolysis using renewable electricity is a promising strategy for high&#8208;purity hydrogen production. To realize the practical application of water electrolysis, an electrocatalyst with high redox properties and low cost is essential for enhancing the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction. Herein, we fabricated Fe&#8208;doped nickel oxalate (Fe&#8208;NiC 2 O 4 ) directly grown on nickel (Ni) foam as an efficient electrocatalyst for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction using a facile one&#8208;step hydrothermal method. Fe&#8208;NiC 2 O 4 served as a precursor for obtaining highly active Fe&#8208;doped Ni oxyhydroxide (Fe&#8208;NiOOH) via in situ electrochemical oxidation. Consequently, 0.75Fe&#8208;NiOOH was demonstrated to be the optimal electrocatalyst, exhibiting outstanding oxygen evolution reaction activity with a low overpotential of 220 mV at a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 20.5 mV dec &#8722;1 . Furthermore, Fe&#8208;NiOOH maintained its oxygen evolution reaction activity without performance decay during long&#8208;term electrochemical measurements, owing to the phase transformation from nickel oxyhydroxide (NiOOH) to &#947;&#8208;NiOOH (gamma nickel oxyhydroxide). These performances significantly surpass those of recently reported transition&#8208;metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiyoung Kim, JeongEun Yoo, Kiyoung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Modification Effect of Se&#8208;doped Porous Carbon for Hydrogen Evolution Coupled Selective Electrooxidation of Ethylene Glycol to Value&#8208;added Glycolic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404540</link>
      <description>Daehee Jang, Minseon Park, Junbeom Maeng, Jungseub Ha, Si&#8208;Young Choi, Nayeon Kim, Min Ho Seo, Won Bae Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377581

                Abstract The ethylene glycol oxidation reaction (EGOR) has attracted attention because ethylene glycol (EG), which exhibits large&#8208;scale production and a low market price, can be reformed into valuable glycolic acid (GCA) with the cogeneration of high&#8208;purity hydrogen gas during the reaction. In this study, a noble catalyst material of Pt nanoparticles supported on Se&#8208;doped porous carbon (Pt/SePC) is prepared and investigated for the selective electrochemical oxidation of EG to GCA. Pt/SePC achieved a maximum EG conversion of 94.6% and GCA selectivity of 84.4% and maintained this high performance with negligible degradation during durability tests. Furthermore, the EGOR required lower overpotential rather than the oxygen evolution reaction, thus the EGOR coupled with the hydrogen evolution reaction can reduce the cell overpotential to 0.60 V, which is much lower than that of water electrolysis (1.58 V). The effect of Se doping is investigated through experimental analyses and density functional theory (DFT) calculations, and they shows that Se modified the binding energy of Pt nanoparticles and the adsorption energy of reactants by lattice deformation and charge density modification. This study provides scientific insights and strategies for electrocatalyst design for the selective oxidation of polyols to value&#8208;added chemicals via the cogeneration of hydrogen gas.</description>
      <author>Daehee Jang, Minseon Park, Junbeom Maeng, Jungseub Ha, Si&#8208;Young Choi, Nayeon Kim, Min Ho Seo, Won Bae Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetically Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Mild Alkaline Electrolytes by Building Catalysts on Magnetic Frame</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405946</link>
      <description>Ming Xie, Haotian Wang, Xianjun Li, Guojun Han, Yongqiang Yang, Xinyue Shi, Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Guo&#8208;Xing Miao, Meng&#8208;Hao Yang, Jing Fu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377734

                Abstract Under large current densities, the excessive hydroxide ion (OH) consumption hampers alkaline water splitting involving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). High OH concentration (&#8776;30 wt.%) is often used to enhance the catalytic activity of OER, but it also leads to higher corrosion in practical systems. To achieve higher catalytic activity in low OH concentration, catalysts on magnetic frame (CMF) are built to utilize the local magnetic convection induced from the host frame's magnetic field distributions. This way, a higher reaction rate can be achieved in relatively lower OH concentrations. A CMF model system with catalytically active CoFeO x nanograins grown on the magnetic Ni foam is demonstrated. The OER current of CoFeO x @NF receives &#8776;90% enhancement under 400 mT (900 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.65 V) compared to that in zero field, and exhibits remarkable durability over 120 h. As a demonstration, the water&#8208;splitting performance sees a maximum 45% magnetic enhancement under 400 mT in 1 m KOH (700 mA cm &#8722;2 at 2.4 V), equivalent to the concentration enhancement of the same electrode in a more corrosive 2 m KOH electrolyte. Therefore, the catalyst&#8208;on&#8208;magnetic&#8208;frame strategy can make efficient use of the catalysts and achieve higher catalytic activity in low OH concentration by harvesting local magnetic convection.</description>
      <author>Ming Xie, Haotian Wang, Xianjun Li, Guojun Han, Yongqiang Yang, Xinyue Shi, Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Guo&#8208;Xing Miao, Meng&#8208;Hao Yang, Jing Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis and Characterization of Copper Phosphide Nanoparticles as Efficient Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-024-09514-4</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zeeshan Shakir, Samina Akbar, Imran Raza, Muhammad Awais, Saima Rehman, Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402379412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zeeshan Shakir, Samina Akbar, Imran Raza, Muhammad Awais, Saima Rehman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-024-09514-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface&#8208;Engineered Ni2P: An Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400684</link>
      <description>C. Retna Raj, Mopidevi Manikanta Kumar, Rahul Singh, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402379719

                The surface engineering of electrocatalysts is one of the promising strategies to increase the intrinsic activity of electrocatalysts. It generates anion/cation vacancy defects and increases the electrochemically active surface area. We describe the surface engineering of Ni2P to favorably tune the bifunctional oxygen electrocatalytic activity and the development of a rechargeable zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB). Ni2P encapsulated with N and P&#8208;dual doped carbon (Ni2P@NPC) is synthesized using a single&#8208;source precursor complex tris&#8208;(2,2'&#8208;bipyridine)nickel(II) bis(hexafluorophosphate). The surface engineering of the as&#8208;synthesized Ni2P@NPC is achieved by the controlled acid treatment at room temperature. The surface engineering removes carbon debris and opens the pores, exfoliates the encapsulating carbon layer, increases the P&#8208;vacancy in the crystal lattice, and boosts the electrochemically active surface area. The surface&#8208;engineered catalyst exhibits enhanced bifunctional activity towards oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The electrocatalytically active sites of engineered catalysts are highly accessible for facilitated electron transfer kinetics. P&#8208;vacancy favors the facile formation of defect&#8208;rich OER active metal oxyhydroxide species. The rechargeable ZAB based on the engineered catalyst delivers a specific capacity of 770.25 mA h gZn&#8208;1, energy density of 692 Wh kgZn&#8208;1, and excellent charge&#8208;discharge cycling performance with negligible voltaic efficiency loss (0.6 %) after 100 h.</description>
      <author>C. Retna Raj, Mopidevi Manikanta Kumar, Rahul Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral helically grooved gold nanoarrows for concurrently enhancing oxygen and hydrogen evolution from electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2136-1</link>
      <description>Lufei Huang, Tao Wang, Ying Li, Ping Wang, Rui Tian, Baowen Zhou, Lin Yao, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402381472

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lufei Huang, Tao Wang, Ying Li, Ping Wang, Rui Tian, Baowen Zhou, Lin Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2136-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of nanocrystalline NiCo2S4 and NiCo alloy embedded in N-doped carbon fibers towards high-performance electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176441</link>
      <description>Xiaobo Yang, Shuang Liang, G. Wang, Bao Zhou, Zhuoqi Duan, Z.X. Xie, Yongmao Hu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1007(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402388057

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaobo Yang, Shuang Liang, G. Wang, Bao Zhou, Zhuoqi Duan, Z.X. Xie, Yongmao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of Co-doped In2O3 integrated with tubular g-C3N4 heterostructure and their synergistic effect on the enhanced photocatalytic degradation of tetracycline and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135340</link>
      <description>Saranraj Kumaravel, Sakthivel Kumaravel, Arkadeep Mukherjee, B. Subash, Govindasami Periyasami, Chandrasatheesh Chandramoorthy, Elangovan Erusappan, Prathap Somu, Young&#8208;Ho Ahn, Chuan-Ming Liu, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402391214

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saranraj Kumaravel, Sakthivel Kumaravel, Arkadeep Mukherjee, B. Subash, Govindasami Periyasami, Chandrasatheesh Chandramoorthy, Elangovan Erusappan, Prathap Somu, Young&#8208;Ho Ahn, Chuan-Ming Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135340</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Earth-Abundant Divalent Cation High-Entropy Spinel Ferrites as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01227</link>
      <description>Tuncay Erdil, Cagla Ozgur, Uygar Geyikci, Ersu LOKCU, &#199;i&#287;dem Toparl&#305;, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402393824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tuncay Erdil, Cagla Ozgur, Uygar Geyikci, Ersu LOKCU, &#199;i&#287;dem Toparl&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01227</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guided Heterostructure Growth of CoFe LDH on Ti&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;T&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; MXene for Durably High Oxygen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404927</link>
      <description>Jiali Sheng, Jiahui Kang, Pan Jiang, Kristoffer Meinander, Xiaodan Hong, Hua Jiang, Nonappa Nonappa, Olli Ikkala, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Bo Peng, Zhongyang Lv, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402395833

                Abstract Heterostructures of layered double hydroxides (LDHs) and MXenes have shown great promise for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, owing to their complementary physical properties. Coupling LDHs with MXenes can potentially enhance their conductivity, stability, and OER activity. In this work, a scalable and straightforward in situ guided growth of CoFeLDH on Ti 3 C 2 T x is introduced, where the surface chemistry of Ti 3 C 2 T x dominates the resulting heterostructures, allowing tunable crystal domain sizes of LDHs. Combined simulation results of Monte Carlo and density functional theory (DFT) validate this guided growth mechanism. Through this way, the optimized heterostructures allow the highest OER activity of the overpotential = 301 mV and Tafel slope = 43 mV dec &#8722;1 at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a considerably durable stability of 0.1% decay over 200 h use, remarkably outperforming all reported LDHs&#8208;MXenes materials. DFT calculations indicate that the charge transfer in heterostructures can decrease the rate&#8208;limiting energy barrier for OER, facilitating OER activity. The combined experimental and theoretical efforts identify the participation role of MXene in heterostructures for OER reactions, providing insights into designing advanced heterostructures for robust OER electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Jiali Sheng, Jiahui Kang, Pan Jiang, Kristoffer Meinander, Xiaodan Hong, Hua Jiang, Nonappa Nonappa, Olli Ikkala, Hannu&#8208;Pekka Komsa, Bo Peng, Zhongyang Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergy of nitrogen dopants and cobalt single atoms in calcium niobate nanosheets for photocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/ad7903</link>
      <description>Sajjad ul Haq, Takuji Ohigashi, Yucheng Huang, Rabia Rehman, Essossimna Djatoubai, Zhi Lin, Muhammad Shuaib Khan, Shaohua Shen, Journal of Physics Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402397842

                Abstract Successful separation of photoexcited charge carriers and their effective utilization are crucial for overcoming the slow kinetics of the four-electron process for photocatalytic oxygen evolution. Herein, a novel strategy utilizing urea as a source of N-doping on Ca2Nb3O10 nanosheets is adopted followed by the successful deposition of Co single atoms (Co-SAs) to achieve a synergistic effect. The presence of N-dopants and Co-SAs is validated via various experimental techniques. Besides, it is observed that the presence of N-doping contributed towards deposition of higher content of Co-SAs (0.21 wt%) in Ca2Nb3O10-xNx&#172;-CoSA nanosheets compared to 0.15 wt% for non-doped Ca2Nb3O10-CoSA. The optimized Ca2Nb3O10-xNx-CoSA nanosheets exhibited an impressive photocatalytic O2 evolution of ~727.22 &#181;mol g-1 h-1 via the synergy of N-dopants and Co-SAs. As a result, O2 evolution response of Ca2Nb3O10-xNx-CoSA is 3.6 times higher than pristine Ca2Nb3O10 nanosheets (201.26 &#181;mol g-1 h-1), 2.24 times better than Ca2Nb3O10-xNx nanosheets (323.42 &#181;mol g-1 h-1), and 1.77 times higher compared to Ca2Nb3O10-CoSA, (409.33 &#181;mol g-1 h-1), clearly demonstrated the synergistic effect of N-dopants and Co-SAs in Ca2Nb3O10-xNx-CoSA nanosheets. Base on the finding of various characterization techniques, the co-presence of N-dopants and Co-SAs is observed to contribute towards better charge carriers separation, and utilization to achieve superior photocatalytic response. Thus, this work presents a novel approach for incorporating N-dopants and Co-SAs on Ca2Nb3O10 nanosheets which can be extended to wide range of nanosheets produced by the soft chemical exfoliation method.</description>
      <author>Sajjad ul Haq, Takuji Ohigashi, Yucheng Huang, Rabia Rehman, Essossimna Djatoubai, Zhi Lin, Muhammad Shuaib Khan, Shaohua Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/ad7903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Cation Exchange Induced 2D Nickel Sulphide Nanoplates with Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05191b</link>
      <description>Jiayi Chen, Xiaomin Xu, Rundong Mao, Cuifang Wang, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Zongyou Yin, Mark A. Buntine, Alexandra Suvorova, Martin Saunders, Zongping Shao, Guohua Jia, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402398131

                Nickel sulphides stand out as promising, earth-abundant transition metal chalcogenides with significant potential for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions. However, the realisation of their full potential is hindered by challenges in...</description>
      <author>Jiayi Chen, Xiaomin Xu, Rundong Mao, Cuifang Wang, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Zongyou Yin, Mark A. Buntine, Alexandra Suvorova, Martin Saunders, Zongping Shao, Guohua Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05191b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancies enhancing hierarchical NiCo2S4@MnO2 electrode for flexible asymmetric supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.068</link>
      <description>Qianwen Liu, Chengjingmeng Zhang, Ruidong Li, Jie Li, Bingyue Zheng, Shuxin Song, Lihua Chen, Tingxi Li, Yong Ma, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402406131

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianwen Liu, Chengjingmeng Zhang, Ruidong Li, Jie Li, Bingyue Zheng, Shuxin Song, Lihua Chen, Tingxi Li, Yong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Active Oxygen Species Derived from Water Splitting for Electrocatalytic Organic Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413457</link>
      <description>Jiangrong Yang, Tian Xia, &#26446;&#28009; Li Hao, Hong Yan, Xianggui Kong, Zhenhua Li, Mingfei Shao, Xue Duan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402409004

                Active oxygen species (OH*/O*) derived from water electrolysis are essential for the electrooxidation of organic compounds into high&#8208;value chemicals, which can determine activity and selectivity, whereas the relationship between them remains unclear. Herein, using glycerol (GLY) electrooxidation as a model reaction, we systematically investigated the relationship between GLY oxidation activity and the formation energy of OH* (&#916;GOH*). We first identified that OH* on Au demonstrates the highest activity for GLY electrooxidation among various pure metals, based on experiments and density functional theory, and revealed that &#916;GOH* on Au&#8208;based alloys is influenced by the metallic composition of OH* coordination sites. Moreover, we observed a linear correlation between the adsorption energy of GLY (Eads) and the d&#8208;band center of Au&#8208;based alloys. Comprehensive microkinetic analysis further reveals a volcano relationship between GLY oxidation activity, the &#916;GOH* and the adsorption free energy of GLY (&#916;Gads). Notably, Au3Pd and Au3Ag alloys, positioned near the peak of the volcano plot, show excellent activity, attributed to their moderate &#916;GOH* and &#916;Gads, striking a balance that is neither too high nor too low. This research provides theoretical insights into modulating active oxygen species from water electrolysis to enhance organic electrooxidation reactions.</description>
      <author>Jiangrong Yang, Tian Xia, &#26446;&#28009; Li Hao, Hong Yan, Xianggui Kong, Zhenhua Li, Mingfei Shao, Xue Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Active Oxygen Species Derived from Water Splitting for Electrocatalytic Organic Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413457</link>
      <description>Jiangrong Yang, Tian Xia, &#26446;&#28009; Li Hao, Hong Yan, Xianggui Kong, Zhenhua Li, Mingfei Shao, Xue Duan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402409013

                Active oxygen species (OH*/O*) derived from water electrolysis are essential for the electrooxidation of organic compounds into high&#8208;value chemicals, which can determine activity and selectivity, whereas the relationship between them remains unclear. Herein, using glycerol (GLY) electrooxidation as a model reaction, we systematically investigated the relationship between GLY oxidation activity and the formation energy of OH* (&#916;GOH*). We first identified that OH* on Au demonstrates the highest activity for GLY electrooxidation among various pure metals, based on experiments and density functional theory, and revealed that &#916;GOH* on Au&#8208;based alloys is influenced by the metallic composition of OH* coordination sites. Moreover, we observed a linear correlation between the adsorption energy of GLY (Eads) and the d&#8208;band center of Au&#8208;based alloys. Comprehensive microkinetic analysis further reveals a volcano relationship between GLY oxidation activity, the &#916;GOH* and the adsorption free energy of GLY (&#916;Gads). Notably, Au3Pd and Au3Ag alloys, positioned near the peak of the volcano plot, show excellent activity, attributed to their moderate &#916;GOH* and &#916;Gads, striking a balance that is neither too high nor too low. This research provides theoretical insights into modulating active oxygen species from water electrolysis to enhance organic electrooxidation reactions.</description>
      <author>Jiangrong Yang, Tian Xia, &#26446;&#28009; Li Hao, Hong Yan, Xianggui Kong, Zhenhua Li, Mingfei Shao, Xue Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413457</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Role of Surface Self&#8208;Reconstruction of Metal Chalcogenides on Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408364</link>
      <description>Weiwei Bao, Jiangying Liu, Taotao Ai, Jie Han, Jungang Hou, LI Wen-hu, Li Wang, Xiangyu Zou, Zhifeng Deng, Junjun Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402412042

                Abstract Transition metal chalcogenides are an important class of electrocatalysts with broad application prospects in alkaline oxygen evolution reactions. Many researchers are focusing on the in situ conversion of metal cations in catalysts, but have rarely considered the contribution of oxidation, leaching, and re&#8208;absorption of chalcogenides to the catalytic activity. Herein, multiple characterization approaches are used to monitor the evolution mechanism and origin CoTe@CoS&#8208;electrocatalyzed oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. The research results reveal that the electro&#8208;oxidative dissolution of Te and S on the electrode surface forms TeO 3 2&#8722; and SO 3 2&#8722; , which are adsorbed on the electrode surface. Moreover, TeO 3 2&#8722; and SO 3 2&#8722; species will further transform into TeO 4 2&#8722; and SO 4 2&#8722; . As expected, the extra addition of mixed tellurite and sulfate ions to the Co (OH) 2 electrolyte produces a synergistic effect that can significantly boost OER activity. Selenites reveal the analogous effect, indicating that the adsorption of chalcogenates the electrode surface has a universal effect on improving OER performance. The findings of this work provide unique insights into the species conversion of catalytic materials and the mechanism of enhancing catalytic activity during OER processes.</description>
      <author>Weiwei Bao, Jiangying Liu, Taotao Ai, Jie Han, Jungang Hou, LI Wen-hu, Li Wang, Xiangyu Zou, Zhifeng Deng, Junjun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterophase homojunction construction by amorphous TiOx and N&#8211;TiO2 photoanode for oxygen evolution reaction kinetics and charge carriers&#8217; transportation enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.051</link>
      <description>Xiaoying Shang, Rongzi Xv, Zhiwei Li, Ying Zheng, Li Fu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 87(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402418335

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoying Shang, Rongzi Xv, Zhiwei Li, Ying Zheng, Li Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Reaction Pathways for Oxygen Evolution as Key Factor for the Catalytic Activity of Nickel-Iron (Oxy)Hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l65kd</link>
      <description>Giuseppe Mattioli, Leonardo Guidoni, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402418491

                We present the results of a comprehensive theoretical investigation, based on state-of-the-art density functional theory simulations, of the structural and electrochemical properties of amorphous pristine and iron-doped nickel-(oxy)hydroxide catalyst films for water oxidation in alkaline solution, hereafter referred to as NiCat and Fe:NiCat. In the case of the structural properties, our simulations accurately reproduce the structural changes occurring in locally ordered units, reported by X-ray absorption spectroscopy measurements when the catalyst films are activated by exposition to a positive potential. We have highlighted the crucial role in this process of a series of proton- coupled electron transfer events in the reversible oxidation of Ni(II) to Ni(III). Once assessed structural models of NiCat and Fe:NiCat in close agreement with experimental results, we used them to investigate the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) atomistic mechanism, activated when the applied potential exceeds the overpotential required to oxidize water and produce molecular oxygen. We have quantitatively compared seven different pathways for the OER enrolled on both the proposed families of reaction mechanisms, namely the adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) and the lattice-oxygen mediate mechanism (LOM), and we have rationalized the effect of iron in the huge enhancement of catalytic activity of Fe:NiCat with respect to NiCat. Regarding the competition between AEM and LOM mechanisms, our results support the idea that simple metal- oxygen-metal atomistic motifs, ubiquitous on the surface of all kinds of crystalline and amorphous metal (oxy)hydroxide catalyst films, are able to promote different mechanisms of both types, all compatible with the application of an external positive potential in the range of those used in real electrochemical devices performing the OER. Finally, our results suggest that the elusive role of iron is related to the significant difference between Ni(IV)-O and Fe(IV)-O bonds in two crucial reaction intermediates immediately preceding the formation of the O-O bond, with Fe ions able to lower the potential required to form such intermediates along most of the investigated reaction paths.</description>
      <author>Giuseppe Mattioli, Leonardo Guidoni</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l65kd</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyoxometalate-incorporated NiFe-based oxyhydroxides for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc03874f</link>
      <description>Yuyan Qiao, Yanqiu Pan, Guifa Long, Wenjun Fan, Fuxiang Zhang, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402425893

                NiFe-based oxyhydroxides are promising electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, but further enhancing their OER performance remains a significant challenge. Herein, we in situ incorporated polyoxometalates...</description>
      <author>Yuyan Qiao, Yanqiu Pan, Guifa Long, Wenjun Fan, Fuxiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc03874f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of electrocatalytic oxygen evolution performance for FeCrNiCoTi alloys via powder modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176427</link>
      <description>Xinqing Liu, Yibing Shao, Shuai Guo, Yulai Song, William P. Meehan, Bo Song, Junjie Ni, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1007(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402430939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinqing Liu, Yibing Shao, Shuai Guo, Yulai Song, William P. Meehan, Bo Song, Junjie Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176427</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis of Ir-Based High-Entropy Alloy Nanomaterials Towards for Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4953778</link>
      <description>Xiaodong Hao, Yuzhao Qi, Shukai Ding, Shufang Ma, Bingshe Xu, Bosheng Zhang, Qigao Cao, Panchao Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402435814

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaodong Hao, Yuzhao Qi, Shukai Ding, Shufang Ma, Bingshe Xu, Bosheng Zhang, Qigao Cao, Panchao Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4953778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing novel metal-free HCOF-Ph@g-C3N4 heterojunctions through molecular expansion to enhance photogenerated carrier involved molecular oxygen activation and photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e01115</link>
      <description>Qingmei Tang, Qingrong Cheng, Zhi&#8208;Quan Pan, Sustainable materials and technologies. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402437806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qingmei Tang, Qingrong Cheng, Zhi&#8208;Quan Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.susmat.2024.e01115</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Electrochemical Conversion of Co2 to Formate Via Redox-Modulated Porous Metal Electrodes Coupled with Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4953570</link>
      <description>Sabahat Asif, Ifra Bashir, Syed Zajif Hussain, Senem &#199;&#239;to&#287;lu, Hat&#239;ce Duran, Ingo Lieberwirth, Habib ur Rehman, Bien Tan, Irshad Hussain, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402439828

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sabahat Asif, Ifra Bashir, Syed Zajif Hussain, Senem &#199;&#239;to&#287;lu, Hat&#239;ce Duran, Ingo Lieberwirth, Habib ur Rehman, Bien Tan, Irshad Hussain</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4953570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Composition Dependent Synergistic Effects on Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysis for CaFe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;1&#8211;&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;x&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;Mn&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;x&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2109/jcersj2.24069</link>
      <description>Asuka Ochi, Shukuji Asakura, Manami Goto, Shunsuke Yagi, Ikuya Yamada, Hidekazu Ikeno, Journal of the Ceramic Society of Japan. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402444163

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asuka Ochi, Shukuji Asakura, Manami Goto, Shunsuke Yagi, Ikuya Yamada, Hidekazu Ikeno</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2109/jcersj2.24069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy-Induced Phase-Control Syntheses of Single-Phase Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ru&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Solid Solutions and Active-Moderate-Sites Synergy in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02027</link>
      <description>Yuhan Liu, Wenfang Zhai, Panpan Cui, Zhengfei Dai, Zhengfei Dai, Bo Huang, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402447144

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhan Liu, Wenfang Zhai, Panpan Cui, Zhengfei Dai, Zhengfei Dai, Bo Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02027</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating Lattice Oxygen Oxidation Mechanism in Asymmetric [IrO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;] Octahedra of Ir&#8208;Based Oxides Toward Superior Acidic Electrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402902</link>
      <description>Yuying Liu, Ziyi Liu, Na Li, Chao Wang, Huijuan Wang, Qianqian Ji, Fengchun Hu, Hao Tan, Xiansong Liu, Chenglong Liu, Zhi Li, Sihua Feng, Bing Tang, Ruiqi Liu, Liyang Lv, Weiren Cheng, Wensheng Yan, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402449034

                Abstract The activation of lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) will endow iridium&#8208;based electrocatalysts with desired acid&#8208;available water oxidation activity, compared to the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM). However, the inherent symmetric [IrO 6 ] octahedra of commercial Ir&#8208;based catalysts generally thermodynamically favor the AEM pathway contributing to the moderate water oxidation performance. Here, based on typical layered Ca 2 IrO 4 (CIO) modeled materials, the d &#8208;orbitals electron repulsion strategy is demonstrated, via constructing asymmetrically polarized Ir&#8210;O&#8210;Ru configuration in Ru&#8208;CIO, to effectively activate the lattice oxygen participating in water oxidation process for decent oxygen&#8208;related electrocatalytic activity. Specifically, a great increase of &#8776;700&#8208;fold and &#8776;170&#8208;fold in mass activity and turnover frequency, respectively, has been realized for the optimal Ru&#8208;CIO electrocatalyst in an acid medium relative to the commercial IrO 2 electrocatalysts, where a small overpotential of only 175 mV is required for achieving 10 mA cm geo &#8210;2 . In situ X&#8208;ray fine structure spectroscopies combined with in situ 18 O&#8208; isotope&#8208;labeled differential electrochemical mass spectrometry analyses reveal that desirable LOM has been boosted by the activated lattice oxygen and the flexible Ir (3+&#948;)+ active sites of asymmetric [IrO 6 ] octahedra, which results in superior OER kinetics for Ir&#8208;based oxide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuying Liu, Ziyi Liu, Na Li, Chao Wang, Huijuan Wang, Qianqian Ji, Fengchun Hu, Hao Tan, Xiansong Liu, Chenglong Liu, Zhi Li, Sihua Feng, Bing Tang, Ruiqi Liu, Liyang Lv, Weiren Cheng, Wensheng Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402902</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Iron Doping in Ordered Nickel Oxide Thin Film Catalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02572</link>
      <description>Ane Etxebarria, Mauricio L&#243;pez Luna, Andrea Martini, Uta Hejral, Martina R&#252;scher, Chao Zhan, Antonia Herzog, Afshan Jamshaid, David Kordus, Arno Bergmann, H. Kuhlenbeck, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402449530

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ane Etxebarria, Mauricio L&#243;pez Luna, Andrea Martini, Uta Hejral, Martina R&#252;scher, Chao Zhan, Antonia Herzog, Afshan Jamshaid, David Kordus, Arno Bergmann, H. Kuhlenbeck, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlling Surface Wetting in High-Alkaline Electrolytes for Single Facet Pt Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalytic Activity Mapping by Scanning Electrochemical Cell Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc04407j</link>
      <description>Geovane Arruda de Oliveira, Moonjoo Kim, Carla Santana Santos, Ndrina Limani, Taek Dong Chung, Emmanuel Batsa Tetteh, Wolfgang Schuhmann, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402460501

                Scanning electrochemical cell microscopy (SECCM) has been used to explore structure-electrocatalytic activity relationships through high-resolution mapping of local activities of electrocatalysts. However, utilizing SECCM in strongly alkaline conditions presents a...</description>
      <author>Geovane Arruda de Oliveira, Moonjoo Kim, Carla Santana Santos, Ndrina Limani, Taek Dong Chung, Emmanuel Batsa Tetteh, Wolfgang Schuhmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc04407j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of graphene incorporation on the oxygen evolution reaction of Co-Fe-based electrocatalysts synthesized via one-step electrodeposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.503</link>
      <description>Mohammad Jahanbazi Goujani, Morteza Alizadeh, Shima Pashangeh, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 87(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402465059

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohammad Jahanbazi Goujani, Morteza Alizadeh, Shima Pashangeh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface oxygen-doping induced atom migration of iron-nickel sulfides with tailored d-band center for enhanced oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155272</link>
      <description>Q. Chen, Jinghan Zhang, Qicheng Zhang, Bin Chen, Wenchao Peng, Yang Li, Xiaobin Fan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402468872

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Q. Chen, Jinghan Zhang, Qicheng Zhang, Bin Chen, Wenchao Peng, Yang Li, Xiaobin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Discharged Dry Cell as an Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2053-1591/ad7a56</link>
      <description>Pitchiah Esakki Karthik, Sanjit Mondal, Lipipuspa Sahoo, Materials Research Express. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402472684

                Abstract Transition metal compounds with a high affinity for oxygen in dry cell configurations, such as MnO2, Mn3O4, and ZnxMn3O4&#8722;x, exhibit exceptional electrocatalytic properties in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the disposal of these dry cell materials, unlike that of rechargeable batteries, poses environmental hazards. In this study, we focused on optimizing these manganese oxides for energy-related applications, specifically OER. To achieve this goal, we investigated the electrocatalytic behaviour of both used and fresh dry cells in OER. Our results show that the used dry cell material achieved a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 at an overpotential of 525 mV, whereas the fresh dry cell required an overpotential 100 mV higher to reach the same current density. We further characterized the nature of these fresh and used materials using various techniques, including X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), thermogravimetric analysis (TGA), Raman spectroscopy, Fourier-transform infrared spectroscopy (FT-IR), and contact angle measurements. The enhanced activity of the used dry cell can be attributed to the formation of highly active Mn3O4 from MnO2 and graphene oxide under discharging conditions.</description>
      <author>Pitchiah Esakki Karthik, Sanjit Mondal, Lipipuspa Sahoo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2053-1591/ad7a56</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel&#8211;Iron Layered Double Hydroxides/Nickel Sulfide Heterostructured Electrocatalysts on Surface-Modified Ti Foam for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08215</link>
      <description>Habib Gemechu Edao, Chia-Yu Chang, Woldesenbet Bafe Dilebo, Fikiru Temesgen Angerasa, Endalkachew Asefa Moges, Yosef Nikodimos, Chemeda Barasa Guta, Keseven Lakshmanan, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Meng&#8208;Che Tsai, Wei&#8208;Nien Su, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402474891

                Electrochemical approaches for generating hydrogen from water splitting can be more promising if the challenges in the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can be harnessed. The interface heterostructure materials offer strong electronic coupling and appropriate charge transport at the interface regions, promoting accessible active sites to prompt kinetics and optimize the adsorption-desorption of active species. Herein, we have designed an efficient multi-interface-engineered Ni</description>
      <author>Habib Gemechu Edao, Chia-Yu Chang, Woldesenbet Bafe Dilebo, Fikiru Temesgen Angerasa, Endalkachew Asefa Moges, Yosef Nikodimos, Chemeda Barasa Guta, Keseven Lakshmanan, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Meng&#8208;Che Tsai, Wei&#8208;Nien Su, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Facet Regulation and Ru Incorporation of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnanoscienceau.4c00037</link>
      <description>Mengting Zhao, Hanfeng Liang, ACS Nanoscience Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402477642

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengting Zhao, Hanfeng Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnanoscienceau.4c00037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating Template&#8208;To&#8208;Precursor Interactions for Synthesizing Highly Active Single Atomic Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/8714253</link>
      <description>Dong&#8208;Gun Kim, Subin Park, Yong Nam Choi, Eunhee Lee, Y.&#8208;H. Cho, Jae Young Jung, Nam Dong Kim, Pil Kim, Sung Jong Yoo, International Journal of Energy Research. 2024(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402479297

                Iron&#8208; and nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C) catalysts have garnered attention owing to their high oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity, which is comparable to that of Pt/C catalysts. Among the various methods for designing Fe&#9472;N&#9472;C catalysts, the use of templates has been emphasized as a means to create hierarchical porous structures. This strategy has enabled the achievement of high ORR activity. In this study, we propose a method for manufacturing a catalyst with high ORR activity by maximizing the interactions between commercial silica templates and catalyst precursors. By manipulating the charge on the commercial silica surface and adjusting the pH of the dispersion, the catalyst fabricated through these methods exhibited superior ORR activity compared to Pt/C and recently reported nonprecious metal catalysts. Through diverse physicochemical and electrochemical analyses, we confirmed that this activity stems from the effectively generated hierarchical porous structure and the resulting high density of Fe&#9472;N active sites. This catalyst exhibited a kinetic current density of over 2.73 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is more than double that of platinum and displayed a high ORR mass activity of 4.49 mA mg &#8722;1 . This strategy holds significant potential for application in various carbon&#8208;based materials, paving the way for the development of highly efficient electrochemical energy devices.</description>
      <author>Dong&#8208;Gun Kim, Subin Park, Yong Nam Choi, Eunhee Lee, Y.&#8208;H. Cho, Jae Young Jung, Nam Dong Kim, Pil Kim, Sung Jong Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/8714253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Compositional Optimization of Fe&#8211;Co&#8211;Ni Ternary Amorphous Electrocatalysts for Efficient Oxygen Evolution in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405468</link>
      <description>Changsoo Lee, Young Hwa Yun, Se&#8208;Ho Kim, Gisu Doo, Sechan Lee, Hyun-Jeong Park, Youngtae Park, J. Shin, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Sang&#8208;Kyung Kim, EunAe Cho, Chanwon Jung, MinJoong Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402488374

                Abstract Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) offers a sustainable path for hydrogen production with advantages such as high current density, dynamic responsiveness, and low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts. However, the development of efficient and durable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts under operating conditions is crucial for achieving the AEMWE. This study systematically investigated Fe&#8211;Co&#8211;Ni ternary amorphous electrocatalysts for the OER in AEMWE through a comprehensive material library system comprising 21 composition series. The study aims to explore the relationship between composition, degree of crystallinity, and electrocatalytic activity using ternary contours and binary plots to derive optimal catalysts. The findings reveal that higher Co and lower Fe contents lead to increased structural disorder within the Fe&#8211;Co&#8211;Ni system, whereas an appropriate amount of Fe addition is necessary for OER activity. It is concluded that the amorphous structure of Fe&#8211;Co 3 &#8211;Ni possesses an optimal ternary composition and degree of crystallinity to facilitate the OER. Post&#8208;OER analyses reveal that the optimized ternary amorphous structure induces structural reconstruction into an OER&#8208;favorable OOH&#8208;rich surface. The Fe&#8211;Co 3 &#8211;Ni electrocatalysts exhibit outstanding performances in both half&#8208;cells and single&#8208;cells, with an overpotential of 256 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722; 2 and a current density of 2.0 A cm &#8722; 2 at 1.89 V, respectively.</description>
      <author>Changsoo Lee, Young Hwa Yun, Se&#8208;Ho Kim, Gisu Doo, Sechan Lee, Hyun-Jeong Park, Youngtae Park, J. Shin, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Sang&#8208;Kyung Kim, EunAe Cho, Chanwon Jung, MinJoong Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational screening of transition metal atom doped ZnS and ZnSe nanostructures as promising bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04011b</link>
      <description>Feifei Xia, Shu Li, Fengli Yang, Yingpin Wen, Chunzhi Zheng, RSC Advances. 14(40)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402491900

                The computed OER and ORR overpotentials of pristine and TM doped ZnX (X = S and Se) nanostructures.</description>
      <author>Feifei Xia, Shu Li, Fengli Yang, Yingpin Wen, Chunzhi Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra04011b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic &#8216;gelectrodes&#8217; based on Co and Ni&#8211;Fe oxy/hydroxides for sustainable and enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03866e</link>
      <description>Anu Bovas, T. P. Radhakrishnan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402492776

                &#8216;Gelectrodes&#8217; based on nanocomposites of cobalt oxyhydroxide and nickel&#8211;iron hydroxide in chitosan on nickel foam are developed, and their efficient mediation of the oxygen evolution reaction with high and sustainable current densities demonstrated.</description>
      <author>Anu Bovas, T. P. Radhakrishnan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03866e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-production of hydrogen, oxygen, and electricity via an integrated solar-driven system with decoupled water electrolyzer and Na-Zn ion battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.062</link>
      <description>Fei Lv, Longjie Liu, Jiazhe Wu, Pengfei Wang, Lixia Pan, Dengwei Jing, Yubin Chen, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402494176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Lv, Longjie Liu, Jiazhe Wu, Pengfei Wang, Lixia Pan, Dengwei Jing, Yubin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal doped into layered double hydroxide as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161233</link>
      <description>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402495714

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shilong Li, Caiwei Yue, Haohao Wang, Jirui Du, Hongyun Cui, Min Pu, Ming Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of oxygen defects and calabash-like hollow carbon matrix enables VO2 as high-performance cathode for zinc ion battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.097</link>
      <description>Xiaoqing Liu, Ze Xu, Jinjiang Wu, Kexin Wang, Chuang Yu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402496582

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoqing Liu, Ze Xu, Jinjiang Wu, Kexin Wang, Chuang Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of hollow CoFe Prussian blue analogues and their derived CoP-FeP nanoboxes as efficient electrocatalysts as oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235454</link>
      <description>Shiqi Zhang, Ying Cheng, Zhiyuan Ni, Xuefei Lei, Biao Wang, Xuanwen Liu, Rui Guo, Journal of Power Sources. 623(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402503792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiqi Zhang, Ying Cheng, Zhiyuan Ni, Xuefei Lei, Biao Wang, Xuanwen Liu, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; in MoSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Exhibits Bifunctional Water Oxidation and Oxygen Reduction (OER and ORR) Catalytic Reactions for Energy Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01586</link>
      <description>Merin Mary Sebastian, Ditty Dixon, T. Daniel Thangadurai, Nandakumar Kalarikkal, Alex Schechter, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402506190

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Merin Mary Sebastian, Ditty Dixon, T. Daniel Thangadurai, Nandakumar Kalarikkal, Alex Schechter</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Bottleneck of Activity and Stability of RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Electrocatalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03643</link>
      <description>Weimo Li, Ce Wang, Xiaofeng Lu, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402507206

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weimo Li, Ce Wang, Xiaofeng Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights of oxygen vacancies engineered structural, morphological, and electrochemical attributes of Cr-doped Co3O4 nanoparticles as redox active battery-type electrodes for hybrid supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113751</link>
      <description>K. Mallikarjuna, B. Deva Prasad Raju, Mohamed A. Ghanem, G.R. Dillip, Sang Woo Joo, Journal of Energy Storage. 100(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402508520

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Mallikarjuna, B. Deva Prasad Raju, Mohamed A. Ghanem, G.R. Dillip, Sang Woo Joo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Valent Cobalt-manganese Spinel Nanowires Induced by Fluorine-Doping for Durable Acid Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176500</link>
      <description>Xufeng Hong, Yong Gao, Mengyao Ji, Jinhan Li, Yingshui Yao, Zhicheng Yu, Kun Chang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402512599

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xufeng Hong, Yong Gao, Mengyao Ji, Jinhan Li, Yingshui Yao, Zhicheng Yu, Kun Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176500</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restricting the over-oxidation of active sites in high-entropy electrocatalysts towards ultra-stabilized oxygen evolution in alkaline water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05449k</link>
      <description>Yimin Zhang, Jianli Kang, Haonan Xie, Hongxia Yin, Zhijia Zhang, Yuhan Ma, Guangxin Sun, Enzuo Liu, Liying Ma, Biao Chen, Junwei Sha, Lihua Qian, Wenbin Hu, Chunnian He, Naiqin Zhao, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402519737

                Based on ionic electronegativity, theoretical calculation guided the synthesis of np-MnFeCoNiCuOOH exhibiting ultra-stabilized oxygen evolution in alkaline water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Yimin Zhang, Jianli Kang, Haonan Xie, Hongxia Yin, Zhijia Zhang, Yuhan Ma, Guangxin Sun, Enzuo Liu, Liying Ma, Biao Chen, Junwei Sha, Lihua Qian, Wenbin Hu, Chunnian He, Naiqin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05449k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dependence of Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysis at Thin Cathodically-Deposited Nickel-Iron-Selenide on Fe in the Alkaline Electrolyte vs. Codeposited Fe</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145062</link>
      <description>Jihan Dhainy, M. El Jamal, Issaaf Mouawad, Lara I. Halaoui, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402520122

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jihan Dhainy, M. El Jamal, Issaaf Mouawad, Lara I. Halaoui</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of Core&#8208;Shell Ir@TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles through Hydrogen Treatment as Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408848</link>
      <description>Jihyeon Park, E Liu, Shayan Angizi, Ahmed M. Abdellah, Ecem Yelekli Kirici, Drew Higgins, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402520720

                Abstract The transition to a sustainable energy economy requires the availability of renewably produced hydrogen through proton exchange membrane water electrolysis. The techno&#8208;economic viability of this technology requires addressing materials challenges regarding the lack of active and stable catalysts for the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic conditions. Herein, core&#8208;shell iridium/titanium dioxide (Core&#8208;shell Ir@TiO 2 ) catalysts for acidic OER are synthesized through a polyol method to create TiO 2 nanoparticles, followed by urea reduction with Ir, and subsequent annealing in hydrogen. The formation process of the core&#8208;shell structure is observed through in situ environmental transmission electron microscopy under annealing conditions. Ir segregation occurred from an initially blended mixed metal oxide structure to a core&#8208;shell configuration at 500 &#176;C. Core&#8208;shell Ir@TiO 2 showed a three&#8208;fold higher stability number (i.e., S&#8208;number) than commercial IrO x (3.34 &#215; 10 6 versus 1.02 &#215; 10 6 ). Furthermore, an Ir&#8208;mass normalized activity of 1,880 A g Ir &#8722;1 at 1.7 V versus RHE is measured for Core&#8208;shell Ir@TiO 2 , compared to 624 A g Ir &#8722;1 for commercial IrO x . The developed synthetic route to prepare a composite structure with a TiO 2 core and Ir&#8208;based shell has enabled an Ir content reduction without a compromise in activity and stability, thus offering a promising avenue for developing next&#8208;generation catalysts tailored for acidic water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Jihyeon Park, E Liu, Shayan Angizi, Ahmed M. Abdellah, Ecem Yelekli Kirici, Drew Higgins</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Correlation between Spin Effect and Catalytic Activity of Two Dimensional Metal Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402538465

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of aflatoxin B1 on growth, photosynthetic oxygen evolution and regreening of Chlorella fusca</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5962/p.309334</link>
      <description>O. H. Sayed, E. M. Fadl-Allah, Cryptogamie Algologie. 13(1)] 1992. https://openalex.org/W4402490839

                No abstract</description>
      <author>O. H. Sayed, E. M. Fadl-Allah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 1992 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5962/p.309334</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing entropy-stabilized synthesis kinetics to modulate the oxygen evolution mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.08.014</link>
      <description>Zeshuo Meng, Hengyue Xu, Zhengyan Du, Zijin Xu, Jian Xu, Wei Zhang, Xiaoying Hu, Haoteng Sun, Hongwei Tian, Jingsan Xu, Weitao Zheng, Sheng Dai, Materials Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402433891

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeshuo Meng, Hengyue Xu, Zhengyan Du, Zijin Xu, Jian Xu, Wei Zhang, Xiaoying Hu, Haoteng Sun, Hongwei Tian, Jingsan Xu, Weitao Zheng, Sheng Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.08.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating oxygen evolution and reduction mechanisms in nitrogen-doped carbon-based photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110439</link>
      <description>Yan Wang, Jiaqi Zhang, Xiaofeng Wu, Sibo Wang, Masakazu Anpo, Yuanxing Fang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402404700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Wang, Jiaqi Zhang, Xiaofeng Wu, Sibo Wang, Masakazu Anpo, Yuanxing Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.110439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core-shell like rGO coated Co9S8 hollow dodecahedron for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112318</link>
      <description>Hongjuan Hao, Hongbin Pu, Dingze Lu, Min Zhou, Boqun Zhang, Xin Zhang, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402327345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongjuan Hao, Hongbin Pu, Dingze Lu, Min Zhou, Boqun Zhang, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-doped cobalt-based hydroxide assisted with low-temperature molten salt for industrial oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5813(24)60456-1</link>
      <description>Fuli Wang, Qianxi L&#252;, Yiwen Dong, Jingyi Xie, Z.D. Wang, Bin Dong, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Journal of Fuel Chemistry and Technology. 52(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402401447

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuli Wang, Qianxi L&#252;, Yiwen Dong, Jingyi Xie, Z.D. Wang, Bin Dong, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5813(24)60456-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recovery of niobium and titanium from low-grade niobium ores and the evaluation of Fe5Si3 alloy by-product as oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176424</link>
      <description>He Sun, Jia-Ming Chen, Yu-Sheng Yang, Min Qiu, Milin Zhang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1007(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402389900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>He Sun, Jia-Ming Chen, Yu-Sheng Yang, Min Qiu, Milin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176424</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual internal electric field induced by Ni3C selectively deposited onto Mn2O3 on faceted BiVO4 for boosting photocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124589</link>
      <description>Xiaoming Xu, Yahui Cheng, Xiaoyan Zhu, Jiaying Huang, Bowen Zhu, Jingjing Meng, Junshan Li, Guolin Jing, Lihui Zheng, Shaogui Yang, Cheng Sun, Xiaohui Li, Ruixia Yuan, Yongfa Zhu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402486272

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoming Xu, Yahui Cheng, Xiaoyan Zhu, Jiaying Huang, Bowen Zhu, Jingjing Meng, Junshan Li, Guolin Jing, Lihui Zheng, Shaogui Yang, Cheng Sun, Xiaohui Li, Ruixia Yuan, Yongfa Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of oxygen and stratification and their relationship in the North Pacific Ocean in CMIP6 Earth system models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-3985-2024</link>
      <description>Lyuba Novi, Annalisa Bracco, Takamitsu Ito, Yohei Takano, Biogeosciences. 21(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402522349

                Abstract. This study examines the linkages between the upper-ocean (0&#8211;200 m) oxygen (O2) content and stratification in the North Pacific Ocean using four Earth system models (ESMs), an ocean hindcast simulation, and an ocean reanalysis. The trends and variability in oceanic O2 content are driven by the imbalance between physical supply and biological demand. Physical supply is primarily controlled by ocean ventilation, which is responsible for the transport of O2-rich surface waters to the subsurface. Isopycnic potential vorticity (IPV), a quasi-conservative tracer proportional to density stratification that can be evaluated from temperature and salinity measurements, is used herein as a dynamical proxy for ocean ventilation. The predictability potential of the IPV field is evaluated through its information entropy. The results highlight a strong O2&#8211;IPV connection and somewhat higher (as compared to the rest of the basin) predictability potential for IPV across the tropical Pacific, where the El Ni&#241;o&#8211;Southern Oscillation occurs. This pattern of higher predictability and strong anticorrelation between O2 and stratification is robust across multiple models and datasets. In contrast, IPV at mid-latitudes has low predictability potential and its center of action differs from that of O2. In addition, the locations of extreme events or hotspots may or may not differ between the two fields, with a strong model dependency, which persists in future projections. On the one hand, these results suggest that it may be possible to monitor ocean O2 in the tropical Pacific based on a few observational sites co-located with the more abundant IPV measurements; on the other, they lead us to question the robustness of the IPV&#8211;O2 relationship in the extratropics. The proposed framework helps to characterize and interpret O2 variability in relation to physical variability and may be especially useful in the analysis of new observation-based data products derived from the BGC-Argo float array in combination with the traditional but far more abundant Argo data.</description>
      <author>Lyuba Novi, Annalisa Bracco, Takamitsu Ito, Yohei Takano</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-3985-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-induced evolution of anammox granular sludge explains its unique responses during preservation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.122447</link>
      <description>Leiyan Guo, Chao Pan, Wei Wang, Yang Yu, Dongdong Xu, Wenda Chen, Wenji Li, Ping Zheng, Meng Zhang, Water Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402533251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leiyan Guo, Chao Pan, Wei Wang, Yang Yu, Dongdong Xu, Wenda Chen, Wenji Li, Ping Zheng, Meng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.122447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cr dopant mediates hydroxyl spillover on RuO2 for high-efficiency proton exchange membrane electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51871-z</link>
      <description>Yu-An Shen, Xiaolong Zhang, Meng Qu, Jie Ma, Sheng Zhu, Yulin Min, Min&#8208;Rui Gao, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402369856

                Simultaneously improving the activity and stability of catalysts for anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) remains a notable challenge. Here, we report a chromium-doped ruthenium dioxide with oxygen vacancies, termed Cr</description>
      <author>Yu-An Shen, Xiaolong Zhang, Meng Qu, Jie Ma, Sheng Zhu, Yulin Min, Min&#8208;Rui Gao, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51871-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supporting Ru3+ doped copper phosphate with Pt/C-like hydrogen evolution reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc02540g</link>
      <description>Meiting Wang, Juan Jian, Zhuo Wang, Xiangxin Xue, Ping Nie, Limin Chang, Journal of Materials Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402421720

                Design bifunctional catalyst with excellent water splitting property in both alkaline electrolyte and seawater remain a challenge. Wherein, metal phosphates are widely reported oxygen evolution reaction (OER) materials. However, their...</description>
      <author>Meiting Wang, Juan Jian, Zhuo Wang, Xiangxin Xue, Ping Nie, Limin Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc02540g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factorial Optimization of CoCuFe-LDH/Graphene Ternary Composites as Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10870</link>
      <description>Daniele Alves, Rafael de Andrade Moral, Darshana Jayakumari, Eithne Dempsey, Carmel B. Breslin, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402478012

                The layered double hydroxides (LDHs) have demonstrated significant potential as non-noble-metal electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Their unique compositional and structural properties contribute to their efficiency and stability as catalysts. In this study, CoCuFe-LDH composites were grown on graphene (G) via a cost-effective and straightforward one-step hydrothermal process. A 2-level full-factorial model was employed to determine the impact of Co (1.5, 3, and 4.5 mmol) and graphene (10, 30, and 50 mg) concentrations on the onset potential of OER and HER, which were the chosen response variables. OER and HER activity variabilities were assessed in triplicate using Co</description>
      <author>Daniele Alves, Rafael de Andrade Moral, Darshana Jayakumari, Eithne Dempsey, Carmel B. Breslin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INFLUENCE OF Ni CONTENT OF ELECTRODEPOSITED Pd-Ni ALLOY COATINGS ON THEIR ELECTROCATALYTIC ACTIVITY IN ALKALINE MEDIUM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59957/jctm.v59.i5.2024.12</link>
      <description>J. Georgieva, Tzvetanka Boiadjieva-Scherzer, M. Monev, Journal of Chemical Technology and Metallurgy. 59(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377205

                The influence of the Ni content (1.4 - 9.0 wt. %) in electrodeposited Pd-Ni alloy coatings on the rate of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in an alkaline media was investigated. Electrocatalytic activity of the electrodeposited layers towards methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) was also studied. The composition and surface morphology of the samples were characterized by energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The crystal structure of the Pd-Ni alloys was examined by X-ray diffraction (XRD). Electrochemical experiments were performed by cyclic voltammetry (CV). The presence of concentration ranges with respect to the Ni content is shown, wherein the electrocatalytic activity of the Pd-Ni alloy towards HER, OER and MOR is higher than that of pure Pd.</description>
      <author>J. Georgieva, Tzvetanka Boiadjieva-Scherzer, M. Monev</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59957/jctm.v59.i5.2024.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas Evolution in Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00211</link>
      <description>Paul A. Kempler, Robert H. Coridan, Long Luo, Chemical Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402453997

                Gas bubbles generated by the hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction during water electrolysis influence the energy conversion efficiency of hydrogen production. Here, we survey what is known about the interaction of gas bubbles and electrode surfaces and the influence of gas evolution on practicable devices used for water electrolysis. We outline the physical processes occurring during the life cycle of a bubble, summarize techniques used to characterize gas evolution phenomena in situ and in practical device environments, and discuss ways that electrodes can be tailored to facilitate gas removal at high current densities. Lastly, we review efforts to model the behavior of individual gas bubbles and multiphase flows produced at gas-evolving electrodes. We conclude our review with a short summary of outstanding questions that could be answered by future efforts to characterize gas evolution in electrochemical device environments or by improved simulations of multiphase flows.</description>
      <author>Paul A. Kempler, Robert H. Coridan, Long Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemrev.4c00211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Silicon&#8208;Supported Catalytic Materials for Energy Conversion and Storage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401459</link>
      <description>Man Wong, Wen Ou, Zhen&#8208;Tao Yu, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402512252

                Porous silicon (Si) has a tetrahedral structure similar to that of sp3&#8208; hybridized carbon atoms in a typical diamond structure, which affords it unique chemical and physical properties including an adjustable intrinsic bandgap, a high&#8208;speed carrier transfer efficiency. It has shown great potential in photocatalysis, rechargeable batteries, solar cells, detectors, and electrocatalysis. This review introduces various porous Si&#8208;supported electrocatalysts and analyzes the reasons why porous Si is used as a new carrier/active sites from the perspectives of its molecular structure, electronic properties, synthesis methods, etc. The electrochemical applications of porous Si&#8208;based electrocatalysts in energy conversion reactions such as hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, and total water decomposition together with lithium&#8208;ion batteries (LIBs) and supercapacitors in energy storage are summarized. The challenges and future research directions for porous Si are also discussed. This review aims to deepen the understanding of porous Si and promote the development and applications of this new type of Si material.</description>
      <author>Man Wong, Wen Ou, Zhen&#8208;Tao Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401459</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis on the Conceptual and Functional Factors Affecting the Effectiveness of PEM Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0565.v1</link>
      <description>Gaydaa Al Zohbi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402426024

                Hydrogen has the potential to decarbonize the energy and industrial sector in the future, mainly if it is generated by water electrolysis. Proton Exchange Membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) system is regarded as a propitious technology to produce green hydrogen from water using power supplied by renewable energy sources. It offers many benefits such as high performance, high proton conductibility, quick response, compact size, and low working temperature. Many conceptual and functional parameters influence the effectiveness of PEM, including temperature, pressure of anode and cathode regions, water content and wideness of layer, and cathode and anode exchange current density. In addition, the anodic half reaction (known as oxygen evolution reaction (OER)), and cathodic half reaction (known as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)) perform an important function in the development of PEMWE. The current paper aims at presenting these parameters and discussing their impacts on the performance of PEM. Also, the PEM efficiency is presented. The different methods used to enhance the scattering of OER electrocatalyst and minimizing catalyst loading to minimize the price of PEMWE are also highlighted. Moreover, the alternative of noble metals that could be used as electrocatalyst in HER and OER to minimize the cost of PEM are reviewed and presented.</description>
      <author>Gaydaa Al Zohbi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202409.0565.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox Activity of Co Species in the Active Sites of CoN x /CoO x Facilitates Oxygen Electrocatalysis for Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402972</link>
      <description>Huimin Yang, Hao Wang, Haorong Cheng, Xinyuan Xu, Jing Li, Xiaoyan He, Lin Tian, Li Zhao, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402333995

                Developing efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts is crucial for enhancing the performance of rechargeable Zn-air batteries (ZABs). In this study, cobalt/cobalt oxides embedded in N-doped carbon nanofibers (Co/CoOx/NCNFs) were synthesized through a combination of electrospinning and annealing processes. The resulting Co/CoOx/NCNFs catalysts feature abundant CoNx and CoOx active species, leveraging the large specific surface area of nanofibers to facilitate oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The optimized Co/CoOx/NCNFs-0.1 achieved a half-wave potential (vs. RHE) of 0.82 V and required only 429 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; in a typical three-electrode system with 0.1 M KOH using an electrochemical workstation equipped with a pine instruments rotator, outperforming the Pt/C+RuO2. The assembled ZABs exhibited high specific capacity (771 mAh gZn-1), substantial power density (981.6 mWh gZn-1), and long-term stability (&gt;325 h). In situ Raman spectroscopy confirmed that the electrocatalytic processes involve the redox activity of Co (II and III) species derived from abundant CoNx and CoOx, elaborating the origin of the catalysts' exceptional oxygen electrocatalysis performance. This work not only presents a straightforward and effective approach for producing bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts in ZABs but also sheds light on the catalytic mechanisms underlying ORR and OER for CoNx/CoOx-based oxygen electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Huimin Yang, Hao Wang, Haorong Cheng, Xinyuan Xu, Jing Li, Xiaoyan He, Lin Tian, Li Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru@NiMoS aggregate with boosted electrochemical catalysis for enhanced electrochemiluminescence and lidocaine detection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smo.20240011</link>
      <description>Yongzhuang Lu, Haoran Wang, Qiyao Li, Qian Liu, Xiaoxu Zhang, Yuying Jia, X.D. Cai, Zheng Zhao, Yanfu Huan, Ben Zhong Tang, Smart Molecules. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402498837

                Abstract A binder&#8208;free Ru@NiMoS electrode was engineered by in situ growth of two&#8208;dimensional NiMoS nanosheets on nickel foam. This process effectively promoted the electrostatic&#8208;driven aggregation of Ru(bpy) 3 2+ , harnessing the synergistic effect to enhance electrochemiluminescence (ECL) performance. The integration (Ru@NiMoS) achieved an impressive ECL efficiency of 70.1%, marking an impressive 36.9&#8208;fold enhancement over conventional Ru. Additionally, its ECL intensity was found to be remarkably 172.2 times greater than that of Ru. Within the Ru(bpy) 3 2+ /TPA system, NiMoS emerged as a pivotal electrochemical catalyst, markedly boosting both the oxygen evolution reaction and the generation of reactive intermediates. Leveraging these distinctive properties, a highly efficient ECL sensor for lidocaine detection was developed. This sensor exhibited a linear response within the concentration range of 1 nM to 1 &#956;M and achieved a remarkably low detection limit of 0.22 nM, underlining its substantial potential for practical application.</description>
      <author>Yongzhuang Lu, Haoran Wang, Qiyao Li, Qian Liu, Xiaoxu Zhang, Yuying Jia, X.D. Cai, Zheng Zhao, Yanfu Huan, Ben Zhong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smo.20240011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic Properties of Polyampholytes, Polyampholyte-Metal Complexes, Polyampholyte-Metal Nanoparticles and Polyampholyte-Enzyme Conjugates: a Mini-Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31489/2959-0663/3-24-8</link>
      <description>Sarkyt E. Kudaibergenov, Eurasian Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402527974

                This mini-review briefly discusses the catalytic properties of polyampholytes, polyampholyte-metal complexes, polyampholyte-metal nanoparticles and polyampholyte-catalase conjugates. Polyampholyte-based catalysts can mimic enzyme functions, facilitating reactions like hydrolysis, decomposition, hydrogenation, and oxidation of various substrates. Special focus is given to amphoteric hydrogels and cryogels that encapsulate metal nanoparticles or enzymes. These materials have demonstrated effectiveness in the hydrogenation of nitroaromatic compounds, oxidation of disulfide and aliphatic (or aromatic) alcohols under mild conditions, both in batch and flow-through reactors. Kinetic parameters, turnover numbers (TON), turnover frequencies (TOF), and activation energies are presented for a series of specific catalytic processes. Notably, flow-through reactors exhibit significantly higher catalytic efficiency compared to batch reactors and can be used continuously for extended periods. Additionally, the review explores the potential of light-driven hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions from water, facilitated by metal nanoparticles within amphoteric hydrogels in the presence of photosensitizers.</description>
      <author>Sarkyt E. Kudaibergenov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31489/2959-0663/3-24-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni3S2 particle&#8211;embedded nanotubes as a high-performance electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0225168</link>
      <description>Pengcheng Zhu, Li Ye, Xiaolei Li, Tianxing Wang, Zhong Yao, Lin Zhuang, APL Materials. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402454503

                Hydrogen evolution reactions (HERs) and oxygen evolution reactions (OERs) are crucial for renewable energy production. Developing stable, cost-effective, and highly catalytic HER and OER electrocatalysts is paramount. In this study, a combination of hydrothermal synthesis and annealing was used to fabricate nickel sulfide (Ni3S2) particle&#8211;embedded nanotubes supported on nickel (Ni) foam (Ni3S2 PN/NF). The Ni3S2 PN/NF structures featured a highly branched morphology with a large specific surface area, surpassing that of conventional Ni metal nanotubes. This design increased the number of reactive sites and enhanced the charge-transfer process. The Ni foam substrate expanded the contact area of Ni3S2, thereby improving conductivity and facilitating the adsorption/desorption of intermediates on the Ni3S2 surface. Density functional theory calculations showed that the electronic structure of Ni3S2 provides excellent conductivity. Moreover, the multi-branched structure and inherent conductivity of the NiS nanomaterials enhanced the Ni3S2 PN/NF performance in 1M KOH, with overpotentials of 87 and 210 mV with iR compensation at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for the HER and OER, respectively. The synthesized Ni3S2 PN/NF also exhibited robust durability for 20 h. These results demonstrate that Ni3S2 PN/NF is an excellent catalyst for both HER and OER.</description>
      <author>Pengcheng Zhu, Li Ye, Xiaolei Li, Tianxing Wang, Zhong Yao, Lin Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0225168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling crystal orientation-dependent interface property in composite cathodes for solid-state batteries by in situ microscopic probe</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52226-4</link>
      <description>Sunyoung Lee, Hayoung Park, Jae Young Kim, Jihoon Kim, Min&#8208;Ju Choi, Sang-Wook Han, Sewon Kim, Wonju Kim, Ho Won Jang, Jungwon Park, Kisuk Kang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402441219

                A critical bottleneck toward all-solid-state batteries lies in how the solid(electrode)-solid(electrolyte) interface is fabricated and maintained over repeated cycles. Conventional composite cathodes, with crystallographically distinct electrode/electrolyte interfaces of random particles, create complexities with varying (electro)chemical compatibilities. To address this, we employ an epitaxial model system where the crystal orientations of cathode and solid electrolyte are precisely controlled, and probe the interfaces in real-time during co-sintering by in situ electron microscopy. The interfacial reaction is highly dependent on crystal orientation/alignment, especially the availability of open ion channels. Interfaces bearing open ion paths of NCM are more susceptible to interdiffusion, but stabilize with the early formed passivation layer. Conversely, interfaces with closed ion pathway exhibit stability at intermediate temperatures, but deteriorate rapidly at high temperature due to oxygen evolution, increasing interfacial resistance. The elucidation of these distinct interfacial behaviors emphasizes the need for decoupling collective interfacial properties to enable rational design in solid-state batteries.</description>
      <author>Sunyoung Lee, Hayoung Park, Jae Young Kim, Jihoon Kim, Min&#8208;Ju Choi, Sang-Wook Han, Sewon Kim, Wonju Kim, Ho Won Jang, Jungwon Park, Kisuk Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52226-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissolution Manufacturing Strategy for the Facile Synthesis of Nanoporous Metallic Glass Multifunctional Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401109</link>
      <description>Shenghao Zeng, Wenqing Ruan, Zhe Chen, Shuai Ren, J.Z. Jiang, Jiajia Lin, Heting Zhang, Zhenxuan Zhang, Jianan Fu, Qing Chen, Xiong Liang, Jiang Ma, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402362637

                Abstract The quest for heightened energy efficiency is inextricably linked to advancements in energy storage and conversion technologies, wherein multifunctional catalysts play a pivotal role by mitigating the slow kinetics endemic to many catalytic reactions. The intricate synthesis and bespoke design of such catalysts, however, present notable challenges. Addressing this, the present study capitalizes on a novel dissolution manufacturing strategy to engineer self&#8208;supporting, nanoporous multifunctional electrocatalysts, circumventing the prevalent issue of customizing catalytic functionalities upon demand. This innovative approach grants the flexibility to finely tune the incorporation of active species and metalloid binders, culminating in the creation of a self&#8208;supporting nanoporous metal glass electrocatalyst doped with RuO 2 (NPMG@RuO 2 ) with outstanding performance in alkaline media. The catalyst showcases superior electrocatalytic activity, achieving low overpotentials of 41.50 mV for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and 226.0 mV for Oxygen Evolution Reaction alongside sustained stability over 620 hours.These achievements are attributed to the distinct nanoporous architecture that ensures a high density of catalytic sites and mechanical strength, bolstered by the synergistic interplay between RuO 2 and Pt&#8208;based metallic glass. The findings provide a versatile template for the development of nanoporous multifunctional catalysts, signifying a leap forward in the realm of energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Shenghao Zeng, Wenqing Ruan, Zhe Chen, Shuai Ren, J.Z. Jiang, Jiajia Lin, Heting Zhang, Zhenxuan Zhang, Jianan Fu, Qing Chen, Xiong Liang, Jiang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arsenene/Ti&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction as a Promising Z&#8208;Scheme Photocatalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408353</link>
      <description>Ling Hua, Youxi Wang, Zhenyu Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377844

                Abstract In order to address imminent energy and environmental challenges, photocatalytic water splitting emerges as a promising way for harnessing solar radiation to generate clean chemical energy. 2D arsenene (&#946;&#8208;As) has notable catalytic activity in hydrogen production. Based on first principles calculations and non&#8208;adiabatic molecular dynamics (NAMD) simulations, the &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 heterojunction is predicted to be a promising Z&#8208;scheme photocatalyst for overall solar water splitting. It has a desirable energy band structure with the valence band maximum of Ti 2 CO 2 and the conduction band minimum of &#946;&#8208;As well below and above the redox potentials of H 2 O. Both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can proceed spontaneously under light irradiation. NAMD simulations confirm that it is a Z&#8208;scheme photocatalyst with fast electron&#8211;hole combination dynamics. Instead of by intrinsic electric field, such a fast electron&#8211;hole combination is driven by a large nonadiabatic coupling. The heterojunction exhibits strong optical absorption in the visible and ultraviolet regions. The estimated solar&#8208;to&#8208;hydrogen (STH) efficiency limit of &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 reaches 32%, which is the highest among all &#946;&#8208;As based junctions reported in the literature. These results suggest that &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 is a promising photocatalyst for achieving overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Ling Hua, Youxi Wang, Zhenyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Processing of molybdenum industrial waste into sustainable and efficient nanocatalysts for water electrolysis reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6972-z</link>
      <description>F. Ursino, Giacometta Mineo, Antonino Scandurra, M. Scuderi, Angelo Forestan, Catya Alba, R. Reitano, A. Terrasi, S. Mirabella, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402499807

                Abstract The increasing need for sustainable energy and the transition from a linear to a circular economy pose great challenges to the materials science community. In this view, the chance of producing efficient nanocatalysts for water splitting using industrial waste as starting material is attractive. Here, we report low-cost processes to convert Mo-based industrial waste powder into efficient catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). pH controlled hydrothermal processing of Mo-based industrial waste powder leads to pure orthorhombic MoO 3 nanobelts (50&#8211;200 nm wide, 10 &#181;m long) with promising OER performances at 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 with an overpotential of 324 mV and Tafel slope of 45 mV&#183;dec &#8722;1 in alkaline electrolyte. Indeed, MoS 2 /MoO 3 nanostructures were obtained after sulfurization during hydrothermal processes of the MoO 3 nanobelts. HER tests in acidic environment show a promising overpotential of 208 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 94 mV&#183;dec &#8722;1 . OER and HER performances of nanocatalysts obtained from Mo industrial waste powder are comparable or better than Mo-based nanocatalysts obtained from pure commercial Mo reagent. This work shows the great potential of reusing industrial waste for energy applications, opening a promising road to join waste management and efficient and sustainable nanocatalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>F. Ursino, Giacometta Mineo, Antonino Scandurra, M. Scuderi, Angelo Forestan, Catya Alba, R. Reitano, A. Terrasi, S. Mirabella</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6972-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical synthesis and properties of titanium dioxide&#8211;titanium suboxides composite for cathodic protection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32434/0321-4095-2024-155-4-41-50</link>
      <description>&#1042;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1085;&#1099;&#1096;, O. Shmychkova, T. V. Luk&#8217;yanenko, &#1040;. &#1041;. &#1042;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;, Voprosy Khimii i Khimicheskoi Tekhnologii. None(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402425413

                This study reports a combined electrochemical method for preparation of a titanium dioxide&#8211;suboxide composite with an electrochemically deposited non-continuous platinum layer on the surface, which can be used for cathodic protection of metal structures. Platinum significantly modifies the properties of TiO2, stabilizes the surface, and prevents the formation of a passive non-conductive layer. The coating has significant advantages compared to Ti/Pt, traditionally used for electrochemical protection, as the platinum content in the composite is significantly reduced. Unlike a continuous precious metal layer, this method of composite formation, particularly thermal treatment in an air atmosphere at 5000C, allows protecting the platinum, which is encapsulated in titanium oxides, and avoiding the creeping passivation typical of traditionally used materials. The surface of the coatings was investigated using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, X-ray diffraction, scanning electron microscopy, and X-ray microanalysis. Studies of the electrocatalytic properties, especially concerning the oxygen evolution reaction, revealed deviations of the Tafel slope from the theoretical value, which is explained by structural heterogeneity and the presence of a semiconductor component. The stability and corrosion resistance of the composites were studied. It was found that the properties remain unchanged even after prolonged exposure to a corrosive environment.</description>
      <author>&#1042;. &#1040;. &#1050;&#1085;&#1099;&#1096;, O. Shmychkova, T. V. Luk&#8217;yanenko, &#1040;. &#1041;. &#1042;&#1077;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1086;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32434/0321-4095-2024-155-4-41-50</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;- tolerant CuFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; as Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Transition from Rechargeable Li-O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Li-CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad76e1</link>
      <description>Pamangadan C. Sharafudeen, Snehangshu Patra, Perumal Elumalai, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. 171(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402489128

                CO 2 -tolerant rechargeable Lithium-Air batteries are seen as a high-performing alternative to Li-ion batteries. They utilize O 2 from the air, reducing it at the cathode to form lithium peroxide (Li 2 O 2 ) during discharge which is then oxidized to form lithium-metal and freeing O 2 during charging. Most of the present studies involve pure O 2 as the cathode material instead of aerial O 2 , which has a stiff-challenge due to atmospheric CO 2 which produces Li 2 CO 3 during discharge, posing a resistive load on the battery if not re-oxidized on charging. Ideally, presence of CO 2 should enhance the charge-storage capacity if it is cycled reversibly. Thus, present research aims at taking advantage of both O 2 and CO 2 by employing metallic Cu on CuFe 2 O 4 catalyst, synthesized from a one-step auto-combustion route. The Cu metal present in the catalyst leads to a low surface-area, yet the catalyst demonstrates excellent oxygen reduction reaction and moderate oxygen evolution reaction activity. excellent CO 2 reduction reaction activity, oxidizing both the Li 2 O 2 and the Li 2 CO 3 during charge in both 10% CO 2 and 100% CO 2 atmospheres. The fabricated Li-CO 2 battery operates for practical application, suggesting the suitability of the catalyst for the transition from practical Li-O 2 battery to Li-Air battery.</description>
      <author>Pamangadan C. Sharafudeen, Snehangshu Patra, Perumal Elumalai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad76e1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium Clusters Modification Carbon Layer&#8208;Encapsulated NiCoP Nanoneedles as Advanced Electrocatalyst for Efficient Seawater Splitting Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401197</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Liu, Xueer Ning, Aize Hao, Muhammad Farooq Khan, Shania Rehman, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402333956

                Developing efficient and durable electrocatalyst for seawater splitting is crucial in hydrogen production. Herein, a multi-scale design strategy was employed to fabricate ruthenium clusters modification carbon layer-encapsulated nickel-cobalt-phosphorus (Ru/C/NiCoP) nanoneedles electrocatalyst supported on nickel foam (NF). We demonstrated that Ru/C/NiCoP/NF exhibited exceptional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performances, with low overpotential, Tafel slope and superior stability. Furthermore, the electrocatalytic mechanism of Ru/C/NiCoP was elucidated through the combination of ex-situ and in-situ characterizations, along with comprehensive electrochemical tests. Strikingly, Ru clusters and the carbon layer engendered robust electronic interaction reaction, accelerated the charge transfer rate, provided more active sites, and enhanced intrinsic catalytic activity, thus substantially promoting the OER kinetics and HER reaction steps as well as stability. In addition, the two-electrode system constructed with Ru/C/NiCoP/NF achieved current density of 10 mA cm-2 in both pure water and seawater at ultra-low potential of 1.46/1.47 V, with Faraday efficiency close to 100%. Even at higher current density of 100 mA cm-2, the required driving voltage remained low at 1.75/1.77 V, maintaining stable operation for 150 h, outperforming most reported non-noble catalysts. This innovative strategy provides facile and versatile approach for developing advanced electrocatalysts in seawater electrolysis application.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Liu, Xueer Ning, Aize Hao, Muhammad Farooq Khan, Shania Rehman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swelling the &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;/&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;Band Center Difference Induced by Heterostructure Self&#8208;Optimization Engineering for Enhanced Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402923</link>
      <description>Xuemin Wang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Na Li, Zhigang Li, Cui Zhang, Shuangxi Liu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402483676

                Abstract Monitoring the dynamic behavior of active species and modulating their electronic architecture are crucial for the development of efficient catalysts. Here, a 3D ordered multi&#8208;level porous Ni 2 P/CeO 2 heterojunction catalyst with a &#8220;self&#8208;optimization effect&#8221; is strategically synthesized for efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This catalyst exhibits a low overpotential of 235 mV at 20 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1.0 m KOH. During the OER process, the heterojunction catalyst specifically undergoes a unique phase transition involving the leaching of the P element, which triggers the formation of the PO 4 3&#8722; &#8208;NiOOH/CeO 2 catalyst with PO 4 3&#8722; adsorbed on the surface of the reconstructed product NiOOH/CeO 2 . Density functional theory calculations reveal that the CeO 2 and adsorbed&#8208;PO 4 3&#8722; in the self&#8208;optimized structure are essential and minor factors for enhancing catalytic activity, respectively. They collaborate to promote the redistribution of electron density in surface Ni and O, increasing the d / p &#8208;band center difference. This phenomenon results in optimized adsorption/desorption of the key intermediates such as *OOH and improved catalytic performance. Overall, this research highlights the potential of d / p &#8208;band modulation for the rational design of cost&#8208;effective and high&#8208;efficiency electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xuemin Wang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Na Li, Zhigang Li, Cui Zhang, Shuangxi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402923</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of NH4Cl supplementation on growth, photosynthesis, triacylglycerol content in Chlamydomonas reinhardtii under mixotrophic cultivation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/jambio/lxae233</link>
      <description>Wattanapong Sittisaree, Kittisak Yokthongwattana, Chanat Aonbangkhen, Yodying Yingchutrakul, Sucheewin Krobthong, Journal of Applied Microbiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402429263

                Abstract Aim Ammonium chloride (NH4Cl) is one of the nitrogen sources for microalgal cultivation. An excessive amounts of NH4Cl are toxic for microalgae. However, combining mixotrophic conditions and excessive quantities of NH4Cl positively affects microalgal biomass and lipid production. In this study, we investigated the impact of NH4Cl on the growth, biomass, and triglyceride (TAG) content of the green microalga Chlamydomonas reinhardtii especially under mixotrophic condition. Methods and Results Under photoautotrophic conditions (without organic carbon supplementation), adding 25 mM NH4Cl had no significant effect on microalgal growth or TAG content. However, under mixotrophic condition (with acetate supplementation), NH4Cl interfered with microalgal growth while inducing TAG content. To explore these effects further, we conducted a two-step cultivation process and found that NH4Cl reduced microalgal growth, but induced total lipid and TAG content, especially after 4-day cultivation. The photosynthesis performances showed that NH4Cl completely inhibited oxygen evolution on Day 4. However, NH4Cl slightly reduced the Fv/Fm ratio indicating that the NH4Cl supplementation directly affects microalgal photosynthesis. To investigate the TAG induction effect by NH4Cl, we compared the protein expression profiles of microalgae grown mixotrophically with and without 25 mM NH4Cl using a proteomics approach. This analysis identified 1,782 proteins, with putative acetate uptake transporter GFY5 and Acyl-coenzyme A oxidase being overexpressed in the NH4Cl-treated group. Conclusion These findings suggested that NH4Cl supplementation may stimulate acetate utilization and fatty acid synthesis pathways in microalgae cells. Our study indicated that NH4Cl supplementation can induce microalgal biomass and lipid production, particularly when combined with mixotrophic conditions.</description>
      <author>Wattanapong Sittisaree, Kittisak Yokthongwattana, Chanat Aonbangkhen, Yodying Yingchutrakul, Sucheewin Krobthong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/jambio/lxae233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Evidence for Buffer-Enhanced Proton-Coupled Electron Transfer in Metal Aquo Bond Formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l776x</link>
      <description>Matthew C. Kessinger, Thomas Whittemore, Silvia Grandi, Evgeny O. Danilov, Stefano Caramori, Felix N. Castellano, Gerald J. Meyer, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402529806

                Proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) reactions play a crucial role in the interconversion of metal-aqua and metal-hydroxo species present in transition metal complexes and oxide surfaces (M(III)-OH + e&#8722; + H+ M(II)-OH2). For ruthenium-based water oxidation catalysts, PCET reactions involved in the mechanism of oxygen evolution have demonstrated a strong dependence on the identity and concentration of the proton donor and acceptor with significant rate enhancements observed for electrocatalysis performed in acetate, phosphate, and borate buffered electrolytes. However, the systematic study of this phenomenon has been hampered by the inability to independently measure discrete rates for electron transfer (ET) and proton transfer (PT) under electrochemical applied potentials. Herein, the PCET kinetics and mechanism of metal aqua bond formation in a ruthenium water oxidation catalyst [Ru(tpy)(bpy&#8242;)H2O]2+, Ru(II)&#8722;OH2 where tpy is 2,2&#8242;:6&#8242;,2&#8243;-terpyridine and bpy&#8242; is 4,4&#8242;-diaminopropylsilatrane-2,2&#8242;-bypyridine were investigated at a conductive metal oxide interface as a function of buffer identity and concentration. The reaction of interest was triggered by visible light excitation of the catalyst and the kinetics of the independent ET and PT steps of the PCET mechanism were determined through nanosecond transient absorption spectroscopy. Kinetic measurements performed in aqueous acetate, phosphate, or borate buffer solutions revealed two distinct regimes of PT kinetics solely dependent on the buffer concentration. At the greatest buffer concentrations investigated (2 M acetate) spectral signals corresponding to the discreet ET and PT steps were absent indicative in a change in underlying PCET mechanism. Likewise, kinetic modeling indicated that PT from protonated acetate or phosphate occurred with rate constants that were 2-4 orders of magnitude greater than those for bulk water. In all, these results suggest that the presence of buffer-bases can significantly enhance PCET rates and, in this reaction, may alter the underlying mechanism.</description>
      <author>Matthew C. Kessinger, Thomas Whittemore, Silvia Grandi, Evgeny O. Danilov, Stefano Caramori, Felix N. Castellano, Gerald J. Meyer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-l776x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of residual oxygen on superconducting niobium films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0225589</link>
      <description>Miguel Manzo-Perez, Moeid Jamalzadeh, Zhujun Huang, Xiao Tong, Kim Kisslinger, Dmytro Nykypanchuk, Davood Shahrjerdi, Applied Physics Letters. 125(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402458592

                The integration of niobium (Nb) into emerging superconducting circuits can enhance their performance and function. However, growth of high purity Nb can be challenging due to its high reactivity with oxygen. Here, we examine the role of residual oxygen inside the growth chamber in transforming the structural, chemical, and superconducting properties of Nb films. We demonstrate that an increase in unintentional oxygen impurities lowers the superconducting critical temperature of Nb. This evolution coincides with the reduction of Nb crystal domains, which are separated by highly disordered oxygen-rich regions. Moreover, chemical analysis reveals the formation of niobium monoxide within the film during growth. These findings provide a comprehensive picture of how residual oxygen in the growth chamber can affect the properties of the Nb films. This study contributes to the materials science and engineering knowledge of superconducting Nb growth.</description>
      <author>Miguel Manzo-Perez, Moeid Jamalzadeh, Zhujun Huang, Xiao Tong, Kim Kisslinger, Dmytro Nykypanchuk, Davood Shahrjerdi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0225589</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peranan medan magnet dan campuran etanol-biodiesel minyak jelantah pada pembakaran droplet terhadap perilaku api dan emisi gas buang</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29303/dtm.v14i2.924</link>
      <description>Dony Perdana, S.F.W.A. Fiyanto, Dinamika Teknik Mesin. 14(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402417070

                Petroleum reserves are increasingly depleting, causing a scarcity of petroleum fuel caused by the rapid progress of transportation and the manufacturing industry. This condition forces researchers to search for and develop new renewable energy source. The purpose of research is to understanding and determines role of north-south (U-S) and south-south (S-S) magnetic fields to blend waste cooking oil biodiesel-ethanol on flame evolution, flue gas emissions, and temperature during droplet combustion. Waste cooking oil biodiesel and ethanol were used in this research by adding variations in the direction of repulsive and attractive magnetic fields with an intensity of 11000 gauss. Diameter of droplets tested was 0.3 mm and was placed on a type K thermocouple wire with diameter of 0.1 mm. This research found the role of attractive magnetic field (U-S) in blend waste cooking oil biodiesel-ethanol 20% to produce the shortest flame evolution of 704 ms, lowest CO of 165 ppm, and highest temperature of 828.5 oC. This happens because ethanol has a low flash point and large oxygen content, causing the combustion reaction to occur rapidly. The attractive of magnetic field (U-S) plays a role on attracting oxygen around flame to enter combustion reaction, while the H2O resulting from combustion is pumped out of flame.</description>
      <author>Dony Perdana, S.F.W.A. Fiyanto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29303/dtm.v14i2.924</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bi Off&#8208;Centering in Centrosymmetric BiOBr Leading to Ultrahigh Bifunctional Piezocatalytic Fuel Generation Efficiencies in Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411464</link>
      <description>Maqsuma Banoo, Kushal Samanta, Ashima Sah, Raju Roy, Monika Bhakar, Dirtha Sanyal, Digamber G. Porob, Konstantin Glazyrin, D. Topwal, Goutam Sheet, Dibyajyoti Ghosh, Ujjal K. Gautam, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402393547

                Abstract Piezocatalytic water&#8208;splitting to simultaneously produce H 2 and H 2 O 2 has many potential advantages. However, the necessity to utilize materials having polar structures limits the choice of piezocatalysts. Herein, it is demonstrated that centrosymmetric BiOBr with oxygen defects can simultaneously produce H 2 and H 2 O 2 with ultrahigh efficiencies from pure and seawater without needing assistance from noble metals or scavengers. High&#8208;pressure studies confirm that there are no non&#8208;polar&#8208;to&#8208;polar phase transitions in BiOBr, though a novel isostructural phase is discovered. Computational studies reveal that oxygen vacancy distorts the BiOBr structure to induce charge&#8208;localization and polarization. Furthermore, high pressure (i) reduces carrier effective masses and (ii) increases relative O&#8208;2 p contribution in the valence band maximum to assist catalysis and improve stability. The role of oxygen vacancy is confirmed by changing its concentration, which proportionally affects H 2 evolution. The work paves the way for defect engineering to develop piezocatalysts from a large pool of non&#8208;polar materials.</description>
      <author>Maqsuma Banoo, Kushal Samanta, Ashima Sah, Raju Roy, Monika Bhakar, Dirtha Sanyal, Digamber G. Porob, Konstantin Glazyrin, D. Topwal, Goutam Sheet, Dibyajyoti Ghosh, Ujjal K. Gautam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative studies on the microstructures of ternary CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 glasses, melts and correlation with their high-temperature viscosities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/lnvg1782</link>
      <description>Jinglin You, Xiu&#8208;Zhi Tang, Fuxiang Zhang, A. Canizar&#232;s, Catherine Bessada, Li L&#252;, Keke Tang, Qiang Zhang, Shaoping Wan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383938

                Microstructure of CaO-SiO2-based glassy samples with various Al2O3 contents were examined quantitatively by Raman spectroscopy and 27Al MAS NMR (magic-angle spinning nuclear magnetic resonance). Sequence of multiple cluster models of aluminosilicate system modified with Ca2+ and Na+ cations have been designed, and Raman spectra simulation were carried out after geometric optimisation by quantum chemistry (QC) ab initio calculation. The functional relationship between Raman scattering cross-section (RSCS) and stress index of silicon-oxygen tetrahedron (SIT) for aluminosilicates was established, which was applied to the calibration of experimental Raman spectra. Some five-fold coordinated aluminium (AlV, around 5 per cent) and less than 2 per cent six-fold coordinated aluminium (AlVI) were detected by 27Al MAS NMR, while most of aluminium remained in tetrahedral sites (AlIV). The hyperfine quantitative results of Raman spectroscopy and NMR showed a gradually production of AlIV with addition of Al2O3, along with the significant adjustment of Qi species distribution, in which Q1, Q2 reduced and fully polymerised Q4 increased while Q3 showed a non-monotonic variation and obtained the maximum at Al2O3 = 18 mol per cent. Furthermore, the effects of aluminium to bridging oxygen bond types (T-Ob, T = Si, Al) and the degree of polymerisation were also discussed in detail. The evolution of microstructure and its correlation with the viscosity of CaO-SiO2 based melts, incorporating various Al2O3 additives, have been investigated by employing in situ high temperature Raman spectroscopy at 1823 K and viscosity model. These structural features related to composition are essential theoretic foundation to understand their properties. The average Qi evolution culminates in an overall enhancement of the degree of polymerisation. Viscosity was determined utilising a rigorously selected viscosity model, elucidating a consistent upward trajectory as Al2O3 content is incrementally added. Furthermore, a quantitative analysis of the relationship between viscosity and structure was conducted based on the average number of non-bridging oxygen per network-forming tetrahedron (NBO/T). It provides valuable insights for examining and predicting viscosity behaviour of aluminosilicate systems.</description>
      <author>Jinglin You, Xiu&#8208;Zhi Tang, Fuxiang Zhang, A. Canizar&#232;s, Catherine Bessada, Li L&#252;, Keke Tang, Qiang Zhang, Shaoping Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/lnvg1782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation via repression: Regulator of symbiosome differentiation (RSD) acts as zone-specific repressor to mediate nodule development</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.tzg3n6</link>
      <description>Akanksha Bhardwaj, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402490914

                This talk will be pre-recorded, with virtual Q A. Medicago truncatula forms indeterminate nodules having successive development zones. Indeterminate nodules maintain an oxygen gradient to uncouple symbiosome differentiation at invasion zone and nitrogen fixation at fixation zone. The oxygen gradient maxima to minima from apex to base of nodule length depends on *leghemoglobins (LgHbs )* expression which is responsible for oxygen buffering as LgHbs create micro-oxic environment. In this study, we demonstrate the mode of action of Regulator of Symbiosome Differentiation (RSD), a transcriptional repressor. RSD interacts with Nodule Inception (NIN) and NIN-like protein 2 (NLP2). Studies confirm NIN-NLP2 activate *LgHbs* expression. RSD expression and protein localization remains confined within invasion and interzone. We identified this zone-specific expression of RSD is crucial as RSD represses *LgHb* expression at invasion zone. Manipulation of the stoichiometry of RSD, NIN, and NLP2 in planta disrupts *LgHb* expression and impairs functional nodule development. To unravel, the dynamics of the invasion zone-specific regulation, we performed translatome and transcriptome profiling using the RSD promoter, to identify putative targets of RSD. Collectively, our findings suggest that RSD-mediated repression of NIN and NLP2-targets are crucial for symbiosome differentiation. RSD recruitment in the nitrogen-fixing clade also recommends its evolution during nodulation and conserved functionality in other legume species as well. Thus RSD, as a repressor from its invasion zone optimizes the genetic network crucial for functional nodule development.</description>
      <author>Akanksha Bhardwaj</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.tzg3n6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic modelling of the Fe-Al-Ti-O system and evolution of Al-Ti complex inclusions during Ti-added ultra-low carbon steel production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/fwlu4527</link>
      <description>Young Joo Park, Youn&#8208;Bae Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383135

                Ti-added ultra-low carbon (ULC) steel is produced by adding Al and Ti during the secondary refining process to deoxidise molten steel and to bind C and N which are detrimental to the deep drawing quality of the steel product. However, the production of Ti-added ULC steel faces challenges, including submerged entry nozzle clogging and surface defects on cold rolled coils. The troubles were often attributed to &#8216;Al-Ti complex inclusions&#8217; in the molten steel. However, the evolution of oxide inclusions including their stability has been still unclear. In the present study, the evolution of these inclusions in Ti-added ULC steel was investigated by phase diagram measurement, CALPHAD thermodynamic modelling, high-temperature stability test for the oxides, and observation of transient behaviour of oxide inclusions in the steel. The phase diagram of the Al-Ti-O system was elucidated with an emphasis on oxygen potential, which significantly controls the stability of the oxides. CALPHAD thermodynamic models and a self-consistent database were developed. The transient behaviour of Al-Ti complex inclusions in Ti-added ULC steel was observed in situ using a confocal scanning laser microscope. This was additionally validated by the new thermodynamic model. The equilibrium phases of the oxide inclusions were investigated using a high-temperature resistance furnace, and were analysed using a secondary electron microscope, energy dispersive spectrometer, and electron back-scattered diffraction. By considering the morphology and crystal structure of these inclusions, the evolution of Al-Ti oxide inclusions was elucidated. Various behaviour of Al-Ti inclusions and their influence on steel cleanliness are discussed.</description>
      <author>Young Joo Park, Youn&#8208;Bae Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/fwlu4527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase equilibria of Al2TiO5&#8211;Ti3O5 pseudobrookite solid solution in the Al2O3&#8211;TiOx system under various oxygen partial pressures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/mcam4452</link>
      <description>Young Joo Park, W.K. Kim, Youn&#8208;Bae Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383589

                The phase equilibria in the Al2O3&#8211;TiOx system were investigated in wide ranges of temperature and oxygen partial pressure: 1300~1600&#176;C and 10-16.6~10-8 atm, respectively. The equilibrium phases and their compositions were identified using X-ray diffraction (XRD) and electron probe micro-analysis (EPMA), respectively. Most noticeably, a wide range of pseudobrookite solid solution was found in equilibrium with almost pure alumina. At each temperature, the cationic ratio expressed as RTi = nTi/(nAl + nTi)) of the pseudobrookite solid solution showed a noteworthy dependency on the oxygen partial pressure. This resulted in the formation of a broad range of pseudobrookite solid solutions, ranging from Al2TiO5 (RTi = 1/3) to Ti3O5 (RTi = 1.0). Complete miscibility within the pseudobrookite solid solution was observed at 1600&#176;C, with only a minor miscibility gap becoming evident below 1500&#176;C. Based on the results obtained in the present study, the behaviours of Al2TiO5 pseudobrookite have implications in two key domains: (1) understanding changes in the physical properties of the materials, and (2) elucidating the evolution of Al&#8211;Ti complex oxide inclusions in liquid steel which can deteriorate the steel cleanliness.</description>
      <author>Young Joo Park, W.K. Kim, Youn&#8208;Bae Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/mcam4452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Study of the Hydrogen Auto-Ignition Process in Oxygen&#8211;Nitrogen and Oxygen&#8211;Water Vapor Oxidizer: Numerical Investigations in Mixture Fraction Space and 3D Forced Homogeneous Isotropic Turbulent Flow Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174525</link>
      <description>Lena Caban, Artur Tyliszczak, Energies. 17(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402363958

                In this paper, we analyze the auto-ignition process of hydrogen in a hot oxidizer stream composed of oxygen&#8211;nitrogen and oxygen&#8211;water vapor with nitrogen/water vapor mass fractions in a range of 0.1&#8211;0.9. The temperature of the oxidizer varies from 1100 K to 1500 K and the temperature of hydrogen is assumed to be 300 K. The research is performed in 1D mixture fraction space and in a forced homogeneous isotropic turbulent (HIT) flow field. In the latter case, the Large Eddy Simulation (LES) method combined with the Eulerian Stochastic Field (ESF) combustion model is applied. The results obtained in mixture fraction space aim to determine the most reactive mixture fraction, maximum flame temperature, and dependence on the scalar dissipation rate. Among others, we found that the ignition in H2-O2-H2O mixtures occurs later than in H2-O2-N2 mixtures, especially at low oxidizer temperatures. On the other hand, for a high oxidizer temperature, the ignitability of H2-O2-H2O mixtures is extended, i.e., the ignition occurs for a larger content of H2O and takes place faster. The 3D LES-ESF results show that the ignition time is virtually independent of initial conditions, e.g., randomness of an initial flow field and turbulence intensity. The latter parameter, however, strongly affects the flame evolution. It is shown that the presence of water vapor decreases ignitability and makes flames more prone to extinction.</description>
      <author>Lena Caban, Artur Tyliszczak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17174525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degenerated intraligamentary leiomioma as a simulator of malignant ovarian pathology. Report of a case</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.51288/00840316</link>
      <description>Ernesto Lara, Dariela Perdomo, H&#233;ctor Puente Gonz&#225;lez, Revista de Obstetricia y Ginecolog&#237;a de Venezuela. 84(03)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402468802

                Leiomyomas are benign mesenchymal tumors that occur as the most common uterine neoplasm in women of reproductive age. Depending on its growth, its blood supply may be compromised, causing degenerative changes due to lack of oxygen, which gives it an atypical appearance that may cause confusion with the diagnosis. The case of a 47-year-old patient is described, who consults for a progressive increase in the volume of abdominal circumference of 7 months of evolution, referred to the gynecology oncology consultation due to a large retrouterine tumor mass of probable ovarian origin with a high risk of malignancy. After performing preoperative studies, she was taken to the operating room, obtaining as a definitive diagnosis, leiomyoma with hyaline and focal hydropic degeneration. Leiomyomas with degenerative changes can simulate malignant ovarian tumors, which is why they should be considered as a differential diagnosis before surgical interventions for large abdominopelvic tumors. Keywords: Leiomyoma, Hyaline Degeneration, Hydropic Degeneration, Simulator.</description>
      <author>Ernesto Lara, Dariela Perdomo, H&#233;ctor Puente Gonz&#225;lez</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.51288/00840316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Younger age for the oldest magnetic white dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.04695</link>
      <description>Sivan Ginzburg, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402386119

                Sufficiently old white dwarfs cool down through a convective envelope that directly couples their degenerate cores to the surface. Magnetic fields may inhibit this convection by stiffening the criterion for convective instability. We consistently implemented the modified criterion in the stellar evolution code MESA, and computed the cooling of white dwarfs as a function of their mass and magnetic field $B$. In contrast to previous estimates, we find that magnetic fields can significantly change the cooling time $t$ even if they are relatively weak $B^2\ll 8\pi P$, where $P$ is the pressure at the edge of the degenerate core. Fields $B\gtrsim 1\textrm{ MG}$ open a radiative window that decouples the core from the convective envelope, effectively lowering the luminosity to that of a fully radiative white dwarf. We identified a population of observed white dwarfs that are younger by $\Delta t\sim\textrm{Gyr}$ than currently thought due to this magnetic inhibition of convection - comparable to the cooling delay due to carbon-oxygen phase separation. In volume-limited samples, the frequency and strength of magnetic fields increase with age. Accounting for magnetic inhibition is therefore essential for accurate cooling models for cosmic chronology and for determining the origin of the magnetic fields.</description>
      <author>Sivan Ginzburg</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.04695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Non-Point Source Pollution Prevention and Control System in Nansi Lake Basin Based on System Dynamics Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177831</link>
      <description>Mengxia Liu, Chunyu Liu, Min Xiao, Meirui Li, Mingjun Jiang, Shicai Wang, Lei Yin, Baolei Zhang, Sustainability. 16(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402373209

                Agriculture, as an important activity on which human beings depend for their livelihood, brings serious environmental problems while meeting the needs of human survival, among which agricultural non-point source (NPS) pollution is one of the most urgent environmental problems. This study quantitatively assessed the loading characteristics spatial and temporal evolution patterns of two agricultural NPS pollutants, chemical oxygen demand (COD) and ammonia nitrogen (NH3-N), from 2010 to 2020 in the Nansi Lake Basin as an example, and constructed a system dynamics (SD) simulation model to simulate and analyze agricultural NPS pollution under different development and treatment scenarios, based on an investigation of the regional prevention and control strategy of agricultural NPS pollution and the technological system. The results show that the current status of agricultural NPS pollution load in the Nansi Lake Basin is poor, and the level of pollution load is high, showing obvious geographical differences. In terms of temporal changes, the pollution loads of the two pollutants showed a decreasing trend from 2010 to 2020, among which the pollution load of NH3-N showed the largest change. Spatially, the spatial distribution of each type of pollutant has some similarities, with smaller pollution loads in Jining and Zaozhuang and relatively larger pollution loads in Heze and Ningyang. The main source of COD pollution in the Nansi Lake Basin is rural life, with an emission proportion of 52.85%, and the main sources of NH3-N pollution from agricultural NPS pollution in the area are rural life and livestock and poultry farming, with emission proportions of 47.55% and 35.36%, respectively. Under the status quo continuum scenario, the pollution load values for COD are consistently higher than those for NH3-N, so the relative impact of COD is greater. In this study, the principles and methods of SD in system science are adopted to deal with the agricultural NPS pollution of Nansi Lake Basin, and the evolution of its behavioral characteristics are simulated, forecasted, and predicted, and policy experiments are conducted, with a view to providing references for the prevention and control of agricultural NPS pollution in Nansi Lake Basin and further research.</description>
      <author>Mengxia Liu, Chunyu Liu, Min Xiao, Meirui Li, Mingjun Jiang, Shicai Wang, Lei Yin, Baolei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16177831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Star&#8211;Planet Composition Connection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-astro-071221-053007</link>
      <description>Johanna Teske, Annual Review of Astronomy and Astrophysics. 62(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402503252

                The mantra &#8220;know thy star, know thy planet&#8221; has proven to be very important for many aspects of exoplanet science. Here I review how stellar abundances inform our understanding of planet composition and, thus, formation and evolution. In particular, I discuss how: &#9642; The strongest star&#8211;planet connection is still the giant planet&#8211;metallicity correlation, the strength of which may indicate a break point between the formation of planets versus brown dwarfs. &#9642; We do not have very good constraints on the lower metallicity limit for planet formation, although new statistics from TESS are helping, and it appears that, at low [Fe/H], &#945; elements can substitute for iron as seeds for planet formation. &#9642; The depletion of refractory versus volatile elements in stellar photospheres (particularly the Sun) was initially suggested as a sign of small planet formation but is challenging to interpret, and small differences in binary star compositions can be attributed mostly to processes other than planet formation. &#9642; We can and should go beyond comparisons of the carbon-to-oxygen ratio in giant planets and their host stars, incorporating other volatile and refractory species to better constrain planet formation pathways. &#9642; There appears to be a positive correlation between small planet bulk density and host star metallicity, but exactly how closely small planet refractory compositions match those of their host stars&#8212;and their true diversity&#8212;is still uncertain.</description>
      <author>Johanna Teske</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1146/annurev-astro-071221-053007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IL-1&#946; primed mesenchymal stromal cells moderate hemorrhagic shock-induced vascular permeability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4866976/v1</link>
      <description>Nathalie Baudry, Aur&#233;lie Campeanu, Claude Aussel, Caroline Doutrelon, Marion Grosbot, S&#233;bastien Banzet, &#201;ric Vicaut, Juliette Peltzer, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402463365

                Abstract Background: Hemorrhagic shock (HS) corresponds to absolute hypovolemia creating an imbalance between oxygen supply and consumption. This causes an impaired hemostasis, a systemic inflammatory response, and microvascular permeability which can lead to multiple organ failure (MOF). There is no specific treatment for the endothelial dysfunction that plays a major role in the evolution towards MOF. Mesenchymal Stromal Cells (MSC) have been used in clinical trials for their immunomodulation and tissue repair capabilities for many years. Moreover, we previously showed that IL-1&#946;-primed-MSC (MSCp) attenuated HS-induced organ injuries. The objective was to determine whether MSCp could prevent the onset of MOF after HS by preventing endothelial dysfunction. Methods: We developed a rat model: 90min of HS at a fixed Mean Arterial Pressure of 35mmHg, followed by resuscitation and transfusion. MSCp treatment was administered intravenously at the beginning of the resuscitation. After 6h, plasmatic endothelial markers, vascular permeability (Evans Blue (EB) administration) and renal and hepatic water contents (difference between wet and dry weight), were evaluated. We also evaluated the ability of MSCp to limit the adhesion of leukocytes to an activated endothelium in vitro. Results: Our results indicate that early administration of MSCp could reduce hepatic vascular leakage associated with a trend to decrease of Syndecan-1, ICAM-1, vWF and VCAM-1. In vitro, these cells are able to decrease leukocyte-endothelial cell bonding. Therefore, we suggest that MSCp are able to prevent endothelial dysfonction that contributes to liver injury.</description>
      <author>Nathalie Baudry, Aur&#233;lie Campeanu, Claude Aussel, Caroline Doutrelon, Marion Grosbot, S&#233;bastien Banzet, &#201;ric Vicaut, Juliette Peltzer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4866976/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling and 3-D simulation of petroleum coke calcination process: investigation of the effect of main operating variables</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/ijcre-2024-0016</link>
      <description>Mohammad Hosein Eghbal Ahmadi, Shokoufe Tayyebi, Amir Mosayebi, International Journal of Chemical Reactor Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402507204

                Abstract Coke calcination is a process that involves heating green petroleum coke to purify it and eliminate volatile materials for subsequent processing. Due to the complexity of the rotary kiln used in this process, conducting experimental studies can be challenging and restricted. However, quantitative analyses based on developed models can provide a foundation for optimizing and controlling the process, which can significantly enhance the design efficiency. A three-dimensional simulation model of a rotary calcining kiln for petroleum coke was created using COMSOL Multiphysics in a steady-state mode. This model accounted for all relevant physical and chemical phenomena in the gas stream and coke bed flow, including heat transfer, combustion, and the evolution of volatile matter and coke dust. The mathematical modeling yielded distributions of temperature and mass fractions within the kiln, as well as the velocity field. The results revealed two distinct peak temperatures in the gas phase: 1,780 K near the primary air injection point and 1,605 K near the tertiary air injection points. The findings were analyzed, and the impact of key variables was explored. The simulation data indicated that for every decrease of 10&#8211;15 m/s in air flow, the gas peak temperature dropped by approximately 100&#176;. Additionally, an increase in the input oxygen concentration led to enhanced combustion, resulting in higher peak concentrations of CO 2 . The developed simulation model has proven to be a valuable and promising tool for the design and optimization of petroleum coke rotary kilns.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Hosein Eghbal Ahmadi, Shokoufe Tayyebi, Amir Mosayebi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/ijcre-2024-0016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macroalgae from the early Cambrian Chengjiang biota</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/spp2.1585</link>
      <description>Gaorong Li, Fan Wei, Jason Guo, Peiyun Cong, Papers in Palaeontology. 10(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402484130

                Abstract The Chengjiang biota, a Burgess Shale&#8208;type Lagerst&#228;tte in eastern Yunnan, South China (Cambrian Series 2, Stage 3), provides valuable information regarding the origin and early evolution of metazoans, and complex marine ecosystems. Although the major animal phyla in the Chengjiang biota have been extensively studied, macroalgae have received comparatively little attention. Here, we establish new taxa Yunnanospirellus typica and Y . elegans , describe five genera and six species ( Tawuia sp., Morania fragmenta , Liulingjitaenia alloplecta , Longfengshania stipitata , Lo . spheria and Paralongfengshania sicyoides ) not previously reported in the Chengjiang biota, and elucidate the pith structure of Enteromophites intestinalis . With 13 genera and 17 species now recorded, macroalgae rank fourth in species&#8208;level biodiversity in the Chengjiang biota (behind Euarthropoda, Porifera and Priapulida). Macroalgae account for 71.57% of total abundance, far more than all other animal phyla in the Chengjiang biota. Fuxianospira is the most dominant genus, accounting for 52.01% of all macroalgae specimens. Unattached (floating, planktonic or drifting) forms dominate (eight attached; nine unattached species). The high diversity of attached macroalgae indicates that the macroalgal communities adapted to the Proterozoic firm substrate (probably covered by microbial mats) persisted from the Ediacaran to the early Cambrian, providing compelling evidence for the existence of firm substrate during this time. Meanwhile, the blooming of unattached macroalgae in the Chengjiang biota suggests that other niches were also rich in macroalgae. Unattached macroalgae might have provided oxygen and energy to metazoans, eventually leading to ecological expansion in the upper and middle water column of the early Cambrian seas.</description>
      <author>Gaorong Li, Fan Wei, Jason Guo, Peiyun Cong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/spp2.1585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The oxygen paradox in alkaline zinc-air battery via the competition of an unidentified anodic chemical reduction with cathodic kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-2rxlx</link>
      <description>Subhra R. Pattanayak, Pallavi Thakur, Ravi K. Biroju, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402498178

                Can the fuel in use adversely affect the performance of an energy storage system? Here, oxygen (O2) in zinc-air (O2) battery (ZAB) is shown to impact the anodic process adversely, leading to early cell failure, though its amount limiting can affect the cathodic reaction kinetics. An unexplored chemical reduction process of dissolved O2 on metallic zinc in alkaline medium leading to peroxide radical (O2&#729;&#175;) species generation is proven, by electron paramagnetic resonance spectroscopy (EPR) and hydrodynamic voltammetry studies, followed by the formation of ZnO passivation layer on the Zn surface causing cell death. Keeping similar discharge times, early ZnO passivation occurred on the ZAB with its anode kept in an O2 rich environment than in the other one of O2 free environment. A slight modification in the cell design ensuring the limited availability of O2 at anode provided ~5 times extended cyclability (~7 hours to ~35 hours) than the ZAB with no such control leading to enhanced specific capacity. Presence of O2 in the anodic compartment leads to early cell failure from passivating ZnO formation impeding charge transfer. Limiting the O2 transfer from the cathodic side to anodic compartment can extend the cell cyclability and enhance discharge capacity. As alkaline ZABs are proposed for applications ranging from portable hearing aids to mini-grids, with self-discharge from the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) on metallic Zn as a major roadblock, this study unravels predominant parasitic chemical process by O2 on the Zn surface, highlighting the importance of cathodic O2 crossover inhibition in the alkaline ZAB.</description>
      <author>Subhra R. Pattanayak, Pallavi Thakur, Ravi K. Biroju</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-2rxlx</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2838/1/011001</link>
      <description>, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2838(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402357804

                With the rapid progress of science and technology, the research and application in the fields of energy technology and materials science are increasingly in-depth, and experts and scholars around the world are committed to promoting the innovation and development in these areas. It is against this background that we welcomed the highly anticipated 2024 8 th International Conference on Energy Technology and Materials Science (ICETMS 2024). The conference was successfully held in Chongqing, China from May 31 st to June 2 nd , 2024, attracting the participation of almost 100 scholars, researchers and industry experts from all over the world. The convening of this conference has benefited from the active participation and enthusiastic support of experts and scholars around the world. We received a large number of high-quality paper submissions, covering New and Renewable Energy Technologies, Traditional Energy Transformation and Cleaner Production, Energy Storage Technologies and Battery Materials, Energy Security and Sustainable Development, Energy System Simulation and Optimization, and many other aspects. After a rigorous review process, excellent papers from different countries and regions were finally accepted, which fully demonstrated the latest research results and innovative ideas in these domains. In the course of the conference, we invited well-known experts and scholars at home and abroad to give keynote speeches and reports, and their wonderful speeches provided valuable academic inspiration and reflection for the participants. Among these, with the research Industrial Fabrication of Electrocatalysts for Green Hydrogen Production , Prof Hui Pan (University of Macau, China) introduced the design, synthesis and possible industrial production of novel electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions (HER and OER). And his research demonstrated that multi-metal compound systems were catalytically active for OER and HER in electrochemical energy devices, which may find practical application in hydrogen-energy technologies. At the same time, we also organized a number of group discussions, providing participants with more in-depth communication and interaction opportunities. The successful holding of this conference not only promoted the academic exchanges and cooperation in the fields of energy technology and materials science, but also injected new vitality and impetus into the development of these domains. Finally, we would like to express our heartfelt thanks and high respect to all the experts and scholars who participated in this conference. At the same time, we would also like to thank the organizing committee for its hard work and selfless dedication, which has provided a strong guarantee for the success of the conference. We look forward to continuing to work with experts and scholars in the coming days to promote the development and progress of energy technology and materials science! List of Committee Member is available in this Pdf.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2838/1/011001</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
