<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 01:12:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing ruthenium oxide with bimetallic Co2CrO4 for highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.260</link>
      <description>Mengyue Qi, Xinyu Zheng, Huamei Tong, Haibo Liu, Di Li, Zaoxue Yan, Deli Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 677(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4401375873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyue Qi, Xinyu Zheng, Huamei Tong, Haibo Liu, Di Li, Zaoxue Yan, Deli Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Defect Engineering Approach to Generate a Ru-Comof@Mos2 Heterointerface with Enhanced Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4912480</link>
      <description>Boka Fikadu Banti, Mahendra Goddati, Njemuwa Nwaji, Juyong Gwak, Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Hyojin Kang, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Jaebeom Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401160688

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boka Fikadu Banti, Mahendra Goddati, Njemuwa Nwaji, Juyong Gwak, Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Hyojin Kang, Hee&#8208;Joon Chun, Jaebeom Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4912480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Ir/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Composite Oxygen Evolution Catalyst and Load Analysis as Anode Catalyst Layer of Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c02299</link>
      <description>Peng Huang, Xiao Xu Xu, Yashi Hao, Hong Zhao, Xin Liang, Zuobo Yang, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401163043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Huang, Xiao Xu Xu, Yashi Hao, Hong Zhao, Xin Liang, Zuobo Yang, Jimmy Yun, Jie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c02299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Industrially Important Ir&#8211;W-Based Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Bifunctional Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00330</link>
      <description>Imtiaz Ahmed, Saptarshi Ghosh Dastider, Rathindranath Biswas, Ayan Roy, Krishnakanta Mondal, Krishna Kanta Haldar, ACS Applied Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401169681

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Imtiaz Ahmed, Saptarshi Ghosh Dastider, Rathindranath Biswas, Ayan Roy, Krishnakanta Mondal, Krishna Kanta Haldar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaenm.4c00330</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen and Sulfur Incorporated Chitosan-Derived Carbon Sphere Hybrid MXene as Highly Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101528</link>
      <description>Mohamedazeem M. Mohideen, Abdul Qadir, S. Balachandran, Saeideh Kholghi Eshkalak, Yong Liu, Materials Today Physics. 46(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401170316

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohamedazeem M. Mohideen, Abdul Qadir, S. Balachandran, Saeideh Kholghi Eshkalak, Yong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtphys.2024.101528</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface hydroxylation engineering to boost oxygen evolution reaction on IrO2/TiO2 for PEM water electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124462</link>
      <description>Chaoyu Yang, Wenhui Ling, Yanping Zhu, Yunxiao Yang, Shu Dong, Chengyu Wu, Zhangrui Wang, Shuai Yang, Jun Li, Guoliang Wang, Yifan Huang, Bo Yang, Qingqing Cheng, Zhi Liu, Hui Yang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401171460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoyu Yang, Wenhui Ling, Yanping Zhu, Yunxiao Yang, Shu Dong, Chengyu Wu, Zhangrui Wang, Shuai Yang, Jun Li, Guoliang Wang, Yifan Huang, Bo Yang, Qingqing Cheng, Zhi Liu, Hui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructure Fe7S8/Mn(OH)2 of incomplete sulfurization induces Mn atoms with high density of states for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction and supercapacitor electrochemical performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.244</link>
      <description>Dexing Meng, Hong Liang, Zhaojun Fang, Qianqian Jiang, Huabo Huang, Xiaodong Wu, Jianguo Tang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401171992

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dexing Meng, Hong Liang, Zhaojun Fang, Qianqian Jiang, Huabo Huang, Xiaodong Wu, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photosynthesis of CH3OH via oxygen-atom-grafting from CO2 to CH4 enabled by AuPd/GaN</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50801-3</link>
      <description>Hui Su, Jing&#8208;Tan Han, Botong Miao, Mahdi Salehi, Chao&#8208;Jun Li, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401178530

                The direct co-conversion of methane and carbon dioxide into valuable chemicals has been a longstanding scientific pursuit for carbon neutrality and combating climate change. Herein, we present a photo-driven chemical process that reforms these two major greenhouse gases together to generate green methanol and CO, two high-valued industrial chemicals. Isotopic labeling and control experiments indicate an oxygen-atom-graft occurs, wherein CO</description>
      <author>Hui Su, Jing&#8208;Tan Han, Botong Miao, Mahdi Salehi, Chao&#8208;Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50801-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low&#8208;Cost Self&#8208;Reconstructed High Entropy Oxide as an Ultra&#8208;Durable OER Electrocatalyst for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402241</link>
      <description>S. Karthikeyan, S. Ramakrishnan, Sampath Prabhakaran, Mohan Raj Subramaniam, Mohamed Mamlouk, Do Hwan Kim, Dong Jin Yoo, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401179912

                Abstract Future energy loss can be minimized to a greater extent via developing highly active electrocatalysts for alkaline water electrolyzers. Incorporating an innovative design like high entropy oxides, dealloying, structural reconstruction, in situ activation can potentially reduce the energy barriers between practical and theoretical potentials. Here, a Fd&#8208;3m spinel group high entropy oxide is developed via a simple solvothermal and calcination approach. The developed (FeCoMnZnMg) 3 O 4 electrocatalyst shows a near equimolar distribution of all the metal elements resulting in higher entropy (&#916;S &#8776;1.61R) and higher surface area. The self&#8208;reconstructed spinel high entropy oxide (S&#8208;HEO) catalyst exhibited a lower overpotential of 240 mV to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and enhanced reaction kinetics (59 mV dec &#8722;1 ). Noticeably, the S&#8208;HEO displayed an outstanding durability of 1000 h without any potential loss, significantly outperforming most of the reported OER electrocatalysts. Further, S&#8208;HEO is evaluated as the anode catalyst for an anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) in 1 m , 0.1 m KOH, and DI water at 20 and 60 &#176;C. These results demonstrate that S&#8208;HEO is a highly attractive, non&#8208;noble class of materials for high active oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts allowing fine&#8208;tuning beyond the limits of bi&#8208; or trimetallic oxides.</description>
      <author>S. Karthikeyan, S. Ramakrishnan, Sampath Prabhakaran, Mohan Raj Subramaniam, Mohamed Mamlouk, Do Hwan Kim, Dong Jin Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Surface Oxygen Valence States via Interfacial Potential in BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/CoO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;/Au Photoanode for Enhanced Selective Photoelectrochemical Oxidation of Glycerol to Dihydroxyacetone</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409349</link>
      <description>Lu Wang, Zizhong Chen, Qi Zhao, Ning Wen, Liang Shen, Xiuling Jiao, Yuguo Xia, Dairong Chen, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401179940

                Abstract The concept of photoelectrochemical conversion of biomass into industrially valuable chemicals presents a compelling strategy to supplant the lower&#8208;value oxygen evolution typically associated with photoanodes. Here, a surface potential manipulation method by regulating the surface oxygen valence states is put forward, which is demonstrated to be effective in enhancing the selective photoelectrochemical oxidation of glycerol to dihydroxyacetone (DHA). This involves the concurrent establishment of a BiVO 4 /CoO x heterojunction and a BiVO 4 /Au Schottky junction, aiming to fine&#8208;tune the BiVO 4 photoanode's surface potential and improve both its charge carrier separation and interfacial transfer kinetics. The BiVO 4 /CoO x /Au photoanode exhibits a photocurrent density of 6.15 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). Meanwhile, selective glycerol oxidation efficiency achieves a DHA evolution rate of 339.74 mmol m &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 and a selectivity exceeding 60%. Experiments and theoretical analysis underscore the pivotal role played by the surface potential in mediating glycerol and DHA adsorption and desorption processes. Additionally, the diminished surface potential attributed to the CoO x and Au amendments is responsible for the decreased Gibbs free energy of the dehydrogenation's rate&#8208;limiting step involving the intermediate carbon species. This work demonstrates a method to design glycerol oxidation catalysts by modulating the interfacial molecular adsorption/desorption by surface potential regulation.</description>
      <author>Lu Wang, Zizhong Chen, Qi Zhao, Ning Wen, Liang Shen, Xiuling Jiao, Yuguo Xia, Dairong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneously Improving Energy Storage and Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Causing Regional Defects in MOF-on-MOF Derived Hollow Se-Doped CoP-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P Heterojunctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08244</link>
      <description>Shuangxing Cui, Yifan Tang, Wan Cui, Guochang Li, Xunwen Xiao, Lei Han, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401183523

                Doping heteroatoms into metal phosphides to modify their electronic structure is an effective method, but the incomplete exposure of active sites is its inherent drawback. In this experiment, both Se doping and P vacancies are simultaneously introduced into CoP-Fe</description>
      <author>Shuangxing Cui, Yifan Tang, Wan Cui, Guochang Li, Xunwen Xiao, Lei Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Location effects of vanadium in NiFe layered double hydroxides for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03436h</link>
      <description>Mengze Ma, Yanhui Zhang, Xiaoqian Ding, Jianlei Jing, Linbo Jin, Wei Liu, Daojin Zhou, Xiaoming Sun, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401185722

                V can exist as three vanadium-based species, i.e. , doped V III in LDHs laminates, intercalated VO 3 &#8722; between LDHs interlayers, and free VO 3 &#8722; as an additive in KOH electrolyte. The study shows their role in altering the OER performance of NiFe-LDHs.</description>
      <author>Mengze Ma, Yanhui Zhang, Xiaoqian Ding, Jianlei Jing, Linbo Jin, Wei Liu, Daojin Zhou, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03436h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous&#8208;Crystalline Heterostructured Nanoporous High&#8208;Entropy Alloys for High&#8208;Efficiency pH&#8208;Universal Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400793</link>
      <description>Xueqian Yu, Xianzu Gong, Haiqing Qiao, Xiaobing Liu, Chao Ma, Ruijuan Xiao, Ran Li, Zhang Tao, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401188558

                Abstract Developing high&#8208;efficiency durable electrocatalysts in wide pH range for water splitting is significant for environmentally&#8208;friendly synthesis of renewable hydrogen energy. Herein, a facile method by dealloying designable multicomponent metallic glass precursors is reported to synthesize amorphous&#8208;crystalline heterostructured nanoporous high&#8208;entropy alloys (AC&#8208;HEAs) of CuAgAuPtPd, CuAgAuIrRu, and CuAgAuPtPdIrRu, heaped up by nanocrystalline particles with an average size of 2&#8208;3 nm and the amorphous glued phase. The synthesized AC&#8208;HEA&#8208;CuAgAuPtPd owns highly catalytic performances for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), with 9.5 and 20 mV to reach 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 and 1.0 m KOH, and AC&#8208;HEA&#8208;CuAgAuIrRu delivers 208 and 200 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Moreover, a two&#8208;electrode electrolyzer made of the AC&#8208;HEA&#8208;CuAgAuIrRu bifunctional electrodes exhibit a low cell voltage of 1.48 and 1.49 V in the acidic and alkaline conditions at 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 for overall water splitting. Combining the enhanced catalytic activities from nanoscale amorphous structure and atom&#8208;level synergistic catalyst in AC&#8208;HEAs provides an effective pathway for pH&#8208;universal electrocatalysts of water splitting.</description>
      <author>Xueqian Yu, Xianzu Gong, Haiqing Qiao, Xiaobing Liu, Chao Ma, Ruijuan Xiao, Ran Li, Zhang Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Coupling Effect of Multi-Metallic Heterostructure to Enhance Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Quasi-Solid-State Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144795</link>
      <description>Jiaheng Wang, Fengxiang Yang, YuChen Wang, Yang Zhao, Jia Li, Aiping Fang, Songyuan Wu, Qingwei Wang, Jiarui Li, Jiaxu Gong, Jiaxu Gong, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401198496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaheng Wang, Fengxiang Yang, YuChen Wang, Yang Zhao, Jia Li, Aiping Fang, Songyuan Wu, Qingwei Wang, Jiarui Li, Jiaxu Gong, Jiaxu Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of anodic treatment of nickel in deep eutectic solvents on electrocatalytic activity in oxygen evolution and urea oxidation reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32434/0321-4095-2024-154-3-145-154</link>
      <description>V. S. Protsenko, D.O. Makhota, S. &#1040;. Korniy, T.E. Butyrina, &#1060;. &#1048;. &#1044;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, Voprosy Khimii i Khimicheskoi Tekhnologii. None(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401198913

                The influence of anodic potentiostatic treatment of nickel surface in deep eutectic solvents, ethaline and reline (eutectic mixtures of choline chloride with ethylene glycol and urea, respectively), on the electrocatalytic activity in the electrochemical reactions of oxygen evolution and urea oxidation in an aqueous alkaline medium (1 M NaOH) was investigated for the first time. It was shown that, depending on the chosen treatment potential and the nature of the eutectic solvent used, a significant increase in the rate of the studied processes was observed. Specifically, after anodic treatment of nickel under certain conditions, the polarization of the oxygen evolution reaction at a current density of 0.1 A/cm2 could be reduced by approximately 150&#8211;200 mV, and the maximum current density of urea oxidation could be increased by an order of magnitude (from 0.012 A/cm2 to 0.131 A/cm2 at a urea concentration of 0.33 mol/dm3 in alkaline solution). The observed increase in electrocatalytic activity after anodic treatment of nickel in deep eutectic solvents is likely related to changes in surface morphology patterns and the nature and concentration of relevant electroactive sites on the electrode surface. The results obtained in this work can be used for the development of highly efficient electrode materials for green hydrogen energy.</description>
      <author>V. S. Protsenko, D.O. Makhota, S. &#1040;. Korniy, T.E. Butyrina, &#1060;. &#1048;. &#1044;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32434/0321-4095-2024-154-3-145-154</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-iron Co-doped ammonium phosphomolybdate for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution in acidic electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.292</link>
      <description>L. Y. Xin, Li Luo, Tian Gan, Xianhe Liu, Ze-Da Meng, Mengjiao Zhu, Shou&#8208;Qing Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401203924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. Y. Xin, Li Luo, Tian Gan, Xianhe Liu, Ze-Da Meng, Mengjiao Zhu, Shou&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing post-treatment strategies for enhanced oxygen reduction/evolution activity in Co&#8211;N&#8211;C electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.388</link>
      <description>Gulnara Yusibova, Kefeng Ping, Maike K&#228;&#228;rik, Jaan Leis, Jaan Aruv&#228;li, Kri&#353;j&#257;nis &#352;mits, Tanel K&#228;&#228;mbre, Vambola Kisand, Yevgen Karpichev, Kaido Tammeveski, Nade&#382;da Kongi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401208758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gulnara Yusibova, Kefeng Ping, Maike K&#228;&#228;rik, Jaan Leis, Jaan Aruv&#228;li, Kri&#353;j&#257;nis &#352;mits, Tanel K&#228;&#228;mbre, Vambola Kisand, Yevgen Karpichev, Kaido Tammeveski, Nade&#382;da Kongi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZIF-67 Nanostructures Anchored on 3D Graphene Sheets: A Non-noble Electrocatalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01181</link>
      <description>Duk&#8208;Hyun Choe, Komal Patil, Sun-Woo Kim, Seyeon Cho, Yujin Cho, Jincheol Kim, Dong Han Seo, Jongsung Park, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401212933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Duk&#8208;Hyun Choe, Komal Patil, Sun-Woo Kim, Seyeon Cho, Yujin Cho, Jincheol Kim, Dong Han Seo, Jongsung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural optimization: Ternary FeNiZn sulfide nanoparticles anchored on nanosheets to strengthen oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.414</link>
      <description>Jun Yu, Xiaofeng Wang, Yangping Zhang, Tianpeng Liu, Zhengying Wu, Shudi Yu, Yukou Du, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401217392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Yu, Xiaofeng Wang, Yangping Zhang, Tianpeng Liu, Zhengying Wu, Shudi Yu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ingenious Regulation and Activation of Sites in the 2h-Mos2basal Planes by Oxygen Incorporation for Enhanced Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution of CDS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4912824</link>
      <description>Guixin Zeng, Honghai Miao, Jiangbo Wu, Jianjian Yi, Xingwang Zhu, Haiping Qi, Zhao Mo, Jinyuan Liu, Baibiao Huang, Hongxiang Xu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401219512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guixin Zeng, Honghai Miao, Jiangbo Wu, Jianjian Yi, Xingwang Zhu, Haiping Qi, Zhao Mo, Jinyuan Liu, Baibiao Huang, Hongxiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4912824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot modulated construction of Ni-MOF/NiFe2O4 heterostructured catalyst for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02915-2</link>
      <description>Xingyu Guo, Zhiqiang Yang, Jing Zhao, Rui Liu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401229023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingyu Guo, Zhiqiang Yang, Jing Zhao, Rui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02915-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic oxygen evolution activity of nickel-doped manganese oxide nanorods in acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03221g</link>
      <description>Chao Wang, B. Xin, Yong Wang, Yvpei Li, Pengfei Xing, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401229672

                Active and stable electrocatalysts based on earth-abundant elements for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial for the hydrogen production using proton-exchange membrane water electrolyzers. Here, nickel-doped manganese oxide nanorods...</description>
      <author>Chao Wang, B. Xin, Yong Wang, Yvpei Li, Pengfei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03221g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-doped nickel&#8211;iron metal/metal oxide electrode with improved performance by promoting synergistic effects in the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102225</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Gong, Jiawei Ge, Junlei Qi, Honghe Ding, Leijie Zhang, Peiyu Ma, Zuohuan Chen, Nian Zhang, Jilong Xu, Lijuan Zhu, Jing L&#252;, Guiqiang Li, Junjie Ge, Yifan Ye, Materials Today Chemistry. 40(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401230203

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Gong, Jiawei Ge, Junlei Qi, Honghe Ding, Leijie Zhang, Peiyu Ma, Zuohuan Chen, Nian Zhang, Jilong Xu, Lijuan Zhu, Jing L&#252;, Guiqiang Li, Junjie Ge, Yifan Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of strain and dopants on breaking the activity-stability trade-off of RuO2 acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4721957/v1</link>
      <description>Hyoyoung Lee, Haibo Liu, Yixuan Wang, Hao Li, Min Gyu Kim, Mingbo Wu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401232471

                Abstract Ruthenium dioxide (RuO&#8322;) electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) suffer from mediocre activity and rather instability induced by high Ru-O covalency. Here, the tensile strained Sr0.1Ta0.1Ru0.8O2-x (TS-Sr0.1Ta0.1Ru0.8O2-x) nanocatalysts were synthesized via a molten salt-assisted quenching strategy. The TS spacially elongates the Ru-O bond and reduces covalency, thereby inhibiting the lattice oxygen participation and structural decomposition. The synergistic electronic modulations among Sr-Ru-Ta groups both optimize deprotonation on oxygen sites and intermediates absorption on Ru sites, lowering the OER energy barrier. Those result in a well-balanced activity-stability profile, confirmed by comprehensive experimental and theoretical analyses. Our TS-Sr0.1Ta0.1Ru0.8O2-x electrode demonstrated an overpotential of 166 mV at 10 mA cm-2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and an order of magnitude higher S-number, indicating exceptional stability compared to bare Sr0.1Ta0.1Ru0.8O2-x. It exhibited degradation rates of 0.02 mV/h at 10 mA cm-2 over 1000 h and 0.25 mV/h at 200 mA cm-2 over 200 h. This study elucidates the effectiveness of tensile strain and strategic doping in enhancing the activity and stability of Ru-based catalysts for acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Hyoyoung Lee, Haibo Liu, Yixuan Wang, Hao Li, Min Gyu Kim, Mingbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4721957/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal V doping optimizes the binding affinity of CuCoO2 with OH- contributes to efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175795</link>
      <description>Shiyu Ma, Jilin Bai, Wei Wang, Chao Jiang, Qian Shen, Lifeng Liu, Xiujian Zhao, Dehua Xiong, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401240700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiyu Ma, Jilin Bai, Wei Wang, Chao Jiang, Qian Shen, Lifeng Liu, Xiujian Zhao, Dehua Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Identification of O&#9472;O Bond Formation Through Three&#8208;Step Oxidation During Water Splitting by Operando Soft X&#8208;ray Absorption Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202401236</link>
      <description>Yucheng Huang, Yujie Wu, Ying&#8211;Rui Lu, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Hong&#8208;Ji Lin, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Chi&#8208;Liang Chen, Chao Jing, Jing Zhou, Linjuan Zhang, Yanyong Wang, Wu&#8208;Ching Chou, Shuangyin Wang, Zhiwei Hu, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401241330

                Abstract Anionic redox allows the direct formation of O&#9472;O bonds from lattice oxygens and provides higher catalytic in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) than does the conventional metal ion mechanism. While previous theories have predicted and experiments have suggested the possible O&#9472;O bond, it has not yet been directly observed in the OER process. In this study, operando soft X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (sXAS) at the O K&#8208;edge and the operando Raman spectra is performed on layered double CoFe hydroxides (LDHs) after intercalation with [Cr(C 2 O 4 ) 3 ] 3&#8722; , and revealed a three&#8208;step oxidation process, staring from Co 2+ to Co 3+ , further to Co 4+ (3d6L), and ultimately leading to the formation of O&#9472;O bonds and O 2 evolution above a threshold voltage (1.4 V). In contrast, a gradual oxidation of Fe is observed in CoFe LDHs. The OER activity exhibits a significant enhancement, with the overpotential decreasing from 300 to 248 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , following the intercalation of [Cr(C 2 O 4 ) 3 ] 3&#8722; into CoFe LDHs, underscoring a crucial role of anionic redox in facilitating water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yucheng Huang, Yujie Wu, Ying&#8211;Rui Lu, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Hong&#8208;Ji Lin, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Chi&#8208;Liang Chen, Chao Jing, Jing Zhou, Linjuan Zhang, Yanyong Wang, Wu&#8208;Ching Chou, Shuangyin Wang, Zhiwei Hu, Chung&#8208;Li Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202401236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Engineering of Mn Porphyrin/Au Electrodes for Identifying MnO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; as the Active Species under Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01420</link>
      <description>Yongman Kim, Yong-Chan Jeong, D. Na, Young Jae Kim, Jeong Young Park, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401243424

                Understanding the influence of surface structural features at a molecular level is beneficial in guiding an electrode's mechanistic proposals for electrocatalytic reactions. The relationship between structural stability and catalytic activity significantly impacts reaction performance, even though atomistic knowledge of active sites remains a topic of discussion. In this context, this work presents scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) results for the highly ordered arrangement of manganese porphyrin molecules on a Au(111) surface; STM allows us to monitor active sites at a molecular level to focus on long-standing issues with the electrocatalytic process, especially the exact nature of the real active sites at the interfaces. After water oxidation, manganese porphyrin rapidly decomposes into active catalytic species as bright protrusions. These newly formed active species drastically lost catalytic activity, up to 82%, through only acid treatment, one of the oxide removal methods, not by deionized water and acetone treatments. STM results of the obviated active species on the Au surface by an acidic solution support the forfeited catalytic activity. In addition, it shows a 67% decrement in catalytic activity by adsorption of phosphonic acid, one of the oxide's preferred adsorption materials, compared to the pristine one. Based on these observations, we confirm that the newly formed active species, as water oxidation catalysts, mostly consist of manganese oxides. Notable findings of our work provide molecular evidence for the active sites of Au and modified Au electrodes that spur the future development of water oxidation catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yongman Kim, Yong-Chan Jeong, D. Na, Young Jae Kim, Jeong Young Park</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01420</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Catalytic Activity and Selectivity of Manganese Dioxide-Modified Nickel&#8211;Iron-Based Hydroxide Electrodes for Initiating the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Natural Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080502</link>
      <description>Fangfang Liu, Miaomiao Fan, Haofeng Yan, Sheng Wang, Jimei Song, Hui Wang, Jianwei Ren, Catalysts. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401243930

                Transition metal oxides, particularly NiFe(OH)2, are recognized for their high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and structural stability. However, their performance in natural seawater electrolysis remains insufficiently studied. Manganese dioxide (MnO2), which is known for its multiple crystal phases and high OER selectivity, can be incorporated to enhance the catalytic properties. In this study, the OER catalytic performance of carbon cloth-supported manganese dioxide-modified nickel&#8211;iron bimetallic hydroxide (MnO2-NiFe-LDH/CC) electrodes was explored in both alkaline and natural seawater. Electrochemical tests demonstrated that the MnO2-NiFe-LDH/CC electrode achieved overpotentials of 284 mV and 363 mV at current densities of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 and 100 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2, respectively, with a Tafel slope of 68.6 mV&#183;dec&#8722;1 in alkaline seawater. Most importantly, the prepared MnO2-NiFe-LDH/CC electrode maintained stable OER performance over 120 h of testing. In natural seawater, the MnO2-NiFe-LDH/CC electrode outperformed the NiFe-LDH/CC electrode by exhibiting an oxygen evolution selectivity of 61.1%. This study highlights the potential of MnO2-modified nickel&#8211;iron-based materials for efficient and stable OER in seawater electrolysis, which offers a promising approach for sustainable hydrogen production in coastal desert regions.</description>
      <author>Fangfang Liu, Miaomiao Fan, Haofeng Yan, Sheng Wang, Jimei Song, Hui Wang, Jianwei Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering of active site coupling to facilitate interatomic charge transfer for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134986</link>
      <description>Qiaoling Xu, Lei Zhang, Hongyue Zhao, Xinyu Yin, Anqi Wang, Xiaowei Li, Guangzhi Hu, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. 701(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401248419

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiaoling Xu, Lei Zhang, Hongyue Zhao, Xinyu Yin, Anqi Wang, Xiaowei Li, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Performance of Double-Shell Structured Nixfe2-Xp/Nife2o4 for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4913996</link>
      <description>Junseong Kim, Kyeongseok Min, Hyunjin Lee, Hyeonseok Kwon, Sang Eun Shim, Sung&#8208;Hyeon Baeck, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401250208

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junseong Kim, Kyeongseok Min, Hyunjin Lee, Hyeonseok Kwon, Sang Eun Shim, Sung&#8208;Hyeon Baeck</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4913996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field Assisted Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Beyond Spin Effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31635/renewables.024.202400067</link>
      <description>Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Jing Fu, Renewables. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401250803

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Jing Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31635/renewables.024.202400067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Oxygen Evolution Reaction activity of CuCo based Hydroxides with V2CTx MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02700k</link>
      <description>Bastian Schmiedecke, Bing Wu, Thorsten Schultz, Aline Alencar Emerenciano, N. L. Sharma, Danielle Douglas-Henry, Apostolos Koutsioukis, Mehmet Turan Goerueryilmaz, Valeria Nicolosi, Tristan Petit, Norbert Koch, Zden&#283;k Sofer, Michelle P. Browne, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401252416

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key reaction in the production of green hydrogen by water electrolysis. In alkaline media, the current state of the art catalysts used for...</description>
      <author>Bastian Schmiedecke, Bing Wu, Thorsten Schultz, Aline Alencar Emerenciano, N. L. Sharma, Danielle Douglas-Henry, Apostolos Koutsioukis, Mehmet Turan Goerueryilmaz, Valeria Nicolosi, Tristan Petit, Norbert Koch, Zden&#283;k Sofer, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02700k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lithium Orbital Hybridization Chemistry to Stimulate Oxygen Redox with Reversible Phase Evolution in Sodium-Layered Oxide Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04814</link>
      <description>Haojie Dong, Haoliang Liu, Yu&#8208;Guo Guo, Yi&#8208;Hu Feng, Xu Zhu, Shaowen Xu, Fengxiang Sui, Lianzheng Yu, Mengting Liu, Jin&#8208;Zhi Guo, Ya&#8208;Xia Yin, Bing Xiao, Xing&#8208;Long Wu, Yu&#8208;Guo Guo, Pengfei Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401255814

                Searching for high energy-density electrode materials for sodium ion batteries has revealed Na-deficient intercalation compounds with lattice oxygen redox as promising high-capacity cathodes. However, anionic redox reactions commonly encountered poor electrochemical reversibility and unfavorable structural transformations during dynamic (de)sodiation processes. To address this issue, we employed lithium orbital hybridization chemistry to create Na-O-Li configuration in a prototype P2-layered Na</description>
      <author>Haojie Dong, Haoliang Liu, Yu&#8208;Guo Guo, Yi&#8208;Hu Feng, Xu Zhu, Shaowen Xu, Fengxiang Sui, Lianzheng Yu, Mengting Liu, Jin&#8208;Zhi Guo, Ya&#8208;Xia Yin, Bing Xiao, Xing&#8208;Long Wu, Yu&#8208;Guo Guo, Pengfei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Fe and Cr doped ZnO nanoparticles for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.437</link>
      <description>Naresh Bodicherla, T.V.M. Sreekanth, K. Prasad, Dongseob Kim, Jonghoon Kim, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401258823

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naresh Bodicherla, T.V.M. Sreekanth, K. Prasad, Dongseob Kim, Jonghoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co&#8211;FeOOH thin nanosheets derived from 2D ZIF-L for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.440</link>
      <description>Tingting Zheng, Xiao Yuan, Yulin Min, Tianchen Cui, Yiting Peng, Qiaoxia Li, Shaowei Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401265502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Zheng, Xiao Yuan, Yulin Min, Tianchen Cui, Yiting Peng, Qiaoxia Li, Shaowei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Surface Reconstruction of Te-Doped NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide for Robust Oxygen Evolution at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03672</link>
      <description>Yanyan Li, Haoran Guo, Jiayang Zhao, Kanglei Pang, Rui Song, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401266450

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanyan Li, Haoran Guo, Jiayang Zhao, Kanglei Pang, Rui Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Porous Carbon Supported Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles for Oxygen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction in a Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02599</link>
      <description>Bin Zhang, Xu Dong, Suer Guo, Meng Chen, Xingge He, Xin Chen, Mingxing Zhang, Jingui Duan, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401266868

                The oxygen reduction/evolution reaction (ORR/OER) represents a pivotal process in metal-air batteries; however, it is constrained by the limitations of slow kinetics. Nevertheless, the creation of long-lasting and bifunctional catalysts represents a significant challenge. This study presents a series of hierarchical porous carbon-supported cobalt pyrophosphate (Co</description>
      <author>Bin Zhang, Xu Dong, Suer Guo, Meng Chen, Xingge He, Xin Chen, Mingxing Zhang, Jingui Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic promotion of the oxygen evolution reaction by Co and Fe dual-doping of NiS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01329h</link>
      <description>Wenjuan Xu, Y.H. Wang, Jiangyan Dang, Xiaoying Zhang, Wenliang Li, Jingping Zhang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401275179

                Bimetallic doped Co,Fe&#8211;NiS2 nanosheet arrays are a promising non-precious metal electrocatalyst for the oxygen reduction reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Wenjuan Xu, Y.H. Wang, Jiangyan Dang, Xiaoying Zhang, Wenliang Li, Jingping Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01329h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Cation Intercalation Facilitating Chemical Oxidation of Water and Surface Stabilization During the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12813</link>
      <description>Huiyan Zeng, Zhongfei Liu, Jun Qi, Jiajun Chen, Yanquan Zeng, Chonghui Yang, Zhenzhong Li, Chao Wang, Long Gu, Yanyan Zhang, Shu Miao, Chunzhen Yang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401276935

                A comprehensive understanding of the dynamic processes at the catalyst/electrolyte interfaces is crucial for the development of advanced electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the chemical processes related to surface corrosion and catalyst degradation have not been well understood so far. In this study, we employ LiCoO 2 as a model catalyst and observe distinct OER activities and surface stabilities in different alkaline solutions. Operando X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD) and online mass spectroscopy (OMS) measurements prove the selective intercalation of alkali cations into the layered structure of LiCoO 2 during OER. It is proposed that the dynamic cation intercalations facilitate the chemical oxidation process between highly oxidative Co species and adsorbed water molecules, triggering the so&#8208;called electrochemical&#8208;chemical reaction mechanism (EC&#8208;mechanism). The results of this study emphasize the influence of cations on OER and provide insights into new strategies for achieving both high activity and stability in high&#8208;performance OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Huiyan Zeng, Zhongfei Liu, Jun Qi, Jiajun Chen, Yanquan Zeng, Chonghui Yang, Zhenzhong Li, Chao Wang, Long Gu, Yanyan Zhang, Shu Miao, Chunzhen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution with Nickel Oxide Nanoparticle-Modified Glassy Carbon Electrodes in Alkaline Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c04700</link>
      <description>Abdulrahman I. Alharthi, Omar A. Hazazi, Badreah A. Al Jahdaly, Mohammed A. Kassem, Mohamed I. Awad, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401282919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulrahman I. Alharthi, Omar A. Hazazi, Badreah A. Al Jahdaly, Mohammed A. Kassem, Mohamed I. Awad</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c04700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of cobalt phosphide/nitride/carbon nanotube composite: An efficient bifunctional catalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.394</link>
      <description>Zhaoyu Cai, Li Xu, Yifan Zhou, Longqing Gao, Xiaowei An, Xuli Ma, Yufei Ma, Jie Liu, Xiumin Li, Keyong Tang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401283306

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaoyu Cai, Li Xu, Yifan Zhou, Longqing Gao, Xiaowei An, Xuli Ma, Yufei Ma, Jie Liu, Xiumin Li, Keyong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Fast&#8208;Discharging Performance and Cyclability in Oxygen&#8208;Redox&#8208;Based P3&#8208;Type Na&#8208;Layered Cathode via Vacancies in TM layers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402412</link>
      <description>Sangyeop Lee, Heejun Kweon, Sangyeop Lee, Min&#8208;kyung Cho, Hobin Ahn, Jinho Ahn, Bonyoung Ku, Myungeun Choi, Hun&#8208;Gi Jung, Dong Ok Shin, Jongsoon Kim, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401288212

                Abstract Oxygen redox in layered oxide cathodes for Na&#8208;ion batteries is considered a promising approach for improving the energy density. However, oxygen&#8208;redox&#8208;based cathodes suffer from sluggish kinetics and undesirable structural change during charge/discharge, leading to poor electrochemical performances. Herein, introducing vacancies (&#9633;) in the transition metal layers enables the enhanced oxygen redox&#8208;based electrochemical performances in the P3&#8208;type Mn&#8208;based layered oxide cathode is demonstrated. The vacancies can play a role of the local distortion buffers, resulting in the enhanced oxygen redox kinetics and the suppressed structural deformation such as P3&#8208;O3(II) phase transition. The oxygen&#8208;redox&#8208;based P3&#8208;type Na 0.56 [Ni 0.1 Mn 0.81 &#9633; 0.09 ]O 2 exhibits the large discharge capacity of &#8776;140.95 mAh g &#8722;1 at 26 mA g &#8722;1 with a high average discharge voltage of &#8776;3.54 V (vs Na + /Na). Even at 650 mA g &#8722;1 , its discharge capacity and average operation voltages delivered &#8776;122.06 mAh g &#8722;1 and &#8776;3.22 V, respectively. Especially, the small gap of average discharge voltage indicates both improves power&#8208;capability and enhanced kinetics of oxygen redox in P3&#8208;type Na 0.56 [Ni 0.1 Mn 0.81 &#9633; 0.09 ]O 2 . Moreover, the vacancy buffer in the transition metal layers results in the stable cycle&#8208;performance of P3&#8208;type Na 0.56 [Ni 0.1 Mn 0.81 &#9633; 0.09 ]O 2 with the capacity retention of &#8776;80.80% for 100 cycles, due to the suppressed P3&#8208;O3(II) phase transition.</description>
      <author>Sangyeop Lee, Heejun Kweon, Sangyeop Lee, Min&#8208;kyung Cho, Hobin Ahn, Jinho Ahn, Bonyoung Ku, Myungeun Choi, Hun&#8208;Gi Jung, Dong Ok Shin, Jongsoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Synthesis of High&#8208;Entropy (Oxy)Hydroxides Via Electrochemical Reconfiguration As Catalysts For Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404379</link>
      <description>Weilin Shen, Yan Du, Huibin Liu, Chi&#8208;Wing Tsang, Xiao Chen, Changhai Liang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401290098

                Abstract Surface reconstruction plays a pivotal role in enhancing the activity of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), particularly in terms of the structural transformation from metal oxides to (oxy)hydroxides. Herein, a novel (oxy)hydroxide (FeCoNiCuMoOOH) with high entropy is developed by the electrochemical reconstitution of corresponding oxide (FeCoNiCuMoO x ). Significantly, the FeCoNiCuMoOOH exhibits much higher OER electrocatalytic activity and durability with an overpotential as low as 201 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and with a Tafel slope of 39.4 mV dec &#8722;1 . The FeCoNiCuMoOOH/NF presents high stability when testing under a constant current at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 within 1000 h. The surface reconstruction is a process of dissolution&#8208;reprecipitation of Cu and Mo species and co&#8208;hydroxylation of five metal species, which ultimately leads to the formation of FeCoNiCuMoOOH from FeCoNiCuMoOx. This study holds great significance in the realm of designing high&#8208;entropy (oxy)hydroxides catalysts with exceptional activity and stability for OER.</description>
      <author>Weilin Shen, Yan Du, Huibin Liu, Chi&#8208;Wing Tsang, Xiao Chen, Changhai Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Co&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;(SO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Clusters within Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408094</link>
      <description>Zuozhong Liang, Guojun Zhou, Huang Tan, Yonghong Mou, Jieling Zhang, Hongbo Guo, Shujiao Yang, Haitao Lei, Haoquan Zheng, Wei Zhang, Haiping Lin, Rui Cao, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401290707

                Abstract Multinuclear metal clusters are ideal candidates to catalyze small molecule activation reactions involving the transfer of multiple electrons. However, synthesizing active metal clusters is a big challenge. Herein, on constructing an unparalleled Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 cluster within porphyrin&#8208;based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) and the electrocatalytic features of such Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 clusters for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is reported. The reaction of Co II sulfate and metal complexes of tetrakis(4&#8208;pyridyl)porphyrin under solvothermal conditions afforded Co 4 &#8208;M&#8208;MOFs (M&#9552;Co, Cu, and Zn). Crystallographic studies revealed that these Co 4 &#8208;M&#8208;MOFs have the same framework structure, having the Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 clusters connected by metalloporphyrin units through Co&#9472;N pyridyl bonds. In the Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 cluster, the four Co II ions are chemically and symmetrically equivalent and are each coordinated with four sulfate O atoms to give a distorted cube&#8208;like structure. Electrocatalytic studies showed that these Co 4 &#8208;M&#8208;MOFs are all active for electrocatalytic OER and ORR. Importantly, by regulating the activity of the metalloporphyrin units, it is confirmed that the Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 cluster is active for oxygen electrocatalysis. With the use of Co porphyrins as connecting units, Co 4 &#8208;Co&#8208;MOF displays the highest electrocatalytic activity in this series of MOFs by showing a 10 mA cm &#8722;2 OER current density at 357 mV overpotential and an ORR half&#8208;wave potential at 0.83 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). Theoretical studies revealed the synergistic effect of two proximal Co atoms in the Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 cluster in OER by facilitating the formation of O&#9472;O bonds. This work is of fundamental significance to present the construction of Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 clusters in framework structures for oxygen electrocatalysis and to demonstrate the cooperation between two proximal Co atoms in such clusters during the O&#9472;O bond formation process.</description>
      <author>Zuozhong Liang, Guojun Zhou, Huang Tan, Yonghong Mou, Jieling Zhang, Hongbo Guo, Shujiao Yang, Haitao Lei, Haoquan Zheng, Wei Zhang, Haiping Lin, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ grown ternary metal hydroxides@3D oriented crumpled V2C MXene sheets for improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e35643</link>
      <description>Anum Iqbal, Hamzeh Sabouni, Nasser M. Hamdan, Heliyon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401296732

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anum Iqbal, Hamzeh Sabouni, Nasser M. Hamdan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e35643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Pt dissolution a concern from the counter electrode in electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144824</link>
      <description>Xiang Lyu, Jun Yang, Alexey Serov, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401305159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Lyu, Jun Yang, Alexey Serov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Oxygen&#8208;Defect Bismuth Catalyst toward Concerted Production of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with over 150% Cell Faradaic Efficiency in Continuously Flowing Paired&#8208;Electrosynthesis System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408341</link>
      <description>Qiqi Zhang, Changsheng Cao, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjie Xu, Xintao Wu, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401308478

                Abstract The electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) from O 2 or H 2 O via the two&#8208;electron (2e &#8722; ) oxygen reduction (2e &#8722; ORR) or water oxidation (2e &#8722; WOR) reaction provides a green and sustainable alternative to the traditional anthraquinone process. Herein, a paired&#8208;electrosynthesis tactic is reported for concerted H 2 O 2 production at a high rate by coupling the 2e &#8722; ORR and 2e &#8722; WOR, in which the bifunctional oxygen&#8208;vacancy&#8208;enriched Bi 2 O 3 nanorods (O v &#8208;Bi 2 O 3 &#8208;EO), obtained through electrochemically oxidative reconstruction of Bi&#8208;based metal&#8211;organic framework (Bi&#8208;MOF) nanorod precursor, are used as both efficient anodic and cathodic electrocatalysts, achieving concurrent H 2 O 2 production at both electrodes with high Faradaic efficiencies. Specifically, the coupled 2e &#8722; ORR//2e &#8722; WOR electrolysis system based on such distinctive oxygen&#8208;defect Bi catalyst displays excellent performance for the paired&#8208;electrosynthesis of H 2 O 2 , delivering a remarkable cell Faradaic efficiency of 154.8% and an ultrahigh H 2 O 2 production rate of 4.3 mmol h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 . Experiments combined with theoretical analysis reveal the crucial role of oxygen vacancies in optimizing the adsorption of intermediates associated with the selective two&#8208;electron reaction pathways, thereby improving the activity and selectivity of the 2e &#8722; reaction processes at both electrodes. This work establishes a new paradigm for developing advanced electrocatalysts and designing novel paired&#8208;electrolysis systems for scalable and sustainable H 2 O 2 electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Qiqi Zhang, Changsheng Cao, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjie Xu, Xintao Wu, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo-LDH sheets and Ag3PO4 nanoparticles decorated on graphitic carbon nitride for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175860</link>
      <description>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Younghwan Im, Misook Kang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401311945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Younghwan Im, Misook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/Crystalline Ni-Fe Based Electrodes with Rich Oxygen Vacancies Enable Highly Active Oxygen Evolution in Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916694</link>
      <description>Jingcheng Zhang, Xiulin Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401323219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingcheng Zhang, Xiulin Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress and challenges in engineering the atomic structure of oxygen electrocatalysts for zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154561</link>
      <description>Jinyeong Choi, Hyeokjun Jang, Jihan Park, Duho Han, Abhishek Lahiri, Pilgun Oh, Joohyuk Park, Minjoon Park, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326374

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinyeong Choi, Hyeokjun Jang, Jihan Park, Duho Han, Abhishek Lahiri, Pilgun Oh, Joohyuk Park, Minjoon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional &#960;&#8211;d-Conjugated Cobalt-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02588</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Zhe Chuan Feng, Yantao Wang, Junfeng Huang, Cailing Xu, Hua Li, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326994

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Zhe Chuan Feng, Yantao Wang, Junfeng Huang, Cailing Xu, Hua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon cloth supporting (CrMnFeCoCu)3O4 high entropy oxide as electrocatalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175874</link>
      <description>Xuanmeng He, Zeqin Zhang, Xianwei Jiang, Haibo Liu, Tengfei Xing, Xinzhen Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401327382

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuanmeng He, Zeqin Zhang, Xianwei Jiang, Haibo Liu, Tengfei Xing, Xinzhen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure regulation of Fe-doped Ni2P nanocrystals towards durable electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02845-z</link>
      <description>Ya Liu, Xing Cao, Jia Li, Meisheng Han, Gaowei Zhang, Yubin Zhao, Huanhui Chen, Liang Yu, Junrong Zeng, Zhenbo Chen, Ya Liu, Lijuan Song, Yejun Qiu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401329786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya Liu, Xing Cao, Jia Li, Meisheng Han, Gaowei Zhang, Yubin Zhao, Huanhui Chen, Liang Yu, Junrong Zeng, Zhenbo Chen, Ya Liu, Lijuan Song, Yejun Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02845-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the electrocatalytic efficiency of hydrothermally developed ZnMnO3 with rGO for oxygen evolution reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.372</link>
      <description>Mukhtiar Hussain, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, B.M. Alotaibi, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Imran Saleem, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401331983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukhtiar Hussain, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, B.M. Alotaibi, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Imran Saleem</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Ozone Pollutant Elimination in N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis to Produce Nitrate with Reduced Reaction Steps</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405918</link>
      <description>Yaodong Yu, Jiao Liu, Mingzi Sun, Jiani Han, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Bolong Huang, Jianping Lai, Sheng Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337627

                Abstract The synthesis of nitrate by the electrochemical N 2 oxidation reaction (NOR) is currently one of the most promising routes. However, the traditional generation of nitrate depends on the oxidation reaction between N 2 and H 2 O (or &#183;OH), which involves complex reaction steps and intermediates, showing strong competition from oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, an effective NOR method is proposed to directly oxidize N 2 by using O 3 as a reactive oxygen source to reduce the reaction step. Electrochemical tests demonstrate that the nitrate yield of Pd&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 /CNT electrocatalyst reaches the milligram level, which is the highest yield reported so far for electrocatalytic NOR. Quantitative characterization is employed to establish a comprehensive set of benchmarks to confirm the intrinsic nature of nitrogen activation and test the O 3 &#8208;mediated reaction mechanism. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that the heterostructure Pd&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 leads to a strong adsorption preference for N 2 and O 3 , which greatly reduces the activation energy barrier for N 2 . This accelerates the synthesis of nitrate based on the direct formation mechanism, which reduces energy barriers and the reaction steps, thus increasing the performance of electrocatalytic nitrate production. The techno&#8208;economic analysis underscores the promising feasibility and sustainable economic value of the presented method.</description>
      <author>Yaodong Yu, Jiao Liu, Mingzi Sun, Jiani Han, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Bolong Huang, Jianping Lai, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontispiz: Amorphous MnRuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202483361</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li, Angewandte Chemie. 136(33)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401340700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202483361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontispiece: Amorphous MnRuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202483361</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. 63(33)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401341005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202483361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review on chemisorbed oxyanions on electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110089</link>
      <description>Han-Ming Zhang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401344088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Han-Ming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong electronic coupling between Ni-based MOF and Ni2P enables high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction for various application scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154483</link>
      <description>Yirong Wang, Xuan Yu, Zhonghong Xia, Xuanrong Li, Ya Gao, Jing Zhang, Wuliang Feng, Xingli Zou, Yufeng Zhao, Chemical Engineering Journal. 497(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401344671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yirong Wang, Xuan Yu, Zhonghong Xia, Xuanrong Li, Ya Gao, Jing Zhang, Wuliang Feng, Xingli Zou, Yufeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating lattice oxygen in local amorphous S-modified NiFe-LDH ultrathin nanosheets toward superior alkaline/natural seawater oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.031</link>
      <description>Shiwei Song, Yanhui Wang, Pengfei Tian, Jianbing Zang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiwei Song, Yanhui Wang, Pengfei Tian, Jianbing Zang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermally Synthesized rGO/MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanohybrids as Superior Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02192</link>
      <description>Simiyon Denisdon, P. Senthil Kumar, B. Chitra, R. Gayathri, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352112

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simiyon Denisdon, P. Senthil Kumar, B. Chitra, R. Gayathri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Water-Lotus-like Iridium&#8211;Cobalt Carbonate Hydroxides on Plasma-Treated Carbon Fibers for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02591</link>
      <description>Yingpeng Xie, Jinfeng Qiu, Guangliang Chen, Yingchun Guo, Peisong Tang, Bin He, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352734

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingpeng Xie, Jinfeng Qiu, Guangliang Chen, Yingchun Guo, Peisong Tang, Bin He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional (2D) Oxysulfide nanosheets with sulfur-rich vacancy as an visible-light-driven difunctional photocatalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175898</link>
      <description>Hui Liang, Han Sun, Shuyu Jiang, Shu Cui, Fujiao Song, Lan Fan, Jia Gao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354256

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Liang, Han Sun, Shuyu Jiang, Shu Cui, Fujiao Song, Lan Fan, Jia Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni/Ni-MoS2/Ni-MoS2-Fe3O4 multilayer electrode for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175901</link>
      <description>Wei Jiang, Junjie Li, Yuanlong Chen, Fankai Zhu, Jing Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Jiang, Junjie Li, Yuanlong Chen, Fankai Zhu, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel&#8217;s Effect on Iron Oxide for Oxygen-Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04258</link>
      <description>Zahra Zand, Fatemeh Jafari, Maryam Gharedaghloo, Subhajit Nandy, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358416

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahra Zand, Fatemeh Jafari, Maryam Gharedaghloo, Subhajit Nandy, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring In Situ Kinetics of Oxygen Vacancy-Rich B/P-Incorporated Cobalt Oxide Nanowires for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00816</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Maulik Patel, Henry Charlton, Rinkoo Bhabal, R. Fernandes, Rupali Patel, N. Patel, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Maulik Patel, Henry Charlton, Rinkoo Bhabal, R. Fernandes, Rupali Patel, N. Patel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of oxygen via water oxidation using PANI@CuMn2O4 nanocomposite electrocatalyst for OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129803</link>
      <description>Hala M. Abo-Dief, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401360175

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hala M. Abo-Dief</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Catalytic Performances of Metal-doped Ta2O5 Catalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction with Computations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03554b</link>
      <description>Congcong Han, Tao Wang, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401361496

                The design of stable and active alternative catalysts to iridium oxide for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been a long pursuit in acidic water splitting. Tantalum pentoxide (Ta2O5)...</description>
      <author>Congcong Han, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03554b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j</link>
      <description>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401365414

                We firstly investigate the electrochemical dealloying effect and mechanism of a high-chromium alloy in alkaline NaNO3 solution under oxygen evolution potential. The electrochemical treatment can form dealloyed layers with Cr-enriched...</description>
      <author>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373364

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core&#8208;shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores&#8217; local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells&#8217; surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nimn2o4 Nanoflower Grown on Activated Carbon Derived from Tamarind Seed as Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reactions and Energy Storage by Three-Electrode Measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917324</link>
      <description>Anas Ramadan, Hamouda Adam Hamouda, N Al-Subaie, Yousif Shoaib Mohammed, Murtada Mohamed Edris, Nijuan Liu, Ruibin Guo, Anwar I. Alduma, Hebing Pei, Zunli Mo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373593

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anas Ramadan, Hamouda Adam Hamouda, N Al-Subaie, Yousif Shoaib Mohammed, Murtada Mohamed Edris, Nijuan Liu, Ruibin Guo, Anwar I. Alduma, Hebing Pei, Zunli Mo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376553

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core&#8208;shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores&#8217; local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells&#8217; surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k</link>
      <description>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376763

                Trade-off between activity and durability of acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is of key concern in the field of electrocatalysis. RuO2 delivers good activity but displays poor stability due...</description>
      <author>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381907

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381979

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382194

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382356

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382599

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics Of Oxygen Evolution in a Thermally Stratified Reservoir Under Climate Warming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4914468</link>
      <description>Bing Ma, Fei Dong, Wenqi Peng, Xiaobo Liu, Aiping Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401241824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Ma, Fei Dong, Wenqi Peng, Xiaobo Liu, Aiping Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4914468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via the Reconstruction of M(OH)x/Fe3O4 Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01574f</link>
      <description>Xiaoqu Wang, Limin Wang, Yongchun Liu, Raj Kumar, Jia Li, Qiulan Huang, Dujuan Huang, Youjun Fan, Du&#8208;Hong Chen, Wei Chen, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401375578

                For large-scale hydrogen production from electrocatalysis of water, the Ni- and/or Fe-based catalysts were commonly used but limited by the ultrahigh overpotential and poor stability at high current density (&gt;500...</description>
      <author>Xiaoqu Wang, Limin Wang, Yongchun Liu, Raj Kumar, Jia Li, Qiulan Huang, Dujuan Huang, Youjun Fan, Du&#8208;Hong Chen, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01574f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuO2/CoMo2Ox Catalyst with Low Ruthenium Loading for Long-Term Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12209-024-00405-1</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Xiongwei Zhong, Zhikun Liu, Kang-Lin Peng, Transactions of Tianjin University. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401207527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Xiongwei Zhong, Zhikun Liu, Kang-Lin Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12209-024-00405-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Znal2se4/Xse2 (X= Ti, Zr, Hf) Heterostructures for the Efficient Photocatalytic Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolutions with Z-Schemes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4918293</link>
      <description>Hao Sun, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, Xiaohu Li, Yuliang Liu, Wenkai Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Sun, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, Xiaohu Li, Yuliang Liu, Wenkai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4918293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice-compatible piezoelectric modification for suppressing lattice oxygen evolution of Ni-rich cathode materials at high cut-off voltage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103678</link>
      <description>Yizhen Huang, Dan Su, Lu Zheng, Guangchang Yang, Shuo Li, Juantao Jiang, Qichang Pan, Sijiang Hu, Yaohao Li, Qingyu Li, Xiaohui Zhang, Fenghua Zheng, Xing Ou, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401273531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yizhen Huang, Dan Su, Lu Zheng, Guangchang Yang, Shuo Li, Juantao Jiang, Qichang Pan, Sijiang Hu, Yaohao Li, Qingyu Li, Xiaohui Zhang, Fenghua Zheng, Xing Ou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidation Evolution and Activity Origin of N-Doped Carbon in the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12209-024-00406-0</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Wu, Chuanqi Cheng, Shanshan Lu, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi, Transactions of Tianjin University. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401213777

                Abstract N-doped carbon materials, with their applications as electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), have been extensively studied. However, a negletcted fact is that the operating potential of the ORR is higher than the theoretical oxidation potential of carbon, possibly leading to the oxidation of carbon materials. Consequently, the influence of the structural oxidation evolution on ORR performance and the real active sites are not clear. In this study, we discover a two-step oxidation process of N-doped carbon during the ORR. The first oxidation process is caused by the applied potential and bubbling oxygen during the ORR, leading to the oxidative dissolution of N and the formation of abundant oxygen-containing functional groups. This oxidation process also converts the reaction path from the four-electron (4e) ORR to the two-electron (2e) ORR. Subsequently, the enhanced 2e ORR generates oxidative H 2 O 2 , which initiates the second stage of oxidation to some newly formed oxygen-containing functional groups, such as quinones to dicarboxyls, further diversifying the oxygen-containing functional groups and making carboxyl groups as the dominant species. We also reveal the synergistic effect of multiple oxygen-containing functional groups by providing additional opportunities to access active sites with optimized adsorption of OOH*, thus leading to high efficiency and durability in electrocatalytic H 2 O 2 production.</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Wu, Chuanqi Cheng, Shanshan Lu, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12209-024-00406-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of fuel dosage in self-propagation combustion: Evolution of BiOCl to BiOCl/Bi24O31Cl10 heterojunction enriched with oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj02709d</link>
      <description>Lei Han, Wenjun Zhang, Meng Chen, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401225223

                BiOCl has garnered considerable attention recently. However, its relatively wide bandgap and poor separation efficiency of charge carriers limit its application in the visible light range. Introducing oxygen vacancies (OVs)...</description>
      <author>Lei Han, Wenjun Zhang, Meng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj02709d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructural evolution of the inner oxide layer of a Si-modified austenitic stainless steel exposed to oxygen-saturated lead-bismuth eutectic (LBE): toward the origin of LBE penetration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112350</link>
      <description>Ang Xie, Shenghu Chen, Lichang Yin, Neng He, Chunlin Chen, Lijian Rong, Corrosion Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376089

                Microstructural evolution of inner oxide layer of a Si-modified austenitic stainless steel exposed to oxygen-saturated static lead-bismuth eutectic (LBE) at 550 &#176;C up to 3000 h has been investigated. A dual-phase separated structure consisting of Fe-Cr spinel and (Fe, Cr)1-xNix phase is formed in inner oxide layer, attributed to partitioning of Ni and Cr associated with Fe-Cr spinel formation. SiO2 is preferentially formed preceding the Fe-Cr spinel at internal oxidation frontier, leading to dispersed SiO2 nanoparticles within Fe-Cr spinel. The mechanism of LBE penetration into inner oxide layer is further developed based on preferable dissolution process of (Fe, Cr)1-xNix phase.</description>
      <author>Ang Xie, Shenghu Chen, Lichang Yin, Neng He, Chunlin Chen, Lijian Rong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Tuning of BiVO4/MnFe-MOF Photoanodes Boosts Hole Extraction for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00836g</link>
      <description>Chenchen Feng, L.L. Liu, Houyu Fu, Faqi Zhan, Henan Jia, Xiang Cheng, Fucheng Yu, Qi Zhou, Zheng Bian, Beibei Zhang, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373580

                To achieve extremely effective photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting, it is imperative to suppress charge recombination at the interfaces between the oxygen evolution cocatalyst (OEC) and BiVO4. In view of this,...</description>
      <author>Chenchen Feng, L.L. Liu, Houyu Fu, Faqi Zhan, Henan Jia, Xiang Cheng, Fucheng Yu, Qi Zhou, Zheng Bian, Beibei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00836g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of nanoscale stabilized oxide catalysts for OER with OC22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01390e</link>
      <description>Richard Tran, Liqiang Huang, Yuan Zi, Lars C. Grabow, Benjamin M. Comer, Xuqing Wu, Stefan J. Raaijman, Nishant K. Sinha, Sajanikumari Sadasivan, Shibin Thundiyil, Kuldeep Mamtani, Ganesh Iyer, Lars C. Grabow, Ligang Lu, Jiefu Chen, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401379356

                The efficiency of H 2 production via water electrolysis is typically limited to the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As such, significant emphasis has been placed upon improving the rate of...</description>
      <author>Richard Tran, Liqiang Huang, Yuan Zi, Lars C. Grabow, Benjamin M. Comer, Xuqing Wu, Stefan J. Raaijman, Nishant K. Sinha, Sajanikumari Sadasivan, Shibin Thundiyil, Kuldeep Mamtani, Ganesh Iyer, Lars C. Grabow, Ligang Lu, Jiefu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01390e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Alkaline Water Splitting Efficiency: NiOOH-MnOOH Heterojunctions via In Situ Anodic Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00512k</link>
      <description>Yuru Zhou, Jing Hu, You&#8208;Nian Liu, Wen Fan, panpan tao, Jing Wang, Haitao Huang, Xun Cao, Haijin Li, Siwei Li, Materials Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401357428

                Designing noble metal-free electrocatalysts remains a challenge for oxygen evolution reactions (OER) in alkaline solutions. In this study, we present a facile electrodeposition approach coupled with an in-situ anodic oxidation...</description>
      <author>Yuru Zhou, Jing Hu, You&#8208;Nian Liu, Wen Fan, panpan tao, Jing Wang, Haitao Huang, Xun Cao, Haijin Li, Siwei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00512k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing Product Crossover and C-C Bond Cleavage in a Glycerol Membrane Electrode Assembly Reformer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee01824a</link>
      <description>Chencheng Dai, Qian Wu, Tianze Wu, Shouxin Zhang, Libo Sun, Xiaogang Wang, Adrian C. Fisher, Zhichuan J. Xu, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401234420

                Generating hydrogen through water electrolysis is impeded by high costs and substantial energy consumption mainly due to high equilibrium potential and sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Glycerol...</description>
      <author>Chencheng Dai, Qian Wu, Tianze Wu, Shouxin Zhang, Libo Sun, Xiaogang Wang, Adrian C. Fisher, Zhichuan J. Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee01824a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ultrafast reconfigurability and ultrahigh durability of NiFe phosphides electrocatalyst with a Fe-rich surface induced by in-situ acid corrosion for water oxidations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01378f</link>
      <description>Min Jiang, Jiaming Zhang, Hanxiao Liao, Huanhuan Zhai, Xuanzhi Liu, Pengfei Tan, Yi&#8208;Yang Sun, Yongjin Ma, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401173936

                NiFe based catalysts are expected to replace commercially available noble metal-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their reconfigurability into high performance NiFe oxyhydroxides from their phosphides. However,...</description>
      <author>Min Jiang, Jiaming Zhang, Hanxiao Liao, Huanhuan Zhai, Xuanzhi Liu, Pengfei Tan, Yi&#8208;Yang Sun, Yongjin Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01378f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Electrocatalytic Synergy in Graphene/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Nickel Networks for Water Splitting through a Combined Experimental and Theoretical Lens</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08869</link>
      <description>Dipankar Saha, Ayush Bhardwaj, Jiacheng Wang, Varun Pande, Robert Hengstebeck, Peng Bai, James J. Watkins, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401256725

                The development of low-cost and active electrocatalysts signifies an important effort toward accelerating economical water electrolysis and overcoming the sluggish hydrogen or oxygen evolution reaction (HER or OER) kinetics. Herein, we report a scalable and rapid synthesis of inexpensive Ni and MoS</description>
      <author>Dipankar Saha, Ayush Bhardwaj, Jiacheng Wang, Varun Pande, Robert Hengstebeck, Peng Bai, James J. Watkins</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite oxides as electrocatalysts for water electrolysis: From crystalline to amorphous</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.595</link>
      <description>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Hao Ming Chen, Zongping Shao, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401254700

                Abstract Crystalline perovskite oxides are regarded as promising electrocatalysts for water electrolysis, particularly for anodic oxygen evolution reactions, owing to their low cost and high intrinsic activity. Perovskite oxides with noncrystalline or amorphous characteristics also exhibit promising electrocatalytic performance toward electrochemical water splitting. In this review, a fundamental understanding of the characteristics and advantages of crystalline, noncrystalline, and amorphous perovskite oxides is presented. Subsequently, recent progress in the development of advanced electrocatalysts for water electrolysis by engineering and breaking the crystallinity of perovskite oxides is reviewed, with a special focus on the underlying structure&#8211;activity relationships. Finally, the remaining challenges and unsolved issues are presented, and an outlook is briefly proposed for the future exploration of next&#8208;generation water&#8208;splitting electrocatalysts based on perovskite oxides.</description>
      <author>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Hao Ming Chen, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma&#8208;assisted Surface Engineering to Stabilize Mn3+ in Electrodeposited Manganese Oxide Films for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401033</link>
      <description>Chu Qin, Shijun Tian, Jialong Wu, Junliang Mou, Libo Feng, Zhongqing Jiang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401182641

                Manganese oxide is a unique type of transition metal oxide that effectively functions as a catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, manganese oxide (MnOx) polymorphs are synthesized through electrochemical deposition and treated with an atmospheric pressure plasma jet (APPJ). The APPJ surface treatment can generate numerous oxygen vacancies and modify the crystallinity of the MnOx films, which can enhance the long&#8208;term stability of the MnOx films by stabilizing the Mn3+ content in the highly oxidizing environment. The increase in Mn3+ content and concentration of oxygen vacancies in the material synergistically increase the adsorption capacity of OH* and the electron&#8208;transferring capacity of MnOx films in the OER process, making them more stable and effective for OER. MnOx films treated with APPJ exhibit significantly higher activity, better stability, and lower Tafel slopes for OER than untreated MnOx films. The MnOx films treated with APPJ can remain stable for up to 92 hours during OER with a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2, with an onset overpotential of 310 mV. This strategy, which combines APPJ surface treatment techniques with electrodeposition methods, is innovative in the surface modification of manganese oxides with mixed valences to create OER catalysts with stable Mn3+ content.</description>
      <author>Chu Qin, Shijun Tian, Jialong Wu, Junliang Mou, Libo Feng, Zhongqing Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rod&#8208;Shaped Au@Ce Nano&#8208;Platforms for Enhancing Photodynamic Tumor Collaborative Therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400945</link>
      <description>Yuxiang Sun, Ziqi Cao, Xiaoli Zhang, Xingchen Zhu, Zhenyang Xu, Huaichun Zhou, Xiaoer Wei, Wenxian Du, Li Xu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401308457

                Abstract Tumor photodynamic therapy (PDT) relies on intratumoral free radicals, while the limited oxygen source and the depletion of tissue oxygen may exacerbate the hypoxia. As the treatment progresses, there will eventually be a problem of insufficient free radicals. Here, it is found that Au@CeO 2 nano&#8208;rods (Au@Ce NRs), assembled by gold nano&#8208;rods (Au NRs) and ceria nanoparticles (CeO 2 NPs), can efficaciously absorb near&#8208;infrared light (NIR) to promote the release of oxygen and free radicals. Au@Ce NRs exhibit a higher proportion of Ce 3+ (Ce 2 O 3 ) after oxygen release, while Ce 3+ is subsequently oxidized to Ce 4+ (CeO 2 ) by trace H 2 O 2 . Interestingly, Au@Ce NRs re&#8208;oxidized by trace H 2 O 2 can re&#8208;releasing oxygen and free radicals again upon NIR treatment, achieving oxygenation/oxygen evolution, similar to charging/discharging. This loop maximizes the conversion of limited oxygen source into highly cytotoxic free radicals. As a result, when B16&#8208;F10 cells are treated by NIR/Au@Ce NRs, more tumor cells undergo apoptosis, consistent with the higher level of free radicals. Importantly, NIR/Au@Ce NRs successfully suppresses tumor growth and promotes the generation of epidermal collagen fibers in the transplanted tumor model. Therefore, the rod&#8208;shaped Au@Ce NRs provide an ideal platform for maximizing the utilization of intratumoral oxygen sources and improving the treatment of melanoma.</description>
      <author>Yuxiang Sun, Ziqi Cao, Xiaoli Zhang, Xingchen Zhu, Zhenyang Xu, Huaichun Zhou, Xiaoer Wei, Wenxian Du, Li Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Light and Electrode Polarization on BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanodes for Glycerol Oxidation.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6bc3</link>
      <description>Mart&#237; Molera, M. Sarret, Cristian F&#225;brega, Teresa Andreu, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351802

                Abstract In recent years, there has been a growing interest in the photoelectrochemical oxidation of glycerol to produce high-value products. Most studies have focused solely on the photocatalytic properties of the electrodes, overlooking their electrocatalytic properties and the different products obtained under dark conditions. Our work aims to address this gap by comparing the electrocatalytic activity under dark and light conditions to determine whether light influences the reactivity of the electrodes or if it just reduces the overpotential of the reaction. To achieve this, we employed two model semiconductors, TiO2 and BiVO4. We have analyzed their polarization curves under both dark and light conditions and evaluated the competence of glycerol oxidation reaction with the oxygen evolution reaction. Furthermore, we conducted long-term (photo)electrolysis revealing the beneficial role of light on the electrolytic process, as it enables the obtention of C3 products on illuminated TiO2 photoanodes at low electrode polarization, comparable to the performance of BiVO4.</description>
      <author>Mart&#237; Molera, M. Sarret, Cristian F&#225;brega, Teresa Andreu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6bc3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe2O4 Nanoparticles on Bio-Based Polymer Derived Nitrogen Doped Carbon as Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Li-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad69c9</link>
      <description>Pirapath Arkasalerks, Amarshi Patra, Kottisa Sumala Patnaik, Koichi Higashimine, Noriyoshi Matsumi, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401160320

                Abstract Lithium-air batteries (LABs) are gaining attention as a promising energy storage solution. Their theoretical energy density of 3,505 Whkg-1 exceeds that of conventional lithium-ion batteries (500&#8211;800 Whkg-1). The commercial viability and widespread adoption of lithium-air batteries face challenges such as poor cycling stability, limited lifespan, and unresolved side reactions. In this study, we synthesized spinel CoFe2O4-decorated on bio-based poly(2,5-benzimidazole) derived N-doped carbon for electrocatalysts. Notably, strong metal-substrate interaction (SMSI) was observed through various characterizations. The bifunctional electrocatalytic activity and stability toward oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction were significantly enhanced by the SMSI, The LAB demonstrated a high discharge capacity of 18,356 mAhg-1 at a current density of 200 mAg-1, maintaining a remarkable discharge capacity of 1,000 mAhg-1 even at a high current density of 400 mAg-1 for 200 cycles. CoFe2O4-decorated on bio-derived ABPBI holds promise as a practical air-breathing electrode for high-capacity rechargeable LABs.</description>
      <author>Pirapath Arkasalerks, Amarshi Patra, Kottisa Sumala Patnaik, Koichi Higashimine, Noriyoshi Matsumi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad69c9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Iron Active Sites of FeOOH via Al&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; and Heteroatom Doping&#8208;Induced Asymmetric Oxygen Vacancy Electronic Structure for Efficient Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404552</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Lv, Ying&#8208;Fei Chang, Xinyu Chen, Jinyu Guo, Jing Sun, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Hong&#8208;Ying Zang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358383

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction is the essential anodic reaction for water splitting. Designing tunable electronic structures to overcome its slow kinetics is an effective strategy. Herein, the molecular ammonium iron sulfate dodecahydrate is employed as the precursor to synthesize the C, N, S triatomic co&#8208;doped Fe(Al)OOH on Ni foam (C,N,S&#8208;Fe(Al)OOH&#8208;NF) with asymmetric electronic structure. Both in situ oxygen vacancies and their special electronic configuration enable the electron transfer between the d&#8208;p orbitals and get the increase of OER activity. Density functional theory calculation further indicates the effect of electronic structure on catalytic activity and stability at the oxygen vacancies. In alkaline solution, the catalyst C,N,S&#8208;Fe(Al)OOH&#8208;NF shows good catalytic activity and stability for water splitting. For OER, the overpotential of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 is 264 mV, the tafel slope is 46.4 mV dec &#8722;1 , the HER overpotential of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 is 188 mV, the tafel slope is 59.3 mV dec &#8722;1 . The stability of the catalyst can maintain &#8776;100 h. This work has extraordinary implications for understanding the mechanistic relationship between electronic structure and catalytic activity for designing friendly metal (oxy)hydroxide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Lv, Ying&#8208;Fei Chang, Xinyu Chen, Jinyu Guo, Jing Sun, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Hong&#8208;Ying Zang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Power of &lt;scp&gt;PM6&lt;/scp&gt;:&lt;scp&gt;Y6&lt;/scp&gt; Semitransparent Photoanodes by Computational Balancement of Photon Absorption in Photoanode/Photovoltaic Organic Tandems: &amp;gt;7 &lt;scp&gt;mA&lt;/scp&gt; cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;2&lt;/sup&gt; Solar Synthetic Fuels Production at Bias&#8208;Free Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12809</link>
      <description>Francisco Bernal&#8208;Texca, Emmanouela Andrioti, Jordi Martorell, Carles Ros, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401230065

                This study first demonstrates the potential of organic photoabsorbing blends in overcoming a critical limitation of metal oxide photoanodes in tandem modules: insufficient photogenerated current. Various organic blends, including PTB7&#8208;Th:FOIC, PTB7&#8208;Th:O6T&#8208;4F, PM6:Y6, and PM6:FM, were systematically tested. When coupled with electron transport layer (ETL) contacts, these blends exhibit exceptional charge separation and extraction, with PM6:Y6 achieving saturation photocurrents up to 16.8 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V RHE (oxygen evolution thermodynamic potential). For the first time, a tandem structure utilizing organic photoanodes has been computationally designed and fabricated and the implementation of a double PM6:Y6 photoanode/photovoltaic structure resulted in photogenerated currents exceeding 7 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0 V RHE (hydrogen evolution thermodynamic potential) and anodic current onset potentials as low as &#8722;0.5 V RHE . The herein&#8208;presented organic&#8208;based approach paves the way for further exploration of different blend combinations to target specific oxidative reactions by selecting precise donor/acceptor candidates among the multiple existing ones.</description>
      <author>Francisco Bernal&#8208;Texca, Emmanouela Andrioti, Jordi Martorell, Carles Ros</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineering of Nickel-Based Compounds for Energy-Saving H2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153801</link>
      <description>Yi Zeng, Xueqiang Qi, Shun Lu, Mohamed N. Khalil, Xiuxiu Dong, Haoqi Wang, Energies. 17(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401252488

                The urea oxidation reaction (UOR), requiring less energy to produce hydrogen, is considered as a potential alternative to the traditional oxygen evolution reaction. Consequently, developing highly efficient UOR catalysts to facilitate H2 production has garnered widespread attention. A promising approach to enhancing the effectiveness of these electrocatalysts is defect engineering. By introducing structural defects, defect engineering can expose more active sites and optimize their electronic structure, thereby improving their activity. This work offers a comprehensive overview of recent progress in defect engineering of nickel-based electrocatalysts for the UOR. It summarizes various strategies for generating defects, including the creation of vacancies, doping, the incorporation of single atoms, amorphization, and achieving high refractivity. Furthermore, we discuss the advanced characterization techniques commonly used to identify the presence of defects in these electrocatalysts, as well as to determine their detailed structures. Finally, we outline the prospects and challenges associated with the systematic design and fabrication of novel UOR electrocatalysts with tunable defects, aiming to further enhance their efficiency and stability.</description>
      <author>Yi Zeng, Xueqiang Qi, Shun Lu, Mohamed N. Khalil, Xiuxiu Dong, Haoqi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of Amides through Cu- and Co-Incorporated Nickel Hydroxide-Catalyzed Oxidation of Primary Amines Coupled with Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02797</link>
      <description>Manman Song, Minghui Feng, Zheng Chen, Shanshan Lv, Yan Zhou, Zheng Chen, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401212320

                The electrocatalytic oxidation of organic molecules coupled with hydrogen evolution reaction can reduce overpotential and can be connected in series with nonelectrochemical processes to achieve the preparation of more high-value compounds. Herein, Cu- and Co-incorporated nickel hydroxide (CuCo&#8211;Ni(OH)2) was synthesized and applied to the anodic benzylamine oxidation reaction, which is 280 mV lower than the corresponding oxygen evolution reaction to reach the current density of 50 mA cm&#8211;2. When the electrocatalytic oxidation of benzylamine and hydrogen evolution reaction are coupled to form an electrolytic cell, the potential to reach 10 mA cm&#8211;2 is reduced by 197 mV compared to the overall water splitting. The benzylamine is converted to benzamide with 99.3% conversion and 90.2% faraday efficiency under 1.45 V constant voltage electrolysis, and the catalytic performance remains at a high level after 4 cycles. The characterization and density functional theory calculations show that Cu and Co share the transfer charge from Ni, making it easy for CuCo&#8211;Ni(OH)2 to deprotonate Ni&#8211;O* sites. The formed Ni&#8211;O* sites exhibit lower energy barriers in the proton transfer of benzylamine to benzonitrile and hydration intermediates, resulting in a better catalytic performance of CuCo&#8211;Ni(OH)2 than Ni(OH)2 in the electrocatalytic oxidation of benzylamine to benzamide.</description>
      <author>Manman Song, Minghui Feng, Zheng Chen, Shanshan Lv, Yan Zhou, Zheng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quantitative description of light-limited cyanobacterial growth using flux balance analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012280</link>
      <description>Rune H&#246;per, Daria Komkova, Tom&#225;&#353; Zav&#345;el, Ralf Steuer, PLoS Computational Biology. 20(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401328669

                The metabolism of phototrophic cyanobacteria is an integral part of global biogeochemical cycles, and the capability of cyanobacteria to assimilate atmospheric CO 2 into organic carbon has manifold potential applications for a sustainable biotechnology. To elucidate the properties of cyanobacterial metabolism and growth, computational reconstructions of genome-scale metabolic networks play an increasingly important role. Here, we present an updated reconstruction of the metabolic network of the cyanobacterium Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803 and its quantitative evaluation using flux balance analysis (FBA). To overcome limitations of conventional FBA, and to allow for the integration of experimental analyses, we develop a novel approach to describe light absorption and light utilization within the framework of FBA. Our approach incorporates photoinhibition and a variable quantum yield into the constraint-based description of light-limited phototrophic growth. We show that the resulting model is capable of predicting quantitative properties of cyanobacterial growth, including photosynthetic oxygen evolution and the ATP/NADPH ratio required for growth and cellular maintenance. Our approach retains the computational and conceptual simplicity of FBA and is readily applicable to other phototrophic microorganisms.</description>
      <author>Rune H&#246;per, Daria Komkova, Tom&#225;&#353; Zav&#345;el, Ralf Steuer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noble Metal&#8208;Free High Entropy Perovskite Oxide with High Cationic Dispersion Enhanced Oxygen Redox Reactivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401836</link>
      <description>Arindam Chatterjee, Dipsikha Ganguly, S. Ramaprabhu, Subramshu S. Bhattacharya, ChemistrySelect. 9(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401363653

                Abstract High entropy perovskite oxide (HEPO) materials have received significant interest as efficient electrocatalysts owing to their chemical and structural stability, effective interaction of multiple metal active sites with the reaction intermediate species resulting in enhanced catalytic activity. The effect of high&#8208;entropy strategy could achieve the regulation of the structural durability by tailoring the composition. Herein, we design a novel transition metal and rare&#8208;earth metal based high entropy perovskite oxide (Co 0.11 Mn 0.11 Ni 0.11 Fe 0.14 La 0.13 Nd 0.13 Gd 0.13 Pr 0.13 )O 3, showing superior catalytic activity in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and also promising electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction (OER). High degree of cationic dispersion in the lattice and multiple electrocatalytic active sites enhance the oxygen ion migration at the surface and facilitate electron transfer, manifesting good ORR performance. Notably, the as&#8208;prepared high entropy material exhibits onset and half&#8208;wave potential of 1.02 V and 0.89 V versus RHE, respectively, exceeding the performance of the benchmarked Pt/C catalyst in the ORR process with reasonable redox kinetics. Moreover, the material also presents faster kinetics with reasonably low overpotential and excellent electrochemical stability in the OER process as well. This study shows the viability of designing non&#8208;precious high entropy materials as highly efficient oxide electrocatalyst by utilizing its broad compositional space.</description>
      <author>Arindam Chatterjee, Dipsikha Ganguly, S. Ramaprabhu, Subramshu S. Bhattacharya</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Fe&#8208;Doped Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;NiS@Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanorod Array with Regulated Heterostructural Interface and Band Structure for Expediting Alkaline Electrocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409849</link>
      <description>Ruidong Shi, Yuanting Li, Xiaoxin Xu, Xue Wang, Gongbing Zhou, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401260932

                Abstract Aiming to efficiently expedite alkaline overall water splitting (OWS) by addressing challenges such as sluggish kinetics and limited stability, a hollow Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 &#8208;NiS@Ni(OH) 2 nanorod array with surface nanosheets is devised, featuring a high&#8208;index Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 (101)&#8208;NiS(211) heterostructural interface and an upshifted d &#8208;band center. This nanoarchitecture intensifies the adsorption and interaction of H 2 O and OH &#8722; reactants on the electrocatalyst surface, suitably bonds the * H intermediate in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and accelerates electron movement of * H, minimizes the energy requirement of the rate&#8208;limiting phase ( * OH &#8594; * O) in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by facilitating O&#9472;H cleavage of * OH and optimally adsorbs * O, amplifies the exposure of surface&#8208;active centers, and ultimately reduces the apparent activation energy. Consequently, the overpotentials are as low as 66.4 mV (HER) and 254.9 mV (OER) at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , alongside high turnover frequencies of 142 s &#8722;1 (H 2 ) and 279 s &#8722;1 (O 2 ) at 100 and 300 mV, respectively, markedly outperforming direct&#8208;electrodeposited analogues. When functioning as a bifunctional electrode in OWS, this material merely requires 1.57 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and sustains an operation for 168 h, approaching Pt/C||RuO 2 benchmark.</description>
      <author>Ruidong Shi, Yuanting Li, Xiaoxin Xu, Xue Wang, Gongbing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Produksi Hidrogen Dari Air Laut Menggunakan Metode Elektrolisis Berbantuan Elektrokatalis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14710/jebt.2024.23562</link>
      <description>Febiana Natasha, Ezra Solafide Hutajulu, Hilfi Pardi, Jurnal Energi Baru dan Terbarukan. 5(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401279225

                Hidrogen berpotensi sebagai sumber energi bersih yang ideal untuk menurunkan emisi karbondioksida di masa depan. Hal ini dikarenakan hidrogen memiliki kepadatan energi yang tinggi sekitar 142.351 MJ/kg dan bebas dari gas beracun. Oleh karena itu, diperkirakan permintaan hidrogen akan meningkat sekitar 18% pada tahun 2050 untuk memenuhi kebutuhan energi pengganti bahan bakar fosil. Tujuan penelitian, yakni untuk merangkum reaksi-reaksi redoks pada elektroda dalam metode elektrolisis udara laut, menampilkan berbagai elektrokatalis dalam memproduksi hidrogen dari udara laut, dan elektrolisis sebagai media pendukung berlangsungnya proses produksi hidrogen air laut. Hasil yang ditampilkan adalah adanya 3 reaksi redoks dalam elektrolisis udara laut yang terdiri atas Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), Chlorine Evolution Reaction (CER), dan Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER). Adapun elektrokatalis yang efisien dalam mendukung reaksi HER sebanyak 25 buah. Selain itu, terdapat 4 elektrolit yang mendukung kinerja dari reaksi elektrolisis udara laut dalam memproduksi hidrogen adalah H 2 SO 4 , NaCl, KOH dan NaOH. Oleh karena itu, pengembangan hidrogen dari air laut secara lebih lanjut patut dikembangkan guna mewujudkan Net Zero Emission.</description>
      <author>Febiana Natasha, Ezra Solafide Hutajulu, Hilfi Pardi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14710/jebt.2024.23562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing the Operation Current Density of Alkaline Water Oxidation above 1 A cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; via Electrocatalyst Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402034</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Yan Zhang, Kunyan Wang, Lei Tan, Faiza Meharban, Sheng Wang, Xiaopeng Li, Chao Lin, Wei Luo, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358181

                Abstract Rapid cost reduction of green hydrogen is essential for the large&#8208;scale deployment of hydrogen&#8208;based energy system. A major component in achieving this is the development of advanced water electrolyzers. Sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the bottleneck for water electrolysis, and tremendous efforts have been devoted to develop electrocatalysts that accelerate the OER kinetics. Recent advances have highlighted the potential of precious metal&#8208;free OER electrocatalyst capable of stable operation at current densities above 1 A cm 2 . This brings an opportunity of constructing new&#8208;generation electrolyzer with lower cost and higher productivity. However, achieving such high operating current densities presents new challenges. This review summarize the recent progress of high&#8208;performance OER catalysts, and identifies key factors that can be leveraged to enhance catalyst activity. These factors include interface/surface engineering, amorphous and crystal phase coupling, hierarchical structure design, structural reconstruction and phase conversion, high entropy catalyst, and defect engineering. Additionally, the pressing challenges that have been largely ignored in previous research is addressed, such as sustaining long&#8208;term stability under crucial conditions, disadvantages of immobilized powder electrocatalysts, electrode scale design, the necessity of designing innovative electrolyzer cell designs and advance characterization techniques.</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Yan Zhang, Kunyan Wang, Lei Tan, Faiza Meharban, Sheng Wang, Xiaopeng Li, Chao Lin, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Intermediates Adsorption by Manipulating the Second Coordination Shell of Ir Single Atoms for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410520</link>
      <description>Jie Wei, Hua Tang, Haibo Liu, Guiliang Liu, Li Sheng, Minghui Fan, Yiling Ma, Zhirong Zhang, Jie Zeng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401197997

                The precise regulation of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) with the desired local chemical environment is vital to elucidate the relationship between the SACs structure and the catalytic performance. The debate on the effect of the local coordination environment is quite complicated even for the SACs with the same composition and chemical nature, calling for increased attention on the regulation of second coordination shell. For oxide&#8208;supported SACs, it remains a significant challenge to precisely manipulate the second coordination shell of single atoms supported on oxides due to the structural robustness of oxides. Here, Ir single atoms are anchored on NiO supports via different bonding strategies, resulting in the diverse Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Ni coordination numbers for Ir sites. Specifically, Ir1/NiO, Ir1&#8208;NiO, and Ir1@NiO SACs with increasing Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Ni coordination numbers of 3, 4, and 5 were synthesized, respectively. We found that the activity of the three samples towards oxygen evolution reaction (OER) exhibited a volcano&#8208;shaped relationship with the Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Ni coordination number, with Ir1&#8208;NiO showing the lowest overpotential of 225 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2. Mechanism investigations indicate that the moderate coordination number of Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Ni in Ir1&#8208;NiO creates the higher occupied Ir dz2 orbital, weakening the adsorption strength for *OOH intermediates and thereby enhancing the OER activity.</description>
      <author>Jie Wei, Hua Tang, Haibo Liu, Guiliang Liu, Li Sheng, Minghui Fan, Yiling Ma, Zhirong Zhang, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410520</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Intermediates Adsorption by Manipulating the Second Coordination Shell of Ir Single Atoms for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410520</link>
      <description>Jie Wei, Hua Tang, Yan Liu, Guiliang Liu, Sheng Li, Minghui Fan, Yiling Ma, Zhirong Zhang, Jie Zeng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401198329

                The precise regulation of single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) with the desired local chemical environment is vital to elucidate the relationship between the SACs structure and the catalytic performance. The debate on the effect of the local coordination environment is quite complicated even for the SACs with the same composition and chemical nature, calling for increased attention on the regulation of second coordination shell. For oxide&#8208;supported SACs, it remains a significant challenge to precisely manipulate the second coordination shell of single atoms supported on oxides due to the structural robustness of oxides. Here, Ir single atoms are anchored on NiO supports via different bonding strategies, resulting in the diverse Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Ni coordination numbers for Ir sites. Specifically, Ir1/NiO, Ir1&#8208;NiO, and Ir1@NiO SACs with increasing Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Ni coordination numbers of 3, 4, and 5 were synthesized, respectively. We found that the activity of the three samples towards oxygen evolution reaction (OER) exhibited a volcano&#8208;shaped relationship with the Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Ni coordination number, with Ir1&#8208;NiO showing the lowest overpotential of 225 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2. Mechanism investigations indicate that the moderate coordination number of Ir&#8208;O&#8208;Ni in Ir1&#8208;NiO creates the higher occupied Ir dz2 orbital, weakening the adsorption strength for *OOH intermediates and thereby enhancing the OER activity.</description>
      <author>Jie Wei, Hua Tang, Yan Liu, Guiliang Liu, Sheng Li, Minghui Fan, Yiling Ma, Zhirong Zhang, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410520</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inter-atomic Electronic Interactions Enables by Rh Single Atoms/CuCo2S4@MoS2 Core-Shell Heterostructure for High-efficiency Solar-assisted Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02881c</link>
      <description>Xinfeng Zhu, Kaixuan Dong, Dinh Chuong Nguyen, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401242535

                In this work, we developed an electrocatalyst based on the Rh single atoms confined CuCo2S4@MoS2 core&#8211;shell heterostructure, namely Rh SAs/CuCo2S4@MoS2, for the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and anodic oxygen...</description>
      <author>Xinfeng Zhu, Kaixuan Dong, Dinh Chuong Nguyen, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02881c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A coefficient identification problem for a system of advection-diffusion-reaction equations in water quality modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/jiip-2024-0030</link>
      <description>&#208;inh Nho H&#224;o, Nguy&#7877;n Trung Th&#224;nh, Nguyen Van Duc, Nguyen Van Thang, Journal of Inverse and Ill-Posed Problems. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401289540

                Abstract The inverse problem of reconstructing two space-varying coefficients in a system of one-dimensional (1-d) time-dependent advection-diffusion-reaction (ADR) equations is considered. The ADR system can be used as a water quality model which describes the evolution of the biochemical oxygen demand (BOD) and dissolved oxygen (DO) in a river or stream. The coefficients to be reconstructed represents the effect of the deoxygenation and superficial reaeration processes on the DO and BOD concentration in water. H&#246;lder stability estimates for the coefficients of interest are established using the Carleman estimate technique.</description>
      <author>&#208;inh Nho H&#224;o, Nguy&#7877;n Trung Th&#224;nh, Nguyen Van Duc, Nguyen Van Thang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/jiip-2024-0030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of the Fire Point on the Thermal Dynamic Disaster in the Goaf</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7080270</link>
      <description>Xiaokun Chen, Chao Song, Zhipeng Zhang, Fire. 7(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326784

                A thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf is one of the most serious coal mine disasters formed by coal spontaneous combustion and gas interweaving. However, the influence of the high-temperature hidden fire source formed in the goaf on the evolution law of thermal dynamic disasters is not clear, and effective prevention and control measures cannot be taken. Therefore, this paper uses the experimental platform of thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf to study the influence of different fire point positions on the development of thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf through a similar simulation experiment of thermal dynamic disaster evolution in the goaf and analyzes the corresponding relationship between temperature and CO concentration in the upper corner. The results show that under different locations of heat source, the high-temperature heat source of coal spontaneous combustion migrates to the air leakage side with sufficient oxygen supply, and an oxygen-poor circle is formed near the ignition point. Under the action of air leakage flow, CH4 accumulates in the deep part of the goaf on the return air side. Due to the increase in coal, part of CH4 is produced, which leads to the increase in concentration of CH4 at the ignition point. Under the action of different heat sources, the changing trend of concentration of CO and temperature in the return air corner is the same, but the temperature change in the return air corner shows a lag compared with the change in the concentration of CO, so concentration monitoring of CO can reflect the evolution process of the fire field in the goaf more quickly than temperature monitoring.</description>
      <author>Xiaokun Chen, Chao Song, Zhipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7080270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced vanadium redox reaction catalytic properties enabled by tunning oxygen vacancy in rutile tio&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; coated graphite felt electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2814/1/012022</link>
      <description>Yancai Liu, Xiaobo Duan, Haonan Wang, Jiaao Yu, Jian Zhu, Birou Lu, Ming Zhu, Bin Zheng, Lei Zhang, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2814(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333780

                Abstract Catalyzing vanadium redox reactions in VRFBs with transition metal oxides is an effective and affordable approach. In this study, the surface electron distribution of TiO 2 was regulated by introducing oxygen vacancies into its lattice, enabling the electrode to exhibit outstanding catalytic efficacy in VO 2 + /VO 2+ and V 3+ /V 2+ redox transformations and suppress the detrimental side reaction (HER and OER) simultaneously. Benefiting from the enhanced catalytic activity and selectivity, the 1000-TiO 2 -GF electrode sustained a stable operation for 100 cycles at 120 mA cm &#8722;2 with no discernible efficiency degradation. The DFT results indicate that oxygen vacancy in TiO 2 provides more extra electrons to its neighboring titanium, further strengthening the interaction between the electron-rich titanium and oxygen in VO 2 + /VO 2+ , thus enhancing its catalytic performance. The enhanced catalytic activity for V 3+ /V 2+ on oxygen vacancy-rich TiO 2 coating can be attributed to the effective suppression of hydrogen evolution reaction, which can occupy active sites exclusively and produce detrimental H 2 bubbles. This insight provides valuable guidance for the innovative design of catalysts in vanadium redox flow batteries.</description>
      <author>Yancai Liu, Xiaobo Duan, Haonan Wang, Jiaao Yu, Jian Zhu, Birou Lu, Ming Zhu, Bin Zheng, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2814/1/012022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Pyrolysis and Incineration of Lewisite by Thermodynamic Equilibrium Calculation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202400055</link>
      <description>X.K. Liu, Yuanpeng Zhang, Lin Yang, Weiwei Song, Haitao Wang, ChemistrySelect. 9(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401379683

                Abstract Lewisite is a representative chemical warfare agent that contains arsenic. Thermal decomposition is an essential method for Lewisite destruction, and appropriate destruction conditions can enhance the environmental friendliness of this method by minimizing the hazards of destruction products. In this study, the variation of Lewisite during pyrolysis and incineration was calculated, with particular emphasis on the evolution behaviors of arsenic and chloride with temperature, pressure, and molar ratio. The main products identified during pyrolysis were HCl(g), C, As, and AsCl 3 (g). Under anoxic conditions, AsCl 3 (g) and As were the dominant species. In oxygen&#8208;enriched conditions, arsenic existed primarily as AsCl 3 (g), As 2 O 5 , As 2 O 4 , and AsOCl. Below 600 &#176;C, arsenic predominantly existed in high valence forms such as As 2 O 5 . Above 600 &#176;C, the binding capacity of chlorine and arsenic was stronger than that of oxygen, resulting in an AsCl 3 (g) molar fraction exceeding 75 % at 1200 &#176;C. The primary chlorides in oxygen&#8208;enriched conditions were Cl 2 (g), HCl(g), AsCl 3 (g), and Cl(g). Lower incineration temperatures (around 500 &#176;C), sufficient oxygen conditions (molar ratio above 4 : 1), and positive pressures were conducive to reducing the toxicity of destruction products. The results are in good agreement with the experimental data.</description>
      <author>X.K. Liu, Yuanpeng Zhang, Lin Yang, Weiwei Song, Haitao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202400055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observations of Extremely Metal-Poor O Stars: Weak Winds and Constraints
  for Evolution Models</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.20313</link>
      <description>O. Grace Telford, John Chisholm, A. A. C. Sander, V. S. Ramachandran, Kristen B. W. McQuinn, Danielle A. Berg, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401202758

                Metal-poor massive stars drive the evolution of low-mass galaxies, both locally and at high redshift. However, quantifying the feedback they impart to their local surroundings remains uncertain because models of stellar evolution, mass loss, and ionizing spectra are unconstrained by observations below 20% solar metallicity ($Z_\odot$). We present new Keck Cosmic Web Imager optical spectroscopy of three O stars in the nearby dwarf galaxies Leo P, Sextans A, and WLM, which have gas-phase oxygen abundances of 3-14% $Z_\odot$. To characterize their fundamental stellar properties and radiation-driven winds, we fit PoWR atmosphere models to the optical spectra simultaneously with Hubble Space Telescope far-ultraviolet (FUV) spectra and multi-wavelength photometry. We find that all three stars have effective temperatures consistent with their spectral types and surface gravities typical of main-sequence dwarf stars. Yet, the combination of those inferred parameters and luminosity for the two lower-$Z$ stars is not reproduced by stellar evolution models, even those that include rotation or binary interactions. The scenario of multiple-star systems is difficult to reconcile with all available data, suggesting that these observations pose a challenge to current evolution models. We highlight the importance of validating the relationship between stellar mass, temperature, and luminosity at very low $Z$ for accurate estimates of ionizing photon production and spectral hardness. Finally, all three stars' FUV wind profiles reveal low mass-loss rates and terminal wind velocities in tension with expectations from widely adopted radiation-driven wind models. These results provide empirical benchmarks for future development of mass-loss and evolution models for metal-poor stellar populations.</description>
      <author>O. Grace Telford, John Chisholm, A. A. C. Sander, V. S. Ramachandran, Kristen B. W. McQuinn, Danielle A. Berg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.20313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the mechanisms of Devonian oceanic anoxia: impact of ocean dynamics, palaeogeography and orbital forcing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1983</link>
      <description>Justin G&#233;rard, Lo&#239;c Sablon, Jarno J. C. Huygh, Anne&#8208;Christine Da Silva, Alexandre Pohl, Christian V&#233;rard, Michel Crucifix, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401225082

                Abstract. The Devonian is a warmer-than-present geological period spanning from 419 to 359 million years ago (Ma) characterized by multiple identified ocean anoxic/hypoxic events. Despite decades of extensive investigation, no consensus has been reached regarding the drivers of these anoxic events. While growing geological evidence has demonstrated a temporal correlation between astronomical forcing and anoxia during this period, underlying physical mechanisms remain unknown, hence questioning causality. Here, we perform multiple sensitivity experiments, using an Earth system model of intermediate complexity (cGENIE), to isolate the influences of specific Devonian climate and palaeogeography components on ocean oxygen levels, contributing to the better understanding of the intricate interplay of factors preconditioning the ocean to anoxia. We quantify the impact of continental configuration, ocean-atmosphere biogeochemistry (global mean oceanic PO4 concentration and atmospheric pO2), climatic forcing (pCO2) and astronomical forcing on background oceanic circulation and oxygenation during the Devonian. Our results indicate that continental configuration is crucial for Devonian ocean anoxia, significantly influencing ocean circulation and oxygen levels while consistently modulating the effects of other Devonian climate components such as oceanic PO4 concentration, atmospheric pO2 and pCO2, and orbital forcing. The evolution of continental configuration provides a plausible explanation for the increased frequency of ocean anoxic events identified during the Middle and Late Devonian periods, as it contributed to the expansion of oxygen-depleted zones. Our simulations also show that both the decreased atmospheric pO2 and increased oceanic PO2 concentration exacerbate ocean anoxia, consistent with established knowledge. The variation of pCO2 reveals a wide range of ocean dynamics patterns, including stable oscillations, multiple convection cells, multistability and hysteresis; all leading to significant variations of the ocean oxygen levels, therefore strongly impacting the preconditioning of the ocean to anoxia. Furthermore, multistability and important hysteresis (particularly slow ocean time response) offer different mechanisms to account for the prolonged duration of some ocean anoxic events. Finally, we found that astronomical forcing substantially impacts ocean anoxia by altering ocean circulation and oxygen solubility, with obliquity consistently emerging as the primary orbital parameter driving ocean oxygen variations.</description>
      <author>Justin G&#233;rard, Lo&#239;c Sablon, Jarno J. C. Huygh, Anne&#8208;Christine Da Silva, Alexandre Pohl, Christian V&#233;rard, Michel Crucifix</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piezo&#8208;catalysis Mechanism Elucidation by Tracking Oxygen Reduction to Hydrogen Peroxide with In&#8208;situ EPR Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410381</link>
      <description>Jie He, Zhi Li, Pengju Feng, Gang Lu, Tengda Ding, Li Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Mingshan Zhu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401225169

                For piezoelectric catalysis, the catalytic mechanism is a topic of great controversy, with debates centered around whether it belongs to the energy band theory of photocatalysis or the screening charge effect of electrochemical catalysis. Due to the formation of different intermediate active&#8208;species during two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) via electro&#8208; and photo&#8208;catalysis, the key to solving this problem is precisely monitoring the active species involved in ORR during electro&#8208;, photo&#8208;, and piezo&#8208;catalysis under identical condition. Here, a semiconductor material, BiOBr with abundant oxygen vacancies (BOB&#8208;OV) was found remarkable catalytic activity in H2O2 production by all three catalytic methods. By employing in&#8208;situ electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy, the H2O2 evolution pathway through piezo&#8208;catalysis over BOB&#8208;OV was monitored, which showed a similar reaction pathway to that observed in photo&#8208;catalytic process. This finding represents solid evidence supporting the notion that piezo&#8208;catalytic mechanism of ORR is more inclined towards photo&#8208;catalysis rather than electro&#8208;catalysis. Significantly, this exploratory conclusion provides insight to deepen our understanding of piezo&#8208;catalysis.</description>
      <author>Jie He, Zhi Li, Pengju Feng, Gang Lu, Tengda Ding, Li Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Mingshan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piezo&#8208;catalysis Mechanism Elucidation by Tracking Oxygen Reduction to Hydrogen Peroxide with In&#8208;situ EPR Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410381</link>
      <description>Jie He, Zhi Li, Pengju Feng, Gang L&#252;, Tengda Ding, Li Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Zhu Mingshan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401225016

                For piezoelectric catalysis, the catalytic mechanism is a topic of great controversy, with debates centered around whether it belongs to the energy band theory of photocatalysis or the screening charge effect of electrochemical catalysis. Due to the formation of different intermediate active&#8208;species during two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) via electro&#8208; and photo&#8208;catalysis, the key to solving this problem is precisely monitoring the active species involved in ORR during electro&#8208;, photo&#8208;, and piezo&#8208;catalysis under identical condition. Here, a semiconductor material, BiOBr with abundant oxygen vacancies (BOB&#8208;OV) was found remarkable catalytic activity in H2O2 production by all three catalytic methods. By employing in&#8208;situ electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy, the H2O2 evolution pathway through piezo&#8208;catalysis over BOB&#8208;OV was monitored, which showed a similar reaction pathway to that observed in photo&#8208;catalytic process. This finding represents solid evidence supporting the notion that piezo&#8208;catalytic mechanism of ORR is more inclined towards photo&#8208;catalysis rather than electro&#8208;catalysis. Significantly, this exploratory conclusion provides insight to deepen our understanding of piezo&#8208;catalysis.</description>
      <author>Jie He, Zhi Li, Pengju Feng, Gang L&#252;, Tengda Ding, Li Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Zhu Mingshan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Challenges in Analytical Strategies for Fruity Thiol Profiling in Beer: From Sensitivity Optimization to Ecologically Responsible Methodologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61935/acetr.3.1.2024.p204</link>
      <description>H.L. Liu, Jianghua Zhao, Delin Han, F. Deng, Advances in Computer and Engineering Technology Research. 1(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401378525

                The fruity thiols in beer, such as 3SH, 3SHA, 4MMP, and 3S4MP, constitute significant components of its volatile profile, playing a pivotal role in shaping the overall flavor alongside hydrocarbons and oxygen-containing compounds. This paper, drawing extensively on relevant literature, presents a comprehensive summary of the composition, aroma contribution, challenges in thiol detection, and advancements in analytical methods and technologies for these compounds. It outlines the limitations and attempted improvements of direct measurement approaches, the innovations and evolution of derivatization methods, and the integration of various specific sample preparation techniques (e.g., SPE, SPME, LLE, and derivatization) with modern, advanced detection equipment, accompanied by an evaluation of the precision and inclusivity of these methods. Concluding the discussion, the article offers a perspective on the future refinement of thiol determination in the brewing industry. This review aims to serve the objective of more precise beer flavor modulation.</description>
      <author>H.L. Liu, Jianghua Zhao, Delin Han, F. Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61935/acetr.3.1.2024.p204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhibiting Voltage Decay in Li-Rich Layered Oxide Cathode: From O3-Type to O2-Type Structural Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01473-7</link>
      <description>Guo&#8208;Hua Zhang, Xiaohui Wen, Yuheng Gao, Renyuan Zhang, Zhimei Huang, Nano-Micro Letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401233024

                Abstract Li-rich layered oxide (LRLO) cathodes have been regarded as promising candidates for next-generation Li-ion batteries due to their exceptionally high energy density, which combines cationic and anionic redox activities. However, continuous voltage decay during cycling remains the primary obstacle for practical applications, which has yet to be fundamentally addressed. It is widely acknowledged that voltage decay originates from the irreversible migration of transition metal ions, which usually further exacerbates structural evolution and aggravates the irreversible oxygen redox reactions. Recently, constructing O2-type structure has been considered one of the most promising approaches for inhibiting voltage decay. In this review, the relationship between voltage decay and structural evolution is systematically elucidated. Strategies to suppress voltage decay are systematically summarized. Additionally, the design of O2-type structure and the corresponding mechanism of suppressing voltage decay are comprehensively discussed. Unfortunately, the reported O2-type LRLO cathodes still exhibit partially disordered structure with extended cycles. Herein, the factors that may cause the irreversible transition metal migrations in O2-type LRLO materials are also explored, while the perspectives and challenges for designing high-performance O2-type LRLO cathodes without voltage decay are proposed.</description>
      <author>Guo&#8208;Hua Zhang, Xiaohui Wen, Yuheng Gao, Renyuan Zhang, Zhimei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01473-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quality of Life and Exercise Capacity in Early Stage and Subclinical Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy: A Secondary Analysis of the VANISH Trial</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1161/circheartfailure.124.011663</link>
      <description>Catherine G. Ireland, Danielle S. Burstein, Sharlene M. Day, Anna Axelsson Raja, Mark W. Russell, Kenneth Zahka, Alexandre C. Pereira, Charles E. Canter, Richard G. Bach, Matthew T. Wheeler, Joseph W. Rossano, Anjali Tiku Owens, Henning Bundgaard, Luisa Mestroni, Matthew R.G. Taylor, Amit R. Patel, Ivan Wilmot, Jonathan H. Soslow, Jason R. Becker, Ilya Giverts, E. John Orav, Brian Claggett, Kimberly Y. Lin, Carolyn Y. Ho, Circulation Heart Failure. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401223998

                BACKGROUND: The health-related quality of life (HRQOL) and cardiopulmonary exercise testing (CPET) performance of individuals with subclinical and early stage hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM) have not been systematically studied. Improved understanding will inform the natural history of HCM and factors influencing well-being. METHODS: VANISH trial (Valsartan for Attenuating Disease Evolution in Early Sarcomeric HCM) participants with early stage sarcomeric HCM (primary analysis cohort) and subclinical HCM (sarcomere variant without left ventricular hypertrophy comprising the exploratory cohort) who completed baseline and year 2 HRQOL assessment via the pediatric quality of life inventory and CPET were studied. Metrics correlating with baseline HRQOL and CPET performance were identified. The impact of valsartan treatment on these measures was analyzed in the early stage cohort. RESULTS: Two hundred participants were included: 166 with early stage HCM (mean age, 23&#177;10 years; 40% female; 97% White; and 92% New York Heart Association class I) and 34 subclinical sarcomere variant carriers (mean age, 16&#177;5 years; 50% female; and 100% White). Baseline HRQOL was good in both cohorts, although slightly better in subclinical HCM (composite pediatric quality of life score 84.6&#177;10.6 versus 90.2&#177;9.8; P =0.005). Both cohorts demonstrated mildly reduced functional status (mean percent predicted peak oxygen uptake 73&#177;16 versus 78&#177;12 mL/kg per minute; P =0.18). Percent predicted peak oxygen uptake and peak oxygen pulse correlated with HRQOL. Valsartan improved physical HRQOL in early stage HCM (adjusted mean change in pediatric quality of life score +4.1 versus placebo; P =0.01) but did not significantly impact CPET performance. CONCLUSIONS: Functional capacity can be impaired in young, healthy people with early stage HCM, despite New York Heart Association class I status and good HRQOL. Peak oxygen uptake was similarly decreased in subclinical HCM despite normal left ventricular wall thickness and excellent HRQOL. Valsartan improved physical pediatric quality of life scores but did not significantly impact CPET performance. Further studies are needed for validation and to understand how to improve patient experience. REGISTRATION: URL: https://www.clinicaltrials.gov ; Unique identifier: NCT01912534.</description>
      <author>Catherine G. Ireland, Danielle S. Burstein, Sharlene M. Day, Anna Axelsson Raja, Mark W. Russell, Kenneth Zahka, Alexandre C. Pereira, Charles E. Canter, Richard G. Bach, Matthew T. Wheeler, Joseph W. Rossano, Anjali Tiku Owens, Henning Bundgaard, Luisa Mestroni, Matthew R.G. Taylor, Amit R. Patel, Ivan Wilmot, Jonathan H. Soslow, Jason R. Becker, Ilya Giverts, E. John Orav, Brian Claggett, Kimberly Y. Lin, Carolyn Y. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1161/circheartfailure.124.011663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrocarbon Accumulation and Overpressure Evolution in Deep&#8211;Ultradeep Reservoirs in the Case of the Guole Area of the Tarim Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min14080790</link>
      <description>Zhanfeng Qiao, Tianfu Zhang, Ruyue Wang, Yahao Huang, Yifan Xue, Jiajun Chen, Haonan Tian, Anjiang Shen, Chunsong Si, Minerals. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401161162

                Usually, deep oil and gas accumulation is often controlled by strike&#8211;slip faults. However, in the Tarim Basin, deep Ordovician oil and gas accumulations are also found in areas far from the fault zone. The process of oil and gas accumulation in deep reservoirs far from strike&#8211;slip fault zones is still unclear at present. The source and evolution of Ordovician fluids were analyzed using inclusion geochemical methods and the U&#8211;Pb dating technique. The analysis of rare earth elements and carbon&#8211;oxygen&#8211;strontium isotopes in the reservoirs showed that the reservoirs were weakly modified by diagenetic fluid. The fluid was derived from the fluid formation during the same period as the seawater, and no oxidizing fluid invaded the reservoir. The late oil and gas reservoirs had good sealing properties. The U&#8211;Pb dating results combined with homogenization temperature data revealed that the first-stage oil was charged during the Late Caledonian Period, and the second-stage natural gas was charged during the Middle Yanshanian Period. The evolution of the paleo-pressure showed that the charging of natural gas in the Middle Yanshanian was the main reason for the formation of reservoir overpressure. The strike&#8211;slip fault zone was basically inactive in the Middle Yanshanian. During this period, the charged natural gas mainly migrated to the reservoir along the unconformity surface and the open strike&#8211;slip fault zone in the upper part of the Ordovician reservoir. The source of the fluid shows that the reservoir in the late stage had good sealing properties, and there was no intrusion of exogenous fluid. The overpressure in the reservoir is well preserved at present.</description>
      <author>Zhanfeng Qiao, Tianfu Zhang, Ruyue Wang, Yahao Huang, Yifan Xue, Jiajun Chen, Haonan Tian, Anjiang Shen, Chunsong Si</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min14080790</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of river&#8211;aquifer disconnections and the migration and transformation of iron and manganese under non-time-varying/time-varying riverbed permeability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175156</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Zhijiang Yuan, Xiaosi Su, The Science of The Total Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401171184

                Changes in the composition, structure, and thickness of riverbed sediments caused by riverbed clogging strongly affect the hydraulic connection, migration and transformation of nutrients between river water and groundwater in groundwater source areas. However, previous studies have not extensively investigated the mechanisms of river-aquifer disconnection and the migration and transformation processes of iron and manganese under non-time-varying and time-varying conditions of riverbed permeability. This study developed a model using the COMSOL Multiphysics platform to characterize the riverbed clogging-groundwater exploitation-disconnection process, considering microbial growth and related biogeochemical processes, and investigated feedbacks between the reactive migration of iron and manganese and physical clogging-groundwater exploitation processes or bioclogging processes. The research findings showed that under non-time-varying conditions of riverbed permeability, the evolution of river-aquifer disconnection was strongly affected by the thickness and permeability coefficient of riverbed sediments. The dissolved oxygen attenuation rate in the disconnection zone decreased by up to 88.8 %. Additionally, the Mn</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Zhijiang Yuan, Xiaosi Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ORIGIN AND EVOLUTION OF A PEAT BOG FROM NORTHEASTERN ROMANIA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.30892/auog.34201-918</link>
      <description>Gheorghe B&#259;d&#259;lu&#355;&#259;, Carmen&#8211;Andreea B&#259;d&#259;lu&#355;&#259;, Marcel M&#238;ndrescu, Diana ISTRATE, Ionu&#539; Bogdan NIGA, Analele Universit&#259;&#355;ii din Oradea Seria Geografie. 34(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401184871

                Peatlands are highly sensitive ecosystems that respond to hydrological, climatic, and geomorphological changes. In this study, we investigate the origin and historical evolution of a peatland located in Northeastern Romania, on the Suceava plateau. Our approach includes the analysis of historical maps and physical characteristics of both the peat (grain size, LOI - loss on ignition) and water (pH, dissolved oxygen, electrical conductivity). Our findings suggest that the development of this peatland has been more prominent along the surface than the depth. The presence of gravel and sand at the base of the peat deposit, along with surface morphological evidence, supports the hypothesis that this peatland originated in an ancient paleomeander. pH analysis indicates that the peatland is mesotrophic, while granulometric and LOI analyses suggest a fluviogenic origin.The significant changes observed in the sedimentary structure of the peatland may be attributed to climate change, with potential anthropogenic influences over the past 50 years. Furthermore, our study contributes valuable insights to geomorphological research in the Suceava valley, revealing visible changes spanning the last 250 years.</description>
      <author>Gheorghe B&#259;d&#259;lu&#355;&#259;, Carmen&#8211;Andreea B&#259;d&#259;lu&#355;&#259;, Marcel M&#238;ndrescu, Diana ISTRATE, Ionu&#539; Bogdan NIGA</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.30892/auog.34201-918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A defect-chemistry-informed phase-field model of grain growth in oxide
  electroceramics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.17650</link>
      <description>Kai Wang, Roger A. De Souza, Xiang-Long Peng, Rotraut Merkle, Wolfgang Rheinheimer, Karsten Albe, Bai&#8208;Xiang Xu, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401200953

                Dopants can significantly affect the properties of oxide ceramics through their impact on the property-determined microstructure characteristics such as grain boundary segregation, space charge layer formation in the grain boundary vicinity, and the resultant microstructure features like bimodality due to abnormal grain growth. To support rational oxide ceramics design, we propose a multiphysics-based and defect-chemistry-informed phase-field grain growth model to simulate the microstructure evolution of oxide ceramics. It fully respects the thermodynamics of charged point defects (oxygen vacancies and dopants) in both the grain interior and boundaries and considers the competing kinetics of defect diffusion and grain boundary movement. The proposed phase-field model is benchmarked against well-known simplified bicrystal models, including the Mott-Schottky and Gouy-Chapman models. Various simulation results are presented to reveal the impacts of defect formation energy differences between the grain interior and the grain boundary core on the key microstructural aspects. In particular, simulation results confirm that the solute drag effect alone can lead to bimodal grain size distribution, without any contribution from grain misorientation and other anisotropy. Interestingly, abnormal grain growth simulations demonstrate that grain boundary potentials can vary substantially: grain boundaries of larger grains tend to have lower potentials than those of smaller grains. Such heterogeneous grain boundary potential distribution may inspire a new material optimization strategy through microstructure design. This study provides a comprehensive framework for defect-chemistry-consistent investigations of microstructure evolution in polycrystalline oxide ceramics, offering fundamental insights into in-situ processes during critical manufacturing stages.</description>
      <author>Kai Wang, Roger A. De Souza, Xiang-Long Peng, Rotraut Merkle, Wolfgang Rheinheimer, Karsten Albe, Bai&#8208;Xiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.17650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-scheme carbon doped-TiO2/ZnIn2S4 heterojunction for enhanced photocatalytic degradation of microcystin-LR and hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.142996</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Lin Ding, Xibao Li, Zhenzhou Wang, Xiwei Xu, Xubiao Luo, Xubiao Luo, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401270799

                Photocatalytic degradation of pollutants coupled with hydrogen (H2) evolution has emerged as a promising solution for environmental and energy crises. However, the fast recombination of photoexcited electrons and holes limits photocatalytic activities. Herein, an S-scheme heterojunction carbon doped-TiO2 /ZnIn2S4 (C-TiO2/ZnIn2S4) was designed by substituting oxygen sites within C-TiO2 by ZnIn2S4. Under visible light irradiation, the optimal C-TiO2/ZnIn2S4 exhibits a higher degradation efficiency (88.6%) of microcystin-LR (MC-LR), compared to pristine C-TiO2 (72.9%) and ZnIn2S4 (66.8%). Furthermore, the H2 yield of the C-TiO2/ZnIn2S4 reaches 1526.9 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1, which is 3.83 times and 2.87 times that of the C-TiO2 and ZnIn2S4, respectively. Experimental and theoretical investigations reveal that an internal electric field (IEF) informed in the C-TiO2/ZnIn2S4 heterojunction, accelerates the separation of photogenerated charge pairs, thereby enhancing photocatalytic efficiency of MC-LR degradation and H2 production. This work highlights a new perspective on the development of high-performance photocatalysts for wastewater treatment and H2 generation.</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Lin Ding, Xibao Li, Zhenzhou Wang, Xiwei Xu, Xubiao Luo, Xubiao Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.142996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History of Earth evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/85/20240962</link>
      <description>Yifei Zhang, Applied and Computational Engineering. 85(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401185646

                The paper delves deeply into crucial subjects spanning the birth of our solar system to humanitys ascendancy on Earth. It aims to enable humankind to gain a deeper understanding of our own origins and the Earths genesis and evolution. Given that Earth is our sole habitat, we must gain insights into the conditions necessary for it to sustain life or identify potential terrestrial planets suitable for human habitation. Throughout its history, Earth has weathered countless encounters with meteorites, comets, and asteroids, dating back to the formation of the solar system. These events, though rare, played a pivotal role in shaping our planets atmosphere, magnetic field, and unique environmental characteristics. Perhaps the most extraordinary aspect of Earths history is the emergence of life itselfa true marvel. Starting with single-celled protists, life evolved into complex multicellular organisms. Yet, a pivotal moment in Earths history came with a momentous global extinction event triggered by the rise of oxygen. This event reshaped the planets natural ecosystem, leading to the extinction of many species and the emergence of new ones. Humanitys own journey, navigating the depths of history, eventually led to our dominance over the Earth.</description>
      <author>Yifei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.54254/2755-2721/85/20240962</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoceramic particle reinforced high alloying Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/14644207241269595</link>
      <description>Hailong Cong, Xianping Zhang, ZeFan Cheng, Hai Chao Li, Pei Wang, Wanting Sun, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers Part L Journal of Materials Design and Applications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401277442

                In the metal matrix composites (MMCs) reinforced with nanoparticles, the enhancement of composite performance is often closely associated with the types of nanoparticles. It is vital to explore the influences and differences of various nanoparticles on the microstructure evolution and mechanical properties of highly alloyed aluminum-based composites. This study is the first to employ hot pressing for preparing Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composite materials reinforced with SiC and Al 2 O 3 nano-ceramic particles, respectively. By employing hot extrusion and T6 heat treatment techniques, a systematic investigation was conducted on the effects of the addition of nano-ceramic particles on the microstructure evolution and mechanical properties of the Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composites, and a comparative analysis was performed on the two types of composite materials. The experimental results demonstrated that the Mg atoms in the &#945;-Al matrix were consumed by the addition of SiC/Al 2 O 3 nano-ceramic particles, and thereby the grain size primary &#951;&#8217; (MgZn 2 ) strengthening phase was refined, leading to an enhanced overall mechanical performance of the Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composite. In particular, the Mg 2 Si phase was generated by the addition of SiC nanoceramic particles, through the interfacial reactions, and thus with the synergistic effects of precipitation strengthening and Orowan strengthening, the ultimate compressive strength and compressibility of Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composite can be increased to 844 MPa and 27.5%, respectively. On the other hand, the addition of Al 2 O 3 nanoceramic particles can bring about the formation of an oxygen-rich phase and refined precipitates at grain boundaries. Accordingly, the elongation is increased to 43.5% while a high ultimate compressive strength in the composites can be maintained. It is anticipated that nanoceramic particle-reinforced Al-based metal composites have significant potential for achieving both high strength and exceptional ductility for the application in the industry field.</description>
      <author>Hailong Cong, Xianping Zhang, ZeFan Cheng, Hai Chao Li, Pei Wang, Wanting Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/14644207241269595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics&#8208;Matched Electrode Design for Zn&#8208;Metal Free Zinc Ion Batteries with High Energy Density and Stabilities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407120</link>
      <description>Jiahe Zhang, Chengqian Zhang, Shi Cai Cui, Xiaojun Zhang, Ke Wang, Yihe Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401223909

                Abstract The metal&#8208;free rocking chair type Zn&#8208;ion batteries (ZIBs) provide a promising approach toward the promotion of the Zn&#8208;based batteries by circumventing the challenges including dendrite growth, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and surface corrosion. In order to sufficiently exploit the available capacity of this metal&#8208;free batteries, it is necessary to effectively enhance the sluggish reaction kinetics of divalent zinc ions. Equally important is to achieve a balance in the kinetics between cathode and anode. Here, hetero&#8208;valent doping and oxygen vacancy engineering are employed to effectively enhance the reaction dynamics of V 2 O 5 cathodes and MoO 3 anodes. Moreover, to the best of the knowledge, for the first time, the strategy of kinetics matching between the two electrodes is applied to the construction of rocking&#8208;chair zinc ion batteries, enabling the cathode and anode to share similar zinc ion migration rates, and achieving a high energy density of up to 58.7 Wh kg &#8722;1 (based on the total electrode mass) as well as excellent cycling stability (90% after 500 cycles). This work demonstrates the importance of kinetics matching in zinc&#8208;ion full&#8208;cell performance and pave a benefitable avenue to for the pursuit of advanced multi&#8208;valent metal&#8208;ion batteries.</description>
      <author>Jiahe Zhang, Chengqian Zhang, Shi Cai Cui, Xiaojun Zhang, Ke Wang, Yihe Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wettability step electrode to generate millimeter-scale gas&#8211;liquid interface for drag reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0220158</link>
      <description>Mengzhuo Zhang, Haibao Hu, Liuzhen Ren, Jun Wen, Luo Xie, Physics of Fluids. 36(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337021

                Superhydrophobic surfaces can seal the gas&#8211;liquid interface (GLI) under water to produce the drag reduction effect. Enhancing the stability and slip length of the GLI is an important issue in this context. Herein, we fabricate wettability step electrodes (WSEs) by creating an array of millimeter-scale circular superhydrophobic regions on a hydrophilic graphite plate by using an economical and efficient mask spraying method. When the WSE was electrified as an anode, the oxygen produced by the electrolytic reaction was preferentially precipitated in the superhydrophobic regions and ultimately formed an array of millimeter-scale GLIs. The evolution process of this GLI can be divided into a spreading stage and a growth stage. The results of experiments revealed that the spreading duration of the GLI increased with the diameter of the superhydrophobic regions (D) and decreased with the spacing between adjacent superhydrophobic regions (L). During the growth stage, the height of the GLI decreased with the ratio D/(L + D) and increased over the duration of electrification according to a 1/3 power-law relationship. Finally, we measured the slip characteristic on a single millimeter-scale GLI by particle image velocimetry. The result showed that the effective slip length of the GLI with a streamwise length of 2 mm can exceed 100 &#956;m, thus confirming the potential of the millimeter-scale GLI for drag reduction.</description>
      <author>Mengzhuo Zhang, Haibao Hu, Liuzhen Ren, Jun Wen, Luo Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0220158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Defect Engineering of Fe&#8208;MIL for Self&#8208;Enhanced Peroxidase&#8208;Like Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403354</link>
      <description>Yujia Cai, Yu Wu, Yinjun Tang, Weiqing Xu, Yifei Chen, Rina Su, Yuexi Fan, Wenxuan Jiang, Yating Wen, Wenling Gu, Hongcheng Sun, Chengzhou Zhu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333995

                Abstract Defect engineering is an effective strategy to enhance the enzyme&#8208;like activity of nanozymes. However, previous efforts have primarily focused on introducing defects via de novo synthesis and post&#8208;synthetic treatment, overlooking the dynamic evolution of defects during the catalytic process involving highly reactive oxygen species. Herein, a defect&#8208;engineered metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nanozyme with mixed linkers is reported. Over twofold peroxidase (POD)&#8208;like activity enhancement compared with unmodified nanozyme highlights the critical role of in situ defect formation in enhancing the catalytic performance of nanozyme. Experimental results reveal that highly active hydroxyl radical (&#8226;OH) generated in the catalytic process etches the 2,5&#8208;dihydroxyterephthalic acid ligands, contributing to electronic structure modulation of metal sites and enlarged pore sizes in the framework. The self&#8208;enhanced POD&#8208;like activity induced by in situ defect engineering promotes the generation of &#8226;OH, holding promise in colorimetric sensing for detecting dichlorvos. Utilizing smartphone photography for RGB value extraction, the resultant sensing platform achieves the detection for dichlorvos ranging from 5 to 300 ng mL &#8722;1 with a low detection limit of 2.06 ng mL &#8722;1 . This pioneering work in creating in situ defects in MOFs to improve catalytic activity offers a novel perspective on traditional defect engineering.</description>
      <author>Yujia Cai, Yu Wu, Yinjun Tang, Weiqing Xu, Yifei Chen, Rina Su, Yuexi Fan, Wenxuan Jiang, Yating Wen, Wenling Gu, Hongcheng Sun, Chengzhou Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambipolar doping of a charge-transfer insulator in the Emery model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.19545</link>
      <description>G. Sordi, G. L. Reaney, Nicolas Kowalski, P. S&#233;mon, A.&#8211;M. S. Tremblay, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401201774

                Understanding the similarities and differences between adding or removing electrons from a charge-transfer insulator may provide insights about the origin of the electron-hole asymmetry found in cuprates. Here we study with cellular dynamical mean-field theory the Emery model set in the charge-transfer insulator regime, and dope it with either electrons or holes. We consider the normal state only and focus on the doping evolution of the orbital character of the dopants and on the nature of the doping driven transition. Regarding the orbital character of the dopants, we found an electron-hole asymmetry: doped electrons mostly enter the copper orbitals, whereas doped holes mostly enter the oxygen orbitals. Regarding the nature of the doping driven transition, we found no qualitative electron-hole asymmetry: upon either electron or hole doping, there is a two-stage transition from a charge-transfer insulator to a strongly correlated pseudogap and then to a metal. This shows that a strongly correlated pseudogap is an emergent feature of doped correlated insulators in two dimensions, in qualitative agreement with recent experiments on ambipolar Sr$_{1-x}$La$_{x}$CuO$_{2+y}$ cuprate films. Our results indicate that merely doping with holes or electrons a charge-transfer insulator is not sufficient for explaining the electron-hole asymmetry observed in the normal state phase diagram of cuprates. Our work reinforces the view that actual hole-doped cuprates are more correlated than their electron-doped counterparts.</description>
      <author>G. Sordi, G. L. Reaney, Nicolas Kowalski, P. S&#233;mon, A.&#8211;M. S. Tremblay</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.19545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excited&#8208;State Dynamics and Optical Properties of Silica Under Ultrafast Laser Irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/apxr.202400106</link>
      <description>Arshak A. Tsaturyan, Elena P. Silaeva, Razvan Stoian, Jean&#8208;Philippe Colombier, Advanced Physics Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354141

                Abstract Excited by intense infrared ultrafast light pulses, a wide bandgap material undergoes nonlinear ionization, generating a high density of free electrons in conduction states. As a result, the electronic band structure is critically modified and the bandgap shrinks. This induces rapid changes in optical properties, dramatically affecting the absorption spectrum during light coupling to the dielectric surface or during nonlinear propagation inside the bulk. This study analyzes the structural behavior and the modification of the optical properties of laser&#8208;excited silica glass at the molecular cluster level through first&#8208;principles simulations. Employing density functional theory and the GW approximations for band structure under nonequilibrium conditions, alongside the Bethe&#8211;Salpeter equation, the dynamics of the optical properties of fused silica are comprehensively explored. The behavior of excited fused silica in a wide photon energy range (from a few to 20 eV) is thus predicted. Laser&#8208;induced electron excitation triggers a redistribution of charges between oxygen and silicon atoms, accompanied by a significant increase in electronic pressure, local atomic structure rearrangement, and material expansion. Molecular dynamics simulations offer a temporal perspective on the excited state dynamics, unveiling the intricate interplay between electronic and atomic effects on bandgap evolution. The analysis sheds light on excitonic resonances, intraband and interband transitions in fused silica under ultrafast laser irradiation, providing valuable insights into its excited state behavior and optical properties.</description>
      <author>Arshak A. Tsaturyan, Elena P. Silaeva, Razvan Stoian, Jean&#8208;Philippe Colombier</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/apxr.202400106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotation and Abundances of the Benchmark Brown Dwarf HD 33632 Ab from Keck/KPIC High-resolution Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad58d3</link>
      <description>Chih-Chun Hsu, Jason Wang, Jerry W. Xuan, Jean-Baptiste Ruffio, Evan Morris, Daniel Echeverri, Yinzi Xin, Joshua Liberman, Luke Finnerty, Katelyn Horstman, Ben Sappey, Gregory Doppmann, Dimitri Mawet, Nemanja Jovanovi&#263;, Michael P. Fitzgerald, Jacques-Robert Delorme, J. Kent Wallace, Ashley Baker, Randall Bartos, Geoffrey A. Blake, Benjamin Calvin, Sylvain Cetre, Ronald L&#243;pez, Jacklyn Pezzato, Tobias Schofield, Andrew Skemer, Ji Wang, The Astrophysical Journal. 971(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401275175

                Abstract We present the projected rotational velocity and molecular abundances for HD 33632 Ab obtained via Keck Planet Imager and Characterizer (KPIC) high-resolution spectroscopy. HD 33632 Ab is a nearby benchmark brown dwarf companion at a separation of &#8764;20 au that straddles the L&#8211;T transition. Using a forward-modeling framework with on-axis host star spectra, which provides self-consistent substellar atmospheric and retrieval models for HD 33632 Ab, we derive a projected rotational velocity of 53 &#177; 3 km s &#8722;1 and carbon monoxide and water mass fractions of logCO = &#8722;2.3 &#177; 0.3 and logH 2 O = &#8722;2.7 &#177; 0.2, respectively. The inferred carbon-to-oxygen ratio (C/O = 0.58 &#177; 0.14), molecular abundances, and metallicity ([C/H] = 0.0 &#177; 0.2 dex) of HD 33632 Ab are consistent with its host star. Although detectable methane opacities are expected in L&#8211;T transition objects, we did not recover methane in our KPIC spectra, partly due to the high v sin i and to disequilibrium chemistry at the pressures to which we are sensitive. We parameterize the spin as the ratio of rotation to the breakup velocity, and compare HD 33632 Ab to a compilation of &gt;200 very low-mass objects ( M &#8818; 0.1 M &#8857; ) that have spin measurements in the literature. There appears to be no clear trend for the isolated low-mass field objects versus mass, but a tentative trend is identified for low-mass companions and directly imaged exoplanets, similar to previous findings. A larger sample of close-in gas giant exoplanets and brown dwarfs will critically examine our understanding of their formation and evolution through rotation and chemical abundance measurements.</description>
      <author>Chih-Chun Hsu, Jason Wang, Jerry W. Xuan, Jean-Baptiste Ruffio, Evan Morris, Daniel Echeverri, Yinzi Xin, Joshua Liberman, Luke Finnerty, Katelyn Horstman, Ben Sappey, Gregory Doppmann, Dimitri Mawet, Nemanja Jovanovi&#263;, Michael P. Fitzgerald, Jacques-Robert Delorme, J. Kent Wallace, Ashley Baker, Randall Bartos, Geoffrey A. Blake, Benjamin Calvin, Sylvain Cetre, Ronald L&#243;pez, Jacklyn Pezzato, Tobias Schofield, Andrew Skemer, Ji Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad58d3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Controlled Condition Ice Encasement of Creeping Bentgrass and Annual Bluegrass on Plant Recovery, Gas Evolution, and Metabolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21273/jashs05394-24</link>
      <description>Megan Gendjar, Devendra Prasad Chalise, Randolph M. Beaudry, Emily Merewitz, Journal of the American Society for Horticultural Science. 149(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333606

                Two cool-season putting green turfgrass species, annual bluegrass and creeping bentgrass, are differential in ice encasement tolerance. Physiological mechanisms associated with creeping bentgrass ice encasement tolerance and annual bluegrass susceptibility are not understood. The objectives were to evaluate oxygen, ethylene, and CO 2 content within the upper soil space of the plants while frozen and immediately after ice melt after 0, 5, 10, 20, and 28 days of ice encasement (2.54 cm of ice) in growth chamber conditions. Following ice melt, plant samples were separated into leaf, crown, and root tissues and used to evaluate carbohydrate and amino acid content. Annual bluegrass exhibited higher damage (slower recovery rates) on most sampling days compared with creeping bentgrass. The organs that were most damaged and exhibited a differential principal component analysis snapshot, were the leaf and crown tissues. Creeping bentgrass may preserve leaf and crown tissues for postwinter recovery whereas significant metabolic changes occur in annual bluegrass leaves and crowns. Creeping bentgrass retained total amino acids in leaves following ice encasement whereas total leaf amino acid levels declined in annual bluegrass. Specific carbohydrates and amino acids such as the ability to maintain high levels of fructose, asparagine, and proline may be important indicators of the tolerance to ice encasement stress. On the basis of more prominent carbohydrate and amino acid loss in leaves and crowns and higher levels of CO 2 evolution, annual bluegrass may exhibit a higher metabolism and/or tissue damage during ice encasement compared with creeping bentgrass, which could reduce spring recuperative potential.</description>
      <author>Megan Gendjar, Devendra Prasad Chalise, Randolph M. Beaudry, Emily Merewitz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21273/jashs05394-24</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging coevolutionary insights and AI-based structural modeling to unravel receptor&#8211;peptide ligand-binding mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2400862121</link>
      <description>Simon Snoeck, Hyun Kyung Lee, Marc W. Schmid, Kyle W. Bender, Matthias J. Neeracher, &#193;lvaro D. Fern&#225;ndez-Fern&#225;ndez, Julia Santiago, Cyril Zipfel, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 121(33)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358444

                Secreted signaling peptides are central regulators of growth, development, and stress responses, but specific steps in the evolution of these peptides and their receptors are not well understood. Also, the molecular mechanisms of peptide&#8211;receptor binding are only known for a few examples, primarily owing to the limited availability of protein structural determination capabilities to few laboratories worldwide. Plants have evolved a multitude of secreted signaling peptides and corresponding transmembrane receptors. Stress-responsive SERINE RICH ENDOGENOUS PEPTIDES (SCOOPs) were recently identified. Bioactive SCOOPs are proteolytically processed by subtilases and are perceived by the leucine-rich repeat receptor kinase MALE DISCOVERER 1-INTERACTING RECEPTOR-LIKE KINASE 2 (MIK2) in the model plant Arabidopsis thaliana . How SCOOPs and MIK2 have (co)evolved, and how SCOOPs bind to MIK2 are unknown. Using in silico analysis of 350 plant genomes and subsequent functional testing, we revealed the conservation of MIK2 as SCOOP receptor within the plant order Brassicales. We then leveraged AI-based structural modeling and comparative genomics to identify two conserved putative SCOOP&#8211;MIK2 binding pockets across Brassicales MIK2 homologues predicted to interact with the &#8220;SxS&#8221; motif of otherwise sequence-divergent SCOOPs. Mutagenesis of both predicted binding pockets compromised SCOOP binding to MIK2, SCOOP-induced complex formation between MIK2 and its coreceptor BRASSINOSTEROID INSENSITIVE 1-ASSOCIATED KINASE 1, and SCOOP-induced reactive oxygen species production, thus, confirming our in silico predictions. Collectively, in addition to revealing the elusive SCOOP&#8211;MIK2 binding mechanism, our analytic pipeline combining phylogenomics, AI-based structural predictions, and experimental biochemical and physiological validation provides a blueprint for the elucidation of peptide ligand&#8211;receptor perception mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Simon Snoeck, Hyun Kyung Lee, Marc W. Schmid, Kyle W. Bender, Matthias J. Neeracher, &#193;lvaro D. Fern&#225;ndez-Fern&#225;ndez, Julia Santiago, Cyril Zipfel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2400862121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of a Full-Length transcriptome resource for the African sharptooth catfish (Clarias gariepinus), a prototypical air-breathing Fish, based on isoform sequencing (Iso-Seq)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gene.2024.148802</link>
      <description>Feiran Zhang, Wenjing Wan, Yang Li, Bo Wang, Yiting Shao, Xiangyi Di, Han Zhang, Wenlong Cai, Yiliang Wei, Xiaoli Ma, Gene. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401171730

                The African sharptooth catfish (Clarias gariepinus) assumes significance in aquaculture, given its role as a farmed freshwater species with modified gill structures functioning as an air-breathing organ (ABO). To provide a scientific basis for further elucidating the air-breathing formation mechanism and deeply utilizing the genetic resources of Clarias gariepinus, we utilized the PacBio sequencing platform to acquire a comprehensive full-length transcriptome from five juvenile developmental stages and various adult tissues, including the ABO, gills, liver, skin, and muscle. We generated 25,766,688 high-quality reads, with an average length of 2,006 bp and an N50 of 2,241 bp. Following rigorous quality control, 34,890 (97.7 %) of the high-quality isoforms were mapped to the reference genome for gene and transcript annotation, yielding 387 novel isoforms and 14,614 new isoforms. Additionally, we identified 28,582 open reading frames, 48 SNPs, 5,464 variable splices, and 6,141 variable polyadenylation sites, along with 475 long non-coding RNAs. Many DEGs were involved with low oxygen GO terms and KEGG pathways, such as response to stimulus, biological regulation and catalytic activities. Furthermore, it was found that transcription factors such as zf-C2H2, Homeobox, bHLH, and MYB could underpin the African sharptooth catfish's developmental plasticity and its capacity to adapt its morphology and function to its environment. Through the comprehensive analysis of its genomic characteristics, it was found that the African sharptooth catfish has developed a series of unique respiratory adaptive mechanisms during the evolutionary process, These results not only advances the understanding of genetic adaptations to hypoxia in Clarias fish but also provides a valuable framework for future studies aimed at improving aquaculture practices,besides provide important references and inspirations for the evolution of aquatic organisms.</description>
      <author>Feiran Zhang, Wenjing Wan, Yang Li, Bo Wang, Yiting Shao, Xiangyi Di, Han Zhang, Wenlong Cai, Yiliang Wei, Xiaoli Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gene.2024.148802</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JOYS+: link between ice and gas of complex organic molecules. Comparing
  JWST and ALMA data of two low-mass protostars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.20066</link>
      <description>Y. Chen, W. R. M. Rocha, E. F. van Dishoeck, M. L. van Gelder, P. Nazari, Katerina Slavicinska, L. Francis, B. Tabone, Michael E. Ressler, Pamela Klaassen, H. Beuther, A. C. A. Boogert, C. Gieser, Patrick Kavanagh, G. Perotti, Valentin J. M. Le Gouellec, Liton Majumdar, M. G&#252;del, Thomas Henning, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401202477

                A rich inventory of complex organic molecules (COMs) has been observed in high abundances in the gas phase toward Class 0 protostars. These molecules are suggested to be formed in ices and sublimate in the warm inner envelope close to the protostar. However, only the most abundant COM, methanol (CH3OH), has been firmly detected in ices before the era of James Webb Space Telescope (JWST). Now it is possible to detect the interstellar ices of other COMs and constrain their ice column densities quantitatively. We aim to determine the column densities of several oxygen-bearing COMs (O-COMs) in both gas and ice for two low-mass protostellar sources, NGC 1333 IRAS 2A and B1-c, as case studies in our JWST Observations of Young protoStars (JOYS+) program. By comparing the column density ratios w.r.t. CH3OH between both phases measured in the same sources, we can probe into the evolution of COMs from ice to gas in the early stages of star formation. We are able to fit the fingerprints range of COM ices between 6.8 and 8.8 um in the JWST/MIRI-MRS spectra of B1-c using similar components as recently used for IRAS 2A. We claim detection of CH4, OCN-, HCOO-, HCOOH, CH3CHO, C2H5OH, CH3OCH3, CH3OCHO, and CH3COCH3 in B1-c, and upper limits are estimated for SO2, CH3COOH, and CH3CN. The comparison of O-COM ratios w.r.t CH3OH between ice and gas shows two different cases. 1) the column density ratios of CH3OCHO and CH3OCH3 match well between the two phases, which may be attributed to a direct inheritance from ice to gas or strong chemical links with CH3OH. 2) the ice ratios of CH3CHO and C2H5OH w.r.t. CH3OH are higher than the gas ratios by 1-2 orders of magnitudes. This difference can be explained by the gas-phase reprocessing following sublimation, or different spatial distributions of COMs in the envelope.</description>
      <author>Y. Chen, W. R. M. Rocha, E. F. van Dishoeck, M. L. van Gelder, P. Nazari, Katerina Slavicinska, L. Francis, B. Tabone, Michael E. Ressler, Pamela Klaassen, H. Beuther, A. C. A. Boogert, C. Gieser, Patrick Kavanagh, G. Perotti, Valentin J. M. Le Gouellec, Liton Majumdar, M. G&#252;del, Thomas Henning</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.20066</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
