<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 01:07:05 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of nanostructured MnCo2O4.5 with spheres and puffed rice balls-like structures as high-performance electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136696</link>
      <description>K. Prasad, T.V.M. Sreekanth, Kisoo Yoo, Jong&#8208;Hoon Kim, Materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398194054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Prasad, T.V.M. Sreekanth, Kisoo Yoo, Jong&#8208;Hoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhance the Performance of OER Electrocatalyst via Synergistic Oxygen Vacancies and NiFe2O4-Phosphorene Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174949</link>
      <description>Yijie Mao, Xiao Wang, Jianxiang Wu, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Qing Xu, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398200746

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yijie Mao, Xiao Wang, Jianxiang Wu, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Qing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174949</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the oxygen evolution reaction activity of Iron (oxy) hydroxide by increasing reactive sites with morphology modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174911</link>
      <description>Harish S. Chavan, JeongEun Yoo, D Patil, Jiyoung Kim, Yongseon Choi, Ki&#8208;Young Lee, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398200773

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harish S. Chavan, JeongEun Yoo, D Patil, Jiyoung Kim, Yongseon Choi, Ki&#8208;Young Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174911</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Dependent Surface Restructuring on Nickel (Oxy)hydroxides: A Self-Activation Process for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02292</link>
      <description>Yunduo Yao, Guangxin Zhao, Xuyun Guo, Pei Xiong, Zhihang Xu, Longhai Zhang, C. P. Chen, Cunying Xu, Tai Wu, Y. L. Soo, Zhiming Cui, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Ye Zhu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398206347

                Unraveling the catalyst surface structure and behavior during reactions is essential for both mechanistic understanding and performance optimization. Here we report a phenomenon of facet-dependent surface restructuring intrinsic to &#946;-Ni(OH)2 catalysts during oxygen evolution reaction (OER), discovered by the correlative ex situ and operando characterization. The ex situ study after OER reveals &#946;-Ni(OH)2 restructuring at the edge facets to form nanoporous Ni1&#8211;xO, which is Ni deficient containing Ni3+ species. Operando liquid transmission electron microscopy (TEM) and Raman spectroscopy further identify the active role of the intermediate &#946;-NiOOH phase in both the OER catalysis and Ni1&#8211;xO formation, pinpointing the complete surface restructuring pathway. Such surface restructuring is shown to effectively increase the exposed active sites, accelerate Ni oxidation kinetics, and optimize *OH intermediate bonding energy toward fast OER kinetics, which leads to an extraordinary activity enhancement of &#8764;16-fold. Facilitated by such a self-activation process, the specially prepared &#946;-Ni(OH)2 with larger edge facets exhibits a 470-fold current enhancement than that of the benchmark IrO2, demonstrating a promising way to optimize metal-(oxy)hydroxide-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yunduo Yao, Guangxin Zhao, Xuyun Guo, Pei Xiong, Zhihang Xu, Longhai Zhang, C. P. Chen, Cunying Xu, Tai Wu, Y. L. Soo, Zhiming Cui, Molly Meng&#8208;Jung Li, Ye Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering oxygen-evolving catalysts for acidic water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0200438</link>
      <description>Xuan Minh Chau Ta, Th&#224;nh Tr&#7847;n&#8208;Ph&#250;, Thi Kim Anh Nguyen, Manjunath Chatti, Rahman Daiyan, Applied physics reviews. 11(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398206370

                The utilization of water electrolysis for green hydrogen (H2) production, powered by renewable energy, is a promising avenue for sustainable development. Proton-exchange-membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) stands out as one of the most efficient H2 production technologies. However, implementing it on an industrial scale faces substantial challenges, particularly regarding the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The OER, a critical process with inherently slow kinetics requiring additional potential, significantly influences overall water-splitting efficiency. Most OER electrocatalysts in PEMWE struggle with poor stability in harsh acidic environments at high oxidative potentials. While rare-earth metal oxides, such as iridium or ruthenium oxides, offer stability in commercial oxygen-evolving electrocatalysts (OECs), their use depends on achieving economically and sustainably viable operations. An alternative approach involves developing low- or non-noble metal-based OECs with sustaining high activity and long-term durability. Although such materials currently exhibit lower activity and stability than noble-based OECs, notable progress has been made in enhancing their performance. This review provides an overview of recent advancements in designing acidic-stable OECs based on low or without noble metal contents. It delves into the thermodynamics and degradation mechanisms of OECs in acidic media, evaluation parameters for activity and stability, strategies for developing active and acid-stable OECs, and the challenges and opportunities of acid water electrolysis. Through a detailed analysis of these aspects, the review aims to identify opportunities for engineering actively durable OECs.</description>
      <author>Xuan Minh Chau Ta, Th&#224;nh Tr&#7847;n&#8208;Ph&#250;, Thi Kim Anh Nguyen, Manjunath Chatti, Rahman Daiyan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0200438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel Tellurate Nanorods and Nanoparticles for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00935</link>
      <description>Harishchandra Singh, Miska Veijola-Kara, Ekta Rani, Leticia S. Bezerra, Parisa Talebi, Hugo L. S. Santos, Akhilesh Kumar Patel, Marko Huttula, Pedro H. C. Camargo, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398206879

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Harishchandra Singh, Miska Veijola-Kara, Ekta Rani, Leticia S. Bezerra, Parisa Talebi, Hugo L. S. Santos, Akhilesh Kumar Patel, Marko Huttula, Pedro H. C. Camargo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-derived MnCe3.67C6Permeable microflower: A robust electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.291</link>
      <description>Abdul Rasheed Rashid, Sumaira Manzoor, Monday Peter Ajisafe, Safyan Akram Khan, Bing Sun, &#350;enay Yal&#231;&#305;n, Huibin Qin, Suleyman I. Allakhverdiev, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398208043

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Rasheed Rashid, Sumaira Manzoor, Monday Peter Ajisafe, Safyan Akram Khan, Bing Sun, &#350;enay Yal&#231;&#305;n, Huibin Qin, Suleyman I. Allakhverdiev</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.291</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten doped FeCoP&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles embedded into carbon for highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02326a</link>
      <description>Xinyao Quan, Jiajia Ma, Qian-Shuo Shao, Hao&#8208;Cong Li, Lingxiang Sun, Gui-Li Huang, Yan Su, Hong Zhang, Yuning Wang, Xiaoqing Wang, RSC advances. 14(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398209309

                Tungsten-doped bimetallic phosphide nanoparticles were embedded into carbon by ball milling and phosphorisation, which required only 264 and 310 mV overpotentials to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 current density for OER, respectively.</description>
      <author>Xinyao Quan, Jiajia Ma, Qian-Shuo Shao, Hao&#8208;Cong Li, Lingxiang Sun, Gui-Li Huang, Yan Su, Hong Zhang, Yuning Wang, Xiaoqing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02326a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning-enabled fast exploration of stable and active single-atom catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59717/j.xinn-mater.2024.100072</link>
      <description>Woonghyeon Park, Juhwan Noh, Geun Ho Gu, Ga Eun Nam, Sang&#8208;Mun Jung, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Yousung Jung, &#152;The &#156;Innovation materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398211163

                &lt;p&gt;Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can convert renewable energy into hydrogen through water electrolysis. Identifying stable and active single-atom catalysts (SACs) for OER under acidic conditions holds great promise for developing cost-effective and efficient energy storage solutions, but challenging due to the vast number of potential material compositions and diverse surface morphologies. Here, to accelerate new discoveries, we present a high-throughput screening (HTS) framework that leverages the power of machine learning (ML) and density functional theory (DFT). The proposed framework includes an assessment of both the thermodynamic and electrochemical stability of support surfaces. In addition, the integration of ML and uncertainty quantification for predicting the binding energies dramatically reduces the computational cost (by over a factor of 10), facilitating the identification of catalytically active SACs. Following the proposed scheme, we suggest 14 new promising SACs for OER across the 795 binary oxide supports and 21 transition metal atom combinations. These catalysts are found to break the scaling relation due to the enhanced *OOH binding with the support, which arises from favorable hydrogen bonding interactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <author>Woonghyeon Park, Juhwan Noh, Geun Ho Gu, Ga Eun Nam, Sang&#8208;Mun Jung, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, Yousung Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59717/j.xinn-mater.2024.100072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis by Coordination Engineering in Cobalt Phosphate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403310</link>
      <description>Jing Qi, Qizhen Chen, Mingxing Chen, Wei Zhang, Xinxin Shen, Jing Li, Enbo Shangguan, Rui Cao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398216358

                Abstract Understanding the structure&#8208;activity correlation is an important prerequisite for the rational design of high&#8208;efficiency electrocatalysts at the atomic level. However, the effect of coordination environment on electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains enigmatic. In this work, the regulation of proton transfer involved in water oxidation by coordination engineering based on Co 3 (PO 4 ) 2 and CoHPO 4 is reported. The HPO 4 2&#8722; anion has intermediate p K a value between Co(II)&#8208;H 2 O and Co(III)&#8208;H 2 O to be served as an appealing proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer (PCET) induction group. From theoretical calculations, the pH&#8208;dependent OER properties, deuterium kinetic isotope effects, operando electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) and Raman studies, the CoHPO 4 catalyst beneficially reduces the energy barrier of proton hopping and modulates the formation energy of high&#8208;valent Co species, thereby enhancing OER activity. This work demonstrates a promising strategy that involves tuning the local coordination environment to optimize PCET steps and electrocatalytic activities for electrochemical applications. In addition, the designed system offers a motif to understand the structure&#8208;efficiency relationship from those amino&#8208;acid residue with proton buffer ability in natural photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Jing Qi, Qizhen Chen, Mingxing Chen, Wei Zhang, Xinxin Shen, Jing Li, Enbo Shangguan, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atom-Decorated Transition Metal Oxides Nanomaterials for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00285g</link>
      <description>Chengzhang Li, Cheng&#8208;Zong Yuan, Lingxian Wang, Fengjie Wu, Xiaoguang Lei, Xiaomeng Zhang, An&#8208;Wu Xu, Materials chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398217996

                As one promising technology for highly pure hydrogen production under mild conditions, electrochemical water splitting has been garnering substantial interest, while its efficiency and rate are primarily restricted by the...</description>
      <author>Chengzhang Li, Cheng&#8208;Zong Yuan, Lingxian Wang, Fengjie Wu, Xiaoguang Lei, Xiaomeng Zhang, An&#8208;Wu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00285g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the effect of doping LaCoO3 in CoFe2O4 forming nanocomposite, towards Oxygen Evolution and Methanol Oxidation reactions in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i5.9153</link>
      <description>Reena Parihar, P. C. Mishra, Yamini Singh, Narendra Kumar Singh, Indian Journal of Chemistry. 63(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398222016

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Reena Parihar, P. C. Mishra, Yamini Singh, Narendra Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i5.9153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combustion Growth of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide for Efficient and Durable Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03766</link>
      <description>Zhe Yu, J. Gao, Min Jiang, Yanpeng Chen, Haifeng Yuan, Simeng Li, Jinxin Li, Dongxuan Guo, Mei Hong, Shihe Yang, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398222286

                NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH) with abundant heterostructures represents a state-of-the-art electrocatalyst for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, NiFe LDH/Fe2O3 nanosheet arrays have been fabricated by facile combustion of corrosion-engineered NiFe foam (NFF). The in situ grown, self-supported electrocatalyst exhibited a low overpotential of 248 mV for the OER at 50 mA cm&#8211;2, a small Tafel slope of 31 mV dec&#8211;1, and excellent durability over 100 h under the industrial benchmarking 500 mA cm&#8211;2 current density. A balanced Ni and Fe composition under optimal corrosion and combustion contributed to the desirable electrochemical properties. Comprehensive ex-situ analyses and operando characterizations including Fourier-transformed alternating current voltammetry (FTACV) and in situ Raman demonstrate the beneficial role of modulated interfacial electron transfer, dynamic atomic structural transformation to NiOOH, and the high-valence active metal sites. This study provides a low-cost and easy-to-expand way to synthesize efficient and durable electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhe Yu, J. Gao, Min Jiang, Yanpeng Chen, Haifeng Yuan, Simeng Li, Jinxin Li, Dongxuan Guo, Mei Hong, Shihe Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c03766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embedded Como-Pom@If Nanoflower by Facile Room Temperature Etching as an Enhanced Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4837784</link>
      <description>Bo Li, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398225820

                Reasonable design and development of non-precious metal Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) electrocatalysts with high efficiency, low cost and stability are of great significance for electrocatalytic water splitting. The unique molecular structure and exceptional properties of polyoxometalates (POMs) have caught significant attention from the scientific community. Herein, CoMo-POM@IF nanoflowers has been successfully synthesized by facile etching iron foam (IF) at room temperature using polyoxometalates (POMs) as a precursor. POMs as a carbon-free metal-oxygen clusters with unique structural characteristics can be uniformly nucleated at room temperature, which can not only enable efficient green synthesis, but also provide a clear source of catalytic activity. CoMo-POM@IF catalysts with perfect nanoflake layer structure are obtained with the optimal reaction time, and the embedding of POM nanoparticles increased the surface roughness to expose more active sites. The embedding of POMs nanoparticles increases the surface roughness and electrochemically active area, showing great advantages in OER. An overpotential of 282 mV is measured at a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm-2 in 1 M KOH, showing long-term electrochemical stability. The green synthesis of POMs electrocatalyst provides great ideas for the development of room temperature oxygen evolution electrocatalyst and speeds up the development of OER electrocatalyst in the actual production.</description>
      <author>Bo Li, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4837784</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo5/Nitrogen doped carbon as an efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for Zn&#8211;Air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118369</link>
      <description>Jingyu Wang, Tianai Zhang, Simin He, Chunwen Sun, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398236341

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingyu Wang, Tianai Zhang, Simin He, Chunwen Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure and surface optimization of NiFeP-based heterostructure immobilized on carbon nanotube for boosting electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174957</link>
      <description>Qian Wang, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Xia Liu, Hui Ding, Li Zhang, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398239078

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Wang, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Xia Liu, Hui Ding, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174957</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic &#8216;Gelectrodes&#8217; for Sustainable and Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-z9f59</link>
      <description>Anu Bovas, T. P. Radhakrishnan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398240909

                Development of cost-effective catalysts that provide low overpotentials and enhanced electrochemical kinetics is a critical goal of contemporary research on electrochemical water splitting and similar technologically significant processes. Translation to practical applications demands that they should also enable high current densities to be ex-tracted. A simple strategy of encapsulating the active electrocatalyst in hydrogel polymer matrices is shown to provide a solution in several respects, especially regarding the last criterion. The concept is illustrated using two examples of &#8216;gelectrodes&#8217; based on nanocomposites of cobalt oxyhydroxide and nickel-iron hydroxide with chitosan on nickel foam, and their efficient mediation of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Comparison with various control systems show that significantly lower overpotentials and higher current densities with extended temporal stability can be achieved with the gelectrodes; the cobalt oxyhydroxide - chitosan and nickel-iron hydroxide - chitosan systems provide stable current densities up to 1.6 - 1.7 A cm-2 for the OER with alkaline aqueous electrolyte. This simple design strategy is expected to open up a general route to technologically useful electrocatalyst performance.</description>
      <author>Anu Bovas, T. P. Radhakrishnan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-z9f59</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performance of Nitrogen&#8208;Doped Carbon Nanoparticles Carrying FeNiCu as Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400830</link>
      <description>Qiao Guo, Rui Yuan, Yifei Zhao, Ying Yu, Jie Fu, Longsheng Cao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398242923

                Abstract Catalysts for zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) must be stable over long&#8208;term charging&#8208;discharging cycles and exhibit bifunctional catalytic activity. In this study, by doping nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (NC) materials with three metal atoms (Fe, Ni, and Cu), a single&#8208;atom&#8208;distributed FeNiCu&#8208;NC bifunctional catalyst is prepared. The catalyst includes Fe(Ni&#8208;doped)&#8208;N 4 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), Fe(Cu&#8208;doped)&#8208;N 4 for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and the NiCu&#8208;NC catalytic structure for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) in the nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanoparticles. This single&#8208;atom distribution catalyst structure enhances the bifunctional catalytic activity. If a trimetallic single&#8208;atom catalyst is designed, it will surpass the typical bimetallic single&#8208;atom catcalyst. FeNiCu&#8208;NC exhibits outstanding performance as an electrocatalyst, with a half&#8208;wave potential ( E 1/2 ) of 0.876 V versus RHE, overpotential ( E j = 10 ) of 253 mV versus RHE at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a small potential gap ( &#916;E = 0.61 V). As the anode in a ZAB, FeNiCu&#8208;NC can undergo continuous charge&#8208;discharged cycles for 575 h without significant attenuation. This study presents a new method for achieving high&#8208;performance, low&#8208;cost ZABs via trimetallic single&#8208;atom doping.</description>
      <author>Qiao Guo, Rui Yuan, Yifei Zhao, Ying Yu, Jie Fu, Longsheng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inactive Ag Modification and Defect Engineering Optimization on Three-Dimensional Coral-Like High-Entropy Oxides to Trigger Effective Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4839860</link>
      <description>Bing Zhang, Ping Geng, Mengzhao Liu, Ming Cui, Weiming L&#252;, Weiming Yi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398243423

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Zhang, Ping Geng, Mengzhao Liu, Ming Cui, Weiming L&#252;, Weiming Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4839860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-Mn Pair-Site Triggers Key Oxygen Intermediate for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4839786</link>
      <description>Faming Gao, yuanzhe wang, Kuo Wei, Yanli Song, Adekunle Adedapo Obisanya, Heen Li, Jing Wang, Hongguan Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398244782

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Faming Gao, yuanzhe wang, Kuo Wei, Yanli Song, Adekunle Adedapo Obisanya, Heen Li, Jing Wang, Hongguan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4839786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel layered cobalt oxide Ba2Co9O14 as an efficient and durable bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for rechargeable zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144450</link>
      <description>Dexuan Huang, Tong Liu, Aidong Xu, Jian Zhou, Yao Wang, Xiaoling Hu, Electrochimica acta. 494(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398247622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dexuan Huang, Tong Liu, Aidong Xu, Jian Zhou, Yao Wang, Xiaoling Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144450</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the Configuration Entropy of Layered Hydroxides Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4833203</link>
      <description>Da Li, Peifang Guo, Xiuping Yan, Yufei He, Renbing Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398249046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Da Li, Peifang Guo, Xiuping Yan, Yufei He, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4833203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rich oxygen vacancy and amorphous/crystalline ruthenium-doped CoCu -layered double hydroxide electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.169</link>
      <description>Yanan Wang, Li Jing, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Bo Liu, Yan Sun, Xianyu Chu, Chunbo Liu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398253008

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanan Wang, Li Jing, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Bo Liu, Yan Sun, Xianyu Chu, Chunbo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination Engineering of Carbon Dots and Mn in Co&#8208;Based Phosphides for Highly Efficient Seawater Splitting at Ampere&#8208;Level Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402478</link>
      <description>Tingting Fang, Xin Yu, Xu Han, Juan Gao, Yunlong Ma, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398253231

                Abstract Direct electrolysis of seawater to generate hydrogen is an attractive approach for storing renewable energy. However, direct seawater splitting suffers from low current density and limited operating stability, which severely hinders its industrialization. Herein, a promising strategy is reported to obtain a nano needle&#8208;like array catalyst&#8208;CDs&#8208;Mn&#8208;Co x P on nickel foam, in which the Mn&#9472;O&#9472;C bond tightly binds Mn, Carbon dots (CDs), and Co x P together. The coordination engineering of CDs and Mn not only effectively regulates the electronic structure of Co x P, but also endows the as&#8208;prepared catalyst with selectivity and marked long&#8208;term stability at ampere&#8208;level current density. Low overpotentials of 208 and 447 mV are required to achieve 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in simulated seawater, respectively. Cell potentials of 1.78 and 1.86 V are needed to reach 500 and 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline seawater along with excellent durability for 350 h. DFT studies have verified that the introduction of Mn and CDs effectively shifts the d&#8208;band center of Co&#8208;3d toward higher energy, thereby strengthening the adsorption of intermediates and enhancing the catalytic activity. This study sheds light on the development of highly effective and stable catalysts for large&#8208;scale seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Tingting Fang, Xin Yu, Xu Han, Juan Gao, Yunlong Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing medium-entropy spinel oxide FeNiMnO4/CeO2 heterojunction as high-performance electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00770k</link>
      <description>Hao Wu, Zhichao Wang, Yuan Shi, Zexu Li, Dong Fan, Yilun Ren, Fengqi Li, Haifeng Bian, Cong Wang, Yurong Yang, Jimin Gu, Shaochun Tang, Yan Ma, Yu Deng, Xiangkang Meng, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398757676

                Medium-entropy oxides are commonly employed as electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in electrolysers aimed at producing sustainable hydrogen. However, the poor conductivity poses a significant obstacle to further...</description>
      <author>Hao Wu, Zhichao Wang, Yuan Shi, Zexu Li, Dong Fan, Yilun Ren, Fengqi Li, Haifeng Bian, Cong Wang, Yurong Yang, Jimin Gu, Shaochun Tang, Yan Ma, Yu Deng, Xiangkang Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00770k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-deficient LaMnO3+&#948; tuned by electrochemical methods for peroxymonosulfate activation towards organics removal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2024.206955</link>
      <description>Ximu Li, Huang Yao, Jie Miao, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Applied Catalysis O Open. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398762392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ximu Li, Huang Yao, Jie Miao, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2024.206955</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient hydrogen production via overall water splitting using CuO/ZnO decorated reduced graphene oxide as bifunctional electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.355</link>
      <description>Umer Younas, Fizza Mobeen, Aimon Saleem, Faisal Ali, Maryam Al Huwayz, Adnan Ashraf, Awais Ahmad, Norah Alwadai, Muhammad Pervaiz, Munawar Iqbal, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398762739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Umer Younas, Fizza Mobeen, Aimon Saleem, Faisal Ali, Maryam Al Huwayz, Adnan Ashraf, Awais Ahmad, Norah Alwadai, Muhammad Pervaiz, Munawar Iqbal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the acidic oxygen evolution reaction performance of RuO2-TiO2 by a reduction-oxidation process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad501d</link>
      <description>J. Zhang, Yu Song, Wenwei Liu, Qian Zheng, Liang Yu, Tianli Wu, Tao Li, Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398763012

                Abstract As a promising alternative to Ir based acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, Ru suffers from severe fading issues. Supporting it on robust oxides such as TiO2 is a simple and effective way to enhance its lifetime. Here, we find that a simple reduction-oxidation process can further improve both activity and stability of RuO2-TiO2 composites at high potentials. In this process, the degree of oxidation was carefully controlled to form Ru/RuO2 heterostructure to improve OER activity. Moreover, due to the oxophilicity difference of Ru and Ti, the structure of catalysts was changed from supported to embedded, which enhanced the protective effect of TiO2 and mitigated the dissolution of Ru element in acidic electrolyte, making as-prepared Ru/RuO2-TiO2 with better durability at all tested potentials.</description>
      <author>J. Zhang, Yu Song, Wenwei Liu, Qian Zheng, Liang Yu, Tianli Wu, Tao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad501d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-doped nickel phosphide hollow nanospheres synthesized by solvothermal phosphidization of layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc01389a</link>
      <description>Zeyi Wang, Shilin Liu, Jun Du, Yan Ma, Yafei Hu, Yichuang Xing, Xin L&#252;, Chao Wang, Green chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398765333

                Active and stable electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are the key to the development of hydrogen production from alkaline water electrolysis. Here, iron-doped nickel phosphide grown on nickel foam...</description>
      <author>Zeyi Wang, Shilin Liu, Jun Du, Yan Ma, Yafei Hu, Yichuang Xing, Xin L&#252;, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc01389a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic coating strategy with oxidized oxygen anion capture to suppress lattice oxygen evolution of Ni-rich cathode materials at high voltage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152525</link>
      <description>Yizhen Huang, Tao Ma, Mo Li, Lianxi Zheng, Dan Su, Juantao Jiang, Qichang Pan, Sijiang Hu, Shaoyi Wang, Qingyu Li, Fenghua Zheng, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398765641

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yizhen Huang, Tao Ma, Mo Li, Lianxi Zheng, Dan Su, Juantao Jiang, Qichang Pan, Sijiang Hu, Shaoyi Wang, Qingyu Li, Fenghua Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline-dependent surface reconstruction at low applied potential region for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.187</link>
      <description>Yuan&#8208;Zhao Hua, Sheng Wang, Weiying Ye, Zhihao Qi, Yonggang Yang, Zhilin Zhang, Chenyang Cai, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398768779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan&#8208;Zhao Hua, Sheng Wang, Weiying Ye, Zhihao Qi, Yonggang Yang, Zhilin Zhang, Chenyang Cai, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional ultra-thin CuCoNiMnAl high-entropy alloy nanosheets for lithium-ion storage and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234738</link>
      <description>Xingqun Zhu, Jing Li, Rai Nauman Ali, Ming Song, Journal of power sources. 610(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398769883

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingqun Zhu, Jing Li, Rai Nauman Ali, Ming Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building strong metal-support interaction between TiN and RuO2 for efficient acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.315</link>
      <description>G. J. Wang, Wei Wan, Min Chen, Jing Li, Xinke Wu, Shuyi Huang, Li Ke, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398769927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. J. Wang, Wei Wan, Min Chen, Jing Li, Xinke Wu, Shuyi Huang, Li Ke, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of the Activity of Electrochemical Ozone Production over Rutile PbO2 Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400827</link>
      <description>Jingwei Jiang, Zhongyuan Guo, Shao-Kang Deng, Jing Xue, Heng Liu, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Lihua Cheng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398770085

                Ozonation water treatment technology has attracted increasing attention due to its environmental benign and high efficiency. Rutile PbO2 is a promising anode material for electrochemical ozone production (EOP). However, the reaction mechanism underlying ozone production catalyzed by PbO2 was rarely studied and not well&#8208;understood, which was in part due to the overlook of the electrochemistry&#8208;driven formation of oxygen vacancy (OV) of PbO2. Herein, we unrevealed the origin of the EOP activity of PbO2 starting from the electrochemical surface state analysis using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, activity analysis, and catalytic volcano modeling. Interestingly, we found that under experimental EOP potential (i.e., a potential around 2.2 V vs. reversible hydrogen electrode), OV can still be generated easily on PbO2 surfaces. Our subsequent kinetic and thermodynamic analyses show that these OV sites on PbO2 surfaces are highly active for the EOP reaction through an interesting atomic oxygen (O*)&#8208;O2 coupled mechanism. In particular, rutile PbO2(101) with the &#8220;in&#8208;situ&#8221; generated OV exhibited superior EOP activities, outperforming (111) and (110). Finally, by catalytic modeling, we found that PbO2 is close to the theoretical optimum of the reaction, suggesting a superior EOP performance of rutile PbO2. All these analyses are in good agreement with experimental observations.</description>
      <author>Jingwei Jiang, Zhongyuan Guo, Shao-Kang Deng, Jing Xue, Heng Liu, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Lihua Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing 3d Transition Metal Cation-Doped MRuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; As Durable Acidic Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts for PEM Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04096</link>
      <description>Panpan Sun, Zelong Qiao, Xiaobin Dong, Run Jiang, Zhong-Ting Hu, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398770378

                The continuous dissolution and oxidation of active sites in Ru-based electrocatalysts have greatly hindered their practical application in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE). In this work, we first used density functional theory (DFT) to calculate the dissolution energy of Ru in the 3d transition metal-doped MRuOx (M = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, and Zn) to evaluate their stability for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and screen out ZnRuOx as the best candidate. To confirm the theoretical predictions, we experimentally synthesized these MRuOx materials and found that ZnRuOx indeed displays robust acidic OER stability with a negligible decay of &#951;10 after 15 000 CV cycles. Of importance, using ZnRuOx as the anode, the PEMWE can run stably for 120 h at 200 mA cm&#8211;2. We also further uncover the stability mechanism of ZnRuOx, i.e., Zn atoms doped in the outside of ZnRuOx nanocrystal would form a "Zn-rich" shell, which effectively shortened average Ru&#8211;O bond lengths in ZnRuOx to strengthen the Ru&#8211;O interaction and therefore boosted intrinsic stability of ZnRuOx in acidic OER. In short, this work not only provides a new study paradigm of using DFT calculations to guide the experimental synthesis but also offers a proof-of-concept with 3d metal dopants as RuO2 stabilizer as a universal principle to develop high-durability Ru-based catalysts for PEMWE.</description>
      <author>Panpan Sun, Zelong Qiao, Xiaobin Dong, Run Jiang, Zhong-Ting Hu, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04096</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Electronic Factors behind the Electrochemical Stability of 3D-Metal Tungstates under Oxygen Evolution Reaction Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07301</link>
      <description>Abhishek Rajput, Pabitra K. Nayak, Dibyajyoti Ghosh, Biswarup Chakraborty, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398770868

                Transition metal tungstates (TMTs) possess a wolframite-like lattice structure and preferably form via an electrostatic interaction between a divalent transition metal cation (MII) and an oxyanion of tungsten ([WO4]2&#8211;). A unit cell of a TMT is primarily composed of two repeating units, [MO6]oh and [WO6]oh, which are held together via several M&#8722;&#956;2&#8211;O&#8211;W bridging links. The bond character (ionic or covalent) of this bridging unit determines the stability of the lattice and influences the electronic structure of the bulk TMT materials. Recently, TMTs have been successfully employed as an electrode material for various applications, including electrochemical water splitting. Despite the wide electrocatalytic applications of TMTs, the study of the structure&#8211;activity correlation and electronic factors responsible for in situ structural evolution to electroactive species during electrochemical reactions is still in its infancy. Herein, a series of TMTs, MIIWVIO4 (M = Mn/Fe/Co/Ni), have been prepared and employed as electrocatalysts to study the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under alkaline conditions and to scrutinize the role of transition metals in controlling the energetics of the formation of electroactive species. Since the [WO6]oh unit is common in the TMTs considered, the variation of the central atom of the corresponding [MO6]oh unit plays an intriguing role in controlling the electronic structure and stability of the lattice under anodic potential. Under the OER conditions, a potential-dependent structural transformation of MWO4 is noticed, where MnWO4 appears to be the most labile, whereas NiWO4 is stable up to a high anodic potential of &#8764;1.68 V (vs RHE). Potential-dependent hydrolytic [WO4]2&#8211; dissolution to form MOx active species, traced by in situ Raman and various spectro-/microscopic analyses, can directly be related to the electronic factors of the lattice, viz., crystal field splitting energy (CFSE) of MII in [MO6]oh, formation enthalpy (&#916;Hf), decomposition enthalpy (&#916;Hd), and Madelung factor associated with the MWO4 ionic lattice. Additionally, the magnitude of the L&#246;wdin and Bader charges on M of the M&#8722;&#956;2&#8211;O&#8211;W bond is directly related to the degree of ionicity or covalency in the MWO4 lattice, which indirectly influences the electronic structure and activity. The experimental results substantiated by the computational study explain the electrochemical activity of the TMTs with the help of various structural and electronic factors and bonding interactions in the lattice, which has never been realized. Therefore, the study presented here can be taken as a general guideline to correlate the reactivity to the structure of the inorganic materials.</description>
      <author>Abhishek Rajput, Pabitra K. Nayak, Dibyajyoti Ghosh, Biswarup Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic OER behavior of Bi-Fe-O system: An understanding from the perspective of the presence of oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00348a</link>
      <description>Shaswati Jyoti, Aditi Vijay, Umberto Terranova, Santosh K. Gupta, K. Sudarshan, Sonalika Vaidya, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398775430

                This study aims to understand and correlate the role of the nature and relative concentration of the oxygen vacancies with the trend observed in OER with the Bi-Fe-O system. To...</description>
      <author>Shaswati Jyoti, Aditi Vijay, Umberto Terranova, Santosh K. Gupta, K. Sudarshan, Sonalika Vaidya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00348a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Modulated Microscale Assembly of MOF Derived Iron/Nickel Selenide for Optimizing Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02452d</link>
      <description>Wenhao Guo, Huaipeng Pang, Xinyu Yang, Lin Li, Jinxiang Peng, Meiqi Zhao, Chun&#8208;Chao Hou, Yingmei Zhu, Fanlu Meng, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398775742

                Formulating hierarchical structures via systematic assembly of MOF-derived electrocatalysts emerge as a potent strategy to dictate the electrocatalytic efficacy of oxygen evolution reactions. However, research into the microscale implications of...</description>
      <author>Wenhao Guo, Huaipeng Pang, Xinyu Yang, Lin Li, Jinxiang Peng, Meiqi Zhao, Chun&#8208;Chao Hou, Yingmei Zhu, Fanlu Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02452d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel arrangement of active and ultra-stable electrocatalyst based on iron/nickel/cobalt oxy/hydroxides for continuous oxygen evolution from alkaline seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118377</link>
      <description>Mehdi Hamze, Milad Rezaei, Seyed Hadi Tabaian, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398785615

                This research offers novel ideas for development a new class of materials with enhanced OER kinetics utilizing an easy electrochemical deposition technique. Here, the Ti/CoNiyOx/FeOOH electrocatalyst was prepared in two steps. First, CoNiyOx thin film was anodically electrodeposited on an activated titanium substrate. Then iron oxyhydroxide (FeOOH) nanosheets were cathodically electrodeposited on the first layer. The properties of this electrocatalyst was evaluated and compared with some monolayer electrocatalysts using field emission scanning electron microscopy (FE-SEM), Raman, energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and electrochemical methods. The Ti/CoNiyOx/FeOOH electrode requires an overpotential less than 330 mV at 100 mA/cm2 with Tafel constant of only 23.7 mV/dec for OER. The Ti/CoNiyOx/FeOOH electrode delivered long-term electrochemical stability in a solution containing corrosive chloride ions for more than 90 h at a constant current density of 100 mA/cm2 (with less than 9 % potential increase). Overall seawater splitting using the synthesized Ti/CoNiyOx/FeOOH electrode was performed at a current density of 100 mA/cm2 by a voltage as low as 1.58 V. The exceptional activity was ascribed to the synergistic effects of high electrochemical active sites and appropriate charge transfer ability found in CoNiyOx/FeOOH junction.</description>
      <author>Mehdi Hamze, Milad Rezaei, Seyed Hadi Tabaian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-row transition metal carbonates catalyze the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction: Iron is master of them all</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00708e</link>
      <description>Iranna Udachyan, Jayesh T. Bhanushali, Tomer Zidki, Amir Mizrahi, Dan Meyerstein, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398787687

                In pursuing green hydrogen fuel, electrochemical water-splitting emerges as the optimal method. A critical challenge in advancing this process is identifying a cost-effective electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution on the anode....</description>
      <author>Iranna Udachyan, Jayesh T. Bhanushali, Tomer Zidki, Amir Mizrahi, Dan Meyerstein</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00708e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo&#8208;oxalate Organic Framework as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400225</link>
      <description>Haibo Bao, Min Wang, Lingxia Zhang, European journal of inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398794527

                Developing nonprecious metallic electrocatalysts for water splitting is of vital importance for sustainable environment and energy technologies. As for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), FeCo&#8208;based bimetallic catalysts have been found to act as promising candidates owing to their high intrinsic activity. Herein, a novel FeCo&#8208;oxalate organic framework was grown on nickel foam (FeCo&#8208;OA@NF) under mild conditions. The optimized electrocatalyst shows good OER performance with a low overpotential of 275 mV at the current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline environment, comparable to that of commercial Ru&#8208;based catalyst. Moreover, the quantification of produced oxygen by both gas chromatography and drainage method demonstrates nearly 100% Faradaic efficiency. Except for the contribution of Fe and Co species for the excellent OER catalytic activity, in&#8208;situ Raman spectroscopy reveals that the positive effect of oxalate coordination also makes a difference, which can possibly reduce electron transport resistance and provide more active sites. This work provides a promising approach for the preparation of alkaline oxygen evolution electrocatalysts with low&#8208;cost and high performance.</description>
      <author>Haibo Bao, Min Wang, Lingxia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co@CoO chiral nanostructures enabling efficient oxygen electrocatalysis by modulated spin-polarization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152545</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Ran, Mingsu Si, Daqiang Gao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399010167

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Ran, Mingsu Si, Daqiang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Reversible Sn&#8208;Air Battery Possessing the Ultra&#8208;Low Charging Potential with the Assistance of Light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407856</link>
      <description>Mingze Gao, Ruiya Wang, Xinxin L&#252;, Yanchen Fan, Ziyang Guo, Yonggang Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399011156

                Aqueous Sn&#8208;air batteries are attracting a great deal of interest in recent years due to the ultra&#8208;high safety, low cost, dendrite&#8208;free and highly reversible Sn anode. However, the slurry oxygen reduction/evolution reaction (ORR/OER) kinetics on the air cathodes seriously affect the Sn&#8208;air battery performances. Although various advanced catalysts have been developed, the charge overpotentials (~1000 mV) of these Sn&#8208;air batteries are still not satisfactory. Herein, iron oxide (Fe2O3) modified titanium dioxide (TiO2) nanorods with heterogeneous structure are firstly synthesized on Ti mesh (Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti), and the obtained Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti is further applied as catalytic electrodes for Sn&#8208;air batteries. The core&#8208;shell heterogeneous structure of Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti can effectively facilitate the conversion of electrochemical intermediates and separation of photo&#8208;excited electrons and holes to active oxygen&#8208;related reaction processes. DFT and experimental results also confirm that Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti can not only act as the electrocatalysts to improve ORR/OER properties, but also exhibit the superior photo&#8208;catalytic activity to promote charge kinetics. Hence, the Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti&#8208;based Sn&#8208;air batteries show ultra&#8208;low overpotential of ~40 mV, excellent rate capability and good cycling stability under light irradiation. This work will shed light on rational photo&#8208;assisted catalytic cathode design for new&#8208;type metal&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Mingze Gao, Ruiya Wang, Xinxin L&#252;, Yanchen Fan, Ziyang Guo, Yonggang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous NiMoP patchy nanospheres enfolded by rGO sheets for efficient oxygen evolution reaction and durable supercapacitor electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112187</link>
      <description>B.N. Vamsi Krishna, Obula Reddy Ankinapalli, Goli Nagaraju, Journal of energy storage. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399014361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B.N. Vamsi Krishna, Obula Reddy Ankinapalli, Goli Nagaraju</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution and Zinc&#8208;Air Battery Performance via Electronic Spin Modulation in Heterostructured Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202400572</link>
      <description>Linlin Yang, He Ren, Marc Botifoll, Yongcai Zhang, Yang Ding, Chong Di, Cong He, Ying Xu, Llu&#305;&#769;s Balcells, Jordi Arbiol, Yingtang Zhou, Andreu Cabot, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399019773

                Abstract Beyond optimizing electronic energy levels, the modulation of the electronic spin configuration is an effective strategy, often overlooked, to boost activity and selectivity in a range of catalytic reactions, including the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This electronic spin modulation is frequently accomplished using external magnetic fields, which makes it impractical for real applications. Herein, spin modulation is achieved by engineering Ni/MnFe 2 O 4 heterojunctions, whose surface is reconstructed into NiOOH/MnFeOOH during the OER. NiOOH/MnFeOOH shows a high spin state of Ni, which regulates the OH &#8208; and O 2 adsorption energy and enables spin alignment of oxygen intermediates. As a result, NiOOH/MnFeOOH electrocatalysts provide excellent OER performance with an overpotential of 261 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 . Besides, rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries based on Ni/MnFe 2 O 4 show a high open circuit potential of 1.56 V and excellent stability for more than 1000 cycles. This outstanding performance is rationalized using density functional theory calculations, which show that the optimal spin state of both Ni active sites and oxygen intermediates facilitates spin&#8208;selected charge transport, optimizes the reaction kinetics, and decreases the energy barrier to the evolution of oxygen. This study provides valuable insight into spin polarization modulation by heterojunctions enabling the design of next&#8208;generation OER catalysts with boosted performance. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Linlin Yang, He Ren, Marc Botifoll, Yongcai Zhang, Yang Ding, Chong Di, Cong He, Ying Xu, Llu&#305;&#769;s Balcells, Jordi Arbiol, Yingtang Zhou, Andreu Cabot</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202400572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron, Tungsten Dual&#8208;Doped Nickel Sulfide as Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311770</link>
      <description>Sangni Wang, Ding Yuan, Sihan Sun, Shuhan Huang, Yirong Wu, Lei Zhang, Shi Xue Dou, Huan Liu, Yihua Dou, Jiantie Xu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399021892

                Abstract Developing low&#8208;cost and highly efficient bifunctional catalysts for both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is a challenging problem in electrochemical overall water splitting. Here, iron, tungsten dual&#8208;doped nickel sulfide catalyst (Fe/W&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 ) is synthesized on the nickel foam, and it exhibits excellent OER and HER performance. As a result, the water electrolyze based on Fe/W&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 bifunctional catalyst illustrates 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.69 V (without iR &#8208;compensation) and highly durable overall water splitting over 100 h tested under 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . Experimental results and DFT calculations indicate that the synergistic interaction between Fe doping and Ni vacancy induced by W leaching during the in situ oxidation process can maximize exposed OER active sites on the reconstructed NiOOH species for accelerating OER kinetics, while the Fe/W dual&#8208;doping optimizes the electronic structure of Fe/W&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 and the binding strength of intermediates for boosting HER. This study unlocks the different promoting mechanisms of incorporating Fe and W for boosting the OER and HER activity of Ni 3 S 2 for water splitting, which provides significant guidance for designing high&#8208;performance bifunctional catalysts for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Sangni Wang, Ding Yuan, Sihan Sun, Shuhan Huang, Yirong Wu, Lei Zhang, Shi Xue Dou, Huan Liu, Yihua Dou, Jiantie Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atmospheric oxygen plasma-activated novel multicomponent transition metal phosphides (MnCoCu&#8211;P) for enhanced electrocatalytic water splitting to green hydrogen production: A universal catalyst across various pH electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.352</link>
      <description>Rakesh Kulkarni, Lakshmi Prasanna Lingamdinne, Janardhan Reddy Koduru, Siddulu Naidu Talapaneni, Zahid Husain Momin, Chandrika Ashwinikumar Pal, Yongki Choi, Yoon&#8208;Young Chang, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399022690

                Hydrogen (H2) is widely acknowledged as a promising, sustainable, and environmentally friendly energy carrier, offering numerous environmental benefits over conventional fossil fuels. However, the advancement of this technology is severely hindered by the scarcity of effective and robust catalysts for hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions activity. This study marks the inaugural fabrication of a hybrid tri-metallic electrocatalyst, termed MnCoCu&#8211;P, through hydrothermal synthesis. Subsequently, the catalyst undergoes atmospheric O2 plasma surface activation, aiming to amplify the efficiency of water splitting. The novel atmospheric O2 plasma-activated MnCoCu&#8211;P electrode outperforms the reported classic metal phosphides, and it outperformed the compared commercial Pt/C and RuO2 benchmark catalysts with outstanding performances of 0.488 and 1.20 V towards HER and OER at 1000 mA/cm2, respectively. Additionally, the MnCoCu&#8211;P (5 min) catalyst Faradic efficiency was calculated under alkaline conditions in 1.0 M KOH, and both the produced gas H2 and O2 match the theoretical and experimental calculated values well, indicating a high efficiency of almost 100%. In the 2-E system, MnCoCu&#8211;P (5 min)&#8214;MnCoCu&#8211;P (5 min) demonstrated remarkable performance by attaining a current density of 1000 mA/cm2 at low total cell voltages of 1.93 V and outperforming the benchmark Pt/C&#8214;RuO2 electrode system. On the other hand, the MnCoCu&#8211;P electrode possesses excellent activity under industrial conditions at 6.0 M @ 60 &#176;C exhibited 1.89 V at 1000 mA/cm2 and performs well in natural water systems. Moreover, the 5 min O2 plasma-treated MnCoCu&#8211;P&#8214;MnCoCu&#8211;P electrodes showed improved activity in all the pH solutions which makes it one of the potential candidates for commercial application in the future.</description>
      <author>Rakesh Kulkarni, Lakshmi Prasanna Lingamdinne, Janardhan Reddy Koduru, Siddulu Naidu Talapaneni, Zahid Husain Momin, Chandrika Ashwinikumar Pal, Yongki Choi, Yoon&#8208;Young Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering heterostructured and hierarchical CoP/CoFeP nanosheet for effective oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline freshwater and seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.342</link>
      <description>Mingxing Chen, Zhiwei Zhu, Xue Li, Jing Li, Enbo Shangguan, &#25964;&#27835; &#23721;&#23822;, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399027924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingxing Chen, Zhiwei Zhu, Xue Li, Jing Li, Enbo Shangguan, &#25964;&#27835; &#23721;&#23822;</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile fabrication of nickel-cobalt oxide for efficient oxygen evolution reaction from ammonia leaching solution of spent lithium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.356</link>
      <description>Cheng Yang, Gaojie Chen, Liang Xu, Yongpan Tian, Zhuo Zhao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399027942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Yang, Gaojie Chen, Liang Xu, Yongpan Tian, Zhuo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination environment modulation to optimize d-orbit arrangement of Mn-based MOF electrocatalyst for lithium-oxygen battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103519</link>
      <description>Xinxiang Wang, Haoyang Xu, Xiaojuan Wen, Guilei Tian, Sheng Liu, Fengxia Fan, Pengfei Liu, Chenrui Zeng, Chuan Wang, Shuhan Wang, Ruixin Zheng, Chaozhu Shu, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399034437

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinxiang Wang, Haoyang Xu, Xiaojuan Wen, Guilei Tian, Sheng Liu, Fengxia Fan, Pengfei Liu, Chenrui Zeng, Chuan Wang, Shuhan Wang, Ruixin Zheng, Chaozhu Shu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion of the oxygen evolution reaction by introducing MoS2 into CoFe LDH via improved charge transfer and electrocatalytical activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131993</link>
      <description>Yongping Luo, Yuchen Duan, Yu Xie, Yongya Wang, Xianchan Li, Yike Liu, Shunjian Xu, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399036857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongping Luo, Yuchen Duan, Yu Xie, Yongya Wang, Xianchan Li, Yike Liu, Shunjian Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically thin iridium nanosheets for oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01117a</link>
      <description>Gea&#8208;Jae Joo, Younghyun Wy, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Bon Seung Goo, Yongmin Kwon, Jin Hong Kim, Jin Sik Choi, Sang Woo Han, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399051421

                2D nanostructures of noble metals hold great potential for developing efficient electrocatalysts due to their high atom efficiency associated with their large specific surface area and abundant active sites. Here,...</description>
      <author>Gea&#8208;Jae Joo, Younghyun Wy, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Bon Seung Goo, Yongmin Kwon, Jin Hong Kim, Jin Sik Choi, Sang Woo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01117a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Evolution Reaction on Nickel Oxyhydroxide&#8217;s Surface: Toward a Super Catalyst for Oxygen-Evolution Reaction with Ultralow Overpotentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00888</link>
      <description>Mohammad Khateri, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054326

                This study challenges the conventional understanding of nickel (hydr)oxides as inefficient catalysts for oxygen-evolution reaction (OER) under alkaline conditions. It is demonstrated that nickel oxyhydroxide, characterized by several methods, forms on Ni foam's surface and exhibits OER activity at extremely low potentials. This activity becomes particularly notable at the peak of Ni(II) oxidation to Ni(III), which follows charge accumulation. Remarkably, this mesoporous, super hydrophilic, and high-surface-area catalyst requires a minimal overpotential, as low as 130 mV, with a current density of 200 &#956;A/cm2, and displays a Tafel slope of 77.9 mV/decade in alkaline media (0.10 M KOH). Considering the amount of oxygen produced and the concentration of redox-active Ni ions in the redox peak region, the turnover frequency was calculated to be 1.1 &#215; 10&#8211;3 s&#8211;1 at a potential of 1.36 V. Achieving these parameters at such a remarkably low overpotential holds significant promise. This study also proposes a mechanism for OER at this low overpotential, based on in situ Raman spectroscopic analysis of the Ni(II) to Ni(III) oxidation peak and the OER region. The observed low overpotential for OER can be attributed to the complex interplay between the OER process and the phenomenon of charge accumulation. All these factors result in an exceptionally low overpotential for OER. Our findings hold profound implications for the development of highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts for OER, particularly in water-splitting applications. This research not only expands our understanding of nickel oxyhydroxide as a potential OER catalyst but also opens avenues for future exploration in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Khateri, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Activation through Deep Oxidation of Co4N by Jahn&#8722;Teller&#8208;active Dopants for Improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405839</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054838

                Triggering the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism is crucial for improving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, because it could bypass the scaling relation limitation associated with the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism through the directly formation of oxygen&#8722;oxygen bond. High&#8208;valence transition metal sites are favorable for activating the lattice oxygen, but the deep oxidation of pre&#8208;catalysts suffers from a high thermodynamic barrier. Here, taking advantage of the Jahn&#8722;Teller (J&#8722;T) distortion induced structural instability, we incorporate high&#8208;spin Mn3+ (t2g3eg1) dopant into Co4N. Mn dopants enable a surface structural transformation from Co4N to CoOOH, and finally to CoO2, as observed by various in&#8208;situ spectroscopic investigations. Furthermore, the reconstructed surface on Mn doped Co4N triggers the lattice oxygen activation, as evidenced experimentally by pH&#8208;dependent OER, tetramethylammonium cation adsorption and on&#8208;line electrochemical mass spectrometry measurements of 18O&#8208;labelled catalysts. In general, this work not only offers the introducing J&#8722;T effect approach to regulate the structural transition, but also provides an understanding about the influence of catalyst&#8217;s electronic configuration on determining the reaction route, which may inspire the design of more efficient catalysts with activated lattice oxygen.</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Activation through Deep Oxidation of Co4N by Jahn&#8722;Teller&#8208;active Dopants for Improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405839</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054892

                Triggering the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism is crucial for improving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, because it could bypass the scaling relation limitation associated with the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism through the directly formation of oxygen&#8722;oxygen bond. High&#8208;valence transition metal sites are favorable for activating the lattice oxygen, but the deep oxidation of pre&#8208;catalysts suffers from a high thermodynamic barrier. Here, taking advantage of the Jahn&#8722;Teller (J&#8722;T) distortion induced structural instability, we incorporate high&#8208;spin Mn3+ (t2g3eg1) dopant into Co4N. Mn dopants enable a surface structural transformation from Co4N to CoOOH, and finally to CoO2, as observed by various in&#8208;situ spectroscopic investigations. Furthermore, the reconstructed surface on Mn doped Co4N triggers the lattice oxygen activation, as evidenced experimentally by pH&#8208;dependent OER, tetramethylammonium cation adsorption and on&#8208;line electrochemical mass spectrometry measurements of 18O&#8208;labelled catalysts. In general, this work not only offers the introducing J&#8722;T effect approach to regulate the structural transition, but also provides an understanding about the influence of catalyst&#8217;s electronic configuration on determining the reaction route, which may inspire the design of more efficient catalysts with activated lattice oxygen.</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Bulk and Surface Engineering for Expeditious and Durable Reversible Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cells Air Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403998</link>
      <description>Xi Chen, Na Yu, Yufei Song, Tong Liu, Hengyue Xu, Daqin Guan, Zheng Li, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Jaka Sunarso, Francesco Ciucci, Meng Ni, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399055707

                Abstract Reversible protonic ceramic electrochemical cells (R&#8208;PCECs) offer the potential for high&#8208;efficiency power generation and green hydrogen production at intermediate temperatures. However, the commercial viability of R&#8208;PCECs is hampered by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) within conventional air electrodes operating at reduced temperatures. To address this challenge, we introduce a novel approach based on the simultaneous optimization of bulk&#8208;phase metal&#8208;oxygen bonds and in&#8208;situ formation of a metal oxide nano&#8208;catalyst surface modification. This strategy is designed to expedite the ORR/OER electrocatalytic activity of air electrodes exhibiting triple (O 2&#8722; , H + , e &#8722; ) conductivity. Specifically, our engineered air electrode nanocomposite&#8208;Ba(Co 0.4 Fe 0.4 Zr 0.1 Y 0.1 ) 0.95 Ni 0.05 F 0.1 O 2.9&#8208;&#948; demonstrates remarkable ORR/OER catalytic activity and exceptional durability in R&#8208;PCECs. This is evidenced by significantly improved peak power density from 626 mW cm &#8722;2 to 996 mW cm &#8722;2 and highly stable reversibility over a 100&#8208;hour cycling period. This research offers a rational design strategy to achieve high&#8208;performance R&#8208;PCEC air electrodes with superior operational activity and stability for efficient and sustainable energy conversion and storage. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Xi Chen, Na Yu, Yufei Song, Tong Liu, Hengyue Xu, Daqin Guan, Zheng Li, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Jaka Sunarso, Francesco Ciucci, Meng Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403998</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-4f as an electron-modulation reservoir weakening Fe-O bond to induce iron vacancies in CeFevNi hydroxide for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.205</link>
      <description>Le Gao, Yue Yao, Yun Chen, Jiajun Huang, Yiling Ma, Wenbin Chen, Huan Li, Yu Wang, Lishan Jia, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399067370

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Le Gao, Yue Yao, Yun Chen, Jiajun Huang, Yiling Ma, Wenbin Chen, Huan Li, Yu Wang, Lishan Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of CuO -decorated TiO2 nanoparticles via oxygen-limited pyrolysis of Cu(II) complex for efficient photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113199</link>
      <description>Chao Yang, Xueying Zhao, Yunlong Zhao, Chenchen Ji, Ren&#8208;Jang Wu, Lu Wang, Xueqing Shao, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399068682

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Yang, Xueying Zhao, Yunlong Zhao, Chenchen Ji, Ren&#8208;Jang Wu, Lu Wang, Xueqing Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous&#8208;Spin&#8208;Polarized 2D &#960;&#8208;d Conjugated Frameworks Towards Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401987</link>
      <description>Won Seok Lee, Hiroaki Maeda, Yen&#8208;Ting Kuo, Koki Muraoka, Naoya Fukui, Kenji Takada, Sono Sasaki, Hiroshi Nishihara, Akira Nakayama, Hong&#8208;Kang Tian, Hiroshi Nishihara, Ken Sakaushi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399070034

                Abstract Alternative strategies to design sustainable&#8208;element&#8208;based electrocatalysts enhancing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics are demanded to develop affordable yet high&#8208;performance water&#8208;electrolyzers for green hydrogen production. Here, it is demonstrated that the spontaneous&#8208;spin&#8208;polarized 2D &#960;&#8208;d conjugated framework comprising abundant elements of nickel and iron with a ratio of Ni:Fe = 1:4 with benzenehexathiol linker (BHT) can improve OER kinetics by its unique electronic property. Among the bimetallic NiFe x:y &#8208;BHTs with various ratios with Ni:Fe = x:y, the NiFe 1:4 &#8208;BHT exhibits the highest OER activity. The NiFe 1:4 &#8208;BHT shows a specific current density of 140 A g &#8722;1 at the overpotential of 350 mV. This performance is one of the best activities among state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art non&#8208;precious OER electrocatalysts and even comparable to that of the platinum&#8208;group&#8208;metals of RuO 2 and IrO 2 . The density functional theory calculations uncover that introducing Ni into the homometallic Fe&#8208;BHT (e.g., Ni:Fe = 0:1) can emerge a spontaneous&#8208;spin&#8208;polarized state. Thus, this material can achieve improved OER kinetics with spin&#8208;polarization which previously required external magnetic fields. This work shows that a rational design of 2D &#960;&#8208;d conjugated frameworks can be a powerful strategy to synthesize promising electrocatalysts with abundant elements for a wide spectrum of next&#8208;generation energy devices.</description>
      <author>Won Seok Lee, Hiroaki Maeda, Yen&#8208;Ting Kuo, Koki Muraoka, Naoya Fukui, Kenji Takada, Sono Sasaki, Hiroshi Nishihara, Akira Nakayama, Hong&#8208;Kang Tian, Hiroshi Nishihara, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401987</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Water Oxidation Catalytic Activity of a Mn-Based Magnetic Metal&#8211;Organic Framework: The Role of Proton Conductivity and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01078</link>
      <description>Sayan Saha, Avik De, Soumadip Banerjee, Abhijit K. Das, C. Andr&#233; Ohlin, Raju Mondal, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399071995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sayan Saha, Avik De, Soumadip Banerjee, Abhijit K. Das, C. Andr&#233; Ohlin, Raju Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Engineering of 3D Self&#8208;Supported Bifunctional Oxygen Electrodes for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries and Fuel Cell Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400347</link>
      <description>Milan Babu Poudel, Mannix P. Balanay, Prakash Chandra Lohani, Karthikeyan Sekar, Dong Jin Yoo, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399077859

                Abstract The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are cornerstone half reactions involved in many renewable energy technologies. High&#8208;density single&#8208;atom catalysts maximize the atom utilization and isolated active sites. Furthermore, introduction of pyri&#8208;N into the carbon&#8208;based nanostructures as an oxygen electrocatalyst creates an abundance of active sites. Here, an innovative strategy is reported based on atomic scale dispersion of Co atoms into the pyri&#8208;N enriched carbon nanotube encapsulated Ni nanoparticles grown on 3D electrospun carbon nanofiber nano&#8208;assemblies. Notably, the Co SA Ni&#8208;NCNT/CNF electrocatalyst exhibited excellent OER and ORR activity in terms of low overpotentials and higher half&#8208;wave potentials. The atomically distributed Co allows the maximum exposure of active sites on the pyri&#8208;N dominated multidimensional carbon skeleton, and synergistic effects with Ni nanoparticles greatly reduced the delocalization around the metal centers and provided an ideal environment for interactions with oxygen intermediates, thus facilitating the 4e &#8722; pathway, as evidenced by the DFT calculations. Moreover, Zn&#8208;air batteries using a Co SA Ni&#8208;NCNT/CNF air cathode exhibited a high&#8208;power density and admirable specific capacity. This studies may provide an avenue for the rational modulation of single&#8208;atom catalysts and cost&#8208;effective, large&#8208;scale synthesis of bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries and anion exchange membrane fuel cell.</description>
      <author>Milan Babu Poudel, Mannix P. Balanay, Prakash Chandra Lohani, Karthikeyan Sekar, Dong Jin Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress on electronic and active site engineering of cobalt&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.573</link>
      <description>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Jia Wang, Tingting Wang, Jian Ju, Yizhong Lu, Wei Chen, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399077872

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting has been identified as a potential candidate for producing clean hydrogen energy with zero carbon emission. However, the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction on the anode side of the water&#8208;splitting device significantly hinders its practical applications. Generally, the efficiency of oxygen evolution processes depends greatly on the availability of cost&#8208;effective catalysts with high activity and selectivity. In recent years, extensive theoretical and experimental studies have demonstrated that cobalt (Co)&#8208;based nanomaterials, especially low&#8208;dimensional Co&#8208;based nanomaterials with a huge specific surface area and abundant unsaturated active sites, have emerged as versatile electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions, and thus, great progress has been made in the rational design and synthesis of Co&#8208;based nanomaterials for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions. Considering the remarkable progress in this area, in this timely review, we highlight the most recent developments in Co&#8208;based nanomaterials relating to their dimensional control, defect regulation (conductivity), electronic structure regulation, and so forth. Furthermore, a brief conclusion about recent progress achieved in oxygen evolution on Co&#8208;based nanomaterials, as well as an outlook on future research challenges, is given.</description>
      <author>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Jia Wang, Tingting Wang, Jian Ju, Yizhong Lu, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoengineered Cobalt Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110946</link>
      <description>R. Venkatachalam, Sunil Mehla, Lathe A. Jones, Suresh K. Bhargava, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399081051

                The alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a bottleneck in green hydrogen production owing to its slow reaction kinetics and low catalytic efficiencies of earth abundant electrocatalysts in the alkaline OER reaction. This study investigates the OER performance of hierarchically porous cobalt electrocatalysts synthesized using the dynamic hydrogen bubble templating (DHBT) method. Characterization studies revealed that electrocatalysts synthesized under optimized conditions using the DHBT method consisted of cobalt nanosheets, and hierarchical porosity with macropores distributed in a honeycomb network and mesopores distributed between cobalt nanosheets. Moreover, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy studies revealed the presence of Co(OH)2 as the predominant surface cobalt species while Raman studies revealed the presence of the cubic Co3O4 phase in the synthesized electrocatalysts. The best performing electrocatalyst required only 360 mV of overpotential to initiate a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, exhibited a Tafel slope of 37 mV dec&#8722;1, and stable OER activity over 24 h. The DHBT method offers a facile, low cost and rapid synthesis approach for preparation for highly efficient cobalt electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>R. Venkatachalam, Sunil Mehla, Lathe A. Jones, Suresh K. Bhargava</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling electroplating sludge into bioengineering-enabled highly stable dual-site Fe-Ni2P@C electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6719-x</link>
      <description>Jiawen Liu, Zhi&#8208;Liang Zuo, Feng Gao, K. Yi, Jai-Ming Lin, Mengye Wang, Lin Zhang, Haibo Feng, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399099589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawen Liu, Zhi&#8208;Liang Zuo, Feng Gao, K. Yi, Jai-Ming Lin, Mengye Wang, Lin Zhang, Haibo Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6719-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Investigations on CoFe2O4@Co3O4 Nano-composite as an Enhanced Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00877-8</link>
      <description>Xihuan Zhang, Abdelhadi El Jaouhari, Chunyue Li, Maimoune Adnane, Wanying Liu, Abderrahman Mellalou, Fouad Ghamouss, Yuanhua Lin, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399105282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xihuan Zhang, Abdelhadi El Jaouhari, Chunyue Li, Maimoune Adnane, Wanying Liu, Abderrahman Mellalou, Fouad Ghamouss, Yuanhua Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00877-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g</link>
      <description>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao, RSC advances. 14(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399110116

                In this study, we explord the catalytic activity of NiCoFe_phosphide nanosheets as highly active and stable catalysts for OER. Electrochemical analysis exhibits a low overpotential of 259 mV in (1 M KOH), achieving a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a low Tafel slope of 50.47 mV dec &#8722;1 .</description>
      <author>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dy2NiRuO6 perovskite with high activity and durability for the oxygen evolution reaction in acidic electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta06788b</link>
      <description>Isabel Rodr&#237;guez-Garc&#237;a, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, Dmitry Galyamin, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Paula Kayser, Mohamed Abdel Salam, J. A. Alonso, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Sergio Rojas, M. Retuerto, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399110197

                Ru mixed oxides may be suitable materials to replace state-of-the-art Ir-based catalysts in the anode of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. To do that, the activity and especially the durability of...</description>
      <author>Isabel Rodr&#237;guez-Garc&#237;a, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, Dmitry Galyamin, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Paula Kayser, Mohamed Abdel Salam, J. A. Alonso, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Sergio Rojas, M. Retuerto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta06788b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replication Data for: Correlative operando microscopy of oxygen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/tnthxs</link>
      <description>J. Tyler Mefford, Harvard Dataverse. None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4398813804

                This dataset contains source data for Figures 1-5 and Supplementary Information Figures S2-S12 from "Correlative operando microscopy of oxygen evolution electrocatalysts." Data for each figure is provided in .xlsx files with filenames corresponding to the figure labels in the publication.</description>
      <author>J. Tyler Mefford</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/tnthxs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on fundamentals for designing stable ruthenium-based catalysts for the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60013-6</link>
      <description>Wangyan Gou, Yichen Wang, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu, Cuihua xuebao/Chinese journal of catalysis. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398224626

                Clean and renewable energy is generally localized and intermittent. Thus, energy conversion and storage technologies are necessary to compensate for these shortcomings. Electrolytic water splitting presents a reliable and promising energy technology for producing high purity hydrogen (H2). Among the platinum metals, ruthenium (Ru) has gained significant attentions as it generally outperforms commercial catalysts in terms of activity at a more affordable price. Although great progress has been made in improving the catalytic activity of Ru-based catalysts, stability remains a major challenge hindering their practical applications. To this end, this review introduces the fundamentals of the stability over Ru-based catalysts for water splitting, including the reaction mechanisms of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), measurement methods and evaluation criteria, as well as deactivation mechanisms. Moreover, the up-to-date advances of representative strategies for improving HER and OER stability of Ru-based catalysts are further discussed with respect to specific design principles and underlying mechanisms. Ultimately, insights into the challenges and opportunities for Ru-based electrocatalysts are provided to promote the development of next-generation Ru-based catalysts with exceptional stability. This review aims at guiding the design and synthesis of superior catalysts, generating increased interest among researchers, and stimulating further advanced research.</description>
      <author>Wangyan Gou, Yichen Wang, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-2067(24)60013-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retaining the self-released chalcogenate at reconstructed cobalt sites by self-transformed carbonate regulation for boosted oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.021</link>
      <description>Jing Zhao, Zhe Xue, Qing Wang, Xiangyang Li, Shoujie Liu, Xu Zhao, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398784867

                The in-situ generated oxyanions at electrochemically reconstructed catalysts from metal-based non-oxide compounds have been proven to significantly accelerate oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics. However, it remains a challenge to retain these self-released oxyanions at reconstructed catalysts, hindering its utilization as a tool to develop efficient OER catalysts. Here, we demonstrate a versatile self-transformed carbonate regulation strategy to efficiently retain the self-released chalcogenate at Co oxyhydroxides reconstructed from carbon-incorporated Co selenides under OER conditions. These self-transformed CO32&#8722; can induce electron accumulation and narrow d bond at Co sites to facilitate the Co 3d&#8211;O 2p orbital hybridization between Co sites and SeOx2&#8722; for enhanced SeOx2&#8722; retention, which can accelerate the rate-limiting step for *OOH formation during OER. Relative to CoOOH-SeOx2&#8722; with limited SeOx2&#8722; residues, CoOOH-CO32&#8722;/SeOx2&#8722; with elevated SeOx2&#8722; retention by CO32&#8722; regulation exhibited a 5.6-fold increase in current density and a remarkable lower Tafel slope towards OER. This strategy paves a rational avenue to design efficient catalysts for electrooxidation reactions through finely regulating self-released oxyanions at reconstructed structures.</description>
      <author>Jing Zhao, Zhe Xue, Qing Wang, Xiangyang Li, Shoujie Liu, Xu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-induced hollow binary metal-organic framework derived Fe-doped cobalt-carbon nanomaterials for oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.168</link>
      <description>Haitao Ni, Shaojie Xu, Rong Lin, Yi Ding, Jinjie Qian, Journal of colloid and interface science. 671(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398249855

                There is significant anticipation for high-efficiency and cost-effective non-precious metal-based catalysts to advance the industrial application of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for hydrogen production. This study introduces an efficient strategy that utilizes ligand-induced metal-organic framework (MOF) building blocks for the synthesis of hollow binary zeolitic imidazolate frameworks 67 (ZIF-67) and Prussian blue analogues (PBAs) (ZIF-67@PBA) heterostructures through a hybrid MOF-on-MOF approach. Manipulating the Co</description>
      <author>Haitao Ni, Shaojie Xu, Rong Lin, Yi Ding, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.168</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and oxygen-evolution-reaction performance of sulphur-doped flower-like NiFe-based composites supported on biomass porous carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.2024.192.693</link>
      <description>Qihong Lou, Shan Zhong, Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, Digest Journal of Nanomaterials and Biostructures. 19(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398239346

                Hydrogen gas generated through water electrolysis can replace fossil fuels. Thus, developing cost-effective and efficient water-splitting electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction is highly important. Herein, biomass-porous-carbon-supported sulphur-doped flower-like NiFe-based alloy composites are prepared using an in situ impregnation&#8211;heat treatment technology. The spherical flower (diameter &#8776; 1 &#956;m, petal thickness &#8776; 20 nm) main components are Ni0.5Fe0.5 and Fe9Ni9S16. The 800 &#176;C heat-treated catalyst demonstrates outstanding catalytic performance in oxygen evolution reactions. At a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 , it exhibits a minimal overpotential of 298.62 mV</description>
      <author>Qihong Lou, Shan Zhong, Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.2024.192.693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopic Investigations of Complex Electronic Interactions by Elemental Doping and Material Compositing of Cobalt Oxide for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405384</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399080117

                Abstract Doping and compositing are two universal design strategies used to engineer the electronic state of a material and mitigate its disadvantages. These two strategies are extensively applied to design efficient electrocatalysts for water splitting. Using cobalt oxide (CoO) as a model catalyst, it is proven that the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance can be progressively improved, first by Fe&#8208;doping to form Fe&#8208;CoO solid solution, and further by the addition of CeO 2 to produce a Fe&#8208;CoO/CeO 2 composite. X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) reveals that distinct electronic interactions are induced by the processes of doping and compositing. Fe&#8208;doping of CoO can break down the structural symmetry, changing the electronic structure of both Co and O species at the surface and decreasing the flat&#8208;band potential (V fb ). In comparison, subsequent compositing of Fe&#8208;CoO with CeO 2 induces negligible electronic changes in the Fe&#8208;CoO (as seen in ex situ characterizations), but significantly modifies the oxidative transformations of both Co and Fe under OER conditions. The spectroscopic investigations reveal that Fe&#8208;doping and CeO 2 compositing play different roles in modifying the electronic properties of CoO in its pristine state and during OER catalysis, in return, providing useful guidance for the design of more efficient electrocatalysts using these two strategies.</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel catalysed and decorated CO2 laser induced graphene from bio-waste-derived thermoset polymer as a high-performance catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119275</link>
      <description>Suparna Saha, Shweta Hiwase, Sukanta K. Mondal, A. R. A. S. Deshmukh, Satishchandra Ogale, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398755838

                In this work, we examine carbonization of natural product derived thermoset polymer by CO2 laser-assisted direct-write transient pyrolysis process without and with the addition of nickel salt for possible catalytic intervention. We find that nickel indeed plays an interesting and crucial role in significantly enhancing the graphene content in the laser processed sample (Ni-LIG) retaining its few monolayer character. The unique and significant advantages of laser induced transient pyrolysis process are: a) it is a direct write process enabling in-process functionality patterning, if needed, b) it is highly energy economic because energy is localized and directed to the desired process zone, c) being a transient process it can be implemented under ambient conditions, and d) it creates distinctly different microstructure as compared to furnace annealing. It was further observed that upon incorporation of the Ni-(CH3COO)2.4H2O salt in the polymer the LIG process reduces it to Ni (111), which in turn catalyses the nucleation process and lowers the activation barrier for graphene formation by annealing the defects. Moreover, due to the very low lattice mismatch between Ni (111) and graphene facilitates its high growth quality. The concurrent decoration of Ni/NiO on graphene is also shown to promote water dissociation as well as adsorption of water oxidation intermediates. This leads to an impressive value of the overpotential for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at 10 mA/cm2 of only 290 mV in 1M KOH. Additionally, the catalytic capacity and structure remain stable after 30 h of continuous work in 1M KOH.</description>
      <author>Suparna Saha, Shweta Hiwase, Sukanta K. Mondal, A. R. A. S. Deshmukh, Satishchandra Ogale</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions by Using the V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CT&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;@Sm Nanocomposite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00993</link>
      <description>Eisha Mazhar, Irfan Ali, Saif Ullah Awan, Syed Rizwan, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398318329

                The rational design and advancement of highly efficient and readily available bifunctional electrocatalysts are crucial in pursuing renewable-energy-driven electrocatalytic water splitting as a potential strategy for clean hydrogen generation. Researchers have increasingly focused on transition-metal carbides (MXenes) in the past decade due to their distinctive properties, particularly their potential as cocatalysts in electrocatalytic systems. Herein, we have presented a method for surface modification of V2CTx MXene to create an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for water-splitting applications. The desired results are achieved through the intercalation of rare earth element Sm (samarium) with V2CTx MXene by the sonochemical method. The anchoring of samarium on the surface of two-dimensional MXene served as a conductive medium, and their extensive interfacial effects enabled the fast transportation of ions by creating short and conductive channels at the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interface by exposing more active sites. The OER and HER electrocatalytic activity of the electrode material was investigated by using a 1.0 M KOH electrolyte. The results showed that the Sm@V2CTx nanocomposite (referred to as V1) exhibited exceptional performance for the OER with an overpotential of 350 mV (vs RHE) delivered at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 100 mV/dec. For HER, the system is capable of delivering an overpotential of 236 mV (vs RHE) and fast kinetics, having a Tafel slope of 88 mV/dec. Furthermore, it exhibits excellent stability for over 14 h. This research showcases the capability of earth-abundant MXene materials and the modification of their electrocatalytic activity to act as a foundation for creating a broad range of high-performance, environmentally sustainable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Eisha Mazhar, Irfan Ali, Saif Ullah Awan, Syed Rizwan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing NiO/Co3O4/KNbO3 heterostructure with NiO and Co3O4 particles coupled on KNO3 cubes for high-performance urea-assisted alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.435</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liping Du, Jingwen Chen, Jing Tan, Xuemin Bai, Yahui Chen, Jikui Zhu, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399067586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liping Du, Jingwen Chen, Jing Tan, Xuemin Bai, Yahui Chen, Jikui Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cauliflower-Like Pd/Moc||Mo2c/C Heterostructure as an Efficient Trifunctional Catalyst for Formic Acid Oxidation, Hydrogen Evolution, and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4844553</link>
      <description>Ting Wang, Yuquan Feng, SU Jian-jun, Wei Qi, Xin Run, Jiannan Cai, Zhang Xiao-feng, Qiufeng Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399109585

                Developing efficient Pd-based multi-functional catalytic materials for formic acid oxidation reaction (FAO), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) remains a significant challenge. Transition metal interstitial carbides (TMICs) have emerged as promising candidates for electrocatalysis due to their unique structure. Cauliflower-shaped Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C nanostructured heterogeneous composites were prepared using a high-temperature pyrolysis and ethanol reduction method. The resulting materials exhibit high electrocatalytic performance towards FAO, HER, and ORR. In terms of FAO, the mass activity of Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C is 1.87 A mgPd-1, which is 2.75 times higher than that of Pd/C (0.68 A mgPd-1). As for the HER, a much lower overpotential of -28 mV is required to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm-2 compared to Pd/C(-40 mV). Fortunately, Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C also exhibits excellent ORR activity with a half-wave potential of 0.798 V and the maximum current density of approximately 5.73 mA cm-2 in alkaline electrolytes. The use of heterostructures enables the rearrangement of surface electrons, modifies active sites, and promotes the interaction between MoC||Mo2C/C and Pd. This leads to significant multifunctional catalytic performance. These findings could lead to the development of other noble metal-based materials loaded on intermetallic compounds with stable and effective electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Ting Wang, Yuquan Feng, SU Jian-jun, Wei Qi, Xin Run, Jiannan Cai, Zhang Xiao-feng, Qiufeng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4844553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of phenols evolution during pyrolysis of Shendong coal macerals swelled with oxygen-containing organic solvents: Experimental and DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152648</link>
      <description>Linyang Wang, Qing Yao, Rui Cao, Lei He, Ming Sun, Xiaoxun Ma, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399068710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linyang Wang, Qing Yao, Rui Cao, Lei He, Ming Sun, Xiaoxun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product characterization and pore structure evolution of a tar-rich coal following pyrolysis under nitrogen, steam/nitrogen, and oxygen/nitrogen atmospheres</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106563</link>
      <description>Zhibing Chang, Chuchu Wang, Wenhao Kuang, Ying Tang, Xiaodan Wu, Shuqin Li, Journal of analytical and applied pyrolysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399071752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhibing Chang, Chuchu Wang, Wenhao Kuang, Ying Tang, Xiaodan Wu, Shuqin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterojunction catalysts of ultra-thin carbon layer activated Platinum nanoparticles for bifunctional pH-universal hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.265</link>
      <description>Hao Yu, Dongfang Chen, Guangxin Yang, Yuan Yuan, Huiyu Song, Shanwen Wang, Pucheng Pei, Xiao&#8211;Ming Xu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399007201

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Yu, Dongfang Chen, Guangxin Yang, Yuan Yuan, Huiyu Song, Shanwen Wang, Pucheng Pei, Xiao&#8211;Ming Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Investigation of Lattice Oxygen Loss from Preferentially Faceted Electrodeposited LiCoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; via Scanning Electrochemical Microscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4f22</link>
      <description>Abhiroop Mishra, Jiangli Lin, Beniamin Zahiri, Paul V. Braun, Joaqu&#237;n Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;L&#243;pez, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398199031

                Abstract Lattice oxygen loss from transition metal oxide cathodes in Li-ion batteries (LiBs) is a key factor responsible in their gradual capacity decline over time. Understanding and mitigating this phenomenon is crucial for the development of next-generation LiBs. The effect of various parameters on lattice oxygen loss, such as cathode chemical composition, has been studied extensively. However, there is a lack of experimental investigation into the lattice oxygen stability across different crystallographic facets within the same cathode composition. Here, we employed in situ scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM) to investigate oxygen evolution from preferentially faceted, electrodeposited LiCoO2 cathodes. Samples predominantly exposing the (003) basal planes and the (101), (102), (110) fast Li-ion diffusing facets exhibited oxygen evolution at potentials exceeding 3.5 V vs Li+/Li. Finite element simulations helped quantify the flux of oxygen evolution on the first charge cycle to 33&#177;5 pmol/cm2s for the basal plane and 37&#177;9 pmol/cm2s for the faceted samples at potentials above 4 V based on single spot measurements. However, spatially resolved measurements showed that faceted samples exhibited significant heterogeneity in their oxygen evolution, reaching twofold values compared to the basal plane samples at potentials beyond 4.5 V.</description>
      <author>Abhiroop Mishra, Jiangli Lin, Beniamin Zahiri, Paul V. Braun, Joaqu&#237;n Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;L&#243;pez</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4f22</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Engineering Assisted CoNiP Nanosheet Arrays for Electrochemical Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00114a</link>
      <description>Linfei Zhang, Wenjing Ren, C Z Liu, Na He, Xinru He, Chunxian Guo, Yulin Jiang, Yong Hu, Shengliang Zhong, Materials advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398775816

                Electrochemical overall water splitting is a green, environmentally friendly, and efficient hydrogen production method that involves two half-reactions: oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Due to the...</description>
      <author>Linfei Zhang, Wenjing Ren, C Z Liu, Na He, Xinru He, Chunxian Guo, Yulin Jiang, Yong Hu, Shengliang Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00114a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Bi-functional Oxide Electrode for Selective Oxidative C-C Cleavage of Glycerol to Formate and Synchronized Green Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00434e</link>
      <description>Arindam Saha, Vasantharadevi Murugiah, Ravi Ranjan, Inderjeet Chauhan, Kshirodra Kumar Patra, Himanshu Bajpai, Avishek Saha, Chinnakonda S. Gopinath, Sustainable energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398225373

                Alkaline water electrolysis is a mature method to produce green hydrogen, but it is at a significantly high cost due to the high overpotential for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However,...</description>
      <author>Arindam Saha, Vasantharadevi Murugiah, Ravi Ranjan, Inderjeet Chauhan, Kshirodra Kumar Patra, Himanshu Bajpai, Avishek Saha, Chinnakonda S. Gopinath</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00434e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Electron Redistribution in Platinum for Enhanced Alkaline Water Splitting Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00503a</link>
      <description>Wensheng Zhang, Xu Chen, Jinyu Zhao, Ning Lin, Guipeng Wang, Xiaomin Wang, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399109099

                The potential of hydrogen production via water splitting technology makes it urgent to develop low-cost and highly active bifunctional catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER). In this study,...</description>
      <author>Wensheng Zhang, Xu Chen, Jinyu Zhao, Ning Lin, Guipeng Wang, Xiaomin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00503a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treasure-Bowl Style Bifunctional Site in Cerium-Tungsten Hetero-Clusters for Superior Solar-Driven Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh00111g</link>
      <description>Pengliang Sun, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino, Fang Tan, Huanhuan Zhang, Qingquan Kong, Guangzhi Hu, Thomas W&#229;gberg, Materials horizons. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398211646

                Electrochemical water splitting powered by renewable energy sources hold potential for clean hydrogen production. However, there is still persistent challenges such as low solar-to-hydrogen conversion efficiency and sluggish oxygen evolution...</description>
      <author>Pengliang Sun, Eduardo Gracia&#8208;Espino, Fang Tan, Huanhuan Zhang, Qingquan Kong, Guangzhi Hu, Thomas W&#229;gberg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh00111g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Potential of NiCo2O4 Nanocomposite: Morphology Modification via Urea Quantity, Hydrothermal and Calcination Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01581a</link>
      <description>Ataollah Niyati, Arianna Moranda, Juan F. Basb&#250;s, Ombretta Paladino, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398225747

                Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) electrocatalysts are critical in minimizing energy loss during the anodic four-electron transfer process that is required for water oxidation. Improving and selecting optimal non-nobel OER electrocatalysts...</description>
      <author>Ataollah Niyati, Arianna Moranda, Juan F. Basb&#250;s, Ombretta Paladino</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01581a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the active interface structure of MnO2 to achieve sustainable water oxidation in Acidic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02256d</link>
      <description>San-Jiang Pan, Shen Wang, Yu Wang, H.B. Li, Deng Zhao, Liu Yang, Hua Liao, Jiajing Kou, Nan Li, Desong Wang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399055133

                Developing cost-effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis is crucial to achieving large-scale hydrogen production through water electrolysis. Here, we propose the...</description>
      <author>San-Jiang Pan, Shen Wang, Yu Wang, H.B. Li, Deng Zhao, Liu Yang, Hua Liao, Jiajing Kou, Nan Li, Desong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02256d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Oxygen Vacancies with Different Valence States on the Photo(electro)catalytic Performance of a 2D TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;:N (001) System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c01809</link>
      <description>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Shaoqiang Guo, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398781021

                The effect of different valence states Vo on the photo(electro)catalytic performance of the 2D TiO2:N system was investigated using the GGA+U method with first principles. In the poor oxygen conditions, the Ef values of 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0/Vo1+/Vo2+) systems are all less than zero, and all of them are exothermic. Photocatalytic investigations revealed that among the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo1+), 2D Ti24O46N (Vo2+), and 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) systems, the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system has the best carrier activity, the longest electron&#8211;hole lifetime, prominent visible light, infrared light redshift, and outstanding oxidation ability. The photocatalytic decomposition of water and oxygen evolution is highly advantageous. Electrocatalytic studies showed that compared with the free energy of 2D Ti24O46N (Vo1+) and 2D Ti24O46N (Vo2+) systems the free energy &#916;GH* of the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system is &#8722;0.156 eV and the smallest, which is conducive to hydrogen evolution. The overpotential of the oxygen evolution reaction is 0.360 V, which is close to zero, and the four reaction processes are all downward, indicating that the OER reaction can be driven independently by the photogenerated holes, which is conducive to the electrocatalytic reaction. Moreover, the ability of decomposing water is relatively good. The 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system is a candidate nanomaterial and can be applied as a novel photoelectric catalyst.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Shaoqiang Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c01809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BaCoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Tetrahedral Cobalt Coordination: The Missing Element to Understand Energy Storage and Conversion Applications in BaCoO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14047</link>
      <description>Aliou Diatta, Claire Colin, Romain Viennois, M. Beaudhuin, Julien Haines, Patrick Hermet, Arie van der Lee, Leszek Konczewicz, P. Armand, J&#233;r&#244;me Rouquette, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050116

                Barium&#8211;cobaltate-based perovskite (BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;) and barium&#8211;cobaltate-based nanocomposites have been intensively studied in energy storage and conversion devices mainly due to flexible oxygen stoichiometry and tunable nonprecious transition metal oxidation states. Although a rich and complex family of structural polymorphs has already been reported for these perovskites in the literature, the potential structural evolution that may occur during the oxygen reduction reaction and the oxygen evolution reaction has not been investigated so far. In this study, we synthesized and characterized the lowest Co-oxidation state possible in the compound, BaCoO2, which exhibits a quartz-derived, trigonal structure with a helicoidally corner-sharing, CoO4-tetrahedral-framework as already proposed by Spitsbergen et al. Oxygen can reversibly be inserted in such a crystal structure to form BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;, i.e., with 0 &#8804; &#948; &#8804; 1, based on the results of an in situ coupled thermogravimetric - neutron diffraction study and which presents therefore giant oxygen capacity storage due to the extreme tunability of the electronic configuration of the cobalt cations which defines the fundamental origins of the materials performance. The reversible conversion of BaCoO2 to BaCoO3&#8722;&#948; associated with a similar electronic conductivity above 900 K permits to clarify the high potential of BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;-based energy storage and conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Aliou Diatta, Claire Colin, Romain Viennois, M. Beaudhuin, Julien Haines, Patrick Hermet, Arie van der Lee, Leszek Konczewicz, P. Armand, J&#233;r&#244;me Rouquette</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Enhanced Ni3N-CeO2/NF Nanoparticle Catalysts for Efficient and Stable Electrolytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110935</link>
      <description>Xianghao Meng, Xin Zhao, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Yiting Peng, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399042805

                Highly efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts are of critical significance in the domain of water electrolysis. In this study, a Ni3N-CeO2/NF heterostructure is synthesized through a facile hydrothermal technique followed by a subsequent nitridation process. This catalyst is endowed with an abundance of oxygen vacancies, thereby conferring a richer array of active sites. Therefore, the catalyst demonstrates a markedly low overpotential of 350 mV for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 and a low overpotential of 42 mV for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Serving as a dual-function electrode, this electrocatalyst is employed in overall water splitting in alkaline environments, demonstrating impressive efficiency at a cell voltage of 1.52 V of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The in situ Raman spectroscopic analysis demonstrates that cerium dioxide (CeO2) facilitates the rapid reconfiguration of oxygen vacancy-enriched nickel oxyhydroxide (NiOOH), thereby enhancing the OER performance. This investigation elucidates the catalytic role of CeO2 in augmenting the OER efficiency of nickel nitride (Ni3N) for water electrolysis, offering valuable insights for the design of high-performance bifunctional catalysts tailored for water splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Xianghao Meng, Xin Zhao, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Yiting Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress and perspective on electrocatalysis in neutral media: Mechanisms, materials, and advanced characterizations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/idm2.12172</link>
      <description>Fu-Shun Lai, Haochuan Shang, Yuechao Jiao, Xinyi Chen, Tianran Zhang, Xiangfeng Liu, Interdisciplinary materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398252762

                Abstract Electrocatalysis, which involves oxidation and reduction reactions with direct electron transfer, is essential for a variety of clean energy conversion devices. Currently, the vast majority of studies regarding electrocatalysis reactions focus on strong acidic or alkaline media because of the higher catalytic activity. Nevertheless, some inherent drawbacks, including the corrosive environment, expensive proton exchange membranes, and side effects, are still hard to break through. A sustainably promising way to overcome these shortcomings is to deploy neutral/near&#8208;neutral electrolytes for electrocatalysis reactions. Unfortunately, insufficient research in this area due to the lack of attention to related issues has slowed down the development process. In this review, we systematically review the catalytic reaction mechanisms, neutral electrolytes, electrocatalysts, and modification strategies carried out in neutral media on the three most common electrocatalytic reactions, that is, hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, and oxygen evolution reaction. Furthermore, the advanced characterization tools for guiding catalyst synthesis and mechanistic studies are also summarized. Eventually, we propose some challenges and perspectives on electrocatalysis reactions in neutral media and hope it will attract more research interest and provide guidance in neutral electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Fu-Shun Lai, Haochuan Shang, Yuechao Jiao, Xinyi Chen, Tianran Zhang, Xiangfeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/idm2.12172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From density functional theory to machine learning predictive models for electrical properties of spinel oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62788-4</link>
      <description>Yuval Elbaz, Maytal Caspary Toroker, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399037502

                Abstract This work focuses on predicting and characterizing the electronic conductivity of spinel oxides, which are promising materials for energy storage devices and for the oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions due to their attractive properties and abundance of transition metals that can act as active sites for catalysis. To this end, a new database was developed from first principles, including band structure and conductivity properties of spinel oxides, and machine learning algorithms were trained on this database to predict electronic conductivity and band gaps based solely on the compositions. The models developed in this study are scaled from the quantum level up to a continuum conductivity model. The relatively small database used in this study allowed for accurate predictions of band gap and conductivity. By altering the composition of spinel oxides, the model was able to predict high conductivity for spinels with high nickel content and to match experimental trends for manganese cobalt spinels. The ability to predict material properties is especially important in energy conversion devices such as batteries and supercapacitors where redox reactions take place.</description>
      <author>Yuval Elbaz, Maytal Caspary Toroker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62788-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Comprehensive Understanding of Intrinsic Contribution of Nickel Foam as a Conductive Substrate in Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4838947</link>
      <description>Umer Rashid, Youqi Zhu, Chuanbao Cao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398758006

                Using nickel foam as a substrate for electrocatalyst to report overpotential in a manuscript is a popular method in electrochemical testing or water-splitting i.e., the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, use of coated Nickel foam as substrate methodology is, in essence, not reasonable for studying the intrinsic chemistry difference of electrocatalysts. To assess water-splitting devices, Ni-foam is a valid substrate if nanoparticles are grown uniformly; however, when drop-casted ink methodology is used or there is inhomogeneous growth of nanoparticles, it becomes difficult to determine whether a particular electrocatalyst is intrinsically active or not. In order to gain a rational understanding of the electrochemical activity and overpotential findings of a specific catalyst, it is essential to recognize the limitations of Ni-foam on reflecting its intrinsic role in electrocatalytic activity. Ni-foam is therefore should not be preferred as a conductive substrate during electrochemical testing (ET). On the contrary, use of other neutral substrates like carbon fiber paper (CFP) and glassy carbon electrode (GCE) should be employed.</description>
      <author>Umer Rashid, Youqi Zhu, Chuanbao Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4838947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoOx/CoMo on Cu nanowires as an efficiently bifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400582</link>
      <description>Xingchen Chai, Cang Yuan, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Lei Wang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399047706

                Electrocatalytic water splitting is a promising approach for sustainable hydrogen production. The design and development of efficient and stable bifunctional catalysts are the key to realizing hydrogen production from water splitting. Herein, we successfully synthesized bifunctional MoOx/CoMo grown on copper nanowires (Cu NWs) through an electrodeposition approach, showing excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performances. The MoOx/CoMo/Cu NWs catalyst exhibited overpotentials as low as 56 mV and 211 mV to deliver a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 for HER and OER in alkaline media, respectively. Moreover, the MoOx/CoMo/Cu NWs as bifunctional electrodes for overall water splitting achieved a low voltage of 1.45 and 1.62 V at 10 and 50 mA cm&#8208;2, respectively, with a stability of 10 h at 50 mA cm&#8208;2. This work provides a promising strategy for designing highly active catalysts that replace precious&#8208;metal&#8208;based catalysts on energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Xingchen Chai, Cang Yuan, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Oxidation of Small Molecules for Energy&#8208;Saving Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401242</link>
      <description>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Liangshuang Fei, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399047723

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting is a promising technique for the production of high&#8208;purity hydrogen. Substituting the slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction with an oxidation reaction that is thermodynamically more favorable enables the energy&#8208;efficient production of hydrogen. Moreover, this approach facilitates the degradation of environmental pollutants and synthesis of value&#8208;added chemicals through the rational selection of small molecules as substrates. Strategies for small&#8208;molecule selection and electrocatalyst design are critical to electrocatalytic performance, with a focus on achieving a high current density, selectivity, Faradaic efficiency, and operational durability. This perspective discusses the key factors required for further advancement, including technoeconomic analysis, new reactor system design, meeting the requirements of industrial applications, bridging the gap between fundamental research and practical applications, and product detection and separation. This perspective aims to advance the development of hybrid water electrolysis applications.</description>
      <author>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Liangshuang Fei, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactivity and Durability of Covalent Organic Frameworks Derived Co&#8208;based Hybrid Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400068</link>
      <description>Yuling Zhang, Longfei Xiao, Yiping Mo, Gao Liu, Shanshan Liu, Wangyang L&#252;, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398782793

                Developing bifunctional non&#8208;precious metal electrocatalysts of superior reactivity and durability is essential. Herein, we report a class of phthalocyanine&#8208;based covalent organic frameworks as self&#8208;sacrificial precursors derived Co&#8208;based hybrid electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The fabricated Co&#8208;COFs/CNT&#8208;700 catalysts displayed highly efficient ORR properties with a half&#8208;potential of 0.83 V, while its half&#8208;wave potential in alkaline solution at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 is 1.70 V in the OER test, reflecting exceptional OER activity. Moreover, zinc&#8208;air batteries assembled with Co&#8208;COFs/CNT&#8208;700 catalysts exhibit a marginally higher power density (114 mW cm2) than traditional Pt/C&#8208;IrO2 batteries in an air atmosphere, along with an enhanced cycling stability (5.1% potential loss after 65 h). This work may pave a facile and efficient approach for fabricating electrocatalytic materials with controllably introduced metals and heteroatoms.</description>
      <author>Yuling Zhang, Longfei Xiao, Yiping Mo, Gao Liu, Shanshan Liu, Wangyang L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Ni nanoparticles/N-doped carbon sheets for freshwater and seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131995</link>
      <description>Dawei Wang, Xuehong Wang, Hao Qiu, Yixuan Tao, Jie Yin, Juan Li, Wenpin Wang, Zhongcheng Li, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398793128

                Electric-driven water dissociation is considered to be a sustainable approach for the generation of H2. Ni nanoparticles show poor freshwater/seawater electrolysis activity owing to the severe aggregation of Ni, which blocks the active sites to catalyze water splitting. Here, we present Ni nanoparticles/N-doped carbon sheets by the thermal treatment of Ni-based triazole-benzoic acid complexes. The electronic state and coordination environment of Ni are modulated by the formation of the confined space with the N-doped carbon layer. Ni/N-doped carbon sheets promote acidic/alkaline hydrogen evolution activity with 143/81 mV@10 mA/cm2. Upon being used as the catalysts for water oxidation reaction, it expedited alkaline oxygen evolution 218/312 mV@10/50 mA/cm2 for Ni/N-doped carbon, which is even superior to commercial RuO2 with 309/364 mV. Tests for alkaline freshwater/seawater splitting find that Ni/N-doped carbon sheets possess remarkable activity with 1.56/1.62 V@10 mA/cm2 as well as outstanding stability. Our work offers an efficient strategy to rationally regulate the coordination structure of metal nanoparticles for promoting water electrolysis activity.</description>
      <author>Dawei Wang, Xuehong Wang, Hao Qiu, Yixuan Tao, Jie Yin, Juan Li, Wenpin Wang, Zhongcheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructure catalyst coupled wood-derived carbon and cobalt-iron alloy/oxide for reversible oxygen conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42773-024-00348-9</link>
      <description>Limin Zhou, Junxiao Li, Jiao Yin, Gaoyue Zhang, Pengxiang Zhang, Jing-Jing Zhou, Anqi Zhang, Ao Wang, Baojun Li, Yanyan Liu, Kang Sun, Biochar. 6(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398780760

                Abstract As promising energy-storage devices, zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) exhibit slow reaction kinetics for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) occurring at their electrodes. High-performance bifunctional catalysts must thus be synthesized to accelerate the reversible conversion of oxygen and improve the rate and overall performance of ZABs. Herein, we reported the promising prospects of self-supported composite electrodes composed of wood-derived carbon (WDC) and bimetallic cobalt-iron alloys/oxides (CoFe-CoFe 2 O 4 @WDC) as efficient electrocatalysts for alkaline ORR/OER. WDC provided a favorable three-phase interface for heterogeneous reactions owing to its layered porous structure and genetic stability, thereby enabling mass diffusion and improving reaction kinetics. The CoFe 2 O 4 spinel surface was reduced to bimetallic CoFe alloy to form abundant heterostructure interfaces that promote electron transfer. Under alkaline conditions, the optimized composite electrode exhibited a remarkable high half-wave potential of 0.85 V and an exceptionally low overpotential of 1.49 V. It also exhibited stable performance over an impressive 2340 cycles in a ZAB. Theoretical calculations also confirmed that the heterointerface addresses the issue of proton scarcity throughout the reaction and actively facilitates the creation of O&#8211;O bonds during the reversible transformation of oxygen. This study introduces a new concept for developing bifunctional and efficient electrocatalysts based on charcoal and encourages the sustainable and high-value use of forest biomass resources. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Limin Zhou, Junxiao Li, Jiao Yin, Gaoyue Zhang, Pengxiang Zhang, Jing-Jing Zhou, Anqi Zhang, Ao Wang, Baojun Li, Yanyan Liu, Kang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42773-024-00348-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrystalline CuOx Thin Films for Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.1556.v1</link>
      <description>E. Silva, F&#225;bio Viadanna Serr&#227;o, Gustavo Henrique dos Santos Domingos, Thiago M.B.F. Oliveira, Marco A. L. Cordeiro, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398782624

                New advances in creating effective and affordable copper-based catalysts for water splitting represent a promising strategy for driving sustainable energy technologies. However, ma- terials containing copper are susceptible to corrosion and agglomeration. In this study, we describe a synthesis route to produce olamine-functionalized CuO nanoparticles using the Hot Injection method. Nanoparticles were obtained and subsequently deposited on FTO substrates, undergoing thermal treatment at 500&amp;deg;C and 600&amp;deg;C in atmospheres containing O2 and N2, aiming to enhance the adhesion of the active material to the substrate and modify its oxidation state. Microstructural properties were analyzed using XRD, SEM, and TEM, while electrochemical properties were studied using CV, LSV, and EIS. Electrodes treated thermally in an N2 atmosphere at 600&amp;deg;C exhibited higher ESCA, indicating a greater area of active sites exposed to surface reactions and, therefore, superior catalytic activity in Hy- drogen Evolution Reaction (HER). These findings show an interesting strategy for avoiding rapid electron-hole recombination and, consequently, CuO corrosion. For Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), samples treated thermally in O2 atmosphere at 500&amp;deg;C and 600&amp;deg;C appear to be more effective.</description>
      <author>E. Silva, F&#225;bio Viadanna Serr&#227;o, Gustavo Henrique dos Santos Domingos, Thiago M.B.F. Oliveira, Marco A. L. Cordeiro</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.1556.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent organic framework&#8208;derived Fe, Co&#8208;nitrogen codoped carbon as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable efficient Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.145</link>
      <description>Zhanpeng Chen, Jiabi Jiang, Mingjun Jing, Yiming Bai, Xiaoyan Zhang, Wenhui Deng, Yufeng Wu, Fang Chen, Mingguang Yi, Meixia Yang, Xinkai Xu, Tianjing Wu, Zhiwei Yang, Xianyou Wang, Carbon neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050151

                Abstract The development of cathode materials with controllable physicochemical structures and explicit catalytic sites is important in rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) have garnered increasing attention owing to their facile synthesis methods, ordered pore structure, and selectivity of functional groups. However, the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) or oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) inhibit their practical applications in ZABs. Herein, nucleophilic substitution is adopted to synthesize pyridine bi&#8208;triazine covalent organic framework (denoted as O&#8208;COF), and meanwhile, ionothermal conversion synthesis is employed to load MO x (M=Fe, Co) onto carbon nanosheet (named as FeCo@NC) to modulate the electronic structure. The Fe, Co&#8208;N codoped carbon material possesses a large portion of pyridinic N and M&#8208;N, high graphitization, and a larger BET surface area. An outstanding bifunctional activity has been exhibited in FeCo@NC, which provides a small voltage at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER (E 10 = 1.67 V) and a remarkable half&#8208;wave voltage for ORR (E 1/2 = 0.86 V). More impressively, when assembling ZABs, it displays notable rate performance, significant specific capacity (783.9 mAh g Zn &#8722;1 ), and satisfactory long&#8208;term endurance. This method of regulating covalent organic framework and ionothermal synthesis can be extended to design diverse catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhanpeng Chen, Jiabi Jiang, Mingjun Jing, Yiming Bai, Xiaoyan Zhang, Wenhui Deng, Yufeng Wu, Fang Chen, Mingguang Yi, Meixia Yang, Xinkai Xu, Tianjing Wu, Zhiwei Yang, Xianyou Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;MOF&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;Derived Iron&#8208;Cobalt Phosphide Nanoframe as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12747</link>
      <description>Yanqi Yuan, Kun Wang, Boan Zhong, Dongkun Yu, Fei Ye, Jing Liu, Joydeep Dutta, Peng Zhang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398216964

                Transition metal phosphides (TMPs) have emerged as an alternative to precious metals as efficient and low&#8208;cost catalysts for water electrolysis. Elemental doping and morphology control are effective approaches to further improve the performance of TMPs. Herein, Fe&#8208;doped CoP nanoframes (Fe&#8208;CoP NFs) with specific open cage configuration were designed and synthesized. The unique nano&#8208;framework structured Fe&#8208;CoP material shows overpotentials of only 255 and 122 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), respectively, overwhelming most transition metal phosphides. For overall water splitting, the cell voltage is 1.65 V for Fe&#8208;CoP NFs at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , much superior to what is observed for the classical nanocubic structures. Fe&#8208;CoP NFs show no activity degradation up to 100 h which contrasts sharply with the rapidly decaying performance of noble metal catalyst reference. The superior electrocatalytic performance of Fe&#8208;CoP NFs due to abundant accessible active sites, reduced kinetic energy barrier, and preferable *O&#8208;containing intermediate adsorption is demonstrated through experimental observations and theoretical calculations. Our findings could provide a potential method for the preparation of multifunctional material with hollow structures and offer more hopeful prospects for obtaining efficient earth&#8208;abundant catalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yanqi Yuan, Kun Wang, Boan Zhong, Dongkun Yu, Fei Ye, Jing Liu, Joydeep Dutta, Peng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic water splitting activity by using Ni0.85Se anchored on amorphous Ni4Mo alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.300</link>
      <description>Renjie Li, Lili Cui, Dou Zhang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398792265

                To design and construct bifunctional electrocatalyst with high activity is important to the commercial development of electrochemical water splitting (EWS) technology. The carbon clothe (CC) supported on Ni(OH)2 nanosheet is used as template to tune the morphology of Ni0.85Se. To improve the activity of Ni0.85Se, amorphous Ni4Mo alloy is anchored on the Ni0.85Se to obtain the Ni0.85Se/Ni4Mo catalyst (NS/NM) by electrodeposition method. The electron state and conductivity of NS/NM are modulated compared to that of the NS sample. It is found that the electron transfers from Ni4Mo to Ni0.85Se. Benefiting from the tuned electron state of Ni0.85Se and Ni4Mo, the enhanced number of exposed active sites and lower Rct value, the NS/NM heterostructure electrode requires low overpotentials of 51 and 206 mV to obtain 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The optimized electrode shows fast kinetics and exhibits near to 100% Faraday efficiency for HER and OER in 1 M KOH. Importantly, it is noted that the electrocatalytic activity of NS/NM catalyst for both HER and OER is enhanced obviously in comparison with NS sample. With heterostructure catalyst, the EWS only proceeds at 1.48 V to yield 10 mA cm&#8722;2, which is reduced about 110 mV compared to NS electrode. Here, a novel kind of bifunctional heterostructure electrocatalyst is constructed.</description>
      <author>Renjie Li, Lili Cui, Dou Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Ultrastable Iodide Oxidation Reaction Over Defect&#8208;Passivated Perovskite Photoanode for Unassisted Solar Fuel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401055</link>
      <description>Juwon Yun, Young Sun Park, Hyungsoo Lee, Wooyong Jeong, Chang&#8208;Seop Jeong, Chan Uk Lee, Jeongyoub Lee, Subin Moon, Euna Kwon, Soo Bin Lee, Sumin Kim, Junghwan Kim, Seungho Yu, Jooho Moon, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399044053

                Abstract Recently, lead halide perovskites have emerged as promising photoanode materials for efficient hydrogen production. However, the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and interfacial defect&#8208;mediated charge accumulation inevitably result in efficiency loss and degradation of perovskite photoanodes. Herein, a defect&#8208;passivated electron transport layer&#8208;based perovskite photoanode combined with a catalyst layer favorable is introduced for iodide oxidation reaction bearing a small thermodynamic barrier and rapid kinetics compared to OER for efficient solar fuel generation. The resulting perovskite photoanode revealed a saturated photocurrent density of 22.4 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0.3 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (V RHE ) with an impressive onset potential of &#8722;0.2 V RHE as well as durability for 225 h in a neutral electrolyte. In addition, an unbiased hydrogen&#8208;production device comprising a perovskite photoanode and Pt coil electrocatalyst is demonstrated, achieving a remarkable solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion efficiency of 11.45% and stable operation for 25 h. Moreover, a wireless artificial leaf&#8208;structured device realizing solar&#8208;driven hydrogen generation in natural sea water under outdoor sunlight is presented.</description>
      <author>Juwon Yun, Young Sun Park, Hyungsoo Lee, Wooyong Jeong, Chang&#8208;Seop Jeong, Chan Uk Lee, Jeongyoub Lee, Subin Moon, Euna Kwon, Soo Bin Lee, Sumin Kim, Junghwan Kim, Seungho Yu, Jooho Moon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Performance Limitation of Liquid Alkaline Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4fe6</link>
      <description>Guanzhi Wang, Andrew W. Tricker, Jin Yi Lang, Jianxin Wang, Iryna V. Zenyuk, Di&#8208;Jia Liu, Rangachary Mukundan, Ping Xiong, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398243873

                Abstract Liquid alkaline water electrolyzers (LAWEs), being the most commercially mature electrolysis technology, play a pivotal role in large-scale hydrogen production. However, LAWEs suffer from low operational efficiency, primarily due to un-optimized electrode structure and chemical compositions. Thus, we investigated how various electrode configurations could impact LAWE performance. Our results show that Ni felt electrodes outperform the conventional Ni foam thanks to improved electrochemical active surface area (ECSA) and preferred electrode surface structure that minimizes the micro-gaps in between the electrode and separator. By comparing the stainless steel (SS) felt electrodes with Ni felt electrodes, SS not only shows better oxygen evolution reaction activity but also improved hydrogen evolution reaction activity, which is less studied in the literature. We also show that a bilayer structure with small pore radius facing the separator could further improve LAWE performance by further optimizing interfacial contact between electrode and separator. These findings enable LAWEs to sustain 2 A cm-2 at 2.2 V and operate steadily at 1 A cm-2 for nearly 600 h with negligible performance decay. Our studies establish criteria for selecting electrodes to achieve high-performance LAWE and, in turn, expedite the adoption of LAWEs in hydrogen production and the transition towards low-carbon economies.</description>
      <author>Guanzhi Wang, Andrew W. Tricker, Jin Yi Lang, Jianxin Wang, Iryna V. Zenyuk, Di&#8208;Jia Liu, Rangachary Mukundan, Ping Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4fe6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Noble Metal-free Ternary Chalcogenide Electrocatalysts for
  Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.14187</link>
      <description>Shantanu Singh, Ahamed Irshad, Germany Diaz De la Cruz, Boyang Zhao, Billal Zayat, Qiaowan Chang, S. R. Narayanan, Jayakanth Ravichandran, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398796735

                Hydrogen has been identified as a clean, zero carbon, sustainable, and promising energy source for the future, and electrochemical water splitting for hydrogen production is an emission-free, efficient energy conversion technology. A major limitation of this approach is the unavailability of efficient, abundant, inexpensive catalysts, which prompts the need for new catalytic materials. Here, we report the synthesis and electrocatalytic properties of a novel transition metal-based ternary chalcogenide family, LaMS$_3$ (M = Mn, Fe, Co, Ni). Powder X-ray diffraction confirms the phase purity of these materials, while composition analysis using energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS) confirms the presence of the stoichiometric ratio of elements in these compounds. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) were used to study the chemical states on the surface and in bulk, respectively. These materials exhibit bifunctional catalytic activity towards the two half-reactions of the water-splitting process, with LaNiS$_3$ being the most active material for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The LaMS$_3$ compounds show long-term stability with negligible change in the overpotential at a constant current density of 10 mA cm$^{-2}$ over 18 hours of measurements. As compared to the corresponding ternary oxides, the LaMS$_3$ materials exhibit higher activity and significantly lower Tafel slopes. The ability to catalyze both half-reactions of water electrolysis makes these materials promising candidates for bifunctional catalysts and presents a new avenue to search for high-efficiency electrocatalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Shantanu Singh, Ahamed Irshad, Germany Diaz De la Cruz, Boyang Zhao, Billal Zayat, Qiaowan Chang, S. R. Narayanan, Jayakanth Ravichandran</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.14187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of Biphasic Boride Electrocatalysts on Dealloyed Bulk Ni&#8211;Mo Alloy as Self-Supporting Electrode for Water Splitting at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04157</link>
      <description>Guangyao Yang, Weiliang Peng, Zhipeng Chen, Shaobo Li, Han Qin, Renzong Hu, Bin Yuan, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050071

                Nickel&#8211;molybdenum&#8211;boron (Ni&#8211;Mo&#8211;B)-based catalysts with biphasic interfaces are highly advantageous in bifunctional electrocatalytic activity in alkaline water-splitting. However, it remains an ongoing challenge to obtain porous Ni&#8211;Mo alloy substrates that provide stable adhesion to catalysts, ensuring the long-term performance of bifunctional self-supporting electrodes at a high current density. Herein, a porous Ni&#8211;Mo alloy substrate was effectively obtained by a cost-effective dealloying process on a commercial Ni&#8211;Mo alloy with high-energy crystal planes. Subsequently, the Mo2NiB2/Ni3B bifunctional catalyst was in situ synthesized on this substrate via boriding heat treatment, resulting in outstanding catalytic activity and stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the abundant biphasic interfaces and surface-reconstructed sites of the Mo2NiB2/Ni3B catalyst can decrease the energy barriers for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively. Thus, the designed self-supporting electrodes show bifunctional catalytic activity with overpotentials of 151 mV for HER and 260 mV for OER at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2. Markedly, the assembled water electrolyzer can be driven up to 10 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.64 V and maintain catalytic activity at a high current density of 1000 mA cm&#8211;2 for 100 h. The new strategy is expected to provide a low-cost scheme for designing self-supporting bifunctional electrodes with high activity and excellent stability and contribute to the development of hydrogen energy technology.</description>
      <author>Guangyao Yang, Weiliang Peng, Zhipeng Chen, Shaobo Li, Han Qin, Renzong Hu, Bin Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Large-area ultrathin 2D Co(OH)2 nanosheets: A bifunctional electrode material for supercapacitor and water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101608</link>
      <description>Pallavi Bhaktapralhad Jagdale, Sayali Ashok Patil, Amanda Sfeir, Narad Barman, Asif Iqbal, S&#233;bastien Royer, Ranjit Thapa, Akshaya K. Samal, Debasis Ghosh, Manav Saxena, Materials today energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398694170

                Ultrathin film of active materials having thickness &lt;5 nm emerged as a promising candidate for miniaturized energy storage and conversion devices. However, the small lateral size restricts its real device applications. Herein, we report large area, 2D, ultrathin (thickness: 4.3&#177;0.3 nm) Co(OH)2 nanosheets as bi-functional electrode material for supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction developed by Ionic layer epitaxy (ILE) method at the water-air interface. The symmetric supercapacitor device exhibited excellent volumetric capacitance of 2313 F cm-3 at 0.4 mA cm-2 current density. Additionally, it exhibited a remarkable volumetric energy density of 0.205 Wh cm-3 at a power density of 0.145 W cm-3, which is better than reported 2D electrode materials. Furthermore, the Co(OH)2 ultrathin-film electrodes showed improved OER electrocatalytic activity with low overpotential (&#414;10, 330 mV) and Tafel slope (47 mV dec-1). The structural and morphological investigations after long-term operations show substantial stability of the electrode material. The theoretical investigations of electronic structures, quantum capacitance, and free energy profiles for the OER mechanism corroborate the experimental results.</description>
      <author>Pallavi Bhaktapralhad Jagdale, Sayali Ashok Patil, Amanda Sfeir, Narad Barman, Asif Iqbal, S&#233;bastien Royer, Ranjit Thapa, Akshaya K. Samal, Debasis Ghosh, Manav Saxena</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long&#8208;Lasting Hybrid Seawater Electrolysis Enabled by Anodic Mass Transport Intensification for Energy&#8208;Saving Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407601</link>
      <description>Dongtong He, Pengju Yang, Kaizhou Yang, Jieshan Qiu, Zhiyu Wang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398236738

                Abstract Hybrid water electrolysis offers a groundbreaking approach to energy&#8208;saving hydrogen production by utilizing thermodynamically favorable and value&#8208;added reactions to replace sluggish anodic oxygen evolution in overall water splitting. However, numerous anodic processes generate intermediates or products incompatible with aqueous environments, thereby degrading anodic performance to limit the efficiency and durability of hybrid water electrolysis. Herein, this difficulty is addressed by applying anodic mass transport intensification in conjunction with catalyst engineering, realizing a long&#8208;lasting hybrid seawater electrolysis coupling sulfion oxidation reaction (SOR) for efficient hydrogen production below 1.2 V at an industrial&#8208;level current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . An exceptional longevity of 2000 h is achieved for the electrolysis by eliminating anode passivation by sulfur deposition during SOR, a general concern in the sulfur&#8208;involved industrial sector. This technology cut the electricity expense of hydrogen production to 2.80 kWh m &#8722;3 H 2 , undercutting alkaline water electrolysis by 34.9&#8211;51.1%. Simultaneously, fast upcycling of sulfion pollutants to value&#8208;added sulfur is achieved to add additional economic and environmental profits, enabling hydrogen production at a midpoint expense ($ 0.93) of the United States Department of Energy's 2026 target ($ 2.0) for the cost per gallon of gasoline&#8208;equivalent.</description>
      <author>Dongtong He, Pengju Yang, Kaizhou Yang, Jieshan Qiu, Zhiyu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recovering Nickel&#8208;Based Materials from Spent NiMH Batteries for Electrochemical Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400135</link>
      <description>Ikhbayar Batsukh, Munkhbaatar Adiya, Lkhagvajav Sarantuya, G. Sevjidsuren, Mungunshagai Gansukh, Munkhbayar Batmunkh, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398209335

                Abstract In this work, we explored the recovering possibilities of nickel&#8208;based products from the cathode materials of spent nickel&#8208;metal hydride (NiMH) batteries collected from car repair centers in Mongolia. Specifically, nickel&#8208;based by&#8208;products such as metallic nickel, Ni microparticles, nickel oxide, nickel chloride, and betta&#8208;phase ( &#946; ) nickel hydroxide powders are successfully produced. X&#8208;ray diffraction patterns suggested that all samples show high crystallinity and phase purity. Ni microparticles were recovered using a chemical reduction method from a leachate solution prepared by dissolving the cathode of the spent NiMH battery in hydrochloric acid. Notably, &#946; &#8208;Ni(OH)&#8322; displayed two redox peaks in KOH electrolyte solution, suggesting that it has excellent electrochemical potential and can be reused for the fabrication of new NiMH batteries. To validate the electrochemical performances, we examined the catalytic activity of nickel microparticles as a catalyst for the degradation of Congo red (CR) dye and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The reduction reaction rate of CR dye in the presence of a nickel catalyst was 2.17&#215;10 &#8722;3 s &#8722;1 , significantly higher than the control experiment without a nickel catalyst. These results provide possible solutions for developing sustainable battery systems by recovering different nickel&#8208;based products from spent NiMH batteries.</description>
      <author>Ikhbayar Batsukh, Munkhbaatar Adiya, Lkhagvajav Sarantuya, G. Sevjidsuren, Mungunshagai Gansukh, Munkhbayar Batmunkh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Pyrolysis Mechanism of Binuclear Chromium-Based Complexes for Superior OER Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04688</link>
      <description>Meixing Gan, Li Li, Xixian Yang, Hongwei Rong, Zheng Wang, Yuebin Li, Yuexing Zhang, Xueli Chen, Peng Xu, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398775852

                Transition metal oxides are widely pursued as potent electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, single-metal chromium catalysts remain underexplored due to their intrinsic activity limitations. Herein, we successfully synthesize mixed-valence, nitrogen-doped Cr2O3/CrO3/CrN@NC nanoelectrocatalysts via one-step targeted pyrolysis techniques from a binuclear Cr-based complex (Cr2(Salophen)2(CH3OH)2), which is strategically designed as a precursor. Comprehensive pyrolysis mechanisms were thoroughly delineated by using coupled thermogravimetric analysis and mass spectrometry (TG&#8211;MS) alongside X-ray diffraction. Below 800 &#176;C, the generation of a reducing atmosphere was noted, while continuous pyrolysis at temperatures exceeding 800 &#176;C promoted highly oxidized CrO3 species with an elevated +6 oxidation state. The optimized catalyst pyrolyzed at 1000 &#176;C (Cr2O3/CrO3/CrN@NCs-1000) demonstrated remarkable OER activity with a low overpotential of 290 mV in 1 M KOH and excellent stability. Further density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed a much smaller reaction energy barrier of CrO3 than the low oxidation state species for OER reactivity. This work reveals fresh strategies for rationally engineering chromium-based electrocatalysts and overcoming intrinsic roadblocks to enable efficient OER catalysis through a deliberate oxidation state and compositional tuning.</description>
      <author>Meixing Gan, Li Li, Xixian Yang, Hongwei Rong, Zheng Wang, Yuebin Li, Yuexing Zhang, Xueli Chen, Peng Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MnO2 anchored N&#8211;Ti3C2 MXene as a bifunctional electrode for enhanced water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.323</link>
      <description>Sandra Mathew, K.R. Sunaja Devi, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398978119

                The domain of energy research is vigorously exploring a wide array of materials, from advanced carbon-based substances like graphene and carbon nanotubes to emerging contenders like MXenes. Ti3C2 MXene offers exceptional performance in electrochemistry, benefiting from its remarkable electronic conductivity, considerable surface area, chemical stability, cost-effectiveness, hydrophilicity, and eco-friendliness. However, it undergoes self-accumulation, which diminishes the number of electrochemically active sites, resulting in decreased performance. In this study, MnO2 particles are intricately anchored onto the surfaces and within the layers of nitrogen-doped Ti3C2 (N&#8211;Ti3C2), resulting in the creation of innovative interface engineered N&#8211;Ti3C2/MnO2 nanosheets. Due to its distinctive heterostructure and favourable interfacial interaction, the N&#8211;Ti3C2/MnO2 electrode shows better performance in both the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions, exhibiting low overpotentials of 130 mV and 289 mV, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Furthermore, it requires a cell voltage of 1.7 V to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 during the overall water splitting process. The N&#8211;Ti3C2/MnO2 composite also maintains sustained durability for a period of 4 h. This enhanced electrochemical activity of N&#8211;Ti3C2/MnO2 can be due to the synergistic effects resulting from the intricate contact between N&#8211;Ti3C2 and MnO2. This research presents a simple methodology for designing MXenes-based multicomponent electrodes for electrochemical water splitting reactions and its potential application for electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Sandra Mathew, K.R. Sunaja Devi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin transition metal oxychalcogenides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4432594/v1</link>
      <description>Manish Chhowalla, Wenshuo Xu, Yi-Ming Wu, Shibo Xi, Yan Wang, Ye Wang, Yuxuan Ke, L. K. Ding, Xiao Wang, Jieun Yang, Wenjing Zhang, Kian Ping Loh, Feng Ding, Zheng Liu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398773932

                Abstract Two-dimensional (2D) transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) exfoliated from bulk layered materials possess interesting properties. Most transition metal oxides (TMOs) are not layered and therefore cannot be exfoliated. Here we report the synthesis of a new family of ultrathin materials &#8211; transition metal oxychalcogenides (TMOCs) and demonstrate their unique properties. Specifically, 2D TMOCs such as HfSxOy, ZrSxOy, TiSxOy, TaSxOy, NbSxOy, VSexOy, HfSexOy, ZrSexOy, TaTexOy (x, y ~ 0&#8211;2) from bulk TMDs (HfS2, ZrS2, TiS2, TaS2, NbS2, VSe2, HfSe2, ZrSe2, TaTe2) have been fabricated using tetrabutylammonium intercalation. The stoichiometry of TMOCs can be adjusted, which enables control of their optical band gaps and tunability of electrical conductivity by more than 8 orders of magnitude. Our results show that by tuning the chalcogen to oxygen ratio along with local atomic structure in TMOCs, it is possible to impart unexpected properties. For example, in contrast to conventional TMDs, the hybrid structure renders TMOCs surprisingly stable and electrochemically active in strong acids, which allows them to be used as proof-of-concept catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at pH &#8776; 0. The HfS0.52O1.09 catalysts show high mass activity (10,3000 A g&#8211;1 at an overpotential of 0.5 V) and exhibit durability in proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysers.</description>
      <author>Manish Chhowalla, Wenshuo Xu, Yi-Ming Wu, Shibo Xi, Yan Wang, Ye Wang, Yuxuan Ke, L. K. Ding, Xiao Wang, Jieun Yang, Wenjing Zhang, Kian Ping Loh, Feng Ding, Zheng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4432594/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disinfection of Irrigation Water using Titanium Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/labqlv</link>
      <description>Geletu Qing, Mojtaba Abolhassani, Raheleh Daneshpour, Shelby L. Foster, Marty Matlock, Greg Thoma, Lauren Greenlee, Harvard Dataverse. None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4398746206

                The microbiological safety of irrigation water is critical to the prevention of fresh produce contamination with human pathogens. This work reports on the electrochemical disinfection of natural irrigation water using an undivided batch cell assembled with titanium (Ti) electrodes as both anode and cathode. Although Ti is considered an inactive electrode material for most applications due to the presence of an oxide film on the surface, we show here that it can efficiently catalyze the electrochemical oxidation of a few ppm of chloride ions in natural irrigation water to free chlorine species, which in turn enable fast disinfection. Disinfection experiments were performed by applying a polarity-reversing direct current between the two Ti electrodes. Compared to applying a polarity-constant direct current, the polarity-reversal technique effectively inhibited extensive oxidation of the Ti electrode surface as indicated by a lower oxide/hydroxide content on the electrode surface, thus providing excellent stability during electrolysis. The natural irrigation water was collected from the Waiahole Ditch Irrigation System in Hawaii. The naturally occurring concentration of chloride in the water was 1.84 mg/L and no other chemicals were added. E. coli K12 ER2738 was selected as a model bacterium to evaluate the electrochemical cell&#8217;s disinfection capability. The applied current density was varied between 0 mA/cm2 and 2 mA/cm2, and the half-period (T/2) of the polarity-reversing direct current was varied between 5 s and 60 s. The best disinfection performance was achieved at 2 mA/cm2 and T/2 = 10 s, requiring only 5 min of treatment for the complete disinfection of E. coli (4-log reduction). The trends in the concentration of free and total chlorine in the solution matched very well with those of the disinfection efficiency, suggesting that E. coli was inactivated by free chlorine species electrogenerated at the Ti electrodes. Hydrogen peroxide, short-lived oxidants, and direct electron transfer most likely had minor contributions to the disinfection process. The presence of a volcano-shaped dependence of the free and total chlorine concentration and disinfection efficiency on T/2 suggests that the chloride oxidation activity of the Ti electrode was closely related to the oxidation state (or the thickness of the oxide layer) of the electrode surface, i.e., there exists an optimal oxide layer thickness at which the Ti electrode shows the highest electrocatalytic activity toward chloride oxidation. During the disinfection experiment, disinfection byproducts (DBPs) of chlorate, bromodichloromethane, dibromochloromethane, and bromoform were not detected in the solution. Chloroform was first seen in the solution at 10 min (2.5 &#956;g/L), and then its concentration increased to 9.0 &#956;g/L at 20 min. These values are significantly lower than recommendations for drinking water, and the timeframe of chloroform production suggests a 5 min disinfection treatment avoids significant DBP formation. As a comparison, Pt/Ti electrodes prepared by electrodeposition showed negligible disinfection at 2 mA/cm2, but the disinfection efficiency increased dramatically at 4 mA/cm2 and 6 mA/cm2. This phenomenon was most likely due to the Pt catalyst&#8217;s high activity, readily catalyzing side reactions such as oxygen evolution and oxidation of organic matter in the natural irrigation water. The Ti electrodes consumed less electrical energy than the Pt/Ti electrodes because they needed a lower current density to achieve similar disinfection efficiency. The current work demonstrates that the Ti electrode electrochemical cell can provide an efficient, robust, and cost-effective solution to irrigation water disinfection, and thus is well suited for agriculture sector applications.</description>
      <author>Geletu Qing, Mojtaba Abolhassani, Raheleh Daneshpour, Shelby L. Foster, Marty Matlock, Greg Thoma, Lauren Greenlee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/labqlv</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Widespread adaptive evolution in the photosystems of angiosperms provides new insight into the evolution of photosystem II repair.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.23.595573</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Hannah Joan Robbins, Steven Kelly, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399019908

                Oxygenic photosynthesis generates the initial energy source which fuels nearly all life on earth. At the heart of the process are the photosystems, pigment binding multi-protein complexes that catalyse the first step of photochemical conversion of light energy into chemical energy. Here, we investigate the molecular evolution at single residue resolution of the plastid-encoded subunits of the photosystems across 773 angiosperm species. We show that despite an extremely high level of conservation, 7% of residues in the photosystems, spanning all photosystem subunits, exhibit hallmarks of adaptive evolution. Through in silico modelling of these adaptive substitutions we uncover the impact of these changes on the properties of the photosystems, focussing on their effects on co-factor binding and the formation of inter-subunit interfaces. We further reveal that evolution has repeatedly destabilised the interaction photosystem II and its D1 subunit, thereby reducing the energetic barrier for D1 turn-over and photosystem repair. Together, these results provide new insight into the trajectory of photosystem evolution during the radiation of the angiosperms.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Hannah Joan Robbins, Steven Kelly</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.23.595573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and seasonal characteristics of organic vapors in urban Beijing: insights from Vocus-PTR measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1325</link>
      <description>Zhaojin An, Rujing Yin, Xinyan Zhao, Xiaoxiao Li, Ye Yuan, Jinxin Guo, Yuyang Li, X. Li, Dandan Li, Yaowei Li, Dongbin Wang, Chao Yan, Kebin He, Douglas R. Worsnop, Frank N. Keutsch, Jingkun Jiang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398219656

                Abstract. Understanding the compositions and evolution of atmospheric organic vapors is crucial for exploring their impact on air quality. However, the molecular and seasonal characteristics of organic vapors in urban areas, with complex anthropogenic emissions and high variability, remain inadequately understood. In this study, we conducted measurements in urban Beijing during 2021&#8211;2022 covering four seasons using a Vocus-PTR, an improved Proton Transfer Reaction-Mass Spectrometry (PTR-MS). During the measurement period, a total of 895 peaks are observed, and 543 of them can be assigned to formulas. The contribution of CxHyOz species is most significant, which compose up to 53.7 % of the number and 76.0 % of the mass of total organics. With enhanced sensitivity and mass resolution, various sub-ppt level species and organics with multiple oxygens (&#8805;3) were discovered. When counting the species number, 42.2 % of the organics measured are at sub-ppt level and 37.8 % of the species contain 3&#8211;8 oxygens. Organic vapors with multiple oxygens mainly consist of intermediate volatility and semi-volatile compounds, and many of them are found to be the multi-generational oxidation products of various volatile organic precursors. In summer, the fast photooxidation process generates organic vapors with multiple oxygens, and leads to an increase in both their concentration and proportion. While in other seasons, the variations of organic vapors with multiple oxygens are closely correlated with those of organic vapors with 1&#8211;2 oxygens, which could be heavily influenced by primary emissions. Organic vapors with low oxygen content (&#8804; 2 oxygens) are comparable to the results obtained by traditional PTR-MS measurements in both urban Beijing and neighboring regions.</description>
      <author>Zhaojin An, Rujing Yin, Xinyan Zhao, Xiaoxiao Li, Ye Yuan, Jinxin Guo, Yuyang Li, X. Li, Dandan Li, Yaowei Li, Dongbin Wang, Chao Yan, Kebin He, Douglas R. Worsnop, Frank N. Keutsch, Jingkun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinG3D: visualizing the spatio-temporal dynamics of clonal evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-024-05813-7</link>
      <description>Alan J. Hu, Awino Maureiq Edith Ojwang, Kayode D. Olumoyin, Katarzyna A. Rejniak, BMC bioinformatics. 25(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399044258

                Abstract Background Cancers are spatially heterogenous, thus their clonal evolution, especially following anti-cancer treatments, depends on where the mutated cells are located within the tumor tissue. For example, cells exposed to different concentrations of drugs, such as cells located near the vessels in contrast to those residing far from the vasculature, can undergo a different evolutionary path. However, classical representations of cell lineage trees do not account for this spatial component of emerging cancer clones. Here, we propose routines to trace spatial and temporal clonal evolution in computer simulations of the tumor evolution models. Results The LinG3D (Lineage Graphs in 3D) is an open-source collection of routines (in MATLAB, Python, and R) that enables spatio-temporal visualization of clonal evolution in a two-dimensional tumor slice from computer simulations of the tumor evolution models. These routines draw traces of tumor clones in both time and space, and may include a projection of a selected microenvironmental factor, such as the drug or oxygen distribution within the tumor, if such a microenvironmental factor is used in the tumor evolution model. The utility of LinG3D has been demonstrated through examples of simulated tumors with different number of clones and, additionally, in experimental colony growth assay. Conclusions This routine package extends the classical lineage trees, that show cellular clone relationships in time, by adding the space component to show the locations of cellular clones within the 2D tumor tissue patch from computer simulations of tumor evolution models.</description>
      <author>Alan J. Hu, Awino Maureiq Edith Ojwang, Kayode D. Olumoyin, Katarzyna A. Rejniak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-024-05813-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulate local chemical order to achieve high strength and ductility in TiZrNbVAl lightweight high entropy alloys via adding oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2024.146721</link>
      <description>Jiaxiang Cui, Bang Dou, Manling Sui, Nan Cui, Benpeng Wang, Shihai Sun, Hongnian Cai, Liang Wang, Yunfei Xue, Materials science and engineering. A, Structural materials: proporties, microstructures and processing/Materials science &amp; engineering. A, Structural materials: properties, microstructure and processing. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399035862

                TiZrNbVAl lightweight high-entropy alloys (LHEAs) with body-centered cubic (BCC) structure have received extensive attention due to their low density and considerable mechanical properties. And the mechanical properties of these LHEAs can be further improved by adjusting the local chemical order (LCO). Here, we report a strategy for regulating LCOs in TiZrNbVAl LHEAs by adding oxygen. The results showed that the yield strength of LHEA increased from 787.8 MPa to 1029.5 MPa after oxygen addition. Moreover, the microstructure evolution proves that LCOs is conducive to promoting the transition of dislocation from plane slip, which is easy to produce stress concentration, to multistage slip, which improves the homogenizing deformation ability, and increasing the ductility from 12.8% to 20.9%, which is an increase of &#8764;63%. Our work provides a paradigm for achieving outstanding strength-ductility tradeoff in BCC-LHEAs via O doping.</description>
      <author>Jiaxiang Cui, Bang Dou, Manling Sui, Nan Cui, Benpeng Wang, Shihai Sun, Hongnian Cai, Liang Wang, Yunfei Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2024.146721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROS-Resistant Redox Mediator in Lithium-Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4370577/v1</link>
      <description>Won&#8208;Jin Kwak, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Jisun Hwang, J.-H. Kim, Gabriel N. Morais, Kunlin Tang, Min Sun Choi, Hee Joung Choi, Hwa Shik Youn, Seoung&#8208;Tae Kim, Ju-Young Ha, Seok Ju Kang, Shuming Chen, Sung-Eun Suh, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398780276

                Abstract The utilization of redox mediators (RMs) in lithium-oxygen batteries (LOBs) have underscored their utility in addressing the challenge of the elevated overpotential during the charging process. Nonetheless, the generation of highly electrophilic singlet oxygen (1O2) throughout the battery cycles leads to adverse reactions with RMs, thereby impeding their effectiveness. In the quest for enhanced RM durability, this study unveils a novel RM, 7,7'-bi-7-azabicyclo[2.2.1]heptane (BAC), incorporating N&#8211;N interconnected aza-bicycles, and assesses its efficacy and robustness relative to those of other N&#8211;N non-bicyclic RMs. Unlike non-bicyclic RMs, which exhibit diminished O2 evolution after exposure to 1O2, BAC maintains consistent O2 profiles during charging, indicating its superior 1O2 resistance and steady redox-catalyst performance in LOBs. Theoretical analyses align with the experimental findings that the bicyclic structural design of BAC confers a superior ability to resist oxidative degradation through cleavage of the C&#8211;H bonds adjacent to nitrogen atoms.</description>
      <author>Won&#8208;Jin Kwak, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Jisun Hwang, J.-H. Kim, Gabriel N. Morais, Kunlin Tang, Min Sun Choi, Hee Joung Choi, Hwa Shik Youn, Seoung&#8208;Tae Kim, Ju-Young Ha, Seok Ju Kang, Shuming Chen, Sung-Eun Suh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4370577/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exciton Dissociation into Charge Carriers in Porphyrinic Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Light&#8208;Assisted Li&#8208;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405440</link>
      <description>Bo Wen, Yaohui Huang, Zhuoliang Jiang, Yuzhe Wang, Weibo Hua, Sylvio Indris, Fujun Li, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399041581

                Abstract Light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries exhibit a high round&#8208;trip efficiency attributable to the assistance of light&#8208;generated electrons and holes in oxygen reduction and evolution reactions. Nonetheless, the excitonic effect arising from Coulomb interaction between electrons and holes impedes carrier separation, thus hindering efficient utilization of photo&#8208;energy. Herein, porphyrinic metal&#8208;organic frameworks with (Fe 2 Ni)O(COO) 6 clusters were used as photocathodes to accelerate exciton dissociation into charge carriers for light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries. The coupling of Ni 3d and Fe 3d orbitals boosts ligand&#8208;to&#8208;metal cluster charge transfer, and hence drives exciton dissociation and activates O 2 for superoxide ( &#8226; O 2 &#8722; ) radicals, rather than singlet oxygen ( 1 O 2 ) under photoexcitation. These enable the light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries with a low total overvoltage of 0.28 V and round&#8208;trip efficiency of 92% under light irradiation of 100 mW cm &#8722;2 . This work highlights the excitonic effect in photoelectrochemical processes and provides insights into photocathode design for light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Bo Wen, Yaohui Huang, Zhuoliang Jiang, Yuzhe Wang, Weibo Hua, Sylvio Indris, Fujun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Observation of the Tetragonal-Orthorhombic transition in polycrystalline
  YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_{6+\delta}$ samples during the oxidation process at constant
  temperature via thermogravimetry and differential thermometry analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.12650</link>
      <description>Lorenzo Gallo, C. Sobrero, J. Malarr&#305;&#769;a, Roberto F. Luccas, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398230212

                This work examines the oxygenation process of polycrystalline powder of YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_{6+\delta}$ superconductor material through constant temperature thermogravimetric analysis. Starting from completely deoxygenated samples ($\delta$ = 0), both the mass evolution in an oxygen atmosphere and a differential temperature value referenced to an inert sample (alumina powder) subjected to the same experimental conditions are recorded. The oxygenation process itself is identified as an exothermic process accompanied by a second also exothermic associated process. This second process is identified as the Tetragonal-Orthorhombic transition present in the material. Based on the obtained results, the structural phase diagram of the material is reconstructed. Issues of metastability of the structural phases, as well as the potential of the equipment used to obtain these results comparable to those obtained in large facilities, are discussed. Reinterpretations of previously discussed works in the literature are inferred.</description>
      <author>Lorenzo Gallo, C. Sobrero, J. Malarr&#305;&#769;a, Roberto F. Luccas</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.12650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic and biochemical impacts on the development of hypoxia in the Louisiana&#8211;Texas shelf &#8211; Part 1: roles of nutrient limitation and plankton community</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-2385-2024</link>
      <description>Yanda Ou, Z. George Xue, Biogeosciences. 21(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398217385

                Abstract. A three-dimensional coupled hydrodynamic&#8211;biogeochemical model with multiple nutrient and plankton functional groups was developed and adapted to the Gulf of Mexico to investigate the role of nutrients and the complexity of plankton community in dissolved oxygen (DO) dynamics. A 15-year hindcast was achieved covering the period of 2006&#8211;2020. Extensive model validation against in situ data demonstrates that the model was capable of reproducing vertical distributions of DO and spatial distributions of bottom DO concentration, as well as their interannual variations. The study demonstrates that bottom DO dynamics and hypoxia evolution are significantly influenced by both physical processes and local biochemistry, with sedimentary oxygen consumption and vertical diffusion identified as key contributors. Summer hydrodynamics play a critical role in nutrient distribution and limitation: a notable expansion of Si limitation was simulated when coastal currents shifted eastward or northward. This effect, especially pronounced on the western part of the Louisiana&#8211;Texas shelf, underscores the importance of nutrient limitation in shaping DO dynamics. The model identifies a bi-peak primary production pattern in spring and early summer, aligned with satellite chlorophyll a variations, attributed to the complexity of the plankton community and interactions among different plankton groups. Our findings emphasize the necessity of integrating sophisticated plankton community dynamics into biogeochemical models to understand primary production variability and its impact on bottom hypoxia.</description>
      <author>Yanda Ou, Z. George Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-2385-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heat transfer and thermodynamic analysis of autothermal reactors by catalytic oxidation and steam-methanol reforming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/lckjue</link>
      <description>Junjie Chen, Harvard Dataverse. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4398632710

                Numerical simulations are carried out to understand the heat energy transport characteristics of an autothermal reactor by steam-methanol reforming on copper-based catalysts. Mathematical expressions are derived for the reactor system based upon the principles of chemical kinetics and fluid mechanics. Enthalpy analysis is performed and the evolution of energy in the reforming and oxidation processes is discussed in terms of reaction heat flux. The effects of different factors on the thermal behavior of the autothermal reactor is evaluated in order to fully describe the thermal energy change in the reactor. The objective of the present study is to understand the heat energy transport characteristics of microchannel reactors for hydrogen production by steam-methanol reforming on copper-based catalysts. Emphasis is placed on the effects of different factors on the thermal behavior of autothermal reactors. The results indicate that the heat required for the endothermic reforming reaction must pass through the wall of the tube. Minimal oxygen requirements serve to inhibit carbon formation in the catalyst bed. Small size and weight allow for rapid catalyst bed heat-up to operating temperatures which is a critical requirement for quick start capability necessary in most vehicle applications. The temperature within the hot spot can be increased or decreased respectively by increasing or decreasing respectively the amount of oxygen supplied to the mixture. Direct heating is of considerable advantage as it largely overcomes the problems encountered with reaction rates being limited by the rate of heat transfer through the tube wall. The intervening walls may be flat plates or cylindrical walls with heat transfer capabilities. The separation is often affected by an adsorption process after condensing out the steam from the shifted gas. Silicon is considered a good material for fabrication of microreactors due to the high strength of the silicon-silicon bonds which results in the chemical inertness and thermal stability of silicon.</description>
      <author>Junjie Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/lckjue</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magmatic and hydrothermal evolution of the superlarge Dashui goldfield in the West Qinling Orogen, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106095</link>
      <description>Haotian Yang, Fan Yang, Gilby Jepson, Leon Bagas, Jian Tu, Hongying Li, Zesheng Qian, Ore geology reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399030419

                Gold (Au) is a precious metal that has played an important role in the development of the global economy. It is therefore important to better define the genesis of Au mineralisation as an aid to focus exploration as the consumption of Au increases. The Dashui goldfield contains a super large Au resource of over 120 t (tonnes) in the West Qinling Orogen, central China. Despite several studies have focused on the genesis of the Dashui goldfield, the original physico&#8211;chemical natures of the magmatic and hydrothermal evolution remain unclear. Biotite and apatite in the mineralised diorite porphyry in the goldfield are sensitive to the changes in the physico&#8211;chemical conditions and the evolution of magmatic and hydrothermal fluids, and thus provide important keys to address these issues. Hence, we conducted detailed in&#8211;situ major and trace element studies of biotite and apatite from the ore&#8211;bearing diorite porphyry in the Dashui goldfield. Our aim is to elucidate the physico&#8211;chemical conditions, magma source, and the magmatic and hydrothermal evolution processes during the deposition of the gold, and to enhance the understanding of the Au genesis in the West Qinling Au province. Using the geochemistry of magmatic apatite, and magmatic and hydrothermal biotite, we have found that the crystallisation temperature and pressure along with emplacement depth of diorite porphyry were constrained at &#8764; 737&#8211;791 &#176;C, 1.08&#8211;1.73 kbar, and 3.94&#8211;6.30 km. The diorite porphyry has the geochemical affinities with calcium alkaline orogenic suites derived from a mixed crustal and mantle source. During the early emplacement of the diorite porphyry, the melt had a high oxygen fugacity and was highly enriched in Au. During the late magma crystallisation of the diorite porphyry, the magma was enriched continuously in most elements with the Ba/Rb ratios in the biotite varying from 10 to 5, and most of the Au was hosted by pyrite. Additionally, elements were continuously dissolved into fluids generating Cl&#8211;rich hydrothermal fluids during the evolution of the magma. During hydrothermal evolution, Au is migrated with As and Sb in the vapour phases of fluids, whereas Au migrated with Cl in the liquid phase. When temperatures dropped to &#8764; 200&#8211;400 &#176;C, Au started to combine with S and Si in the liquid phase of fluids. Subsequently, hydrothermal fluids interacted with host carbonate to form the Dashui goldfield, the Au during this stage was also transported and hosted in magnetite, hematite, and quartz within the carbonate rocks.</description>
      <author>Haotian Yang, Fan Yang, Gilby Jepson, Leon Bagas, Jian Tu, Hongying Li, Zesheng Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of electric field on bubble generation and dissolution characteristics in oil&#8211;paper insulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1049/hve2.12456</link>
      <description>Chaojie Yang, Tao Zhao, Yunpeng Liu, Jiajun Yang, Jiaxue Xu, Yingcong Xu, High voltage. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398261700

                Abstract The interturn paper insulation of oil&#8208;immersed power transformer windings, under the combined influence of electric fields, moisture, and conductor heating, will produce bubbles, which pose a significant threat to the insulation system. However, there is limited research on the characteristics of bubble evolution in oil&#8211;paper insulation under the influence of electric fields and the subsequent dissolution process. Based on the continuous observation of bubble size using electron microscopes, experimental and theoretical investigations into the formation and dissolution of bubbles under electric field conditions are presented. The effects of different field strengths on bubble evolution and dissolution characteristics were studied. The results showed that the electric field promoted both the generation and dissolution of bubbles, with a more pronounced effect observed at higher field strengths (below partial discharge (PD) inception electric field, hereafter referred to as PDIE). However, when the field strength exceeded PDIE, the bubbles tended to shrink and gradually increase in size. The changes in bubble volume were related to not only gas diffusion but also oxygen consumption and fault gases generation due to PD. A better understanding of the formation and dissolution characteristics of bubbles under varying field strengths is achieved. Furthermore, it also provides a reference for assessing the risk of bubble generation and conducting bubble&#8208;related fault diagnosis during the overload operation of oil&#8208;immersed power equipment.</description>
      <author>Chaojie Yang, Tao Zhao, Yunpeng Liu, Jiajun Yang, Jiaxue Xu, Yingcong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1049/hve2.12456</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Reversible Sn&#8208;Air Battery Possessing the Ultra&#8208;Low Charging Potential with the Assistance of Light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407856</link>
      <description>Mingze Gao, Ruiya Wang, Xinxin L&#252;, Yanchen Fan, Ziyang Guo, Yonggang Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399011189

                Aqueous Sn&#8208;air batteries are attracting a great deal of interest in recent years due to the ultra&#8208;high safety, low cost, dendrite&#8208;free and highly reversible Sn anode. However, the slurry oxygen reduction/evolution reaction (ORR/OER) kinetics on the air cathodes seriously affect the Sn&#8208;air battery performances. Although various advanced catalysts have been developed, the charge overpotentials (~1000 mV) of these Sn&#8208;air batteries are still not satisfactory. Herein, iron oxide (Fe2O3) modified titanium dioxide (TiO2) nanorods with heterogeneous structure are firstly synthesized on Ti mesh (Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti), and the obtained Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti is further applied as catalytic electrodes for Sn&#8208;air batteries. The core&#8208;shell heterogeneous structure of Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti can effectively facilitate the conversion of electrochemical intermediates and separation of photo&#8208;excited electrons and holes to active oxygen&#8208;related reaction processes. DFT and experimental results also confirm that Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti can not only act as the electrocatalysts to improve ORR/OER properties, but also exhibit the superior photo&#8208;catalytic activity to promote charge kinetics. Hence, the Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti&#8208;based Sn&#8208;air batteries show ultra&#8208;low overpotential of ~40 mV, excellent rate capability and good cycling stability under light irradiation. This work will shed light on rational photo&#8208;assisted catalytic cathode design for new&#8208;type metal&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Mingze Gao, Ruiya Wang, Xinxin L&#252;, Yanchen Fan, Ziyang Guo, Yonggang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing sulfur redox state and geochemical implications in deep-time using mineral chemistry network analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.024</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Hern&#225;ndez Moore, Joseph Diedolf, S. M. Morrison, Daniel R. Hummer, Geochimica et cosmochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398794660

                Sulfur (S) is a central element in global biogeochemical cycling and Earth's redox evolution. Minerals that contain S are an important record of local environmental conditions at the time of their formation based on chemical speciation and redox. However, the oxidation state of S for hundreds of different S-containing minerals and thousands of S-containing mineral localities is unknown, largely sulfides and sulfosalts, and the redox state alone does not fully capture mineral chemistry diversity, thus limiting understanding of S redox evolution. Here, we use mineral chemistry network analysis and the weighted Mineral Element Electronegativity Coefficient of Variation (wMEECV) metric to investigate the element interactions and localities of S-containing minerals from the Mineral Evolution Database (MED) to infer the redox state of S in minerals where the redox state is unknown (SU). Louvain community detection of the S mineral chemistry redox network reveals that there are three main network communities that are separated by redox state. The S6+ community includes minerals that contain the S6+ redox state and a small number of S4+ and S2+ minerals, the S2&#8722; community includes S2&#8722;-containing minerals, and the SU community includes minerals in which the redox state of S is unknown. The wMEECV values of the SU community closely overlap with the wMEECV values of the S2&#8722; community, and do not overlap with the wMEECV values of the S6+ community, indicating the SU community minerals contain predominately reduced S. Assuming that SU community minerals contain reduced S, as supported by their network chemical associations and wMEECV values, then reduced S-containing minerals make up approximately 81 % of S-containing mineral localities in the S mineral chemistry network, even though the majority of all mineral localities (S-containing and non-S-containing) are oxygen (O)-containing minerals. Additionally, reduced S-containing minerals make up the majority (&#8764;75 %) of all non-O containing mineral localities in the MED, representing the importance of reduced S as an electron source and substrate in the evolution of microbial metabolic networks. The range wMEECV values of S6+ community minerals expands through time due primarily to formation of chemically diverse sulfate minerals, coinciding with crustal oxidation from the late Proterozoic to Phanerozoic and the expansion of the marine sulfate reservoir. The intersection of shared constituent elements among reduced and oxidized S in the mineral chemistry network represents redox convergence of weathered S in the geosphere that was crucial in the formation of natural resource deposits and the evolution of biogeochemical cycles.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Hern&#225;ndez Moore, Joseph Diedolf, S. M. Morrison, Daniel R. Hummer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Catalytic Activity of Magnetic Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/magnetochemistry10060040</link>
      <description>Ian Shuttleworth, Magnetochemistry. 10(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399073281

                High-performance catalysts for the oxygen reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions (ORR and HER, respectively) are highly sought-after, particularly with the commitment of numerous agencies to the removal of conventional gas vehicles in the next few decades. Surprisingly little focus has been placed on the development of magnetic models to describe these systems. The current work will review the current understanding of surface heterogeneous catalysis across select magnetic surfaces, with attention focused on studies involving extended surfaces, which inherently are more accessible to fundamental analysis than the more applied nanoparticle systems. However, even the most up-to-date magnetic variants of this theory have focused on the tight binding limit of the d-band model. In this limit, the reactivity of the surface is governed by the position of the center of the d-band, and the model does not account for the higher moments of the d-band, such as the width, asymmetry, and modality. A summary of the theory supporting this analysis will be presented, along with a summary of the current literature on this level of analysis. The review will then conclude with a discussion of suggested directions for future investigations.</description>
      <author>Ian Shuttleworth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/magnetochemistry10060040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>West African Monsoon Dynamics and Its Control on the Stable Oxygen Isotopic Composition of Precipitation in the Late Cenozoic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024jd040748</link>
      <description>Daniel Boateng, Jeffrey N. A. Aryee, Michael Baidu, Frank H. Arthur, Sebastian G. Mutz, Journal of geophysical research. Atmospheres. 129(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398259253

                Abstract This study presents an overview of the Late Cenozoic evolution of the West African Monsoon (WAM), and the associated changes in atmospheric dynamics and oxygen isotopic composition of precipitation (&#948; 18 O p ). This evolution is established by using the high&#8208;resolution isotope&#8208;enabled GCM ECHAM5&#8208;wiso to simulate the climatic responses to paleoenvironmental changes during the Mid&#8208;Holocene (MH), Last Glacial Maximum (LGM), and Mid&#8208;Pliocene (MP). The simulated responses are compared to a set of GCM outputs from Paleoclimate Model Intercomparison Project Phase 4 (PMIP4) to assess the added value of a high resolution and model consistency across different time periods. Results show WAM magnitudes and pattern changes that are consistent with PMIP4 models and proxy reconstructions. ECHAM5&#8208;wiso estimates the highest WAM intensification in the MH, with a precipitation increase of up to 150 mm/month reaching 25&#176;N during the monsoon season. The WAM intensification in the MP estimated by ECHAM5&#8208;wiso (up to 80 mm/month) aligns with the mid&#8208;range of the PMIP4 estimates, while the LGM dryness magnitude matches most of the models. Despite an enhanced hydrological cycle in MP, MH simulations indicate a &#8764;50% precipitation increase and a greater northward extent of WAM than the MP simulations. Strengthened conditions of the WAM in the MH and MP result from a pronounced meridional temperature gradient driving low&#8208;level westerly, Sahel&#8208;Sahara vegetation expansion, and a northward shift of the Africa Easterly Jet. The simulated &#948; 18 O p values patterns and their relationship with temperature and precipitation are non&#8208;stationarity over time, emphasizing the implications of assuming stationarity in proxy reconstruction transfer functions.</description>
      <author>Daniel Boateng, Jeffrey N. A. Aryee, Michael Baidu, Frank H. Arthur, Sebastian G. Mutz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024jd040748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arousal as a universal embedding for spatiotemporal brain dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.njvyzq</link>
      <description>Ryan V. Raut, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4399071520

                Neural activity in awake organisms shows widespread and spatiotemporally diverse correlations with behavioral and physiological measurements. We propose that this covariation reflects in part the dynamics of a unified, arousal-related process that regulates brain-wide physiology on the timescale of seconds. Taken together with theoretical foundations in dynamical systems, this interpretation leads us to a surprising prediction: that a single, scalar measurement of arousal (e.g., pupil diameter) should suffice to reconstruct the continuous evolution of multimodal, spatiotemporal measurements of large-scale brain physiology. To test this hypothesis, we perform multimodal, cortex-wide optical imaging and behavioral monitoring in awake mice. We demonstrate that spatiotemporal measurements of neuronal calcium, metabolism, and blood-oxygen can be accurately and parsimoniously modeled from a low-dimensional state-space reconstructed from the time history of pupil diameter. Extending this framework to behavioral and electrophysiological measurements from the Allen Brain Observatory, we demonstrate the ability to integrate diverse experimental data into a unified generative model via mappings from an intrinsic arousal manifold. Our results support the hypothesis that spontaneous, spatially structured fluctuations in brain-wide physiology&#8212;widely interpreted to reflect regionally-specific neural communication&#8212;are in large part reflections of an arousal-related process. This enriched view of arousal dynamics has broad implications for interpreting observations of brain, body, and behavior as measured across modalities, contexts, and scales.</description>
      <author>Ryan V. Raut</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.njvyzq</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct estimates of nitrogen abundance for Seyfert 2 nuclei</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.13906</link>
      <description>O. L. Dors, M. V. Cardaci, G. F. H&#228;gele, M. Valerdi, Gabriele da Silva Ilha, C. B. Oliveira, Rogemar A. Riffel, Sophia R. Flury, K. Z. Arellano-C&#243;rdova, T. Storchi-Bergmann, Rogemar A. Riffel, Guilherme C. Almeida, I. N. Morais, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399026240

                We derive the nitrogen and oxygen abundances in the Narrow Line Regions (NLRs) of a sample of 38 local ($z \: &lt; \: 0.4$) Seyfert~2 nuclei. For that, we consider narrow optical emission line intensities and direct estimates of the electron temperatures ($T_{\rm e}$-method). We find nitrogen abundances in the range $7.6 \: &lt; \: \rm 12+log(N/H) \: &lt; \: 8.6$ (mean value $8.06\pm0.22$) or $\rm 0.4 \: &lt; \: (N/N_{\odot}) \: &lt; 4.7$, in the metallicity regime $8.3 \: &lt; \: \rm 12+log(O/H) \: &lt; \: 9.0$. Our results indicate that the dispersion in N/H abundance for a fixed O/H value in AGNs is in agreement with that for disc \ion{H}{ii} regions with similar metallicity. We show that Seyfert~2 nuclei follow a similar (N/O)-(O/H) relation to the one followed by star-forming objects. Finally, we find that active galaxies called as 'nitrogen-loud' observed at very high redshift ($z \: &gt; \: 5$) show N/O values in consonance with those derived for local NLRs. This result indicates that the main star-formation event is completed in the early evolution stages of active galaxies.</description>
      <author>O. L. Dors, M. V. Cardaci, G. F. H&#228;gele, M. Valerdi, Gabriele da Silva Ilha, C. B. Oliveira, Rogemar A. Riffel, Sophia R. Flury, K. Z. Arellano-C&#243;rdova, T. Storchi-Bergmann, Rogemar A. Riffel, Guilherme C. Almeida, I. N. Morais</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.13906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depth-resolved Characterization of Meissner Screening Breakdown in Surface Treated Niobium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4402391/v1</link>
      <description>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. Andrew MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398268608

                Abstract We report direct measurements of the magnetic field screening at the limits of the Meissner phase for two superconducting Nb samples. The samples are processed with two different surface treatments that have been developed for superconducting radio-frequency cavity applications &#8212; a &#8220;baseline&#8221; treatment and an oxygen-doping (&#8220;O-doping&#8221; ) treatment. The measurements show: 1) that the screening length is significantly longer in the &#8220;O-doping&#8221; sample compared to the &#8220;baseline&#8221; sample; 2) that the screening length near the limits of the Meissner phase increases with applied field; 3) the evolution of the screening profile as the material transitions from the Meissner phase to the mixed phase; and 4) a demonstration of the absence of any screening profile for the highest applied field, indicative of the full flux entering the sample. Measurements are performed utilizing the &#946; -detected nuclear magnetic resonance (&#946; -NMR) technique that allows depth resolved studies of the local magnetic field within the first 100 nm of the surface. The study takes advantage of the &#946; -SRF beamline, a new facility at TRIUMF, Canada, where field levels up to 200 mT are available parallel to the sample surface to replicate radio frequency (RF) fields near the Meissner breakdown limits of Nb.</description>
      <author>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. Andrew MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4402391/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of orbital ordering in cooperative Jahn-Teller models:
  Machine-learning enabled large-scale simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.14776</link>
      <description>S. K. Ghosh, Sheng Zhang, Chun&#8208;Yu Cheng, Gia-Wei Chern, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398886343

                We present a scalable machine learning (ML) force-field model for the adiabatic dynamics of cooperative Jahn-Teller (JT) systems. Large scale dynamical simulations of the JT model also shed light on the orbital ordering dynamics in colossal magnetoresistance manganites. The JT effect in these materials describes the distortion of local oxygen octahedra driven by a coupling to the orbital degrees of freedom of $e_g$ electrons. An effective electron-mediated interaction between the local JT modes leads to a structural transition and the emergence of long-range orbital order at low temperatures. Assuming the principle of locality, a deep-learning neural-network model is developed to accurately and efficiently predict the electron-induced forces that drive the dynamical evolution of JT phonons. A group-theoretical method is utilized to develop a descriptor that incorporates the combined orbital and lattice symmetry into the ML model. Large-scale Langevin dynamics simulations, enabled by the ML force-field models, are performed to investigate the coarsening dynamics of the composite JT distortion and orbital order after a thermal quench. The late-stage coarsening of orbital domains exhibits pronounced freezing behaviors which are likely related to the unusual morphology of the domain structures. Our work highlights a promising avenue for multi-scale dynamical modeling of correlated electron systems.</description>
      <author>S. K. Ghosh, Sheng Zhang, Chun&#8208;Yu Cheng, Gia-Wei Chern</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.14776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and Evolution In Silico Studies Unlock the h4-HPPD C-Terminal Tail Gating Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines12061196</link>
      <description>Alfonso Trezza, Ancuta Birgauan, Michela Geminiani, Anna Visibelli, Annalisa Santucci, Biomedicines. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399105635

                The enzyme 4-hydroxyphenylpyruvate dioxygenase (4-HPPD) is involved in the catabolism of the amino acid tyrosine in organisms such as bacteria, plants, and animals. It catalyzes the conversion of 4-hydroxyphenylpyruvate to a homogenisate in the presence of molecular oxygen and Fe(II) as a cofactor. This enzyme represents a key step in the biosynthesis of important compounds, and its activity deficiency leads to severe, rare autosomal recessive disorders, like tyrosinemia type III and hawkinsinuria, for which no cure is currently available. The 4-HPPD C-terminal tail plays a crucial role in the enzyme catalysis/gating mechanism, ensuring the integrity of the active site for catalysis through fine regulation of the C-terminal tail conformation. However, despite growing interest in the 4-HPPD catalytic mechanism and structure, the gating mechanism remains unclear. Furthermore, the absence of the whole 3D structure makes the bioinformatic approach the only possible study to define the enzyme structure/molecular mechanism. Here, wild-type 4-HPPD and its mutants were deeply dissected by applying a comprehensive bioinformatics/evolution study, and we showed for the first time the entire molecular mechanism and regulation of the enzyme gating process, proposing the full-length 3D structure of human 4-HPPD and two novel key residues involved in the 4-HPPD C-terminal tail conformational change.</description>
      <author>Alfonso Trezza, Ancuta Birgauan, Michela Geminiani, Anna Visibelli, Annalisa Santucci</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines12061196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cable&#8208;Stayed Honeycomb Superstructure to Improve the Stability of Li&#8208;Rich Materials via Inhibiting Interlaminar Lattice Strain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404982</link>
      <description>Yunshan Jiang, Zhirong Liao, Fu&#8208;Da Yu, Ke Wang, Xin&#8208;yu Li, Xiawei Yang, Guoren Xu, Gang Sun, Yuanguang Xia, Wen Yin, Liang Deng, Linjie Zhao, Zhen Wang, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398247794

                Abstract In layered Li&#8208;rich materials, over stoichiometric Li forms an ordered occupation of LiTM6 in TM layer, showing a honeycomb superstructure along [001] direction. At the atomic scale, the instability of the superstructure at high voltage is the root cause of problems such as capacity/voltage decay of Li&#8208;rich materials. Here we report a Li&#8208;rich material with a high Li/Ni disorder, these interlayer Ni atoms locate above the honeycomb superstructure and share adjacent O coordination with honeycomb TM. These Ni&#8208;O bonds act as cable&#8208;stayed bridge to the honeycomb plane, and improve the high&#8208;voltage stability. The cable&#8208;stayed honeycomb superstructure is confirmed by in&#8208;situ X&#8208;ray diffraction to have a unique cell evolution mechanism that it can alleviate interlaminar lattice strain by promoting in&#8208;plane expansion along a&#8208;axis and inhibiting c&#8208;axis stretching. Electrochemical tests also demonstrate significantly improved long cycle performance after 500 cycles (86% for Li&#8208;rich/Li half cell and 82% for Li&#8208;rich/Si&#8208;C full cell) and reduced irreversible oxygen release. This work proves the feasibility of achieving outstanding stability of lithium&#8208;rich materials through superstructure regulation and provides new insights for the development of the next&#8208;generation high&#8208;energy&#8208;density cathodes. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Yunshan Jiang, Zhirong Liao, Fu&#8208;Da Yu, Ke Wang, Xin&#8208;yu Li, Xiawei Yang, Guoren Xu, Gang Sun, Yuanguang Xia, Wen Yin, Liang Deng, Linjie Zhao, Zhen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404982</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase Engineering and Dispersion Stabilization of Cobalt toward Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310499</link>
      <description>Chao Zhang, Yihang Luo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399069290

                Abstract Phase engineering is promising to increase the intrinsic activity of the catalyst toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, the polymorphism interface is unstable due to the presence of metastable phases. Herein, phase engineering and dispersion stabilization are applied simultaneously to boost the HER activity of cobalt without sacrificing the stability. A fast and facile approach (plasma cathodic electro deposition) is developed to prepare cobalt film with a hetero&#8208;phase structure. The polymorphs of cobalt are realized through reduced stacking fault energy due to the doping of Mo, and the high temperature treatment resulted from the plasma discharge. Meanwhile, homogeneously dispersed oxide/carbide nanoparticles are produced from the reaction of plasma&#8208;induced oxygen/carbon atoms with electro&#8208;deposited metal. The existence of rich polymorphism interface and oxide/carbide help to facilitate H 2 production by the tuning of electronic structure and the increase of active sites. Furthermore, oxide/carbide dispersoid effectively prevents the phase transition through a pinning effect on the grain boundary. As&#8208;prepared Co&#8208;hybrid/CoO_MoC exhibits both high HER activity and robust stability (44 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , Tafel slope of 53.2 mV dec &#8722;1 , no degradation after 100 h test). The work reported here provides an alternate approach to the design of advanced HER catalysts for real application.</description>
      <author>Chao Zhang, Yihang Luo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling of multiple-defect conducting, planar protonic ceramic electrolysis cells using a Nernst&#8211;Planck formulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234706</link>
      <description>Amogh Thatte, Michael Pastula, Anthony Wood, Huayang Zhu, Robert J. Kee, Robert J. Braun, Journal of power sources. 611(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398793528

                Advancing protonic ceramic electrochemical cell (PCEC) technology offers promise for a variety of energy applications, including membrane reactors, fuel cells, and electrolyzers. Computational modeling of PCECs requires tracking the movement of three mobile charge carriers: protons, oxygen vacancies, and small polarons to adequately predict the cell operating characteristics. This paper develops an experimentally validated, quasi-2D (1+ 1D), transient, dual-channel cell model based on a multiple-charged defect-conducting electrolyte. The new model advances predictive capabilities on a number of fronts. First, it reduces empiricism, simplifies integration of experimentally derived modeling parameters, and enables rapid model scale-up to large cell platforms. Additionally, it predicts the distribution of properties in the streamwise gas flow direction and cell faradaic efficiency over a wide range of operating cell conditions helping to establish the inlet gas conditions needed to produce a dry hydrogen product gas. Model simulation reveals that the evolution of steady-state, thermal-neutral voltages in a PCEC can significantly change from initial operating values due to a dynamic, complex interaction which arises from local decreases in faradaic efficiency. Insights from model-based performance predictions touch upon thermal management considerations and the means for regulating cell temperature when trying to achieve either adiabatic or quasi-isothermal PCEC operation.</description>
      <author>Amogh Thatte, Michael Pastula, Anthony Wood, Huayang Zhu, Robert J. Kee, Robert J. Braun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecological and Health Risks of Vanadium in the Biogeosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44169-024-00065-1</link>
      <description>Mengnan Wang, Baogang Zhang, Han Zhang, Rongyue Geng, Yi Huang, Wenyan He, Yanguo Teng, Reviews of environmental contamination and toxicology. 262(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398774327

                Vanadium (V) is ubiquitously distributed in environmental media, imposing toxic hazards to organisms in biogeosphere. This review focuses on a comprehensive summary of the ecological and human health risks ascribed to V pollution, based on existing V toxicity relevant publications. Lower doses of V (&lt; 2 mg/L) is beneficial to plant growth, however, V reduces plant biomass, induces toxic effects on plant morphology and adversely affects the absorption of essential plant elements at higher levels (&#8805; 2 mg/L). Oxidative stress induced by reactive oxygen species (ROS) produced under V stress may be the main reason for V toxicity to terrestrial and aquatic organisms. Although V contributes to high-efficient biological nitrogen fixation as a co-factor, V alters microbial community structures and drives its evolution. V can also accumulate in and harm human bodies. Knowledge gaps and further perspectives in aspects of V risks are thereby proposed, such as more toxic data reports for deriving V environmental quality criteria, elucidating the molecular mechanisms of detoxification and tolerance of organisms to V for bioremediation applications, and exploring the medical potential of V with the prevention of V toxicity to humans. This review advances our understanding of the toxic effects of V in the ecosystem and inspires future efforts on V management as well as application.</description>
      <author>Mengnan Wang, Baogang Zhang, Han Zhang, Rongyue Geng, Yi Huang, Wenyan He, Yanguo Teng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44169-024-00065-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological assessment of oocyte quality during assisted reproductive technology cycle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5935/1518-0557.20240034</link>
      <description>Romualdo Sciorio, Luca Tramontano, Pierfrancesco Greco, Ermanno Greco, JBRA. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398763901

                Following the advancement of medically assisted reproduction (MAR) technology, and the rationale to extend the culture to the blastocyst stage, performing elective single embryo transfer (eSET), gamete quality and assessment have acquired large relevance in ART. Embryo quality is strictly correlated with gametes quality and culture conditions. Oocyte maturity assessment is therefore imperative for fertilization and embryo evolution. Mature oocytes at the metaphase II stage result in a higher fertilization rate compared to immature oocytes. Indeed, oocyte morphology evaluation represents an important and challenging task that may serve as a valuable prognostic tool for future embryo development and implantation potential. Different grading systems have been reported to assess human embryos, however, in many cases, it is still a major challenge to select the single embryo to transfer with the highest implantation potential. Further, eSET has conferred a challenge to embryologists, who must try to enhance embryo culture and selection to provide an adequate success rate, whilst reducing the overall number of embryos transferred. Above the standard morphological assessment, there are several invasive or non-invasive approaches for embryo selection such as preimplantation genetic testing, time-lapse technology, proteomics and metabolomics, as well as oxygen utilization and analysis of oxidative stress in culture medium. This short review is not designed to be a comprehensive review of all possible features that may influence oocyte quality. It does give, however, a brief overview and describes the prognostic value of the morphological characteristics of human oocytes on their developmental capacity following ART treatments.</description>
      <author>Romualdo Sciorio, Luca Tramontano, Pierfrancesco Greco, Ermanno Greco</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5935/1518-0557.20240034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of oxide inclusions and cleanliness control in Al-killed GCr15SiMn bearing steel during secondary refining process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233231222113</link>
      <description>Guolei Zhang, Guoguang Cheng, Tao&#65533; Zhang, Hongsheng Miao, Zhong Xu, Ironmaking &amp; steelmaking. 51(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399057676

                The evolution of oxide inclusions and cleanliness control in Al-killed GCr15SiMn bearing steel was investigated using a combination of industrial tests and thermodynamic calculations during the secondary refining process. Three different refining conditions were employed in the LF process. With varying ranges of slag basicity (about 5.6&#8211;5.7, 4.8&#8211;4.9 and 3.9&#8211;4.3) and Al content (0.028&#8211;0.035 mass%, 0.023&#8211;0.025 mass% and 0.014&#8211;0.02 mass%), the total oxygen content in the steel after VD refining was measured as 0.0019 mass%, 0.0017 mass% and 0.0008 mass%, respectively. Throughout the refining process, the inclusions underwent a transformation from MgO-Al 2 O 3 (or Al 2 O 3 ) into CaO-Al 2 O 3 (-MgO), and eventually to CaO-Al 2 O 3 -SiO 2 inclusions. Furthermore, it was observed that under high Al content and slag basicity refining conditions, a significant number of inclusions in VD treatment were formed and transformed into CaO&#183;Al 2 O 3 &#183;SiO 2 inclusions enriched with 60 mass% CaO. This indicated that when the proportion of CaO in calcium aluminates exceeded 45 mass%, there was an increased risk of larger-sized inclusions. Conversely, refining conditions with a slag basicity of 3.9&#8211;4.3 and an Al content of 0.014&#8211;0.02 mass% demonstrated effective inclusion control, resulting in lower number density, smaller sizes within 10 &#956;m and an average composition located in the liquid region. This study carries important practical significance for the smelting of high cleanliness GCr15SiMn bearing steel.</description>
      <author>Guolei Zhang, Guoguang Cheng, Tao&#65533; Zhang, Hongsheng Miao, Zhong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233231222113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub&#8208;2 Nm Micro&#8208;Strained High&#8208;Entropy&#8208;Alloy Nanoparticles Boosts Hydrogen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403674</link>
      <description>Heng Luo, L&#252; Li, Fangxu Lin, Q. Zhang, Kai Wang, Dawei Wang, Lin Gu, Mingchuan Luo, Fan Lv, Shaojun Guo, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399019008

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy alloys (HEAs) confine multifarious elements into the same lattice, leading to intense lattice distortion effect. The lattice distortion tends to induce local microstrain at atomic level and thus affect surface adsorptions towards different adsorbates in various electrocatalytic reactions, yet remains unexplored. Herein, we report a class of sub&#8208;2 nm IrRuRhMoW HEA nanoparticles (NPs) with distinct local microstrain induced by lattice distortion for boosting alkaline hydrogen oxidation (HOR) and evolution reactions (HER). We demonstrate that the distortion&#8208;rich HEA catalysts with optimized electronic structure can downshift the d&#8208;band center and generate uncoordinated oxygen sites to enhance the surface oxophilicity. As a result, the IrRuRhMoW HEA NPs show a remarkable HOR kinetic current density of 8.09 mA &#956;g &#8208;1 PGM at 50 mV versus RHE, 8.89, 22.47 times higher than those of IrRuRh NPs without internal strain and commercial Pt/C, respectively, which is the best value among all the reported non&#8208;Pt based catalysts. IrRuRhMoW HEA NPs also display great HER performances with a TOF value of 5.93 H 2 s &#8208;1 at 70 mV versus RHE, 4.6&#8208;fold higher than that of Pt/C catalyst, exceeding most noble metal&#8208;based catalysts. Experimental characterizations and theoretical studies collectively confirm that weakened hydrogen (H ad ) and enhanced hydroxyl (OH ad ) adsorption are achieved by simultaneously modulating the hydrogen adsorption binding energy and surface oxophilicity originated from intensified ligand effect and microstrain effect over IrRuRhMoW HEA NPs, which guarantees the remarkable performances toward HOR/HER. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Heng Luo, L&#252; Li, Fangxu Lin, Q. Zhang, Kai Wang, Dawei Wang, Lin Gu, Mingchuan Luo, Fan Lv, Shaojun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403674</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction Activity and Suppression of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction for Transition Metal Oxide Catalysts: The Role of Proton Intercalation and Heteroatom Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00223</link>
      <description>Qingdong Li, Oguz Kaan Kucukosman, Qingquan Ma, Junjie Ouyang, Pavel Kucheryavy, Hengfei Gu, Conor Long, Z. Y. Zhang, Joshua Young, Jenny V. Lockard, Eric Garfunkel, Jianan Gao, Zhang Wen, Huixin He, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398764852

                During the electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), interstitial proton intercalation readily occurs in some transition metal oxide (TMO) catalysts and changes their d-band electronic structure. This work fabricated phosphorus (P)-doped tungsten oxide (WO3) with enriched oxygen vacancies (OVs) to study the impact of proton intercalation and heteroatom doping on eNRR and HER. Our results demonstrated that the electronic structure of the P-OV-WO3 catalyst was altered by in situ proton intercalation as indicated by the greater negative onset potential of eNRR at &#8722;0.05 V compared to the proton intercalation potential of 0.3 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). Compared to the non-P-doped WO3, the introduction of P doping in WO3 (e.g., 4.8 at. %) led to a reduction of more than 36% in proton intercalation. As a result, the HER activity of the P-OV-WO3 was significantly suppressed, as demonstrated by a considerably negative shift of the onset HER potential from &#8722;0.06 to &#8722;0.15 V and a slower HER kinetics with the Tafel slope increased from 129.0 to 343.1 mV/dec. Density functional theory calculations revealed the synergy of the proton intercalation, substitutional P doping, and the associated OVs in the improvement of N2 activation and hydrogenation in eNRR. The increased eNRR and the suppressed HER led to a high Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 64.1% and the NH3 yield of 24.5 &#956;g&#183;mg cat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.15 V versus RHE in H2SO4 (pH = 2) as the electrolyte. The specific NH3 yield is more than 20 times higher than that of C-WO3 (1.1 &#956;g&#183;mg cat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 with a FE of 20%). The results exceed most of the reported eNRR performances for TMO-based catalysts. Thus, the synergistic proton intercalation and P doping could lead to newer designs and applications of TMO-based catalysts for improved eNRR while suppressing the competing HER.</description>
      <author>Qingdong Li, Oguz Kaan Kucukosman, Qingquan Ma, Junjie Ouyang, Pavel Kucheryavy, Hengfei Gu, Conor Long, Z. Y. Zhang, Joshua Young, Jenny V. Lockard, Eric Garfunkel, Jianan Gao, Zhang Wen, Huixin He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferric iron in eclogitic garnet and clinopyroxene from the V. Grib kimberlite pipe (NW Russia): evidence of a highly oxidized subducted slab</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/petrology/egae054</link>
      <description>Marras Giulia, Martine Denis, Arvieux Catherine, Agasheva Elena, Vincenzo Stagno, Journal of petrology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398782767

                Abstract Estimates of oxygen fugacity of eclogitic rocks are linked to the redox evolution of the oceanic protolith during subduction and its residence in the lithospheric mantle, and, based on knowledge of pressures and temperatures, allow modelling of the speciation of volatile elements and diamond (or graphite) versus carbonate stability. To date, the oxygen fugacity of mantle eclogites has been shown to vary between -6 (Kasai, Congo and Udachnaya, Siberia) and -0.1 (Udachnaya, Siberia) log units (relative to the fayalite-magnetite-quartz buffer, FMQ), linked to the low Fe3+ contents of garnets. In this study we investigated the Fe oxidation state of coexisting garnet and clinopyroxene hand-picked out of 17 diamond-free high-MgO and low-MgO mantle eclogites (dated at 2.84 Ga) from the V. Grib kimberlite pipe (East-European platform). Measured Fe3+/&#8721;Fe values range between 0.03 and 0.19 for garnet and 0.18 to 0.38 for clinopyroxene, the former being higher than what was measured previously in garnets equilibrated at mantle conditions. The Fe3+/&#8721;Fe of the reconstructed bulk rock ranges between 0.10 and 0.15 for high-MgO eclogites and 0.10 and 0.24 for low-MgO eclogites (with uncertainties of &#177; 0.02 and &#177; 0.03 in both cases). Thermobarometric calculations result in equilibration pressures and temperatures of 3.0 - 5.2 (&#177; 0.4) GPa and 720 - 1050 (&#177; 60) &#176;C for both high-MgO and low-MgO eclogites, slightly lower than previous P-T estimates of mantle eclogites from the Udachnaya kimberlite pipe (Siberian craton). At these conditions, &#8710;logfo2 (FMQ) calculated using the available oxythermobarometric model varies from -1.7 to -0.6 log units for high-MgO eclogites and from -2.9 to 0.9 log units for low-MgO eclogites. Samples recording &#8710;logfo2 (FMQ) &#8804; -1 log units overlap with North Slave, West Africa and Udachnaya eclogites, with no difference among eclogite types. The average values of -1.2 (&#177; 0.4) log units for high-MgO and -0.6 (&#177; 1.1) log units for low-MgO eclogites suggest different redox conditions of basaltic protoliths during subduction worldwide. Previous geochemical studies on the same rock samples reported evidence of cryptic metasomatism in both garnet and clinopyroxene that we demonstrate being not recorded by their major elements, while modal metasomatism evidenced by the presence of phlogopite as a product of interaction with a kimberlitic melt only affects the MgO of the bulk rock. Therefore, we suggest that high Fe3+/&#8721;Fe ratios for garnet (&amp;gt; 0.10) and for reconstructed bulk rocks in the case of both low-MgO and high-MgO samples cannot be due to metasomatic interaction with an oxidized fluid, but rather are the consequence of Fe3+ redistribution in an unusually oxidized mafic protolith upon metamorphism. Our results highlight the redox variability of eclogites of Archaean age at conditions more oxidized than present-day MORBs and imply an oxidizing nature of the convective mantle source where magma was formed with consequent speciation of C in the form of carbonate fluid explaining, therefore, the lack of diamonds in V. Grib kimberlite pipe.</description>
      <author>Marras Giulia, Martine Denis, Arvieux Catherine, Agasheva Elena, Vincenzo Stagno</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/petrology/egae054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage of Diabetic Retinopathy with Blood Antioxidants and Gut Microbiota in Type Two Diabetes Mellitus Saudi Patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46889/joar.2024.5202</link>
      <description>Rania Fahmy, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399096455

                Background: The retina is a light-sensitive nerve layer located at the back of the eye that creates images of objects. These cells kept alive by getting oxygen and nutrients from tiny blood vessels in the eye. Retinopathy is a disease of the retina that is more prevalent in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients. Diabetic retinopathy is a leading cause of blindness because hyperglycemia weakens retinal capillaries, resulting in leakage of blood into the surrounding space. This bleeding can result in formation of scar tissue, which can cause traction retinal detachment and maculopathy. The development of a panel of blood biomarkers to monitor diabetic retinopathies is essential for both diagnosis and prognosis. Proteomics as a powerful tool for the analysis of complex mixtures of proteins and the identification of biomarkers can be of great importance. Purpose: To detect early nerve fiber layer changes around macula and optic disc in diabetic patients and to correlate diabetic retinopathy with blood antioxidants and gut microbiota in T2DM in Saudi patients. Materials and Methods: In this cross-sectional case-control study, a total of 77 eyes of 39 subjects aged 40-60 years who did not have any history of eye injuries or eye diseases affecting fundus viewing, were recruited from King Saud University Campus and the department of ophthalmology in King Abdul Aziz university hospital in Riyadh. All subjects underwent full ophthalmic examination including Peripapillary retinal nerve fiber layer thickness and macular profile, Proteomic approach of collected overnight fasting plasma and Microbial stool examination. Results: The nerve fiber layer thickness around the optic disc was measured for all groups and there was no statistically significant difference in all quadrants between groups. The total retinal thickness at the macular area was different among all groups and tends to increase in group 3 due to diabetic retinopathy. The macular thickness in the 4 quadrants revealed no statistical difference except in the inferior quadrant. Glutathione S transferase and lipid peroxides showed no significant difference between the three studied groups; vitamin C and Glutathione were surprisingly higher in controlled diabetic patients relative to controls. Moreover, over growth of bacteroids participated to the evolution of retinopathy in diabetic patients. Conclusion: As hyperglycemia and oxidative stress are implicated in the pathogenesis of diabetic retinopathy, the present study certified that the progressive damage can be delayed in controlled type 2 diabetic patients using different treatment modalities that subside oxidative stress.</description>
      <author>Rania Fahmy</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46889/joar.2024.5202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#2473 Renal failure in the emergency department: indications for emergency hemodialysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ndt/gfae069.1579</link>
      <description>Hana Hedhli, Raouf Hajji, Mouna Jemai, Sarra Jouini, Chaima Mahrsia, Safia Othmani, Nephrology, dialysis, transplantation/Nephrology dialysis transplantation. 39(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398233752

                Abstract Background and Aims kidney failure is a frequent reason for emergency department (ED) visits. Patients may require emergency hemodialysis and this situation may increases mortality risk. We set out to study the clinical relevance and biological characteristics of patients with renal failure presenting to the emergency department with an indication for emergency hemodialysis. Method A prospective observational study conducted in ED conducted over a 6-month period. Patients were included if they were 18 years or older and suffering from acute or chronic renal insufficiency defined by creatinine clearance (CrCL) calculated by MDRD&amp;lt;60 ml/min. Information is recorded on demographics, clinical profile, clinical presentation, laboratory, causes of for emergency hemodialysis and in-hospital complications. Results Eighty one patients were enrolled, among them 61.7% patients had an indication for emergency hemodialysis. Mean age was 61&#177; 12, sex-ratio=1,7. Sixty seven patients (82.7%) were known to have a chronic kidney failure and 17.3 % were discovered at the emergency department at the same hospitalisation period. Clinical profile (%): Anuric patients (11.1), preserved diuresis (40.7). Clinical presentation (%): deterioration of general condition (35.8), dyspnea and chest pain (21) and fever (17.3). Clinical examination showed a peripheral oxygen saturation between 70 and 100% with a mean of 94.81, a respiratory rhythm mean of 20 cycles/min, a systolic blood pressure mean of 134.61 mmHg and a diastolic blood pressure mean of 70 mmHg. biological exams showed that kalemia was between 2.4 and 8.6 and 45 of those patients had kalemia more or equal to 5.5. Twelve per cent of these patients had hyperkalemia signs on the electrocardiogram. The average were 28 mmol/l with a maximum of 83.3 mmol/l. Creatinine values were between 185 et 2620 &#956;mol/l with a median of 81. The value of Ph was between 7.04 and 7.53 with a median of 7.29 mm Hg. The value of HCO3- value was between 4.6 and 28.4 with a median of 14.2. Causes of emergency hemodialysis were acidosis in 12 cases, severe anemia with blood transfusion in 4 cases, hyperkalemia in 10 cases, acute pulmonary oedema in 5 cases and acute renal failure in 6 cases .the evolution of the patients was marked by improvement of 61.7% of the patients, only 3 of the 81 patients died during the hospitalization. Conclusion This study showed that the causes of emergency dialysis can be avoided by improving care and educating patients to improve the prognosis.</description>
      <author>Hana Hedhli, Raouf Hajji, Mouna Jemai, Sarra Jouini, Chaima Mahrsia, Safia Othmani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ndt/gfae069.1579</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
