<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:44:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Boosting oxygen evolution reaction rates with mesoporous Fe-doped MoCo-phosphide nanosheets"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393251122

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Boosting oxygen evolution reaction rates with mesoporous Fe-doped MoCo-phosphide nanosheets"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393251195

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Synthesis Heterojunction of g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; to Enhance the Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00637</link>
      <description>Qingyan Zhang, Guowei Liu, Taifeng Liu, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393267411

                Heterojunctions formed between semiconductors have been confirmed to efficiently enhance the separation of photogenerated carriers, thereby boosting the photocatalytic activity. However, achieving controllable synthesis of heterojunctions remains a challenge. In this study, g-C3N4 (CN) was positively charged by carefully adjusting the pH of the solution. Subsequently, it was precisely located on the (010) crystal facet of decahedral BiVO4 (BVO) under light irradiation, where photogenerated negative electrons accumulate on the (010) facet of BVO. This process results in the construction of a composite with a heterojunction between CN and the (010) facet of BVO. The optimal photocatalytic oxygen production activity of this composite reaches 2966.9 &#956;mol/g/h, a remarkable 3.3 times better than that of BVO alone. This result shows that the heterojunction can significantly improve the oxygen production activity of the composite photocatalyst. By a combination of the Kubelka&#8211;Munk function, Mott&#8211;Schottky, and theoretical calculations, we found that the migration of photogenerated electrons from BVO to CN matches well with the S-scheme mechanism. This work provides valuable suggestions and guidance for the precise synthesis of heterojunction photocatalyst and is looking forward to being applied to other materials related to environmental and energy research.</description>
      <author>Qingyan Zhang, Guowei Liu, Taifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Boosting oxygen evolution reaction rates with mesoporous Fe-doped MoCo-phosphide nanosheets"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393280937

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Boosting oxygen evolution reaction rates with mesoporous Fe-doped MoCo-phosphide nanosheets"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393280950

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Boosting oxygen evolution reaction rates with mesoporous Fe-doped MoCo-phosphide nanosheets"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Wei Zuo, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393281153

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Wei Zuo, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic RB5 Dye Degradation and Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) Catalysis by WO3 Nano-Pellets: Mechanistic Insights and water remediation Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104216</link>
      <description>Shasvat Rathod, Pratik M. Pataniya, Kinjal K. Joshi, Mehdihasan I. Shekh, C.K. Sumesh, Sanni Kapatel, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393281215

                Transition metal oxides (TMO), a non-noble element based oxides, establish remarkable potential in the realm of textile wastewater remediation and water splitting due to their sustainable catalytic performance. Highly functional TMO materials, in form of nanostrcutures, are of great interest owing to their robust photo and electro-catalytic activities for instituting sustainable development for the water and energy resource management framework. In the present article, we have reported catalytically active WO3 nano-pellets (NP) synthesized using microwave-assisted for photocatalytic wastewater remediation and electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Promisingly, WO3 NP abetted degradation of the reactive black 5 (RB5) dye by almost 95 % in short time interval of 60 min in exposer of sun light. Present work includes the strategies to remove and observe the progression of reaction kinetics of dye degradation in neutral and alkaline media. By varying concentration of the catalyst (ranging from 250 mg/L to 1000 mg/L, in the step of 250 mg/L), we have prolifically verified that 750 mg/L turn out optimal dosage for 100% degradation in time interval of 120 min. Besides, WO3 NP has shown highest photocatalytic behaviour at 9 pH. The WO3 NP shows the electrocatalytic OER performance in an alkaline condition (1M KOH) with an overpotential of 418 mV to generate the geometric current density of 10 mA/cm&#178; and Tafel slope of 178 mV dec&#8315;&#185;. Owing to robust nature, WO3 NP shows the almost similar photocatalytic response for ten cycles dye degradation and demonstrates the stable electrochemical charge transport for OER at 10 mA/cm2 for 50 hours.</description>
      <author>Shasvat Rathod, Pratik M. Pataniya, Kinjal K. Joshi, Mehdihasan I. Shekh, C.K. Sumesh, Sanni Kapatel</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104216</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Boosting oxygen evolution reaction rates with mesoporous Fe-doped MoCo-phosphide nanosheets"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393283781

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra00146j/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile strategy of "laser-direct-writing" to develop self-supported Ni30B70-Ti catalysts for boosted and durable alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00230j</link>
      <description>Ya Gao, Shengli Zhu, Zhenduo Cui, Zhaoyang Li, S. L. Wu, Zhonghui Gao, Wence Xu, Meiqing Guo, Yanqin Liang, Hui Jiang, Sustainable energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393284823

                Seawater splitting, avoiding the use of limited freshwater resources, is a promising technology to produce renewable and sustainable hydrogen energy. In this work, a Ni30B70 catalyst supported on Titanium foam...</description>
      <author>Ya Gao, Shengli Zhu, Zhenduo Cui, Zhaoyang Li, S. L. Wu, Zhonghui Gao, Wence Xu, Meiqing Guo, Yanqin Liang, Hui Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00230j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt nanoparticles anchored by oxygen vacancies in MXenes for efficient electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00020j</link>
      <description>Qi Zhao, Yue Zhang, Changwang Ke, Weilin Yang, J. Yue, Xiaofei Yang, Weiping Xiao, Nanoscale (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393285003

                Pt/MXene heterostructures were prepared by constructing oxygen vacancies on MXene to anchor Pt nanoparticles, which exhibited accelerated HER kinetics in 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 solution due to the synergistic effect between MXenes and Pt nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>Qi Zhao, Yue Zhang, Changwang Ke, Weilin Yang, J. Yue, Xiaofei Yang, Weiping Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00020j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeNi3 nanosheets with multiple defects induced by H+-ion irradiation show enhanced electrocatalytic action during the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100649</link>
      <description>Rongfang Zhang, Caiyun Qi, Xiaoping Gao, Yuying Li, Jianpeng Wang, FlatChem (Amsterdam). 45(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393289800

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is vital in electrocatalytic water-splitting. However, efficient non-precious metal electrocatalysts are required to improve the reaction efficiency. Therefore, this study aims to increase the OER activity of FeNi3 nanosheets using high-energy H+-ion irradiation to create multiple defects. The optimized sample (FeNi3-16) achieves a lower overpotential of 260 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 than its pristine counterpart (FeNi3, 320 mV). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that the multiple defects in Fe and Ni can synergistically reduce the d-band centres of the Fe and Ni sites, which improves the electron transfer efficiency during the OER. This ion-irradiation technique may be applied to other electrocatalysts for various energy device.</description>
      <author>Rongfang Zhang, Caiyun Qi, Xiaoping Gao, Yuying Li, Jianpeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acid Electrolyte Anions Adsorption Effects on IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08103</link>
      <description>S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya, Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393302584

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis is a promising technology merging the usage of intermittent renewable energy sources with the production of green hydrogen. The anodic oxygen evolution reaction remains the bottleneck of the efficiency of these devices due to sluggish reaction kinetics, high cost, and the scarcity of state-of-the-art catalytic materials. Though most research is focused on the discovery of new catalytic materials, understanding the effects of acid electrolyte anions is crucial to designing and optimizing existing electrocatalysts in diverse electrochemical microenvironments. Herein, we systematically study the effects of acid electrolytes on the IrO2(110) surface under OER reaction conditions using density functional theory. The potential-dependent anion adsorption results show that HPO42&#8211; adsorbs the strongest, followed by SO42&#8211;, NO3&#8211;, and ClO4&#8211; respectively at 1.6 V (vs RHE). HPO42&#8211; and SO42&#8211; block the Ir-active sites by competitively adsorbing with the OER intermediates while ClO4&#8211; does not interfere with OER performance. By evaluating dipole-field interactions, surface work function changes, Bader charges of adsorbed anions, and the effects of adsorbed electrolyte anions on the adsorption of the OER intermediates, we provide further insights into acid anion electrolyte effects under the OER conditions. This expansion of fundamental understanding of the effects of acid electrolyte anion adsorption on IrO2 assists in engineering better-performing catalysts with integrated electrolyte microenvironment for OER.</description>
      <author>S. A. Keishana Navodye, G. T. Kasun Kalhara Gunasooriya</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the oxygen evolution activity and stability of Pb anode in Mn2+-containing acidic solution by embedding MnCo2O4 particles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.290</link>
      <description>Xiaocong Zhong, Yanwei Ren, Huai Jiang, Kuifang Zhang, Ruixiang Wang, Zhifeng Xu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393306091

                Due to the excellent activity and stability of MnCo2O4 toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic solution, a Pb&#8211;MnCo2O4 composite anode for zinc electrowinning was prepared by embedding dispersed MnCo2O4 particles into a Pb matrix in a powder metallurgy process. In this work, the phase structure, chemical composition, and morphology of the oxide layers formed on Pure-Pb and Pb&#8211;MnCo2O4 were analyzed by XRD, SEM, and EDS. Galvanostatic polorization, Tafel tests, and EIS measurements were performed to investigate the anodic potential variation and OER kinetics of the Pure-Pb and Pb&#8211;MnCo2O4 composite anodes. Compared with that on the Pure-Pb anode, the oxide layer on Pb&#8211;MnCo2O4 is thinner, more compact, and more stable in a 160 g L&#8722;1 H2SO4 solution containing 4 g L&#8722;1 Mn2+. Consequently, the Pb&#8211;MnCo2O4 composite anode exhibited a much lower anode slime production (8.7 mg) during 72 h of the simulated zinc electrowinning process. Despite the smaller surface area and lower PbO2 content of the oxide layer, the Pb&#8211;MnCo2O4 composite anode presented preferable OER kinetics with a lower OER charge transfer resistance (0.729 &#937; cm2) and a smaller Tafel slope (90.74 mV dec&#8722;1), which contributed to a 70 mV reduction in the anodic potential compared with that of the Pure-Pb anode.</description>
      <author>Xiaocong Zhong, Yanwei Ren, Huai Jiang, Kuifang Zhang, Ruixiang Wang, Zhifeng Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Graphitic Carbon Nitride-Encapsulated SrFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Spinel Nanocomposite Electrode for Enhancing Supercapacitor and Oxygen Evolution Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04525</link>
      <description>Silambarasan Kuppusamy, Dinesh Selvakumaran, K. K. Lakshmanan, Mohd Khairul Ahmad, Energy &amp; fuels (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393308570

                In the past few years, there has been a notable upswing in the excitement surrounding bifunctional materials, primarily due to their versatility in accommodating energy storage and conversion needs. One class of materials that garnered considerable attention is strontium ferrite nanoparticles (NPs), which are known for their remarkable electrochemical properties stemming from their exceptional physical and chemical characteristics. In this study, we have synthesized a novel, cost-effective, and highly efficient composite electrode designed for dual functionality in supercapacitor (SC) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) applications in alkaline environments. Herein, we prepared SrFe2O4@g-C3N4 composite through a coprecipitation and pyrolysis method, resulting in featuring a porous g-C3N4 matrix and strontium (Sr) spinel structure. The composite materials were thoroughly characterized using techniques such as powder X-ray diffraction (XRD), energy-dispersive spectroscopy (EDS), transmission electron microscopy (TEM), and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. The SrFe2O4@g-C3N4 electrode exhibited outstanding pseudocapacitive behavior and delivered a specific capacitance of 1055 F/g at a current density of 1 A/g. Remarkably, it displayed a capacitance retention of 93% even after 5000 galvanostatic charge&#8211;discharge (GCD) cycles. Furthermore, in comparative assessments with bare SrFe2O4 or g-C3N4 electrodes, the SrFe2O4@g-C3N4 composite electrode displayed superior and stable electrocatalytic performance. It required minimal overpotentials (only 170 mV) to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 during the OER. These results emphasize the substantial potential of Sr-based nanocomposites as auspicious materials for applications in supercapacitors and as stable electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Silambarasan Kuppusamy, Dinesh Selvakumaran, K. K. Lakshmanan, Mohd Khairul Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring hypervalent Nickel induced by oxygen vacancy toward enhanced oxygen evolution reaction performance in self-supporting NiFe-(oxy)hydroxides electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.184</link>
      <description>Chun Kong, Chunyi Zhi, Zirui Wu, Wenqiang Yang, Juan Yang, Zhongti Sun, Journal of colloid and interface science (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393320806

                NiFe-(oxy)hydroxides are the most active transition metal oxide electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under the alkaline media. Herein, we controllably manipulated oxygen vacancy (VO)-tunable NiFe-(oxy) hydroxides that their OER performances possessed a volcano-type relationship with VO concentration, positively-correlated with Ni3+/Ni2+ ratio. Theoretical simulations further unearthed the enhanced activation and dissociation of H2O by the inserting of VO. As a result, the optimal sample featuring the Ni3+/Ni2+ ratio of 30.3 % and VO of 23.8 % exhibited the overpotential of 243 mV at the current density of 100 mA cm&#8211;2, simultaneously lasting 120 h durability without any attenuation, exceding the most reported NiFe-(oxy)hydroxides. This work offers an innovative view to understand the OER performance using hypervalent Ni ratio induced by VO defects.</description>
      <author>Chun Kong, Chunyi Zhi, Zirui Wu, Wenqiang Yang, Juan Yang, Zhongti Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Light Response and Electron Redistribution of Active Sites by Structuring Cos2/Mos2 Heterojunction for Highly Efficient Photo-Assisted Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4777173</link>
      <description>Yanrong Ren, Chaoyang Shi, Enze Zhu, Danyang Wei, Zhiwei Meng, Baoyu Huang, Mingli Xu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393322301

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Yanrong Ren, Chaoyang Shi, Enze Zhu, Danyang Wei, Zhiwei Meng, Baoyu Huang, Mingli Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4777173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable N-doped NiMoO4/NiO2 electrocatalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt04034h</link>
      <description>Zhengfang Hou, Fangyuan Fan, Zhe Wang, Yeshuang Du, Dalton transactions (2003. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393322437

                Recently, there has been a significant increasing interest in the research of highly active and stable transition metal-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Non-noble metals nanocatalysts with excellent inherent...</description>
      <author>Zhengfang Hou, Fangyuan Fan, Zhe Wang, Yeshuang Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt04034h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Engineering Layered Bimetallic Oxyhydroxides For Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4777421</link>
      <description>Xiaolin Zhang, Huanjun Xu, Qiang Shen, Weiling Sun, Xu Han, Dan Jiang, Yang Cao, Duanwei He, Xiaoqiang Cui, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393324035

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Xiaolin Zhang, Huanjun Xu, Qiang Shen, Weiling Sun, Xu Han, Dan Jiang, Yang Cao, Duanwei He, Xiaoqiang Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4777421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of iron-modulated VN/V3O4/Co5&#183;47N nanoparticles with rich heterogeneous interfaces for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.301</link>
      <description>Dangxia Wang, Yaoxia Yang, Xingwei Guo, Yu Zhang, Bin L&#252;, Qingtao Wang, Dongfei Sun, Jian Li, Ziqiang Lei, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393332725

                With the increasing need of clean energy demand, the development of efficient and green electrocatalysts for water electrolysis plays an irreplaceable role in the realization of large-scale production of hydrogen. Herein, an original iron modulated heterogeneous VN/V3O4/Co5&#183;47N nanoparticles (FVOCN) is successfully synthesized using hydrothermal technique and in situ pyrolysis protocol. Through a series of characterization, it is found that the addition of iron in VN/V3O4/Co5&#183;47N (VOCN) can significantly regulate the electronic structure and make it have better electrochemical oxygen evolution activity in 1 M KOH solution as opposed to the VOCN. The catalyst is obtained at the sintering temperature of 600 &#176;C has the best performance, which only requires a lower overpotential of 270 mV to attain the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and superior to commercial IrO2. The method of introducing iron into vanadium-based, cobalt-based nitrides and vanadium-based oxides can broaden the research content of new electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts and provide a reference idea for the development of energy industry.</description>
      <author>Dangxia Wang, Yaoxia Yang, Xingwei Guo, Yu Zhang, Bin L&#252;, Qingtao Wang, Dongfei Sun, Jian Li, Ziqiang Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-engineering of CaTiO3 for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction through enhanced oxygen vacancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.318</link>
      <description>Priya Yadav, Ch Anil, Ravi K. Kunchala, Smrutipragnya Samal, B. S. Naidu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393332728

                Surface engineering has been an important strategy in attaining a higher catalytic activity in comparison with pristine samples. CaTiO3 is a well-known photoactive material but lacks photo-to-electron conversion efficiency. Herein, we demonstrate a simple path-way that could achieve a higher surface area, active site exposure, and oxygen vacancies. The experimental results using different concentrations of HNO3 illustrated the selective leaching of Ca(II) ions, which leads to the partial conversion of Ti4+ to Ti3+ and the formation of oxygen vacancy. This eventually resulted in an engineered electronic state that modifies the band alignment and improves the charge transfer and migration rate. The optimized photocatalyst (CTO-5) exhibits approximately six times enhanced hydrogen evolution rate of 58.1 &#956;mol&#8729;g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 than the pristine CaTiO3 (8.7 &#956;mol&#8729;g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1). Our work offers new intuitions into the rational design of photocatalysts with surface-engineering methodology without using any noble metal.</description>
      <author>Priya Yadav, Ch Anil, Ravi K. Kunchala, Smrutipragnya Samal, B. S. Naidu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of spinel (Fe0.2Co0.2Ni0.2Cr0.2M0.2)3O4 (M = Mg, Mn, Zn, and Cu) high-entropy oxides with tunable valance states for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174304</link>
      <description>Yuanxi Guo, Xinxin Zhang, Hehe Wei, Haitao Yu, Ying Xie, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393339884

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanxi Guo, Xinxin Zhang, Hehe Wei, Haitao Yu, Ying Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of CuSe/polypyrrole electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00339-024-07429-3</link>
      <description>Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Nargis Bano, Sameh M. Osman, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Applied physics. A, Materials science &amp; processing (Print). 130(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393342827

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Sumaira Manzoor, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Nargis Bano, Sameh M. Osman, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00339-024-07429-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow-structured cobalt sulfide electrocatalyst for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction: Rational tuning of electronic structure using iron and fluorine dual-doping strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.201</link>
      <description>Hye-Jin Kim, Kyeongseok Min, Guoqiang Song, Junseong Kim, Hyung Chul Ham, Sung&#8208;Hyeon Baeck, Journal of colloid and interface science (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393346162

                Utilizing renewable electricity for water electrolysis offers a promising way for generating high-purity hydrogen gases while mitigating the emission of environmental pollutants. To realize the water electrolysis, it is necessary to develop highly active and precious metal-free electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) which incurs significant overpotential due to its complicated four-electron transfer mechanism. Hence, we propose a facile preparation method for hollow-structured Fe and F dual-doped CoS2 nanosphere (Fe-CoS2-F) as an efficient OER electrocatalyst. The uniform hollow and porous structure of Fe-CoS2-F enlarge the specific surface area and increase the number of exposed active sites. Furthermore, the Fe and F dual-dopants synergistically contributed to the adjustment of electronic structure, thereby promoting the adsorption/desorption of oxygen-containing reaction intermediates on active sites during the alkaline OER procedure. As a result, the prepared Fe-CoS2-F exhibits outstanding OER activity, characterized by a low overpotential of 298 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope as small as 46.0 mV dec&#8722;1. Based on computational theoretical calculations, the introduction of the dual-dopants into CoS2 structure reduce the excessively strong adsorption energy of reaction intermediate in the rate determining step, leading to effectively promoted electrocatalytic cycle for OER in alkaline environment. This study presents an effective strategy for preparing noble metal-free OER electrocatalysts with promising potential for large-scale industrial water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Hye-Jin Kim, Kyeongseok Min, Guoqiang Song, Junseong Kim, Hyung Chul Ham, Sung&#8208;Hyeon Baeck</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ growth of Mo-CoFe LDH on nickel foam for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144189</link>
      <description>Yuchen Duan, Bin Hu, Yongping Luo, Yu Xie, Yong Chen, Yifan Zhang, Yun Ling, Jinsheng Zhao, Electrochimica acta. 487(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393321245

                The study of non-precious metals to prepare catalytic materials with high performance and excellent stability is an important part of improving hydrogen production by electrolysis of water. In this work, we report on the preparation of direct composite Mo-CoFe LDH/NF as the working electrode of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) using nickel foam as the substrate via one-step hydrothermal method. The direct growth in situ ensured the close contact between LDH and NF substrate, thereby reducing the charge transfer resistance and making the electrode have high electrocatalytic performance. At the current density of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2, the oxygen evolution overpotential of the Mo-CoFe LDH/NF catalytic material was 252 mV, the Tafel slope was 22.07 mV/dec, and the material could be maintained in alkaline solution for 10 hours, showing good stability. Therefore, this work proposed new ideas for the design and fabrication of low-cost and efficient electrocatalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Yuchen Duan, Bin Hu, Yongping Luo, Yu Xie, Yong Chen, Yifan Zhang, Yun Ling, Jinsheng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst based on Fe, Co, and nitrogen co-doped graphene-coated alumina nanofibers for Zn-air battery air electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160024</link>
      <description>Marek Mooste, Zakarya Ahmed, Pavels Kapitulskis, Roman Ivanov, Alexey Treshchalov, Helle&#8208;Mai Piirsoo, Arvo Kikas, Vambola Kisand, Kaupo Kukli, Irina Hussainova, Kaido Tammeveski, Applied surface science (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393346761

                Aqueous rechargeable zinc-air battery (RZAB) is an emerging environmentally friendly energy storage device for a wide variety of industrial applications such as electric vehicles, consumer electronics, and stationary power plants. For successful commercialization of RZABs, a cost-effective bifunctional catalyst is highly required to catalyze the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the air electrode. Dual transition-metal and nitrogen-doped nanocarbon materials have shown good potential as an affordable and scalable bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts alternative to Pt-group metal-based catalysts for RZAB. To achieve this goal, we have developed electrocatalysts based on Fe, Co, and nitrogen co-doped graphene-augmented inorganic alumina nanofibers (Fe/Co-NGr). The Fe/Co-NGr catalysts demonstrate high oxygen reduction and evolution reaction reversibility (&#916;E) of 0.85&#8211;0.88 V due to the graphene-covered nanofibrous structure doped with FeCo alloy nanoparticles and containing nitrogen, transition metal (TM) coordinated to nitrogen and TM oxide active sites. The primary zinc-air battery with Fe/Co-NGr air electrode exhibits a high maximum power density of 149 mW cm&#8722;2 and a specific capacity of 807 mAh gZn-1. The RZAB assessment has shown a low charge&#8211;discharge voltage gap of 0.86 V and high energy utilization efficiency of 58 % up to 90 h of charge&#8211;discharge cycling at 5 mA cm&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Marek Mooste, Zakarya Ahmed, Pavels Kapitulskis, Roman Ivanov, Alexey Treshchalov, Helle&#8208;Mai Piirsoo, Arvo Kikas, Vambola Kisand, Kaupo Kukli, Irina Hussainova, Kaido Tammeveski</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Selenides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202301574</link>
      <description>Zuoqiang Wu, Energy technology (Weinheim. Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393852952

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential to the water splitting and CO 2 reduction reactions, while this reaction is kinetically sluggish and demands the efficient electrocatalyst. Transition metal selenides (TMSes) have gained greater attention as nonprecious metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts due to their low cost, earth abundance, and high efficiency. Typically, TMSe can exhibit superior OER activity to their counterparts such as hydroxides/oxyhydroxides and sulfides. As such, their unique way to boost the catalytic activity is intriguing to researchers and many studies have been recently carried out. The last decades have witnessed the rapid development of TMSe&#8208;based electrocatalysts in design and preparation for OER. However, there is still no exclusive review summarizing the recent development of this material for OER electrocatalysis. Herein, this article underscores the significant promise of TMSes in advancing the field of high&#8208;performance OER electrocatalysts. The research progress is summarized and the importance of strategies to improve the performance of selenide electrodes including multimetal composite, hybrid composite with carbonaceous materials, morphological engineering, heterostructure engineering, and vacancies engineering is emphasized. Finally, the future challenges and opportunities concerning the improvement of TMSe electrocatalysts are outlined, which are essential for their further application in electrochemical energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Zuoqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202301574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supplementary Data for 'The electron-proton bottleneck of photosynthetic oxygen evolution'</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7681840</link>
      <description>Paul Greife, Matthias Sch&#246;nborn, Holger Dau, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393546533

                Supplementary data for the publication: 'The electron-proton bottleneck of photosynthetic oxygen evolution', Greife et al. Heat_Artefact_Spectrum.xlsx Spectrum assigned to rapid heating by laser-flash excitation of high-activity Photosystem II membrane particles. This spectrum was used for heat artefact correction of the step-scan data set. The first column is the wavenumber in cm-1, the second column the absorption in arbitrary OD units. Log_Averaged_Interferograms.xlsx Averaged time-resolved FTIR interferograms recorded before and after the application of a saturating excitation flash to high activity Photosystem II membrane particles from spinach. In total 10 sequential flashes were applied. The first column is the time in milliseconds. Remaining columns are the mirror positions of the phase-corrected interferograms with the centerburst shifted to the first position. Amplitude is in arbitrary units. Individual columns correspond to individual time courses at the respective mirror positions. Rows corresponds to interferograms at the respective time. The data for each of the 10 flashes is provided in a separate spreadsheet, which is accordingly labeled. The mirror positions were chosen such that after Fourier transformation the wavenumber range of the resulting spectra corresponds to 929.33 cm-1 to 1858.67 cm-1 , with data points equally spaced on a wavenumber axis.</description>
      <author>Paul Greife, Matthias Sch&#246;nborn, Holger Dau</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7681840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution System with the Coupling of Polyoxometalates with Bismuth Vanadate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14040236</link>
      <description>Boon Chong Ong, Teik&#8208;Thye Lim, Can Xue, Zhili Dong, Catalysts. 14(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393379318

                In this work, a coupling system consisting of bismuth vanadate (BiVO4) and cobalt-based polyoxometalates (Co-POMs) was developed to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction. Crystallization-driven self-assembly and the wet chemical synthesis method were deployed in synthesizing Co-POMs and monoclinic&#8211;tetragonal mixed&#8211;phase BiVO4, respectively. The introduction of Co-POMs into a BiVO4-containing mixture significantly enhanced the water oxidation reaction, with a more than twofold increment in the total amount of oxygen evolved. For instance, 461.2 &#181;mol of oxygen was evolved from the system containing 20 mg of Co-POMs compared to 195 &#181;mol of oxygen produced from a pristine BiVO4 system. This extraordinary improvement in the oxygen evolution reaction indicates the existence of a positive synergic effect between BiVO4 and Co-POMs, in which Co-POMs could act as effective cocatalysts to extract photogenerated charge carriers generated by BiVO4 and improve the charge transfer process. However, the amount of oxygen produced was slightly reduced to 440.7 &#181;mol with an increase in AgNO3 loading from 30 mg to 60 mg. This unforeseen phenomenon could be elucidated by the shielding effect of silver particles, in which a higher AgNO3 loading led to a more prominent shielding effect. The presence of silver nanoparticles on post-reaction BiVO4 was confirmed by TEM and XPS analysis. This newly established process scheme provides an insight into the development of an efficient photocatalytic oxygen evolution system in realizing future commercial applications toward green energy production.</description>
      <author>Boon Chong Ong, Teik&#8208;Thye Lim, Can Xue, Zhili Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14040236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data for: Manganese Dissolution in alkaline medium with and without concurrent oxygen evolution in LiMn2O4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10377481</link>
      <description>Marcel Risch, Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393739103

                Raw data and processed data shown in figures of the publication titled: "Manganese Dissolution in alkaline medium with and without concurrent oxygen evolution in LiMn2O4" DOI: 10.1039/D3YA00434A by Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen,[a,b] Max Baumung,[a,b] Michael Tatzel,[c] Cynthia A. Volkert[b] and Marcel Risch[a,b] [a] Dr. Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Dr. Max Baumung, Dr. Marcel RischNachwuchsgruppe Gestaltung des SauerstoffentwicklungsmechanismusHelmholtz-Zentrum Berlin f&#252;r Materialien und Energie GmbHHahn-Meitner-Platz 1, 14109 BerlinE-mail: marcel.risch@helmholtz-berlin.de [b] Dr. Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Dr. Max Baumung, Prof. Dr. Cynthia A. Volkert, Dr. Marcel RischInstitut f&#252;r Material PhysikGeorg-August-Universit&#228;t G&#246;ttingenFriedrich-Hund-Platz 1, 37085 G&#246;ttingen [c] Prof. Dr. Michael TatzelAbteilung Sedimentologie und UmweltgeologieGeorg-August-Universit&#228;t G&#246;ttingenGoldschmidtstr. 3, 37077 G&#246;ttingen</description>
      <author>Marcel Risch, Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10377481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data for: Manganese Dissolution in alkaline medium with and without concurrent oxygen evolution in LiMn2O4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10377482</link>
      <description>Marcel Risch, Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4393828218

                Raw data and processed data shown in figures of the publication titled: "Manganese Dissolution in alkaline medium with and without concurrent oxygen evolution in LiMn2O4" DOI: 10.1039/D3YA00434A by Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen,[a,b] Max Baumung,[a,b] Michael Tatzel,[c] Cynthia A. Volkert[b] and Marcel Risch[a,b] [a] Dr. Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Dr. Max Baumung, Dr. Marcel RischNachwuchsgruppe Gestaltung des SauerstoffentwicklungsmechanismusHelmholtz-Zentrum Berlin f&#252;r Materialien und Energie GmbHHahn-Meitner-Platz 1, 14109 BerlinE-mail: marcel.risch@helmholtz-berlin.de [b] Dr. Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Dr. Max Baumung, Prof. Dr. Cynthia A. Volkert, Dr. Marcel RischInstitut f&#252;r Material PhysikGeorg-August-Universit&#228;t G&#246;ttingenFriedrich-Hund-Platz 1, 37085 G&#246;ttingen [c] Prof. Dr. Michael TatzelAbteilung Sedimentologie und UmweltgeologieGeorg-August-Universit&#228;t G&#246;ttingenGoldschmidtstr. 3, 37077 G&#246;ttingen</description>
      <author>Marcel Risch, Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10377482</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction catalysis for energy efficient CO2 reduction devices</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393399933</link>
      <description>Ad&#232;le Peugeot, HAL (Le Centre pour la Communication Scientifique Directe). None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4393399933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ad&#232;le Peugeot</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393399933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Progress of High-Entropy Oxides as Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c05202</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Jingbi You, Zhen Xi, Baolin Yi, Yao Zhao, Yuhui Li, Hangzhou Zhang, Energy &amp; fuels (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393566072

                Equimolar or nearly molar mixtures of five or more metals are used to create high-entropy oxides (HEOs). HEOs also possess the kinetic slow diffusion effect, structural lattice distortion, the thermodynamic high-entropy effect, and the cocktail effect. Consequently, a growing number of scientists are investigating high-entropy oxides. High active site density, low overpotential, and entropic stabilization effects are the main reasons why HEOs now show good electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction. However, the complexity of the elemental composition, organization, and surface morphology of high-entropy oxides limits the use of HEOs. The development of HEOs and the mechanisms behind OER are reviewed in this work, along with a description of the OER response pathways and evaluation standards. The OER performance of HEOs with diverse organizational structures is reviewed in this research because HEOs come in a variety of kinds. Additionally, when HEOs are utilized as carriers, the trend of OER performance is examined. Lastly, potential future development problems and opportunities for HEO electrocatalysts are discussed.</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Jingbi You, Zhen Xi, Baolin Yi, Yao Zhao, Yuhui Li, Hangzhou Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c05202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron in the Presence of Iridium for Oxygen-Evolution Reaction under Alkaline Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00069</link>
      <description>Mohammad Saleh Ali Akbari, Subhajit Nandy, Keun Hwa Chae, P. Aleshkevych, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393527642

                The potential of the oxygen-evolution reaction (OER) to serve as a vital source of electrons for reducing water, carbon dioxide, and ammonia is an area of intense research. Among the numerous catalysts investigated for the OER, Ir compounds have emerged as particularly promising candidates. A notable highlight of this study is the concurrent OER activity of both Ir and Fe. Remarkably, Ir independently exhibits high OER activity, even at exceedingly low overpotentials, establishing its distinctiveness among other metal oxides. Under alkaline conditions, the presence of both Fe and Ir (hydr)oxides in OER systems introduces complexity, given that Fe (hydr)oxides are also known for their efficiency in the OER. This combination of elements creates a multifaceted reaction environment, where the unique properties of each component interact, influencing the overall OER process. In this study, the focus is on investigating the OER process on an Ir wire in an alkaline environment (with pH 13 and 14) in the presence of K2FeO4. To gain a comprehensive understanding of the reaction, various techniques, such as electrochemical methods, X-ray diffraction (XRD), electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR), X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS), Raman spectroscopy, transmission electron microscopy (TEM), and scanning electron microscopy (SEM), were employed. Following an in-depth investigation and detailed analysis of the interaction between K2FeO4 and an Ir wire, it was observed that the activity of the OER increased at overpotentials exceeding 320 mV. The observed improvement was limited to cases where Fe species had deposited on the surface of the Ir wire. The Tafel slopes were found to be 196.10 (149.20) and 102.16 (56.30) mV/decade for the Ir electrode in 0.10 M (1.0 M) KOH, in the absence and presence of K2FeO4, respectively. XAS analysis revealed the presence of the FeHyOx species on the surface of IrO2. These experiments indicate that Fe and Ir sites can independently catalyze the OER without exhibiting any synergistic interaction between them.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Saleh Ali Akbari, Subhajit Nandy, Keun Hwa Chae, P. Aleshkevych, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Advances of Non-Noble Metal Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071637</link>
      <description>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Gang Li, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Xianjie Yuan, Yingjia Wang, Bin Cao, Materials (Basel). 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393871266

                Water splitting is an important way to obtain hydrogen applied in clean energy, which mainly consists of two half-reactions: hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the kinetics of the OER of water splitting, which occurs at the anode, is slow and inefficient, especially in acid. Currently, the main OER catalysts are still based on noble metals, such as Ir and Ru, which are the main active components. Hence, the exploration of new OER catalysts with low cost, high activity, and stability has become a key issue in the research of electrolytic water hydrogen production technology. In this paper, the reaction mechanism of OER in acid was discussed and summarized, and the main methods to improve the activity and stability of non-noble metal OER catalysts were summarized and categorized. Finally, the future prospects of OER catalysts in acid were made to provide a little reference idea for the development of advanced OER catalysts in acid in the future.</description>
      <author>Zhimin Yan, Shengmin Guo, Zhaojun Tan, Lijun Wang, Gang Li, Mingqi Tang, Zaiqiang Feng, Xianjie Yuan, Yingjia Wang, Bin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron-Incorporated Cobalt&#8211;Nickel Oxide Nanosheets for Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03136</link>
      <description>Yue Wang, Ashwani Kumar, Eko Budiyanto, Haritha Cheraparambil, Claudia Weidenthaler, Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393903021

                The composition and crystal structure are crucial parameters for the activity and stability of the electrocatalysts. Herein, we synthesize a series of CoxNi&#8211;B oxide nanosheets with low degree of crystallinity for alkaline media oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The sample with an optimized ratio Co8Ni&#8211;B oxide shows the best OER performance, achieving a current density of 10 mA/cm2 at an overpotential of 312 mV and a Tafel slope of 47 mV/dec in the 1 M KOH electrolyte. This sample is stable in the purified Fe-free KOH electrolyte and strongly activated in the nonpurified commercial electrolyte due to the Fe impurity uptake. The high surface area and partially crystalline structure caused by boron incorporation and low-temperature treatment provide more accessible active sites with retaining good stability against leaching during the OER. In situ electrochemical Raman spectroscopy investigation reveals the formation of OER active Co and Ni oxyhydroxides in Co8Ni&#8211;B oxides under a potential bias. The Ni substitution in Co oxides modulates the electronic structure of Co, and the OER activity of the electrocatalyst can be enhanced by Fe uptake from the KOH electrolyte.</description>
      <author>Yue Wang, Ashwani Kumar, Eko Budiyanto, Haritha Cheraparambil, Claudia Weidenthaler, Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional Nico2s4 Nanosheets Deliver Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4781076</link>
      <description>Kun Xiang, Meng Li, Jidong Zhang, Chuanxiao Cheng, Shaotao Dai, Qiong Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393619882

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Kun Xiang, Meng Li, Jidong Zhang, Chuanxiao Cheng, Shaotao Dai, Qiong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4781076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidized phosphorus linking promotes the activity of a cobalt molecular assembly for electrochemical oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118237</link>
      <description>Jian Yang, Runze He, Jiong Wang, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry (1992). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393447058

                Molecular assemblies represent a classical type of active electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), while the practical application is limited by the relatively low electrical conductivity. Herein, a cobalt molecular assembly was synthesized and supported by a conductive phosphorus doped graphene. It served as a potential OER electrocatalyst by affording a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at a small overpotential of 390 mV, and the turnover frequency of cobalt sites was increased by 21.5 times comparing to the assembly supported by the pristine graphene. Our observations unveil that the potential linking of oxidized phosphorus atoms in the carbon matrix is mainly responsible for the high activity of cobalt molecular assembly. The overall OER catalytic cycle was analyzed by in situ attenuated total reflectance-surface enhanced infrared absorption spectroscopy, suggesting that the formation of *OOH species on the cobalt sites could be critical for the final evolution of oxygen. These results open a potential avenue into the exploration of highly active OER electrocatalysts toward replacing the noble metals based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jian Yang, Runze He, Jiong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118237</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional activity and theoretical study of transition metal molybdates for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.254</link>
      <description>Namita Dalai, Manikandan Kandasamy, Shraddhanjali Senapati, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Bijayalaxmi Jena, International journal of hydrogen energy. 64(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393393474

                Effective, sturdy and cheap electrocatalysts are extremely desirable for water electrolysis. In this work, transition metal molybdates (MMoO4, M = Fe, Co, Ni) with extraordinary oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in basic electrolyte solution was reported. &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 catalyst exhibits better electrocatalytic performance and robustness for both HER and OER compared to NiMoO4 and CoMoO4. Theoretical study (DFT calculation) disclose that the Fe atoms increase the energy states near the Fermi level in &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 which makes it more conductive leading to superior OER and HER activity. Compared to CoMoO4 and NiMoO4, &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 have well defined multiple Mo 4d orbitals at the conduction band. These are empty states in conduction band, ready to receive the electrons. Further, the computed overpotential values for NiMoO4, CoMoO4, and &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 surfaces follow the trend, &#946;-Fe2(MoO4)3 &lt; NiMoO4 &lt; CoMoO4, corroborating with the experimental results.</description>
      <author>Namita Dalai, Manikandan Kandasamy, Shraddhanjali Senapati, Brahmananda Chakraborty, Bijayalaxmi Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.03.254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Surface Reconstruction During Oxygen Evolution Reaction on the Defined Spinel Oxide Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401095</link>
      <description>Kyungbeen Yeom, Jung Hyun Jo, Hyun-Seop Shin, Hyunsoo Ji, Sun-Young Moon, Ji&#8208;Eun Park, Seongbeom Lee, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Dong Hyeon Mok, Megalamane S. Bootharaju, Seoin Back, Taeghwan Hyeon, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Advanced functional materials (Print). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393364585

                Abstract The reconstructed surface structure of Co&#8208;based spinel oxides serves as the active site for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the structural complexity of spinel oxides and surface dynamics during the OER hinder the understanding of the reconstruction mechanism and electronic structure of the active site. In this study, spinel Co 3 O 4 @(CoFeV) 3 O 4 nanocube (CoFeV) is reported, a (001) facet&#8208;defined spinel oxide comprising Co, Fe, and V deposited on the Co 3 O 4 nanocube template to exclude facet&#8208;dependent factors. Introducing highly dissoluble V cations accelerates the reconstruction process to enhance the electrocatalytic activity. CoFeV exhibited enhanced electrocatalytic activity (266 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 M KOH) and durability (maintained stable electrocatalytic activity during a 200 h chronopotentiometry (CP) test at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ) with significantly enlarged electrochemically active surface area (ECSA). The experimental and theoretical results demonstrated that V dissolution during catalysis induced oxygen vacancies, accelerating the surface reconstruction to highly active oxyhydroxide. Consequently, the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) of CoFeV as the anode exhibited a remarkable performance of 6.19 A cm &#8722;2 at 2.0 V cell in 1 M KOH and robust durability for 96 h at a constant current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Kyungbeen Yeom, Jung Hyun Jo, Hyun-Seop Shin, Hyunsoo Ji, Sun-Young Moon, Ji&#8208;Eun Park, Seongbeom Lee, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Dong Hyeon Mok, Megalamane S. Bootharaju, Seoin Back, Taeghwan Hyeon, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202401095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Set for Operando Identification of a Side-On Nickel Superoxide Intermediate and the Mechanism of Oxygen Evolution on Nickel Oxyhydroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7319397</link>
      <description>Seunghwa Lee, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Lichen Bai, Hao Ming Chen, Xile Hu, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4393557894

                Dataset of the paper entitled "Operando Identification of a Side-On Nickel Superoxide Intermediate and the Mechanism of Oxygen Evolution on Nickel Oxyhydroxide"</description>
      <author>Seunghwa Lee, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Lichen Bai, Hao Ming Chen, Xile Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7319397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Set for Operando Identification of a Side-On Nickel Superoxide Intermediate and the Mechanism of Oxygen Evolution on Nickel Oxyhydroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7319396</link>
      <description>Seunghwa Lee, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Lichen Bai, Hao Ming Chen, Xile Hu, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4393809773

                Dataset of the paper entitled "Operando Identification of a Side-On Nickel Superoxide Intermediate and the Mechanism of Oxygen Evolution on Nickel Oxyhydroxide"</description>
      <author>Seunghwa Lee, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Lichen Bai, Hao Ming Chen, Xile Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.7319396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset of "Tracking high-valent surface iron species in the oxygen evolution reaction on cobalt iron (oxy)hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5723297</link>
      <description>Seunghwa Lee, Aliki Moysiadou, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Hao Ming Chen, Xile Hu, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4393474992

                Dataset of the paper entitled "Tracking high-valent surface iron species in the oxygen evolution reaction on cobalt iron (oxy)hydroxides"</description>
      <author>Seunghwa Lee, Aliki Moysiadou, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Hao Ming Chen, Xile Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5723297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dataset of "Tracking high-valent surface iron species in the oxygen evolution reaction on cobalt iron (oxy)hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5723296</link>
      <description>Seunghwa Lee, Aliki Moysiadou, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Hao Ming Chen, Xile Hu, Zenodo (CERN European Organization for Nuclear Research). None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4393691265

                Dataset of the paper entitled "Tracking high-valent surface iron species in the oxygen evolution reaction on cobalt iron (oxy)hydroxides"</description>
      <author>Seunghwa Lee, Aliki Moysiadou, You&#8208;Chiuan Chu, Hao Ming Chen, Xile Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.5723296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited CrMnFeCoNi Oxy-carbide film and effect of selective dissolution of Cr on oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.02.068</link>
      <description>Tian Xia, Chenghua Sun, Rongguang Wang, Journal of Materials Science and Technology (Shenyang). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393550831

                High entropy compounds were proven to exhibit excellent catalytic activity. Here, a series of amorphous CrMnFeCoNi Oxy-carbide films were successfully synthesized by one-step electrodeposition. As demonstrated, the film presented superior electrocatalytic activity for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with an overpotential of 295 mV at a current density of 10 mA/cm2. Uniquely, selective dissolution of Chromium (Cr) was observed, which increased the catalytic activity and showed high stability under a large current density of up to 400 mA/cm2. Cr dissolution not only increased the surface area but also improved the conductivity due to newly formed metal-metal bonding, promoting electron transfer and improving OER performance. As revealed by density functional theory (DFT) calculations, Cr-dissolution mediates the bonding of OER intermediates over surface active sites and ultimately reduces OER overpotential. The one-step electrodeposition method and the micro-dissolution mechanism provided a potential way to design and prepare high entropy compound electrodes, aiming to achieve efficient water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Tian Xia, Chenghua Sun, Rongguang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.02.068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New strategies for the elaboration of porous materials based on iridium towards the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4393370747</link>
      <description>Marine Elmaalouf, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4393370747

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marine Elmaalouf</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4393370747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epitaxially Heterointerficial Electron Bridge Synchoronizes Oxygen Evolution Activity and Stability on a Layered Double Hydroxide Surface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00037d</link>
      <description>Jia Wang, Zelin Zhao, Min Guo, Xiao Liang, Haolin Tang, Jiantao Li, Zongkui Kou, Junsheng Li, EES catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4393619881

                Scalable green hydrogen production via electrocatalytic water splitting is largely restricted by insufficient activity and stability of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts at the cathode. As a class of most...</description>
      <author>Jia Wang, Zelin Zhao, Min Guo, Xiao Liang, Haolin Tang, Jiantao Li, Zongkui Kou, Junsheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ey00037d</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
