<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:43:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Effect Promoting Self-Healing Behavior of Two-Dimensional Metal Oxide Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05870</link>
      <description>Dongdong Gao, Wenxiang Zhu, Jinxin Chen, Keyang Qin, Mengjie Ma, Jie Shi, Qun Wang, Zhenglong Fan, Qi Shao, Fan Liao, Mingwang Shao, Zhenhui Kang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391991674

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongdong Gao, Wenxiang Zhu, Jinxin Chen, Keyang Qin, Mengjie Ma, Jie Shi, Qun Wang, Zhenglong Fan, Qi Shao, Fan Liao, Mingwang Shao, Zhenhui Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dense Heterogeneous Interfaces Boost the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4733793</link>
      <description>Shuai Liu, Fumin Wang, Jiawei Wang, Weitao Zheng, Xinyuan He, Tongxue Zhang, Zhiwei Zhang, Qian Liu, Xijun Liu, Xubin Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392000713

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Liu, Fumin Wang, Jiawei Wang, Weitao Zheng, Xinyuan He, Tongxue Zhang, Zhiwei Zhang, Qian Liu, Xijun Liu, Xubin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4733793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silver zirconate: A versatile visible light harvesting photocatalyst for oxygen evolution, PMS activation, and bactericidal activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2024.115537</link>
      <description>Rudra Pratap Singh, Mrunal M. Shiwankar, Amit Kumar Maurya, Awanti S. Talmale, G.S. Gaikwad, Atul V. Wankhade, Journal of Photochemistry and Photobiology A: Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392005660

                Herein, we have synthesized silver zirconate using a co-precipitation method at room temperature. The synthesized Ag2ZrO3 (SZ) was then subjected to calcination at different temperatures (300 &#176;C, 500 &#176;C, and 700 &#176;C). The synthesized Ag2ZrO3 material was evaluated for its photocatalytic oxygen evolution, activation of peroxymonosulfate (PMS) ions, and antibacterial activity under visible light irradiation. Among the different samples, the SZ sample (Ag2ZrO3 synthesized at room temperature) exhibited the highest photocatalytic oxygen evolution rate (2175.02 &#956;molg-1h&#8722;1). This enhanced performance can be attributed to the higher surface area of SZ compared to the other samples. Furthermore, all four samples were tested for the photoactivation of peroxymonosulfate (PMS) ions to assess their ability for the decontamination of organic pollutant. The SZ photocatalyst demonstrated complete degradation (100 %) of RhB dye (2.1 &#215; 10-5 M) within 120 min of visible light irradiation in the presence of PMS. In contrast, without PMS, only 54.33 % degradation of RhB was recorded in 300 min. This result indicates that SZ effectively activates PMS ions for the degradation of organic pollutants. Additionally, SZ exhibited excellent bactericidal activity against E. coli and S. aureus bacteria, both in the dark and in the presence of visible light. The findings demonstrate the multifunctional properties of Ag2ZrO3, making it suitable for a wide range of environmental remediation applications.</description>
      <author>Rudra Pratap Singh, Mrunal M. Shiwankar, Amit Kumar Maurya, Awanti S. Talmale, G.S. Gaikwad, Atul V. Wankhade</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jphotochem.2024.115537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfate anchored on the defective NiO by ion irradiation realizes enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149890</link>
      <description>Derun Li, Wenfeng Guo, Zhuo Xing, Tao Jiang, Zhaowu Wang, Shanshan Wu, Liuqing Huang, Yichao Liu, Hengyi Wu, Changzhong Jiang, Feng Ren, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392005855

                NiO has attracted wide attention in the past decade as a cost-effective electrochemical catalyst for OER. However, its relatively poor performance and conductivity limit its commercial applications. Here, we highlight a unique ion irradiation method to enhance the catalytic activity of NiO. Benefiting from sulfate anchoring and the introduction of oxygen vacancies by He+ ion irradiation, the optimal catalyst (ir-S-NiO) exhibits an outstanding OER performance with a low overpotential of 269 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Moreover, the fabricated Anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) constructed by the ir-S-NiO is demonstrated to need a cell voltage of 1.72 V to reach a current density of 0.1 A cm&#8722;2 and shows remarkably long-term stability for 200 h without obvious attenuation at the current density of 0.5 A cm&#8722;2. This work provides a new method for the development of high-performance and stable OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Derun Li, Wenfeng Guo, Zhuo Xing, Tao Jiang, Zhaowu Wang, Shanshan Wu, Liuqing Huang, Yichao Liu, Hengyi Wu, Changzhong Jiang, Feng Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of nickel phosphide/iron oxyhydroxide heterostructure nanoparticles for oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109402</link>
      <description>Yichuang Xing, Shuling Liu, Yuan Liu, Xuechun Xiao, Yvpei Li, Zeyi Wang, Yafei Hu, B. Xin, He Wang, Chao Wang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392005890

                Active and stable oxygen evolution electrocatalysts are essential in increasing the efficiency of the water electrolyzers. The Ni2P/Fe(O)OH heterostructure nanoparticles are prepared via solvothermal phosphidization of Ni metal-organic frameworks (MOF) followed by immersing in Fe3+ aqueous solution. Characterizations reveal that the Ni2P/Fe(O)OH heterostructure nanoparticles are 12.83 nm in size averagely, and the heterointerface induces electron interactions between the Ni2P and Fe(O)OH phases. When used to catalyze OER in alkaline solutions, the Ni2P/Fe(O)OH-40/nickel foam (NF) is the most active and exhibits 240 mV overpotential to reach 10 mA cm-2 oxygen evolution (OER) current densities, which is significantly better than the Ni2P/NF. Lower apparent activation energy, charge transfer resistance, and Tafel slope, along with higher electron rate constant are observed at Ni2P/Fe(O)OH-40/NF, which suggests that the OER kinetics is more facile at the heterostructure surface. Both Ni2P/Fe(O)OH-40/NF and Ni2P/NF involve decoupled electron and proton transfer process, and higher degree of lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) participation is observed at Ni2P/Fe(O)OH-40/NF, which results from the increased acidity of the Ni3+ sites. Density functional theory calculations prove that the formation of heterostructure with Fe(O)OH alters the band structure and the OER intermediate adsorption energies, that lead to lower energy barrier in the rate-determining step. The Ni2P/Fe(O)OH-40/NF is also stable towards OER in alkaline solutions.</description>
      <author>Yichuang Xing, Shuling Liu, Yuan Liu, Xuechun Xiao, Yvpei Li, Zeyi Wang, Yafei Hu, B. Xin, He Wang, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled fabrication of various nanostructures iron-based tellurides as highly performed oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.051</link>
      <description>Munirah D. Albaqami, Mehar Un Nisa, Sumaira Manzoor, Jafar Hussain Shah, S. Noor Mohammad, &#350;enay Yal&#231;&#305;n, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Suleyman I. Allakhverdiev, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392010419

                Electrochemical water splitting is a process that shows promise for the sustainable conversion, storage, and delivery of hydrogen energy. The support development of electrocatalysts that support hydrogen and oxygen evolution processes (HER/OER) without requiring precious metals and with superior activity and durability is crucial for the broad adoption of water electrolysis. Compared to the traditional powder-coated type, a freestanding electrode architecture exhibits superior stability and kinetics. In this study, the layered FeTe-PANI nanocomposite is designed for hydrogen generation. Various nanostructures of FeTe-PANI like nanorods and nanosheets by controllable expansion of surfactants such as hexadecyl trimethyl ammonium bromide (CTAB) can be adjusted to agglomerations. The nanosheets combined with nanorods (FeTe-PANI) show remarkable electrocatalytic activity with 195 mV overpotentials at 10 mAcm&#8722;2 for OER. Additionally, FeTe-PANI employed in a 2-electrode electrolyzer as a cathodic electrode electrocatalyst in 1.0 Molar potassium hydroxide media, yields a cell voltage of 1.52 V at a current density of 10 mAcm&#8722;2 with a noteworthy 80 h sturdiness, making it an ideal electrocatalyst towards empirical deployment of water splitting electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Munirah D. Albaqami, Mehar Un Nisa, Sumaira Manzoor, Jafar Hussain Shah, S. Noor Mohammad, &#350;enay Yal&#231;&#305;n, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Suleyman I. Allakhverdiev</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-organic framework-derived heterostructured CoSe2-ZnSe nanorods coupled with carbon polyhedron supported carbon paper for oxygen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.190</link>
      <description>Shuaiqiang Liu, Yu Li, Yinghua Yan, Huazhao Yang, Chuanmin Ding, Junwen Wang, Donghong Duan, Qinbo Yuan, Xiaogang Hao, Shibin Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 60(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392010859

                Development of low-cost, efficient, and stable oxygen evolution electrocatalysts is crucial for the conversion and storage of renewable energy. Therefore, an effective integrated heterostructure catalyst is needed to achieve a lower overpotential during oxygen evolution process. In this paper, cobalt-zinc bimetallic MOF precursors are used as templates to prepare bimetallic cobalt-based selenides with good oxygen evolution catalytic activity and stability on carbon fiber paper. Due to the high specific surface area and porous structure of the coupling structure of nanorods and polyhedra, and the strong electronic coupling between CoSe2 and ZnSe on nanorods. CoSe2-ZnSe/CP exhibits excellent electrocatalytic activity in 1 M KOH solution. It only requires an overpotential of 275 mV to reach the current density of 10 mA cm-2, and the Tafel slope is 68.9 mV dec-1. In addition, after 12 h of continuous operation of CoSe2-ZnSe/CP, the activity decay of the catalyst is negligible. This work provides a method for the design of heterogeneous bimetallic selenide integrated oxygen evolution electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Shuaiqiang Liu, Yu Li, Yinghua Yan, Huazhao Yang, Chuanmin Ding, Junwen Wang, Donghong Duan, Qinbo Yuan, Xiaogang Hao, Shibin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited graphene@Co3O4 nanosheets for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234219</link>
      <description>Qianyu Wang, Zi-Ye Liu, Ji-Ming Hu, Journal of Power Sources. 599(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392014924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qianyu Wang, Zi-Ye Liu, Ji-Ming Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the Spin Polarization of NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide for the Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06180</link>
      <description>Wenwu Cao, Xianhui Gao, Jie Wu, Anqi Huang, Huan Hu, Zhongwei Chen, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392018831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenwu Cao, Xianhui Gao, Jie Wu, Anqi Huang, Huan Hu, Zhongwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c06180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black brookite rich in oxygen vacancies as an active photocatalyst for
  CO2 conversion: experiments and first-principles calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2402.12731</link>
      <description>Masae Katai, Parisa Edalati, Jacqueline Hidalgo-Jim&#233;nez, Yu Shundo, Taner Akbay, Tatsumi Ishihara, Makoto Arita, Masayoshi Fuji, Kaveh Edalati, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392019991

                Photocatalytic CO2 conversion is a clean technology to deal with CO2 emissions, and titanium oxide (TiO2) polymorphs are the most investigated photocatalysts for such an application. In this study, black TiO2 brookite is produced by a high-pressure torsion (HPT) method and employed as an active photocatalyst for CO2 conversion. Black brookite with a large concentration of lattice defects (vacancies, dislocations and grain boundaries) showed enhanced light absorbance, narrowed optical bandgap and diminished recombination rate of electrons and holes. The photocatalytic activity of the black oxide for CO2 conversion was higher compared to commercial brookite and benchmark P25 catalyst powders. First-principles calculations suggested that the presence of oxygen vacancies in black brookite is effective not only for reducing optical bandgap but also for providing active sites for the adsorption of CO2 on the surface of TiO2.</description>
      <author>Masae Katai, Parisa Edalati, Jacqueline Hidalgo-Jim&#233;nez, Yu Shundo, Taner Akbay, Tatsumi Ishihara, Makoto Arita, Masayoshi Fuji, Kaveh Edalati</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2402.12731</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Increased Readiness for Water Splitting: NiO&#8208;Induced Weakening of Bonds in Water Molecules as Possible Cause of Ultra&#8208;Low Oxygen Evolution Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310665</link>
      <description>Tom Bookholt, Xian Qin, Bettina Lilli, Dirk Enke, Marten Huck, Danni Balkenhohl, Klara R&#252;we, Julia Brune, Johann P. Klare, Karsten K&#252;pper, Anja Schuster, Jenrik Bergjan, Martin Steinhart, Harald Gr&#246;ger, Diemo Daum, Helmut Sch&#228;fer, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392035916

                Abstract The development of non&#8208;precious metal&#8208;based electrodes that actively and stably support the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water electrolysis systems remains a challenge, especially at low pH levels. The recently published study has conclusively shown that the addition of haematite to H 2 SO 4 is a highly effective method of significantly reducing oxygen evolution overpotential and extending anode life. The far superior result is achieved by concentrating oxygen evolution centres on the oxide particles rather than on the electrode. However, unsatisfactory Faradaic efficiencies of the OER and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) parts as well as the required high haematite load impede applicability and upscaling of this process. Here it is shown that the same performance is achieved with three times less metal oxide powder if NiO/H 2 SO 4 suspensions are used along with stainless steel anodes. The reason for the enormous improvement in OER performance by adding NiO to the electrolyte is the weakening of the intramolecular O&#9472;H bond in the water molecules, which is under the direct influence of the nickel oxide suspended in the electrolyte. The manipulation of bonds in water molecules to increase the tendency of the water to split is a ground&#8208;breaking development, as shown in this first example.</description>
      <author>Tom Bookholt, Xian Qin, Bettina Lilli, Dirk Enke, Marten Huck, Danni Balkenhohl, Klara R&#252;we, Julia Brune, Johann P. Klare, Karsten K&#252;pper, Anja Schuster, Jenrik Bergjan, Martin Steinhart, Harald Gr&#246;ger, Diemo Daum, Helmut Sch&#228;fer</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Conversion from Alloy Nanoparticles to Oxide Nanowires: Strain Wave&#8208;Driven Ru&#8208;O&#8208;Mn Collaborative Catalysis for Durable Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400754</link>
      <description>Mingyue Xiao, Jingjun Liu, Rongchao Li, Yang Sun, Feng Liu, Jianying Gan, Shixin Gao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392043167

                Abstract Metal&#8208;doped ruthenium oxides with low prices have gained widespread attention due to their editable compositions, distorted structures, and diverse morphologies for electrocatalysis. However, the mainstream challenge lies in breaking the so&#8208;called seesaw relationship between activity and stability during acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, strain wave&#8208;featured Mn&#8208;RuO 2 nanowires (NWs) with asymmetric Ru&#8208;O&#8208;Mn bonds are first fabricated by thermally driven rapid solid phase conversion from RuMn alloy nanoparticles (NPs) at moderate temperature (450 &#176;C). In 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 , the resultant NWs display a surprisingly ultralow overpotential of 168 mV at 10 mA cm &#8211;2 and run at a stable cell voltage (1.67 V) for 150 h at 50 mA cm &#8211;2 in PEMWE, far exceeding IrO 2 ||Pt/C assemble. The simultaneous enhancement of both activity and stability stems from the presence of dense strain waves composed of alternating compressive and tensile ones in the distorted NWs, which collaboratively activate the Ru&#8208;O&#8208;Mn sites for faster OER. More importantly, the atomic strain waves trigger dynamic Ru&#8208;O&#8208;Mn regeneration via the refilling of oxygen vacancies by oxyanions adsorbed on adjacent Mn and Ru sites, achieving long&#8208;term stability. This work opens a door to designing non&#8208;precious metal&#8208;assisted ruthenium oxides with unique strains for practical application in commercial PEMWE.</description>
      <author>Mingyue Xiao, Jingjun Liu, Rongchao Li, Yang Sun, Feng Liu, Jianying Gan, Shixin Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-doped Carbon Layer Encapsulating NiFeP Nanosheet Arrays as High-performance Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173933</link>
      <description>Shuai Wang, Weiye Shi, Qinling Zhou, Ye Zhang, Chunqing Huo, Shengjue Deng, Shen Lin, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392056073

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Wang, Weiye Shi, Qinling Zhou, Ye Zhang, Chunqing Huo, Shengjue Deng, Shen Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting activity on molten salt-synthesized Ce doped cobalt hydroxyl nitrate nanorods by oxygen vacancies for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131214</link>
      <description>Na Xu, Ning Yu, Zhaoxia Jin, Yanan Zhou, Yusheng Zhang, Jin-Long Tan, Yulu Zhou, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong, Fuel. 365(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392074898

                Rationalizing the development of highly active, non-precious electrocatalysts through facile and cost-effective synthesis methods for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) constitutes a paramount research objective. In this study, we introduce an innovative molten salt approach to fabricate an arrayed nanorod architecture supported on a cobalt foam substrate denoted as Ce doped cobalt hydroxyl nitrate (Ce-CoNH). Cerium (Ce) is strategically employed to induce oxygen vacancies and effect localized electronic structure modifications of the cobalt (Co) sites. In comparison to individual CoNH catalysts, Ce-CoNH exhibits exceptional catalytic activity in alkaline water oxidation, achieving a notably low overpotential of 270 mV at a current density of 50 mA cm&#8722;2. Notably, the Ce-CoNH catalyst also demonstrates remarkable durability, sustaining a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 for an impressive duration of 50 h, surpassing the performance of Ce-free CoNH samples, which can be attributed to the flexible influence of Ce doping and the robust nanorod structure. Collectively, our study underscores the viability of molten salt-synthesized heteroatom substitution, accompanied by the introduction of defect-rich structures, as an effective strategy for the rational design of advanced electrocatalysts tailored for water electrolysis applications.</description>
      <author>Na Xu, Ning Yu, Zhaoxia Jin, Yanan Zhou, Yusheng Zhang, Jin-Long Tan, Yulu Zhou, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructions of hierarchical nitrogen doped carbon nanotubes anchored on CoFe2O4 nanoflakes for efficient hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234218</link>
      <description>JiaJun Lai, Zeng Chen, Song Peng, Qin Zhou, Zeng Ju, Chao Liu, Xiaopeng Qi, Journal of Power Sources. 599(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392077017

                The three primary reactions in metal-air batteries and electrochemical hydrolysis are the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Therefore, it is crucial to develop efficient low-cost trifunctional catalysts. In this study, we design a self-supported electrocatalyst with hierarchical nanostructure, in which the bamboo-like nitrogen doped carbon nanotubes (NCNTs) encapsulated CoFe nanoparticles (CoFe NPs) in-situ anchored on nanoflower like CoFe2O4 via chemical vapor deposition. Strikingly, the resulting catalysts CoFe@NC/CoFe2O4/IF demonstrate exciting trifunctional catalytic performance, overpotential of 66 mV and 185 mV for HER and OER at current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and a half-wave potential of 0.852 V for ORR, respectively. In addition, the maximum power density of the Zinc-air batteries (ZABs) assembled with CoFe@NC/CoFe2O4/IF as the cathode electrode is 134.5 mW cm&#8722;2; and the overall water splitting requires only a voltage of 1.50 V at a decomposition current density at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. This method provides a new strategy for trifunctional electrocatalysts and offers a promising approach for self-driven water electrolysis devices.</description>
      <author>JiaJun Lai, Zeng Chen, Song Peng, Qin Zhou, Zeng Ju, Chao Liu, Xiaopeng Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dipole Effect on Oxygen Evolution Reaction of 2D Janus Single-Atom Catalysts: A Case of Rh Anchored on the &lt;i&gt;P&lt;/i&gt;6&lt;i&gt;m&lt;/i&gt;2-NP Configurations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03148</link>
      <description>Tao Huang, Yaping Zhong, Lei Li, Wan Hui, Can Leng, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392093761

                Catalytic performance of single-atom catalysts (SACs) relies fundamentally on the electronic nature and local coordination environment of the active site. Here, based on a machine-learning (ML)-aided density functional theory (DFT) method, we reveal that the intrinsic dipole in Janus materials has a significant impact on the catalytic activity of SACs, using 2D &#947;-phosphorus carbide (&#947;-PC) as a model system. Specifically, a local dipole around the active site is a key degree to tune the catalytic activity and can be used as an important descriptor with a high feature importance of 17.1% in predicting the difference of adsorption free energy (&#916;GO* &#8211; &#916;GOH*) to assess the activity of the oxygen evolution reaction. As a result, the catalytic performance of SACs can be tuned by an intrinsic dipole, in stark contrast to those external stimuli strategies previously used. These results suggest that dipole engineering and the revolutionary DFT-ML hybrid scheme are novel approaches for designing high-performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Huang, Yaping Zhong, Lei Li, Wan Hui, Can Leng, Gui&#8208;Fang Huang, Wangyu Hu, Wei&#8208;Qing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Mo cations dissolution and surface reconstruction of CoMoO4 for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173963</link>
      <description>Hong Yin, Yaonan Mo, Chuang Liu, Hengbo Xiao, Zhilong Zheng, Songliu Yuan, Junjie Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392095514

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hong Yin, Yaonan Mo, Chuang Liu, Hengbo Xiao, Zhilong Zheng, Songliu Yuan, Junjie Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast electronic and vibrational spectroscopy of electrochemical transformations on a metal-oxide surface during oxygen evolution from water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-rzgp3</link>
      <description>Tanja Cuk, Xihan Chen, Suryansh Singh, Michael Paolino, James J. P. Stewart, Ilya Vinogradov, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392103902

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) from water fuels the planet through photosynthesis and is a primary means for hydrogen storage in energy technologies. Yet the detection of intermediates of OER central to the catalytic mechanism has been an ongoing challenge. This review covers the relevance of ultrafast electronic and vibrational spectroscopy of the electrochemical transformations of a metal-oxide surface undergoing OER. The electron doped SrTiO3/electrolyte is the system under review because of its high photocurrent efficiency with an ultrafast light trigger and because it allowed for detection of intermediate forms across the electromagnetic spectrum. The first part covers how the efficient catalytic reaction is triggered by ultrafast light pulses, describing the Schottky diode, the depletion layer, and Helmholtz layer under operating conditions to the extent possible. The second part covers the detection of the surface bound intermediates by transient spectroscopy. These target ultrafast (ps-ns) electron transfer from (or hole-trapping to) bound surface water species that are associated with the reactive oxygen intermediates of OER (e.g. OH*, O*). Their detection via a broadband visible probe, a mid-infrared evanescent wave, and coherent acoustic waves is then described. These target, respectively, the electronic states, the vibrational levels, and the lattice strain associated with the intermediates. The review is primarily concerned with how the measurements are made and the intermediates&#8217; experimental spectra. The theoretical descriptions are brought in as a needed to provide context to spectra that are difficult to interpret on their own. A concluding section summarizes the essential findings and methodologies.</description>
      <author>Tanja Cuk, Xihan Chen, Suryansh Singh, Michael Paolino, James J. P. Stewart, Ilya Vinogradov</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-rzgp3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel and Commercially Available Nickel&#8208;Containing Alloys as Electrodes for the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300460</link>
      <description>Nikolas Mao Kubo, Fabian Ketter, Stefan Palkovits, Regina Palkovits, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392105251

                Abstract Water electrolysis is a crucial technology for independency on fossil fuels. However, water splitting is limited by the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER). While many studies report highly active, non&#8208;precious metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts for alkaline OER, applicability under industrial conditions is often omitted. Such conditions require catalysts being applied on nickel or nickel&#8208;containing alloys in elevated electrolyte concentrations. In contrast to the rather inert substrates often used in scientific studies, such industrially applied substrates exhibit significant OER activity themselves and show dynamic behaviour. Therefore, it is crucial to understand the OER behaviour of such substrates. Here, nickel and seven commercially available nickel&#8208;containing alloys are investigated as anodes in alkaline OER and their elemental compositions correlated to their corresponding activities. Repeated potential cycling across the Ni(II)/Ni(III)&#8208;redox couple is established as activity&#8208;enhancing procedure. Overall, the nickel&#8208;base alloy Hastelloy&#174; X exhibits the highest activity due to its Fe&#8208;, Cr&#8208;, Mo&#8208; and Co&#8208;content. Though, the activity gain differs significantly for the various materials. Comparing Ni and Hastelloy&#174; X as least and most active materials, the positive impact of activation on both activity and stability becomes evident. While untreated Ni suffers from poor OER stability, the activity&#8208;enhancing procedure also significantly increases electrode stability in 24 h chronopotentiometry.</description>
      <author>Nikolas Mao Kubo, Fabian Ketter, Stefan Palkovits, Regina Palkovits</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202300460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the d-band states of NiFe-MOFs by combining early and late transition metals for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ce01265d</link>
      <description>Dan Wen, Xie Dan, Bo Huang, Qiuping Huang, Dunmin Lin, Xu Cheng, Fengyu Xie, Guangzhao Wang, Weihua Guo, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392105540

                This work presents a strategy of early-and-late transition metal combination to provide new pathways for efficient water splitting catalyst development.</description>
      <author>Dan Wen, Xie Dan, Bo Huang, Qiuping Huang, Dunmin Lin, Xu Cheng, Fengyu Xie, Guangzhao Wang, Weihua Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ce01265d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarized Ultrathin BN Induced Dynamic Electron Interactions for Enhancing Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202402018</link>
      <description>Yixin Hao, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Cheng Tian, Luqi Wang, Yiyu Chen, Sheng Zhao, Kang-Lin Peng, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Chun&#8208;Han Kuo, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Shengjie Peng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392109777

                Developing ruthenium&#8208;based heterogeneous catalysts with an efficient and stable interface is essential for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we report a defect&#8208;rich ultrathin boron nitride nanosheet support with relatively independent electron donor and acceptor sites, which serves as an electron reservoir and receiving station for RuO2, realizing the rapid supply and reception of electrons. Through precisely controlling the reaction interface, a low OER overpotential of only 180 mV (at 10 mA cm&#8722;2) and long&#8208;term operational stability (350 h) are achieved, suggesting potential practical applications. In&#8208;situ characterization and theoretical calculations have validated the existence of a localized electronic recycling between RuO2 and BNNS. The electron&#8208;rich Ru sites accelerate the adsorption of water molecules and the dissociation of intermediates, while the interconnection between the O&#8208;terminal and B&#8208;terminal edge establishes electronic back&#8208;donation, effectively suppressing the over&#8208;oxidation of lattice oxygen. This study provides a new perspective for constructing a stable and highly active catalytic interface.</description>
      <author>Yixin Hao, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Cheng Tian, Luqi Wang, Yiyu Chen, Sheng Zhao, Kang-Lin Peng, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Chun&#8208;Han Kuo, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202402018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarized Ultrathin BN Induced Dynamic Electron Interactions for Enhancing Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202402018</link>
      <description>Yixin Hao, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Cheng Tian, Luqi Wang, Yiyu Chen, Sheng Zhao, Kang-Lin Peng, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Chun&#8208;Han Kuo, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Shengjie Peng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392110312

                Developing ruthenium&#8208;based heterogeneous catalysts with an efficient and stable interface is essential for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we report a defect&#8208;rich ultrathin boron nitride nanosheet support with relatively independent electron donor and acceptor sites, which serves as an electron reservoir and receiving station for RuO2, realizing the rapid supply and reception of electrons. Through precisely controlling the reaction interface, a low OER overpotential of only 180 mV (at 10 mA cm&#8722;2) and long&#8208;term operational stability (350 h) are achieved, suggesting potential practical applications. In&#8208;situ characterization and theoretical calculations have validated the existence of a localized electronic recycling between RuO2 and BNNS. The electron&#8208;rich Ru sites accelerate the adsorption of water molecules and the dissociation of intermediates, while the interconnection between the O&#8208;terminal and B&#8208;terminal edge establishes electronic back&#8208;donation, effectively suppressing the over&#8208;oxidation of lattice oxygen. This study provides a new perspective for constructing a stable and highly active catalytic interface.</description>
      <author>Yixin Hao, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Cheng Tian, Luqi Wang, Yiyu Chen, Sheng Zhao, Kang-Lin Peng, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Chun&#8208;Han Kuo, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202402018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoflowers of Ternary Cobalt&#8211;Copper&#8211;Manganese Oxide as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202301355</link>
      <description>Jyoti Raghav, P. Rosaiah, Bandar Ali Al&#8208;Asbahi, Soumyendu Roy, Energy Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392130324

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an integral step in the water&#8208;splitting process. Hence, to promote OER, efficient catalysts are required to lower the energy barriers at the electrode/electrolyte interface. Low&#8208;cost and highly active catalysts are in great demand. Herein, a ternary metal oxide, CoCuMnO x , synthesized by a facile hydrothermal method is reported, which possesses excellent catalytic ability for OER in alkaline electrolytes. The nanoscale morphology of the catalyst with flower&#8208;like nanostructures is instrumental in increasing the electrochemical surface area of the electrode. The presence of multivalent ions and the incorporation of copper greatly enhance the electrochemical properties of the catalysts. The catalysts typically demonstrate an overpotential value of 220 mV for achieving 10 mA cm &#8722;2 current density and a Tafel slope of 73 mV dec &#8722;1 . The catalysts demonstrate good stability with minimal degradation in OER activity even after 20 h of chronopotentiometry test. For practical applications, this low&#8208;cost material holds great potential.</description>
      <author>Jyoti Raghav, P. Rosaiah, Bandar Ali Al&#8208;Asbahi, Soumyendu Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202301355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking accelerated oxygen evolution reaction enabled by explosive reconstruction of active species based on Co&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;N@NC</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00196f</link>
      <description>Hyung Wook Choi, Jiwon Kim, Hyeon&#8208;Seok Bang, Khaled Badawy, Ui Young Lee, Dong In Jeong, Yeseul Kim, Kotiba Hamad, Bong Kyun Kang, Byung Mook Weon, Hyung Suk Oh, Nirpendra Singh, Dae Ho Yoon, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392135567

                The development of a hierarchical structure of Co/Co 4 N@NC has been successfully achieved. The robust oxygen evolution reaction activity of Co/Co 4 N@NC is attributed to the modulation of the d-band center, which reconstruct Co 2+ into Co 3+ .</description>
      <author>Hyung Wook Choi, Jiwon Kim, Hyeon&#8208;Seok Bang, Khaled Badawy, Ui Young Lee, Dong In Jeong, Yeseul Kim, Kotiba Hamad, Bong Kyun Kang, Byung Mook Weon, Hyung Suk Oh, Nirpendra Singh, Dae Ho Yoon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00196f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface&#8208;Engineered NiFe/Ni&#8208;S Nanoparticles for Reliable Alkaline Oxygen Production at Industrial Current: A Sulfur Source Confinement Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310737</link>
      <description>Bin Chen, Tao Liu, Xiangwen Zhang, Shichao Zhao, Runfei Yue, Sipu Wang, Lianqin Wang, Zhihao Chen, Yingjie Feng, Jun Huang, Yan Yin, Michael D. Guiver, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392139199

                Abstract Using powder&#8208;based ink appears to be the most suitable candidate for commercializing the membrane electrode assembly (MEA), while research on the powder&#8208;based NPM catalyst for anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) is currently insufficient, especially at high current density. Herein, a sulfur source (NiFe Layered double hydroxide adsorbed ) confinement strategy is developed to integrate Ni 3 S 2 onto the surface of amorphous/crystalline NiFe alloy nanoparticles (denoted NiFe/Ni&#8208;S), achieving advanced control over the sulfidation process for the formation of metal sulfides. The constructed interface under the sulfur source confinement strategy generates abundant active sites that increase electron transport at the electrode&#8208;electrolyte interface and improve ability over an extended period at a high current density. Consequently, the constructed NiFe/Ni&#8208;S delivers an ultra&#8208;low overpotential of 239 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and 0.66 mA under an overpotential of 300 mV. The AEMWE with NiFe/Ni&#8208;S anode exhibits a cell voltage of 1.664 V @ 0.5 A cm &#8722;2 and a 400 h stability at 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Bin Chen, Tao Liu, Xiangwen Zhang, Shichao Zhao, Runfei Yue, Sipu Wang, Lianqin Wang, Zhihao Chen, Yingjie Feng, Jun Huang, Yan Yin, Michael D. Guiver</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of strain in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.007</link>
      <description>Zhixuan Feng, Chia-Tsen Dai, Zhe Zhang, Xuefei Lei, Wenning Mu, Rui Guo, Xuanwen Liu, Jinyuan You, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392122210

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhixuan Feng, Chia-Tsen Dai, Zhe Zhang, Xuefei Lei, Wenning Mu, Rui Guo, Xuanwen Liu, Jinyuan You</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction on iridium-molybdenum mixed oxide electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4392181502</link>
      <description>C&#233;dric Tard, Marine Elmaalouf, Silvia Dur&#225;n, Mateusz Odziomek, Marco Faustini, C&#233;dric Boissi&#232;re, Marion Giraud, Jennifer P&#233;ron, No host. None(None)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4392181502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C&#233;dric Tard, Marine Elmaalouf, Silvia Dur&#225;n, Mateusz Odziomek, Marco Faustini, C&#233;dric Boissi&#232;re, Marion Giraud, Jennifer P&#233;ron</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4392181502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven mechanisms of oxygen evolution reaction proposed recently: A mini review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149992</link>
      <description>Zhixuan Feng, Chia-Tsen Dai, Peng Shi, Xuefei Lei, Rui Guo, Biao Wang, Xuanwen Liu, Jinyuan You, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392142198

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhixuan Feng, Chia-Tsen Dai, Peng Shi, Xuefei Lei, Rui Guo, Biao Wang, Xuanwen Liu, Jinyuan You</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.149992</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electroactive heterojunctions of iron-based compounds in oxygen evolution reaction &#8211; insight into synergy and mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144005</link>
      <description>Anna Dymerska, Ewa Mijowska, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Rustem Zairov, Ewa Mijowska, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392170706

                This research addresses the inherent challenges of low catalytic activity and stability often associated with Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) catalysts. We designed composites with outstanding electrocatalytic performance. The methodology is characterized by low-temperature operation and environmentally friendly substrates. We have successfully fostered a synergistic interplay between Fe and oxygen, carbon and nickel, respectively. Fabricated material composed of three different heterojunctions triggered the stability of the catalyst and facilitated efficient charge transfer in OER. Our optimized catalyst (Fe/Ni_3.0h), emerges as a promising candidate for practical applications, exhibiting an overpotential of 310 mV, a Tafel slope of 37 mV/dec, and a potential retention of 98.8% which is a 50% lower drop in respect to commercial RuO2. Therefore, our approach underlines the substantial influence of conductive Fe-based materials: FeNi3, Fe3C, and Fe3O4 on OER performance with revealed comprehensive mechanism via ex-situ XRD and M&#246;ssbauer spectroscopy analyses.</description>
      <author>Anna Dymerska, Ewa Mijowska, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Rustem Zairov, Ewa Mijowska</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distance effect of single atoms on stability of cobalt oxide catalysts for acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46176-0</link>
      <description>Z. D. Zhang, Chuanyi Jia, Peiyu Ma, Feng Chen, Yang Jin, Jian Huang, Jian&#8208;Guo Zheng, Ming J. Zuo, Mingkai Liu, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392153698

                Abstract Developing efficient and economical electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE). Cobalt oxides are considered promising non-precious OER catalysts due to their high activities. However, the severe dissolution of Co atoms in acid media leads to the collapse of crystal structure, which impedes their application in PEMWE. Here, we report that introducing acid-resistant Ir single atoms into the lattice of spinel cobalt oxides can significantly suppress the Co dissolution and keep them highly stable during the acidic OER process. Combining theoretical and experimental studies, we reveal that the stabilizing effect induced by Ir heteroatoms exhibits a strong dependence on the distance of adjacent Ir single atoms, where the OER stability of cobalt oxides continuously improves with decreasing the distance. When the distance reduces to about 0.6 nm, the spinel cobalt oxides present no obvious degradation over a 60-h stability test for acidic OER, suggesting potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Z. D. Zhang, Chuanyi Jia, Peiyu Ma, Feng Chen, Yang Jin, Jian Huang, Jian&#8208;Guo Zheng, Ming J. Zuo, Mingkai Liu, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46176-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability challenges and opportunities of NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.110</link>
      <description>Yujun Han, Jingyi Wang, Yuhang Liu, Tianqi Li, Tongzhou Wang, Xinyue Li, X. J. Ye, Guodong Li, Jihong Li, Wenbin Hu, Yida Deng, Carbon Neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392196226

                Abstract Water splitting is a critical process for the production of green hydrogen, contributing to the advancement of a circular economy. However, the application of water splitting devices on a large scale is primarily impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode. Thus, developing and designing efficient OER catalysts is a significant target. NiFe&#8208;based catalysts are extensively researched as excellent OER electrocatalysts due to their affordability, abundant reserves, and intrinsic activities. However, they still suffer from long&#8208;term stability challenges. To date, few systematic strategies for improving OER durability have been reported. In this review, various advanced NiFe&#8208;based catalysts are introduced. Moreover, the OER stability challenges of NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts in alkaline media, including iron segregation, structural degradation, and peeling from the substrate are summarized. More importantly, strategies to enhance OER stability are highlighted and opportunities are discussed to facilitate future stability studies for alkaline water electrolysis. This review presents a design strategy for NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts and anion exchange membrane (AEM) electrolyzers to overcome stability challenges in OER, which also emphasizes the importance of long&#8208;term stability in alkaline media and its significance for achieving large&#8208;scale commercialization.</description>
      <author>Yujun Han, Jingyi Wang, Yuhang Liu, Tianqi Li, Tongzhou Wang, Xinyue Li, X. J. Ye, Guodong Li, Jihong Li, Wenbin Hu, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface addition of Ag on PbO2 to enable efficient oxygen evolution reaction in pH-neutral media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150043</link>
      <description>Siming Li, Meng Shi, Chen Wu, Kaiqi Nie, Zheng Wang, Xiaoxu Jiang, Xinbing Liu, Huili Chen, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu, Siming Li, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392184832

                Electrocatalysts, particularly earth-abundant metal oxide ones, exhibit poor performance in catalyzing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under neutral conditions due to low ionic concentrations. This study introduces a novel strategy for fabricating a PbO2 + Ag composite electrode with significantly improved OER activity and stability in a pH-neutral environment. Our results suggest that incorporating Ag as a surface additive improves the efficiency of utilizing adsorbed oxygenated species via the bridge-site-top-site pathway. Moreover, the surface decoration of Ag resulted in enhanced electrocatalytic stability by diverting the attack of oxygenated species to Pb thereby effectively preventing Pb dissolution. The results not only establish a method for utilizing PbO2 in pH-neutral OER applications, but also propose a potential strategy for employing less noble catalysts in cost-effective electrochemical energy conversions.</description>
      <author>Siming Li, Meng Shi, Chen Wu, Kaiqi Nie, Zheng Wang, Xiaoxu Jiang, Xinbing Liu, Huili Chen, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu, Siming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exfoliation of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks to Give 2D MOF Nanosheets for the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202402969</link>
      <description>Peng Wu, Shuang Geng, Xinyu Wang, Xinglong Zhang, Hongfeng Li, Lulu Zhang, Yu Shen, Baoli Zha, Suoying Zhang, Fengwei Huo, Weina Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392156438

                The structure and properties of materials are determined by a diverse range of chemical bond formation and breaking mechanisms, which greatly motivates the development of selectively controlling the chemical bonds in order to achieve materials with specific characteristics. Here, an orientational intervening bond&#8208;breaking strategy is demonstrated for synthesizing ultrathin metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nanosheets through balancing the process of thermal decomposition and liquid nitrogen exfoliation. In such approach, proper thermal treatment can weaken the interlayer bond while maintaining the stability of the intralayer bond in the layered MOFs. And the following liquid nitrogen treatment results in significant deformation and stress in the layered MOFs&#8217; structure due to the instant temperature drop and drastic expansion of liquid N2, leading to the curling, detachment, and separation of the MOF layers. The produced MOF nanosheets with five cycles of treatment are primarily composed of nanosheets that are less than 10 nm in thickness. The MOF nanosheets exhibit enhanced catalytic performance in oxygen evolution reactions owing to the ultrathin thickness without capping agents which provide improved charge transfer efficiency and dense exposed active sites. This strategy underscores the significance of orientational intervention in chemical bonds to engineer innovative materials.</description>
      <author>Peng Wu, Shuang Geng, Xinyu Wang, Xinglong Zhang, Hongfeng Li, Lulu Zhang, Yu Shen, Baoli Zha, Suoying Zhang, Fengwei Huo, Weina Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202402969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exfoliation of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks to Give 2D MOF Nanosheets for the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202402969</link>
      <description>Peng Wu, Shuang Geng, Xinyu Wang, Xinglong Zhang, Hongfeng Li, Lulu Zhang, Yu Shen, Baoli Zha, Suoying Zhang, Fengwei Huo, Suoying Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392166415

                The structure and properties of materials are determined by a diverse range of chemical bond formation and breaking mechanisms, which greatly motivates the development of selectively controlling the chemical bonds in order to achieve materials with specific characteristics. Here, an orientational intervening bond&#8208;breaking strategy is demonstrated for synthesizing ultrathin metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nanosheets through balancing the process of thermal decomposition and liquid nitrogen exfoliation. In such approach, proper thermal treatment can weaken the interlayer bond while maintaining the stability of the intralayer bond in the layered MOFs. And the following liquid nitrogen treatment results in significant deformation and stress in the layered MOFs&#8217; structure due to the instant temperature drop and drastic expansion of liquid N2, leading to the curling, detachment, and separation of the MOF layers. The produced MOF nanosheets with five cycles of treatment are primarily composed of nanosheets that are less than 10 nm in thickness. The MOF nanosheets exhibit enhanced catalytic performance in oxygen evolution reactions owing to the ultrathin thickness without capping agents which provide improved charge transfer efficiency and dense exposed active sites. This strategy underscores the significance of orientational intervention in chemical bonds to engineer innovative materials.</description>
      <author>Peng Wu, Shuang Geng, Xinyu Wang, Xinglong Zhang, Hongfeng Li, Lulu Zhang, Yu Shen, Baoli Zha, Suoying Zhang, Fengwei Huo, Suoying Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202402969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Nanotube Composites with Bimetallic Transition Metal Selenides as Efficient Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16051953</link>
      <description>Saira Riaz, Muhammad Shafiq Anjum, Abid Ali, Yasir Mehmood, Muhammad Ahmad, Norah Alwadai, Munawar Iqbal, Salih Aky&#252;rekli, Noor Hassan, Rizwan Shoukat, Sustainability. 16(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392189844

                Hydrogen fuel is a clean and versatile energy carrier that can be used for various applications, including transportation, power generation, and industrial processes. Electrocatalytic water splitting could be the most beneficial and facile approach for producing hydrogen. In this work, transition metal selenide composites with carbon nanotubes (CNTs) have been investigated for electrocatalytic water splitting. The synthesis process involved the facile one-step hydrothermal growth of transition metal nanoparticles over the CNTs and acted as an efficient electrode toward electrochemical water splitting. Scanning electron microscopy and XRD patterns reveal that nanoparticles were firmly anchored on the CNTs, resulting in the formation of composites. The electrochemical measurements reveal that CNT composite with nickel&#8211;cobalt selenides (NiCo-Se/CNTs@NF) display remarkable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity in basic media, which is an important part of hydrogen production. It demonstrates the lowest overpotential (&#951;10mAcm&#8722;2) of 0.560 V vs. RHE, a reduced Tafel slope of 163 mV/dec, and lower charge transfer impedance for the OER process. The multi-metallic selenide composite with CNTs demonstrating unique nanostructure and synergistic effects offers a promising platform for enhancing electrocatalytic OER performance and opens up new avenues for efficient energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Saira Riaz, Muhammad Shafiq Anjum, Abid Ali, Yasir Mehmood, Muhammad Ahmad, Norah Alwadai, Munawar Iqbal, Salih Aky&#252;rekli, Noor Hassan, Rizwan Shoukat</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16051953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridine caused structural reconfiguration forming ultrathin 2D metal-organic frameworks for oxygen evolution reaction.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta08079j</link>
      <description>Liusi Yang, Shuwei Deng, Shenyuan Fu, Xiaoteng Wang, Gang Liu, Haidong Yang, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392205602

                Two-dimensional metal-organic frameworks (2D MOFs) as an ideal prototype material for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can expose more metal active sites due to their ultrathin 2D structure. Herein, a...</description>
      <author>Liusi Yang, Shuwei Deng, Shenyuan Fu, Xiaoteng Wang, Gang Liu, Haidong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta08079j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural reconstruction of cobalt and ferrocene-based metal-organic framework during electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vlqz5</link>
      <description>Thomas Doughty, Andrea Zingl, Maximilian W&#252;nschek, Christian M. Pichler, Matthew Watkins, Souvik Roy, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392168646

                Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) are increasingly being investigated as electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their unique modular structures that present a hybrid between molecular and heterogeneous catalysts, featuring well-defined active sites. However, many fundamental questions remain open regarding the electrochemical stability of MOFs, structural reconstruction of coordination sites, and the role of in situ-formed species. Here we report structural transformation of a surface-grown MOF containing cobalt nodes and 1,1&#8217;-ferrocenedicarboxylic acid linkers (denoted as CoFc-MOF) during OER in alkaline electrolyte. Ex situ and in situ investigations of CoFc-MOF film suggests that the MOF acts as a pre-catalyst and undergoes a two-step restructuring process under operating conditions to generate a metal oxyhydroxide phase. The MOF-derived metal oxyhydroxide catalyst, supported on nickel foam electrodes, displays high activity towards OER with an overpotential of 190 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2. While this study demonstrates the necessity of investigating structural evolution of MOFs in electrocatalysis, it also shows potential of using MOFs as precursors in catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Thomas Doughty, Andrea Zingl, Maximilian W&#252;nschek, Christian M. Pichler, Matthew Watkins, Souvik Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vlqz5</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
