<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 01:16:07 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Ag3VO4@ZnO electrode material for efficient oxygen evolution reaction showcasing its potential for sustainable energy applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133029</link>
      <description>Ali Junaid, Faiqa Noreen, Abdus Sami, Karam Jabbour, Khadija Bibi, Muhammad Ammar Hassan Shah, Nigarish Bano, Muhammad Shuaib Khan, Asma A. Alothman, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Fuel. 379(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4402315636

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ali Junaid, Faiqa Noreen, Abdus Sami, Karam Jabbour, Khadija Bibi, Muhammad Ammar Hassan Shah, Nigarish Bano, Muhammad Shuaib Khan, Asma A. Alothman, Syed Imran Abbas Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Production of Silicon Using Oxygen-Evolving Sno2 Anode in Molten Cacl2-Nacl</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4942638</link>
      <description>Sai Krishna Padamata, Gu&#240;r&#250;n S&#230;varsd&#243;ttir, Geir Martin Haarberg, SSRN Electronic Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402163034

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sai Krishna Padamata, Gu&#240;r&#250;n S&#230;varsd&#243;ttir, Geir Martin Haarberg</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4942638</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decorated and reconstructed perovskite-oxide electrodes for oxygen electrocatalysis and Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.002</link>
      <description>Guichan Chen, Jiapeng Liu, Dengjie Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402163900

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guichan Chen, Jiapeng Liu, Dengjie Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Catalysts: Exploring Discharge Product Growth and Intrinsic Overpotential in Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00789</link>
      <description>Zhengxuan Yin, Chuying Ouyang, Neil Qiang Su, Journal of Chemical Theory and Computation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402167300

                The lithium&#8211;oxygen (Li&#8211;O2) battery, renowned for its exceptionally high theoretical energy density, is poised to revolutionize next-generation energy storage systems. However, its practical application depends on overcoming several challenges, particularly the high cathode overpotential, which significantly diminishes the battery's energy efficiency and durability. This study delves into the interactions at the cathode surface during oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER), extending the analysis beyond the initial reaction stages to encompass the extensive charge&#8211;discharge process. We introduce and define the concepts of intrinsic equilibrium potential and intrinsic overpotential, demonstrating that these critical parameters are predominantly influenced by the growth of discharge products, rather than the catalysts, thereby underscoring the inherent properties of the battery. This shift in focus from merely enhancing cathode catalysts to understanding and leveraging the intrinsic characteristics of the battery discharge process opens new avenues for optimizing and enhancing the performance of large-scale Li&#8211;O2 batteries. Furthermore, our findings indicate potential broader applications to other metal&#8211;oxygen systems, paving the way for the design of high-capacity, high-efficiency energy storage technologies.</description>
      <author>Zhengxuan Yin, Chuying Ouyang, Neil Qiang Su</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jctc.4c00789</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Compositions and Nanostructures of Trimetallic Prussian Blue Analog&#8208;Derived Carbides for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402916</link>
      <description>Lujiao Mao, Jie Liu, Rong Lin, Jinhang Xue, Yuandong Yang, Shaojie Xu, Qipeng Li, Jinjie Qian, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402168383

                Abstract The electrochemical splitting of water for hydrogen production faces a major challenge due to its anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), necessitating research on the rational design and facile synthesis of OER catalysts to enhance catalytic activity and stability. This study proposes a ligand&#8208;induced MOF&#8208;on&#8208;MOF approach to fabricate various trimetallic MnFeCo&#8208;based Prussian blue analog (PBA) nanostructures. The addition of [Fe(CN) 6 ] 3&#8722; transforms them from cuboids with protruding corners (MnFeCoPBA&#8208;I) to core&#8211;shell configurations (MnFeCoPBA&#8208;II), and finally to hollow structures (MnFeCoPBA&#8208;III). After pyrolysis at 800 &#176;C, they are converted into corresponding PBA&#8208;derived carbon nanomaterials, featuring uniformly dispersed Mn 2 Co 2 C nanoparticles. A comparative analysis demonstrates that the Fe addition enhances catalytic activity, while Mn&#8208;doped materials exhibit excellent stability. Specifically, the optimized MnFeCoNC&#8208;I&#8208;800 demonstrates outstanding OER performance in 1.0 m KOH solution, with an overpotential of 318 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , maintaining stability for up to 150 h. Theoretical calculations elucidate synergistic interactions between Fe dopants and the Mn 2 Co 2 C matrix, reducing barriers for oxygen intermediates and improving intrinsic OER activity. These findings offer valuable insights into the structure&#8208;morphology relationships of MOF precursors, advancing the development of highly active and stable MOF&#8208;derived OER catalysts for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Lujiao Mao, Jie Liu, Rong Lin, Jinhang Xue, Yuandong Yang, Shaojie Xu, Qipeng Li, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The dual gain strategy of introducing nickel doping and anchoring amorphous iron oxyhydroxide nanosheets on ZIF-67 achieves an efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129501</link>
      <description>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Hao Lin, Anaclet Nsabimana, Shigang Shen, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402169439

                A ZIF-67@Ni@FeOOH composite material was synthesized using nickel-doped ZIF-67 as a precursor and was electrochemically characterized as an efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst. The results indicated that Ni doping preserved the polyhedral structure of ZIF-67 while enhancing its OER activity. The introduction of amorphous FeOOH nanosheets allowed ZIF-67@Ni@FeOOH to not only retain its original polyhedral structure but also develop a hollow interior and self-remodeling surface, resulting in numerous defects. These features contribute to improved charge transfer efficiency and enhanced conductivity of the material. The dual enhancement effect is achieved by combining the doping strategy with structural defect engineering. The synergistic effects of Co, Ni, and Fe species further boost OER performance. The ZIF-67@Ni@FeOOH catalyst exhibited remarkable OER efficacy, with the lowest overpotential at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 being 329 mV and a low Tafel slope of 42.95 mV dec&#8722;1. In situ Raman spectroscopy revealed that high-valence hydroxyl oxides, specifically NiOOH and CoOOH, present on the composite surface were the active species for OER. This study offers a promising approach for developing economically viable electrocatalysts with superior efficiency for OER.</description>
      <author>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Hao Lin, Anaclet Nsabimana, Shigang Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129501</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Polarization of Ni Sites at VO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&#8722;Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N Interface Boosts Ethanol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407473</link>
      <description>Min Zhou, Biao Jin, Weijie Kong, Anjie Chen, Yuhe Chen, Qian Zhang, Fei Lu, Xi Wang, Xianghua Zeng, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402170349

                Abstract Substituting thermodynamically favorable ethanol oxidation reaction (EOR) for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) engenders high&#8208;efficiency hydrogen production and generates high value&#8208;added products as well. However, the main obstacles have been the low activity and the absence of an explicit catalytic mechanism. Herein, a heterostructure composed of amorphous vanadium oxide and crystalline nickel nitride (VO x &#8722;Ni 3 N) is developed. The heterostructure immensely boosts the EOR process, achieving the current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 at the low potential of 1.38 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), far surpassing the sluggish OER (1.65 V vs RHE). Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy indicates that the as&#8208;fabricated heterostructure can promote the adsorption of OH &#8722; and the generation of the reactive species (O * ). Theoretical calculations further outline the dual polarization of the Ni site at the interface, specifically the asymmetric charge redistribution (interfacial polarization) and in&#8208;plane polarization. Consequently, the dual polarization modulates the d&#8208;band center, which in turn regulates the adsorption/desorption strength of key reaction intermediates, thereby facilitating the entire EOR process. Moreover, a VO x &#8722;Ni 3 N&#8208;based electrolyzer, coupling hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and EOR, attains 50 mA cm &#8722;2 at a low cell voltage of &#8776;1.5 V. This work thus paves the way for creating dual polarization through interface engineering toward broad catalysis.</description>
      <author>Min Zhou, Biao Jin, Weijie Kong, Anjie Chen, Yuhe Chen, Qian Zhang, Fei Lu, Xi Wang, Xianghua Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407473</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure Properties Correlations on Nickel&#8208;Iron Oxide Catalysts Deposited by Atomic Layer Deposition for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400091</link>
      <description>Estelle Jozwiak, M. Piccinini, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Nicola Pinna, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402171208

                Thermal atomic layer deposition (ALD) is used for the first time to deposit iron&#8208;nickel oxides onto carbon nanotubes in a ternary process to produce a wide range of mixed oxide thin films. When using ferrocene (FeCp 2 ) and nickelocene (NiCp 2 ) with ozone (O 3 ) as metals and oxygen sources, respectively, a competition between the metal precursors and the growth modes is observed. Indeed, while ferrocene promotes a 2D&#8208;growth, nickelocene prefers a 3D&#8208;growth. Although both precursors are homoleptic metallocenes, they behave differently in the ALD of their respective metal oxide, leading to unexpected atomic ratios and films morphologies of the iron&#8208;nickel oxides. The 2Fe:1Ni sample displays the best performances in the electrochemical water oxidation (oxygen evolution reaction) exhibiting an overpotential of 267 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;1 , a Tafel slope of 36.8 mV dec &#8722;1 , as well as a good stability after 15 h of continuous operation.</description>
      <author>Estelle Jozwiak, M. Piccinini, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Nicola Pinna</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Reconstruction Regulation of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N Through Heterostructure Engineering Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406465</link>
      <description>Ye Zeng, Jiaxian Zheng, Heru Zhang, Fen Yao, Dingrong Deng, Qi&#8208;Hui Wu, Peter R. Makgwane, Hanfeng Liang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402171405

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts generally experience structural and electronic modifications during electrocatalysis. This phenomenon, referred to as surface reconstruction, results in the formation of catalytically active species that act as real OER sites. Controlling surface reconstruction therefore is vital for enhancing the OER performance of electrocatalysts. In this study, a new approach is introduced of heterostructure engineering to facilitate the surface reconstruction of target catalysts. Using MnCo carbonate hydroxide (MnCo&#9472;CH)@Co 3 N as a demonstration, it is discovered that the surface reconstruction occurs more readily and rapidly on MnCo&#9472;CH@Co 3 N than on Co 3 N. More interestingly, during the reconstruction process, Mn species migrate to the surface, enabling the in situ formation of highly active Mn&#8208;doped CoOOH. Consequently, the MnCo&#9472;CH@Co 3 N catalyst after reconstruction exhibits a low overpotential of 257 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , compared to 379 mV of individual Co 3 N. This work offers fresh perspectives on understanding the enhanced OER performance of heterostructure electrocatalysts and the role of heterostructure in promoting surface reconstruction.</description>
      <author>Ye Zeng, Jiaxian Zheng, Heru Zhang, Fen Yao, Dingrong Deng, Qi&#8208;Hui Wu, Peter R. Makgwane, Hanfeng Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406465</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically Created Active Centers in a Bimetallic CoNi&#8208;Triazole Metal&#8208;Organic Framework for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400423</link>
      <description>Natchaya Phongsuk, Kanyaporn Adpakpang, Ladawan Pukdeejorhor, Thassanant Atithep, Panyapat Ponchai, ChemPlusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402194337

                Electrochemical water oxidation utilizing bimetallic CoNi&#8208;Tz (Tz = 1,2,4&#8208;triazole) framework is explored. Initially, CoNi&#8208;Tz possesses active tetrahedral Co center and electron&#8208;mediated octahedral Ni chain. After performing an electrochemical activation, the partial structural transformation on the Ni center occurs. This leads to the generation of excessive active centers which can promote catalytic activity of the framework. The activated CoNi&#8208;Tz catalyst displays a remarkably low OER overpotential of 293 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 with a small Tafel slope of 49.98 mV dec&#8208;1, outperforming the single metal Co&#8208;Tz and benchmark IrO2 catalysts.</description>
      <author>Natchaya Phongsuk, Kanyaporn Adpakpang, Ladawan Pukdeejorhor, Thassanant Atithep, Panyapat Ponchai</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cplu.202400423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of SnWO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;, SnW&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;, and WO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Phases in Tin Tungstate Films on Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09713</link>
      <description>Farabi Bozheyev, Steffen Fengler, Jiri Kollmann, Daniel Abou&#8208;Ras, Nico Scharnagl, Mauricio Schieda, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402198323

                An essential step toward enabling the production of renewable and cost-efficient fuels is an improved understanding of the performance of energy conversion materials. In recent years, there has been growing interest in ternary metal oxides. Particularly, &#945;-SnWO4 exhibited promising properties for application to photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting. However, the number of corresponding studies remains limited, and a deeper understanding of the physical and chemical processes in &#945;-SnWO4 is necessary. To date, charge-carrier generation, separation, and transfer have not been exhaustively studied for SnWO4-based photoelectrodes. All of these processes depend on the phase composition, not only &#945;-SnWO4 but also on the related phases SnW3O9 and WO3, as well as on their spatial distributions resulting from the coating synthesis. In the present work, these processes in different phases of tin tungstate films were investigated by transient surface photovoltage (TSPV) spectroscopy to complement the analysis of the applicability of &#945;-SnWO4 thin films for practical PEC oxygen evolution. Pure &#945;-SnWO4 films exhibit higher photoactivities than those of films containing secondary SnW3O9 and WO3 phases due to the higher recombination of charge carriers when these phases are present.</description>
      <author>Farabi Bozheyev, Steffen Fengler, Jiri Kollmann, Daniel Abou&#8208;Ras, Nico Scharnagl, Mauricio Schieda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09713</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Decorated 3D Architectures Built from Nickel Carbonate Hydroxide Nanostructured Spheres as Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03651</link>
      <description>Jun Huang, Weiqiang Hao, Junwei Liu, Shunhong Chen, Xiaonan Liu, Wuyun Zhao, Xiaoqiang Wu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402198754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Huang, Weiqiang Hao, Junwei Liu, Shunhong Chen, Xiaonan Liu, Wuyun Zhao, Xiaoqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ti3C2 Quantum Dots-Modified Oxygen-Vacancy-Rich BiOBr Hollow Microspheres Toward Optimized Photocatalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143255</link>
      <description>Tao Cheng, Zipeng Xing, Qian Zhang, Peng Sun, Hui Peng, Zhenzi Li, Li Wang, Wei Zhou, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402199407

                The Ti3C2 quantum dots (QDs)/oxygen-vacancy-rich BiOBr hollow microspheres composite photocatalyst was prepared using solvothermal synthesis and electrostatic self-assembly techniques. Together, Ti3C2QDs and oxygen vacancies (OVs) enhanced photocatalytic activity by broadening light absorption and improving charge transfer and separation processes, resulting in a significant performance boost. Meanwhile, the photocatalytic efficiency of Ti3C2 QDs/BiOBr-OVs is assessed to investigate its capability for oxygen evolution and degradation of tetracycline (TC) and Rhodamine B (RhB) under visible-light conditions. The rate of oxygen production is observed to be 5.1 times higher than that of pure BiOBr-OVs, while the photocatalytic degradation rates for TC and RhB is up to 97.27% and 99.8%, respectively. The synergistic effect between Ti3C2QDs and OVs greatly enhances charge separation, leading to remarkable photocatalytic activity. Furthermore, the hollow microsphere contributes to the enhanced photocatalytic performance by facilitating multiple light scatterings and providing ample surface-active sites. The resultant Ti3C2QDs/BiOBr-OVs composite photocatalyst demonstrates significant potential for environmental applications.</description>
      <author>Tao Cheng, Zipeng Xing, Qian Zhang, Peng Sun, Hui Peng, Zhenzi Li, Li Wang, Wei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics of Zeolitic Imidazolate Framework-L and Application of Its Derivatives in Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Recent Trends</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176293</link>
      <description>Peng Shi, Sheng Wang, Sheng Wang, Xuefei Lei, Biao Wang, Xuanwen Liu, Junhua You, Rui Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402204521

                Electrochemical water splitting is a sustainable method to address current energy and climate issues. A significant number of research efforts are focused on the development of low-cost, high-efficiency, and high-durability water oxidation half-reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. Materials based on metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) possess porous structures and highly tunable compositions, making them a promising electrode material. As a subfamily of MOFs, Zeolitic Imidazolate Frameworks (ZIFs) have become promising electrode materials due to their porous morphologies and highly tunable compositions. ZIF-L, a member of the ZIF family, not only possesses many characteristics of MOFs but also has a unique 2D morphology, making it an ideal precursor material. However, there are few targeted reports on the application of ZIF-L and its derivatives in OER. In this review, we will focus on the structure, morphology, and phase transitions of ZIF-L, and summarize the applications and modification methods of ZIF-L in the OER field. Finally, we emphasize the development potential and future challenges of ZIF-L-derived electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Peng Shi, Sheng Wang, Sheng Wang, Xuefei Lei, Biao Wang, Xuanwen Liu, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile strategy for synthesis of flower-like FeNiS2 nanocomposite via integration of binary metal-organic framework and metal sulfide for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105049</link>
      <description>Hamideh Imanzadeh, Alireza Khataee, Mehran Nozari-Asbemarz, James J. Leahy, Mandana Amiri, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402205968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hamideh Imanzadeh, Alireza Khataee, Mehran Nozari-Asbemarz, James J. Leahy, Mandana Amiri</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A one-stone-three-birds strategy to construct Mo-FeS2/Ni3S2@C electrocatalyst with strong interfacial coupling effect to achieve efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161147</link>
      <description>Enhong Liu, Haoran Guo, Yanyan Li, Jiayang Zhao, Rui Song, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402206154

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enhong Liu, Haoran Guo, Yanyan Li, Jiayang Zhao, Rui Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Design Strategy for Highly Active Oxide Electrocatalysts by Incorporation of Oxygen&#8208;Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403415</link>
      <description>Narayan Acharya, Surendra B. Karki, Livia Giordano, Farshid Ramezanipour, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402207368

                Using both density functional theory (DFT+U) simulations and experiments, we show that the incorporation of an ordered array of oxygen-vacancies in a perovskite oxide can lead to enhancement of the electrocatalytic activity for the oxygen-evolution reaction (OER). As a benchmark, LaCoO</description>
      <author>Narayan Acharya, Surendra B. Karki, Livia Giordano, Farshid Ramezanipour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic micro-environment regulation of ZIF-67 with broadened pore structure and unsaturated coordination sites for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.368</link>
      <description>Lingxiang Liu, Li Wang, Shasha Cui, Tingting Li, Xiaomeng Yang, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402208249

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingxiang Liu, Li Wang, Shasha Cui, Tingting Li, Xiaomeng Yang, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.368</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel oxide/Nickel Nanohybrids for Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145002</link>
      <description>Fabiola Navarro&#8208;Pardo, Gurpreet Singh Selopal, Alma Paola Hernandez-Gonzalez, Ebrahim Ghasemy, Jiabin Liu, Kulbir Kaur Ghuman, Ana C. Tavares, Zhiming Wang, Federico Rosei, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402209514

                Ni-based materials are cost-efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions (OER and HER). Specifically, high-valence nickel oxides have been recently identified as highly active for both reactions; however, the origin of their activity during operation, particularly towards the HER, is still undefined. Herein, electrodeposition was used to produce Ni-based electrocatalysts supported on carbon fiber paper, followed by UV/O3 treatment to oxidize and modify their surface chemistry. The resulting electrodes were composed of nanoclusters formed by a metallic nickel core and ultrathin sheets of a high-valence nickel oxide whose crystalline structure was similar to NiO2, with Ni2+/Ni3+ oxidation states. Upon investigating the effect of the electrochemical conditioning of these high-valence nickel oxide/nickel electrodes, confirming the formation of surface &#946;-Ni(OH)2. This surface layer improved the performance of the electrode by providing active sites for H2O adsorption and dissociation, as indicated by detailed density functional theory (DFT) calculations. The origin of the higher HER activity of &#946;-Ni(OH)2 (001) surface compared to NiO2 (2D), and Ni (111) surfaces is attributed to its unique electronic structure. The high valence nickel oxide/nickel electrodes possessed robust long-term OER and HER stability over 24h. Finally, the potential for modifying the structural composition of these electrodes and their use as bifunctional electrocatalysts for the water-splitting reaction was demonstrated by using the resulting electrodes in an electrolyzer coupled with/without a photovoltaic cell.</description>
      <author>Fabiola Navarro&#8208;Pardo, Gurpreet Singh Selopal, Alma Paola Hernandez-Gonzalez, Ebrahim Ghasemy, Jiabin Liu, Kulbir Kaur Ghuman, Ana C. Tavares, Zhiming Wang, Federico Rosei</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasmon Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction on AU Decorated Ni(Oh)2 Nanostructures: The Role of Alkaline Cations Solvation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4947018</link>
      <description>Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi, Gustavo Sampaio De Oliveira-Filho, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Lucas D. Germano, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402210293

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Susana I. C&#243;rdoba de Torresi, Gustavo Sampaio De Oliveira-Filho, Ana Paula de Lima Batista, Leonardo D. De Angelis, Lucas D. Germano</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4947018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-Induced Strain Effect to Synthesize an Iron-Doped Orthogonal Cobalt Selenide Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02522</link>
      <description>Yunhua Zheng, Huiting Hu, Qian Long, Yao Zhu, Tao Zhang, Dongya Yang, Fengxian Qiu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402220204

                The etching effect has the capability to control atom doping and trigger phase transformation, thereby enhancing the electrocatalytic reaction. Herein, iron-doped cobalt selenide (Fe-CoSe</description>
      <author>Yunhua Zheng, Huiting Hu, Qian Long, Yao Zhu, Tao Zhang, Dongya Yang, Fengxian Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Reconstruction on Coooh Active Species and Oxygen Evolution Performance for Co9s8/Cu2s Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4946707</link>
      <description>Fan He, Jing Wen, Ting Zhang, Yanyan Wang, Dongmei Zeng, Minmin Zou, You Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402225828

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan He, Jing Wen, Ting Zhang, Yanyan Wang, Dongmei Zeng, Minmin Zou, You Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4946707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectonics of Fe-Doped Ni3S2 Arrays on Ni Foam from MOF Precursors for Promoted Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14171445</link>
      <description>Jingchao Zhang, Yingping Bu, Zhuoyan Li, Ting Yang, Na Zhao, Guanghui Wu, Fujing Zhao, Ren&#8208;Chun Zhang, Daojun Zhang, Nanomaterials. 14(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402226563

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a critical half-reaction in electrochemical overall water splitting and metal&#8211;air battery fields; however, the exploitation of the high activity of non-noble metal electrocatalysts to promote the intrinsic slow kinetics of OER is a vital and urgent research topic. Herein, Fe-doped Ni3S2 arrays were derived from MOF precursors and directly grown on nickel foam via the traditional solvothermal way. The arrays integrated into nickel foam can be used as self-supported electrodes directly without any adhesive. Due to the synergistic effect of Fe and Ni elements in the Ni3S2 structure, the optimized Fe2.3%-Ni3S2/NF electrode delivers excellent OER activity in an alkaline medium. The optimized electrode only requires a small overpotential of 233 mV to reach the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and the catalytic activity of the electrode can surpass several related electrodes reported in the literature. In addition, the long-term stability of the Fe2.3%-Ni3S2/NF electrode showed no significant attenuation after 12 h of testing at a current density of 50 mA cm&#8722;2. The introduction of Fe ions could modulate the electrical conductivity and morphology of the Ni3S2 structure and thus provide a high electrochemically active area, fast reaction sites, and charge transfer rate for OER activity.</description>
      <author>Jingchao Zhang, Yingping Bu, Zhuoyan Li, Ting Yang, Na Zhao, Guanghui Wu, Fujing Zhao, Ren&#8208;Chun Zhang, Daojun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14171445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen&#8208;doped FeP on Ti Foil with Ti3O Interlayer for Efficient and Durable Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400649</link>
      <description>Yanqi Yuan, Boan Zhong, Li Wang, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Liyuan Han, Yan&#8208;Ting Sun, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402228720

                The development of electrocatalysts with low cost, high efficiency, and long&#8208;term durability is crucial for advancing green hydrogen production. Transition metal phosphides (TMPs) have been proved to be efficient electrocatalyst, while the improvement in the performance and durability of the TMPs remains a big challenge. Employing atmospheric pressure chemical vapor deposition (APCVD) and phosphorization, FeP/Ti electrodes are fabricated featuring controllable oxygen ingredients (O&#8208;FeP/Ti). This manipulation of oxygen content fine&#8208;tunes the electronic structure of the catalyst, resulting in improved surface reaction kinetics and catalytic activity. The optimized O&#8208;FeP&#8208;400/Ti exhibits outstanding HER activity with overpotentials of 142 and 159 mV at &#8208;10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and 1 M KOH, respectively. Notably, the obtained O&#8208;FeP/Ti cathode also displays remarkable durability of up to 200 h in acidic electrolyte with surface topography remaining intact. For the first time, the low&#8208;valence titanium oxide (Ti3O) interlayer is identified in the composite electrode and ascribed for the superior connection between Ti substrate and the surface O&#8208;FeP catalyst, as supported by experimental results and density functional theory (DFT) analysis. This work has expanded the potential applications of transition metal phosphides (TMPs) as a cost&#8208;effective, highly efficient and durable catalyst for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yanqi Yuan, Boan Zhong, Li Wang, Jing Liu, Liping Zhao, Liyuan Han, Yan&#8208;Ting Sun, Peng Zhang, Lian Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400649</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A pore-confined strategy for synthesizing CoFe nanoparticles in mesoporous biocarbon matrix as advanced bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for zinc&#8211;air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02969-2</link>
      <description>Xiangjun Zheng, Hongyu Gong, Na Zhang, Wenhua Shi, Hongyun Niu, Yuhang Qian, Likun Jiang, Xuecheng Cao, Ruizhi Yang, Changzhou Yuan, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402231731

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangjun Zheng, Hongyu Gong, Na Zhang, Wenhua Shi, Hongyun Niu, Yuhang Qian, Likun Jiang, Xuecheng Cao, Ruizhi Yang, Changzhou Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02969-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PTFE as a Multifunctional Binder for High&#8208;Current&#8208;Density Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408544</link>
      <description>Bohan Deng, He Xian, Peng Du, Wei Zhao, Yuanzheng Long, Zhuting Zhang, Hongyi Liu, Kai Huang, Hui Wu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402232469

                Abstract Binder plays a crucial role in constructing high&#8208;performance electrodes for water electrolysis. While most research has been focused on advancing electrocatalysts, the application of binders in electrode design has yet to be fully explored. Herein, the in situ incorporation of polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) as a multifunctional binder, which increases electrochemical active sites, enhances mass transfer, and strengthens the mechanical and chemical robustness of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrodes, is reported. The NiFe&#8208;LDH@PTFE/NF electrode prepared by co&#8208;deposition of PTFE with NiFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide onto nickel foam demonstrates exceptional long&#8208;term stability with a minimal potential decay rate of 0.034 mV h &#8722;1 at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for 1000 h. The alkaline water electrolyzer utilizing NiFe&#8208;LDH@PTFE/NF requires only 1.584 V at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 and sustains high energy efficiency over 1000 h under industrial operating conditions. This work opens a new path for stabilizing active sites to obtain durable electrodes for OER as well as other electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Bohan Deng, He Xian, Peng Du, Wei Zhao, Yuanzheng Long, Zhuting Zhang, Hongyi Liu, Kai Huang, Hui Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408544</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Surface Chemistry in 2D Layered BiOI by Facile Liquid&#8208;Phase Exfoliation for Enhanced Photoelectrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400275</link>
      <description>Mengjiao Wang, Jaime Gallego, Micaela Pozzati, Teresa Gatti, Small Structures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402233598

                BiOI is a promising photoelectrocatalyst for oxidation reactions. However, the limited photoelectrocatalytic (PEC) activity necessitates the development of new strategies to modify its surface chemistry and thus enhance functional properties. Herein, we present a simple method to increase photocurrent in a BiOI&#8208;based photoanode by exfoliating microspheres of the oxyhalide produced through hydrothermal synthesis. Following exfoliation in isopropanol, the resulting layered BiOI&#8208;based colloid contains a greater variety of species, including Bi 2 O 2 CO 3 , I 3 &#8722; , IO 3 &#8722; , Bi 5+ , and hydroxides, compared to the original BiOI. These additional species do not directly enhance the PEC oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Instead, they are consumed or converted during PEC OER, resulting in more active sites on the photoelectrode and reduced resistance, which ultimately improves the water oxidation performance of the exfoliated BiOI. Over long&#8208;term chronoamperometry, the exfoliated BiOI demonstrates a photocurrent twice as high as that of the BiOI microspheres. Analysis of the species after PEC OER reveals that the combination of IO 3 &#8722; , Bi 5+ , and I 3 &#8722; species on the BiOI is beneficial for charge transfer, thus enhancing the intrinsic PEC properties of the BiOI. This study offers new insights into the role of surface chemistry in determining PEC performance, aiding the optimization of 2D materials&#8208;based photoelectrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Mengjiao Wang, Jaime Gallego, Micaela Pozzati, Teresa Gatti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400275</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Asymmetrical Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se Bonds in Fe2O(SeO3)2 Boosting Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalytic Performance for Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412025</link>
      <description>Huimin Xu, Kaihang Yue, Lijun Song, Hongcheng Zhang, Hongrui Zhu, Zhijie Zhang, Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402244961

                Here Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC catalysts with high performance were fabricated for zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). The experimental results confirmed that the existence of Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se bonds in Fe2O(SeO3)2 crystal phase, and the Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se bonds could obviously enhance ORR and OER catalytic performance of Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC. Density functional theoretical calculations (DFT) confirmed that the Fe2O(SeO3)2 in Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC had a higher d&#8208;band center of Fe atom and a lower p&#8208;orbital coupling degree with its own lattice O atom than Fe2O3, which leads to Fe site of Fe2O(SeO3)2 being more likely to adsorb external oxygen intermediates. The Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se bonds in Fe2O(SeO3)2 results in the modification of coordination environment of Fe atoms and optimizes the adsorption energy of Fe site for oxygen intermediates. Compared with Fe2O3/Fe3C@NC, the Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC showed obvious enhancements of ORR/OER catalytic activities with a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.91 V for ORR in 0.1 M KOH electrolyte and a low overpotential of 345 mV for OER at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in a 1.0 M KOH electrolyte. The peak power density and specific capacity of Fe2O(SeO3)2/Fe3C@NC&#8208;based ZABs are higher than those of Pt/C+RuO2&#8208;ZABs. The above results demonstrate that the asymmetrical Fe&#8208;O&#8208;Se bonds in Fe2O(SeO3)2 plays a key role in improving the bifunctional catalytic activities of ORR/OER for ZABs.</description>
      <author>Huimin Xu, Kaihang Yue, Lijun Song, Hongcheng Zhang, Hongrui Zhu, Zhijie Zhang, Gao&#8208;Ren Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen reduction reaction coupled electro&#8208;oxidation for highly&#8208;efficient and sustainable water treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414481</link>
      <description>Ran Xiao, Hehe Qin, Xiangyun Liu, Chengcheng Chu, Qiuju Li, Hongying Zhao, Shun Mao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402253229

                Electro-oxidation (EO) technology demonstrates significant potential in wastewater treatment. However, the high energy consumption has become a pivotal constraint hindering its large-scale implementation. Herein, we design an EO and 4-electron oxygen reduction reaction coupled system (EO-4eORR) to replace the traditional EO and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) coupled system (EO-HER). The theoretical cathodic potential of the electrolytic reactor is tuned from 0 V (vs. RHE) in HER to 1.23 V (vs. RHE) in 4eORR, which greatly decreases the required operation voltage of the reactor. Moreover, we demonstrate that convection can improve the mass transfer of oxygen and organic pollutants in the reaction system, leading to low cathodic polarization and high pollutant removal rate. Compared with traditional EO-HER system, the energy consumption of the EO-4eORR system under air aeration for 95% total organic carbon (TOC) removal is greatly decreased to 2.61 kWh/kgTOC (only consider the electrolyzer energy consumption), which is superior to previously reported EO-based water treatment systems. The reported results in this study offer a new technical mode for development of highly efficient and sustainable EO-based treatment systems to remove organic pollutants in waste water.</description>
      <author>Ran Xiao, Hehe Qin, Xiangyun Liu, Chengcheng Chu, Qiuju Li, Hongying Zhao, Shun Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growing a Lamination Structure of Graphdiyne/Nickel Sulfide for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31635/ccschem.024.202404426</link>
      <description>Jinze Li, Yurui Xue, Xuchen Zheng, Han Wu, Yang Gao, Yuliang Li, CCS Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402260974

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinze Li, Yurui Xue, Xuchen Zheng, Han Wu, Yang Gao, Yuliang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31635/ccschem.024.202404426</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and Kinetic Analysis of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Tio2 (100) and (101) Surfaces: A Dft Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4947092</link>
      <description>Francisco Manuel Carvalho Pinto Fernandes, Marcio Soares Pereira, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402262044

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Francisco Manuel Carvalho Pinto Fernandes, Marcio Soares Pereira, Neubi Francisco Xavier, Glauco Favilla Bauerfeldt, Clarissa Oliveira da Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4947092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Engineering of Crystalline/Amorphous CoP/FeCoP&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoarrays for Efficient Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401139</link>
      <description>Jinyang Zhang, Yujing Zhang, Jiayi Zhou, Haoran Guo, Limin Qi, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402270534

                Abstract The development of bifunctional, non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) through morphology and electronic engineering is highly attractive for efficient water splitting. Herein, hierarchical nanoarrays consisting of crystalline cobalt phosphide nanorods covered by amorphous Fe&#8208;doped cobalt phosphide nanocuboids (CoP/FeCoP x ) are constructed as bifunctional catalysts for both HER and OER. Experimental results and theoretical calculations reveal that the catalysts exhibit balanced dual&#8208;catalytic properties due to simultaneous introduction of Fe doping and phosphorus vacancies, leading to an optimized electronic structure of the CoP/FeCoP x . Furthermore, the hierarchical nanoarrays made of crystalline/amorphous heterostructures significantly enhance the performance of the electrocatalysts. As a result, the CoP/FeCoP x catalyst demonstrates remarkable performance in both HER and OER, with overpotentials of 74 and 237 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH, respectively, as well as a low cell voltage of 1.53 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for alkaline overall water splitting. This work integrates the morphology engineering involving design of hierarchical crystalline/amorphous nanoarrays and the electronic engineering through Fe doping and phosphorus vacancies for efficient water electrolysis. It may open a new route toward rational design and feasible fabrication of high&#8208;performance, multifunctional, non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts for energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Jinyang Zhang, Yujing Zhang, Jiayi Zhou, Haoran Guo, Limin Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Promotion of Fe in Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalyst on Charge Transfer for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404060</link>
      <description>Weichao Li, Xiaolu Xiong, Jinxiao Gao, Yue Hu, Qun Yang, Dehua Zheng, Jingxuan Hao, Xiao Lin, Linjuan Zhang, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402270578

                Abstract In recent years, catalysts based on transition metal sulfides have garnered extensive attention due to their low cost and excellent electrocatalytic activity in the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction. Here, the preparation of Fe&#8208;doped Ni 3 S 2 via a one&#8208;step hydrothermal approach is reported by utilizing inexpensive transition metals Ni and Fe. In an alkaline medium, Fe&#8211;Ni 3 S 2 exhibits outstanding electrocatalytic activity and stability for the OER, and the current density can reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with an overpotential of 163 mV. In addition, Pt/C||Fe&#8211;Ni 3 S 2 is used as the membrane electrode of the anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer, which is capable of providing a current density of 650 mA cm &#8722;2 at a cell voltage of 2.0 V, outperforming the benchmark Ir/C. The principle is revealed that the doping of Fe enhances the electrocatalytic water decomposition ability of Ni 3 S 2 by in situ Raman and in situ X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure. The results indicate that the doping of Fe decreases the charge density near Ni atoms, which renders Fe&#8211;Ni 3 S 2 more favorable for the adsorption of OH &#8722; and the formation of * OO &#8722; intermediates. This work puts forward an effective strategy to significantly improve both the alkaline OER activity and stability of low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Weichao Li, Xiaolu Xiong, Jinxiao Gao, Yue Hu, Qun Yang, Dehua Zheng, Jingxuan Hao, Xiao Lin, Linjuan Zhang, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of trimetallic metal-organic framework nanoarrays for efficient and stable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.005</link>
      <description>Guohao Na, Yuewen Wu, Zi Mei, Mingpeng Chen, Dequan Li, Huachuan Sun, Yun Chen, Taigang Zhou, Jian-Hong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Jin Zhang, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Qingju Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402274031

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guohao Na, Yuewen Wu, Zi Mei, Mingpeng Chen, Dequan Li, Huachuan Sun, Yun Chen, Taigang Zhou, Jian-Hong Zhao, Yumin Zhang, Jin Zhang, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Sulfonic Acid-Functionalized g-C3N4/BiOI Bifunctional Heterojunction for Enhanced Photocatalytic Removal of Tartrazine and PEC Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12090243</link>
      <description>Sridharan Balu, Harikrishnan Venkatesvaran, Chien-Chih Wang, Joon Ching Juan, Thomas C.&#8208;K. Yang, Inorganics. 12(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402274528

                A Z-scheme heterojunction photo(electro)catalyst was fabricated by coupling sulfonic acid-modified graphitic carbon nitride (SA-g-CN) with bismuth oxyiodide (BiOI). The SA-g-CN component was prepared via wet-impregnation, while BiOI was synthesized through a hydrothermal method. Comprehensive characterization elucidated the structural and morphological properties of the resulting composite. The SA-g-CN/BiOI exhibited exceptional performance in both photocatalytic degradation of tartrazine (TTZ) and photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Notably, 98.26% TTZ removal was achieved within 60 min of irradiation, while an OER onset potential of 0.94 V (vs. Ag/AgCl) and a high photocurrent density of 6.04 mA were recorded under AM 1.5G illumination. Band energy calculations based on Mott&#8211;Schottky measurements confirmed the formation of a Z-scheme heterojunction, which facilitated efficient charge separation and transfer, thereby enhancing catalytic activity. These findings establish the SA-g-CN/BiOI composite as a promising candidate for sustainable energy generation and environmental remediation applications.</description>
      <author>Sridharan Balu, Harikrishnan Venkatesvaran, Chien-Chih Wang, Joon Ching Juan, Thomas C.&#8208;K. Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12090243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Er-Doping Enhances the Oxygen Evolution Performance of Cobalt Oxide in Acidic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03088</link>
      <description>San-Jiang Pan, Hang Li, Sheng Wang, Yang Fu, Shenao Wang, Zhong&#8208;Yang Xie, Li Wei, Hao Li, Nan Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402274848

                No abstract</description>
      <author>San-Jiang Pan, Hang Li, Sheng Wang, Yang Fu, Shenao Wang, Zhong&#8208;Yang Xie, Li Wei, Hao Li, Nan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full&#8208;Spectrum Light&#8208;Harvesting Solar Thermal Electrocatalyst Boosts Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412049</link>
      <description>Dehui Deng, Mengxuan Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402277278

                Enabling high&#8208;efficiency solar thermal conversion (STC) at catalytic active site is critical but challenging for harnessing solar energy to boost catalytic reactions. Herein, we report the direct integration of full&#8208;spectrum STC and high electrocatalytic oxygen evolution activity by fabricating a hierarchical nanocage architecture composed of graphene&#8208;encapsulated CoNi nanoparticle. This catalyst exhibits a near&#8208;complete 98% absorptivity of solar spectrum and a high STC efficiency of 97%, which is superior than previous solar thermal catalytic materials. It delivers a remarkable potential decrease of over 240 mV at various current densities for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution under solar illumination, which is practically unachievable via traditionally heating the system. The high&#8208;efficiency STC is enabled by a synergy between the regulated electronic structure of graphene via CoNi&#8208;carbon interaction and the multiple absorption of lights by the light&#8208;trapping nanocage. Theoretical calculations suggest that high temperature&#8208;induced vibrational free energy gain promotes the potential&#8208;limiting O* to OOH* step, which decreases the overpotential for oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Dehui Deng, Mengxuan Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Full&#8208;Spectrum Light&#8208;Harvesting Solar Thermal Electrocatalyst Boosts Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412049</link>
      <description>Dehui Deng, Mingxia Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402277700

                Enabling high&#8208;efficiency solar thermal conversion (STC) at catalytic active site is critical but challenging for harnessing solar energy to boost catalytic reactions. Herein, we report the direct integration of full&#8208;spectrum STC and high electrocatalytic oxygen evolution activity by fabricating a hierarchical nanocage architecture composed of graphene&#8208;encapsulated CoNi nanoparticle. This catalyst exhibits a near&#8208;complete 98% absorptivity of solar spectrum and a high STC efficiency of 97%, which is superior than previous solar thermal catalytic materials. It delivers a remarkable potential decrease of over 240 mV at various current densities for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution under solar illumination, which is practically unachievable via traditionally heating the system. The high&#8208;efficiency STC is enabled by a synergy between the regulated electronic structure of graphene via CoNi&#8208;carbon interaction and the multiple absorption of lights by the light&#8208;trapping nanocage. Theoretical calculations suggest that high temperature&#8208;induced vibrational free energy gain promotes the potential&#8208;limiting O* to OOH* step, which decreases the overpotential for oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Dehui Deng, Mingxia Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Long&#8208;Range Disordering RuO2 Catalyst for Highly Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411603</link>
      <description>Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Chao Ma, Xuewen Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402286882

                Non&#8208;iridium acid&#8208;stabilized electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial to reducing the cost of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). Here, we report a strategy to modulate the stability of RuO2 by doping boron (B) atoms, leading to the preparation of a RuO2 catalyst with long&#8208;range disorder (LD&#8208;B/RuO2). The structure of long&#8208;range disorder endowed LD&#8208;B/RuO2 with a low overpotential of 175 mV and an ultra&#8208;long stability, which can maintain OER for about 1.6 months at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 current density in 0.5 M H2SO4 with almost invariable performance. More importantly, a PEM electrolyzer using LD&#8208;B/RuO2 as the anode demonstrated excellent performance, reaching 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 at 1.63 V with durability exceeding 300 h at 250 mA cm&#8722;2 current density. The introduction of B atoms induced the formation of a long&#8208;range disordered structure and symmetry&#8208;breaking B&#8208;Ru&#8208;O motifs, which enabled the catalyst structure to a certain toughness while simultaneously inducing the redistribution of electrons on the active center Ru, which jointly promoted and guaranteed the activity and long&#8208;term stability of LD&#8208;B/RuO2. This study provides a strategy to prepare long&#8208;range disordered RuO2 acidic OER catalysts with high stability using B&#8208;doping to perturb crystallinity, which opens potential possibilities for non&#8208;iridium&#8208;based PEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Chao Ma, Xuewen Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Long&#8208;Range Disordering RuO2 Catalyst for Highly Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411603</link>
      <description>Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Manxiao Cheng, Xuewen Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402287090

                Non&#8208;iridium acid&#8208;stabilized electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial to reducing the cost of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). Here, we report a strategy to modulate the stability of RuO2 by doping boron (B) atoms, leading to the preparation of a RuO2 catalyst with long&#8208;range disorder (LD&#8208;B/RuO2). The structure of long&#8208;range disorder endowed LD&#8208;B/RuO2 with a low overpotential of 175 mV and an ultra&#8208;long stability, which can maintain OER for about 1.6 months at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 current density in 0.5 M H2SO4 with almost invariable performance. More importantly, a PEM electrolyzer using LD&#8208;B/RuO2 as the anode demonstrated excellent performance, reaching 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 at 1.63 V with durability exceeding 300 h at 250 mA cm&#8722;2 current density. The introduction of B atoms induced the formation of a long&#8208;range disordered structure and symmetry&#8208;breaking B&#8208;Ru&#8208;O motifs, which enabled the catalyst structure to a certain toughness while simultaneously inducing the redistribution of electrons on the active center Ru, which jointly promoted and guaranteed the activity and long&#8208;term stability of LD&#8208;B/RuO2. This study provides a strategy to prepare long&#8208;range disordered RuO2 acidic OER catalysts with high stability using B&#8208;doping to perturb crystallinity, which opens potential possibilities for non&#8208;iridium&#8208;based PEMWE applications.</description>
      <author>Guanzhen Chen, Ruihu Lu, Manxiao Cheng, Xuewen Zhang, Ziyun Wang, Yu Xiong, Yunhu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial engineering of the nickel/zinc oxides p-n heterojunction for promoting photo-assisted oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118622</link>
      <description>Shengjie Wei, Haiyang Xu, Dingcheng Sun, Shan Lin, Xu Ji, Yue Yang, Le Zhang, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402290644

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengjie Wei, Haiyang Xu, Dingcheng Sun, Shan Lin, Xu Ji, Yue Yang, Le Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanadium-Doped FeO/NiS Nanosheet Arrays: Synergistic Heterometal Doping and Heterostructure Design for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176386</link>
      <description>Jing Mei, Xiaohong Cheng, Qi Wu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402294028

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Mei, Xiaohong Cheng, Qi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical and structural properties of binder-free iron-based bifunctional catalyst for aqueous Zinc-Oxygen batteries.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oceram.2024.100667</link>
      <description>Jorge Gonz&#225;lez Morales, M. Aparicio, Nataly Carolina Rosero&#8208;Navarro, Franco M. Zanotto, Alejandro A. Franco, Jadra Mosa, Open Ceramics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402298041

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jorge Gonz&#225;lez Morales, M. Aparicio, Nataly Carolina Rosero&#8208;Navarro, Franco M. Zanotto, Alejandro A. Franco, Jadra Mosa</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oceram.2024.100667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of the rhenium substitution on the oxygen evolution reaction of spinel CoFe2O4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4923019</link>
      <description>Xiawa Wang, Xiaoqi Zhou, Yuruo Zheng, Ghulam Hussain, Changcheng Zheng, Man Zhang, Shuyi Li, Batool Shanta, Qiulin Yin, Shaofang Xie, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402301950

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiawa Wang, Xiaoqi Zhou, Yuruo Zheng, Ghulam Hussain, Changcheng Zheng, Man Zhang, Shuyi Li, Batool Shanta, Qiulin Yin, Shaofang Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4923019</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe layered-double-hydroxide nanosheet arrays grown in situ on Ni foam for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.042</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Dai, Yuxing Zhang, Haosen Song, Lu Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 87(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402302184

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Dai, Yuxing Zhang, Haosen Song, Lu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel N-Doped Biomass Carbon Spheres Loaded with In-Situ Grown Feco Layered Double Hydroxide for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4948756</link>
      <description>Chong Cai, Ningzhao Shang, Danhua Sun, Li Wang, Yufan Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402307416

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chong Cai, Ningzhao Shang, Danhua Sun, Li Wang, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4948756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Determining materials for energy conversion across scales: The alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.608</link>
      <description>Philipp Gerschel, Steven Angel, Mohaned Hammad, Andr&#233; Olean&#8208;Oliveira, Bla&#382; Toplak, Vimanshu Chanda, Ricardo Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Hincapi&#233;, Sebastian A. Sanden, Ali Raza Khan, Da Xing, Amin Said Amin, Hartmut Wiggers, Harry E. Hoster, Viktor &#268;oli&#263;, Alfred Ludwig, Christof Schulz, Ulf&#8208;Peter Apfel, Doris Segets, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402309036

                Abstract Despite considerable efforts to develop electrolyzers for energy conversion, progress has been hindered during the implementation stage by different catalyst development requirements in academic and industrial research. Herein, a coherent workflow for the efficient transition of electrocatalysts from basic research to application readiness for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction is proposed. To demonstrate this research approach, La 0.8 Sr 0.2 CoO 3 is selected as a catalyst, and its electrocatalytic performance is compared with that of the benchmark material NiFe 2 O 4 . The La 0.8 Sr 0.2 CoO 3 catalyst with the desired dispersity is successfully synthesized by scalable spray&#8208;flame synthesis. Subsequently, inks are formulated using different binders (Nafion&#174;, Naf; Sustainion&#174;, Sus), and nickel substrates are spray coated, ensuring a homogeneous catalyst distribution. Extensive electrochemical evaluations, including several scale&#8208;bridging techniques, highlight the efficiency of the La 0.8 Sr 0.2 CoO 3 catalyst. Experiments using the scanning droplet cell (SDC) indicate good lateral homogeneity for La 0.8 Sr 0.2 CoO 3 electrodes and NiFe 2 O 4 &#8208;Sus, while the NiFe 2 O 4 &#8208;Naf film suffers from delamination. Among the various half&#8208;cell techniques, SDC proves to be a valuable tool to quickly check whether a catalyst layer is suitable for full&#8208;cell&#8208;level testing and will be used for the fast&#8208;tracking of catalysts in the future. Complementary compression and flow cell experiments provide valuable information on the electrodes' behavior upon exposure to chemical and mechanical stress. Finally, parameters and conditions simulating industrial settings are applied using a zero&#8208;gap cell. Findings from various research fields across different scales obtained based on the developed coherent workflow contribute to a better understanding of the electrocatalytic system at the early stages of development and provide important insights for the evaluation of novel materials that are to be used in large&#8208;scale industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Philipp Gerschel, Steven Angel, Mohaned Hammad, Andr&#233; Olean&#8208;Oliveira, Bla&#382; Toplak, Vimanshu Chanda, Ricardo Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Hincapi&#233;, Sebastian A. Sanden, Ali Raza Khan, Da Xing, Amin Said Amin, Hartmut Wiggers, Harry E. Hoster, Viktor &#268;oli&#263;, Alfred Ludwig, Christof Schulz, Ulf&#8208;Peter Apfel, Doris Segets</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rationalizing the catalytic surface area of oxygen vacancy&#8208;enriched layered perovskite LaSrCrO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanowires on oxygen electrocatalyst for enhanced performance of Li&#8211;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.550</link>
      <description>Myeong&#8208;Chang Sung, Chan Ho Kim, Byoungjoon Hwang, Dong&#8208;Wan Kim, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402309389

                Abstract Efficient electrocatalysis at the cathode is crucial to addressing the limited stability and low rate capability of Li&#8722;O 2 batteries. This study examines the kinetic behavior of Li&#8722;O 2 batteries utilizing layered perovskite LaSrCrO 4 nanowires (NWs) composed of lower oxidation states. Layered perovskite LaSrCrO 4 NWs exhibited improved rate capability over a wide range of current densities and longer cycle life in Li&#8722;O 2 batteries than V&#8208;based layered perovskite (LaSrVO 4 ) and simple perovskite (La 0.8 Sr 0.2 CrO 3 ) NWs. X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and electrochemical surface area analyses showed that the observed performance variations primarily stemmed from active sites such as oxygen vacancies. In situ Raman analysis showed that these active sites significantly modulate the kinetics of oxygen reduction and evolution, which are related to LiO 2 intermediate adsorption. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy showed that the active sites in layered perovskite LaSrCrO 4 NWs contributed to their high charge transfer capability and reduced polarization. This study presents an appealing method for the precise fabrication and analysis of Cr&#8208;based layered perovskites, aimed at achieving highly efficient and stable bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Myeong&#8208;Chang Sung, Chan Ho Kim, Byoungjoon Hwang, Dong&#8208;Wan Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Nanocrystalline/Amorphous Interfaces to Enhance Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance for FeNi&#8208;Based Alloy Fibers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413088</link>
      <description>B. Li, Sida Jiang, Qiang Fu, Ran Wang, Weizhi Xu, Junxiang Chen, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Ping Xu, Xianjie Wang, Jianhua Li, Hongbo Fan, Juntao Huo, Jianfei Sun, Zhiliang Ning, Bo Song, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402309728

                Abstract Efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts play a pivotal role in water electrolysis, notably for industrial high current densities (&gt;1000 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Crystalline/amorphous heterostructure interfaces have proven to be advantageous for enhancing the OER activities of electrocatalytic materials. However, the constructing and tailoring for crystalline/amorphous interfaces still remain a great challenge due to the destruction of active substrates by intricate post&#8208;treatment. Here, a strategy to tailor nanocrystalline/amorphous (N/A) interface and optimize the electrocatalytic performance of as&#8208;cast N/A alloys by adjusting the size of nanocrystals is proposed. The N/A alloy fibers obtained based on this strategy exhibit superior OER performance with an overpotential of 227 mV (@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), maintaining stability for over 1000, 600, and 240 h under high current densities of 500, 1000, and 1800 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. Theoretical calculations and material characterizations reveal that N/A interfaces, facilitated by appropriately sized nanocrystals possessing a loose atomic arrangement, favorable surface electronic structure, advantageous local coordination, and optimal O&#8208;contained intermediate adsorption, can yield abundant active sites without compromising stability. This study not only provides a deeper understanding of the tailoring mechanism of N/A interfaces but also offers a new design perspective for the development of cost&#8208;effective, industrial&#8208;grade electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>B. Li, Sida Jiang, Qiang Fu, Ran Wang, Weizhi Xu, Junxiang Chen, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Ping Xu, Xianjie Wang, Jianhua Li, Hongbo Fan, Juntao Huo, Jianfei Sun, Zhiliang Ning, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating coordination environment in metal-organic Framework@Cuprous oxide Core-Shell catalyst for Promoting electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.040</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Zijian Wang, Jin Ma, Jian Chen, Hong Li, Weiju Hao, Qingyuan Bi, Shuning Xiao, Jinchen Fan, Ming Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402314445

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Zijian Wang, Jin Ma, Jian Chen, Hong Li, Weiju Hao, Qingyuan Bi, Shuning Xiao, Jinchen Fan, Ming Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni and Co-based bifunctional electrocatalysts supported on TiO@C for oxygen evolution and reduction reactions.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145030</link>
      <description>Diana M. Fernandes, V&#237;ctor K. Abdelkader&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Ali Fayad, Conchi O. Ania, Fabiano R. Praxedes, Silvania Lanfredi, Enrique Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Castell&#243;n, Elena Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Aguado, Juan Carlos Hern&#225;ndez&#8208;Garrido, Juan J. Quintana-Gonz&#225;lez, Po S. Poon, Juan Matos, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402315245

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Diana M. Fernandes, V&#237;ctor K. Abdelkader&#8208;Fern&#225;ndez, Ali Fayad, Conchi O. Ania, Fabiano R. Praxedes, Silvania Lanfredi, Enrique Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Castell&#243;n, Elena Rodr&#237;guez&#8208;Aguado, Juan Carlos Hern&#225;ndez&#8208;Garrido, Juan J. Quintana-Gonz&#225;lez, Po S. Poon, Juan Matos</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrocatalytic bromine evolution and extraction from wastewater by oxygen vacancy enriched Ti/Ov-Co3O4-NRs electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2024.118088</link>
      <description>Guang&#8208;Zhong Yin, Renping Li, Wei Li, Zhifeng Gao, Kajia Wei, Hongwei Zhu, Liankai Gu, Yun Jiang, Weiqing Han, Desalination. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402316375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guang&#8208;Zhong Yin, Renping Li, Wei Li, Zhifeng Gao, Kajia Wei, Hongwei Zhu, Liankai Gu, Yun Jiang, Weiqing Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.desal.2024.118088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Progress on the Application of One-Step Fabrication Techniques for Iridium-Based Thin Films in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14091147</link>
      <description>Wenting Li, Junyu Zhu, Hongzhong Cai, Zhongqiu Tong, Xian Wang, Yan Wei, Xingqiang Wang, Changyi Hu, Xingdong Zhao, Xuxiang Zhang, Coatings. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402318295

                Electrochemical water splitting, a sustainable method for hydrogen production, faces the challenge of slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics. Iridium oxide (IrO2) is widely regarded as the most effective catalyst for OER due to its excellent properties. Compared to nanoparticles, IrO2 thin films exhibit significant advantages in OER, including a uniform and stable catalytic interface and excellent mechanical strength. This paper reviews recent advancements in one-step deposition techniques for the preparation of IrO2 thin films and their application in OER. Additionally, it analyzes the advantages and disadvantages of various methods and the latest research achievements, and briefly outlines the future trends and applications.</description>
      <author>Wenting Li, Junyu Zhu, Hongzhong Cai, Zhongqiu Tong, Xian Wang, Yan Wei, Xingqiang Wang, Changyi Hu, Xingdong Zhao, Xuxiang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14091147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon&#8208; and Nitrogen&#8208;Based Complexes as Photocatalysts for Prebiotic and Oxygen Chemistry during Earth Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413768</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, Li Wang, Sibo Wang, Yuanxing Fang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402319090

                Sunlight has long served as primary energy source on our planet, shaping the behavior of living organisms. Extensive research has been dedicated to unraveling the evolutionary pathways involved. When the formation of Earth atmosphere, it primarily consisted of small gas molecules, which are considered crucial for the emergence of life. Recent demonstrations have shown that these molecules can also be transformed into semiconductors, with the potential to harness solar energy and catalyze chemical reactions as photocatalysts. Building upon this research, this minireview focuses on the potential revolutionary impact of photocatalysis on Earth. Initially, it examines key reactions, such as the formation of prebiotic molecules and the oxygen evolution reaction via water oxidation. Additionally, various C&#8208;N complexes in photocatalysts are explored, showcasing their roles in catalyzing chemical reactions. The conclusion and outlook provide a potential pathway for the evolution of Earth, shedding light on the significance of metal&#8208;free photocatalysts in development of Earth.</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, Li Wang, Sibo Wang, Yuanxing Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413768</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuO2/FeCo2O4 as an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135245</link>
      <description>Jiale Li, Weigang Gu, Dajun Wu, Xuekun Hong, Tao Shi, Bin Qian, Shaohui Xu, Paul K. Chu, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402326697

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiale Li, Weigang Gu, Dajun Wu, Xuekun Hong, Tao Shi, Bin Qian, Shaohui Xu, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the influence of deposited layers on Ti/RuO2 anodes to define the electroactivity of oxygen evolution and active chlorine reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118645</link>
      <description>Juan M. Sterling-Montealegre, Luis Norberto Ben&#237;tez, Ricardo E. Palma&#8208;Goyes, Rosa Mar&#237;a Luna-S&#225;nchez, Franklin Ferraro, Roberto Luis Palomino Resendiz, Selene Montserrat Garc&#237;a-Solares, Jorge Vazquez&#8208;Arenas, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402327121

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juan M. Sterling-Montealegre, Luis Norberto Ben&#237;tez, Ricardo E. Palma&#8208;Goyes, Rosa Mar&#237;a Luna-S&#225;nchez, Franklin Ferraro, Roberto Luis Palomino Resendiz, Selene Montserrat Garc&#237;a-Solares, Jorge Vazquez&#8208;Arenas</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe-spinel oxides with nitrogen-doped carbon quantum dots for enhanced oxygen evolution activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118632</link>
      <description>Xinping Yang, Q. T. Tao, Yan Zhang, Jingwen Liu, Jiwen Si, Weikun Ning, Yanbin Sun, Fagui Qiu, Wenqing Li, Shiding Miao, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402328148

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinping Yang, Q. T. Tao, Yan Zhang, Jingwen Liu, Jiwen Si, Weikun Ning, Yanbin Sun, Fagui Qiu, Wenqing Li, Shiding Miao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial regulation of CdIn2S4 and oxygen evolution cocatalyst for rapid hole extraction for photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.481</link>
      <description>Jiangchuan Liu, Yue Zhang, Shengkang Min, Yurong Ren, Changhai Liu, Zhidong Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 87(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402332153

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiangchuan Liu, Yue Zhang, Shengkang Min, Yurong Ren, Changhai Liu, Zhidong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Synthesis of CuO/MnAl2O4 nanocomposite as electrocatalysts for robust oxygen evolution reaction&#8221; [J. Phys. Chem. Solids Volume 193, October 2024, 112121]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112295</link>
      <description>Munaza sadiq, B.M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Khalid I. Hussein, Md Rezaul Karim, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402333018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munaza sadiq, B.M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Khalid I. Hussein, Md Rezaul Karim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Bimetallic Niru@Ti3c2tx Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution: The Impact of Mxene Content on Ru Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4949211</link>
      <description>Merve Buldu&#8208;Akturk, Thorsten Schultz, N. L. Sharma, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402337294

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Merve Buldu&#8208;Akturk, Thorsten Schultz, N. L. Sharma, Norbert Koch, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4949211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the configuration entropy of layered hydroxides toward efficient oxygen evolution reaction for anion exchange membrane electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.08.008</link>
      <description>Da Liu, Peifang Guo, Xiaoxiao Yan, Yufei He, Renbing Wu, Materials Today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402339642

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Da Liu, Peifang Guo, Xiaoxiao Yan, Yufei He, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.08.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thinly-walled NiFe2O4 nanotubes derived from Ni, Fe, N-codoped carbon nanofibers toward oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solidstatesciences.2024.107691</link>
      <description>Zhan Tian, He Wang, Guoqiang Li, Hongrui Jia, Guoxin Zhang, Solid State Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402341259

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhan Tian, He Wang, Guoqiang Li, Hongrui Jia, Guoxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solidstatesciences.2024.107691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of nickel-manganese based bimetallic hydroxide nanosheets for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2838/1/012002</link>
      <description>Shilin Li, Yuran Li, Yue Bian, Han Guo, Yifan Guo, You Long, Zhi Hong Lu, Guangxin Wang, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2838(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402357938

                Abstract This paper uses a common one-step hydrothermal method to prepare NiMn-LDH/NF (Layered Double Hydroxide, LDH) oxygen evolution catalyst with outstanding performance. The NiMn-LDH grows into a nanosheet array structure on nickel foam (NF) and it has a big surface area and exceptional ion transport function that could accelerate the diffusion rate of electrocatalytic products. It attempted to modulate the molar proportion of Ni and Mn to explore the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of the NiMn-LDH/NF catalysts. It was found that when Ni:Mn=4:1 (molar ratio, hereinafter), the nanosheets grew more densely and had better OER performance and stability. The electrochemical test results show that the Ni 4 Mn-LDH/NF catalyst exhibits an overvoltage of 341 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and the Tafel slope is only 98.99 mV dec &#8722;1 .</description>
      <author>Shilin Li, Yuran Li, Yue Bian, Han Guo, Yifan Guo, You Long, Zhi Hong Lu, Guangxin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2838/1/012002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Salt-Flower-Shaped Fep-Cop for Highly Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4950897</link>
      <description>Leilei Li, Xue Jia, Xing-Liang Yin, Ze&#8208;Feng Xu, Chuan-Wu Chen, Ya&#8208;Nan Jing, D. Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402360029

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Leilei Li, Xue Jia, Xing-Liang Yin, Ze&#8208;Feng Xu, Chuan-Wu Chen, Ya&#8208;Nan Jing, D. Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4950897</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advantages on mass transfer structure construction in transition metal&#8208;based cost&#8208;effective catalyst toward alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401166</link>
      <description>Xuehua Zhang, Li Zhang, Songlei Lv, Guodong Xu, Jiawei Shi, Jiehao Li, Weiwei Cai, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402373926

                The electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can be combined with various reactions to fabricate electrochemical energy conversion and storage devices while the slow kinetics and poor mass transfer capability at high current densities were the key constraints to its large&#8208;scale application. Therefore, this review primarily focuses on design and optimization of mass transfer structures of TM&#8208;metal&#8208;based OER catalysts. Nanostructuring, porous design, and the creation of hierarchical architectures have been applied during catalyst synthesis to enhance the surface area and accessibility, thereby improving mass transfer and catalytic OER efficiency. Strategies including doping, substrate invitation, soft/hard templating has been utilized to accelerate mass transfer as well as the ion/electron conduction efficiency for the overall improvement of OER performance of the catalysts. These developments underline the critical role of advanced material design in achieving high&#8208;performance OER catalysts and highlight the potential of TM&#8208;based materials in cost&#8208;effective and scalable applications.</description>
      <author>Xuehua Zhang, Li Zhang, Songlei Lv, Guodong Xu, Jiawei Shi, Jiehao Li, Weiwei Cai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering the Sandwich&#8208;Type Porphyrinic MOF&#8208;Ruthenium&#8211;Nickel Foam Electrode for Boosting Overall Water Splitting via Self&#8208;Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401082</link>
      <description>Tingting Liu, Xinhui Yu, Yuanyuan Wu, Xianyu Chu, Wei Jiang, Bo Liu, Chunbo Liu, Guangbo Che, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402376525

                Abstract The rational construction of a hierarchical noble metal&#8211;metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) structure is anticipated to yield enduring and highly efficient performance in alkaline electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, a sandwich construction strategy is employed to enhance the stability, wherein active RutheniRu (Ru) nanosheets are incorporated onto nickel foam (NF) and subsequently covered with porphyrinic MOFs (PMOFs). In addition, activated PMOF&#8208;NiOOH&#8208;Ru 20 /NF&#8208;C/A electrodes are obtained by electrochemical self&#8208;reconstruction as cathode and anode, respectively. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrated that the resulting PMOF&#8208;NiOOH&#8208;Ru heterointerface effectively facilitated electron transfer, enhanced H 2 O adsorption capacity, and optimized &#916; G values for * H and * O to * OOH. Consequently, PMOF&#8208;NiOOH&#8208;Ru 20 /NF&#8208;C/A exhibited low overpotentials for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), accompanied by minimal Ru leakage. Furthermore, stable overall water splitting can be achieved with a low voltage of 1.456 V@10 mA cm &#8722;2 for over 120 h. Even when operated in simulated seawater, the prepared electrodes demonstrated similar activity and stability. This study contributes to a deeper understanding of the regulation mechanism for the performance and stability of active sites in the electrocatalytic self&#8208;reconstruction process.</description>
      <author>Tingting Liu, Xinhui Yu, Yuanyuan Wu, Xianyu Chu, Wei Jiang, Bo Liu, Chunbo Liu, Guangbo Che</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Role of Electrocatalysts Activation for Iron&#8208;Doped Ni Oxyhydroxide in Enhancing the Catalytic Performance of Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12827</link>
      <description>Jiyoung Kim, JeongEun Yoo, Kiyoung Lee, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377490

                Water electrolysis using renewable electricity is a promising strategy for high&#8208;purity hydrogen production. To realize the practical application of water electrolysis, an electrocatalyst with high redox properties and low cost is essential for enhancing the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction. Herein, we fabricated Fe&#8208;doped nickel oxalate (Fe&#8208;NiC 2 O 4 ) directly grown on nickel (Ni) foam as an efficient electrocatalyst for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction using a facile one&#8208;step hydrothermal method. Fe&#8208;NiC 2 O 4 served as a precursor for obtaining highly active Fe&#8208;doped Ni oxyhydroxide (Fe&#8208;NiOOH) via in situ electrochemical oxidation. Consequently, 0.75Fe&#8208;NiOOH was demonstrated to be the optimal electrocatalyst, exhibiting outstanding oxygen evolution reaction activity with a low overpotential of 220 mV at a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 20.5 mV dec &#8722;1 . Furthermore, Fe&#8208;NiOOH maintained its oxygen evolution reaction activity without performance decay during long&#8208;term electrochemical measurements, owing to the phase transformation from nickel oxyhydroxide (NiOOH) to &#947;&#8208;NiOOH (gamma nickel oxyhydroxide). These performances significantly surpass those of recently reported transition&#8208;metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiyoung Kim, JeongEun Yoo, Kiyoung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Modification Effect of Se&#8208;doped Porous Carbon for Hydrogen Evolution Coupled Selective Electrooxidation of Ethylene Glycol to Value&#8208;added Glycolic Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404540</link>
      <description>Daehee Jang, Minseon Park, Junbeom Maeng, Jungseub Ha, Si&#8208;Young Choi, Nayeon Kim, Min Ho Seo, Won Bae Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377581

                Abstract The ethylene glycol oxidation reaction (EGOR) has attracted attention because ethylene glycol (EG), which exhibits large&#8208;scale production and a low market price, can be reformed into valuable glycolic acid (GCA) with the cogeneration of high&#8208;purity hydrogen gas during the reaction. In this study, a noble catalyst material of Pt nanoparticles supported on Se&#8208;doped porous carbon (Pt/SePC) is prepared and investigated for the selective electrochemical oxidation of EG to GCA. Pt/SePC achieved a maximum EG conversion of 94.6% and GCA selectivity of 84.4% and maintained this high performance with negligible degradation during durability tests. Furthermore, the EGOR required lower overpotential rather than the oxygen evolution reaction, thus the EGOR coupled with the hydrogen evolution reaction can reduce the cell overpotential to 0.60 V, which is much lower than that of water electrolysis (1.58 V). The effect of Se doping is investigated through experimental analyses and density functional theory (DFT) calculations, and they shows that Se modified the binding energy of Pt nanoparticles and the adsorption energy of reactants by lattice deformation and charge density modification. This study provides scientific insights and strategies for electrocatalyst design for the selective oxidation of polyols to value&#8208;added chemicals via the cogeneration of hydrogen gas.</description>
      <author>Daehee Jang, Minseon Park, Junbeom Maeng, Jungseub Ha, Si&#8208;Young Choi, Nayeon Kim, Min Ho Seo, Won Bae Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetically Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Mild Alkaline Electrolytes by Building Catalysts on Magnetic Frame</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405946</link>
      <description>Ming Xie, Haotian Wang, Xianjun Li, Guojun Han, Yongqiang Yang, Xinyue Shi, Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Guo&#8208;Xing Miao, Meng&#8208;Hao Yang, Jing Fu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377734

                Abstract Under large current densities, the excessive hydroxide ion (OH) consumption hampers alkaline water splitting involving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). High OH concentration (&#8776;30 wt.%) is often used to enhance the catalytic activity of OER, but it also leads to higher corrosion in practical systems. To achieve higher catalytic activity in low OH concentration, catalysts on magnetic frame (CMF) are built to utilize the local magnetic convection induced from the host frame's magnetic field distributions. This way, a higher reaction rate can be achieved in relatively lower OH concentrations. A CMF model system with catalytically active CoFeO x nanograins grown on the magnetic Ni foam is demonstrated. The OER current of CoFeO x @NF receives &#8776;90% enhancement under 400 mT (900 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.65 V) compared to that in zero field, and exhibits remarkable durability over 120 h. As a demonstration, the water&#8208;splitting performance sees a maximum 45% magnetic enhancement under 400 mT in 1 m KOH (700 mA cm &#8722;2 at 2.4 V), equivalent to the concentration enhancement of the same electrode in a more corrosive 2 m KOH electrolyte. Therefore, the catalyst&#8208;on&#8208;magnetic&#8208;frame strategy can make efficient use of the catalysts and achieve higher catalytic activity in low OH concentration by harvesting local magnetic convection.</description>
      <author>Ming Xie, Haotian Wang, Xianjun Li, Guojun Han, Yongqiang Yang, Xinyue Shi, Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Guo&#8208;Xing Miao, Meng&#8208;Hao Yang, Jing Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis and Characterization of Copper Phosphide Nanoparticles as Efficient Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-024-09514-4</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zeeshan Shakir, Samina Akbar, Imran Raza, Muhammad Awais, Saima Rehman, Arabian Journal for Science and Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402379412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zeeshan Shakir, Samina Akbar, Imran Raza, Muhammad Awais, Saima Rehman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s13369-024-09514-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface&#8208;Engineered Ni2P: An Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400684</link>
      <description>C. Retna Raj, Mopidevi Manikanta Kumar, Rahul Singh, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402379719

                The surface engineering of electrocatalysts is one of the promising strategies to increase the intrinsic activity of electrocatalysts. It generates anion/cation vacancy defects and increases the electrochemically active surface area. We describe the surface engineering of Ni2P to favorably tune the bifunctional oxygen electrocatalytic activity and the development of a rechargeable zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB). Ni2P encapsulated with N and P&#8208;dual doped carbon (Ni2P@NPC) is synthesized using a single&#8208;source precursor complex tris&#8208;(2,2'&#8208;bipyridine)nickel(II) bis(hexafluorophosphate). The surface engineering of the as&#8208;synthesized Ni2P@NPC is achieved by the controlled acid treatment at room temperature. The surface engineering removes carbon debris and opens the pores, exfoliates the encapsulating carbon layer, increases the P&#8208;vacancy in the crystal lattice, and boosts the electrochemically active surface area. The surface&#8208;engineered catalyst exhibits enhanced bifunctional activity towards oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The electrocatalytically active sites of engineered catalysts are highly accessible for facilitated electron transfer kinetics. P&#8208;vacancy favors the facile formation of defect&#8208;rich OER active metal oxyhydroxide species. The rechargeable ZAB based on the engineered catalyst delivers a specific capacity of 770.25 mA h gZn&#8208;1, energy density of 692 Wh kgZn&#8208;1, and excellent charge&#8208;discharge cycling performance with negligible voltaic efficiency loss (0.6 %) after 100 h.</description>
      <author>C. Retna Raj, Mopidevi Manikanta Kumar, Rahul Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400684</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chiral helically grooved gold nanoarrows for concurrently enhancing oxygen and hydrogen evolution from electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2136-1</link>
      <description>Lufei Huang, Tao Wang, Ying Li, Ping Wang, Rui Tian, Baowen Zhou, Lin Yao, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402381472

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lufei Huang, Tao Wang, Ying Li, Ping Wang, Rui Tian, Baowen Zhou, Lin Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2136-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ESR oxymetry: measurement of photosynthetic oxygen evolution by spin-probe technique</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00352-0</link>
      <description>Kazimierz Strza&#322;ka, Tadeusz Sama, James S. Hyde, No host. 12(1-2)] 1986. https://openalex.org/W4402200352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kazimierz Strza&#322;ka, Tadeusz Sama, James S. Hyde</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 1986 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00352-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuO/Co3O4 heterojunctions for catalytic nitroarenes reduction and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113106</link>
      <description>K. Arathi, K.L. Nagashree, Madhuri P. Rao, Kalyan Raj, P. Shivakumar, D. H. Nagaraju, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402280371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. Arathi, K.L. Nagashree, Madhuri P. Rao, Kalyan Raj, P. Shivakumar, D. H. Nagaraju</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Nanostructures of Iron Phthalocyanine Nanowires Coated on Nickel Foam as Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29174272</link>
      <description>Xianying Meng, Peng Yu, Mingyi Zhang, Molecules. 29(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402374762

                In this paper, iron phthalocyanine nanowires on a nickel foam (FePc@NF) composite catalyst were prepared by a facile solvothermal approach. The catalyst showed good electrochemical oxygen evolution performance. In 1.0 M KOH electrolyte, 289 mV low overpotential and 49.9 mV dec&#8722;1 Tafel slope were seen at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The excellent electrochemical performance comes from the homogeneous dispersion of phthalocyanine nanostructures on the surface of the nickel foam, which avoids the common agglomeration problem of such catalysts and provides a large number of active sites for the OER reaction, thus improving the catalytic performance of the system.</description>
      <author>Xianying Meng, Peng Yu, Mingyi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29174272</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core-shell like rGO coated Co9S8 hollow dodecahedron for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112318</link>
      <description>Hongjuan Hao, Hongbin Pu, Dingze Lu, Min Zhou, Boqun Zhang, Xin Zhang, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402327345

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongjuan Hao, Hongbin Pu, Dingze Lu, Min Zhou, Boqun Zhang, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Reconstruction of Nickel Iron Hydrogen Cyanamide with in-situ Produced Proton Acceptor for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124561</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ajmal, Shishi Zhang, Xiaolei Guo, Xiaokang Liu, Chengxiang Shi, Ruijie Gao, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Lun Pan, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402308153

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ajmal, Shishi Zhang, Xiaolei Guo, Xiaokang Liu, Chengxiang Shi, Ruijie Gao, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Lun Pan, Xiangwen Zhang, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microscopic Insight into the Polarization-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Reaction on the Surface of Intrinsic Ferroelectric Semiconductor &#946;-CuGaO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02073</link>
      <description>Donghao Lu, Lanlan Xu, Jiarong Dai, Xuemeng Guo, Qiang Shi, Xiaojuan Liu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402271746

                Ferroelectric semiconductors hold great promise in the field of photocatalysis due to their spontaneous polarization that can suppress the recombination of photogenerated charges, but the mechanism of the effect of ferroelectric polarization and the intensity of polarization on surface catalytic reactions have never been approached. Here, we have comparatively investigated the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic process on surfaces in polarized and unpolarized orientations of the intrinsic ferroelectric semiconductor &#946;-CuGaO</description>
      <author>Donghao Lu, Lanlan Xu, Jiarong Dai, Xuemeng Guo, Qiang Shi, Xiaojuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-templated fabrication of P-doped CoMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; hollow nanocages for the efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03347g</link>
      <description>Wenxiang Jia, Qian Lu, Tian Tian, Guoxiang Pan, Rui Tan, Bin He, Jiang Liu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402242814

                Finding reservoir-rich and e&#64259;cient electrocatalysts for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for further sustainable energy development. Despite the advantages of high earth abundance, easy availability, and tunable composition,...</description>
      <author>Wenxiang Jia, Qian Lu, Tian Tian, Guoxiang Pan, Rui Tan, Bin He, Jiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03347g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni Surface &amp;amp; Polyacryloyl Hydrazide Mediated Growth of Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@NiCu Alloy Nanocuboids for Effective Methanol Oxidation and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400372</link>
      <description>Sunil Semwal, Aiswarya Samal, Saroj K. Nayak, Rajashri Urkude, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, Umaprasana Ojha, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402281514

                Abstract Strategies to control the size, shape, and lattice arrangement, introduce doping agents, and induce heterostructuring in electrocatalysts are strongly desirable to tailor their activities. Herewith, a one&#8208;pot strategy utilizing polyacryloyl hydrazide (PAHz) as the composition directing agent and metallic Ni surface as the shape directing agent is employed to grow Co 3 O 4 doped NiCu alloy nanocuboids on Ni foam (NF) under hydrothermal conditions for electrocatalytic H 2 production. The resulting bi&#8208;functional electrodes are suitable for methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) coupled green H 2 production with effective energy efficiency. The low overall potential (MOR+HER) of 1.78 V to realize the current density ( j ) value of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and extended durability (100 h@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) along with the selective conversion of methanol to formate support the viability of the NF&#8208;PAHz&#8208;Co 3 O 4 @NiCu for the said operation. The electrode also displays efficacy toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and j OER value of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 is realized at a potential value of 1.65 V RHE with adequate durability. Overall, the synthetic strategy is general, scalable and may be extended to grow other metal oxide doped alloy nanostructures in the future.</description>
      <author>Sunil Semwal, Aiswarya Samal, Saroj K. Nayak, Rajashri Urkude, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, Umaprasana Ojha</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Yolk@Shell-Heterostuctured Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanospheres as Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04799</link>
      <description>Yingxin Liu, Yan Hou, Mingyang Cai, Weishun Song, Xiao&#8208;Quan Yang, Junjie Fu, Liangshun Luo, Xueming Su, Xianggang Huang, Hongwei Gu, Xueqin Cao, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402272508

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingxin Liu, Yan Hou, Mingyang Cai, Weishun Song, Xiao&#8208;Quan Yang, Junjie Fu, Liangshun Luo, Xueming Su, Xianggang Huang, Hongwei Gu, Xueqin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04799</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the adsorption strength of oxygen intermediates on &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;NiC&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;o&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;O&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;4&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:math&gt; by Fe doping to improve the oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.095801</link>
      <description>Xilin Zhang, Sheng Rui, Y. C. Zhai, Rui Zheng, Shan Wang, Zhongjun Ma, Zongxian Yang, Physical Review Materials. 8(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402168197

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xilin Zhang, Sheng Rui, Y. C. Zhai, Rui Zheng, Shan Wang, Zhongjun Ma, Zongxian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevmaterials.8.095801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon&#8208; and Nitrogen&#8208;Based Complexes as Photocatalysts for Prebiotic and Oxygen Chemistry during Earth Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413768</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, Li Wang, Sibo Wang, Yuanxing Fang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402319199

                Sunlight has long served as primary energy source on our planet, shaping the behavior of living organisms. Extensive research has been dedicated to unraveling the evolutionary pathways involved. When the formation of Earth atmosphere, it primarily consisted of small gas molecules, which are considered crucial for the emergence of life. Recent demonstrations have shown that these molecules can also be transformed into semiconductors, with the potential to harness solar energy and catalyze chemical reactions as photocatalysts. Building upon this research, this minireview focuses on the potential revolutionary impact of photocatalysis on Earth. Initially, it examines key reactions, such as the formation of prebiotic molecules and the oxygen evolution reaction via water oxidation. Additionally, various C&#8208;N complexes in photocatalysts are explored, showcasing their roles in catalyzing chemical reactions. The conclusion and outlook provide a potential pathway for the evolution of Earth, shedding light on the significance of metal&#8208;free photocatalysts in development of Earth.</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, Li Wang, Sibo Wang, Yuanxing Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413768</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution-Based Feature Selection for Predicting Dissolved Oxygen Concentrations in Lakes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-70085-9_25</link>
      <description>Runlong Yu, Robert Ladwig, Xiang Xu, Peijun Zhu, Paul C. Hanson, Yiqun Xie, Xiaowei Jia, Lecture notes in computer science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402289046

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Runlong Yu, Robert Ladwig, Xiang Xu, Peijun Zhu, Paul C. Hanson, Yiqun Xie, Xiaowei Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-70085-9_25</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402164392

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402179583

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402164096

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402180294

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Sana Ullah, Asif Hussain, Muhammad Asim Farid, Shaheen Irfan, Roohul Amin, Ahmed M. Fouda, Atif Nazir, Dehua Hou, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Shangfeng Du, Muhammad Tahir, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402179694

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sana Ullah, Asif Hussain, Muhammad Asim Farid, Shaheen Irfan, Roohul Amin, Ahmed M. Fouda, Atif Nazir, Dehua Hou, Ji&#8208;Jun Zou, Shangfeng Du, Muhammad Tahir</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402179868

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Molybdenum tungsten hydrogen oxide doped with phosphorus for enhanced oxygen/hydrogen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402180297

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra05023a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-cycle evolution of thickness and roughness parameters during oxygen plasma enhanced ZnO atomic layer deposition using &lt;i&gt;in situ&lt;/i&gt; spectroscopic ellipsometry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0003830</link>
      <description>Yousra Traouli, Ufuk K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, Sema G. Kilic, Matthew Hilfiker, Daniel Schmidt, Stefan Schoeche, E. F. Schubert, M. Schubert, Journal of Vacuum Science &amp; Technology A Vacuum Surfaces and Films. 42(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402313566

                We investigate the time evolution of ZnO thin film growth in oxygen plasma-enhanced atomic layer deposition using in situ spectroscopic ellipsometry. The recently proposed dynamic-dual-box-model approach [Kilic et al., Sci. Rep. 10, 10392 (2020)] is used to analyze the spectroscopic data post-growth. With the help of this model, we explore the in-cycle surface modifications and reveal the repetitive layer-by-layer growth and surface roughness modification mechanisms during the ZnO ultrathin film deposition. The in situ complex-valued dielectric function of the amorphous ZnO thin film is also determined from the model analysis for photon energies of 1.7&#8211;4 eV. The dielectric function is analyzed using a critical point model approach providing parameters for bandgap energy, amplitude, and broadening in addition to the index of refraction and extinction coefficient. The dynamic-dual-box-model analysis reveals the initial nucleation phase where the surface roughness changes due to nucleation and island growth prior to film coalescence, which then lead to the surface conformal layer-by-layer growth with constant surface roughness. The thickness evolution is resolved with Angstrom-scale resolution vs time. We propose this method for fast development of growth recipes from real-time in situ data analysis. We also present and discuss results from x-ray diffraction, x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, and atomic force microscopy to examine crystallographic, chemical, and morphological characteristics of the ZnO film.</description>
      <author>Yousra Traouli, Ufuk K&#305;l&#305;&#231;, Sema G. Kilic, Matthew Hilfiker, Daniel Schmidt, Stefan Schoeche, E. F. Schubert, M. Schubert</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0003830</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimized dark consumption of Calvin cycle intermediates facilitates the initiation of photosynthesis in &lt;i&gt;Synechocystis&lt;/i&gt; sp. PCC 6803</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/pcp/pcae102</link>
      <description>Kenya Tanaka, Akihiko Kondo, Tomohisa Hasunuma, Plant and Cell Physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402323710

                Abstract Cyanobacteria intricately regulate their metabolic pathways during the diurnal cycle to ensure survival and growth. Under dark conditions, the breakdown of glycogen, an energy reserve, in these organisms replenishes Calvin cycle intermediates, especially downstream glycolytic metabolites, which are necessary for photosynthesis initiation upon light irradiation. However, it remains unclear how the accumulation of these intermediates is maintained in the dark despite limited glycogen availability. Therefore, in this study, we investigated the regulation of downstream glycolytic metabolites of the Calvin cycle under dark and light treatment using Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803. Our results showed that during the dark period, low pyruvate kinase (Pyk) activity ensured metabolite accumulation, while endogenous Pyk overexpression significantly lowered the accumulation of glycolytic intermediates. Remarkably, wild type Synechocystis maintained oxygen evolution ability throughout dark treatment for over 2 d, while Pyk overexpression resulted in decreased oxygen evolution after 16 h of dark treatment. These results indicated that limiting Pyk activity via darkness treatment facilitates photosynthetic initiation by maintaining glycolytic intermediates. Similarly, phosphoenolpyruvate carboxylase (PepC) overexpression decreased oxygen evolution under dark treatment; however, its effect was lower than that of Pyk. Further, we noted that as PepC overexpression decreased the levels of glycolytic intermediates in the dark, sugar phosphates in the Calvin-Benson-Bassham (CBB) cycle showed high accumulation, suggesting that sugar phosphates play important roles in supporting photosynthesis initiation. Therefore, our study highlights the importance of controlling the metabolic pathways through which glycolytic and CBB cycle intermediates are consumed (defined as cataplerosis of CBB cycle) to ensure stable photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Kenya Tanaka, Akihiko Kondo, Tomohisa Hasunuma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/pcp/pcae102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect engineering for surface reconstruction of metal oxide catalysts during OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101091</link>
      <description>Jingxuan Zheng, Zhao Wang, Chem Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402194918

                The bigger pictureChallenges and opportunities:&#8226;The scarcity of active sites limits the large-scale application of metal oxides as commercial oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts. However, the rational design of defect structures can boost their catalytic activity&#8226;The precise design of catalyst defect structures requires a comprehensive understanding of the structure-activity relationship between defects and OER performance. Current research primarily focuses on the correlation between defects and thermodynamic parameters. However, our understanding of the intrinsic relationship between defects and the kinetics and mechanisms of OERs remains limited&#8226;In the adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM), defect structures can accelerate the evolution of active surfaces, promote OH&#8315; adsorption and deprotonation, and facilitate the desorption of the product O&#8322;. In the lattice oxygen intermediate mechanism (LOM), defect structures can enhance the covalency of metal&#8211;oxygen bonds and provide OH&#8315; adsorption sites, facilitating their involvement in lattice oxygen oxidation processesSummaryThe development of electrochemical processes, such as water electrolysis for hydrogen production and rechargeable metal-air batteries, offers promising solutions to the energy crisis and environmental pollution. However, challenges like sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics, high costs of precious metal catalysts, and scarce active sites in transition metal oxides hinder large-scale commercial applications. Defect engineering has emerged as a promising strategy to optimize transition metal oxides by improving their electronic structure, conductivity, and active site availability. Early research focused on static thermodynamic parameters, such as impedance, overpotential, and band gap, neglecting dynamic factors like catalyst surface restructuring and mechanism transformation during reactions. This perspective highlights the intrinsic connection between defect structures, catalyst surface reconstruction, and reaction mechanisms. It also discusses the need for advanced experimental and theoretical computational studies to better understand the surface evolution of catalysts during OERs.Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Jingxuan Zheng, Zhao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2024.101091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hypochlorous acid electrosynthesis and service life assessment of a Ti|Ti-Ru-Ir-oxides anode assembled in a flow electrolyzer: Understanding the influence of the concurrent O2 bubbling flow</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143280</link>
      <description>Juan F. Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Jos&#233; L. Nava, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402314695

                This paper addresses the influence of bubbling flow and service life of the Ti|Ti-Ru-Ir-oxides anode during the electrosynthesis of HClO in a laboratory-scale filter-press-type electrolyzer. The electrolyzer was assembled in a flow plant in recirculation mode. Polarization curves in rotating disk electrode (RDE) revealed the coexistence of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) during HClO electrosynthesis in diluted chloride solutions (containing 35 mM NaCl at pH 3). CFD simulations of the two-phase (O</description>
      <author>Juan F. Rodr&#305;&#769;guez, Jos&#233; L. Nava</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.143280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>INFLUENCE OF Ni CONTENT OF ELECTRODEPOSITED Pd-Ni ALLOY COATINGS ON THEIR ELECTROCATALYTIC ACTIVITY IN ALKALINE MEDIUM</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59957/jctm.v59.i5.2024.12</link>
      <description>J. Georgieva, Tzvetanka Boiadjieva-Scherzer, M. Monev, Journal of Chemical Technology and Metallurgy. 59(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377205

                The influence of the Ni content (1.4 - 9.0 wt. %) in electrodeposited Pd-Ni alloy coatings on the rate of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in an alkaline media was investigated. Electrocatalytic activity of the electrodeposited layers towards methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) was also studied. The composition and surface morphology of the samples were characterized by energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS) and scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The crystal structure of the Pd-Ni alloys was examined by X-ray diffraction (XRD). Electrochemical experiments were performed by cyclic voltammetry (CV). The presence of concentration ranges with respect to the Ni content is shown, wherein the electrocatalytic activity of the Pd-Ni alloy towards HER, OER and MOR is higher than that of pure Pd.</description>
      <author>J. Georgieva, Tzvetanka Boiadjieva-Scherzer, M. Monev</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59957/jctm.v59.i5.2024.12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of adipic acid with high faradaic efficiency within a wide potential window</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51951-0</link>
      <description>Xiang Liu, Yuquan Zhu, Jing Li, Ye Wang, Qiujin Shi, An-Zhen Li, Kaiyue Ji, Wenjun Wang, Xikang Zhao, Jinyu Zheng, Haohong Duan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402166971

                Electrosynthesis of adipic acid (a precursor for nylon-66) from KA oil (a mixture of cyclohexanone and cyclohexanol) represents a sustainable strategy to replace conventional method that requires harsh conditions. However, its industrial possibility is greatly restricted by the low current density and competitive oxygen evolution reaction. Herein, we modify nickel layered double hydroxide with vanadium to promote current density and maintain high faradaic efficiency (&gt;80%) within a wide potential window (1.5 ~ 1.9 V vs. reversible hydrogen electrode). Experimental and theoretical studies reveal two key roles of V modification, including accelerating catalyst reconstruction and strengthening cyclohexanone adsorption. As a proof-of-the-concept, we construct a membrane electrode assembly, producing adipic acid with high faradaic efficiency (82%) and productivity (1536 &#956;mol cm</description>
      <author>Xiang Liu, Yuquan Zhu, Jing Li, Ye Wang, Qiujin Shi, An-Zhen Li, Kaiyue Ji, Wenjun Wang, Xikang Zhao, Jinyu Zheng, Haohong Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-51951-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured MnMoO4 as a trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129927</link>
      <description>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402199718

                Electrochemical water splitting and CO2 reduction are important processes to produce hydrogen and low&#8211;carbon fuels as renewable energy sources. Here, nanostructured MnMoO4, prepared by the reflux precipitation method, was investigated as a trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions. Using a combination of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results, a direct band gap of 3.05 eV was obtained experimentally for the prepared MnMoO4. An overpotential of 0.36 V at a current density of 5 mA cm-2 and a Tafel slope of 58 mV dec-1 were obtained for the oxygen evolution reaction. At a current density of 3 mA cm-2, overpotentials of 0.39 V and 0.58 V were achieved in the absence and presence of CO2 bubbling into a 0.1 M KOH solution, respectively, emphasizing the poisoning effect of CO2 reduction intermediates for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Based on the obtained results, MnMoO4 could be a promising electrocatalyst for water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions.</description>
      <author>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129927</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface engineering of La0.6Sr0.4Co0.2Fe0.8O3&#8722;&#948;/Gd0.1Ce0.9O1.95 heterostructure oxygen electrode for solid oxide electrolysis cells with enhanced CO2 electrolysis performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155461</link>
      <description>Caichen Yang, Ziling Wang, Yuan Tan, Jian Pu, Bo Chi, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402175246

                For CO2 electrolysis in solid oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs), oxygen evolution reaction in the oxygen electrode limits the electrolysis process due to its slower reaction kinetics. Composite oxygen electrodes with good uniformity and interfacial connectivity are expected to promote the charge carriers' transport effectively and thus increase the electrocatalytic performance of the cell. In this work, interface engineering is applied to promote the conventional La0.6Sr0.4Co0.2Fe0.8O3&#8722;&#948;-Gd0.1Ce0.9O1.95 (LSCF-GDC) composite oxygen electrode to form a heterostructure via co-synthesis method. The results prove that LSCF co-synthesized with 40 wt.%GDC (LSCF/40GDC) exhibits higher conductivity and faster oxygen exchange kinetics and bulk diffusion processes. The nickel/yttria stabilized zirconia (Ni-YSZ) supported cell with LSCF/40GDC oxygen electrode could approach an impressive CO2 electrolysis current density of 2.6 A&#183;cm&#8722;2 at 1.6 V and 800 &#176;C. Meanwhile the cell can operate at 1.5 V and 750 &#176;C with electrolysis current density of 1.3 A&#183;cm&#8722;2 for more than 100 h without apparent degradation. This heterostructure enhances the interfacial bonding strength between LSCF and GDC phases, thereby providing a continuous network structure for electron and ion transport. Such an interface engineering via co-synthesis method offers a straightforward and convenient modification for oxygen electrodes, providing an alternative route for advanced materials development of CO2 electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Caichen Yang, Ziling Wang, Yuan Tan, Jian Pu, Bo Chi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thienyl&#8208;Bridged Fused Porphyrin Tapes for Enhanced Heterogeneous Electrocatalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400258</link>
      <description>Hadi Ghahramanzadeh Asl, Deepak Bansal, Drialys Cardenas&#8208;Morcoso, Nicolas D. Boscher, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402311165

                Abstract The development of highly conjugated metalloporphyrin assemblies is a crucial step to improve their catalytic activity for optimal energy conversion processes. Herein, di&#8208;thienyl substituted nickel(II) porphyrin is used to form a highly conjugated porphyrin structure. The resulting porphyrin&#8208;based conjugated polymer catalyst exhibited exceptional oxygen evolution reaction &#8220;OER&#8221; performances, featuring a low onset overpotential of 266 mV and high reaction kinetics (Tafel slope of 69.9 mV/dec) under alkaline pH conditions, achieving a current density of 4.5 mA/cm 2 . The remarkable OER catalytic activity of porphyrin&#8208;based conjugated polymer catalyst is attributed to the enhancement of the conjugation, which occurs through a unique process involving direct fusion of the porphyrins followed by thienyl bridging of the fused porphyrin tapes, ultimately leading to the establishment of a highly cross&#8208;linked porphyrinic network.</description>
      <author>Hadi Ghahramanzadeh Asl, Deepak Bansal, Drialys Cardenas&#8208;Morcoso, Nicolas D. Boscher</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox Activity of Co Species in the Active Sites of CoN x /CoO x Facilitates Oxygen Electrocatalysis for Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402972</link>
      <description>Huimin Yang, Hao Wang, Haorong Cheng, Xinyuan Xu, Jing Li, Xiaoyan He, Lin Tian, Li Zhao, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402333995

                Developing efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts is crucial for enhancing the performance of rechargeable Zn-air batteries (ZABs). In this study, cobalt/cobalt oxides embedded in N-doped carbon nanofibers (Co/CoOx/NCNFs) were synthesized through a combination of electrospinning and annealing processes. The resulting Co/CoOx/NCNFs catalysts feature abundant CoNx and CoOx active species, leveraging the large specific surface area of nanofibers to facilitate oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The optimized Co/CoOx/NCNFs-0.1 achieved a half-wave potential (vs. RHE) of 0.82 V and required only 429 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; in a typical three-electrode system with 0.1 M KOH using an electrochemical workstation equipped with a pine instruments rotator, outperforming the Pt/C+RuO2. The assembled ZABs exhibited high specific capacity (771 mAh gZn-1), substantial power density (981.6 mWh gZn-1), and long-term stability (&gt;325 h). In situ Raman spectroscopy confirmed that the electrocatalytic processes involve the redox activity of Co (II and III) species derived from abundant CoNx and CoOx, elaborating the origin of the catalysts' exceptional oxygen electrocatalysis performance. This work not only presents a straightforward and effective approach for producing bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts in ZABs but also sheds light on the catalytic mechanisms underlying ORR and OER for CoNx/CoOx-based oxygen electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Huimin Yang, Hao Wang, Haorong Cheng, Xinyuan Xu, Jing Li, Xiaoyan He, Lin Tian, Li Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402972</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dissolution Manufacturing Strategy for the Facile Synthesis of Nanoporous Metallic Glass Multifunctional Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401109</link>
      <description>Shenghao Zeng, Wenqing Ruan, Zhe Chen, Shuai Ren, J.Z. Jiang, Jiajia Lin, Heting Zhang, Zhenxuan Zhang, Jianan Fu, Qing Chen, Xiong Liang, Jiang Ma, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402362637

                Abstract The quest for heightened energy efficiency is inextricably linked to advancements in energy storage and conversion technologies, wherein multifunctional catalysts play a pivotal role by mitigating the slow kinetics endemic to many catalytic reactions. The intricate synthesis and bespoke design of such catalysts, however, present notable challenges. Addressing this, the present study capitalizes on a novel dissolution manufacturing strategy to engineer self&#8208;supporting, nanoporous multifunctional electrocatalysts, circumventing the prevalent issue of customizing catalytic functionalities upon demand. This innovative approach grants the flexibility to finely tune the incorporation of active species and metalloid binders, culminating in the creation of a self&#8208;supporting nanoporous metal glass electrocatalyst doped with RuO 2 (NPMG@RuO 2 ) with outstanding performance in alkaline media. The catalyst showcases superior electrocatalytic activity, achieving low overpotentials of 41.50 mV for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and 226.0 mV for Oxygen Evolution Reaction alongside sustained stability over 620 hours.These achievements are attributed to the distinct nanoporous architecture that ensures a high density of catalytic sites and mechanical strength, bolstered by the synergistic interplay between RuO 2 and Pt&#8208;based metallic glass. The findings provide a versatile template for the development of nanoporous multifunctional catalysts, signifying a leap forward in the realm of energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Shenghao Zeng, Wenqing Ruan, Zhe Chen, Shuai Ren, J.Z. Jiang, Jiajia Lin, Heting Zhang, Zhenxuan Zhang, Jianan Fu, Qing Chen, Xiong Liang, Jiang Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401109</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arsenene/Ti&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction as a Promising Z&#8208;Scheme Photocatalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408353</link>
      <description>Ling Hua, Youxi Wang, Zhenyu Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402377844

                Abstract In order to address imminent energy and environmental challenges, photocatalytic water splitting emerges as a promising way for harnessing solar radiation to generate clean chemical energy. 2D arsenene (&#946;&#8208;As) has notable catalytic activity in hydrogen production. Based on first principles calculations and non&#8208;adiabatic molecular dynamics (NAMD) simulations, the &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 heterojunction is predicted to be a promising Z&#8208;scheme photocatalyst for overall solar water splitting. It has a desirable energy band structure with the valence band maximum of Ti 2 CO 2 and the conduction band minimum of &#946;&#8208;As well below and above the redox potentials of H 2 O. Both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can proceed spontaneously under light irradiation. NAMD simulations confirm that it is a Z&#8208;scheme photocatalyst with fast electron&#8211;hole combination dynamics. Instead of by intrinsic electric field, such a fast electron&#8211;hole combination is driven by a large nonadiabatic coupling. The heterojunction exhibits strong optical absorption in the visible and ultraviolet regions. The estimated solar&#8208;to&#8208;hydrogen (STH) efficiency limit of &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 reaches 32%, which is the highest among all &#946;&#8208;As based junctions reported in the literature. These results suggest that &#946;&#8208;As/Ti 2 CO 2 is a promising photocatalyst for achieving overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Ling Hua, Youxi Wang, Zhenyu Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202408353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Sun Tracking Concentrated Solar Power (CSP) Technology with Parabolic Reflectors to Power an Electrolysis System for Yielding Green Hydrogen from Potable Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202456604002</link>
      <description>Angel Joyce Rodeo Parawan, Reylina Garcia Tayactac, E3S Web of Conferences. 566(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402319473

                Hydrogen energy, a clean and sustainable energy source, has received much attention recently. Water electrolysis combines the cathode&#8217;s hydrogen evolution process with the anode&#8217;s oxygen evolution reaction, which is a potential approach for producing hydrogen. High-grade energy is needed for advanced solar energy utilization technology such as electrolysis to provide the most compact, and efficient application. Electrical and thermal energy needs may be satisfied by concentrated solar power (CSP) technology. Utilizing CSP technology with parabolic reflectors has several advantages, including a proven track record of financial return on investment, a well-developed technology, and simplicity of integration with other renewable energy sources or fossil fuels. Given the world&#8217;s current environmental status and the continuing degradation of fossil fuel supplies, the direct use of potable water as a medium for hydrogen synthesis has emerged as a hot research issue. Because of its availability in the Philippines and how it can be produced by desalinating seawater, immediate use of potable water as the medium for water electrolysis can minimize the cost of hydrogen generation. Research on yielding hydrogen gas as an alternative energy source by an electrolysis system powered by sun-tracking CSP with parabolic reflectors was thoroughly done to gather data. Results show that green hydrogen gas can indeed be yielded and can be more effective with the use of sun-tracking CSP.</description>
      <author>Angel Joyce Rodeo Parawan, Reylina Garcia Tayactac</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202456604002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium Clusters Modification Carbon Layer&#8208;Encapsulated NiCoP Nanoneedles as Advanced Electrocatalyst for Efficient Seawater Splitting Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401197</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Liu, Xueer Ning, Aize Hao, Muhammad Farooq Khan, Shania Rehman, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402333956

                Developing efficient and durable electrocatalyst for seawater splitting is crucial in hydrogen production. Herein, a multi-scale design strategy was employed to fabricate ruthenium clusters modification carbon layer-encapsulated nickel-cobalt-phosphorus (Ru/C/NiCoP) nanoneedles electrocatalyst supported on nickel foam (NF). We demonstrated that Ru/C/NiCoP/NF exhibited exceptional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performances, with low overpotential, Tafel slope and superior stability. Furthermore, the electrocatalytic mechanism of Ru/C/NiCoP was elucidated through the combination of ex-situ and in-situ characterizations, along with comprehensive electrochemical tests. Strikingly, Ru clusters and the carbon layer engendered robust electronic interaction reaction, accelerated the charge transfer rate, provided more active sites, and enhanced intrinsic catalytic activity, thus substantially promoting the OER kinetics and HER reaction steps as well as stability. In addition, the two-electrode system constructed with Ru/C/NiCoP/NF achieved current density of 10 mA cm-2 in both pure water and seawater at ultra-low potential of 1.46/1.47 V, with Faraday efficiency close to 100%. Even at higher current density of 100 mA cm-2, the required driving voltage remained low at 1.75/1.77 V, maintaining stable operation for 150 h, outperforming most reported non-noble catalysts. This innovative strategy provides facile and versatile approach for developing advanced electrocatalysts in seawater electrolysis application.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Liu, Xueer Ning, Aize Hao, Muhammad Farooq Khan, Shania Rehman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent Triazine&#8208;Based Frameworks with Ru&#8208;tda Based Catalyst Anchored via Coordination Bond for Photoinduced Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406375</link>
      <description>Martina Salati, Florian Dorchies, Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, Marta Ventosa, Soranyel Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Carrero, Carlota Bozal&#8208;Ginesta, Jan Holub, Olaf R&#252;diger, Julio Lloret&#8208;Fillol, Carolina Gimbert&#8208;Suri&#241;ach, James R. Durrant, Mehmed Z. Ertem, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, Antoni Llobet, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402270252

                Abstract Light&#8208;induced water splitting (h&#957;&#8208;WS) for the production of hydrogen as a solar fuel is considered a promising sustainable strategy for the replacement of fossil fuels. An efficient system for h&#957;&#8208;WS involves a photoactive material that, upon shining light, is capable of separating and transferring charges to catalysts for the hydrogen and oxygen evolution processes. Covalent triazine&#8208;based frameworks (CTFs) represent an interesting class of 2D organic light&#8208;absorbing materials that have recently emerged thanks to their tunable structural, optical and morphological properties. Typically, catalysts (Cat) are metallic nanoparticles generated in situ after photoelectroreduction of metal precursors or directly drop&#8208;casted on top of the CTF material to generate Cat&#8208;CTF assemblies. In this work, the synthesis, characterization and photocatalytic performance of a novel hybrid material, Ru&#8208;CTF , is reported, based on a CTF structure featuring dangling pyridyl groups that allow the Ru&#8208;tda (tda is [2,2&#8242;:6&#8242;,2&#8242;&#8220;&#8208;terpyridine]&#8208;6,6&#8242;&#8221;&#8208;dicarboxylic acid) water oxidation catalyst (WOC) unit to coordinate via covalent bond. The Ru&#8208;CTF molecular hybrid material can carry out the light&#8208;induced water oxidation reaction efficiently at neutral pH, reaching values of maximum TOF of 17 h &#8722;1 and TONs in the range of 220 using sodium persulfate as a sacrificial electron acceptor.</description>
      <author>Martina Salati, Florian Dorchies, Jia&#8208;Wei Wang, Marta Ventosa, Soranyel Gonz&#225;lez&#8208;Carrero, Carlota Bozal&#8208;Ginesta, Jan Holub, Olaf R&#252;diger, Julio Lloret&#8208;Fillol, Carolina Gimbert&#8208;Suri&#241;ach, James R. Durrant, Mehmed Z. Ertem, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, Antoni Llobet</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406375</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A machine-learning interatomic potential to study dry/wet oxidation process of silicon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219764</link>
      <description>Huyang Li, Yuhang Jing, Zhongli Liu, Lingzhi Cong, Junqing Zhao, Yi Sun, Weiqi Li, Jihong Yan, Jianqun Yang, Xingji Li, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402194389

                We developed an accurate and efficient machine learning potential with DFT accuracy and applied it to the silicon dry/wet oxidation process to investigate the underlying physics of thermal oxidation of silicon (001) surfaces. The accuracy of the potential was verified by comparing the melting point and structural properties of silicon, the structural properties of a-SiO2, and the adsorption properties on the silicon surface with experiment and DFT data. In subsequent thermal oxidation simulations, we successfully reproduced the accelerated growth phenomenon of the wet oxidation in the experiment, discussed the oxide growth process in detail, and elucidated that the accelerated growth is due to hydrogen in the system that both enhances the adsorption of oxygen on the silicon surface and promotes the migration of oxygen atoms. Finally, we annealed the oxidized structure, counted the defect information in the structure before and after annealing, and analyzed the defect evolution behavior during the annealing process.</description>
      <author>Huyang Li, Yuhang Jing, Zhongli Liu, Lingzhi Cong, Junqing Zhao, Yi Sun, Weiqi Li, Jihong Yan, Jianqun Yang, Xingji Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0219764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling reaction discrepancy and electrolyte stabilizing effects of auto&#8208;oxygenated porphyrin catalysts in lithium&#8211;oxygen and lithium&#8211;air cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.587</link>
      <description>Boran Kim, Hyunyoung Park, Hyun&#8208;Soo Kim, J.S. Lee, Jongsoon Kim, Won&#8208;Hee Ryu, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402309061

                Abstract Lithium&#8211;oxygen (Li&#8211;O 2 ) batteries are an emerging energy storage alternative with the potential to meet the recent increase in demand for high&#8208;energy&#8208;density batteries. From a practical viewpoint, lithium&#8211;air (Li&#8211;Air) batteries using ambient air instead of pure oxygen could be the final goal. However, the slow oxygen reduction and evolution reactions interfere with reversible cell operation during cycling. Therefore, research continues to explore various catalyst materials. The present study attempts to improve the performance of Li&#8211;Air batteries by using porphyrin&#8208;based materials known to have catalytic effects in Li&#8211;O 2 batteries. The results confirm that the iron phthalocyanine (FePc) catalyst not only exhibits a catalytic effect in an air atmosphere with a low oxygen fraction but also suppresses electrolyte decomposition by stabilizing superoxide radical ions (O 2 &#8722; ) at a high voltage range. Density functional theory calculations are used to gain insight into the exact FePc&#8208;mediated catalytic mechanism in Li&#8211;Air batteries, and various ex situ and in situ analyses reveal the reversible reactions and structural changes in FePc during electrochemical reaction. This study provides a practical solution to ultimately realize an air&#8208;breathing battery using nature&#8208;friendly catalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Boran Kim, Hyunyoung Park, Hyun&#8208;Soo Kim, J.S. Lee, Jongsoon Kim, Won&#8208;Hee Ryu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.587</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative studies on the microstructures of ternary CaO-Al2O3-SiO2 glasses, melts and correlation with their high-temperature viscosities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/lnvg1782</link>
      <description>Jinglin You, Xiu&#8208;Zhi Tang, Fuxiang Zhang, A. Canizar&#232;s, Catherine Bessada, Li L&#252;, Keke Tang, Qiang Zhang, Shaoping Wan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383938

                Microstructure of CaO-SiO2-based glassy samples with various Al2O3 contents were examined quantitatively by Raman spectroscopy and 27Al MAS NMR (magic-angle spinning nuclear magnetic resonance). Sequence of multiple cluster models of aluminosilicate system modified with Ca2+ and Na+ cations have been designed, and Raman spectra simulation were carried out after geometric optimisation by quantum chemistry (QC) ab initio calculation. The functional relationship between Raman scattering cross-section (RSCS) and stress index of silicon-oxygen tetrahedron (SIT) for aluminosilicates was established, which was applied to the calibration of experimental Raman spectra. Some five-fold coordinated aluminium (AlV, around 5 per cent) and less than 2 per cent six-fold coordinated aluminium (AlVI) were detected by 27Al MAS NMR, while most of aluminium remained in tetrahedral sites (AlIV). The hyperfine quantitative results of Raman spectroscopy and NMR showed a gradually production of AlIV with addition of Al2O3, along with the significant adjustment of Qi species distribution, in which Q1, Q2 reduced and fully polymerised Q4 increased while Q3 showed a non-monotonic variation and obtained the maximum at Al2O3 = 18 mol per cent. Furthermore, the effects of aluminium to bridging oxygen bond types (T-Ob, T = Si, Al) and the degree of polymerisation were also discussed in detail. The evolution of microstructure and its correlation with the viscosity of CaO-SiO2 based melts, incorporating various Al2O3 additives, have been investigated by employing in situ high temperature Raman spectroscopy at 1823 K and viscosity model. These structural features related to composition are essential theoretic foundation to understand their properties. The average Qi evolution culminates in an overall enhancement of the degree of polymerisation. Viscosity was determined utilising a rigorously selected viscosity model, elucidating a consistent upward trajectory as Al2O3 content is incrementally added. Furthermore, a quantitative analysis of the relationship between viscosity and structure was conducted based on the average number of non-bridging oxygen per network-forming tetrahedron (NBO/T). It provides valuable insights for examining and predicting viscosity behaviour of aluminosilicate systems.</description>
      <author>Jinglin You, Xiu&#8208;Zhi Tang, Fuxiang Zhang, A. Canizar&#232;s, Catherine Bessada, Li L&#252;, Keke Tang, Qiang Zhang, Shaoping Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/lnvg1782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferpesto 2.0: Elevate Green, Hydro-organic Fusion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202456601002</link>
      <description>Adil Jamal, Akmal Hakimi Hasnur Izwan, Azlinda Saadon, Eisya Syifaa Ahmad Zulfaa, Muhammad Azhar, Nur Aisyatul Auni Wafdi Auni, Noorsaadah Abd Rahman, S.M.S. Shaikh Mohd Salleh, E3S Web of Conferences. 566(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402318186

                Ferpesto, an innovation that combines the properties of a pesticide and fertiliser. While the successful Ferpesto 1.0 project was focusing on the growth of the ground plants, we evolved the original Ferpesto to the upgraded version which now focuses on the aquatic plants. This evolution was made as we discovered that the concerns arose regarding eutrophication in aquatic ecosystems due to excessive nitrates. This led to harmful algae blooms depleting oxygen, releasing toxins, and elevating Biochemical Oxygen Demand (BOD). In response, Ferpesto 2.0 prioritises the growth of aquatic plants, aiming to improve water quality by reducing BOD. Expanding on the original formula with watermelon rind, onion peel, fermented rice, and filtered water, Ferpesto 2.0 introduces a key addition which is hydrogen peroxide (H&#8322;O&#8322;). Observations show that polluted water treated with Ferpesto 2.0 took a longer time to decolorize the methylene blue, indicating the decrease in BOD compared to untreated water. From our survey, individuals that own aquatic ecosystems seek an alternative to maintain the water quality that is both sustainable and affordable. By reusing household wastes, Ferpesto 2.0 contributes to environmentally friendly practices, contributing a healthier and balanced ecosystem for current and future generations.</description>
      <author>Adil Jamal, Akmal Hakimi Hasnur Izwan, Azlinda Saadon, Eisya Syifaa Ahmad Zulfaa, Muhammad Azhar, Nur Aisyatul Auni Wafdi Auni, Noorsaadah Abd Rahman, S.M.S. Shaikh Mohd Salleh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/e3sconf/202456601002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase equilibria of Al2TiO5&#8211;Ti3O5 pseudobrookite solid solution in the Al2O3&#8211;TiOx system under various oxygen partial pressures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.62053/mcam4452</link>
      <description>Young Joo Park, W.K. Kim, Youn&#8208;Bae Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402383589

                The phase equilibria in the Al2O3&#8211;TiOx system were investigated in wide ranges of temperature and oxygen partial pressure: 1300~1600&#176;C and 10-16.6~10-8 atm, respectively. The equilibrium phases and their compositions were identified using X-ray diffraction (XRD) and electron probe micro-analysis (EPMA), respectively. Most noticeably, a wide range of pseudobrookite solid solution was found in equilibrium with almost pure alumina. At each temperature, the cationic ratio expressed as RTi = nTi/(nAl + nTi)) of the pseudobrookite solid solution showed a noteworthy dependency on the oxygen partial pressure. This resulted in the formation of a broad range of pseudobrookite solid solutions, ranging from Al2TiO5 (RTi = 1/3) to Ti3O5 (RTi = 1.0). Complete miscibility within the pseudobrookite solid solution was observed at 1600&#176;C, with only a minor miscibility gap becoming evident below 1500&#176;C. Based on the results obtained in the present study, the behaviours of Al2TiO5 pseudobrookite have implications in two key domains: (1) understanding changes in the physical properties of the materials, and (2) elucidating the evolution of Al&#8211;Ti complex oxide inclusions in liquid steel which can deteriorate the steel cleanliness.</description>
      <author>Young Joo Park, W.K. Kim, Youn&#8208;Bae Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.62053/mcam4452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen reduction reaction coupled electro&#8208;oxidation for highly&#8208;efficient and sustainable water treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414481</link>
      <description>Ran Xiao, Hehe Qin, Xiangyun Liu, Chengcheng Chu, Qiuju Li, Hongying Zhao, Shun Mao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402245388

                Electro&#8208;oxidation (EO) technology demonstrates significant potential in wastewater treatment. However, the high energy consumption has become a pivotal constraint hindering its large&#8208;scale implementation. Herein, we design an EO and 4&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction coupled system (EO&#8208;4eORR) to replace the traditional EO and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) coupled system (EO&#8208;HER). The theoretical cathodic potential of the electrolytic reactor is tuned from 0 V (vs. RHE) in HER to 1.23 V (vs. RHE) in 4eORR, which greatly decreases the required operation voltage of the reactor. Moreover, we demonstrate that convection can improve the mass transfer of oxygen and organic pollutants in the reaction system, leading to low cathodic polarization and high pollutant removal rate. Compared with traditional EO&#8208;HER system, the energy consumption of the EO&#8208;4eORR system under air aeration for 95% total organic carbon (TOC) removal is greatly decreased to 2.61 kWh/kgTOC (only consider the electrolyzer energy consumption), which is superior to previously reported EO&#8208;based water treatment systems. The reported results in this study offer a new technical mode for development of highly efficient and sustainable EO&#8208;based treatment systems to remove organic pollutants in waste water.</description>
      <author>Ran Xiao, Hehe Qin, Xiangyun Liu, Chengcheng Chu, Qiuju Li, Hongying Zhao, Shun Mao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202414481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoacoustic Spectrum Analysis for Soft Tissues</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-61411-8_16</link>
      <description>Yingna Chen, Shiying Wu, Qian Zhang, Jiayan Li, Menglu Qian, Qian Cheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402193119

                Abstract Biomedical photoacoustics has shown great potential for precise medical diagnosis because it can provide structural, physiological/pathological characteristics, and metabolic information of biological tissues noninvasively in vivo. Photoacoustic imaging has made great breakthroughs in many preclinical studies, including microvascular imaging, blood oxygen detection, and tumor detection. However, compared with photoacoustic imaging, the photoacoustic spectrum can provide more information, such as the rich molecular information in the optical spectrum and the rich microstructural information in the ultrasonic spectrum, which is closely related to the disease evolution process. Recently, photoacoustic spectrum analysis (PASA) has demonstrated the ability to quantitatively extract physicochemical information from biological tissues to distinguish between normal and diseased tissues, especially for classifying, grading, and staging cancer tissue, making it one of the most promising methods for noninvasive, accurate diagnosis of clinical diseases. In this chapter, we introduce the methods of PASA for the diagnosis of soft tissue diseases.</description>
      <author>Yingna Chen, Shiying Wu, Qian Zhang, Jiayan Li, Menglu Qian, Qian Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-61411-8_16</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metals in Star-forming Galaxies with KCWI. I. Methodology and First Results on the Abundances of Iron, Magnesium, and Oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad5ff8</link>
      <description>Zhuyun Zhuang, Evan N. Kirby, Charles C. Steidel, Mithi A. C. de los Reyes, Nikolaus Z. Prusinski, Nicha Leethochawalit, Minjung Park, Charlie Conroy, Evan Haze Nu&#241;ez, The Astrophysical Journal. 972(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402321018

                Abstract Understanding the chemical enrichment of different elements is crucial to gaining a complete picture of galaxy chemical evolution. In this study, we present a new sample of 46 low-redshift, low-mass star-forming galaxies at M * &#8764; 10 8&#8722;10 M &#8857; along with two quiescent galaxies at M * &#8764; 10 8.8 M &#8857; observed with the Keck Cosmic Web Imager, aiming to investigate the chemical evolution of galaxies in the transition zone between Local Group satellites and massive field galaxies. We develop a novel method to simultaneously determine stellar abundances of iron and magnesium in star-forming galaxies. With the gas-phase oxygen abundance (O/H) g measured using the strong-line method, we are able to make the first-ever apples-to-apples comparison of &#945; elements in the stars and the interstellar medium. We find that the [Mg/H] * &#8211;[O/H] g relation is much tighter than the [Fe/H] * &#8211;[O/H] g relation, which can be explained by the similar production processes of &#945; elements. Most galaxies in our sample exhibit higher [O/H] g than [Fe/H] * and [Mg/H] * . In addition, we construct mass&#8211;metallicity relations (MZRs) measured as three different elements (Fe * , Mg * , O g ). Compared to the gas O-MZR, the stellar Fe- and Mg-MZRs show larger scatter driven by variations in specific star formation rates (sSFR), with star-forming galaxies exhibiting higher sSFR and lower stellar abundances at fixed mass. The excess of [O/H] g compared to stellar abundances as well as the anticorrelation between sSFR and stellar abundance suggests that galaxy quenching of intermediate-mass galaxies at M * &#8764; 10 8&#8722;10 M &#8857; is primarily driven by starvation.</description>
      <author>Zhuyun Zhuang, Evan N. Kirby, Charles C. Steidel, Mithi A. C. de los Reyes, Nikolaus Z. Prusinski, Nicha Leethochawalit, Minjung Park, Charlie Conroy, Evan Haze Nu&#241;ez</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad5ff8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of ultrahigh-performance barium titanate-based piezoelectrics: Stannum-induced intrinsic and extrinsic contributions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52031-z</link>
      <description>Bo Wu, Huijing Zheng, Yutao Wu, Zhicheng Huang, Hao&#8208;Cheng Thong, Tao Hong, Wei Wang, Chunlin Zhao, Ze Xu, Yixuan Liu, Zhipeng Xing, Naixin Liang, Fang&#8208;Zhou Yao, Chaofeng Wu, Ke Wang, Bing Han, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402245657

                Despite the pivotal role of stannum doping in achieving ultrahigh piezoelectric performance in barium titanate-based ceramics, the fundamental mechanisms underlying this enhancement remain elusive. Here, we introduce a single variable nonstoichiometric stannum strategy in lead-free barium titanate-based ceramics with giant piezoelectricity, revealing that stannum doping contributes intrinsically and extrinsically to enhance piezoelectricity. Density functional theory calculations elucidate the intrinsic enhancement of polarization arising from lattice distortion and increased space for titanium-oxygen bonds induced by optimal stannum doping, which is corroborated by Rayleigh analysis. A phase transition from ferroelectric multiphase coexistence to paraelectric phase is observed, alongside a rapid miniaturized and eventually disappeared domains with increasing stannum doping. This evolution in phase structure and domain configuration induces a nearly vanishing polarization anisotropy and low domain wall energy, facilitating easy polarization rotation and domain wall motion, thereby significantly contributing to the extrinsic piezoelectric response. Consequently, the origins of ultrahigh performance can be attributed to the synergistic effect of stannum-induced intrinsic and extrinsic contributions in barium titanate-based ceramics. This study provides fundamental insights into the role of doping elements and offers guidance for the design of high-performance piezoelectrics.</description>
      <author>Bo Wu, Huijing Zheng, Yutao Wu, Zhicheng Huang, Hao&#8208;Cheng Thong, Tao Hong, Wei Wang, Chunlin Zhao, Ze Xu, Yixuan Liu, Zhipeng Xing, Naixin Liang, Fang&#8208;Zhou Yao, Chaofeng Wu, Ke Wang, Bing Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52031-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave&#8208;Assisted PtRu Alloying on Defective Tungsten Oxide: A Pathway to Improved Hydroxyl Dynamics for Highly&#8208;Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402372</link>
      <description>Bowen Zhou, Juping Wang, Lingfei Guo, Hongdong Li, Weiping Xiao, Guangrui Xu, Dehong Chen, Caixia Li, Yunmei Du, Hao Ding, Hongwei Huang, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402206759

                Abstract Platinum (Pt)&#8208;based compounds are the benchmarked catalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) but exhibit slow kinetics in alkaline environments. The * OH accumulation on Pt surface can block active sites, affecting proton reduction and water re&#8208;adsorption. Alloying Ruthenium (Ru) with Pt sites can significantly modulate the adsorption and desorption of water dissociation intermediates. Choosing suitable supports and utilizing metal&#8208;support interaction (MSI) is crucial for active site optimization. PtRu alloy anchored on tungsten oxide (WO 3 ) with rich oxygen vacancies (O V ) is prepared through an ultrafast microwave&#8208;assisted approach. Benefiting from the coupling effects between alloying and MSI, PtRu/WO 3 &#8208;O V exhibits exceptionally high HER activity. In 1 m KOH, 1 m KOH + seawater, and 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 , it requires ultralow overpotentials of 9, 26, and 6 mV to achieve 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The designed catalyst surpasses commercial Pt/C in mass activity and demonstrates considerable potential for intermittent energy integration. Density functional theory reveals that alloying Ru with Pt sites significantly reduces the energy barrier of dissociating * OH, modulating blockage on the surface and then promoting the overall alkaline HER process. This study offers insights into the rapid synthesis of non&#8208;carbon supported catalysts with Pt site modulation for alkaline hydrogen generation.</description>
      <author>Bowen Zhou, Juping Wang, Lingfei Guo, Hongdong Li, Weiping Xiao, Guangrui Xu, Dehong Chen, Caixia Li, Yunmei Du, Hao Ding, Hongwei Huang, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human&#8211;exoskeleton interaction portrait</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12984-024-01447-1</link>
      <description>Mohammad Shushtari, Julia Foellmer, Arash Arami, Journal of NeuroEngineering and Rehabilitation. 21(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402240792

                Abstract Human&#8211;robot physical interaction contains crucial information for optimizing user experience, enhancing robot performance, and objectively assessing user adaptation. This study introduces a new method to evaluate human&#8211;robot interaction and co-adaptation in lower limb exoskeletons by analyzing muscle activity and interaction torque as a two-dimensional random variable. We introduce the interaction portrait (IP), which visualizes this variable&#8217;s distribution in polar coordinates. We applied IP to compare a recently developed hybrid torque controller (HTC) based on kinematic state feedback and a novel adaptive model-based torque controller (AMTC) with online learning, proposed herein, against a time-based controller (TBC) during treadmill walking at varying speeds. Compared to TBC, both HTC and AMTC significantly lower users&#8217; normalized oxygen uptake, suggesting enhanced user-exoskeleton coordination. IP analysis reveals that this improvement stems from two distinct co-adaptation strategies, unidentifiable by traditional muscle activity or interaction torque analyses alone. HTC encourages users to yield control to the exoskeleton, decreasing overall muscular effort but increasing interaction torque, as the exoskeleton compensates for user dynamics. Conversely, AMTC promotes user engagement through increased muscular effort and reduces interaction torques, aligning it more closely with rehabilitation and gait training applications. IP phase evolution provides insight into each user&#8217;s interaction strategy formation, showcasing IP analysis&#8217;s potential in comparing and designing novel controllers to optimize human&#8211;robot interaction in wearable robots.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Shushtari, Julia Foellmer, Arash Arami</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12984-024-01447-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Edge Defects and Graphitization in a Pt&#8211;Fe/Carbon Electrocatalyst for High&#8208;Power&#8208;Density and Durable Flow Seawater&#8208;Al/Acid Hybrid Fuel Cells and Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202308923</link>
      <description>Hao Li, Mengtian Zhang, Mi Wang, Ming&#8208;Hao Du, Zijian Wang, Yongxing Zou, Guangxing Pan, Jiaheng Zhang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402322672

                Abstract Overcoming the trade&#8208;off between the graphitization of the carbon substrate and enhanced electronic metal&#8211;support interaction (EMSI) and intrinsic activity of Pt&#8208;C catalysts remains a major challenge for ensuring the durable operation of energy conversion devices. This article presents a hybrid catalyst consisting of PtFe nanoparticles and single Pt and Fe atoms supported on N&#8208;doped carbon (PtFe NPs @PtFe SAs &#8208;N&#8208;C), which exhibits improved activities in hydrogen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions (HER and ORR, respectively) and has excellent durability owing to the high graphitization, rich edge defects, and porosity of the carbon in PtFe NPs @PtFe SAs &#8208;N&#8208;C, as well as strong EMSI between the PtFe nanoparticles and edge&#8208;defective carbon embedded with Pt and Fe atoms. According to theoretical calculations, the strong EMSI optimizes the H* adsorption&#8211;desorption and facilitates the adsorption OOH*, accelerating the HER and ORR processes. A novel flow seawater&#8208;Al/acid hybrid fuel cell using the PtFe NPs @PtFe SAs &#8208;N&#8208;C cathode can serve as a high&#8208;efficiency energy conversion device that delivers a high power density of 109.5 mW cm &#8722;2 while producing H 2 at a significantly high rate of 271.6 L m &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 . Moreover, PtFe NPs @PtFe SAs &#8208;N&#8208;C exhibits a remarkable performance (high power density of 298.0 mW cm &#8722;2 and long&#8208;term durability of 1000 h) in a flow Zn&#8211;air battery.</description>
      <author>Hao Li, Mengtian Zhang, Mi Wang, Ming&#8208;Hao Du, Zijian Wang, Yongxing Zou, Guangxing Pan, Jiaheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202308923</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Fluid Evolution in the Skarn Stages of the Baoshan Skarn Cu-Polymetallic Deposit, South China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min14090907</link>
      <description>Ping Zheng, Ke Chen, Junke Zhang, Zhongfa Liu, Yongshun Li, Mingpeng He, Minerals. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402279431

                Baoshan is a world-class skarn Cu-polymetallic deposit located at the junction of the Nanling and Qin-Hang metallogenic belts in China. While there has been extensive research on the mineralogy and geochemistry of skarn deposits, studies on the fluid characteristics and evolutionary history from the early to late skarn stages in such deposits are still limited. In this study, we analyzed garnet and pyroxene from the early skarn stage and scheelite from the late skarn stage of the Baoshan deposit. We distinguished two generations of garnet (Grt1 and Grt2), one generation of pyroxene, and three generations of scheelite (Sch I, Sch II, and Sch III) on the basis of mineral assemblages and microscopic characteristics. Grt1 appears coarse-grained, and Grt2 cuts through Grt1 as veinlets. In Grt1, the andradite end-member increases from the core to the rim, while the grossular portion decreases (Ad35&#8211;36Gr59&#8211;61Sp3&#8211;4 to Ad59&#8211;61Gr36&#8211;37Sp2&#8211;3), and in Grt2, the andradite end-member significantly increases (Ad41&#8211;73Gr25&#8211;55Sp2&#8211;3). Grt1 and Grt2 have similar trace element compositions, with enrichment in Zr and depletion in Nb and Hf, depletion in LREE, enrichment in HREE, and weak negative Eu anomalies. Pyroxene coexists with Grt1 and is similarly cut by Grt2, with its composition mainly being diopside (Di82&#8211;99Hd0.6&#8211;15Jo0&#8211;3.2). Sch I and Sch II appear as anhedral to subhedral grains, while Sch III is predominantly found in veinlets. In Sch I and Sch II, most REEs enter the scheelite lattice via the Na-REE coupled substitution mechanism, with a smaller portion substituting Ca vacancies. In Sch III, the substitution mechanism involving Ca site vacancies may dominate. During the early skarn stage, the oxygen fugacity of the fluid gradually decreased from Grt1 and pyroxene to Grt2. In the late skarn stage, fluid oxygen fugacity remains stable from Sch I and Sch II to Sch III in shallow parts but significantly decreases in deeper parts. The garnet and pyroxene from the Baoshan deposit align with typical skarn Cu deposit compositions, while scheelite in the late skarn stage shows Sch I, Sch II, and shallow Sch III as skarn-type and deep Sch III as vein-type scheelite. Early skarn stage fluids were weakly acidic. Sch I, Sch II, and Sch III originated from fluids related to the Baoshan granite porphyry, with Sch III also showing evidence of water&#8211;rock interaction. This study reconstructed the fluid evolution history from the early to late skarn stages at the Baoshan deposit, providing insights into the ore-forming processes of other skarn deposits.</description>
      <author>Ping Zheng, Ke Chen, Junke Zhang, Zhongfa Liu, Yongshun Li, Mingpeng He</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min14090907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetic modelling of UVC and UVC/H2O2 oxidation of an aqueous mixture of antibiotics in a completely mixed batch photoreactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-34812-7</link>
      <description>Fernando J. Beltr&#225;n, Ana M. Ch&#225;vez, M.A. Jim&#233;nez-L&#243;pez, Pedro M. &#193;lvarez, Environmental Science and Pollution Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402168631

                Abstract The removal kinetics of an aqueous mixture of thirteen antibiotics (i.e., ampicillin, cefuroxime, ciprofloxacin, flumequine, metronidazole, ofloxacin, oxytetracycline, sulfadimethoxine, sulfamethoxazole, sulfamethazine, tetracycline, trimethoprim and tylosin) by batch UV C and UV C /H 2 O 2 processes has been modeled in this work. First, molar absorption coefficients (&#949;), direct quantum yields (&#934;) and the rate constants of the reaction of antibiotics with hydroxyl radical (k HO&#8226; ) (model inputs) were determined for each antibiotic and compared with literature data. The values of these parameters range from 0.3 to 21.8 mM &#8722;1 cm &#8722;1 for &#949;, &lt; 0.01 to 67.8 mmol&#183;E &#8722;1 for &#934; and 3.8 &#215; 10 9 to 1.7 &#215; 10 10 M &#8722;1 s &#8722;1 for k HO&#8226; . Second, a regression model was developed to compute the rate constants of the reactions of the antibiotics with singlet oxygen (k 1 O&#8322; ) from experimental data obtained in batch UV C experiments treating a mixture of the antibiotics. k 1 O&#8322; values in the 1&#8211;50 &#215; 10 6 M &#8722;1 s &#8722;1 range were obtained for the antibiotics studied. Finally, a semi-empirical kinetic model comprising a set of ordinary differential equations was solved to simulate the evolution of the residual concentration of antibiotics and hydrogen peroxide (model outputs) in a completely mixed batch photoreactor. Model predictions were reasonably consistent with the experimental data. The kinetic model developed might be combined with computational fluid dynamics to predict process performance and energy consumption in UV C and UV C /H 2 O 2 applications at full scale.</description>
      <author>Fernando J. Beltr&#225;n, Ana M. Ch&#225;vez, M.A. Jim&#233;nez-L&#243;pez, Pedro M. &#193;lvarez</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11356-024-34812-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factors Associated With the Intubation of Patients With Acute Respiratory Failure and Their Impact on Mortality: a Retrospective Cohort Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4768432/v1</link>
      <description>F&#225;bio Barlem Hohmann, Thais Dias Midega, Ricardo Esper Treml, Vin&#237;cius Barbosa Galindo, G Veiga, Isla R.M. Machado, Manfred Kraft, Sandra Cust&#243;dio, E Paolinelli, Felipe Galdino, Jo&#227;o Manoel Silva, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402171003

                Abstract Introduction: Severe respiratory failure often requires intubation and invasive mechanical ventilation. Identifying the factors that lead to this need is crucial, but there are few studies on the evolution of these factors from the onset of symptoms to respiratory failure. This study aims to identify risk factors for invasive mechanical ventilation as well as clinical outcomes in patients with acute respiratory failure considering the time from the onset of symptoms to respiratory failure. Methods Retrospective cohort study with patients hospitalized between May 1, 2020 and May 1, 2021. Patients over 18 years of age admitted to Intermediate and Intensive Care Units with positive polymerase chain reaction for SARS-CoV-2, chest computed tomography and inflammatory markers performed within 72 hours of admission were included. Patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease using home oxygen, intubation not related to Covid-19, heart failure, previous tracheostomy and hospitalization of less than 24 hours were excluded. The main outcome was to identify the factors that determined tracheal intubation and the evolution of these patients. Results Of the 852 patients treated, 302 were excluded, leaving 550, of which 346 required intubation. Intubated patients had a higher body mass index (p = 0.02), a higher SAPS-3 (p &lt; 0.001) and a shorter time from symptom onset to hospitalization (p &lt; 0.001). Until the eighth day of hospitalization, these patients had higher levels of C-Reactive Protein (p &lt; 0.001), Interleukin-6 (p = 0.003) and D-dimer (p &lt; 0.001). Chest computed tomography scans revealed a larger area of &#8203;&#8203;lung injury since admission. In the Cox model, SAPS-3 (HR = 1.028, 95%CI 1.002&#8211;1.055, p = 0.038) and time to intubation (HR = 1.118, 95%CI 1.021&#8211;1.224, p = 0.016) were independent risk factors for mortality. Patients intubated 15 days after the onset of symptoms had a higher risk of mortality (OR = 2.13, 95% CI 1.07&#8211;4.23). At intubation, the average respiratory rate was 27.5 breaths per minute, with 85% of FiO2 and ROX index of 4.37. The use of non-invasive ventilatory support was longer in the quartile with more than 15 days until intubation (median of 5 [3&#8211;7] days) and the use of a high-flow nasal cannula was associated with a longer time to decide to intubate (p = 0.002). Conclusion In patients with Covid-19 and acute respiratory failure, later intubation was associated with higher mortality. Non-invasive ventilatory support strategies can be used as long as there is no delay in using an invasive strategy when necessary.</description>
      <author>F&#225;bio Barlem Hohmann, Thais Dias Midega, Ricardo Esper Treml, Vin&#237;cius Barbosa Galindo, G Veiga, Isla R.M. Machado, Manfred Kraft, Sandra Cust&#243;dio, E Paolinelli, Felipe Galdino, Jo&#227;o Manoel Silva</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4768432/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstract PR006: Liquid biopsy enables identification of mechanisms of tumor evolution in patients with newly diagnosed high-risk neuroblastoma: A report from the Children&#8217;s Oncology Group</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1158/1538-7445.pediatric24-pr006</link>
      <description>Gabriela Virdzekova, Kelly S. Klega, Kenneth J Boss, Patrick Reynolds, Arlene Naranjo, Elaine R. Mardis, Trevor J. Pugh, Mark A. Applebaum, Rochelle Bagatell, Gad Getz, Steven DuBoi, Brian Cromtpon, Cancer Research. 84(17_Supplement)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402266427

                Abstract Background: Neuroblastoma is the most common extracranial solid tumor diagnosed in children. Outcomes for high-risk neuroblastoma (HR-NB) have improved but causes of treatment-refractory disease and relapse are poorly understood. ANBL1531 is a Children&#8217;s Oncology Group phase 3 study that enrolled over 700 patients with HR-NB. Longitudinal liquid biopsy samples were collected to identify prognostic biomarkers and study patterns of tumor evolution that contribute to treatment resistance. Assessment of circulating tumor DNA (ctDNA) allows for non-invasive serial sequencing of the tumor genome using peripheral blood samples. We describe sequencing approaches and the progress of this ongoing work. Methods: Serial plasma samples were submitted to the Crompton lab for cell-free DNA sequencing by ultra-low passage whole genome sequencing (ULP-WGS) to estimate ctDNA content. To date, the Crompton lab has received 2,184 serial plasma samples. Samples with detectable ctDNA were also sequenced by whole-exome sequencing and a pan-cancer panel targeting 400 genes. We have performed deep pan-cancer panel sequencing on 188 longitudinal blood samples collected from 71 patients. Matched germline and primary tumor sequencing data are available for 56 and 49 of these patients, respectively. Paired baseline and relapse plasma samples with ctDNA &amp;gt; 20% were also sequenced by whole genome sequencing to detect relapse-specific changes in nucleosome positioning. Results: ULP-WGS showed that 332/335 patients (99.1%) with a pre-treatment blood sample had detectable ctDNA ranging between 3-99% of total cell-free DNA. ctDNA remained detectable in 84%, 37%, 27%, 3.1%, 2.9% and 0.7% of cases at pre-induction and pre-cycle 2, 3, 4, end-induction, prior to post-consolidation therapy, and end post-consolidation respectively. Paired analysis of sequencing data revealed heterogeneity in the somatic variants detected between primary tumor and ctDNA samples. Five out of 47 patients assigned to a treatment arm for patients with ALK wild-type HR-NB with available tumor and pre-treatment ctDNA sequencing data had somatic mutations in the ALK gene, however, 3 of these mutations were only detectable in ctDNA. We also detected recurrent mutations in RAS/RAF pathway, DNA damage repair pathway, and NOTCH pathway genes. Signature analysis of pre-treatment and relapse samples revealed presence of mismatch repair deficiency and reactive oxygen species signatures. Using nucleosome positioning we detected recurrent changes in the activity of specific transcription factor programs in relapse samples. Functional validation of prioritized relapse-specific ctDNA variants is ongoing and will also be reported. Conclusions: In summary, this research project bridges critical gaps in understanding the primary resistance mechanisms of HR-NB by employing a non-invasive methodology and comprehensive analysis of genomic and translational contributors to tumor evolution. These data provide an opportunity for the discovery of new therapeutic targets that could improve the outcome for patients with HR-NB. Citation Format: Gabriela Virdzekova, Kelly Klega, Kristopher Boss, Patrick Reynolds, Arlene Naranjo, Elaine Mardis, Trevor Pugh, Mark Applebaum, Rochelle Bagatell, Gad Getz, Steven DuBoi, Brian Cromtpon. Liquid biopsy enables identification of mechanisms of tumor evolution in patients with newly diagnosed high-risk neuroblastoma: A report from the Children&#8217;s Oncology Group [abstract]. In: Proceedings of the AACR Special Conference in Cancer Research: Advances in Pediatric Cancer Research; 2024 Sep 5-8; Toronto, Ontario, Canada. Philadelphia (PA): AACR; Cancer Res 2024;84(17 Suppl):Abstract nr PR006.</description>
      <author>Gabriela Virdzekova, Kelly S. Klega, Kenneth J Boss, Patrick Reynolds, Arlene Naranjo, Elaine R. Mardis, Trevor J. Pugh, Mark A. Applebaum, Rochelle Bagatell, Gad Getz, Steven DuBoi, Brian Cromtpon</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1158/1538-7445.pediatric24-pr006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2838/1/011001</link>
      <description>, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2838(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402357804

                With the rapid progress of science and technology, the research and application in the fields of energy technology and materials science are increasingly in-depth, and experts and scholars around the world are committed to promoting the innovation and development in these areas. It is against this background that we welcomed the highly anticipated 2024 8 th International Conference on Energy Technology and Materials Science (ICETMS 2024). The conference was successfully held in Chongqing, China from May 31 st to June 2 nd , 2024, attracting the participation of almost 100 scholars, researchers and industry experts from all over the world. The convening of this conference has benefited from the active participation and enthusiastic support of experts and scholars around the world. We received a large number of high-quality paper submissions, covering New and Renewable Energy Technologies, Traditional Energy Transformation and Cleaner Production, Energy Storage Technologies and Battery Materials, Energy Security and Sustainable Development, Energy System Simulation and Optimization, and many other aspects. After a rigorous review process, excellent papers from different countries and regions were finally accepted, which fully demonstrated the latest research results and innovative ideas in these domains. In the course of the conference, we invited well-known experts and scholars at home and abroad to give keynote speeches and reports, and their wonderful speeches provided valuable academic inspiration and reflection for the participants. Among these, with the research Industrial Fabrication of Electrocatalysts for Green Hydrogen Production , Prof Hui Pan (University of Macau, China) introduced the design, synthesis and possible industrial production of novel electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions (HER and OER). And his research demonstrated that multi-metal compound systems were catalytically active for OER and HER in electrochemical energy devices, which may find practical application in hydrogen-energy technologies. At the same time, we also organized a number of group discussions, providing participants with more in-depth communication and interaction opportunities. The successful holding of this conference not only promoted the academic exchanges and cooperation in the fields of energy technology and materials science, but also injected new vitality and impetus into the development of these domains. Finally, we would like to express our heartfelt thanks and high respect to all the experts and scholars who participated in this conference. At the same time, we would also like to thank the organizing committee for its hard work and selfless dedication, which has provided a strong guarantee for the success of the conference. We look forward to continuing to work with experts and scholars in the coming days to promote the development and progress of energy technology and materials science! List of Committee Member is available in this Pdf.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2838/1/011001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JOYS+: The link between the ice and gas of complex organic molecules. Comparing JWST and ALMA data of two low-mass protostars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450706</link>
      <description>Yuan Julian Chen, W. R. M. Rocha, E. F. van Dishoeck, M. L. van Gelder, P. Nazari, K. Slavicinska, Logan Francis, B. Tabone, Michael E. Ressler, Pamela Klaassen, H. Beuther, A. C. A. Boogert, C. Gieser, Patrick Kavanagh, G. Perotti, Valentin J. M. Le Gouellec, Liton Majumdar, M. G&#252;del, Thomas Henning, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402217635

                A rich inventory of complex organic molecules (COMs) has been observed in high abundances in the gas phase toward Class 0 protostars. It has been suggested that these molecules are formed in ices and sublimate in the warm inner envelope close to the protostar. However, only the most abundant COM, methanol ( CH3OH ), had been firmly detected in ices before the era of the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST). Now, it is possible to detect the interstellar ices of other COMs and constrain their ice column densities quantitatively. We aim to determine the column densities of several oxygen-bearing COMs (O-COMs) in both gas and ice for two low-mass protostellar sources, NGC 1333 IRAS 2A (hereafter IRAS 2A) and B1-c, as case studies in our JWST Observations of Young protoStars (JOYS+) program. By comparing the column density ratios with respect to CH3OH between both phases measured in the same sources, we can probe the evolution of COMs from ice to gas in the early stages of star formation. The column densities of COMs in gas and ice were derived by fitting the spectra observed by the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) and the JWST/Mid-InfraRed Instrument-Medium Resolution Spectroscopy (MIRI-MRS), respectively. The gas-phase emission lines were fit using local thermal equilibrium models, and the ice absorption bands were fit by matching the infrared spectra measured in laboratories. The column density ratios of four O-COMs ( CH3CHO C2H5OH CH3OCH3 and CH3OCHO ) with respect to CH3OH were compared between ice and gas in IRAS 2A and B1-c. We were able to fit the fingerprint range of COM ices between 6.8 and 8.8 $ m$ in the JWST/MIRI-MRS spectra of B1-c using similar components to the ones recently used for NGC 1333 IRAS 2A. We claim detection of CH4 OCN^- HCOO^- HCOOH CH3CHO C2H5OH CH3OCH3 CH3OCHO and CH3COCH3 in B1-c, and upper limits have been estimated for SO2 CH3COOH and CH3CN . The total abundance of O-COM ices is constrained to be 15&lt;!PCT!&gt; with respect to H2O ice, 80&lt;!PCT!&gt; of which is dominated by CH3OH . The comparison of O-COM ratios with respect to CH3OH between ice and gas shows two different cases. On the one hand, the column density ratios of CH3OCHO and CH3OCH3 match well between the two phases, which may be attributed to a direct inheritance from ice to gas or strong chemical links with CH3OH . On the other hand, the ice ratios of CH3CHO and C2H5OH with respect to CH3OH are higher than the gas ratios by 1--2 orders of magnitude. This difference can be explained by gas-phase reprocessing following sublimation, or different spatial distributions of COMs in the envelope, which is an observational effect resulting from ALMA and JWST tracing different components in a protostellar system. The firm detection of COM ices other than CH3OH is reported in another well-studied low-mass protostar, B1-c, following the recent detection in NGC 1333 IRAS 2A. The column density ratios of four O-COMs with respect to CH3OH show both similarities and differences between gas and ice. Although the straightforward explanations would be the direct inheritance from ice to gas and the gas-phase reprocessing, respectively, other possibilities such as different spatial distributions of molecules cannot be excluded.</description>
      <author>Yuan Julian Chen, W. R. M. Rocha, E. F. van Dishoeck, M. L. van Gelder, P. Nazari, K. Slavicinska, Logan Francis, B. Tabone, Michael E. Ressler, Pamela Klaassen, H. Beuther, A. C. A. Boogert, C. Gieser, Patrick Kavanagh, G. Perotti, Valentin J. M. Le Gouellec, Liton Majumdar, M. G&#252;del, Thomas Henning</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NANO-SIZED PARTICLES IN THE MINERAL RESOURCE EXPLOITATION: OBRAZOVANIE TRANSIT AND DEPOSITION IN THE EARTH'S ATMOSPHERE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25791/infizik.07.2018.088</link>
      <description>Sergei Vasil'evich Viktorov, &#1070;.&#1055;. &#1043;&#1040;&#1051;&#1063;&#1045;&#1053;&#1050;&#1054;, No host. None(7)] 2018. https://openalex.org/W4402231361

                &#1042; &#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1090;&#1100;&#1077; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085; &#1084;&#1077;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1084; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1074;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1086;&#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1086;&#1090;&#1073;&#1086;&#1081;&#1082;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074;&#1086;&#1074; &#1080; &#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1072; &#1090;&#1077;&#1086;&#1088;&#1077;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1072;&#1103; &#1080; &#1101;&#1082;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1072;&#1103; &#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1082;&#1072; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1072; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1090;&#1080;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;&#1099;&#1096;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1042;&#1042;. &#1056;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1091;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1075;&#1086;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1086;&#1084; &#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1085;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1074; &#1086;&#1073;&#1086;&#1079;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1077; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1095;&#1090;&#1080; &#1074;&#1089;&#1077;&#1093; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1103;&#1077;&#1084;&#1099;&#1093; &#1075;&#1077;&#1086;&#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1081;, &#1082;&#1072;&#1082; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1087;&#1086;&#1076;&#1079;&#1077;&#1084;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081;, &#1090;&#1072;&#1082; &#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1086;&#1090;&#1082;&#1088;&#1099;&#1090;&#1086;&#1081; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1082;&#1077; &#1088;&#1091;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1080; &#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1095;&#1072;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1091;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1084;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1078;&#1076;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1081;. &#1069;&#1090;&#1086;&#1090; &#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1073; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1091;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1096;&#1077;&#1083; &#1076;&#1083;&#1080;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1087;&#1091;&#1090;&#1100; &#1101;&#1074;&#1086;&#1083;&#1102;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1080; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1076;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080; &#1086;&#1073;&#1077;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085; &#1096;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1082;&#1080;&#1084; &#1085;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;, &#1095;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077; &#1074;&#1089;&#1077;&#1075;&#1086;, &#1101;&#1084;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1088;&#1077;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1081;, &#1082;&#1086;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1099;&#1077; &#1086;&#1073;&#1099;&#1095;&#1085;&#1086; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1099; &#1085;&#1072; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1099;&#1093; &#1092;&#1080;&#1079;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1080; &#1075;&#1077;&#1086;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1081;. &#1044;&#1086;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1088;&#1091;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086;&#1076;&#1093;&#1086;&#1076;&#1099; &#1082; &#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102; &#1087;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074; &#1086;&#1090;&#1073;&#1086;&#1081;&#1082;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077;&#1089;&#1091;&#1090; &#1074; &#1089;&#1077;&#1073;&#1077; &#1074;&#1085;&#1091;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1077;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1086;&#1088;&#1077;&#1095;&#1080;&#1077; &#1084;&#1077;&#1078;&#1076;&#1091; &#1086;&#1073;&#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1086;&#1073;&#1098;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084;&#1080; &#1079;&#1072;&#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080; &#1075;&#1077;&#1086;&#1084;&#1077;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1080; &#1080; &#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1073;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;&#1084;&#1080; &#1075;&#1077;&#1086;&#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1072;&#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1077;&#1081; &#1079;&#1086;&#1085; &#1087;&#1086;&#1075;&#1083;&#1086;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080;, &#1089; &#1086;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1085;&#1099;, &#1080; &#1089;&#1080;&#1084;&#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1084; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074;&#1077; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074; &#8211; &#1089; &#1076;&#1088;&#1091;&#1075;&#1086;&#1081;. &#1055;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1083;&#1086;&#1078;&#1077;&#1085;&#1072; &#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100; &#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1084;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1085;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1095;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1096;&#1080;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1081;&#1096;&#1080;&#1093; &#1042;&#1042;, &#1089;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1088;&#1078;&#1072;&#1097;&#1080;&#1093; &#1074; &#1089;&#1074;&#1086;&#1077;&#1084; &#1089;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1074;&#1077; &#1082;&#1086;&#1085;&#1076;&#1077;&#1085;&#1089;&#1080;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1082;&#1086;&#1084;&#1087;&#1086;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1099;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1099; &#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1091;&#1102;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1076;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1081;&#1096;&#1080;&#1093; &#1042;&#1042; &#1089;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1088;&#1078;&#1072;&#1097;&#1080;&#1093; &#1072;&#1083;&#1102;&#1084;&#1080;&#1085;&#1080;&#1081;, &#1072; &#1090;&#1072;&#1082;&#1078;&#1077; &#1042;&#1042;, &#1089;&#1086;&#1076;&#1077;&#1088;&#1078;&#1072;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1091;&#1075;&#1083;&#1077;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076; &#1080; &#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1080;&#1094;&#1072;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1082;&#1080;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1073;&#1072;&#1083;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1083;&#1091;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086; &#1072;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1077; &#1088;&#1077;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1079;&#1072;&#1076;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1096;&#1080;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;. &#1056;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1084;&#1086;&#1090;&#1088;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086; &#1080;&#1079;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1101;&#1092;&#1092;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1074;&#1086;&#1079;&#1084;&#1086;&#1078;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1080;&#1093; &#1080;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080;&#1079; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;. &#1055;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1103; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1072; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1076;&#1091;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1074; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1079;&#1072;&#1074;&#1080;&#1089;&#1080;&#1090; &#1086;&#1090; &#1089;&#1086;&#1086;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1074;&#1088;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1073;&#1086;&#1090;&#1099; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1080; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1074;&#1088;&#1077;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080; &#1074;&#1099;&#1083;&#1077;&#1090;&#1072; &#1075;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;. &#1060;&#1080;&#1079;&#1080;&#1082;&#1086;-&#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1086;&#1089;&#1086;&#1073;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1074;&#1088;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1077;&#1097;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1072; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1072; &#1084;&#1086;&#1075;&#1091;&#1090; &#1073;&#1099;&#1090;&#1100; &#1085;&#1077; &#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1077;&#1077; &#1079;&#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080;&#1084;&#1099;&#1084; &#1092;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1084;, &#1090;&#1072;&#1082; &#1082;&#1072;&#1082; &#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086; &#1086;&#1085;&#1080; &#1092;&#1086;&#1088;&#1084;&#1080;&#1088;&#1091;&#1102;&#1090; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1074; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074; &#1080; &#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1103;&#1102;&#1090; &#1093;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1082;&#1080; &#1085;&#1072;&#1095;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1089;&#1090;&#1072;&#1076;&#1080;&#1080; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1072; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1091;&#1096;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1090;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074;&#1072; &#1074; &#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1093; &#1094;&#1077;&#1083;&#1103;&#1093;. &#1042;&#1099;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1085;&#1072; &#1088;&#1091;&#1076;&#1085;&#1080;&#1082;&#1072;&#1093; &#1044;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1077;&#1075;&#1086; &#1042;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072; &#1101;&#1082;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1086;&#1079;&#1074;&#1086;&#1083;&#1080;&#1083;&#1080; &#1101;&#1084;&#1087;&#1080;&#1088;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080; &#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1090;&#1100; &#1079;&#1072;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1090;&#1099; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1084;&#1077;&#1088;&#1099; &#1079;&#1086;&#1085;&#1099; &#1073;&#1088;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1076;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1090;&#1080;&#1087;&#1086;&#1074; &#1042;&#1042; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1086;&#1090;&#1073;&#1086;&#1081;&#1082;&#1077; &#1078;&#1080;&#1083; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1088;&#1077;&#1079;&#1082;&#1072;&#1084;&#1080; &#1087;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1102;. &#1054;&#1094;&#1077;&#1085;&#1086;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1101;&#1082;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1080;&#1084;&#1077;&#1085;&#1090;&#1099; &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077;&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1080;&#1079;&#1074;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1090;&#1077;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1099;&#1081; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1093;&#1086;&#1076; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074; &#1079;&#1086;&#1085;&#1077; &#1073;&#1088;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1076;&#1077;&#1081;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1072; &#1085;&#1072;&#1093;&#1086;&#1076;&#1080;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1103;&#1084;&#1086;&#1081; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1087;&#1086;&#1088;&#1094;&#1080;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083;&#1100;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1089;&#1074;&#1103;&#1079;&#1080; &#1089;&#1086; &#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1100;&#1102; &#1076;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1085;&#1072;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1042;&#1042;. &#1041;&#1099;&#1083;&#1086; &#1090;&#1072;&#1082;&#1078;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1085;&#1072;&#1080;&#1073;&#1086;&#1083;&#1077;&#1077; &#1073;&#1083;&#1072;&#1075;&#1086;&#1087;&#1088;&#1080;&#1103;&#1090;&#1085;&#1086;&#1077; &#1087;&#1086; &#1091;&#1089;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1080;&#1103;&#1084; &#1086;&#1090;&#1073;&#1086;&#1081;&#1082;&#1080; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1077; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1077; &#1076;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1080;&#1075;&#1072;&#1077;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1080; &#1080;&#1089;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1100;&#1079;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1080; &#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1082;&#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1080;&#1079;&#1072;&#1085;&#1090;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; (&#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1089;&#1090;&#1077;&#1081;&#1096;&#1080;&#1093;) &#1042;&#1042; &#1089;&#1086; &#1089;&#1084;&#1077;&#1089;&#1077;&#1074;&#1099;&#1084; &#1084;&#1077;&#1093;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1079;&#1084;&#1086;&#1084; &#1088;&#1077;&#1072;&#1082;&#1094;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1075;&#1086; &#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1074;&#1088;&#1072;&#1097;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103;. &#1058;&#1072;&#1082;&#1080;&#1084; &#1086;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1086;&#1084;, &#1074;&#1099;&#1087;&#1086;&#1083;&#1085;&#1077;&#1085;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1080;&#1089;&#1089;&#1083;&#1077;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1072;&#1079;&#1072;&#1083;&#1080;, &#1095;&#1090;&#1086; &#1089;&#1091;&#1097;&#1077;&#1089;&#1090;&#1074;&#1091;&#1102;&#1097;&#1080;&#1077; &#1084;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1076;&#1099; &#1091;&#1087;&#1088;&#1072;&#1074;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1074;&#1079;&#1088;&#1099;&#1074;&#1086;&#1084; &#1074; &#1080;&#1085;&#1090;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1089;&#1072;&#1093; &#1075;&#1086;&#1088;&#1085;&#1099;&#1093; &#1090;&#1077;&#1093;&#1085;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1081; &#1086;&#1093;&#1074;&#1072;&#1090;&#1099;&#1074;&#1072;&#1102;&#1090; &#1074; &#1086;&#1089;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;&#1085;&#1086;&#1084; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1083;&#1080;&#1095;&#1085;&#1099;&#1077; &#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1077;&#1082;&#1090;&#1099; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1072; &#1074;&#1099;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1080; &#1087;&#1077;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1072;&#1095;&#1080; &#1074; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1079;&#1072;&#1088;&#1103;&#1076;&#1086;&#1074;. &#1055;&#1088;&#1080; &#1101;&#1090;&#1086;&#1084; &#1087;&#1088;&#1072;&#1082;&#1090;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080; &#1085;&#1077; &#1079;&#1072;&#1090;&#1088;&#1072;&#1075;&#1080;&#1074;&#1072;&#1102;&#1090;&#1089;&#1103; &#1087;&#1088;&#1086;&#1094;&#1077;&#1089;&#1089;&#1099; &#1088;&#1072;&#1089;&#1087;&#1088;&#1077;&#1076;&#1077;&#1083;&#1077;&#1085;&#1080;&#1103; &#1101;&#1090;&#1086;&#1081; &#1101;&#1085;&#1077;&#1088;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080; &#1074; &#1088;&#1072;&#1079;&#1088;&#1091;&#1096;&#1072;&#1077;&#1084;&#1086;&#1084; &#1084;&#1072;&#1089;&#1089;&#1080;&#1074;&#1077;. The article deals with the mechanism of development of energy processes during blasting off of rock massifs and gives a theoretical and experimental assessment of the nature of the explosion energy distribution using different types of industrial EXPLOSIVES. The destruction of rocks by explosion will remain in the foreseeable future the basis of almost all applied geotechnologies, both in the underground and in the open development of ore and a signifi cant part of non-metallic deposits. This method of destruction has gone a long way of evolution and is methodologically provided with a wide range of, most often, empirical solutions, which are usually based on the use of extremely simple physical and geometric models. The dominant approaches to the defi nition of the parameters of blasting are an internal contradiction between due to objective laws of geomechanics and geotechnology requirements of the asymmetry of the zones of energy absorption, on the one hand, and the symmetrical character of the distribution in the array of the explosion energy is concentrated charges on the other. The proposed model thermodynamic calculations of the work of expansion of the explosion products and cheap Explosives, containing in its composition of the condensed components. Such products are formed by detonation of the simplest BB containing aluminum, as well as BB containing carbon and having a negative oxygen balance. An analytical solution is obtained under a given condition of expansion of the charging cavity. The changes in the efficiency of explosion products with the possibility of their expiration from the charging cavity are considered. It is shown that the useful work of explosion products depends on the ratio of the characteristic time of the explosion and the characteristic time of departure of gases. Physico-chemical characteristics of the explosive transformation of the substance of the charge can be no less significant factor, since they form the conditions for the transfer of explosion energy to the array and determine the characteristics of the initial stage of the process of explosive destruction of this array in the technological purposes. Made on the mines of the Far East experimental study allowed us to empirically assess the cost of energy and the size of the zone of blasting action of the explosion of different types of explosives when blasting prirezkami lived along strike. Evaluation experiments showed that technologically unproductive consumption of energy in the blasting area of validity the charge is in direct proportional relationship with the speed of detonation. It was also shown that the most favorable energy distribution in the space under the conditions of rejection is achieved by using low-recoil (simplest) EXPLOSIVES with a mixed reaction mechanism of explosive transformation. Thus, studies have shown that the existing methods for managing the explosion in the interest of mining technologies cover mainly different aspects of the process of the release and transfer of energy charges to the array. At the same time, the processes of distribution of this energy in the destructible array are practically not affected.</description>
      <author>Sergei Vasil'evich Viktorov, &#1070;.&#1055;. &#1043;&#1040;&#1051;&#1063;&#1045;&#1053;&#1050;&#1054;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25791/infizik.07.2018.088</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
