<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 01:41:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>High-performance aqueous zinc-ion hybrid micro-supercapacitors enabled by oxygen-rich functionalised MXene nanofibres</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.038</link>
      <description>Yamin Feng, Weifeng Liu, Haineng Bai, Yan Zhang, Yunxiao Du, Yongqiang Liu, Long Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405133476

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yamin Feng, Weifeng Liu, Haineng Bai, Yan Zhang, Yunxiao Du, Yongqiang Liu, Long Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solution Process&#8211;Based Facile Flame&#8211;Boosted Low&#8208;Valence Transition Metal Doping on Pristine Oxide for Highly Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Solar Water Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sus2.253</link>
      <description>Seung Hun Roh, Eujin Kwak, Won Tae Hong, Chengkai Xia, Sungsoon Kim, Heeyeop Chae, Xu Yu, Wooseok Yang, Jong Wook Park, Jung Kyu Kim, SusMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405138127

                ABSTRACT As for the high sustainable solar hydrogen production via water splitting, transition metal doping on an oxide photoanode in photoelectrochemical (PEC) cells has been recognized as an effective approach. However, conventional thermal&#8208;diffusion&#8208;mediated doping strategies face the challenge of resolving sluggish catalytic kinetics for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and its practical utilization for the synthesis of photoanode films. Herein, we introduce facile ultrafast flame&#8208;boosted doping of Mo into a BiVO 4 (FL MoBVO) film for 20 s to achieve an efficient PEC OER. Mo elements in a low&#8208;valence state (i.e., Mo 6&#8722; &#948; ) and Mo 6+ are successfully doped into the photoanode, which manipulate the energy band structure, facilitating the downward shift of band edges and promoting the surface catalytic kinetics. Consequently, the flame&#8208;boosted Mo&#8208;doping results in superior PEC performance in a mild environment with neutral electrolyte without introducing any other additives or co&#8208;catalysts, where the photocurrent density at 1.23 V RHE under 1 sun illumination in pH 7 is outstandingly enhanced, over 9&#8208;fold higher than that of a pristine BiVO 4 . The flame&#8208;boosted doping induces significantly enhanced photoexcited charge transport and catalytic reaction kinetics performances simultaneously. Our report provides the effective strategy boosting both the thermodynamic and kinetic charge migration properties for sustainable materials.</description>
      <author>Seung Hun Roh, Eujin Kwak, Won Tae Hong, Chengkai Xia, Sungsoon Kim, Heeyeop Chae, Xu Yu, Wooseok Yang, Jong Wook Park, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sus2.253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction performance of flower-like CoHS @NCDs through in-situ coupling of Nitrogen-Doped carbon dots and cobalt hydroxide nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118858</link>
      <description>Yang Gao, Haiyan Qi, Tao Jing, Jun Li, Siqi Shen, Qingxin Zeng, Hongxu Zhao, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405143110

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Gao, Haiyan Qi, Tao Jing, Jun Li, Siqi Shen, Qingxin Zeng, Hongxu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co/CoO hetero-nanoparticles incorporated into lignin-derived carbon nanofibers as a self-supported bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.035</link>
      <description>Yali Wang, Ruihui Gan, Xiaodong Shao, Binting Dai, Lin Ma, Jinzheng Yang, Jingli Shi, Xiangwu Zhang, Chang Ma, Zhanshuang Jin, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 682(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405143239

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yali Wang, Ruihui Gan, Xiaodong Shao, Binting Dai, Lin Ma, Jinzheng Yang, Jingli Shi, Xiangwu Zhang, Chang Ma, Zhanshuang Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoS2@MWCNTs Core&#8211;shell Heterostructure for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115060</link>
      <description>Huu Thang Nguyen, Kyu Yeon Jang, Jin Goo Kim, Kimin Chae, Hye Bin Jung, MinJoong Kim, Chang&#8208;Soo Lee, Young&#8208;Woo Lee, Kyu&#8208;Nam Jung, Seung Woo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Hana Yoon, Younghyun Cho, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405165933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huu Thang Nguyen, Kyu Yeon Jang, Jin Goo Kim, Kimin Chae, Hye Bin Jung, MinJoong Kim, Chang&#8208;Soo Lee, Young&#8208;Woo Lee, Kyu&#8208;Nam Jung, Seung Woo Lee, Hyun&#8208;Seok Cho, Hana Yoon, Younghyun Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.115060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global-scale geo-evolutionary feedbacks: a tale by oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tree.2024.11.015</link>
      <description>Xin&#8208;Yi Chu, Hongyu Zhang, Trends in Ecology &amp; Evolution. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405171767

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin&#8208;Yi Chu, Hongyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tree.2024.11.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni-Co-O anodes for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction: Multistage electrode optimization and plasma-assisted activity enhancement enabled by a coherent workflow</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31224/4205</link>
      <description>Vineetha Vinayakumar, Thomas Wagner, Christian Marcks, Jacob Johny, Garlef Wartner, Marc F. Tesch, Ioannis Spanos, A. Ghafari, Adarsh Jain, Oleg Prymak, Ignacio Sanju&#225;n, Ahammed Suhail Odungat, Osama Anwar, Mohit Chatwani, A Rodriguez Jose, Vimanshu Chanda, Axel Knop&#8208;Gericke, Corina Andronescu, Anna K. Mechler, Nicolas W&#246;hrl, Doris Segets, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405171876

                Ni-Co-based oxides (Ni-Co-O) are promising oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts due to their adaptable structures, affordability, abundance, and strong electrochemical performance. While various studies explored the structure-activity relationships and OER mechanisms in these catalysts, comprehensive anode development requires a systematic workflow covering all stages of catalyst optimization. Here, we present an integrated approach for characterizing commercial Ni-Co-O nanomaterials using a combination of analytics during processing, in operando, and post-catalysis to gain insights into parameters influencing anode performance. Key findings include the critical impact of catalyst ink optimization through solvent matrix screening, enabling high-quality electrode layers via ultrasonic spray coating on Ni plates. These Ni-Co-O layers, tested as anodes in alkaline OER, were further enhanced by plasma post-processing, resulting in binder-free surfaces with increased porosity and wettability compared to untreated samples. Notably, plasma treatment also promoted a more redox reversible catalyst structure, improved Fe uptake efficiency, and led to a significantly enhanced OER activity by reducing the overpotential by ~43 mV at 100 mA/cm&#178; compared to untreated samples. Our study highlights the importance of a holistic evaluation approach, from catalyst powder to post-mortem analysis, that enabled us to discover how plasma post-processing can yield binder-free electrodes with superior electrochemical properties.</description>
      <author>Vineetha Vinayakumar, Thomas Wagner, Christian Marcks, Jacob Johny, Garlef Wartner, Marc F. Tesch, Ioannis Spanos, A. Ghafari, Adarsh Jain, Oleg Prymak, Ignacio Sanju&#225;n, Ahammed Suhail Odungat, Osama Anwar, Mohit Chatwani, A Rodriguez Jose, Vimanshu Chanda, Axel Knop&#8208;Gericke, Corina Andronescu, Anna K. Mechler, Nicolas W&#246;hrl, Doris Segets</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31224/4205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ construction of 2D &#946;-Co(OH)2 nanosheets hybridized with 1D N-doped carbon nanotubes as efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158437</link>
      <description>Xiaojin Yin, Wenhao Xi, Pan Wang, Tongchen Wu, Peide Liu, Bifen Gao, Yun Zheng, Bi&#8208;Zhou Lin, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405172982

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojin Yin, Wenhao Xi, Pan Wang, Tongchen Wu, Peide Liu, Bifen Gao, Yun Zheng, Bi&#8208;Zhou Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution reaction via CuO@N-doped carbon nanostructures: a facile synthesis and electrocatalytic investigation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11164-024-05465-5</link>
      <description>Sahariya Priya, Prarthana Srivastava, Gollapalli Veera Satya Srinivas, Sudipta Banerjee, Amanullah Fatehmulla, A. Haldar, Research on Chemical Intermediates. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405173425

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sahariya Priya, Prarthana Srivastava, Gollapalli Veera Satya Srinivas, Sudipta Banerjee, Amanullah Fatehmulla, A. Haldar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11164-024-05465-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multitasking-Effect Ca Ions Triggered Symmetry-Breaking of RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Coordination for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c05139</link>
      <description>Xu Zou, Zhenyu Li, Qing Liang, Fuxi Liu, Tiantian Xu, Kexin Song, Jiang Zhou, Wei Zhang, Weitao Zheng, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405186134

                The development of highly active and stable electrocatalysts for the acid oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is both appealing and challenging. The generation of defects is an emerging strategy for improving the water oxidation efficiency. Herein, we introduced multitasking Ca ions to trigger oxygen vacancies in RuO</description>
      <author>Xu Zou, Zhenyu Li, Qing Liang, Fuxi Liu, Tiantian Xu, Kexin Song, Jiang Zhou, Wei Zhang, Weitao Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c05139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallic ruthenium and ruthenium oxide heterojunctions boost acidic oxygen evolution reaction activity and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145442</link>
      <description>Felix Kwofie, Zhenjiang He, Weifeng Zeng, Mai Gao, Yang Li, Junsong Zhang, Yunjiao Li, Yinong Liu, Quentin Meyer, Anjun Hu, Yi&#8208;Bing Cheng, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405188128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Felix Kwofie, Zhenjiang He, Weifeng Zeng, Mai Gao, Yang Li, Junsong Zhang, Yunjiao Li, Yinong Liu, Quentin Meyer, Anjun Hu, Yi&#8208;Bing Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar&#8208;Driven Hydrogen Peroxide Production via BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Based Photocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407801</link>
      <description>Hui Ling Tan, Casandra Hui Teng Chai, Jerry Zhi Xiong Heng, Quyen Vu Thi, Xuelian Wu, Yun Hau Ng, Enyi Ye, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405199814

                Abstract Solar hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) production has garnered increased research interest owing to its safety, cost&#8208;effectiveness, environmental friendliness, and sustainability. The synthesis of H 2 O 2 relies mainly on renewable resources such as water, oxygen, and solar energy, resulting in minimal waste. Bismuth vanadate (BiVO 4 ) stands out among various oxide semiconductors for selective H 2 O 2 production under visible light via direct two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and two&#8208;electron water oxidation reaction (WOR) pathways. Significant advancements have been achieved using BiVO 4 &#8208;based materials in solar H 2 O 2 production over the last decade. This review explores advancements in BiVO 4 &#8208;based photocatalysts for H 2 O 2 production, focusing on photocatalytic powder suspension (PS) and photoelectrochemical (PEC) systems, representing the main approaches for heterogenous artificial photosynthesis. An overview of fundamental principles, performance assessment methodologies, photocatalyst and photoelectrode development, and optimization of reaction conditions is provided. While diverse strategies, such as heterojunction, doping, crystal facet engineering, cocatalyst loading, and surface passivation, have proven effective in enhancing H 2 O 2 generation, this review offers insights into their similar and distinct implementations within the PS and PEC systems. The challenges and future prospects in this field are also discussed to facilitate the rational design of high&#8208;performing BiVO 4 &#8208;based photocatalysts and photoelectrodes for H 2 O 2 generation under visible light.</description>
      <author>Hui Ling Tan, Casandra Hui Teng Chai, Jerry Zhi Xiong Heng, Quyen Vu Thi, Xuelian Wu, Yun Hau Ng, Enyi Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Redeposition Over Bidirectional Amorphous NiFe&#8208;Oxides toward Surface Self&#8208;Healing for the Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409374</link>
      <description>Tingxi Zhou, Yike Jing, Jing Wang, Fei Yang, Xuesong Yi, Wei Sun, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405200567

                Abstract The NiFe&#8208;oxy/hydroxides (NiFeO x H y ) have emerged as promising candidates for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) but suffer from irreversible metal dissolution to pose a great challenge to long&#8208;term stability. Here, a self&#8208;supported electrode of NiFeO x H y /FeNiO x /SS&#8208;A (substrate&#8208;etched stainless steel, SS&#8208;A; interlayer&#8208;amorphous Fe 3 Ni 1 O x oxide; catalytic layer&#8208;amorphous Ni 3 Fe 1 O x H y ) is fabricated and presents rare self&#8208;healing property of surface cracks, as well excellent activity and stability. It is found that crack repair is driven by the redeposition of dissolved Fe and Ni ions from the amorphous interlayer involved in the OER process because no similar behavior is observed in Fe&#8208;free and crystalline interlayer&#8208;supported NiFeO x H y . Moreover, the repair performance is dependent on current density and electrolysis time, with 71% of surface cracks being repaired after 72 h operated on an industrial level of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . It needs to be emphasized that the irreversible dissolution of Fe and Ni from the catalytic layer of NiFeO x H y still occurs but is effectively suppressed. It is demonstrated that the construction of an amorphous FeNiO x oxide interlayer in self&#8208;supported electrodes plays an important role in improving the stability and is expected to open up an opportunity for the design and develop highly efficient and durable alkaline OER catalytic electrodes.</description>
      <author>Tingxi Zhou, Yike Jing, Jing Wang, Fei Yang, Xuesong Yi, Wei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice modulation strategy toward efficient and durable &lt;scp&gt;RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;based catalysts for acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18665</link>
      <description>Linkai Han, Zhonghua Xiang, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405201017

                Abstract Rutile RuO 2 is recognized for its outstanding acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and notable cost advantage compared to iridium oxide for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). However, the unsatisfactory stability of RuO 2 hinders its practical application. Here, we report a lattice modulation strategy to enhance both the OER activity and stability of RuO 2 . Interestingly, the newly synthesized Mo 0.15 Nb 0.05 &#8208;RuO 2 , with Mo doped first and then Nb, presents the greatest lattice spacing and possesses an overpotential of merely 205 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , which significantly outperforms Nb 0.05 Mo 0.15 &#8208;RuO 2 (239 mV), where Nb was doped first followed by Mo, as well as the initial RuO 2 (323 mV). Remarkably, Mo 0.15 Nb 0.05 &#8208;RuO 2 requires only 1.76 V to achieve 1 A cm &#8722;2 and exhibits exceptional stability in PEMWE testing, with a voltage rise of only 58 mV at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 for more than 80 h.</description>
      <author>Linkai Han, Zhonghua Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise modulation of electron spin states in metal-organic framework towards exceptional oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5541146/v1</link>
      <description>Minghua Huang, Xianbiao Hou, Tengjia Ni, Zhaozheng Zhang, Zhou Jian, Shucong Zhang, Shuixing Dai, Lei Chu, Huanlei Wang, Bolong Huang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405201185

                Abstract Spin configuration and coordination environment changes have emerged as promising strategies to boost the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. However, achieving the precise and gradual regulation of both spin states and coordination environment to elucidate the structure-activity relationship remains a key priority and is rarely reported. In this work, we successfully induce the gradual transition of spin states of Fe sites from low spin state to a medium spin state and ultimately to high spin state by meticulously adjusting coordination environment within NiFe-MOF, while the Ni sites still keep a low spin state. Experimental and theoretical calculations confirm the precise regulation of spin polarization and electrons migration from the Fe-t2g to the Fe-eg orbitals with a reduced coordination saturation, which optimizes the spin orbital exchange interactions between Fe and Ni ions and facilitates adsorption of reaction intermediates. The NiFe-MOF-D3 with unique NiO6-FeO4 geometric structure exhibits low overpotential of 328 mV@1 A cm-2 and 365 mV@1.5 A cm-2 in alkaline medium. Furthermore, the assembled alkaline electrolyzer also presents remarkable activity (1.77 V@500 mA cm-2) and lower cost ($ 0.94) than the target of U.S. Department of Energy ($ 2.00).</description>
      <author>Minghua Huang, Xianbiao Hou, Tengjia Ni, Zhaozheng Zhang, Zhou Jian, Shucong Zhang, Shuixing Dai, Lei Chu, Huanlei Wang, Bolong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5541146/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuBP Microparticle Clusters (MPCs) as a Stable and Efficient Electrocatalyst for High&#8208;Current&#8208;Density Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400645</link>
      <description>Shusen Lin, Rutuja Mandavkar, Md Ahasan Habib, Mehedi Hasan Joni, Sumiya Akter Dristy, Shalmali Burse, Jihoon Lee, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405201670

                Abstract Developing stable and cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts for electrochemical water splitting is essential for advancing sustainable hydrogen production. In this work, CuBP microparticle clusters (MPCs) electrocatalyst is demonstrated on a Ni foam substrate, fabricated by using a one&#8208;pot hydrothermal approach followed by post&#8208;annealing treatment. The optimized CuBP electrode exhibits impressive activities for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), showing overpotentials of 49 and 220 mV at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH, which are comparable to benchmark Pt/C and RuO 2 electrodes. The bifunctional CuBP achieves a cell voltage of 1.52 V at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 , outperforming the Pt/C||RuO 2 systems and also demonstrating excellent stability over 120&#8208;h operations. At 2000 mA cm &#8722;2 , a voltage of 3.12 V is required in CuBP||CuBP configuration whereas the hybrid Pt/C||RuO 2 design exhibits a significantly lower cell voltage of 2.25 V at 2000 mA cm &#8722;2 . The superior catalytic behavior of the CuBP electrode can be attributed to the high active surface area due to the micro&#8208;particle topology, the optimal balance of Cu, B, and P, and the enhanced conductivity achieved through vacuum annealing. Overall, the CuBP electrode is highly efficient and has significant potential to replace traditional RuO&#8322; electrodes.</description>
      <author>Shusen Lin, Rutuja Mandavkar, Md Ahasan Habib, Mehedi Hasan Joni, Sumiya Akter Dristy, Shalmali Burse, Jihoon Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thin Nickel Coatings on Stainless Steel for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution and Reduced Iron Leaching in Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/elsa.202400023</link>
      <description>Yashwardhan Deo, Niklas Thissen, Vera Seidl, Julia Gallenberger, Julia Hoffmann, Jan P. Hofmann, Bastian J. M. Etzold, Anna K. Mechler, Electrochemical Science Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405202960

                ABSTRACT One of the most mature technologies for green hydrogen production is alkaline water electrolysis. However, this process is kinetically limited by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Improving the OER kinetics requires electrocatalysts, which can offer superior catalytic activity and stability in alkaline environments. Stainless steel (SS) has been reported as a cost&#8208;effective and promising OER electrode due to its ability to form active Ni&#8208;Fe oxyhydroxides during OER. However, it is limited by a high Fe&#8208;to&#8208;Ni ratio, leading to severe Fe&#8208;leaching in alkaline environments. This affects not only the electrode activity and stability but can also be detrimental to the electrolyzer system. Therefore, we investigate the effect of different Ni&#8208;coatings on both pure Ni&#8208; and SS&#8208;supports on the OER activity, while monitoring the extent of Fe&#8208;leaching during continuous operation. We show that thin layers of Ni enable enhanced OER activities compared to thicker ones. Especially, a less than 1 &#181;m thick Ni layer on an SS&#8208;support shows superior OER activity and stability with respect to the bare supports. X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy reveals traces of oxidized Fe species on the catalyst surface after OER, suggesting that Fe from the SS may be incorporated into the layer during operation, forming active Ni&#8208;Fe oxyhydroxides with a very low Fe leaching rate. Utilizing inductively coupled plasma&#8208;optical emission spectroscopy, we prove that thin Ni layers on SS decrease Fe leaching whereas the Fe from the uncoated SS&#8208;support dissolves into the electrolyte during operation. Thus, OER active and stable electrodes can be obtained while maintaining a low Fe concentration in the electrolyte. This is particularly relevant for application in high&#8208;performance electrolyzer systems.</description>
      <author>Yashwardhan Deo, Niklas Thissen, Vera Seidl, Julia Gallenberger, Julia Hoffmann, Jan P. Hofmann, Bastian J. M. Etzold, Anna K. Mechler</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/elsa.202400023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An efficient CoSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Ag hybrid catalyst for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819805365_0009</link>
      <description>Qichen Liang, Nana Du, Huajie Xu, Deleted Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405203926

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qichen Liang, Nana Du, Huajie Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1142/9789819805365_0009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of In Situ and Postsynthetic Formation of MOF-Carbon Composites as Electrocatalysts for the Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202412.0685.v1</link>
      <description>Linda Sondermann, Laura Maria Voggenauer, Annette Vollrath, Till Strothmann, Christoph Janiak, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405204241

                Mixed-metal nickel-iron, NixFe materials draw attention as affordable earth-abundant electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here nickel and mixed-metal nickel-iron metal-organic framework (MOF) composites with the carbon materials ketjenblack (KB) or carbon nanotubes (CNT) were synthesized in situ in a one-pot solvothermal reaction. As a direct comparison to these in situ synthesized composites, the neat MOFs were postsynthetically mixed by grinding with KB or CNT, to generate physical mixture composites. The in situ and postsynthetic MOF/carbon samples were comparatively tested as (pre-)catalysts for the OER and most of them outperformed the RuO2 benchmark. Depending on the carbon material and metal ratio the in situ or postsynthethic composites performed better, showing that the method to generate the composite can influence the OER activity. The best material Ni5Fe-CNT was synthesized in situ and achieved an overpotential (&#951;) of 301 mV (RuO2 &#951; = 354 mV), a Tafel slope (b) of 58 mV/dec (RuO2 b = 91 mV/dec), a charge transfer resistance (Rct) of 7 &#8486; (RuO2 Rct= 39 &#8486;) and a faradaic efficiency (FE) of 95% (RuO2 FE = 91%). Structural changes in the materials could be seen through a stability test in the alkaline electrolyte and chronopotentiometry over 12 h showed that the derived electrocatalysts and RuO2 have a good stability.</description>
      <author>Linda Sondermann, Laura Maria Voggenauer, Annette Vollrath, Till Strothmann, Christoph Janiak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202412.0685.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Semi&#8208;coherent Interface and Vacancy Engineering for Constructing NiTe/FeTe/Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/FF to Boost Electrochemical Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407721</link>
      <description>Chunxiao Li, Yuying Feng, Jiahui Jiang, Ting Zhao, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Li Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405208363

                Abstract Transition metal&#8208;based tellurides (TMTs) with excellent electrical conductivity are expected to be ideal electrocatalysts for overall water splitting. However, compared to transition metal sulfides and selenides, the reported applications of TMTs in overall water splitting are fewer. Herein, the NiTe/FeTe/Fe 3 O 4 /FF carnation flower&#8208;like with a semi&#8208;coherent interface is successfully constructed to enhance the electrochemical overall water splitting performance. Specifically, it achieves low overpotentials of 54 and 176 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively. What's more, the electrolyzer requires a cell voltage of 1.5 V to sustain a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and maintains remarkable stability for an extensive duration of 450 h even at a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Semi&#8208;coherent interface engineering and vacancy engineering not only improve the OH&#8315; adsorption capacity of catalysts but also promote the desorption of adsorbed hydrogen (H ads ). In situ Raman spectroscopy reveals that FeOOH and NiOOH formed by NiTe/FeTe/Fe 3 O 4 /FF during the OER are the genuine active sites. This study provides a promising approach for the electrochemical water splitting of TMTs by combining semi&#8208;coherent interface engineering and vacancy engineering.</description>
      <author>Chunxiao Li, Yuying Feng, Jiahui Jiang, Ting Zhao, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolated &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;Block Antimony Atoms Activated CuO@Co&#8208;CN Enable High Performances for Water Splitting and Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405452</link>
      <description>Xinfeng Zhu, Kaixuan Dong, Duy Thanh Tran, Saleem Sidra, Dinh Chuong Nguyen, Do Hwan Kim, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405208813

                Abstract This study reports an effective strategy for designing 3D electrocatalyst via the deposition of ZIF67&#8208;derived Co&#8211;CN shell layer over CuO nanoarrays to form a CuO@Co&#8211;CN hybrid, followed by incorporation with p &#8208;block Sb single atoms (CuO@Co&#8211;CN/Sb) to obtain highly activated catalytic behaviors. Inheriting both the excellent intrinsic catalytic activity of the components and their synergy, the CuO@Co&#8211;CN/Sb material serves as a high&#8208;efficiency multifunctional catalyst for overall water splitting and zinc (Zn)&#8211;air batteries. The material yields a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at a low overpotential of 72 and 250 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction, respectively. Furthermore, an electrolyzer based on CuO@Co&#8211;CN/Sb shows remarkable performance with a derived current density of 0.5 A cm &#8722;2 at low cell voltage of 2.67 V and good stability for 50 h continuous operation at a high current density of 0.5 A cm &#8722;2 . Simultaneously, Zn&#8211;air battery using the CuO@Co&#8211;CN/Sb material as air cathode yields a high open circuit voltage of 1.455 V and a discharge power density of 131.07 mW cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Xinfeng Zhu, Kaixuan Dong, Duy Thanh Tran, Saleem Sidra, Dinh Chuong Nguyen, Do Hwan Kim, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#8220;Electron-reservoir&#8221; CeO2 Layer on S-Co(OH)2 to Stabilize Lattice Oxygen for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction at Large Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110565</link>
      <description>Ying Zhi, Zhimin Li, Yu Tang, Jian Peng, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Guo Chen, Jianhong Yi, Jiangzhao Chen, Jiazhao Wang, Jinsong Wang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405212168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying Zhi, Zhimin Li, Yu Tang, Jian Peng, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Guo Chen, Jianhong Yi, Jiangzhao Chen, Jiazhao Wang, Jinsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D&#8208;Printed Hierarchical Nanostructured N&#8208;Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;NiO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; NF Electrode for Efficient Concurrent Electrocatalytic Production of Hydrogen and Formate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407349</link>
      <description>Zhaojing Han, Haoxiang Tao, Gang Wang, Chuanting Fan, Jie Zhang, Zhiyong Tang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405213199

                Abstract Replacing the oxygen evolution reaction with the alternative glycerol electro&#8208;oxidation reaction (GER) provides a promising strategy to enhance the efficiency of hydrogen production via water electrolysis while co&#8208;generating high&#8208;value chemicals. However, obtaining low&#8208;cost and efficient GER electrocatalysts remains a big challenge. Herein, a self&#8208;supported N&#8208;doped Co 2 NiO 4 nanoflakes (N&#8208;Co 2 NiO 4 NF) is proposed for efficient electrocatalytic oxidation of glycerol to formate. The synergistic effect induced by the interaction of the layered Co 2 NiO 4 nanostructures on the 3D&#8208;printed Nickel&#8208;Yttria&#8208;stabilized zirconia (Ni&#8208;YSZ) substrate and the amorphous nitrogen&#8208;doping promotes the anodic GER. The N&#8208;Co 2 NiO 4 NF exhibits low potentials of 1.07 and 1.18 V ( vs . RHE) for GER to drive 10 and 50 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The constituted two&#8208;electrode electrolyzer (N&#8208;Co 2 NiO 4 NF//NiS&#8208;Co&#8208;NiP) displays excellent activity that only requires ultralow cell voltages of 1.24 and 1.55 V to afford 10 and 200 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively, with a high FE (97%) for formate production and an excellent durability (120 h). This study provides a versatile approach for manufacturing high&#8208;performance Ni&#8208;based electrocatalyst for GER, paving the way for the energy&#8208;saving and environmentally&#8208;friendly co&#8208;production of value&#8208;added chemicals and hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Zhaojing Han, Haoxiang Tao, Gang Wang, Chuanting Fan, Jie Zhang, Zhiyong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of the reconstruction induced high-entropy spinel oxide nanosheets for boosting alkaline water oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158488</link>
      <description>Xuexue Wang, Runqing Lu, Shanhe Gong, Shaokang Yang, Wenbo Wang, Zhongti Sun, Shouxin Zhang, Jun Liu, Xiaomeng Lv, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405235986

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuexue Wang, Runqing Lu, Shanhe Gong, Shaokang Yang, Wenbo Wang, Zhongti Sun, Shouxin Zhang, Jun Liu, Xiaomeng Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158488</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering electron redistribution of CeO2/Ni(OH)2@Mo-NiS nanorod composites with rich oxygen vacancies for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.062</link>
      <description>Chenxu Xie, Zhengtong Ji, Yutong Li, Wenquan Wang, Yong Zhu, Lijun Zhao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405237791

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenxu Xie, Zhengtong Ji, Yutong Li, Wenquan Wang, Yong Zhu, Lijun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>p&#8211;n-Type LaCoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/NiFe LDH Heterostructures for Enhanced Photogenerated Carrier-Assisted Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13756</link>
      <description>Hao Cui, Shijie Jia, Tingting Du, Jiaqing Liu, Lin Xing, Xin Zhang, Fengchun Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405253515

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) poses a significant kinetic challenge for various critical energy conversion and storage technologies including electrocatalytic water splitting and metal-air batteries. In this study, a LaCoO</description>
      <author>Hao Cui, Shijie Jia, Tingting Du, Jiaqing Liu, Lin Xing, Xin Zhang, Fengchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Fenton-like Photo-degradation and Electrocatalytic Oxygen
  Evolution Reaction (OER) in Fe-doped Copper Oxide (CuO) Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.05637</link>
      <description>Suresh Chandra Baral, Dilip Sasmal, Sayak Datta, Mange Ram, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Ahmed Mekki, Somaditya Sen, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405253610

                Although hydrogen generation by water electrolysis is the cheapest of all other available sources, water splitting still occurs with sluggish kinetics. It is a challenging barrier for H2 production on a large scale. Moreover, research is still underway to understand the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and design the catalysts with improved OER performance. Herein, we report the synthesis, characterization, and OER performance of iron-doped copper oxide (CuO) as low-cost catalysts for water oxidation. The OER occurs at about 1.49 V versus the RHE with a Tafel slope of 69 mV/dec in a 1 M KOH solution. The overpotential of 338 mV at 10 mA/cm2 is among the lowest compared with other copper-based materials. The catalyst can deliver a stable current density of &gt;10 mA/cm2 for more than 10 hours. Additionally, wastewater treatment, particularly synthetic dye wastewater, is vital for preventing water scarcity and adverse effects on human health and ecotoxicology. The as-synthesized catalysts are also utilized for Fenton-like photo-degradation under low-power visible household LED lights toward the most commonly industrially used simulated Methylene blue dye wastewater. Almost complete degradation of the MB dye has been achieved within 50 minutes of visible light irradiation with a first-order rate constant of 0.0973/min. This dual functionality feature can open new pathways as a non-noble, highly efficient, and robust catalyst for OER and wastewater treatments.</description>
      <author>Suresh Chandra Baral, Dilip Sasmal, Sayak Datta, Mange Ram, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Ahmed Mekki, Somaditya Sen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.05637</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halting Oxygen Evolution to Achieve Long Cycle Life in Sodium Layered Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418605</link>
      <description>Haoji Wang, Jinqiang Gao, Yu Mei, Lianshan Ni, Yi He, Ningyun Hong, Jiangnan Huang, Wentao Deng, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Chaoping Liang, Tongchao Liu, Xiaobo Ji, Khalil Amine, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405259193

                Oxygen redox chemistries at high voltage have materialized as a revolutionary paradigm for cathodes with high-energy density; however, they are plagued by the challenges of labile oxygen loss and rapid degradations upon cycling, even after concerted endeavors from the research community. Here we propose a multi-concentration stratagem propelled by entropy reinforcement to enhance the electronic structure disorder (ESD) at high desodiation states for impeding undesired oxygen mobility and ensuring controlled oxygen activity, elucidated by density functional theory calculations. The increased disorder strengthens the reversible electrochemistry of lattice oxygen redox, leading to effectively suppressed P-O structural evolution and highly stable localized TMO6 octahedral environments, as demonstrated by soft/hard X-ray absorption spectroscopy. Furthermore, we reveal that a high-entropy state induced by cationic disordering has capacity to perturb cationic redox boundaries, significantly restraining the formation of detrimental P3' phases. As a consequence, the high-voltage cycling stability has been greatly enhanced, up to 4.4 V versus Na+/Na, with an impressive 90.1% capacity retention at 1C over 100 cycles and 76.1% capacity retention at 2C over 300 cycles. The resilient oxygen redox, enabled through the control of ESD, broadens the horizons for entropy engineering and lays the foundation for advancements in high-energy, long-cycling, safe batteries.</description>
      <author>Haoji Wang, Jinqiang Gao, Yu Mei, Lianshan Ni, Yi He, Ningyun Hong, Jiangnan Huang, Wentao Deng, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Chaoping Liang, Tongchao Liu, Xiaobo Ji, Khalil Amine</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halting Oxygen Evolution to Achieve Long Cycle Life in Sodium Layered Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418605</link>
      <description>Haoji Wang, Jinqiang Gao, Yu Mei, Lianshan Ni, Yi He, Ningyun Hong, Jiangnan Huang, Wentao Deng, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Chaoping Liang, Tongchao Liu, Xiaobo Ji, Khalil Amine, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405259697

                Oxygen redox chemistries at high voltage have materialized as a revolutionary paradigm for cathodes with high&#8208;energy density; however, they are plagued by the challenges of labile oxygen loss and rapid degradations upon cycling, even after concerted endeavors from the research community. Here we propose a multi&#8208;concentration stratagem propelled by entropy reinforcement to enhance the electronic structure disorder (ESD) at high desodiation states for impeding undesired oxygen mobility and ensuring controlled oxygen activity, elucidated by density functional theory calculations. The increased disorder strengthens the reversible electrochemistry of lattice oxygen redox, leading to effectively suppressed P&#8208;O structural evolution and highly stable localized TMO6 octahedral environments, as demonstrated by soft/hard X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy. Furthermore, we reveal that a high&#8208;entropy state induced by cationic disordering has capacity to perturb cationic redox boundaries, significantly restraining the formation of detrimental P3' phases. As a consequence, the high&#8208;voltage cycling stability has been greatly enhanced, up to 4.4 V versus Na+/Na, with an impressive 90.1% capacity retention at 1C over 100 cycles and 76.1% capacity retention at 2C over 300 cycles. The resilient oxygen redox, enabled through the control of ESD, broadens the horizons for entropy engineering and lays the foundation for advancements in high&#8208;energy, long&#8208;cycling, safe batteries.</description>
      <author>Haoji Wang, Jinqiang Gao, Yu Mei, Lianshan Ni, Yi He, Ningyun Hong, Jiangnan Huang, Wentao Deng, Guoqiang Zou, Hongshuai Hou, Chaoping Liang, Tongchao Liu, Xiaobo Ji, Khalil Amine</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanical Degradation by Anion Redox in LiNiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Countered via Pillaring</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403837</link>
      <description>Matthew Bergschneider, Fantai Kong, Patrick Conlin, Taesoon Hwang, Seok&#8208;Gwang Doo, Kyeongjae Cho, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405260966

                Abstract A promising next&#8208;generation high&#8208;energy cathode material, LiNiO 2 (LNO) has failed to realize commercialization due to severe capacity degradation during cycling. The dual mechanisms of surface oxygen evolution due to anion redox and anisotropic volume change upon delithiation synergistically pulverize and degrade the material. Detailed Density Functional Theory (DFT) modeling and analysis of the anisotropic structural changes associated with crack formation in LiNiO 2 (LNO) reveals the link of mechanical behavior to charge transfer and oxygen redox activity upon deep charge cycling (&gt;4.2 V vs Li/Li + ). In the two&#8208;phase region and H2&#8211;H3 transition from 66% to 100% delithiation, oxygen of [NiO 6 ] octahedra is discovered to undergo redox in growing the Li&#8208;deficient regions, causing c&#8208;lattice mechanical weakening and collapse as the Li&#8208;slab becomes depleted. Li&#8208;site dopants are investigated to locally compensate against anion redox, resulting in enhanced coulombic repulsion and supporting the interslab layer thickness even at 100% depth of charge. Ionic size and oxidation state of M in Li x&#8208;y M y NiO 2 are found to fundamentally impact stabilization capability, moderating the anisotropic strain and volume expansion asynchronously. Optimization of mixed doping composition may then enable &#8220;zero strain&#8221; high&#8208;Ni Li(Ni,Co,Mn)O 2 (NCM) or LNO.</description>
      <author>Matthew Bergschneider, Fantai Kong, Patrick Conlin, Taesoon Hwang, Seok&#8208;Gwang Doo, Kyeongjae Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing AgO/Ag2O Electrocatalysts with Highly Exposed and Tightly Contacted Active Facets for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402951</link>
      <description>Lei Zhu, Xiao&#8208;Jing Sang, Peng Zhao, Jiansheng Li, Sifan Li, Hao Dong, Xin Zhou, Meiying Liu, Wan&#8208;Sheng You, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405261426

                The development of efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the elucidation of their underlying mechanisms are crucial for overcoming the low efficiency of hydrogen production through the electrolysis of water. Utilizing the electrochemical anodic oxidation method, a series of silver-based electrocatalysts (Ag-x, where x signifies the applied direct current (DC) voltage, x = 0, 5, 10, 15) were prepared employing metallic silver wire as the anode under DC voltages. The resulting silver-based electrodes have been oxidized and reconstructed, yielding AgO/Ag2O composite on the surface. Notably, the Ag-10 electrode exhibited the lowest overpotential (399 mV at 50 mA cm-2 and 456 mV at 100 mA cm-2), along with good stability. The superior OER performance of Ag-10 is not only attributed to the high exposure and tight interface of the AgO (-111) and Ag2O (111) crystal phases, as well as the higher prevalence of Ag-O-O-Ag species on its surface, but also its larger electrochemical active surface area (ECSA). This work provides insight for the synthesis of metal oxide-based electrocatalysts and understanding the electrocatalytic mechanism.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhu, Xiao&#8208;Jing Sang, Peng Zhao, Jiansheng Li, Sifan Li, Hao Dong, Xin Zhou, Meiying Liu, Wan&#8208;Sheng You</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202402951</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Surface Restructuring of Epitaxial IrO2 Thin Films During Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-187853/60012967</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405269549

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46936/aps-187853/60012967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assembly and Valence Modulation of Ordered Bimetallic MOFs for Highly Efficient Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29245845</link>
      <description>Yaling Wu, Zhaopeng Sun, Yingying Chen, Dan Liu, Yan Meng, Yan Zheng, Molecules. 29(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405284174

                Metal synergy can enhance the catalytic performance, and a prefabricated solid precursor can guide the ordered embedding, of secondary metal source ions for the rapid synthesis of bimetallic organic frameworks (MM&#8217;-MOFs) with a stoichiometric ratio of 1:1. In this paper, Co-MOF-1D containing well-defined binding sites was synthesized by mechanical ball milling, which was used as a template for the induced introduction of Fe ions to successfully assemble the ordered bimetallic Co1Fe1-MOF-74@2 (where @2 denotes template-directed synthesis of MOF-74). Its electrocatalytic performance is superior to that of the conventional one-step-synthesized Co1Fe1-MOF-74@1 (where @1 denotes one-step synthesis of MOF-74), and the ratio of the two metal sources, Co and Fe, is close to 1:1. Meanwhile, the iron valence states (FeII and FeIII) in Co1Fe1-MOF-74@2 were further regulated to obtain the electrocatalytic materials Co1Fe1(II)-MOF-74@2 and Co1Fe1(III)-MOF-74@2. The electrochemical performance test results confirm that Co1Fe1(II)-MOF-74@2 regulated by valence state has a better catalytic performance than Co1Fe1(III)-MOF-74@2 in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process. This phenomenon is related to the gradual increase in the valence state of Fe ions in Co1Fe1(II)-MOF-74@2, which promotes the continuous improvement in the performance of the MOF before reaching the optimal steady state and makes the OER performance reach the optimum when the FeII/FeIII mixed-valence state reaches a certain proportion. This provides a new idea for the directed synthesis and optimization of highly efficient catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yaling Wu, Zhaopeng Sun, Yingying Chen, Dan Liu, Yan Meng, Yan Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29245845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing defect-rich CoO post smart Li extraction from spent Li-ion battery toward efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158325</link>
      <description>Shuya Lei, Lin&#8208;Bo Liu, Subiao Liu, Wei Sun, Yue Yang, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405287144

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuya Lei, Lin&#8208;Bo Liu, Subiao Liu, Wei Sun, Yue Yang, Jing&#8208;Li Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable oxygen evolution catalysis: Water-based fabrication of FeNi-MIL-100 on recycled stainless steel substrates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.077</link>
      <description>Zhong Li, Ni Wang, Liangkui Sun, Xingchen Xie, Lixiang He, Mingliang Xiang, Wencheng Hu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405301891

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhong Li, Ni Wang, Liangkui Sun, Xingchen Xie, Lixiang He, Mingliang Xiang, Wencheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancies-Riched composite of ultrathin NiFe-LDH nanosheets on the etched Prussian blue analogue: An efficient alkaline oxygen evolution electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.068</link>
      <description>Chao Wang, Luna Chen, Xinyue Xu, Yajie Liu, Yuan Song, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Guanjun Chen, Tianrong Zhan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405314359

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Wang, Luna Chen, Xinyue Xu, Yajie Liu, Yuan Song, Lingbo Zong, Xingwei Li, Guanjun Chen, Tianrong Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial built-in electric field in 2D Ni(OH)2 heterojunction with the sodium organic compound for enhanced oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158565</link>
      <description>Jiao Zhou, Mingyuan Zhang, Baiyu Ren, Qian Yi, Sheng Wang, Baoyue Zhang, An&#8208;Ping Li, Xinyi Hu, Zhong Li, Guanyu Chen, Yinfen Cheng, Rui Gao, Yange Luan, Jiaru Zhang, Yichao Wang, Yihong Hu, Z. Yang, Bo Liang, Haigang Hao, Jian Zhen Ou, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405316505

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiao Zhou, Mingyuan Zhang, Baiyu Ren, Qian Yi, Sheng Wang, Baoyue Zhang, An&#8208;Ping Li, Xinyi Hu, Zhong Li, Guanyu Chen, Yinfen Cheng, Rui Gao, Yange Luan, Jiaru Zhang, Yichao Wang, Yihong Hu, Z. Yang, Bo Liang, Haigang Hao, Jian Zhen Ou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158565</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction of network structured Polypyrrole-NaBiO2 nanocomposite in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41779-024-01132-5</link>
      <description>Munirah D. Albaqami, Muhammad Imran Anwar, Saikh Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem, Journal of the Australian Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405317491

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munirah D. Albaqami, Muhammad Imran Anwar, Saikh Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41779-024-01132-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled deposition of trimetallic Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;V oxides on nickel foam as high-performance electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.044</link>
      <description>Muhammad Ali Ehsan, Rashida Batool, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Sameer Ali, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Zaka Ullah, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405318518

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Ali Ehsan, Rashida Batool, Abbas Saeed Hakeem, Sameer Ali, Muhammad Faizan Nazar, Zaka Ullah</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical NiFeP/CoP nano-arrays for efficient oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3054301</link>
      <description>Aobo Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405325991

                This paper provides a comprehensive overview of the development, working principles, and catalyst evaluation parameters in the realm of electrochemical water electrolysis, with a primary focus on the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER). The discussion encompasses the historical perspective, reaction mechanisms, and fundamental principles underlying water electrolysis, with a strong emphasis on the pivotal role of electrocatalysts in driving efficient hydrogen production. Furthermore, this paper delves into a specific study that involves the fabrication of 3D hierarchical NiFeP/CoP nano-arrays on conductive carbon cloth. This innovative catalyst architecture, realized through a combination of hydrothermal methods and phosphating treatments, showcases remarkable performance in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) electrocatalysis. The hierarchical structure of this catalyst maximizes the electrochemically active area, exposing a higher number of active sites and facilitating efficient reaction kinetics. The catalytic performance of NiFeP/CoP/CC is distinguished by its low overpotentials, a small Tafel slope, and exceptional stability over prolonged durations. This promising performance positions it as a potential substitute for precious metal catalysts in the pursuit of sustainable energy conversion. In essence, this research significantly contributes to the ongoing endeavor to discover cost-effective, resource-efficient, and highly active electrocatalysts. It marks a notable step forward in the journey towards achieving green energy transformation, aligning with the imperative for sustainable and environmentally friendly energy solutions.</description>
      <author>Aobo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1117/12.3054301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering CoN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and FeN&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Dual Sites with Adjacent Nanoclusters on Flexible Porous Carbon Fibers for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Reduction and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418489</link>
      <description>Zhe L&#252;, Zhe Wang, Zhenbei Yang, Xiaoyan Jin, Tong Li, RuoJie Xu, Ke&#8208;Xin Kong, Shouxin Zhang, Yong Wang, Yipu Liu, Linxing Meng, Zhijuan Pan, Seong&#8208;Ju Hwang, Liang Li, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405337455

                Abstract Dual&#8208;atom catalysts (DACs) possess tunable electronic structures and efficient atom utilization, making them highly promising for catalyzing the oxygen reduction reaction/oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER). However, achieving high catalytic activity and stability for both ORR and OER in DACs remains a challenge. Herein, a flexible membrane of porous carbon fiber anchored with atomically scattered CoN 4 /FeN 4 dual sites and adjacent Co 2 Fe 2 /Fe 5 nanoclusters (Co, Fe&#8208;DACs/NCs@PCF) is synthesized. The local geometry and electronic structure of the CoN 4 /FeN 4 sites, which act as reaction centers for ORR/OER, are finely regulated by the neighboring Co 2 Fe 2 /Fe 5 nanoclusters. This unique structure imparts Co, Fe&#8208;DACs/NCs@PCF with exceptional activity and durability toward ORR/OER, outperforming the performance of single&#8208;atom catalysts containing only CoN 4 or FeN 4 sites, as well as commercial Pt/C and RuO 2 catalysts. Zinc&#8211;air battery employing a Co, Fe&#8208;DACs/NCs@PCF cathode exhibits outstanding stability, maintaining cyclability for over 1500 h, outperforming a Pt/C + RuO 2 air cathode. Theoretical calculations highlight distinct synergies between Fe 5 (Co 2 Fe 2 ) clusters and FeN 4 (CoN 4 ) sites, which optimize the coupling strength of Fe(Co)&#9472;OH at the potential&#8208;determining steps and thus improve ORR (OER) catalytic kinetics. This study lays a theoretical and practical foundation for rational design of heterostructure catalysts featuring coexisting DACs and nanoclusters within porous carbon fibers.</description>
      <author>Zhe L&#252;, Zhe Wang, Zhenbei Yang, Xiaoyan Jin, Tong Li, RuoJie Xu, Ke&#8208;Xin Kong, Shouxin Zhang, Yong Wang, Yipu Liu, Linxing Meng, Zhijuan Pan, Seong&#8208;Ju Hwang, Liang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202418489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct electrodeposition of NiFe-based high-entropy compound on nickel foam for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5328722/v1</link>
      <description>Yibin Yang, Yang Ji-tao, Xinghua Huang, Wang Chen, Yuhao Zhang, Xiaowen Zhang, Lijuan Dong, Zhihao Duan, Mingzhu Wu, Ying Li, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405338076

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting represents a highly promising avenue for sustainable energy conversion and storage, paving the way for a future hydrogen-based society. This approach necessitates the development of durable and cost-effective electrocatalysts for the OER. In this study, we report the as-synthesized NiFe-based high-entropy compound grown on nickel foam via direct electrochemical deposition. Remarkably, electrodeposition onto 1&#215;1 cm2 nickel foam was optimized by strategically varying critical parameters. Subsequently, the fabricated electrodes underwent evaluation for comprehensive water splitting within the identical flow cell under alkaline conditions. The best-performing sample, NiFe-2:1, required relatively low overpotentials of 232 mV to reach a current density of 10 mA cm-2 for the OER. The NiFe-2:1 hydroxides exhibit high entropy, which optimizes the flat-band potential (Efb) and carrier concentration (NA) in high-entropy NiFe-based electrocatalysts. This enhancement facilitates sensitive electron transfer, thereby reducing the kinetic barrier for the OER. Furthermore, this review thoroughly discusses potential degradation mechanisms of active sites and outlines corresponding mitigation strategies. It also offers insights into the discrepancies between research and the design of non-precious metal-based catalysts for the OER, as well as their implementation in practical devices.</description>
      <author>Yibin Yang, Yang Ji-tao, Xinghua Huang, Wang Chen, Yuhao Zhang, Xiaowen Zhang, Lijuan Dong, Zhihao Duan, Mingzhu Wu, Ying Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5328722/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photocatalytic and electrocatalytic properties of IrO2 nanoparticles via Cr and Co ion doping: Insights into surface oxygen defect structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162088</link>
      <description>Hyeri Jeon, Dung Thanh Hoang, Gyuri Kim, In Young Kim, Hangil Lee, Seungwoo Hong, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405338674

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyeri Jeon, Dung Thanh Hoang, Gyuri Kim, In Young Kim, Hangil Lee, Seungwoo Hong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallic Compounds for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch12</link>
      <description>Xiaobo Zheng, Yao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405352517

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) stands as a pivotal electrochemical process, playing a crucial role in various cutting-edge renewable energy technologies such as water-splitting and metal-air batteries. However, its inherent sluggish kinetics necessitate a substantial overpotential to drive the OER, which significantly constrains the widespread application of these devices. Consequently, a range of efficient, durable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts, including carbon-based materials, metals, and metallic compounds, have been engineered to reduce the OER overpotential and enhance energy efficiency. In this section, we provide a comprehensive discussion of the recent intriguing advancements in metallic compounds for the OER, with a deep exploration of the catalytic mechanisms and the underlying structure&#8211;performance relationships. Specifically, we systematically delve into metal oxides, hydroxides, and their supported single-atom/nanoparticle materials, showcasing their superiority in driving the OER. Finally, we offer some new insights into the remaining challenges and opportunities for the development of metallic compounds.</description>
      <author>Xiaobo Zheng, Yao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Materials for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch13</link>
      <description>Zhongjie Yang, D.J. Fu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405352615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongjie Yang, D.J. Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch13</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Based Materials for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch11</link>
      <description>Mengyi Xu, Li Xu, Yurong Su, Meirong Song, Xian&#8208;Fu Zheng, Yuchen Qin, Guang-Xin Ru, Xiuhong Zhu, Li Wang, Sheng Xia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405352622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyi Xu, Li Xu, Yurong Su, Meirong Song, Xian&#8208;Fu Zheng, Yuchen Qin, Guang-Xin Ru, Xiuhong Zhu, Li Wang, Sheng Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527846368.ch11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392767

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392936

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Towards active and stable oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4405205836</link>
      <description>Fabien Claudel, No host. None(None)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4405205836

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fabien Claudel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4405205836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution activity of nickel-based phosphates and effects of their electronic orbitals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00794h</link>
      <description>Yuuki Sugawara, Y Nakase, Gopinathan M. Anilkumar, Keigo Kamata, Takeo Yamaguchi, Nanoscale Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405196768

                Metal phosphate-type compounds have been utilized in diverse applications, and their distinctive chemical properties have recently opened avenues for their use as catalysts. Metal phosphates have previously demonstrated significant electrocatalytic activity for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in electrochemical water splitting. However, the critical factors influencing OER electrocatalysis on Ni-based phosphates have been insufficiently explored. We herein demonstrate nickel (Ni)-based phosphates-monoclinic Ni</description>
      <author>Yuuki Sugawara, Y Nakase, Gopinathan M. Anilkumar, Keigo Kamata, Takeo Yamaguchi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00794h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Plasma in Catalyst Preparation and Modification for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00075</link>
      <description>Naeem Ahmed, Wei Ma, Ruijuan Zhao, Qiu Zhang, Di Wu, Xia Zheng, Haorui Wang, Chunhua Cui, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405318450

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naeem Ahmed, Wei Ma, Ruijuan Zhao, Qiu Zhang, Di Wu, Xia Zheng, Haorui Wang, Chunhua Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alkene Epoxidation and Oxygen Evolution Reactions Compete for Reactive Surface Oxygen Atoms on Gold Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08948</link>
      <description>Richa Ghosh, Geoffrey M. Hopping, Jiong Lu, Drew W. Hollyfield, David W. Flaherty, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274268

                Rates and selectivities for the partial oxidation of organic molecules on reactive electrodes depend on the identity and prevalence of reactive and spectator species. Here, we investigate the mechanism for the epoxidation of 1-hexene (C</description>
      <author>Richa Ghosh, Geoffrey M. Hopping, Jiong Lu, Drew W. Hollyfield, David W. Flaherty</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c08948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Entropy Rare Earth Prussian Blue Analogues for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5033247</link>
      <description>Ke Zhang, Jinzhao Huang, Jiao Feng, Guixin Zhao, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Xiaolong Deng, Zehui Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405171230

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ke Zhang, Jinzhao Huang, Jiao Feng, Guixin Zhao, Yong&#8208;Min Liang, Xiaolong Deng, Zehui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5033247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal atom supported on N-terminated diamond (100) surface as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution and reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242133</link>
      <description>Gaoxian Li, Yuanhang Wang, Nan Gao, Hongdong Li, Applied Physics Letters. 125(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405323235

                To alleviate the increasingly serious energy issues, it is essential to develop highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we employed density functional theory to investigate a broad spectrum of transition metal (TM = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, Zn, Y, Zr, Mo, Ru, Rh, Ag, W, Ir, and Pt) atoms supported on N-terminated diamond (100) surface (TM@ND) as single-atom catalysts for their OER and ORR performances. TM atoms (Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Y, Zr, and Ir) show large binding energy with substrate and thermal stability, which is advantageous for electrocatalytic reactions. Especially, Ir@ND demonstrates high efficacy as an OER electrocatalyst, and Mn@ND is identified as an efficient ORR electrocatalyst, exhibiting the theoretical overpotentials smaller than 1 V. Consequently, it suggests that diamond-based catalysts could serve as promising candidates for energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Gaoxian Li, Yuanhang Wang, Nan Gao, Hongdong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242133</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392818

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392894

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405392952

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Vector Substrate Design for Grain Boundary Engineering: Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance in LaNiO3"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405393013

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01565g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding of the synergetic effect of FeCoN8C dual active centers catalyst for oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162055</link>
      <description>Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405199310

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen&#8208;Shuang Yin, Hui&#8208;Jian Zou, Yan Leng, Xikun Yang, Chungang Min, Feng Tan, Ai&#8208;Min Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrically driven phosphorus dissolution from iron-nickel phosphate surfaces exposing highly active sites for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.031</link>
      <description>Ya Liu, Jinghui Zhu, Liang Yu, Yubin Zhao, Xing Cao, Shoujing Wei, Junrong Zeng, Huanhui Chen, Ziqian Lu, Binyi Chen, Gaowei Zhang, Liubiao Zhong, Yejun Qiu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405199622

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya Liu, Jinghui Zhu, Liang Yu, Yubin Zhao, Xing Cao, Shoujing Wei, Junrong Zeng, Huanhui Chen, Ziqian Lu, Binyi Chen, Gaowei Zhang, Liubiao Zhong, Yejun Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction: Construction of efficient Pb(&lt;scp&gt;ii&lt;/scp&gt;) carboxylate catalysts for the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90216e</link>
      <description>Janak, Vijay S. Sapner, Bhaskar R. Sathe, Sadhika Khullar, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405316906

                Correction for &#8216;Construction of efficient Pb( ii ) carboxylate catalysts for the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions&#8217; by Janak et al. , Dalton Trans. , 2024, https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt02958e.</description>
      <author>Janak, Vijay S. Sapner, Bhaskar R. Sathe, Sadhika Khullar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt90216e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand regulated the Coordination Environment of Cobalt-group-MOF for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen reduction/evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/au.173396889.98261479/v1</link>
      <description>Kun Xie, Long Lin, Pengtao Wang, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang, Authorea (Authorea). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405266739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kun Xie, Long Lin, Pengtao Wang, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/au.173396889.98261479/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of the diatomic-site electronic structure with alloy nanoparticles in hollow carbon nanospheres for efficient oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158579</link>
      <description>Yuxuan Liang, Dingyu Zhang, Yuan Zhang, Fengfeng Yan, Liang Sun, Xinyue Jin, Wei Wang, Lirong Zheng, Wei Li, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405316643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuxuan Liang, Dingyu Zhang, Yuan Zhang, Fengfeng Yan, Liang Sun, Xinyue Jin, Wei Wang, Lirong Zheng, Wei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.158579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Heteroatoms Doped Carbon Bearing Nanoscale Pd-Co Alloy as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Hydrogen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5051190</link>
      <description>C. Renugadevi, L. Cindrella, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405226784

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C. Renugadevi, L. Cindrella</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5051190</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoPc-based donor-acceptor covalent organic frameworks with charge transfer for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.100</link>
      <description>Ruichen Li, Yang Tian, Jingjing Zhang, Ziang Xu, Shujun Chao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405328760

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruichen Li, Yang Tian, Jingjing Zhang, Ziang Xu, Shujun Chao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>W-promoted OER Kinetics of Bimetallic hydroxide: An Experimental Analysis via Operando EIS and Temperature-Dependent Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07619b</link>
      <description>Hariharan N. Dhandapani, M. Ramasubramanian, Priyadharshini Laxminarayanan, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Aditi De, Ramesh Babu Balakrishnan, Subrata Kundu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405185572

                Developing a cost-effective and highly efficient electrocatalyst to improve oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a significant challenge in water splitting. A thorough understanding of reaction kinetics and the physical, chemical,...</description>
      <author>Hariharan N. Dhandapani, M. Ramasubramanian, Priyadharshini Laxminarayanan, Suprobhat Singha Roy, Aditi De, Ramesh Babu Balakrishnan, Subrata Kundu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07619b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond conventional structures: emerging complex metal oxides for efficient oxygen and hydrogen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01020a</link>
      <description>Yinlong Zhu, Zheng Tang, Ling Yuan, Bowen Li, Zongping Shao, Wanlin Guo, Chemical Society Reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405281726

                The core of clean energy technologies such as fuel cells, water electrolyzers, and metal-air batteries depends on a series of oxygen and hydrogen-based electrocatalysis reactions, including the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), which necessitate cost-effective electrocatalysts to improve their energy efficiency. In the recent decade, complex metal oxides (beyond simple transition metal oxides, spinel oxides and ABO</description>
      <author>Yinlong Zhu, Zheng Tang, Ling Yuan, Bowen Li, Zongping Shao, Wanlin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cs01020a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Hydrogen Production via Z-Scheme Water Splitting System Based Solely on Perovskite-type Tantalum Oxynitrides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07592g</link>
      <description>Wenpeng Li, Akio Hirako, Shuji Sekimori, Rhauane A. Galv&#227;o, Mamiko Nakabayashi, Faze Wang, Takashi Hisatomi, Kazunari Domen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405175553

                Z-scheme overall water splitting (ZOWS) systems can provide efficient hydrogen production in response to visible light. However, the integration of narrow-bandgap non-oxide photocatalysts as oxygen evolution photocatalysts (OEPs) in such...</description>
      <author>Wenpeng Li, Akio Hirako, Shuji Sekimori, Rhauane A. Galv&#227;o, Mamiko Nakabayashi, Faze Wang, Takashi Hisatomi, Kazunari Domen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07592g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Restructuring of Asymmetric Built&#8208;in Electric Field Catalysts Facilitates the Efficient Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202422734</link>
      <description>Wansen Ma, Yuhan Zhang, Liwen Hu, Xuewei Lv, Jie Dang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405325603

                Abstract Efficient and stable bifunctional catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction play an important role in realizing hydrogen economy. In this study, the multi&#8208;heterogeneous interfacial catalyst, Ni 2 P@FeP@Co 2 P (denoted as NFC), with an asymmetric built&#8208;in electric field is successfully designed and synthesized. Benefiting from the double charge balance effect, NFC exhibits superior hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic activity. Importantly, the NFC&#8208;assembled anion&#8208;exchange membrane (AEM) electrolyzer exhibits enhanced performance and remarkable stability at industrial current densities and high temperatures, reaching a current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 at the small voltage of 1.95 V. The results of the dynamic X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy tests indicate that the self&#8208;reconfiguration of the NFC during OER provides additional active sites for the reaction. The density functional theory (DFT) results demonstrate that the asymmetric built&#8208;in electric field (BIEF) induces an adaptive distribution of charge, which optimizes the adsorption and desorption of hydrogen/oxygen intermediates during the reaction, thereby enhancing the catalytic kinetics of the overall water splitting process. This work presents novel strategies for the design of highly active catalysts in the field of energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Wansen Ma, Yuhan Zhang, Liwen Hu, Xuewei Lv, Jie Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202422734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Modulation of NiFeOOH Coordination Environment for Enhanced Electrocatalytic&#8208;Conversion of Glucose and Energy&#8208;Efficient Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202412872</link>
      <description>Ning Wei, Sufeng Zhang, Xue Yao, Qinglu Li, Nan Li, Jingrui Li, Dingjie Pan, Qiming Liu, Shaowei Chen, Scott Renneckar, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405279322

                Glucose electrocatalytic-conversion reaction (GCR) is a promising anode reaction to replace the slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER), thus promoting the development of hydrogen production by electrochemical water splitting. Herein, NiFe-based metal-organic framework (MOF) is used as a precursor to prepare W-doped nickel-iron phosphide (W-NiFeP) nanosheet arrays by ion exchange and phosphorylation, which exhibit a high electrocatalytic activity toward the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), featuring an overpotential of only -179 mV to achieve the current density of 100 mA cm</description>
      <author>Ning Wei, Sufeng Zhang, Xue Yao, Qinglu Li, Nan Li, Jingrui Li, Dingjie Pan, Qiming Liu, Shaowei Chen, Scott Renneckar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202412872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Trimetal Catalytic Activities for Efficient Urea Electrooxidation-Coupled Hydrogen Production at Ampere-Level Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14406</link>
      <description>Huachuan Sun, Zhiqiang Luo, Mingpeng Chen, Tong Zhou, Boxue Wang, Bin Xiao, Qingjie Lu, Baoye Zi, Kai Zhao, Xia Zhang, Jianhong Zhao, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Hao Cui, Lei Zhu, Chundong Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Qingju Liu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405274216

                Replacing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with the urea oxidation reaction (UOR) in conjunction with the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) offers a feasible and environmentally friendly approach for handling urea-rich wastewater and generating energy-saving hydrogen. However, the deactivation and detachment of active sites in powder electrocatalysts reported hitherto present significant challenges to achieving high efficiency and sustainability in energy-saving hydrogen production. Herein, a self-supported bimetallic nickel manganese metal-organic framework (NiMn-MOF) nanosheet and its derived heterostructure composed of NiMn-MOF decorated with ultrafine Pt nanocrystals (Pt</description>
      <author>Huachuan Sun, Zhiqiang Luo, Mingpeng Chen, Tong Zhou, Boxue Wang, Bin Xiao, Qingjie Lu, Baoye Zi, Kai Zhao, Xia Zhang, Jianhong Zhao, Tianwei He, Jin Zhang, Hao Cui, Lei Zhu, Chundong Wang, Dingsheng Wang, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-Doped Carbon-Incorporated Cobalt&#8211;Iron Mixed-Metal Phosphide Nanoboxes as Efficient Bifunctional Catalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13462</link>
      <description>Hua Li, Shuiqiang Chen, Fang Su, Zheng Li, Kewen Tang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405238985

                Optimizing the composition and structure of nanocatalysts is an efficient approach to achieving the top electrocatalytic performance. However, the construction of hollow nanocomposites composed of metal phosphides and highly conductive carbon to promote the electrocatalytic performance of metal phosphide-based catalysts is rarely reported. Herein, a CoFeP/C nanobox nanocomposite consisting of Co-Fe mixed-metal phosphides and N-doped carbon was successfully fabricated through an ion-exchange phosphidation strategy derived from ZIF-67 nanocubes. Benefiting from the synergistic effects between multiple components and the unique hollow structure, CoFeP/C nanoboxes can catalyze the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with high activity and stability. Furthermore, in the construction of an alkaline water electrolyzer using CoFeP/C nanoboxes as both OER and HER catalysts, they were capable of efficiently splitting water with a current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Hua Li, Shuiqiang Chen, Fang Su, Zheng Li, Kewen Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering &lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;Orbital States via Molecular Modules in All&#8208;Organic Electrocatalysts toward Direct Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202410507</link>
      <description>Lihong Yu, Xuefeng Zhang, Zi&#8208;Ming Ye, Hong&#8208;Gang Du, Lidong Wang, Pingping Xu, Yuhai Dou, Liming Cao, Chun&#8208;Ting He, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405279486

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an indispensable anode reaction for sustainable hydrogen production from water electrolysis, yet overreliance on metal-based catalysts featured with vibrant d-electrons. It still has notable gap between metal-free and metal-based electrocatalysts, due to lacking accurate and efficient p-band regulation methods on non-metal atoms. Herein, a molecular modularization strategy is proposed for fine-tuning the p-orbital states of series metal-free covalent organic frameworks (COFs) for realizing OER performance beyond benchmark precious metal catalysts. Optimized combination of benzodioxazole/benzodiimide-based building blocks achieves an impressive applied potential of 1.670 &#177; 0.004 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) and 1.735 &#177; 0.006 V versus RHE to deliver enhanced current densities of 0.5 and 1.0 A cm</description>
      <author>Lihong Yu, Xuefeng Zhang, Zi&#8208;Ming Ye, Hong&#8208;Gang Du, Lidong Wang, Pingping Xu, Yuhai Dou, Liming Cao, Chun&#8208;Ting He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202410507</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Architecture and functional regulation of a plant PSII-LHCII megacomplex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq9967</link>
      <description>Jianyu Shan, Dariusz M. Niedzwiedzki, Rupal Singh Tomar, Zhenfeng Liu, Haijun Liu, Science Advances. 10(50)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405361367

                Photosystem II (PSII) splits water in oxygenic photosynthesis on Earth. The structure and function of the C 4 S 4 M 2 -type PSII-LHCII (light-harvesting complex II) megacomplexes from the wild-type and PsbR-deletion mutant plants are studied through electron microscopy (EM), structural mass spectrometry, and ultrafast fluorescence spectroscopy [time-resolved fluorescence (TRF)]. The cryo-EM structure of a type I C 4 S 4 M 2 megacomplex demonstrates that the three domains of PsbR bind to the stromal side of D1, D2, and CP43; associate with the single transmembrane helix of the redox active Cyt b 559 ; and stabilize the luminal extrinsic PsbP, respectively. This megacomplex, with PsbR and PsbY centered around the narrow interface between two dimeric PSII cores, provides the supramolecular structural basis that regulates the plastoquinone occupancy in Q B site, excitation energy transfer, and oxygen evolution. PSII-LHCII megacomplexes (types I and II) and LHC aggregation levels in Arabidopsis psbR mutant were also interrogated and compared to wild-type plants through EM and picosecond TRF.</description>
      <author>Jianyu Shan, Dariusz M. Niedzwiedzki, Rupal Singh Tomar, Zhenfeng Liu, Haijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.adq9967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;AlC Max Phase Integrated With 2D GCN (Nb&#8208;MX/GCN) as a Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Water Splitting Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403746</link>
      <description>V. Sridevi, N. Abirami, R. Arulmozhi, Pavithra Suresh, Kayalvizhi Rajagopal, ChemistrySelect. 9(46)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405229692

                Abstract Noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts are impractical for large&#8208;scale manufacture due to their high cost, limited availability, and poor long&#8208;term stability in performing several functions. Hence, an alternative is the need of the hour that emphasizes blending metals and ceramic property materials with compelling electroconductivity. In this research, we synthesized two bare materials, Nb 2 AlC MAX (Nb&#8208;MX) phase and graphitic carbon&#8208;nitride (GCN) sheets using the calcination method which is then converted into a composite (Nb&#8208;MX/GCN) material through wet impregnation technique. The electrochemical investigations were conducted to assess the catalytic efficacy of the composite material. The synthesized Nb&#8208;MX/GCN electrocatalyst exhibited outstanding electrocatalytic efficiency for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in an alkaline environment. The catalyst exhibits a significantly low overpotential of just 66 mV and 450 mV for the HER and OER performance, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in a 1.0 M KOH solution. In addition, the catalytic activity exhibited no change over 24 h which indicated the excellent stability of the material. This performance surpassed the previously reported electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>V. Sridevi, N. Abirami, R. Arulmozhi, Pavithra Suresh, Kayalvizhi Rajagopal</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403746</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Electrolyte pH in Additive&#8208;Free NiFe Catalyst Electrodeposition for Electro&#8208;Catalytic OER Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400492</link>
      <description>Maximilian Cieluch, Norbert Kazamer, Leonard B&#246;hm, Sebastian Sanden, Swen Zerebecki, Florian J. Wirkert, Ulf&#8208;Peter Apfel, Michael Brodmann, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405247823

                Abstract This study presents the correlation between electrolyte pH, surface morphology, chemical speciation and electro&#8208;catalytic oxygen evolution activity of additive&#8208;free electrodeposited NiFe catalysts for application in anion exchange membrane water electrolysis. Spherical morphologies were identified at pH 0, shifting towards honey&#8208;combed structures at pH 4 with increasing surface area, especially at pH 3. Further, the electrolyte pH was found to influence the NiFe composition and electro&#8208;catalytic activity. Enhanced OER activity was noted at pH 2 with overpotentials of 214 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and 267 mV at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . The results reveal that the electrolyte pH is a parameter not only influencing the morphology but also tailoring the surface area, Fe oxide and Fe hydroxide composition and consequently the catalytic activity. Further, the outcomes highlight the electrolyte pH as a key process parameter that should be adjusted according to the application, and may substitute the addition of electrolyte&#8208;additives, proposing a simpler method for improving catalyst electrodeposition.</description>
      <author>Maximilian Cieluch, Norbert Kazamer, Leonard B&#246;hm, Sebastian Sanden, Swen Zerebecki, Florian J. Wirkert, Ulf&#8208;Peter Apfel, Michael Brodmann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Electrocatalyst Degradation Testing by Accurate and Robust Forecasting of Multidimensional Kinetic Model with Bayesian Data Assimilation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02868</link>
      <description>Miao Wang, Akimitsu Ishii, Ken Sakaushi, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405193872

                Degradation tests represent a significant bottleneck in electrochemical technology development, occasionally requiring tens of thousands of hours. Thus, reliable degradation forecasting in a short time frame is a game-changer in accelerating the establishment of future electrochemical devices. Herein, we show a multidimensional kinetic model for electrocatalyst degradation by quantifying the relationship among potential, current, and time, applicable under various conditions. Aiming to predict reliable degradation behaviors in shorter experimental timeframes and inspired by modern weather forecasting methods, we integrated Bayesian data assimilation with our model to expedite multidimensional parameter optimization. Consequently, we achieved accurate and robust forecasting of electrocatalyst lifetime by employing oxygen evolution reaction as a representative system: it takes just 300 h to obtain the final lifetime of close to 1000 h even with environmental noise. This data-driven approach can accelerate our understanding of the microscopic electrochemical mechanisms and simultaneously directly bridge this understanding to develop next-generation energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Miao Wang, Akimitsu Ishii, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c02868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovations and Challenges in Water Electrolysis for Sustainable Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.55529/jeet.46.22.35</link>
      <description>Tanvir Haider, Zulfiqar Haider, Journal of Energy Engineering and Thermodynamics. None(46)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405208416

                Hydrogen is renewable, efficient energy carrier that can contribute to solve the climate change problem when paired with sustainable electricity and water electrolysis. While PEM electrolysis is outstanding in producing high purity of hydrogen, the AWE electrolysis has been Versatile in meeting several industrial purposes. AEM technology is considered as more cost effective than the existing technologies which uses highly costly metal catalysts such as Pt, Au, Ru, etc. However, water electrolysis which is a sustainable method for hydrogen production supplies only 4% of the global hydrogen due to high costs. Unfortunately, the use of precious metals constrains the prospect of scale-up; nevertheless, automation-based naked-metal electrocatalysts can be advanced as cost-effective yet conductive and electrocatalytically active solutions. But much more work has to be done to improve their characteristics and stability. In the context of this paper, the major developments and problems in water electrolysis are discussed based on the outlook for the effective and inexpensive catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions. To this end, it seeks to overcome these barriers in order to provide direction to future studies and facilitate the development of cost-effective water electrolyzers for sustainable hydrogen generation.</description>
      <author>Tanvir Haider, Zulfiqar Haider</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.55529/jeet.46.22.35</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Urea Oxidation Reaction Through Layered Double Hydroxides: Insights From &lt;scp&gt;ZIF&lt;/scp&gt;&#8208;67&#8208;Derived Nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12510</link>
      <description>Yuri Jeon, Jury J. Medvedev, Yeeun Seong, Xenia V. Medvedeva, Cheongwon Bae, Jeongeon Kim, Anna Klinkova, Juyeong Kim, EcoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405249297

                ABSTRACT Layered double hydroxides (LDHs) are ionic layered compounds characterized by anion&#8208;containing intermediate regions within positively charged brucite&#8208;like layers. LDHs have shown high electrochemical activity in energy conversion systems such as batteries and fuel cells. In this study, we developed a hierarchically porous nanostructure derived from zeolitic imidazolate framework&#8208;67, which was subsequently transformed into an LDH structure with varying Ni concentrations. We precisely controlled the Ni&#8208;to&#8208;Co ratio within the LDH structure and investigated how different mole fractions of Co and Ni influence catalytic activity and selectivity for the electrochemical urea oxidation reaction (UOR). LDH structures with low Ni content (up to 40%) demonstrated high activity and selectivity for O 2 due to their structural instability and the predominant oxygen evolution reaction (OER) originating from ZIF&#8208;67. In contrast, LDHs with high Ni content (over 60%) supressed OER and exhibited enhanced activity for UOR. The resulting hollow structure with an expanded electrochemically active surface in LDHs with high Ni content could improve mass transport and diffusion at the electrode interface, leading to better reaction kinetics and higher current densities. These findings provide a foundational design guideline for metal&#8211;organic framework&#8208;derived nanostructure in UOR. image</description>
      <author>Yuri Jeon, Jury J. Medvedev, Yeeun Seong, Xenia V. Medvedeva, Cheongwon Bae, Jeongeon Kim, Anna Klinkova, Juyeong Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecogeographic body size clines in turtles: analysis and synthesis of pattern and process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/biolinnean/blae108</link>
      <description>C. K. Yang, John B. Iverson, Joshua R. Ennen, Njal Rollinson, Biological Journal of the Linnean Society. 143(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405251489

                Abstract The mechanisms underpinning the evolution of ectotherm body size across temperature and latitude remain an enduring mystery. Oxygen limitation in warmer aquatic environments is often invoked to explain steeper temperature&#8211;size relationships of aquatic species across latitude, but the role of aquatic environments on body size evolution of aquatic species that respire primarily in air is unclear. We tested the generality of intraspecific temperature&#8211;size responses in Testudines, assessing whether turtles generally follow Bergmann&#8217;s Rule, and whether aquatic versus terrestrial turtles exhibit different temperature&#8211;size responses. Using a global dataset of turtle body sizes, we found that turtles generally show decreasing body size with increasing temperature. However, we also found that aquatic, semi-aquatic, and terrestrial turtles respond similarly to temperature. Our study affirms the possibility that temperature&#8211;size relationships are driven partly by oxygen limitation in other ectotherms, but casts doubt on hypotheses related to oxygen limitation for groups that respire primarily in air. We formalize and explore a hypothesis that temperature&#8211;size responses in turtles are a result of heat balance, arguing small size in warm environments reduces overheating risk, and large size in cool environments minimizes heat loss. Ultimately, we provide new insight and direction in the study of ecogeographic clines.</description>
      <author>C. K. Yang, John B. Iverson, Joshua R. Ennen, Njal Rollinson</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/biolinnean/blae108</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilized Oxygen Vacancy Chemistry toward High-Performance Layered Oxide Cathodes for Sodium-Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14724</link>
      <description>Cheng Chen, Zengqing Zhuo, Xia Xiao, Tong Liu, Yihao Shen, Yuan Cheng, Pan Zeng, Duanyun Cao, Ying Zou, Jinghua Guo, Liang Zhang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405318406

                Anionic redox has emerged as a transformative paradigm for high-energy layered transition-metal (TM) oxide cathodes, but it is usually accompanied by the formation of anionic redox-mediated oxygen vacancies (OVs) due to irreversible oxygen release. Additionally, external factor-induced OVs (defined as intrinsic OVs) also play a pivotal role in the physicochemical properties of layered TM oxides. However, an in-depth understanding of the interplay between intrinsic and anionic redox-mediated OVs and the corresponding regulation mechanism of the dynamic evolution of OVs is still missing. Herein, we disclose the strong interrelationship between these OVs and demonstrate that the presence of intrinsic OVs in the TMO</description>
      <author>Cheng Chen, Zengqing Zhuo, Xia Xiao, Tong Liu, Yihao Shen, Yuan Cheng, Pan Zeng, Duanyun Cao, Ying Zou, Jinghua Guo, Liang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and seasonal characteristics of organic vapors in urban Beijing: insights from Vocus-PTR measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-13793-2024</link>
      <description>Zhaojin An, Rujing Yin, Xinyan Zhao, Xiaoxiao Li, Yuyang Li, Yi Yuan, Junchen Guo, Yiqi Zhao, Xue Li, Dandan Li, Yaowei Li, Dongbin Wang, Chao Yan, Kebin He, Douglas R. Worsnop, Frank N. Keutsch, Jingkun Jiang, Atmospheric chemistry and physics. 24(23)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405322441

                Abstract. Understanding the composition and evolution of atmospheric organic vapors is crucial for exploring their impact on air quality. However, the molecular and seasonal characteristics of organic vapors in urban areas, with complex anthropogenic emissions and high variability, remain inadequately understood. In this study, we conducted measurements in urban Beijing during 2021&#8211;2022, covering four seasons, using improved proton-transfer-reaction mass spectrometry (Vocus-PTR-MS). During the measurement period, a total of 895 peaks were observed, and 512 of them can be assigned to formulas. The contribution of CxHyOz species is most significant, composing up to 54 % of the number and 74 % of the mixing ratio of total organics. With enhanced sensitivity and mass resolution, various species with multiple oxygens (&#8805; 3) or at a level of sub-parts per trillion (ppt) were observed, with 44 % of the number measured at sub-ppt level and 38 % of the number containing three&#8211;eight oxygen atoms. Organic vapors with multiple oxygens mainly consist of intermediate/semi-volatile compounds, and many formulae detected were reported to be the oxidation products of various volatile organic precursors. In summer, the fast photooxidation process generated organic vapors with multiple oxygens and led to an increase in both their mixing ratio and proportion, while, in other seasons, the variations in organic vapors with multiple oxygens were closely correlated with those of organic vapors with 1&#8211;2 oxygens, which could be substantially influenced by primary emissions. Organic vapors with low oxygen content (&#8804; 2 oxygens) are comparable to the results obtained by traditional PTR-MS measurements in both urban Beijing and neighboring regions.</description>
      <author>Zhaojin An, Rujing Yin, Xinyan Zhao, Xiaoxiao Li, Yuyang Li, Yi Yuan, Junchen Guo, Yiqi Zhao, Xue Li, Dandan Li, Yaowei Li, Dongbin Wang, Chao Yan, Kebin He, Douglas R. Worsnop, Frank N. Keutsch, Jingkun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/acp-24-13793-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Explode or Not Explode? An Analysis of the Explodability of Binary and Single Stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/2515-5172/ad9baa</link>
      <description>Sangeeta Kumar, Luca Boccioli, Research Notes of the AAS. 8(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405279288

                Abstract Most massive stars in our universe are born in binary systems, and yet their fates are quite uncertain, due to a poor understanding of their evolution. It is well known, however, that the density profile of a collapsing core, particularly at the interface between silicon and oxygen shells, is important when determining the explodability of a star. While this has been studied for single stars, it has been rarely studied for binary stars. In this note, we explore the explodability of single and binary stars using self-consistent supernova simulations. We study the differences in the silicon&#8211;oxygen interface and compactness of the progenitor stars and how they affect the explodability. We find that binary-stripped stars with initial masses above 37 M &#8857; are not as explodable as their single-star counterparts.</description>
      <author>Sangeeta Kumar, Luca Boccioli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/2515-5172/ad9baa</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nutrient-rich spatial refuges buffer against extinction and promote evolutionary rescue in evolving microbial populations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2024.2197</link>
      <description>Matthew Kelbrick, Andy Fenton, Steven R. Parratt, James P. J. Hall, Siobh&#225;n O&#8217;Brien, Proceedings of the Royal Society B Biological Sciences. 291(2036)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405221396

                Microbial populations are often exposed to long-term abiotic disturbances, which can reduce population viability and cause local extinction. Eco-evolutionary theory suggests that spatial refuges can facilitate persistence and evolutionary rescue. However, one drawback of spatial refuges is reduced exposure to nutrients such as carbon and oxygen, suggesting the protective effect of refuges depends on the interplay between environmental conditions and the degree of stress. Here, we test this general idea using mathematical modelling, and experimental evolution of the model bacterium</description>
      <author>Matthew Kelbrick, Andy Fenton, Steven R. Parratt, James P. J. Hall, Siobh&#225;n O&#8217;Brien</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1098/rspb.2024.2197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas dynamics around a Jupiter-mass planet. II. Chemical evolution of circumplanetary material</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451140</link>
      <description>A. Cridland, Elena Lega, M. Benisty, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405229724

                The link between the chemistry of the protoplanetary disk and the properties of the resulting planets have long been a subject of interest in the effort to understand planet formation. These connections have generally been made between mature planets and young protoplanetary disks through the carbon-to-oxygen (C/O) ratio. In a rare number of systems, young protoplanets have been found within their natal protoplanetary disks. These systems offer a unique opportunity to directly study the delivery of gas from the protoplanetary disk to the planet. In this work we post-process 3D numerical simulations of an embedded Jupiter-mass planet in its protoplanetary disk to explore the chemical evolution of gas as it flows from the disk to the planet. The relevant dust to this chemical evolution is assumed to be small co-moving grains with a reduced dust-to-gas ratio indicative of the upper atmosphere of a protoplanetary disk. We find that as the gas enters deep into the planet's gravitational well, it warms significantly (up to $ 800$ K), releasing all of the volatile content from the ice phase. This change in phase can influence our understanding of the delivery of volatile species to the atmospheres of giant planets. The primary carbon, oxygen, and sulphur carrying ices (CO$_2$, H$_2$O, and H$_2$S) are released into the gas phase and along with the warm gas temperatures near the embedded planets lead to the production of unique species such as CS, SO, and SO$_2$ compared to the protoplanetary disk. We compute the column densities of SO, SO$_2$, CS, and H$_2$CS in our model and find that their values are consistent with previous observational studies.</description>
      <author>A. Cridland, Elena Lega, M. Benisty</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451140</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of O,F Co-Modified g-C3N4 for Photocatalytic H2 Evolution Activity Improvement and Corrosion Protection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14121063</link>
      <description>Shiyu Zhou, Pei Li, Chunbo Zhang, Yang Wang, Jingting Hu, Ruokun Jia, Crystals. 14(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405195974

                Herein, we report the rational synthesis of porous g-C3N4 co-modified with oxygen (O) and fluorine (F) for the first time. Incorporating colloidal SiO2 during thermal polymerization introduces lattice oxygen, forming C&#8211;O bonds, while post-treatment with NH4&#183;HF2 establishes C&#8211;F bonds. The dual incorporation of O and F elements extends visible light absorption and effectively promotes the separation and transport of photoexcited charge carriers. Consequently, the co-modified g-C3N4 (O,F-g-C3N4) achieves a 13.2-fold increase in H2 evolution rate compared to pristine g-C3N4. This synthesized O,F-g-C3N4 is then dispersed in waterborne polyurethane (WPU) to create an anti-corrosive coating for Q235 carbon steel substrates. Water resistance, mechanical property, and electrochemical characterization analyses reveal that the O,F-g-C3N4/WPU composite coating exhibits remarkable corrosion resistance with a high protection efficiency of 90.23%. This work offers a straightforward approach for developing highly efficient g-C3N4-based photocatalysts and corrosion-resistant coatings.</description>
      <author>Shiyu Zhou, Pei Li, Chunbo Zhang, Yang Wang, Jingting Hu, Ruokun Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/cryst14121063</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical nanoparticle formation in iron combustion: single particle
  experiments with in-situ multi-parameter diagnostics aided by multi-scale
  simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.08736</link>
      <description>Tao Li, Bich-Diep Nguyen, Yawei Gao, Daoguan Ning, Benjamin B&#246;hm, Arne Scholtissek, Adri C. T. van Duin, Christian Hasse, Andreas Dreizler, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405354530

                The formation of iron oxide nanoparticles (NPs) presents challenges such as efficiency losses and fine dust emissions in practical iron combustion systems, highlighting the need for deeper understanding of the formation mechanisms and thermochemical conditions. This study combines experiments and multi-scale simulations to analyze NP clouds generated by single iron particles burning in high-temperature oxidizing environments. The ambient gas conditions were provided by a laminar flat flame burner, with post-flame oxygen mole fractions varied between 20, 30, and 40 vol% at a constant temperature of ~1800K. High-speed in-situ diagnostics were used to measure particle size, NP initiation, NP cloud evolution, and microparticle surface temperature history. The experimental setup utilized three 10kHz imaging systems: one for two-color pyrometry and two for diffusive-backlight illumination (DBI), targeting particle size and NP measurements. The findings showcase the powerful capabilities of multi-physics diagnostics in quantifying NP initiation time and temperature, which depend on particle size and ambient oxygen concentration. CFD simulations revealed enhanced convection velocity driven by increased Stefan flow, which transported NPs toward parent iron particles under high-oxygen conditions. This delayed the detection of NP clouds, leading to higher microparticle temperatures at NP initiation. Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations uncovered FeO2(g) as a key NP precursor, forming when Fe atoms dissociate from the liquid phase. The initial temperature significantly influenced the resulting nanocluster composition, with Fe(II) dominating at higher temperatures and Fe(III) at lower temperatures. This integrated approach enhances understanding of NP formation in iron combustion, offering insights into the conditions affecting nanoparticle characteristics.</description>
      <author>Tao Li, Bich-Diep Nguyen, Yawei Gao, Daoguan Ning, Benjamin B&#246;hm, Arne Scholtissek, Adri C. T. van Duin, Christian Hasse, Andreas Dreizler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.08736</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early&#8208;Branching Cyanobacteria Grow Faster and Upregulate Superoxide Dismutase Activity Under a Simulated Early Earth Anoxic Atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/gbi.70005</link>
      <description>Sadia S. Tamanna, Joanne S. Boden, Kimberly Michelle Kaiser, Nicola Wannicke, Jonas Hoering, Patricia S&#225;nchez&#8208;Baracaldo, Marcel Deponte, Nicole Frankenberg&#8208;Dinkel, Michelle M. Gehringer, Geobiology. 22(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405322204

                ABSTRACT The evolution of oxygenic photosynthesis during the Archean (4&#8211;2.5 Ga) required the presence of complementary reducing pathways to maintain the cellular redox balance. While the timing of the evolution of superoxide dismutases (SODs), enzymes that convert superoxide to hydrogen peroxide and O 2 , within bacteria and archaea is not resolved, the first SODs appearing in cyanobacteria contained copper and zinc in the reaction center (CuZnSOD). Here, we analyse growth characteristics, SOD gene expression (qRT&#8208;PCR) and cellular enzyme activity in the deep branching strain, Pseudanabaena sp. PCC7367, previously demonstrated to release significantly more O 2 under anoxic conditions. The observed significantly higher growth rates ( p &lt; 0.001) and protein and glycogen contents ( p &lt; 0.05) in anoxically cultured Pseudanabaena PCC7367 compared to control cultures grown under present&#8208;day oxygen&#8208;rich conditions prompted the following question: Is the growth of Pseudanabaena sp. PCC7367 correlated to atmospheric p O 2 and cellular SOD activity? Expression of sodB (encoding FeSOD) and sodC (encoding CuZnSOD) strongly correlated with medium O 2 levels ( p &lt; 0.001). Expression of sodA (encoding MnSOD) correlated significantly to SOD activity during the day ( p = 0.019) when medium O 2 concentrations were the highest. The cellular SOD enzyme activity of anoxically grown cultures was significantly higher ( p &lt; 0.001) 2 h before the onset of the dark phase compared to O 2 &#8208;rich growth conditions. The expression of SOD encoding genes was significantly reduced ( p &lt; 0.05) under anoxic conditions in stirred cultures, as were medium O 2 levels ( p &#8804; 0.001), compared to oxic&#8208;grown cultures, whereas total cellular SOD activity remained comparable. Our data suggest that increasing p O 2 negatively impacts the viability of early cyanobacteria, possibly by increasing photorespiration. Additionally, the increased expression of superoxide&#8208;inactivating genes during the dark phase suggests the increased replacement rates of SODs under modern&#8208;day conditions compared to those on early Earth.</description>
      <author>Sadia S. Tamanna, Joanne S. Boden, Kimberly Michelle Kaiser, Nicola Wannicke, Jonas Hoering, Patricia S&#225;nchez&#8208;Baracaldo, Marcel Deponte, Nicole Frankenberg&#8208;Dinkel, Michelle M. Gehringer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/gbi.70005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viral niche-partitioning: Comparative genomics of giant viruses across environmental gradients in a High Arctic freshwater-saltwater lake</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ismeco/ycae155</link>
      <description>Thomas M. Pitot, Catherine Girard, Josephine Z. Rapp, Vincent Somerville, Alexander I. Culley, Warwick F. Vincent, Sylvain Moineau, Simon Roux, ISME Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405222482

                Abstract Giant viruses (GVs; Nucleocytoviricota) impact the biology and ecology of a wide range of eukaryotic hosts, with implications for global biogeochemical cycles. Here, we investigated GV niche separation in highly stratified Lake A at the northern coast of Ellesmere Island, Nunavut, Canada. This lake is composed of a layer of ice-covered freshwater that overlies saltwater derived from the ancient Arctic Ocean, and it therefore provides a broad gradient of environmental conditions and ecological habitats, each with a distinct protist community and rich assemblages of associated GVs. The upper layer (mixolimnion) had measurable light and oxygen, and contained diverse GVs linked to photosynthetic protists, indicating adaptation to surface biotic and abiotic conditions. In contrast, the saline lower layer (monimolimnion), lacking oxygen and light, hosted GVs associated with predicted heterotrophic protists, some of which are known for a predatory lifestyle, and with several viral genes suggesting adaptation to deep-water anaerobic conditions. Our observations underscore the coupling between physical and chemical gradients, microeukaryotes and their associated GVs in Lake A, and provide insight into the potential for GVs to directly and indirectly impact host metabolism. There were similarities between the genetic composition of GVs and the metabolic processes of their potential hosts, implying co-evolution and niche-adaptation within the lake habitats. Notably, we found a greater presence of viral rhodopsins in deeper water layers, suggesting an evolutionary relationship with potential hosts capable of supplementing their energetic needs to thrive in low energy, anoxic conditions.</description>
      <author>Thomas M. Pitot, Catherine Girard, Josephine Z. Rapp, Vincent Somerville, Alexander I. Culley, Warwick F. Vincent, Sylvain Moineau, Simon Roux</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ismeco/ycae155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Numerical simulation study on the mechanism of plasma dissociation of carbon dioxide in atmospheric pressure packed-bed reactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.74.20241241</link>
      <description>Yi Peng, Chunjing Wang, Jing Li, K. Gao, Han Xu, Chuan-Jie Chen, Muyang Qian, Bingyan Dong, Dezhen Wang, Acta Physica Sinica. 74(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405263325

                The streamer propagation and electric field distribution in a two-dimensional fluid model of a packed bed reactor (PBR) filled with carbon dioxide are comprehensively studied by utilizing the PASSKEy simulation platform in this work. The spatiotemporal evolution of electron density, electric fields and key plasma species in the discharge process are studied in depth. The PBR with layered dielectric spheres is simulated by using the model, indicating that the inner sides of the first layer and the second layer of dielectric spheres are not the main regions for reactions such as CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; dissociation; instead, the main regions are along the streamer propagation path and the outer side of the first layer of dielectric sphere. In this work, the propagation of streamers in an electric field is investigated, highlighting the influence of anode voltage rise and dielectric polarization on local electric field enhancement. This enhancement leads the electron density and temperature to increase, which facilitats streamer propagation and the formation of filamentary microdischarges and surface ionization waves. This work provides a detailed analysis of the local electric field evolution at specific points within the PBR, and a further investigation of the spatiotemporal dynamics of spatial and surface charges, revealing that negative charges concentrate in the streamer and on the dielectric surface, with density being significantly higher than that of positive charges. The positive charge distribution is closely related to the streamer path, and with time going by, the charge distribution becomes dominated in the discharge space. This work also explores the surface charge deposition on the dielectric spheres, and discusses the evolution trend of the distribution. Additionally, this work discusses the temporal and spatial evolution of key plasma species, including ions and radicals, and their contributions to the overall discharge characteristics. The production mechanisms of carbon monoxide particles, carbon dioxide ions, and oxygen ions are analyzed, with a focus on their spatial distribution and correlation with electron density. Finally, the energy deposition within the PBR is examined by integrating the spatial energy deposition of electrons and major positive ions. The results indicate a total energy deposition value of approximately 1.428 mJ/m, with carbon dioxide ions accounting for 8.8% of this value.</description>
      <author>Yi Peng, Chunjing Wang, Jing Li, K. Gao, Han Xu, Chuan-Jie Chen, Muyang Qian, Bingyan Dong, Dezhen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.74.20241241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of superconductivity in electron-hole coexisting
  Sr$_{1-x}$Eu$_{x}$CuO$_{2+y}$ films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.08213</link>
      <description>Hang Yan, Ze-Xian Deng, Xue-Qing Yu, Yanling Xiong, Qun Zhu, Ding Zhang, Can&#8208;Li Song, Xucun Ma, Qi&#8208;Kun Xue, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405301268

                We report transport measurements of infinite-layer cuprate Sr$_{1-x}$Eu$_{x}$CuO$_{2+y}$ films with controlled electron (by trivalent europium) and hole (by interstitial apical oxygen) carriers grown on SrTiO$_3$(001) with molecular beam epitaxy. An unusual enhancement of superconductivity upon moderate electron-hole coexistence in the films is found, which spans over the whole superconducting phase diagram and becomes more prominent in the underdoped regime. The superconductivity exhibits a two-dimensional nature with a thickness of approximately 5.2 nm, irrespective of the varying carriers, confirmed by angle-resolved magnetoresistance measurements and the Berzzinsky-Kosterlitz-Thouless transition. Nevertheless, the electron-hole coexistence enlarges the thermal activation energy of vortex motion that deviates obviously from the usual logarithmic evolution with the magnetic field. Our results offer a promising perspective to understand and enhance the high-temperature superconductivity in cuprates.</description>
      <author>Hang Yan, Ze-Xian Deng, Xue-Qing Yu, Yanling Xiong, Qun Zhu, Ding Zhang, Can&#8208;Li Song, Xucun Ma, Qi&#8208;Kun Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.08213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Properties of Type Ibn/Icn Supernovae and Their
  Progenitor Channels through X-ray Emission</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.09066</link>
      <description>Yusuke Inoue, Keiichi Maeda, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405354908

                Type Ibn/Icn supernovae (SNe Ibn/Icn), which are characterized by narrow helium or carbon lines originated in hydrogen-poor dense circumstellar medium (CSM), provide new insights into the final evolution of massive stars. While SNe Ibn/Icn are expected to emit strong X-rays through the strong SN-CSM interaction, the X-ray emission modeling effort has been limited so far. In the present study, we provide broad-band X-ray light curve (LC) predictions for SNe Ibn/Icn. We find that the soft X-ray LC provides information about the CSM compositions, while the hard X-ray LC is a robust measure of the CSM density, the explosion energy, and the ejecta mass. In addition, considering the evolution of the ionization state in the unshocked CSM, a bright soft X-ray is expected in the first few days since the explosion, which encourages rapid X-ray follow-up observations as a tool to study the nature of SNe Ibn/Icn. Applying our model to the soft X-ray LCs of SNe Ibn 2006jc and 2022ablq, we derive that the CSM potentially contains a larger fraction of carbon and oxygen for SN 2006jc than 2022ablq, highlighting the power of the soft X-ray modeling to address the nature of the CSM. We also discuss detectability and observational strategy, with which the currently operating telescopes such as NuSTAR and Swift can offer an irreplaceable opportunity to explore the nature of these enigmatic rapid transients and their still-unclarified progenitor channel(s).</description>
      <author>Yusuke Inoue, Keiichi Maeda</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.09066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Reactivity-Triggered Oscillatory Lattice Strains of Nanoalloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12550</link>
      <description>Zhi&#8208;Peng Wu, Dong Dinh, Yazan Maswadeh, Dominic Caracciolo, Shouxin Zhang, Tianyi Li, Jorge Vargas, Merry Madiou, Cailing Chen, Zhijie Kong, Zeqi Li, Huabin Zhang, Javier Ruiz&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Shao&#8208;Lun Lu, Lichang Wang, Yang Ren, Valeri Petkov, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405239837

                Understanding the structure evolution of nanoalloys under reaction conditions is vital to the design of active and durable catalysts. Herein, we report an operando measurement of the dynamic lattice strains of dual-noble-metal alloyed with an earth-abundant metal as a model electrocatalyst in a working proton-exchange membrane fuel cell using synchrotron high-energy X-ray diffraction coupled with pair distribution function analysis. The results reveal an interfacial reaction-triggered oscillatory lattice strain in the alloy nanoparticles upon surface dealloying. Analysis of the lattice strains with an apparent oscillatory irregularity in terms of frequency and amplitude using time-frequency domain transformation and theoretical calculation reveals its origin from a metal atom vacancy diffusion pathway to facilitate realloying upon dealloying. This process, coupled with surface metal partial oxidation, constitutes a key factor for the nanoalloy's durability under the electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction condition, which serves as a new guiding principle for engineering durable or self-healable electrocatalysts for sustainable fuel cell energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Zhi&#8208;Peng Wu, Dong Dinh, Yazan Maswadeh, Dominic Caracciolo, Shouxin Zhang, Tianyi Li, Jorge Vargas, Merry Madiou, Cailing Chen, Zhijie Kong, Zeqi Li, Huabin Zhang, Javier Ruiz&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Shao&#8208;Lun Lu, Lichang Wang, Yang Ren, Valeri Petkov, Chuan&#8208;Jian Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anisotropic Strain Evolution of Layered LiNi&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;Mn&lt;sub&gt;0.3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Cathode in Formation Cycle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409279</link>
      <description>Kaili Li, Weixin Chen, Zhiling Liu, Yuansheng Shi, Guoyu Qian, Xueyi Lu, Bin Wei, Qinghua Zhang, Yang Sun, Xia Lu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405338797

                Abstract The formation process plays a key role in developing long life and high energy density materials, during which the phase transition, strain evolution, and structural self&#8208;adaption interact rationally with each other to produce a qualified electrode for Li&#8208;ion batteries (LIBs). Taking the layered LiNi 0.5 Co 0.2 Mn 0.3 O 2 cathode as an example, the substantial structural changes, both in the bulk and at the surface are thoroughly documented during the formation cycle. Upon initial charging, different phases emerge continuously, resulting in lattice mismatches, inhomogeneous strain, and microstructural distortions. The irreversible loss of lattice oxygen, combined with the spontaneous cation mixing and the formation of rock&#8208;salt phase at the surface, contributes to the initial capacity loss. As a self&#8208;adjustment process, this initial capacity loss facilitates the development of a robust Li x Ni 0.5 Co 0.2 Mn 0.3 O 2 electrode by relieving internal strain and stabilizing the rippled layered structure, thereby ensuring highly reversible electrochemical behavior in subsequent cycles. These findings lay a solid foundation for the design and optimization of layered cathodes for rechargeable batteries.</description>
      <author>Kaili Li, Weixin Chen, Zhiling Liu, Yuansheng Shi, Guoyu Qian, Xueyi Lu, Bin Wei, Qinghua Zhang, Yang Sun, Xia Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C/O ratios in self-gravitating protoplanetary discs with dust evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.05099</link>
      <description>Tamara Molyarova, E. I. Vorobyov, Vitaly Akimkin, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405174026

                Elemental abundances, particularly the C/O ratio, are seen as a way to connect the composition of planetary atmospheres with planet formation scenario and the disc chemical environment. We model the chemical composition of gas and ices in a self-gravitating disc on timescales of 0.5\,Myr since its formation to study the evolution of C/O ratio due to dust dynamics and growth, and phase transitions of the volatile species. We use the thin-disc hydrodynamic code FEOSAD, which includes disc self-gravity, thermal balance, dust evolution and turbulent diffusion, and treats dust as a dynamically different and evolving component interacting with the gas. It also describes freeze-out, sublimation and advection of four volatile species: H$_2$O, CO$_2$, CH$_4$ and CO. We demonstrate the effect of gas and dust substructures on the distribution of volatiles and C/O ratios, including the formation of multiple snowlines of one species, and point out the anticorrelation between dust-to-gas ratio and total C/O ratio emerging due to the contribution of oxygen-rich ice mantles. We identify time and spatial locations where two distinct trigger mechanisms for planet formation are operating and differentiate them by C/O ratio range: wide range of the C/O ratios of $0-1.4$ for streaming instability, and a much narrower range $0.3-0.6$ for gravitational instability (with the initial value of 0.34). This conclusion is corroborated by observations, showing that transiting exoplanets, which possibly experienced migration through a variety of disc conditions, have significantly larger spread of C/O in comparison with directly imaged exoplanets likely formed in gravitationally unstable outer disk regions. We show that the ice-phase C/O$\approx0.2-0.3$ between the CO, CO$_2$ and CH$_4$ snowlines corresponds to the composition of the Solar system comets, that represent primordial planetesimals.</description>
      <author>Tamara Molyarova, E. I. Vorobyov, Vitaly Akimkin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2412.05099</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome and evolutionary analysis of &lt;i&gt;Pseudotrichomonas keilini&lt;/i&gt;, a free-living anaerobic eukaryote</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/gbe/evae262</link>
      <description>Hend Abu-Elmakarem, Stephen J. Taerum, C&#233;line Petitjean, Michael Kotyk, Chris Kay, Ivan &#268;epi&#269;ka, David Bass, Gillian H. Gile, Tom A. Williams, Genome Biology and Evolution. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405230354

                Abstract The early evolution of eukaryotes and their adaptations to low-oxygen environments are fascinating open questions in biology. Genome-scale data from novel eukaryotes, and particularly from free-living lineages, are key to answering these questions. The Parabasalia are a major group of anaerobic eukaryotes that form the most speciose lineage of Metamonada. The most well-studied are parasitic parabasalids including Trichomonas vaginalis and Tritrichomonas foetus, but very little genome-scale data is available for free-living members of the group. Here, we sequenced the transcriptome of Pseudotrichomonas keilini, a free-living parabasalian. Comparative genomic analysis indicated that P. keilini possesses a metabolism and gene complement that are in many respects similar to its parasitic relative Trichomonas vaginalis, and that in the time since their most recent common ancestor, it is the Trichomonas vaginalis lineage that has experienced more genomic change, likely due to the transition to a parasitic lifestyle. Features shared between P. keilini and Trichomonas vaginalis include a hydrogenosome (anaerobic mitochondrial homologue) that we predict to function much as in Trichomonas vaginalis, and a complete glycolytic pathway that is likely to represent one of the primary means by which P. keilini obtains ATP. Phylogenomic analysis indicates that P. keilini branches within a clade of endobiotic parabasalids, consistent with the hypothesis that different parabasalid lineages evolved towards parasitic or free-living lifestyles from an endobiotic, anaerobic or microaerophilic common ancestor.</description>
      <author>Hend Abu-Elmakarem, Stephen J. Taerum, C&#233;line Petitjean, Michael Kotyk, Chris Kay, Ivan &#268;epi&#269;ka, David Bass, Gillian H. Gile, Tom A. Williams</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/gbe/evae262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dissolution: Paths in High-Entropy Alloy Composition Space</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-4vt27</link>
      <description>Mads K. Plenge, Jack K. Pedersen, Luis A. Cipriano, Jan Rossmeisl, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405291320

                The stability of a nanoparticle catalyst during electrochemical reaction is crucial for its application. Despite increasing interest in multi-metallic alloy nanoparticles, such as high-entropy alloys (HEAs), for electrocatalysis and emerging models for their catalytic activity, there is limited work on frameworks that can predict the metastability of these alloys under reaction conditions, including stability against electrochemical surface dissolution. Incorporating electrochemical stability in multi-objective optimization would advance HEAs as a catalyst discovery platform. To address the knowledge gap on electrochemical stability, we propose a methodology for simulating the dissolution of n-element alloy nanoparticles comprised of density functional theory and machine learning regression to calculate the dissolution potentials of the surface atoms. We demonstrate the methodology for the Ag-Au-Cu-Ir-Pd-Pt-Rh-Ru HEA system with the conditions of the oxygen reduction reaction. We investigated trends in stability against dissolution through a compositional grid search for the octo-metallic composition space, uncovering two alloying strategies to increase stability against electrochemical surface dissolution: Alloying with a noble metal or a metal with high relative surface energy. In the simulations, stabilization ensues from forming a protective surface layer, and consequently, the dissolution of persistent alloyed nanoparticles results in core-shell structures. The model enables tracing the evolution of the surface and dissolved composition during electrochemical dissolution, forming paths of dissolution and revealing unretainable surface compositions.</description>
      <author>Mads K. Plenge, Jack K. Pedersen, Luis A. Cipriano, Jan Rossmeisl</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-4vt27</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geological and experimental evidence of bioavailable phosphite during the Great Oxygenation Event</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5118430/v1</link>
      <description>Abu Saeed Baidya, Joanne S. Boden, Yuhao Li, Albertus J.B. Smith, Kurt O. Konhauser, Eva Stueeken, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405202297

                Abstract Phosphorus (P) availability throughout geologic time has likely impacted the co-evolution of life and Earth&#8217;s environments. Phylogenetic data suggest that phosphate was the primary P-source for microbial life during the Archean, but phosphite, a reduced form of P, became relatively more important leading up towards the Great Oxygenation Event (GOE) in the Neoarchean to Paleoproterozoic. However, seawater phosphite concentrations during this time, and the potential processes driving this shift in P utilization, are unknown. Here, we performed laboratory experiments simulating the precipitation of banded iron formations (BIFs) as hydrous ferric oxyhydroxides (HFO) in deionized water, diluted seawater, and seawater containing phosphate and phosphite. We also measured phosphite concentrations in BIF samples from four Neoarchean-Paleoproterozoic formations. Our results indicate a weaker removal of phosphite compared to phosphate by HFO irrespective of solution chemistry. Paired with measurements of phosphite (up to 0.05&#8211;250 ppm) in BIFs, we estimate that seawater phosphite concentration at the onset of the GOE could have reached up to 0.01&#8211;0.17 &#181;M. We propose that the preferential removal of phosphate relative to phosphite by HFO, coupled with microbial competition for P facilitated by oxygenic photosynthesis, might have created phosphate-depleted environments, prompting life to exploit alternative P sources such as phosphite.</description>
      <author>Abu Saeed Baidya, Joanne S. Boden, Yuhao Li, Albertus J.B. Smith, Kurt O. Konhauser, Eva Stueeken</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5118430/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ones that got away: Chemical tagging of globular cluster-origin stars with gaia BP/RP spectra</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2689</link>
      <description>Sarah G. Kane, Vasily Belokurov, Miles Cranmer, Stephanie Monty, Hanyuan Zhang, Anke Arentsen, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405224720

                Abstract Globular clusters (GCs) are sites of extremely efficient star formation, and recent studies suggest they significantly contributed to the early Milky Way&#8217;s stellar mass build-up. Although their role has since diminished, GCs&#8217; impact on the Galaxy&#8217;s initial evolution can be traced today by identifying their most chemically unique stars&#8212;those with anomalous nitrogen and aluminum overabundances and oxygen depletion. While they are a perfect tracer of clusters, be it intact or fully dissolved, these high-[N/O], high-[Al/Fe] GC-origin stars are extremely rare within the current Galaxy. To address the scarcity of these unusual, precious former GC members, we train a neural network (NN) to identify high-[N/O], high-[Al/Fe] stars using low-resolution Gaia BP/RP spectra. Our NN achieves a classification accuracy of approximately $\approx 99~{{\%}}$ and a false positive rate of around $\approx 7~{{\%}}$, identifying 878new candidates in the Galactic field. We validate our results with several physically-motivated sanity checks, showing, for example, that the incidence of selected stars in Galactic GCs is significantly higher than in the field. Moreover, we find that most of our GC-origin candidates reside in the inner Galaxy, having likely formed in the proto-Milky Way, consistent with previous research. The fraction of GC candidates in the field drops at a metallicity of [Fe/H]&#8776;&#8722;1, approximately coinciding with the completion of spin-up, i.e. the formation of the Galactic stellar disk.</description>
      <author>Sarah G. Kane, Vasily Belokurov, Miles Cranmer, Stephanie Monty, Hanyuan Zhang, Anke Arentsen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2689</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply on RC3</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1416-ac3</link>
      <description>Robert T. Letscher, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405173779

                Abstract. Within the oligotrophic subtropical oceans, summertime DIC drawdown despite nutrient limitation in surface waters and subsurface oxygen consumption in the absence of Redfieldian stoichiometric nitrate release are two phenomena still awaiting a full mechanistic characterization. The distribution, intensity and seasonality of these phenomena are identified with preformed nitrate as a tracer, where negative preformed nitrate (NPN) anomalies below the euphotic zone correspond to oxygen consumption without Redfieldian NO3- release, and positive performed nitrate (PPN) anomalies found within the upper 100 m occur where O2 is produced without stoichiometric NO3- drawdown. &#160;Many processes that may contribute to these anomalies including N2 fixation, non-Redfieldian DOM cycling, vertically migrating phytoplankton, heterotrophic NO3- uptake and vertical NO3- injection events have been measured or modelled, yet generally cannot fully account for the magnitudes of preformed nitrate anomalies and excess DIC drawdown observed in many oligotrophic subtropical waters. One other candidate process that&#160;may contribute to both phenomena is the formation of carbon-rich transparent exopolymer particles (TEP) and Coomassie-stainable particles (CSP) from dissolved organic precursors in surface waters and their subsequent remineralization below the subsurface chlorophyll maximum (SCM). However, few data exist to quantify exopolymer production and vertical distributions in oligotrophic oceans over an annual cycle, which is necessary to understand their potential role in the evolution of seasonal preformed nitrate anomalies and DIC drawdown. To investigate the significance of exopolymer formation and export to North Pacific subtropical gyre biogeochemistry, we undertook a multi-year time-series (Jan 2020 &#8211; Sep 2022) analysis of TEP, CSP and total dissolved polysaccharides concentrations at Station ALOHA (22&#176; 45&#8217;,158&#176; W), and along a transect from 22&#176; 45&#8217; to 31&#176; N to measure latitudinal variability in June 2021.&#160; Exopolymer C:N stoichiometry at Station ALOHA varied between 16.4 &#8211; 34.3, with values being more carbon-rich in summer; ratios were higher (32&#8211;38) toward the gyre centre at 31&#176; N. TEP concentrations were consistently elevated in surface waters through Spring&#8211;Autumn (4&#8211;8 &#181;M C after carbon conversion) at Station ALOHA with lower concentrations (~1.5&#8211;3 &#181;M C)&#160; and more uniform vertical distribution during winter, indicating that TEP accumulated in surface waters may vertically sink and be exported with winter mixing. The accumulation of TEP in surface waters through Spring&#8211;Autumn and its subsequent export may account for 6.5&#8211;20 % of net community production (NCP), helping reduce the estimated imbalance of N supply and N demand at this site to &lt;10 %. The upper ocean TEP cycle may explain 22&#8211;67 % of the observed PPN/NPN anomalies, helping to close the C, N, and O2 budgets at station ALOHA, while leaving room for significant contributions from other processes such as vertically migrating phytoplankton and heterotrophic nitrate uptake to be further validated. These results suggest that exopolymer production and cycling may be more important to open ocean carbon biogeochemistry than previously expected, with considerable seasonality and spatial variability influenced by physical processes and phytoplankton activity.</description>
      <author>Robert T. Letscher</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1416-ac3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply on RC1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1416-ac1</link>
      <description>Robert T. Letscher, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405173796

                Abstract. Within the oligotrophic subtropical oceans, summertime DIC drawdown despite nutrient limitation in surface waters and subsurface oxygen consumption in the absence of Redfieldian stoichiometric nitrate release are two phenomena still awaiting a full mechanistic characterization. The distribution, intensity and seasonality of these phenomena are identified with preformed nitrate as a tracer, where negative preformed nitrate (NPN) anomalies below the euphotic zone correspond to oxygen consumption without Redfieldian NO3- release, and positive performed nitrate (PPN) anomalies found within the upper 100 m occur where O2 is produced without stoichiometric NO3- drawdown. &#160;Many processes that may contribute to these anomalies including N2 fixation, non-Redfieldian DOM cycling, vertically migrating phytoplankton, heterotrophic NO3- uptake and vertical NO3- injection events have been measured or modelled, yet generally cannot fully account for the magnitudes of preformed nitrate anomalies and excess DIC drawdown observed in many oligotrophic subtropical waters. One other candidate process that&#160;may contribute to both phenomena is the formation of carbon-rich transparent exopolymer particles (TEP) and Coomassie-stainable particles (CSP) from dissolved organic precursors in surface waters and their subsequent remineralization below the subsurface chlorophyll maximum (SCM). However, few data exist to quantify exopolymer production and vertical distributions in oligotrophic oceans over an annual cycle, which is necessary to understand their potential role in the evolution of seasonal preformed nitrate anomalies and DIC drawdown. To investigate the significance of exopolymer formation and export to North Pacific subtropical gyre biogeochemistry, we undertook a multi-year time-series (Jan 2020 &#8211; Sep 2022) analysis of TEP, CSP and total dissolved polysaccharides concentrations at Station ALOHA (22&#176; 45&#8217;,158&#176; W), and along a transect from 22&#176; 45&#8217; to 31&#176; N to measure latitudinal variability in June 2021.&#160; Exopolymer C:N stoichiometry at Station ALOHA varied between 16.4 &#8211; 34.3, with values being more carbon-rich in summer; ratios were higher (32&#8211;38) toward the gyre centre at 31&#176; N. TEP concentrations were consistently elevated in surface waters through Spring&#8211;Autumn (4&#8211;8 &#181;M C after carbon conversion) at Station ALOHA with lower concentrations (~1.5&#8211;3 &#181;M C)&#160; and more uniform vertical distribution during winter, indicating that TEP accumulated in surface waters may vertically sink and be exported with winter mixing. The accumulation of TEP in surface waters through Spring&#8211;Autumn and its subsequent export may account for 6.5&#8211;20 % of net community production (NCP), helping reduce the estimated imbalance of N supply and N demand at this site to &lt;10 %. The upper ocean TEP cycle may explain 22&#8211;67 % of the observed PPN/NPN anomalies, helping to close the C, N, and O2 budgets at station ALOHA, while leaving room for significant contributions from other processes such as vertically migrating phytoplankton and heterotrophic nitrate uptake to be further validated. These results suggest that exopolymer production and cycling may be more important to open ocean carbon biogeochemistry than previously expected, with considerable seasonality and spatial variability influenced by physical processes and phytoplankton activity.</description>
      <author>Robert T. Letscher</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1416-ac1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and optimizing Li substitution in P2-type Sodium Layered Oxides for Sodium-Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-7x9sm</link>
      <description>Mingfeng Xu, Giovanni Gammaitoni, Michael H&#228;fner, Edgar E. Villalobos-Portillo, Carlo Marini, Matteo Bianchini, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4405229224

                In the quest for novel cathode materials for Na-ion batteries, we studied a family of Li-substituted P2 layered oxides with nominal stoichiometry Na5/6LiyNi5/12-3y/2Mn7/12+y/2O2 (y = 2/18, 3/18, 4/18, 5/18). We explored the consequences of Li substitution, as well as the challenge of elevating the Na content in the pristine materials through solid-state synthesis. By in situ temperature-resolved x-ray diffraction (XRD) we observed the synthesis process, clearly showing the formation of an intermediate Li2MnO3 structure with increasing Li content. Structurally, honeycomb ordering is observed in all samples, while we show that Li induces the loss of Na+/vacancy ordering hence it leads to more disordered Na positions. Electrochemically, this family of materials exhibits an increasing trend of polarized hysteresis in the first cycle, suggesting the contribution of oxygen redox. We coupled semi-simultaneous operando x-ray absorption near edge structure (XANES) and XRD to appreciate the structural evolution and redox behavior during this process. We verified that Li in the transition metal site eliminates phase transitions at high voltage and modifies the activation of O-redox. As confirmed by our XANES analysis and by Density Functional Theory calculations, the Li-free sample already surprisingly show anionic redox despite the residual availability of Ni-redox, due to the peculiar density of states dominated by Ni-O hybridized states at high state of charge. On the other hand, Li-containing samples have O non-bonding states that lead to increasing O-redox contribution as expected due to the limited Ni content. One composition (Na0.745(6)Li0.164(4)Ni0.238(1)Mn0.599(3)O2) proves to have the lowest proportion of O-redox among all samples, coupled with reduced phase transitions, disordered occupancy of Na sites, and small volume change during cycling (4.8%). This material hence delivers the best balance of cycling stability (&#8764;92% after 100 cycles in half cells), capacity (&gt; 100 mAh/g) and rate capability. Determining this optimal compositional range is a promising starting point for further development of P2 layered oxides as cathode materials for Na-ion batteries and can be generalized to other families of Na-based layered oxides with redox-inactive dopants.</description>
      <author>Mingfeng Xu, Giovanni Gammaitoni, Michael H&#228;fner, Edgar E. Villalobos-Portillo, Carlo Marini, Matteo Bianchini</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-7x9sm</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
