<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 01:10:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-deficient LaMnO3+&#948; tuned by electrochemical methods for peroxymonosulfate activation towards organics removal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2024.206955</link>
      <description>Ximu Li, Huang Yao, Jie Miao, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Applied Catalysis O Open. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398762392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ximu Li, Huang Yao, Jie Miao, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcato.2024.206955</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient hydrogen production via overall water splitting using CuO/ZnO decorated reduced graphene oxide as bifunctional electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.355</link>
      <description>Umer Younas, Fizza Mobeen, Aimon Saleem, Faisal Ali, Maryam Al Huwayz, Adnan Ashraf, Awais Ahmad, Norah Alwadai, Muhammad Pervaiz, Munawar Iqbal, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398762739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Umer Younas, Fizza Mobeen, Aimon Saleem, Faisal Ali, Maryam Al Huwayz, Adnan Ashraf, Awais Ahmad, Norah Alwadai, Muhammad Pervaiz, Munawar Iqbal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the acidic oxygen evolution reaction performance of RuO2-TiO2 by a reduction-oxidation process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad501d</link>
      <description>J. Zhang, Yu Song, Wenwei Liu, Qian Zheng, Liang Yu, Tianli Wu, Tao Li, Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398763012

                Abstract As a promising alternative to Ir based acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, Ru suffers from severe fading issues. Supporting it on robust oxides such as TiO2 is a simple and effective way to enhance its lifetime. Here, we find that a simple reduction-oxidation process can further improve both activity and stability of RuO2-TiO2 composites at high potentials. In this process, the degree of oxidation was carefully controlled to form Ru/RuO2 heterostructure to improve OER activity. Moreover, due to the oxophilicity difference of Ru and Ti, the structure of catalysts was changed from supported to embedded, which enhanced the protective effect of TiO2 and mitigated the dissolution of Ru element in acidic electrolyte, making as-prepared Ru/RuO2-TiO2 with better durability at all tested potentials.</description>
      <author>J. Zhang, Yu Song, Wenwei Liu, Qian Zheng, Liang Yu, Tianli Wu, Tao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad501d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-doped nickel phosphide hollow nanospheres synthesized by solvothermal phosphidization of layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc01389a</link>
      <description>Zeyi Wang, Shilin Liu, Jun Du, Yan Ma, Yafei Hu, Yichuang Xing, Xin L&#252;, Chao Wang, Green chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398765333

                Active and stable electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are the key to the development of hydrogen production from alkaline water electrolysis. Here, iron-doped nickel phosphide grown on nickel foam...</description>
      <author>Zeyi Wang, Shilin Liu, Jun Du, Yan Ma, Yafei Hu, Yichuang Xing, Xin L&#252;, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc01389a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Organic coating strategy with oxidized oxygen anion capture to suppress lattice oxygen evolution of Ni-rich cathode materials at high voltage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152525</link>
      <description>Yizhen Huang, Tao Ma, Mo Li, Lianxi Zheng, Dan Su, Juantao Jiang, Qichang Pan, Sijiang Hu, Shaoyi Wang, Qingyu Li, Fenghua Zheng, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398765641

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yizhen Huang, Tao Ma, Mo Li, Lianxi Zheng, Dan Su, Juantao Jiang, Qichang Pan, Sijiang Hu, Shaoyi Wang, Qingyu Li, Fenghua Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline-dependent surface reconstruction at low applied potential region for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.187</link>
      <description>Yuan&#8208;Zhao Hua, Sheng Wang, Weiying Ye, Zhihao Qi, Yonggang Yang, Zhilin Zhang, Chenyang Cai, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398768779

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuan&#8208;Zhao Hua, Sheng Wang, Weiying Ye, Zhihao Qi, Yonggang Yang, Zhilin Zhang, Chenyang Cai, Wenshu Yang, Longhua Li, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional ultra-thin CuCoNiMnAl high-entropy alloy nanosheets for lithium-ion storage and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234738</link>
      <description>Xingqun Zhu, Jing Li, Rai Nauman Ali, Ming Song, Journal of power sources. 610(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398769883

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingqun Zhu, Jing Li, Rai Nauman Ali, Ming Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building strong metal-support interaction between TiN and RuO2 for efficient acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.315</link>
      <description>G. J. Wang, Wei Wan, Min Chen, Jing Li, Xinke Wu, Shuyi Huang, Li Ke, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398769927

                No abstract</description>
      <author>G. J. Wang, Wei Wan, Min Chen, Jing Li, Xinke Wu, Shuyi Huang, Li Ke, Xinlong Tian, Zhenye Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of the Activity of Electrochemical Ozone Production over Rutile PbO2 Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400827</link>
      <description>Jingwei Jiang, Zhongyuan Guo, Shao-Kang Deng, Jing Xue, Heng Liu, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Lihua Cheng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398770085

                Ozonation water treatment technology has attracted increasing attention due to its environmental benign and high efficiency. Rutile PbO2 is a promising anode material for electrochemical ozone production (EOP). However, the reaction mechanism underlying ozone production catalyzed by PbO2 was rarely studied and not well&#8208;understood, which was in part due to the overlook of the electrochemistry&#8208;driven formation of oxygen vacancy (OV) of PbO2. Herein, we unrevealed the origin of the EOP activity of PbO2 starting from the electrochemical surface state analysis using density functional theory (DFT) calculations, activity analysis, and catalytic volcano modeling. Interestingly, we found that under experimental EOP potential (i.e., a potential around 2.2 V vs. reversible hydrogen electrode), OV can still be generated easily on PbO2 surfaces. Our subsequent kinetic and thermodynamic analyses show that these OV sites on PbO2 surfaces are highly active for the EOP reaction through an interesting atomic oxygen (O*)&#8208;O2 coupled mechanism. In particular, rutile PbO2(101) with the &#8220;in&#8208;situ&#8221; generated OV exhibited superior EOP activities, outperforming (111) and (110). Finally, by catalytic modeling, we found that PbO2 is close to the theoretical optimum of the reaction, suggesting a superior EOP performance of rutile PbO2. All these analyses are in good agreement with experimental observations.</description>
      <author>Jingwei Jiang, Zhongyuan Guo, Shao-Kang Deng, Jing Xue, Heng Liu, Jie Xu, Hao Li, Lihua Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400827</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing 3d Transition Metal Cation-Doped MRuO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; As Durable Acidic Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts for PEM Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04096</link>
      <description>Panpan Sun, Zelong Qiao, Xiaobin Dong, Run Jiang, Zhong-Ting Hu, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398770378

                The continuous dissolution and oxidation of active sites in Ru-based electrocatalysts have greatly hindered their practical application in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE). In this work, we first used density functional theory (DFT) to calculate the dissolution energy of Ru in the 3d transition metal-doped MRuOx (M = Sc, Ti, V, Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu, and Zn) to evaluate their stability for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and screen out ZnRuOx as the best candidate. To confirm the theoretical predictions, we experimentally synthesized these MRuOx materials and found that ZnRuOx indeed displays robust acidic OER stability with a negligible decay of &#951;10 after 15 000 CV cycles. Of importance, using ZnRuOx as the anode, the PEMWE can run stably for 120 h at 200 mA cm&#8211;2. We also further uncover the stability mechanism of ZnRuOx, i.e., Zn atoms doped in the outside of ZnRuOx nanocrystal would form a "Zn-rich" shell, which effectively shortened average Ru&#8211;O bond lengths in ZnRuOx to strengthen the Ru&#8211;O interaction and therefore boosted intrinsic stability of ZnRuOx in acidic OER. In short, this work not only provides a new study paradigm of using DFT calculations to guide the experimental synthesis but also offers a proof-of-concept with 3d metal dopants as RuO2 stabilizer as a universal principle to develop high-durability Ru-based catalysts for PEMWE.</description>
      <author>Panpan Sun, Zelong Qiao, Xiaobin Dong, Run Jiang, Zhong-Ting Hu, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04096</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural and Electronic Factors behind the Electrochemical Stability of 3D-Metal Tungstates under Oxygen Evolution Reaction Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07301</link>
      <description>Abhishek Rajput, Pabitra K. Nayak, Dibyajyoti Ghosh, Biswarup Chakraborty, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398770868

                Transition metal tungstates (TMTs) possess a wolframite-like lattice structure and preferably form via an electrostatic interaction between a divalent transition metal cation (MII) and an oxyanion of tungsten ([WO4]2&#8211;). A unit cell of a TMT is primarily composed of two repeating units, [MO6]oh and [WO6]oh, which are held together via several M&#8722;&#956;2&#8211;O&#8211;W bridging links. The bond character (ionic or covalent) of this bridging unit determines the stability of the lattice and influences the electronic structure of the bulk TMT materials. Recently, TMTs have been successfully employed as an electrode material for various applications, including electrochemical water splitting. Despite the wide electrocatalytic applications of TMTs, the study of the structure&#8211;activity correlation and electronic factors responsible for in situ structural evolution to electroactive species during electrochemical reactions is still in its infancy. Herein, a series of TMTs, MIIWVIO4 (M = Mn/Fe/Co/Ni), have been prepared and employed as electrocatalysts to study the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under alkaline conditions and to scrutinize the role of transition metals in controlling the energetics of the formation of electroactive species. Since the [WO6]oh unit is common in the TMTs considered, the variation of the central atom of the corresponding [MO6]oh unit plays an intriguing role in controlling the electronic structure and stability of the lattice under anodic potential. Under the OER conditions, a potential-dependent structural transformation of MWO4 is noticed, where MnWO4 appears to be the most labile, whereas NiWO4 is stable up to a high anodic potential of &#8764;1.68 V (vs RHE). Potential-dependent hydrolytic [WO4]2&#8211; dissolution to form MOx active species, traced by in situ Raman and various spectro-/microscopic analyses, can directly be related to the electronic factors of the lattice, viz., crystal field splitting energy (CFSE) of MII in [MO6]oh, formation enthalpy (&#916;Hf), decomposition enthalpy (&#916;Hd), and Madelung factor associated with the MWO4 ionic lattice. Additionally, the magnitude of the L&#246;wdin and Bader charges on M of the M&#8722;&#956;2&#8211;O&#8211;W bond is directly related to the degree of ionicity or covalency in the MWO4 lattice, which indirectly influences the electronic structure and activity. The experimental results substantiated by the computational study explain the electrochemical activity of the TMTs with the help of various structural and electronic factors and bonding interactions in the lattice, which has never been realized. Therefore, the study presented here can be taken as a general guideline to correlate the reactivity to the structure of the inorganic materials.</description>
      <author>Abhishek Rajput, Pabitra K. Nayak, Dibyajyoti Ghosh, Biswarup Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07301</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic OER behavior of Bi-Fe-O system: An understanding from the perspective of the presence of oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00348a</link>
      <description>Shaswati Jyoti, Aditi Vijay, Umberto Terranova, Santosh K. Gupta, K. Sudarshan, Sonalika Vaidya, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398775430

                This study aims to understand and correlate the role of the nature and relative concentration of the oxygen vacancies with the trend observed in OER with the Bi-Fe-O system. To...</description>
      <author>Shaswati Jyoti, Aditi Vijay, Umberto Terranova, Santosh K. Gupta, K. Sudarshan, Sonalika Vaidya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00348a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Modulated Microscale Assembly of MOF Derived Iron/Nickel Selenide for Optimizing Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02452d</link>
      <description>Wenhao Guo, Huaipeng Pang, Xinyu Yang, Lin Li, Jinxiang Peng, Meiqi Zhao, Chun&#8208;Chao Hou, Yingmei Zhu, Fanlu Meng, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398775742

                Formulating hierarchical structures via systematic assembly of MOF-derived electrocatalysts emerge as a potent strategy to dictate the electrocatalytic efficacy of oxygen evolution reactions. However, research into the microscale implications of...</description>
      <author>Wenhao Guo, Huaipeng Pang, Xinyu Yang, Lin Li, Jinxiang Peng, Meiqi Zhao, Chun&#8208;Chao Hou, Yingmei Zhu, Fanlu Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02452d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel arrangement of active and ultra-stable electrocatalyst based on iron/nickel/cobalt oxy/hydroxides for continuous oxygen evolution from alkaline seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118377</link>
      <description>Mehdi Hamze, Milad Rezaei, Seyed Hadi Tabaian, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398785615

                This research offers novel ideas for development a new class of materials with enhanced OER kinetics utilizing an easy electrochemical deposition technique. Here, the Ti/CoNiyOx/FeOOH electrocatalyst was prepared in two steps. First, CoNiyOx thin film was anodically electrodeposited on an activated titanium substrate. Then iron oxyhydroxide (FeOOH) nanosheets were cathodically electrodeposited on the first layer. The properties of this electrocatalyst was evaluated and compared with some monolayer electrocatalysts using field emission scanning electron microscopy (FE-SEM), Raman, energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and electrochemical methods. The Ti/CoNiyOx/FeOOH electrode requires an overpotential less than 330 mV at 100 mA/cm2 with Tafel constant of only 23.7 mV/dec for OER. The Ti/CoNiyOx/FeOOH electrode delivered long-term electrochemical stability in a solution containing corrosive chloride ions for more than 90 h at a constant current density of 100 mA/cm2 (with less than 9 % potential increase). Overall seawater splitting using the synthesized Ti/CoNiyOx/FeOOH electrode was performed at a current density of 100 mA/cm2 by a voltage as low as 1.58 V. The exceptional activity was ascribed to the synergistic effects of high electrochemical active sites and appropriate charge transfer ability found in CoNiyOx/FeOOH junction.</description>
      <author>Mehdi Hamze, Milad Rezaei, Seyed Hadi Tabaian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-row transition metal carbonates catalyze the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction: Iron is master of them all</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00708e</link>
      <description>Iranna Udachyan, Jayesh T. Bhanushali, Tomer Zidki, Amir Mizrahi, Dan Meyerstein, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398787687

                In pursuing green hydrogen fuel, electrochemical water-splitting emerges as the optimal method. A critical challenge in advancing this process is identifying a cost-effective electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution on the anode....</description>
      <author>Iranna Udachyan, Jayesh T. Bhanushali, Tomer Zidki, Amir Mizrahi, Dan Meyerstein</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00708e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo&#8208;oxalate Organic Framework as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400225</link>
      <description>Haibo Bao, Min Wang, Lingxia Zhang, European journal of inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398794527

                Developing nonprecious metallic electrocatalysts for water splitting is of vital importance for sustainable environment and energy technologies. As for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), FeCo&#8208;based bimetallic catalysts have been found to act as promising candidates owing to their high intrinsic activity. Herein, a novel FeCo&#8208;oxalate organic framework was grown on nickel foam (FeCo&#8208;OA@NF) under mild conditions. The optimized electrocatalyst shows good OER performance with a low overpotential of 275 mV at the current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline environment, comparable to that of commercial Ru&#8208;based catalyst. Moreover, the quantification of produced oxygen by both gas chromatography and drainage method demonstrates nearly 100% Faradaic efficiency. Except for the contribution of Fe and Co species for the excellent OER catalytic activity, in&#8208;situ Raman spectroscopy reveals that the positive effect of oxalate coordination also makes a difference, which can possibly reduce electron transport resistance and provide more active sites. This work provides a promising approach for the preparation of alkaline oxygen evolution electrocatalysts with low&#8208;cost and high performance.</description>
      <author>Haibo Bao, Min Wang, Lingxia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co@CoO chiral nanostructures enabling efficient oxygen electrocatalysis by modulated spin-polarization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152545</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Ran, Mingsu Si, Daqiang Gao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399010167

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Ran, Mingsu Si, Daqiang Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Reversible Sn&#8208;Air Battery Possessing the Ultra&#8208;Low Charging Potential with the Assistance of Light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407856</link>
      <description>Mingze Gao, Ruiya Wang, Xinxin L&#252;, Yanchen Fan, Ziyang Guo, Yonggang Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399011156

                Aqueous Sn&#8208;air batteries are attracting a great deal of interest in recent years due to the ultra&#8208;high safety, low cost, dendrite&#8208;free and highly reversible Sn anode. However, the slurry oxygen reduction/evolution reaction (ORR/OER) kinetics on the air cathodes seriously affect the Sn&#8208;air battery performances. Although various advanced catalysts have been developed, the charge overpotentials (~1000 mV) of these Sn&#8208;air batteries are still not satisfactory. Herein, iron oxide (Fe2O3) modified titanium dioxide (TiO2) nanorods with heterogeneous structure are firstly synthesized on Ti mesh (Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti), and the obtained Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti is further applied as catalytic electrodes for Sn&#8208;air batteries. The core&#8208;shell heterogeneous structure of Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti can effectively facilitate the conversion of electrochemical intermediates and separation of photo&#8208;excited electrons and holes to active oxygen&#8208;related reaction processes. DFT and experimental results also confirm that Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti can not only act as the electrocatalysts to improve ORR/OER properties, but also exhibit the superior photo&#8208;catalytic activity to promote charge kinetics. Hence, the Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti&#8208;based Sn&#8208;air batteries show ultra&#8208;low overpotential of ~40 mV, excellent rate capability and good cycling stability under light irradiation. This work will shed light on rational photo&#8208;assisted catalytic cathode design for new&#8208;type metal&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Mingze Gao, Ruiya Wang, Xinxin L&#252;, Yanchen Fan, Ziyang Guo, Yonggang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202407856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous NiMoP patchy nanospheres enfolded by rGO sheets for efficient oxygen evolution reaction and durable supercapacitor electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112187</link>
      <description>B.N. Vamsi Krishna, Obula Reddy Ankinapalli, Goli Nagaraju, Journal of energy storage. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399014361

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B.N. Vamsi Krishna, Obula Reddy Ankinapalli, Goli Nagaraju</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution and Zinc&#8208;Air Battery Performance via Electronic Spin Modulation in Heterostructured Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202400572</link>
      <description>Linlin Yang, He Ren, Marc Botifoll, Yongcai Zhang, Yang Ding, Chong Di, Cong He, Ying Xu, Llu&#305;&#769;s Balcells, Jordi Arbiol, Yingtang Zhou, Andreu Cabot, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399019773

                Abstract Beyond optimizing electronic energy levels, the modulation of the electronic spin configuration is an effective strategy, often overlooked, to boost activity and selectivity in a range of catalytic reactions, including the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This electronic spin modulation is frequently accomplished using external magnetic fields, which makes it impractical for real applications. Herein, spin modulation is achieved by engineering Ni/MnFe 2 O 4 heterojunctions, whose surface is reconstructed into NiOOH/MnFeOOH during the OER. NiOOH/MnFeOOH shows a high spin state of Ni, which regulates the OH &#8208; and O 2 adsorption energy and enables spin alignment of oxygen intermediates. As a result, NiOOH/MnFeOOH electrocatalysts provide excellent OER performance with an overpotential of 261 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 . Besides, rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries based on Ni/MnFe 2 O 4 show a high open circuit potential of 1.56 V and excellent stability for more than 1000 cycles. This outstanding performance is rationalized using density functional theory calculations, which show that the optimal spin state of both Ni active sites and oxygen intermediates facilitates spin&#8208;selected charge transport, optimizes the reaction kinetics, and decreases the energy barrier to the evolution of oxygen. This study provides valuable insight into spin polarization modulation by heterojunctions enabling the design of next&#8208;generation OER catalysts with boosted performance. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Linlin Yang, He Ren, Marc Botifoll, Yongcai Zhang, Yang Ding, Chong Di, Cong He, Ying Xu, Llu&#305;&#769;s Balcells, Jordi Arbiol, Yingtang Zhou, Andreu Cabot</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202400572</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron, Tungsten Dual&#8208;Doped Nickel Sulfide as Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311770</link>
      <description>Sangni Wang, Ding Yuan, Sihan Sun, Shuhan Huang, Yirong Wu, Lei Zhang, Shi Xue Dou, Huan Liu, Yihua Dou, Jiantie Xu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399021892

                Abstract Developing low&#8208;cost and highly efficient bifunctional catalysts for both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is a challenging problem in electrochemical overall water splitting. Here, iron, tungsten dual&#8208;doped nickel sulfide catalyst (Fe/W&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 ) is synthesized on the nickel foam, and it exhibits excellent OER and HER performance. As a result, the water electrolyze based on Fe/W&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 bifunctional catalyst illustrates 10 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.69 V (without iR &#8208;compensation) and highly durable overall water splitting over 100 h tested under 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . Experimental results and DFT calculations indicate that the synergistic interaction between Fe doping and Ni vacancy induced by W leaching during the in situ oxidation process can maximize exposed OER active sites on the reconstructed NiOOH species for accelerating OER kinetics, while the Fe/W dual&#8208;doping optimizes the electronic structure of Fe/W&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 and the binding strength of intermediates for boosting HER. This study unlocks the different promoting mechanisms of incorporating Fe and W for boosting the OER and HER activity of Ni 3 S 2 for water splitting, which provides significant guidance for designing high&#8208;performance bifunctional catalysts for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Sangni Wang, Ding Yuan, Sihan Sun, Shuhan Huang, Yirong Wu, Lei Zhang, Shi Xue Dou, Huan Liu, Yihua Dou, Jiantie Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atmospheric oxygen plasma-activated novel multicomponent transition metal phosphides (MnCoCu&#8211;P) for enhanced electrocatalytic water splitting to green hydrogen production: A universal catalyst across various pH electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.352</link>
      <description>Rakesh Kulkarni, Lakshmi Prasanna Lingamdinne, Janardhan Reddy Koduru, Siddulu Naidu Talapaneni, Zahid Husain Momin, Chandrika Ashwinikumar Pal, Yongki Choi, Yoon&#8208;Young Chang, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399022690

                Hydrogen (H2) is widely acknowledged as a promising, sustainable, and environmentally friendly energy carrier, offering numerous environmental benefits over conventional fossil fuels. However, the advancement of this technology is severely hindered by the scarcity of effective and robust catalysts for hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions activity. This study marks the inaugural fabrication of a hybrid tri-metallic electrocatalyst, termed MnCoCu&#8211;P, through hydrothermal synthesis. Subsequently, the catalyst undergoes atmospheric O2 plasma surface activation, aiming to amplify the efficiency of water splitting. The novel atmospheric O2 plasma-activated MnCoCu&#8211;P electrode outperforms the reported classic metal phosphides, and it outperformed the compared commercial Pt/C and RuO2 benchmark catalysts with outstanding performances of 0.488 and 1.20 V towards HER and OER at 1000 mA/cm2, respectively. Additionally, the MnCoCu&#8211;P (5 min) catalyst Faradic efficiency was calculated under alkaline conditions in 1.0 M KOH, and both the produced gas H2 and O2 match the theoretical and experimental calculated values well, indicating a high efficiency of almost 100%. In the 2-E system, MnCoCu&#8211;P (5 min)&#8214;MnCoCu&#8211;P (5 min) demonstrated remarkable performance by attaining a current density of 1000 mA/cm2 at low total cell voltages of 1.93 V and outperforming the benchmark Pt/C&#8214;RuO2 electrode system. On the other hand, the MnCoCu&#8211;P electrode possesses excellent activity under industrial conditions at 6.0 M @ 60 &#176;C exhibited 1.89 V at 1000 mA/cm2 and performs well in natural water systems. Moreover, the 5 min O2 plasma-treated MnCoCu&#8211;P&#8214;MnCoCu&#8211;P electrodes showed improved activity in all the pH solutions which makes it one of the potential candidates for commercial application in the future.</description>
      <author>Rakesh Kulkarni, Lakshmi Prasanna Lingamdinne, Janardhan Reddy Koduru, Siddulu Naidu Talapaneni, Zahid Husain Momin, Chandrika Ashwinikumar Pal, Yongki Choi, Yoon&#8208;Young Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering heterostructured and hierarchical CoP/CoFeP nanosheet for effective oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline freshwater and seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.342</link>
      <description>Mingxing Chen, Zhiwei Zhu, Xue Li, Jing Li, Enbo Shangguan, &#25964;&#27835; &#23721;&#23822;, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399027924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingxing Chen, Zhiwei Zhu, Xue Li, Jing Li, Enbo Shangguan, &#25964;&#27835; &#23721;&#23822;</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile fabrication of nickel-cobalt oxide for efficient oxygen evolution reaction from ammonia leaching solution of spent lithium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.356</link>
      <description>Cheng Yang, Gaojie Chen, Liang Xu, Yongpan Tian, Zhuo Zhao, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399027942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Yang, Gaojie Chen, Liang Xu, Yongpan Tian, Zhuo Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coordination environment modulation to optimize d-orbit arrangement of Mn-based MOF electrocatalyst for lithium-oxygen battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103519</link>
      <description>Xinxiang Wang, Haoyang Xu, Xiaojuan Wen, Guilei Tian, Sheng Liu, Fengxia Fan, Pengfei Liu, Chenrui Zeng, Chuan Wang, Shuhan Wang, Ruixin Zheng, Chaozhu Shu, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399034437

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinxiang Wang, Haoyang Xu, Xiaojuan Wen, Guilei Tian, Sheng Liu, Fengxia Fan, Pengfei Liu, Chenrui Zeng, Chuan Wang, Shuhan Wang, Ruixin Zheng, Chaozhu Shu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promotion of the oxygen evolution reaction by introducing MoS2 into CoFe LDH via improved charge transfer and electrocatalytical activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131993</link>
      <description>Yongping Luo, Yuchen Duan, Yu Xie, Yongya Wang, Xianchan Li, Yike Liu, Shunjian Xu, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399036857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yongping Luo, Yuchen Duan, Yu Xie, Yongya Wang, Xianchan Li, Yike Liu, Shunjian Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131993</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically thin iridium nanosheets for oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01117a</link>
      <description>Gea&#8208;Jae Joo, Younghyun Wy, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Bon Seung Goo, Yongmin Kwon, Jin Hong Kim, Jin Sik Choi, Sang Woo Han, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399051421

                2D nanostructures of noble metals hold great potential for developing efficient electrocatalysts due to their high atom efficiency associated with their large specific surface area and abundant active sites. Here,...</description>
      <author>Gea&#8208;Jae Joo, Younghyun Wy, Hojin Ahn, Yonghyeon Kim, Bon Seung Goo, Yongmin Kwon, Jin Hong Kim, Jin Sik Choi, Sang Woo Han</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01117a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Evolution Reaction on Nickel Oxyhydroxide&#8217;s Surface: Toward a Super Catalyst for Oxygen-Evolution Reaction with Ultralow Overpotentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00888</link>
      <description>Mohammad Khateri, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054326

                This study challenges the conventional understanding of nickel (hydr)oxides as inefficient catalysts for oxygen-evolution reaction (OER) under alkaline conditions. It is demonstrated that nickel oxyhydroxide, characterized by several methods, forms on Ni foam's surface and exhibits OER activity at extremely low potentials. This activity becomes particularly notable at the peak of Ni(II) oxidation to Ni(III), which follows charge accumulation. Remarkably, this mesoporous, super hydrophilic, and high-surface-area catalyst requires a minimal overpotential, as low as 130 mV, with a current density of 200 &#956;A/cm2, and displays a Tafel slope of 77.9 mV/decade in alkaline media (0.10 M KOH). Considering the amount of oxygen produced and the concentration of redox-active Ni ions in the redox peak region, the turnover frequency was calculated to be 1.1 &#215; 10&#8211;3 s&#8211;1 at a potential of 1.36 V. Achieving these parameters at such a remarkably low overpotential holds significant promise. This study also proposes a mechanism for OER at this low overpotential, based on in situ Raman spectroscopic analysis of the Ni(II) to Ni(III) oxidation peak and the OER region. The observed low overpotential for OER can be attributed to the complex interplay between the OER process and the phenomenon of charge accumulation. All these factors result in an exceptionally low overpotential for OER. Our findings hold profound implications for the development of highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts for OER, particularly in water-splitting applications. This research not only expands our understanding of nickel oxyhydroxide as a potential OER catalyst but also opens avenues for future exploration in electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Khateri, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Activation through Deep Oxidation of Co4N by Jahn&#8722;Teller&#8208;active Dopants for Improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405839</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054838

                Triggering the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism is crucial for improving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, because it could bypass the scaling relation limitation associated with the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism through the directly formation of oxygen&#8722;oxygen bond. High&#8208;valence transition metal sites are favorable for activating the lattice oxygen, but the deep oxidation of pre&#8208;catalysts suffers from a high thermodynamic barrier. Here, taking advantage of the Jahn&#8722;Teller (J&#8722;T) distortion induced structural instability, we incorporate high&#8208;spin Mn3+ (t2g3eg1) dopant into Co4N. Mn dopants enable a surface structural transformation from Co4N to CoOOH, and finally to CoO2, as observed by various in&#8208;situ spectroscopic investigations. Furthermore, the reconstructed surface on Mn doped Co4N triggers the lattice oxygen activation, as evidenced experimentally by pH&#8208;dependent OER, tetramethylammonium cation adsorption and on&#8208;line electrochemical mass spectrometry measurements of 18O&#8208;labelled catalysts. In general, this work not only offers the introducing J&#8722;T effect approach to regulate the structural transition, but also provides an understanding about the influence of catalyst&#8217;s electronic configuration on determining the reaction route, which may inspire the design of more efficient catalysts with activated lattice oxygen.</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Activation through Deep Oxidation of Co4N by Jahn&#8722;Teller&#8208;active Dopants for Improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405839</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399054892

                Triggering the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism is crucial for improving oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, because it could bypass the scaling relation limitation associated with the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism through the directly formation of oxygen&#8722;oxygen bond. High&#8208;valence transition metal sites are favorable for activating the lattice oxygen, but the deep oxidation of pre&#8208;catalysts suffers from a high thermodynamic barrier. Here, taking advantage of the Jahn&#8722;Teller (J&#8722;T) distortion induced structural instability, we incorporate high&#8208;spin Mn3+ (t2g3eg1) dopant into Co4N. Mn dopants enable a surface structural transformation from Co4N to CoOOH, and finally to CoO2, as observed by various in&#8208;situ spectroscopic investigations. Furthermore, the reconstructed surface on Mn doped Co4N triggers the lattice oxygen activation, as evidenced experimentally by pH&#8208;dependent OER, tetramethylammonium cation adsorption and on&#8208;line electrochemical mass spectrometry measurements of 18O&#8208;labelled catalysts. In general, this work not only offers the introducing J&#8722;T effect approach to regulate the structural transition, but also provides an understanding about the influence of catalyst&#8217;s electronic configuration on determining the reaction route, which may inspire the design of more efficient catalysts with activated lattice oxygen.</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Haibin Wang, Yuting Wang, Hao Zhang, Jun Li, Yujian Xia, Jieshu Zhou, Ziyun Wang, Ming Ronnier Luo, Yuhang Wang, Ning Wang, Emiliano Cort&#233;s, Zumin Wang, Alberto Vomiero, Zhen&#8208;Feng Huang, Hangxing Ren, Xianming Yuan, Songhua Chen, Dan Feng, Xuhui Sun, Yongchang Liu, Hongyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405839</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Bulk and Surface Engineering for Expeditious and Durable Reversible Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cells Air Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403998</link>
      <description>Xi Chen, Na Yu, Yufei Song, Tong Liu, Hengyue Xu, Daqin Guan, Zheng Li, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Jaka Sunarso, Francesco Ciucci, Meng Ni, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399055707

                Abstract Reversible protonic ceramic electrochemical cells (R&#8208;PCECs) offer the potential for high&#8208;efficiency power generation and green hydrogen production at intermediate temperatures. However, the commercial viability of R&#8208;PCECs is hampered by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) within conventional air electrodes operating at reduced temperatures. To address this challenge, we introduce a novel approach based on the simultaneous optimization of bulk&#8208;phase metal&#8208;oxygen bonds and in&#8208;situ formation of a metal oxide nano&#8208;catalyst surface modification. This strategy is designed to expedite the ORR/OER electrocatalytic activity of air electrodes exhibiting triple (O 2&#8722; , H + , e &#8722; ) conductivity. Specifically, our engineered air electrode nanocomposite&#8208;Ba(Co 0.4 Fe 0.4 Zr 0.1 Y 0.1 ) 0.95 Ni 0.05 F 0.1 O 2.9&#8208;&#948; demonstrates remarkable ORR/OER catalytic activity and exceptional durability in R&#8208;PCECs. This is evidenced by significantly improved peak power density from 626 mW cm &#8722;2 to 996 mW cm &#8722;2 and highly stable reversibility over a 100&#8208;hour cycling period. This research offers a rational design strategy to achieve high&#8208;performance R&#8208;PCEC air electrodes with superior operational activity and stability for efficient and sustainable energy conversion and storage. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Xi Chen, Na Yu, Yufei Song, Tong Liu, Hengyue Xu, Daqin Guan, Zheng Li, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Jaka Sunarso, Francesco Ciucci, Meng Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403998</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-4f as an electron-modulation reservoir weakening Fe-O bond to induce iron vacancies in CeFevNi hydroxide for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.205</link>
      <description>Le Gao, Yue Yao, Yun Chen, Jiajun Huang, Yiling Ma, Wenbin Chen, Huan Li, Yu Wang, Lishan Jia, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399067370

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Le Gao, Yue Yao, Yun Chen, Jiajun Huang, Yiling Ma, Wenbin Chen, Huan Li, Yu Wang, Lishan Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile synthesis of CuO -decorated TiO2 nanoparticles via oxygen-limited pyrolysis of Cu(II) complex for efficient photocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113199</link>
      <description>Chao Yang, Xueying Zhao, Yunlong Zhao, Chenchen Ji, Ren&#8208;Jang Wu, Lu Wang, Xueqing Shao, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399068682

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Yang, Xueying Zhao, Yunlong Zhao, Chenchen Ji, Ren&#8208;Jang Wu, Lu Wang, Xueqing Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous&#8208;Spin&#8208;Polarized 2D &#960;&#8208;d Conjugated Frameworks Towards Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401987</link>
      <description>Won Seok Lee, Hiroaki Maeda, Yen&#8208;Ting Kuo, Koki Muraoka, Naoya Fukui, Kenji Takada, Sono Sasaki, Hiroshi Nishihara, Akira Nakayama, Hong&#8208;Kang Tian, Hiroshi Nishihara, Ken Sakaushi, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399070034

                Abstract Alternative strategies to design sustainable&#8208;element&#8208;based electrocatalysts enhancing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics are demanded to develop affordable yet high&#8208;performance water&#8208;electrolyzers for green hydrogen production. Here, it is demonstrated that the spontaneous&#8208;spin&#8208;polarized 2D &#960;&#8208;d conjugated framework comprising abundant elements of nickel and iron with a ratio of Ni:Fe = 1:4 with benzenehexathiol linker (BHT) can improve OER kinetics by its unique electronic property. Among the bimetallic NiFe x:y &#8208;BHTs with various ratios with Ni:Fe = x:y, the NiFe 1:4 &#8208;BHT exhibits the highest OER activity. The NiFe 1:4 &#8208;BHT shows a specific current density of 140 A g &#8722;1 at the overpotential of 350 mV. This performance is one of the best activities among state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art non&#8208;precious OER electrocatalysts and even comparable to that of the platinum&#8208;group&#8208;metals of RuO 2 and IrO 2 . The density functional theory calculations uncover that introducing Ni into the homometallic Fe&#8208;BHT (e.g., Ni:Fe = 0:1) can emerge a spontaneous&#8208;spin&#8208;polarized state. Thus, this material can achieve improved OER kinetics with spin&#8208;polarization which previously required external magnetic fields. This work shows that a rational design of 2D &#960;&#8208;d conjugated frameworks can be a powerful strategy to synthesize promising electrocatalysts with abundant elements for a wide spectrum of next&#8208;generation energy devices.</description>
      <author>Won Seok Lee, Hiroaki Maeda, Yen&#8208;Ting Kuo, Koki Muraoka, Naoya Fukui, Kenji Takada, Sono Sasaki, Hiroshi Nishihara, Akira Nakayama, Hong&#8208;Kang Tian, Hiroshi Nishihara, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401987</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Water Oxidation Catalytic Activity of a Mn-Based Magnetic Metal&#8211;Organic Framework: The Role of Proton Conductivity and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01078</link>
      <description>Sayan Saha, Avik De, Soumadip Banerjee, Abhijit K. Das, C. Andr&#233; Ohlin, Raju Mondal, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399071995

                The present work evaluates the water oxidation catalytic activity of a Mn-based metal-organic framework (MOF), which we envisioned to reduce the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) overpotential because of its high electrical conductivity, facilitated by solvent-encapsulated structural features. The presence of Mn centers induces interesting magnetic features in the MOF, which exhibits impressive cryogenic magnetic refrigeration with a &#916;</description>
      <author>Sayan Saha, Avik De, Soumadip Banerjee, Abhijit K. Das, C. Andr&#233; Ohlin, Raju Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Engineering of 3D Self&#8208;Supported Bifunctional Oxygen Electrodes for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries and Fuel Cell Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400347</link>
      <description>Milan Babu Poudel, Mannix P. Balanay, Prakash Chandra Lohani, Karthikeyan Sekar, Dong Jin Yoo, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399077859

                Abstract The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) are cornerstone half reactions involved in many renewable energy technologies. High&#8208;density single&#8208;atom catalysts maximize the atom utilization and isolated active sites. Furthermore, introduction of pyri&#8208;N into the carbon&#8208;based nanostructures as an oxygen electrocatalyst creates an abundance of active sites. Here, an innovative strategy is reported based on atomic scale dispersion of Co atoms into the pyri&#8208;N enriched carbon nanotube encapsulated Ni nanoparticles grown on 3D electrospun carbon nanofiber nano&#8208;assemblies. Notably, the Co SA Ni&#8208;NCNT/CNF electrocatalyst exhibited excellent OER and ORR activity in terms of low overpotentials and higher half&#8208;wave potentials. The atomically distributed Co allows the maximum exposure of active sites on the pyri&#8208;N dominated multidimensional carbon skeleton, and synergistic effects with Ni nanoparticles greatly reduced the delocalization around the metal centers and provided an ideal environment for interactions with oxygen intermediates, thus facilitating the 4e &#8722; pathway, as evidenced by the DFT calculations. Moreover, Zn&#8208;air batteries using a Co SA Ni&#8208;NCNT/CNF air cathode exhibited a high&#8208;power density and admirable specific capacity. This studies may provide an avenue for the rational modulation of single&#8208;atom catalysts and cost&#8208;effective, large&#8208;scale synthesis of bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries and anion exchange membrane fuel cell.</description>
      <author>Milan Babu Poudel, Mannix P. Balanay, Prakash Chandra Lohani, Karthikeyan Sekar, Dong Jin Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400347</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress on electronic and active site engineering of cobalt&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.573</link>
      <description>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Jia Wang, Tingting Wang, Jian Ju, Yizhong Lu, Wei Chen, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399077872

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting has been identified as a potential candidate for producing clean hydrogen energy with zero carbon emission. However, the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction on the anode side of the water&#8208;splitting device significantly hinders its practical applications. Generally, the efficiency of oxygen evolution processes depends greatly on the availability of cost&#8208;effective catalysts with high activity and selectivity. In recent years, extensive theoretical and experimental studies have demonstrated that cobalt (Co)&#8208;based nanomaterials, especially low&#8208;dimensional Co&#8208;based nanomaterials with a huge specific surface area and abundant unsaturated active sites, have emerged as versatile electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions, and thus, great progress has been made in the rational design and synthesis of Co&#8208;based nanomaterials for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions. Considering the remarkable progress in this area, in this timely review, we highlight the most recent developments in Co&#8208;based nanomaterials relating to their dimensional control, defect regulation (conductivity), electronic structure regulation, and so forth. Furthermore, a brief conclusion about recent progress achieved in oxygen evolution on Co&#8208;based nanomaterials, as well as an outlook on future research challenges, is given.</description>
      <author>Chuansheng He, Linlin Yang, Jia Wang, Tingting Wang, Jian Ju, Yizhong Lu, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoengineered Cobalt Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110946</link>
      <description>R. Venkatachalam, Sunil Mehla, Lathe A. Jones, Suresh K. Bhargava, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399081051

                The alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a bottleneck in green hydrogen production owing to its slow reaction kinetics and low catalytic efficiencies of earth abundant electrocatalysts in the alkaline OER reaction. This study investigates the OER performance of hierarchically porous cobalt electrocatalysts synthesized using the dynamic hydrogen bubble templating (DHBT) method. Characterization studies revealed that electrocatalysts synthesized under optimized conditions using the DHBT method consisted of cobalt nanosheets, and hierarchical porosity with macropores distributed in a honeycomb network and mesopores distributed between cobalt nanosheets. Moreover, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy studies revealed the presence of Co(OH)2 as the predominant surface cobalt species while Raman studies revealed the presence of the cubic Co3O4 phase in the synthesized electrocatalysts. The best performing electrocatalyst required only 360 mV of overpotential to initiate a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, exhibited a Tafel slope of 37 mV dec&#8722;1, and stable OER activity over 24 h. The DHBT method offers a facile, low cost and rapid synthesis approach for preparation for highly efficient cobalt electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>R. Venkatachalam, Sunil Mehla, Lathe A. Jones, Suresh K. Bhargava</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling electroplating sludge into bioengineering-enabled highly stable dual-site Fe-Ni2P@C electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6719-x</link>
      <description>Jiawen Liu, Zhi&#8208;Liang Zuo, Feng Gao, K. Yi, Jai-Ming Lin, Mengye Wang, Lin Zhang, Haibo Feng, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399099589

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiawen Liu, Zhi&#8208;Liang Zuo, Feng Gao, K. Yi, Jai-Ming Lin, Mengye Wang, Lin Zhang, Haibo Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6719-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Investigations on CoFe2O4@Co3O4 Nano-composite as an Enhanced Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00877-8</link>
      <description>Xihuan Zhang, Abdelhadi El Jaouhari, Chunyue Li, Maimoune Adnane, Wanying Liu, Abderrahman Mellalou, Fouad Ghamouss, Yuanhua Lin, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399105282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xihuan Zhang, Abdelhadi El Jaouhari, Chunyue Li, Maimoune Adnane, Wanying Liu, Abderrahman Mellalou, Fouad Ghamouss, Yuanhua Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00877-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g</link>
      <description>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao, RSC advances. 14(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399110116

                In this study, we explord the catalytic activity of NiCoFe_phosphide nanosheets as highly active and stable catalysts for OER. Electrochemical analysis exhibits a low overpotential of 259 mV in (1 M KOH), achieving a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a low Tafel slope of 50.47 mV dec &#8722;1 .</description>
      <author>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dy2NiRuO6 perovskite with high activity and durability for the oxygen evolution reaction in acidic electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta06788b</link>
      <description>Isabel Rodr&#237;guez-Garc&#237;a, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, Dmitry Galyamin, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Paula Kayser, Mohamed Abdel Salam, J. A. Alonso, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Sergio Rojas, M. Retuerto, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399110197

                Ru mixed oxides may be suitable materials to replace state-of-the-art Ir-based catalysts in the anode of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. To do that, the activity and especially the durability of...</description>
      <author>Isabel Rodr&#237;guez-Garc&#237;a, Jos&#233; Luis G&#243;mez de la Fuente, Dmitry Galyamin, A. Tolosana-Moranchel, Paula Kayser, Mohamed Abdel Salam, J. A. Alonso, Federico Calle&#8208;Vallejo, Sergio Rojas, M. Retuerto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta06788b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow nanocubic CoP-FeP/NC heterostructures for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131838</link>
      <description>Zhongxian Li, Xingzhao Wang, Yunlin Xu, Xiaoran Li, Jianchao Zhang, Lu Yang, Jiabing Luo, Yan Zhou, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399116895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhongxian Li, Xingzhao Wang, Yunlin Xu, Xiaoran Li, Jianchao Zhang, Lu Yang, Jiabing Luo, Yan Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131838</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping CeO2/Ce(OH)CO3/CF nanohybrids with Gd for structural tuning and oxygen evolution reaction performance enhancing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.359</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Liao, Xi Lu, Xiaojie Jin, Hongyan Chen, Xinyu Huang, Yongxiu Li, Jing Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399116939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Liao, Xi Lu, Xiaojie Jin, Hongyan Chen, Xinyu Huang, Yongxiu Li, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120030

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of Electron Transfer Behavior on Fe2p-Co2p/Npc Oxygen Electrocatalyst by Lattice Cation Substitution Engineering and Charge Transport Network Design for Rechargeable Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4847202</link>
      <description>Long Hao, Yu Chen, Chunming Liu, Junhua You, Rui Guo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120056

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Long Hao, Yu Chen, Chunming Liu, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4847202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gouda K. Helal, Zhenhang Xu, Xin Liu, Yueying Yu, Jinyan Liu, Hongping Su, Jiang Xu, Houbin Li, Gongzhen Cheng, Pingping Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120097

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120100

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrative Active Sites of Cathode for Electron-Oxygen-Proton Coupling To Favor H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production in a Photoelectrochemical System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c01601</link>
      <description>Shan Li, Lei Chen, Jian Wang, Li Tian, Dawei Li, Zhi Yang, Xin Xiao, Chiheng Chu, Baoliang Chen, Environmental science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120400

                The oxygen reduction process generating H2O2 in the photoelectrochemical (PEC) system is milder and environmentally friendly compared with the traditional anthraquinone process but still lacks the efficient electron-oxygen-proton coupling interfaces to improve H2O2 production efficiency. Here, we propose an integrated active site strategy, that is, designing a hydrophobic C&#8211;B&#8211;N interface to refine the dearth of electron, oxygen, and proton balance. Computational calculation results show a lower energy barrier for H2O2 production due to synergistic and coupling effects of boron sites for O2 adsorption, nitrogen sites for H+ binding, and the carbon structure for electron transfer, demonstrating theoretically the feasibility of the strategy. Furthermore, we construct a hydrophobic boron- and nitrogen-doped carbon black gas diffusion cathode (BN-CB-PTFE) with graphite carbon dots decorated on a BiVO4 photoanode (BVO/g-CDs) for H2O2 production. Remarkably, this approach achieves a record H2O2 production rate (9.24 &#956;mol min&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2) at the PEC cathode. The BN-CB-PTFE cathode exhibits an outstanding Faraday efficiency for H2O2 production of &#8764;100%. The newly formed h-BN integrative active site can not only adsorb more O2 but also significantly improve the electron and proton transfer. Unexpectedly, coupling BVO/g-CDs with the BN-CB-PTFE gas diffusion cathode also achieves a record H2O2 production rate (6.60 &#956;mol min&#8211;1 cm&#8211;2) at the PEC photoanode. This study opens new insight into integrative active sites for electron-O2-proton coupling in a PEC H2O2 production system that may be meaningful for environment and energy applications.</description>
      <author>Shan Li, Lei Chen, Jian Wang, Li Tian, Dawei Li, Zhi Yang, Xin Xiao, Chiheng Chu, Baoliang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c01601</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Pot Template-Free Synthesis of Mesoporous ZnCo2O4 Microbubbles for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11170-1</link>
      <description>Yonggang Zheng, Jian Wu, Zhizhong Guo, Jiayi Qin, Jin&#8208;Ming Wu, Wei Wen, Journal of electronic materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120763

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yonggang Zheng, Jian Wu, Zhizhong Guo, Jiayi Qin, Jin&#8208;Ming Wu, Wei Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11170-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoporous Fe and Co Dually Doped Carbon Nanotube-Based Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Efficient Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02088</link>
      <description>Chaoyang Liu, Shang Wu, Shu Tian, Jincai Yang, Jiankun Li, Xin Wang, Lihong Wang, Chen Chen, Ping Zhang, Quanlu Yang, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399120780

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chaoyang Liu, Shang Wu, Shu Tian, Jincai Yang, Jiankun Li, Xin Wang, Lihong Wang, Chen Chen, Ping Zhang, Quanlu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tunable layered Mn oxides for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01144-1</link>
      <description>E Liu, Drew Higgins, Nature Catalysis. 7(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399121605

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E Liu, Drew Higgins</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01144-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Extraordinary Structural Reconstruction of Nanolaminated Ta&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;FeC MAX Phase for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401022</link>
      <description>Shaoping Zhu, Youbing Li, Minghui Yang, Huiyan Xu, Lijuan Cheng, Fei Fang, Qing Huang, Binwu Ying, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399125273

                Abstract Renewable energy technologies, such as water splitting, heavily depend on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Nanolaminated ternary compounds, referred to as MAX phases, show great promise for creating efficient electrocatalysts for OER. However, their limited intrinsic oxidative resistance hinders the utilization of conductivity in M n+1 X n layers, leading to reduced activity. In this study, a method is proposed to improve the poor inoxidizability of MAX phases by carefully adjusting the elemental composition between M n+1 X n layers and single&#8208;atom&#8208;thick A layers. The resulting Ta 2 FeC catalyst demonstrates superior performance compared to conventional Fe/C&#8208;based catalysts with a remarkable record&#8208;low overpotential of 247 mV (@10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and sustained activity for over 240 h. Notably, during OER processing, the single&#8208;atom&#8208;thick Fe layer undergoes self&#8208;reconstruction and enrichment from the interior of the Ta 2 FeC MAX phase toward its surface, forming a Ta 2 FeC@Ta 2 C@FeOOH heterostructure. Through density functional theory (DFT) calculations, this study has found that the incorporation of Ta 2 FeC@Ta 2 C not only enhances the conductivity of FeOOH but also reduces the covalency of Fe&#9472;O bonds, thus alleviating the oxidation of Fe 3+ and O 2&#8722; . This implies that the Ta 2 FeC@Ta 2 C@FeOOH heterostructure experiences less lattice oxygen loss during the OER process compared to pure FeOOH, leading to significantly improved stability. These results highlight promising avenues for further exploration of MAX phases by strategically engineering M&#8208; and A&#8208;site engineering through multi&#8208;metal substitution, to develop M 2 AX@M 2 X@AOOH&#8208;based catalysts for oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Shaoping Zhu, Youbing Li, Minghui Yang, Huiyan Xu, Lijuan Cheng, Fei Fang, Qing Huang, Binwu Ying</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst Doped with Phosphorus for Improved Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01861</link>
      <description>Shu&#8208;Fang Li, Xin Li, Dong Yan, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399126209

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shu&#8208;Fang Li, Xin Li, Dong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and characterization of bifunctional 1T-2H MoS2-Sv/CuS catalyst for electrocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128176</link>
      <description>Dan Li, Shumin Fan, Jian Li, Weiguo Li, Yanli Zhuang, Y.B. Li, Lianwei Shan, Limin Dong, Jie Yao, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399133444

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dan Li, Shumin Fan, Jian Li, Weiguo Li, Yanli Zhuang, Y.B. Li, Lianwei Shan, Limin Dong, Jie Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.128176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanospike Nickel-Iron Oxalate as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-2rpfc</link>
      <description>Krishani Teeluck, Gia M. Carignan, Mehmet Do&#287;an, Kate M. Waldie, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399134127

                Obtaining hydrogen as a renewable fuel through water splitting is severely hindered by the energy-intensive oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Transition metal oxides based on low-cost and earth-abundant elements have been shown to provide high OER rivaling that of commercial IrO2, with nickel iron oxide/oxyhydroxide systems exhibiting some of the lowest reported overpotentials. Here, we report a nickel-iron oxalate material with a nanospike morphology synthesized via a simple and novel hydrothermal method, in which oxalate is generated in situ during material preparation under mild conditions. The as-synthesized nanostructured material displays high catalytic activity for OER, requiring a low overpotential of only 284 mV at a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2, lower than that of its amorphous counterpart and commercial IrO2 (326 and 308 mV, respectively). This material also exhibits excellent long-term stability with retention of the nanospike morphology after several hours under OER conditions.</description>
      <author>Krishani Teeluck, Gia M. Carignan, Mehmet Do&#287;an, Kate M. Waldie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-2rpfc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Multifunctional Electrocatalysts for ORR/OER/HER/HOR: Janus Makes Difference</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404000</link>
      <description>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399140360

                Abstract Multifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) have broad application prospects; However, realization of such kinds of materials remain difficulties because it requires the materials to have not only unique electronic properties, but multiple active centers to deal with different reactions. Here, employing density functional theory (DFT) computations, it is demonstrated that by decorating the Janus&#8208;type 2D transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) of TaSSe with the single atoms, the materials can achieve multifunctionality to catalyze the ORR/OER/HER/HOR. Out of sixteen catalytic systems, Pt&#8208;V S (i.e., Pt atom embedded in the sulfur vacancy), Pd&#8208;V Se , and Pt&#8208;V Se @TaSSe are promising multifunctional catalysts with superior stability. Among them, the Pt&#8208;V S @TaSSe catalyst exhibits the highest activity with theoretical overpotentials &#951; ORR = 0.40 V, &#951; OER = 0.39 V, and &#951; HER/HOR = 0.07 V, respectively, better than the traditional Pt (111), IrO 2 (110). The interplays between the catalyst and the reaction intermediate over the course of the reaction are then systematically investigated. Generally, this study presents a viable approach for the design and development of advanced multifunctional electrocatalysts. It enriches the application of Janus, a new 2D material, in electrochemical energy storage and conversion technology.</description>
      <author>Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Xiangyu Guo, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404000</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Stainless Steel Oxide Layers through Potential Cycling&#9472;AEM Water Electrolysis Free of Critical Raw Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01107</link>
      <description>T.B. Ferriday, Suhas Nuggehalli Sampathkumar, Mounir Mensi, Hugh Middleton, Jan Van herle, Mohan Lal Kolhe, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141185

                Anion exchange membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWEs) have an intrinsic advantage over acidic proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers through their ability to use inexpensive, stable materials such as stainless steel (SS) to catalyze the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As such, the study of active oxide layers on SS has garnered great interest. Potential cycling is a means to create such active oxide layers in situ as they are readily formed in alkaline solutions when exposed to elevated potentials. Cycling conditions in the literature are rife with unexplained variations, and a complete account of how these variations affect the activity and constitution of SS oxide layers remains unreported, along with their influence on AEMWE performance. In this paper, we seek to fill this gap in the literature by strategically cycling SS felt (SSF) electrodes under different scan rates and ranges. The SSF anodes were rapidly activated within the first 50 cycles, as shown by the 10-fold decline in charge transfer resistance, and the subsequent 1000 cycles tuned the metal oxide surface composition. Cycling the Ni redox couple (RC) increases Ni content, which is further enhanced by lowering the cycling rate, while cycling the Fe RC increases Cr content. Fair OER activity was uncovered through cycling the Ni RC, while Fe cycling produced SSF electrodes active toward both the OER and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This indicates that inert SSF electrodes can be activated to become efficient OER and HER electrodes. To this effect, a single-cell AEMWE without any traditional catalyst or ionomer generated 1.0 A cm&#8211;2 at 1.94 V &#177; 13.3 mV with an SSF anode, showing a fair performance for a cell free of critical raw materials.</description>
      <author>T.B. Ferriday, Suhas Nuggehalli Sampathkumar, Mounir Mensi, Hugh Middleton, Jan Van herle, Mohan Lal Kolhe</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Electrochemical water splitting enhancement by introducing mesoporous NiCoFe-trimetallic phosphide nanosheets as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141696

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02344g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical looping dry reforming of waste glycerol coupled with thermochemical water splitting cycle by mesoporous Fe2O3-Co3O4/CeO2 oxygen carriers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152681</link>
      <description>Kai Wu, Binlin Dou, Hua Zhang, Yadong Wang, Haisheng Chen, Yujie Xu, Wei Li, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399143182

                A coupled chemical looping conversion of glycerol and CO2 with thermochemical water splitting (WS) cycle is substantially researched due to its potential for one-step renewable H2 and syngas production. The major challenge lies on having good controls of redox reactions of the oxygen carriers (OCs) used and its unusual sensitivity to the changes of the compositions, chemical states and structure, etc. Here, we develop the OCs that consists of Fe2O3-Co3O4 supported on the mesoporous CeO2 structure (Fe2O3-Co3O4/CeO2), which simultaneously promote glycerol oxidization (GO), dry reforming of glycerol (GDR), and WS processes. The easy migration and activation of lattice oxygen by Fe2O3-Co3O4/CeO2 greatly improved the GO and GDR to produce syngas at the first step, and the pure H2 production by the reduced Fe2O3-Co3O4/CeO2 achieved excellent WS and oxygen storage at 750&#8451;. The low-content Fe dopant in the OC presented a beneficial effect on the anti-sintering performance, and increase of Co-doping indicated a high activity to WS as well as enhanced GDR. The Fe2O3-Co3O4/CeO2 with 7:5:10 of Co: Fe: Ce molar ratio presented the highest glycerol and CO2 conversions and the highest H2 yield, also illustrated the excellent activity and stability in 40 consecutive redox cycles.</description>
      <author>Kai Wu, Binlin Dou, Hua Zhang, Yadong Wang, Haisheng Chen, Yujie Xu, Wei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D/2D interfacial coupling of NiFe-LDH and Ti3C2T for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.367</link>
      <description>A. Waheed, Sadaf Siddique, Mutawara Mahmood Baig, Muhammad Taqi Mehran, Muhammad Aksam Iftikhar, Jamil Ahmad, Hassan A. Arafat, Faisal Shahzad, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399150460

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Waheed, Sadaf Siddique, Mutawara Mahmood Baig, Muhammad Taqi Mehran, Muhammad Aksam Iftikhar, Jamil Ahmad, Hassan A. Arafat, Faisal Shahzad</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.367</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excellent ethanol oxidation and oxygen evolution reaction from ultrafine nickel hydroxide nanorods stabilized at room temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2024.117445</link>
      <description>Shweta Kumari, . Sunaina, Sapna Devi, Menaka Jha, Materials science and engineering. B, Solid-state materials for advanced technology/Materials science &amp; engineering. B, Solid-state materials for advanced technology. 306(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399150720

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shweta Kumari, . Sunaina, Sapna Devi, Menaka Jha</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mseb.2024.117445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of Flower-Like Co 2 P/Wo 3-X /Cc Catalysts with Oxygen Vacancies For Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4848439</link>
      <description>Hui Guo, Dongxv Li, Ping Lu, Huimin Jiang, Mohammed A. Amin, Jianjian Lin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399157500

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Guo, Dongxv Li, Ping Lu, Huimin Jiang, Mohammed A. Amin, Jianjian Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4848439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon quantum dots decorated NiCo layered double hydroxide for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction and supercapacitor application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-024-12793-0</link>
      <description>D. A. Wadkar, Kiran Jadhav, S. D. Jituri, S.H. Mujawar, Journal of materials science. Materials in electronics. 35(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399169730

                No abstract</description>
      <author>D. A. Wadkar, Kiran Jadhav, S. D. Jituri, S.H. Mujawar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-024-12793-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bird Nest-Like Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/CoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosphere Heterojunctions with Amorphous/Crystalline Structure for Enhanced Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01984</link>
      <description>Yingxin Liu, Hao Yan, Mingyang Cai, Wenliang Song, Ziling Huang, Xianggang Huang, Xin Wang, Hongwei Gu, Xueqin Cao, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399169854

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingxin Liu, Hao Yan, Mingyang Cai, Wenliang Song, Ziling Huang, Xianggang Huang, Xin Wang, Hongwei Gu, Xueqin Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precisely Constructing Orbital&#8208;Coupled Fe&#8208;Co Dual&#8208;atom Sites for High&#8208;Energy&#8208;Efficiency Zn&#8208;Air/Iodide Hybrid Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405533</link>
      <description>Jingyuan Qiao, Yurong You, Lingqiao Kong, Wei Feng, H.-T. Zhang, Haibin Huang, Caifang Li, Wei He, ZhengMing Sun, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399172904

                Abstract Rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) are promising for energy storage and conversion. However, the high charging voltage and low energy efficiency hinder their commercialization. Herein, we address these challenges by employing precisely constructed multifunctional Fe&#8208;Co diatomic site catalyst (FeCo&#8208;DACs) and integrating iodide/iodate redox into ZABs to create Zinc&#8208;air/iodide hybrid batteries (ZAIHBs) with highly efficient multifunctional catalyst. The strong coupling between the 3d orbitals of Fe and Co weakens the excessively strong binding strength between active sites and intermediates, enhancing the catalytic activities for oxygen reduction/evolution reaction and iodide/iodate redox. Consequently, FeCo&#8208;DACs exhibits outstanding bifunctional oxygen catalytic activity with a small potential gap (&#916;E = 0.66 V) and outstanding stability. Moreover, an outstanding catalytic performance towards iodide/iodate redox is obtained. Therefore, FeCo&#8208;DAC&#8208;based ZAIHBs exhibit high energy efficiency of up to 75% at 10 mA cm &#8208;2 and excellent cycling stability (72% after 500 hours). This research offers critical insights into the rational design of DACs, and paves the way for high&#8208;energy efficiency energy storage devices. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Jingyuan Qiao, Yurong You, Lingqiao Kong, Wei Feng, H.-T. Zhang, Haibin Huang, Caifang Li, Wei He, ZhengMing Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405533</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;Organic-Framework-Derived Nitrogen-Doped Carbon-Matrix-Encapsulating Co0.5Ni0.5 Alloy as a Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17112629</link>
      <description>Jinglin Liu, Lina Han, Song Xiao, Anqi Zhu, Yingjie Zhang, Xiaoyuan Zeng, Peng Dong, Materials. 17(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399185590

                The development of low-cost, high-performance oxygen electrocatalysts is of great significance for energy conversion and storage. As a potential substitute for precious metal electrocatalysts, the construction of efficient and cost-effective oxygen electrocatalysts is conducive to promoting the widespread application of zinc&#8211;air batteries. Herein, CoxNiyMOF nanoparticles encapsulated within a carbon matrix were synthesized and employed as cathode catalysts in zinc&#8211;air batteries. Co0.5Ni0.5MOF exhibits superior oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance and durability. The zinc&#8211;air battery assembled with Co0.5Ni0.5MOF as the air cathode exhibits a maximum power density of 138.6 mW&#183;cm&#8722;2. These improvements are mainly attributed to the optimized metal composition of the cobalt&#8211;nickel alloy, which increases the specific surface area of the material and optimizes its pore structure. Significantly, the optimization of the electronic structure and active sites within the material has led to amplified ORR/OER activity and better zinc&#8211;air battery performance. This study underscores the immense promise of Co0.5Ni0.5MOF catalysts as feasible substitutes for commercial Pt/C catalysts in zinc&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Jinglin Liu, Lina Han, Song Xiao, Anqi Zhu, Yingjie Zhang, Xiaoyuan Zeng, Peng Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17112629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir single atoms on NiFeZn-LDH matrix for exceptional oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6749-4</link>
      <description>Muhammad Israr, Muhammad Humayun, Jiaqi Zhang, Khadim Shah, Xin Tan, Chen Chen, Yadong Li, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399194464

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Israr, Muhammad Humayun, Jiaqi Zhang, Khadim Shah, Xin Tan, Chen Chen, Yadong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6749-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Replication Data for: Correlative operando microscopy of oxygen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/tnthxs</link>
      <description>J. Tyler Mefford, Harvard Dataverse. None(None)] 2021. https://openalex.org/W4398813804

                This dataset contains source data for Figures 1-5 and Supplementary Information Figures S2-S12 from "Correlative operando microscopy of oxygen evolution electrocatalysts." Data for each figure is provided in .xlsx files with filenames corresponding to the figure labels in the publication.</description>
      <author>J. Tyler Mefford</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7910/dvn/tnthxs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retaining the self-released chalcogenate at reconstructed cobalt sites by self-transformed carbonate regulation for boosted oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.021</link>
      <description>Jing Zhao, Zhe Xue, Qing Wang, Xiangyang Li, Shoujie Liu, Xu Zhao, Journal of Energy Chemistry/Journal of energy chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398784867

                The in-situ generated oxyanions at electrochemically reconstructed catalysts from metal-based non-oxide compounds have been proven to significantly accelerate oxygen evolution reaction (OER) kinetics. However, it remains a challenge to retain these self-released oxyanions at reconstructed catalysts, hindering its utilization as a tool to develop efficient OER catalysts. Here, we demonstrate a versatile self-transformed carbonate regulation strategy to efficiently retain the self-released chalcogenate at Co oxyhydroxides reconstructed from carbon-incorporated Co selenides under OER conditions. These self-transformed CO32&#8722; can induce electron accumulation and narrow d bond at Co sites to facilitate the Co 3d&#8211;O 2p orbital hybridization between Co sites and SeOx2&#8722; for enhanced SeOx2&#8722; retention, which can accelerate the rate-limiting step for *OOH formation during OER. Relative to CoOOH-SeOx2&#8722; with limited SeOx2&#8722; residues, CoOOH-CO32&#8722;/SeOx2&#8722; with elevated SeOx2&#8722; retention by CO32&#8722; regulation exhibited a 5.6-fold increase in current density and a remarkable lower Tafel slope towards OER. This strategy paves a rational avenue to design efficient catalysts for electrooxidation reactions through finely regulating self-released oxyanions at reconstructed structures.</description>
      <author>Jing Zhao, Zhe Xue, Qing Wang, Xiangyang Li, Shoujie Liu, Xu Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.05.021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopic Investigations of Complex Electronic Interactions by Elemental Doping and Material Compositing of Cobalt Oxide for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405384</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399080117

                Abstract Doping and compositing are two universal design strategies used to engineer the electronic state of a material and mitigate its disadvantages. These two strategies are extensively applied to design efficient electrocatalysts for water splitting. Using cobalt oxide (CoO) as a model catalyst, it is proven that the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance can be progressively improved, first by Fe&#8208;doping to form Fe&#8208;CoO solid solution, and further by the addition of CeO 2 to produce a Fe&#8208;CoO/CeO 2 composite. X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) reveals that distinct electronic interactions are induced by the processes of doping and compositing. Fe&#8208;doping of CoO can break down the structural symmetry, changing the electronic structure of both Co and O species at the surface and decreasing the flat&#8208;band potential (V fb ). In comparison, subsequent compositing of Fe&#8208;CoO with CeO 2 induces negligible electronic changes in the Fe&#8208;CoO (as seen in ex situ characterizations), but significantly modifies the oxidative transformations of both Co and Fe under OER conditions. The spectroscopic investigations reveal that Fe&#8208;doping and CeO 2 compositing play different roles in modifying the electronic properties of CoO in its pristine state and during OER catalysis, in return, providing useful guidance for the design of more efficient electrocatalysts using these two strategies.</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Adam H. Clark, Natasha Hales, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Radim Skoup&#253;, Thomas Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy as a Powerful Tool for Uncovering Property-Activity Relationships for Oxygen Evolution Transition Metal Oxide Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2533/chimia.2024.320</link>
      <description>Emiliana Fabbri, Thomas J. Schmidt, Chimia. 78(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399135286

                The development of a sustainable and environmentally friendly energy economy encompasses efficient hydrogen production from renewable energy via electrolysis. In this context, great efforts have recently been dedicated to the development of more efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts. Understanding the mechanism of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on transition metal oxide catalysts is of great interest, but the reaction and system complexity render the characterization of active sites and the understanding of reaction mechanisms challenging. Time resolved Quick X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy (XAS) can provide dynamic snapshots of the electronic and local structure of nanocatalysts, revealing the &#8216;real active phase&#8217; of the catalyst, which can substantially differ from the as-prepared catalyst powder or the catalyst in form of an electrode under non-operating conditions. In this contribution, several examples will be presented showing how operando XAS can reveal catalyst-support interactions, changes in the reaction mechanism, and dynamic reversible/irreversible changes in the electronic and local structure of OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Emiliana Fabbri, Thomas J. Schmidt</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2533/chimia.2024.320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing NiO/Co3O4/KNbO3 heterostructure with NiO and Co3O4 particles coupled on KNO3 cubes for high-performance urea-assisted alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.435</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liping Du, Jingwen Chen, Jing Tan, Xuemin Bai, Yahui Chen, Jikui Zhu, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399067586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liping Du, Jingwen Chen, Jing Tan, Xuemin Bai, Yahui Chen, Jikui Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.435</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-Term Evaluation of Inserted Nanocomposite Hydrogel-Based Phosphorescent Oxygen Biosensors: Evolution of Local Tissue Oxygen Levels and Foreign Body Response</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c00336</link>
      <description>David Chimene, Waqas Saleem, Nichole Longbottom, Brian S. Ko, Ananthakrishna Soundaram Jeevarathinam, Staci J. Horn, Michael J. McShane, ACS applied bio materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141031

                Phosphorescence-based oxygen-sensing hydrogels are a promising platform technology for an upcoming generation of insertable biosensors that are smaller, softer, and potentially more biocompatible than earlier designs. However, much remains unknown about their long-term performance and biocompatibility in vivo. In this paper, we design and evaluate a range of hydrogel sensors that contain oxygen-sensitive phosphors stabilized by micro- and nanocarrier systems. These devices demonstrated consistently good performance and biocompatibility in young adult rats for over three months. This study thoroughly establishes the biocompatibility and long-term suitability of phosphorescence lifetime sensors in vivo, providing the groundwork for expansion of this platform technology into a family of small, unobtrusive biosensors for a range of clinically relevant metabolites.</description>
      <author>David Chimene, Waqas Saleem, Nichole Longbottom, Brian S. Ko, Ananthakrishna Soundaram Jeevarathinam, Staci J. Horn, Michael J. McShane</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsabm.4c00336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cauliflower-Like Pd/Moc||Mo2c/C Heterostructure as an Efficient Trifunctional Catalyst for Formic Acid Oxidation, Hydrogen Evolution, and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4844553</link>
      <description>Ting Wang, Yuquan Feng, SU Jian-jun, Wei Qi, Xin Run, Jiannan Cai, Zhang Xiao-feng, Qiufeng Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399109585

                Developing efficient Pd-based multi-functional catalytic materials for formic acid oxidation reaction (FAO), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) remains a significant challenge. Transition metal interstitial carbides (TMICs) have emerged as promising candidates for electrocatalysis due to their unique structure. Cauliflower-shaped Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C nanostructured heterogeneous composites were prepared using a high-temperature pyrolysis and ethanol reduction method. The resulting materials exhibit high electrocatalytic performance towards FAO, HER, and ORR. In terms of FAO, the mass activity of Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C is 1.87 A mgPd-1, which is 2.75 times higher than that of Pd/C (0.68 A mgPd-1). As for the HER, a much lower overpotential of -28 mV is required to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm-2 compared to Pd/C(-40 mV). Fortunately, Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C also exhibits excellent ORR activity with a half-wave potential of 0.798 V and the maximum current density of approximately 5.73 mA cm-2 in alkaline electrolytes. The use of heterostructures enables the rearrangement of surface electrons, modifies active sites, and promotes the interaction between MoC||Mo2C/C and Pd. This leads to significant multifunctional catalytic performance. These findings could lead to the development of other noble metal-based materials loaded on intermetallic compounds with stable and effective electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Ting Wang, Yuquan Feng, SU Jian-jun, Wei Qi, Xin Run, Jiannan Cai, Zhang Xiao-feng, Qiufeng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4844553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of phenols evolution during pyrolysis of Shendong coal macerals swelled with oxygen-containing organic solvents: Experimental and DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152648</link>
      <description>Linyang Wang, Qing Yao, Rui Cao, Lei He, Ming Sun, Xiaoxun Ma, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399068710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linyang Wang, Qing Yao, Rui Cao, Lei He, Ming Sun, Xiaoxun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Product characterization and pore structure evolution of a tar-rich coal following pyrolysis under nitrogen, steam/nitrogen, and oxygen/nitrogen atmospheres</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106563</link>
      <description>Zhibing Chang, Chuchu Wang, Wenhao Kuang, Ying Tang, Xiaodan Wu, Shuqin Li, Journal of analytical and applied pyrolysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399071752

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhibing Chang, Chuchu Wang, Wenhao Kuang, Ying Tang, Xiaodan Wu, Shuqin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jaap.2024.106563</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterojunction catalysts of ultra-thin carbon layer activated Platinum nanoparticles for bifunctional pH-universal hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.265</link>
      <description>Hao Yu, Dongfang Chen, Guangxin Yang, Yuan Yuan, Huiyu Song, Shanwen Wang, Pucheng Pei, Xiao&#8211;Ming Xu, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399007201

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Yu, Dongfang Chen, Guangxin Yang, Yuan Yuan, Huiyu Song, Shanwen Wang, Pucheng Pei, Xiao&#8211;Ming Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolation and Crystallographic Characterization of an Octavalent Co2O2 Diamond Core</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mctcl</link>
      <description>Joseph E. Schneider, Shilin Zeng, Sophie W. Anferov, Alexander S. Filatov, John S. Anderson, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399176742

                High-valent cobalt-oxides play a pivotal role in alternative energy technology as catalysts for water splitting and as cath-odes in lithium-ion batteries. Despite this importance, the properties governing the stability of high-valent cobalt-oxides, and specifically possible oxygen evolution pathways, are not clear. One root of this limited understanding is the scarcity of high-valent, Co(IV)-containing model complexes; there are no reports of stable, well-defined complexes with multiple Co(IV) centers. Here, an oxidatively robust fluorinated ligand scaffold enables the isolation and crystallographic charac-terization of a Co(IV)2-bis-&#956;-oxo complex. This complex is remarkably stable, in stark contrast with previously reported Co(IV)2 species which are highly reactive, which demonstrates that oxy-Co(IV)2 species are not necessarily unstable with respect to oxygen evolution. This example underscores a new design strategy for highly oxidizing transition metal frag-ments and provides detailed data on a previously inaccessible chemical unit of relevance to O&#8211;O bond formation and oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Joseph E. Schneider, Shilin Zeng, Sophie W. Anferov, Alexander S. Filatov, John S. Anderson</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-mctcl</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Engineering Assisted CoNiP Nanosheet Arrays for Electrochemical Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00114a</link>
      <description>Linfei Zhang, Wenjing Ren, C Z Liu, Na He, Xinru He, Chunxian Guo, Yulin Jiang, Yong Hu, Shengliang Zhong, Materials advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398775816

                Electrochemical overall water splitting is a green, environmentally friendly, and efficient hydrogen production method that involves two half-reactions: oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Due to the...</description>
      <author>Linfei Zhang, Wenjing Ren, C Z Liu, Na He, Xinru He, Chunxian Guo, Yulin Jiang, Yong Hu, Shengliang Zhong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00114a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical mesoporous N-doped carbon as efficient ORR/OER bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00637b</link>
      <description>Li Ping, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Yanhong Xiang, Meiqi Li, Yongjie Zhao, Jian-Min Dou, Suna Wang, Yun&#8208;Wu Li, Huiyan Ma, Liqiang Xu, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399194950

                The construction of efficient oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER) bifunctional electrocatalysts is crucial for promising rechargeable Zinc-air batteries. Hierarchical mesoporous N doped carbon structures (HMNC) with superior catalytic...</description>
      <author>Li Ping, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Yanhong Xiang, Meiqi Li, Yongjie Zhao, Jian-Min Dou, Suna Wang, Yun&#8208;Wu Li, Huiyan Ma, Liqiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00637b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Electron Redistribution in Platinum for Enhanced Alkaline Water Splitting Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00503a</link>
      <description>Wensheng Zhang, Xu Chen, Jinyu Zhao, Ning Lin, Guipeng Wang, Xiaomin Wang, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399109099

                The potential of hydrogen production via water splitting technology makes it urgent to develop low-cost and highly active bifunctional catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER). In this study,...</description>
      <author>Wensheng Zhang, Xu Chen, Jinyu Zhao, Ning Lin, Guipeng Wang, Xiaomin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00503a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the active interface structure of MnO2 to achieve sustainable water oxidation in Acidic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02256d</link>
      <description>San-Jiang Pan, Shen Wang, Yu Wang, H.B. Li, Deng Zhao, Liu Yang, Hua Liao, Jiajing Kou, Nan Li, Desong Wang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399055133

                Developing cost-effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis is crucial to achieving large-scale hydrogen production through water electrolysis. Here, we propose the...</description>
      <author>San-Jiang Pan, Shen Wang, Yu Wang, H.B. Li, Deng Zhao, Liu Yang, Hua Liao, Jiajing Kou, Nan Li, Desong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02256d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Oxygen Vacancies with Different Valence States on the Photo(electro)catalytic Performance of a 2D TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;:N (001) System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c01809</link>
      <description>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Shaoqiang Guo, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398781021

                The effect of different valence states Vo on the photo(electro)catalytic performance of the 2D TiO2:N system was investigated using the GGA+U method with first principles. In the poor oxygen conditions, the Ef values of 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0/Vo1+/Vo2+) systems are all less than zero, and all of them are exothermic. Photocatalytic investigations revealed that among the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo1+), 2D Ti24O46N (Vo2+), and 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) systems, the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system has the best carrier activity, the longest electron&#8211;hole lifetime, prominent visible light, infrared light redshift, and outstanding oxidation ability. The photocatalytic decomposition of water and oxygen evolution is highly advantageous. Electrocatalytic studies showed that compared with the free energy of 2D Ti24O46N (Vo1+) and 2D Ti24O46N (Vo2+) systems the free energy &#916;GH* of the 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system is &#8722;0.156 eV and the smallest, which is conducive to hydrogen evolution. The overpotential of the oxygen evolution reaction is 0.360 V, which is close to zero, and the four reaction processes are all downward, indicating that the OER reaction can be driven independently by the photogenerated holes, which is conducive to the electrocatalytic reaction. Moreover, the ability of decomposing water is relatively good. The 2D Ti24O46N (Vo0) system is a candidate nanomaterial and can be applied as a novel photoelectric catalyst.</description>
      <author>Wenxing Wang, Qingyu Hou, Shaoqiang Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c01809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>BaCoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Tetrahedral Cobalt Coordination: The Missing Element to Understand Energy Storage and Conversion Applications in BaCoO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt;-Based Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14047</link>
      <description>Aliou Diatta, Claire Colin, Romain Viennois, M. Beaudhuin, Julien Haines, Patrick Hermet, Arie van der Lee, Leszek Konczewicz, P. Armand, J&#233;r&#244;me Rouquette, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050116

                Barium&#8211;cobaltate-based perovskite (BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;) and barium&#8211;cobaltate-based nanocomposites have been intensively studied in energy storage and conversion devices mainly due to flexible oxygen stoichiometry and tunable nonprecious transition metal oxidation states. Although a rich and complex family of structural polymorphs has already been reported for these perovskites in the literature, the potential structural evolution that may occur during the oxygen reduction reaction and the oxygen evolution reaction has not been investigated so far. In this study, we synthesized and characterized the lowest Co-oxidation state possible in the compound, BaCoO2, which exhibits a quartz-derived, trigonal structure with a helicoidally corner-sharing, CoO4-tetrahedral-framework as already proposed by Spitsbergen et al. Oxygen can reversibly be inserted in such a crystal structure to form BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;, i.e., with 0 &#8804; &#948; &#8804; 1, based on the results of an in situ coupled thermogravimetric - neutron diffraction study and which presents therefore giant oxygen capacity storage due to the extreme tunability of the electronic configuration of the cobalt cations which defines the fundamental origins of the materials performance. The reversible conversion of BaCoO2 to BaCoO3&#8722;&#948; associated with a similar electronic conductivity above 900 K permits to clarify the high potential of BaCoO3&#8722;&#948;-based energy storage and conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Aliou Diatta, Claire Colin, Romain Viennois, M. Beaudhuin, Julien Haines, Patrick Hermet, Arie van der Lee, Leszek Konczewicz, P. Armand, J&#233;r&#244;me Rouquette</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c14047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy-Enhanced Ni3N-CeO2/NF Nanoparticle Catalysts for Efficient and Stable Electrolytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110935</link>
      <description>Xianghao Meng, Xin Zhao, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Yiting Peng, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399042805

                Highly efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts are of critical significance in the domain of water electrolysis. In this study, a Ni3N-CeO2/NF heterostructure is synthesized through a facile hydrothermal technique followed by a subsequent nitridation process. This catalyst is endowed with an abundance of oxygen vacancies, thereby conferring a richer array of active sites. Therefore, the catalyst demonstrates a markedly low overpotential of 350 mV for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 and a low overpotential of 42 mV for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Serving as a dual-function electrode, this electrocatalyst is employed in overall water splitting in alkaline environments, demonstrating impressive efficiency at a cell voltage of 1.52 V of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The in situ Raman spectroscopic analysis demonstrates that cerium dioxide (CeO2) facilitates the rapid reconfiguration of oxygen vacancy-enriched nickel oxyhydroxide (NiOOH), thereby enhancing the OER performance. This investigation elucidates the catalytic role of CeO2 in augmenting the OER efficiency of nickel nitride (Ni3N) for water electrolysis, offering valuable insights for the design of high-performance bifunctional catalysts tailored for water splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Xianghao Meng, Xin Zhao, Yulin Min, Qiaoxia Li, Yiting Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110935</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controllable Phase Separation Engineering of Iron&#8211;Cobalt Alloy Heterojunction for Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01147</link>
      <description>Yanhong Ding, Xiao-Tong Han, Qian Yang, Yan Jiang, Gang Bai, Jianping Zhang, Weihua Li, Baoshan Hu, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399175458

                The tailor-made transition metal alloy-based heterojunctions hold a promising prospect for the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, a series of iron-cobalt bimetallic alloy heterojunctions are purposely designed and constructed via a newly developed controllable phase separation engineering strategy. The results show that the phase separation process and alloy component distribution rely on the metal molar ratio (Fe/Co), indicative of the metal content dependent behavior. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that the electronic structure and charge distribution of iron-cobalt bimetallic alloy can be modulated and optimized, thus leading to the formation of an electron-rich interface layer, which likely tunes the</description>
      <author>Yanhong Ding, Xiao-Tong Han, Qian Yang, Yan Jiang, Gang Bai, Jianping Zhang, Weihua Li, Baoshan Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01147</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From density functional theory to machine learning predictive models for electrical properties of spinel oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62788-4</link>
      <description>Yuval Elbaz, Maytal Caspary Toroker, Scientific reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399037502

                Abstract This work focuses on predicting and characterizing the electronic conductivity of spinel oxides, which are promising materials for energy storage devices and for the oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions due to their attractive properties and abundance of transition metals that can act as active sites for catalysis. To this end, a new database was developed from first principles, including band structure and conductivity properties of spinel oxides, and machine learning algorithms were trained on this database to predict electronic conductivity and band gaps based solely on the compositions. The models developed in this study are scaled from the quantum level up to a continuum conductivity model. The relatively small database used in this study allowed for accurate predictions of band gap and conductivity. By altering the composition of spinel oxides, the model was able to predict high conductivity for spinels with high nickel content and to match experimental trends for manganese cobalt spinels. The ability to predict material properties is especially important in energy conversion devices such as batteries and supercapacitors where redox reactions take place.</description>
      <author>Yuval Elbaz, Maytal Caspary Toroker</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-62788-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MoOx/CoMo on Cu nanowires as an efficiently bifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400582</link>
      <description>Xingchen Chai, Cang Yuan, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Lei Wang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399047706

                Electrocatalytic water splitting is a promising approach for sustainable hydrogen production. The design and development of efficient and stable bifunctional catalysts are the key to realizing hydrogen production from water splitting. Herein, we successfully synthesized bifunctional MoOx/CoMo grown on copper nanowires (Cu NWs) through an electrodeposition approach, showing excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performances. The MoOx/CoMo/Cu NWs catalyst exhibited overpotentials as low as 56 mV and 211 mV to deliver a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 for HER and OER in alkaline media, respectively. Moreover, the MoOx/CoMo/Cu NWs as bifunctional electrodes for overall water splitting achieved a low voltage of 1.45 and 1.62 V at 10 and 50 mA cm&#8208;2, respectively, with a stability of 10 h at 50 mA cm&#8208;2. This work provides a promising strategy for designing highly active catalysts that replace precious&#8208;metal&#8208;based catalysts on energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Xingchen Chai, Cang Yuan, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400582</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Application of a Gas Diffusion Electrode (GDE) Cell for Operando and In Situ Studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2533/chimia.2024.344</link>
      <description>Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Rebecca Pittkowski, Stefanie Punke, Olivia Aalling&#8208;Frederiksen, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Matthias Arenz, Chimia. 78(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399135277

                Presented here is an electrochemical three-electrode Gas Diffusion Electrode (GDE) cell tailored for operandoand in situ investigations of electrocatalytic processes, with a particular focus on X-ray scattering studies. The optimized cell is engineered to accommodate the minimal sample-detector distances requisite for comprehensive X-ray total scattering investigations. An in-depth understanding of catalytic processes requires their study under &#8216;working&#8217; conditions. Configured as a flow-cell, the setup therefore enables the examination of electrocatalysts under high current densities and associated gas evolution phenomena, particularly pertinent for reactions like the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Notably, its transparency simplifies cell alignment, troubleshooting, and facilitates scans through the catalyst layer, crucial for background corrections. Demonstrating its versatility, we showcase its utility through Small Angle X-ray Scattering (SAXS), X-ray Diffraction (XRD), and X-ray Pair Distribution Function (PDF) analyses of total scattering data.</description>
      <author>Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Rebecca Pittkowski, Stefanie Punke, Olivia Aalling&#8208;Frederiksen, Kirsten M. &#216;. Jensen, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2533/chimia.2024.344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Oxidation of Small Molecules for Energy&#8208;Saving Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401242</link>
      <description>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Liangshuang Fei, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399047723

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting is a promising technique for the production of high&#8208;purity hydrogen. Substituting the slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction with an oxidation reaction that is thermodynamically more favorable enables the energy&#8208;efficient production of hydrogen. Moreover, this approach facilitates the degradation of environmental pollutants and synthesis of value&#8208;added chemicals through the rational selection of small molecules as substrates. Strategies for small&#8208;molecule selection and electrocatalyst design are critical to electrocatalytic performance, with a focus on achieving a high current density, selectivity, Faradaic efficiency, and operational durability. This perspective discusses the key factors required for further advancement, including technoeconomic analysis, new reactor system design, meeting the requirements of industrial applications, bridging the gap between fundamental research and practical applications, and product detection and separation. This perspective aims to advance the development of hybrid water electrolysis applications.</description>
      <author>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Liangshuang Fei, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Image, Volume 6, Number 5, May 2024</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.606</link>
      <description>Hongyu Gong, Guanliang Sun, Wei Shi, Dongwei Li, Xiangjun Zheng, Huan Shi, Xiu Liang, Ruizhi Yang, Changzhou Yuan, Carbon energy. 6(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399142520

                Front cover image: Enhancing both the number of active sites available and the intrinsic activity of Co-based oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts simultaneously is a desirable goal. In the article number CEY2432, Yuan et al. reported a ZIF-67-derived hierarchical porous cobalt sulfide decorated by Au nanoparticles (denoted as HP-Au@CoxSy@ZIF-67) hybrid. The novel three-dimensional hierarchical structure significantly enlarges the three-phase interfaces, accelerating the mass transfer and exposing the active centers. Meanwhile, the electronic structure of Co is modulated by Au through charge transfer, wherein Au and NaBH4 reductant result in an interesting "competition effect" to regulate the relative ratio of Co2+/Co3+. Consequently, HP-Au@CoxSy@ZIF-67 displayed excellent OER performance, enabling efficient water splitting and Zn&#8211;air battery application.</description>
      <author>Hongyu Gong, Guanliang Sun, Wei Shi, Dongwei Li, Xiangjun Zheng, Huan Shi, Xiu Liang, Ruizhi Yang, Changzhou Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactivity and Durability of Covalent Organic Frameworks Derived Co&#8208;based Hybrid Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400068</link>
      <description>Yuling Zhang, Longfei Xiao, Yiping Mo, Gao Liu, Shanshan Liu, Wangyang L&#252;, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398782793

                Developing bifunctional non&#8208;precious metal electrocatalysts of superior reactivity and durability is essential. Herein, we report a class of phthalocyanine&#8208;based covalent organic frameworks as self&#8208;sacrificial precursors derived Co&#8208;based hybrid electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The fabricated Co&#8208;COFs/CNT&#8208;700 catalysts displayed highly efficient ORR properties with a half&#8208;potential of 0.83 V, while its half&#8208;wave potential in alkaline solution at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 is 1.70 V in the OER test, reflecting exceptional OER activity. Moreover, zinc&#8208;air batteries assembled with Co&#8208;COFs/CNT&#8208;700 catalysts exhibit a marginally higher power density (114 mW cm2) than traditional Pt/C&#8208;IrO2 batteries in an air atmosphere, along with an enhanced cycling stability (5.1% potential loss after 65 h). This work may pave a facile and efficient approach for fabricating electrocatalytic materials with controllably introduced metals and heteroatoms.</description>
      <author>Yuling Zhang, Longfei Xiao, Yiping Mo, Gao Liu, Shanshan Liu, Wangyang L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Ni nanoparticles/N-doped carbon sheets for freshwater and seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131995</link>
      <description>Dawei Wang, Xuehong Wang, Hao Qiu, Yixuan Tao, Jie Yin, Juan Li, Wenpin Wang, Zhongcheng Li, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398793128

                Electric-driven water dissociation is considered to be a sustainable approach for the generation of H2. Ni nanoparticles show poor freshwater/seawater electrolysis activity owing to the severe aggregation of Ni, which blocks the active sites to catalyze water splitting. Here, we present Ni nanoparticles/N-doped carbon sheets by the thermal treatment of Ni-based triazole-benzoic acid complexes. The electronic state and coordination environment of Ni are modulated by the formation of the confined space with the N-doped carbon layer. Ni/N-doped carbon sheets promote acidic/alkaline hydrogen evolution activity with 143/81 mV@10 mA/cm2. Upon being used as the catalysts for water oxidation reaction, it expedited alkaline oxygen evolution 218/312 mV@10/50 mA/cm2 for Ni/N-doped carbon, which is even superior to commercial RuO2 with 309/364 mV. Tests for alkaline freshwater/seawater splitting find that Ni/N-doped carbon sheets possess remarkable activity with 1.56/1.62 V@10 mA/cm2 as well as outstanding stability. Our work offers an efficient strategy to rationally regulate the coordination structure of metal nanoparticles for promoting water electrolysis activity.</description>
      <author>Dawei Wang, Xuehong Wang, Hao Qiu, Yixuan Tao, Jie Yin, Juan Li, Wenpin Wang, Zhongcheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131995</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in Joule&#8208;heating synthesis of functional nanomaterials for photo and electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/phmt.14</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Li, Laiyu Luo, Siyu Wang, Haojie Song, Baojiang Jiang, PhotoMat . None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399150132

                Abstract Background Catalyst synthesis plays a crucial role in advancing photo and electrocatalysis technologies for sustainable development. However, the traditional thermal radiation heating method suffers from the disadvantages of high energy consumption, low heat transfer efficiency, slow heating speed and long heating time, which leads to the inefficiency and cost increases in catalyst preparation. Aims The Joule&#8208;heating ultrafast synthesis method with rapid heating/quenching and shorter heating time has attracted much attention. Despite its potential, there is a lack of comprehensive reviews specifically addressing the synthesis of advanced photo and electrocatalysts via Joule&#8208;heating. Therefore, this review aims to help people quickly understand the advantages of Joule&#8208;heating in the synthesis of photo and electrocatalysts. Discussion Herein, we firstly introduce the principles and devices of Joule&#8208;heating, and then we discuss breakthroughs in defect modulation, heterojunction construction, single&#8208;atom catalysts, bimetallic alloy catalysts, high&#8208;entropy alloy catalysts and metastable catalysts achieved through Joule&#8208;heating technology. The diverse applications of these catalysts include hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, oxygen reduction reactions, carbon dioxide reduction reactions, nitrogen reduction reaction and degradation of organic pollutants. Furthermore, this review provides a forward&#8208;looking perspective on future directions for employing Joule&#8208;heating methods in the field of photo and electrocatalysis research. Conclusion This review highlights the pivotal role played by Joule&#8208;heating techniques in advancing nanomaterial synthesis as well as developing sustainable high&#8208;performance catalyst systems.</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Li, Laiyu Luo, Siyu Wang, Haojie Song, Baojiang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/phmt.14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterostructure catalyst coupled wood-derived carbon and cobalt-iron alloy/oxide for reversible oxygen conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42773-024-00348-9</link>
      <description>Limin Zhou, Junxiao Li, Jiao Yin, Gaoyue Zhang, Pengxiang Zhang, Jing-Jing Zhou, Anqi Zhang, Ao Wang, Baojun Li, Yanyan Liu, Kang Sun, Biochar. 6(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398780760

                Abstract As promising energy-storage devices, zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) exhibit slow reaction kinetics for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) occurring at their electrodes. High-performance bifunctional catalysts must thus be synthesized to accelerate the reversible conversion of oxygen and improve the rate and overall performance of ZABs. Herein, we reported the promising prospects of self-supported composite electrodes composed of wood-derived carbon (WDC) and bimetallic cobalt-iron alloys/oxides (CoFe-CoFe 2 O 4 @WDC) as efficient electrocatalysts for alkaline ORR/OER. WDC provided a favorable three-phase interface for heterogeneous reactions owing to its layered porous structure and genetic stability, thereby enabling mass diffusion and improving reaction kinetics. The CoFe 2 O 4 spinel surface was reduced to bimetallic CoFe alloy to form abundant heterostructure interfaces that promote electron transfer. Under alkaline conditions, the optimized composite electrode exhibited a remarkable high half-wave potential of 0.85 V and an exceptionally low overpotential of 1.49 V. It also exhibited stable performance over an impressive 2340 cycles in a ZAB. Theoretical calculations also confirmed that the heterointerface addresses the issue of proton scarcity throughout the reaction and actively facilitates the creation of O&#8211;O bonds during the reversible transformation of oxygen. This study introduces a new concept for developing bifunctional and efficient electrocatalysts based on charcoal and encourages the sustainable and high-value use of forest biomass resources. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Limin Zhou, Junxiao Li, Jiao Yin, Gaoyue Zhang, Pengxiang Zhang, Jing-Jing Zhou, Anqi Zhang, Ao Wang, Baojun Li, Yanyan Liu, Kang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42773-024-00348-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrystalline CuOx Thin Films for Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.1556.v2</link>
      <description>E. Silva, F&#225;bio Viadanna Serr&#227;o, Gustavo Henrique dos Santos Domingos, Thiago M.B.F. Oliveira, Marco A. L. Cordeiro, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399138178

                New advances in creating effective and affordable copper-based catalysts for water splitting represent a promising strategy for driving sustainable energy technologies. However, ma- terials containing copper are susceptible to corrosion and agglomeration. In this study, we describe a synthesis route to produce olamine-functionalized CuO nanoparticles using the Hot Injection method. Nanoparticles were obtained and subsequently deposited on FTO substrates, undergoing thermal treatment at 500&amp;deg;C and 600&amp;deg;C in atmospheres containing O2 and N2, aiming to enhance the adhesion of the active material to the substrate and modify its oxidation state. Microstructural properties were analyzed using XRD, SEM, and TEM, while electrochemical properties were studied using CV, LSV, and EIS. Electrodes treated thermally in an N2 atmosphere at 600&amp;deg;C exhibited higher ESCA, indicating a greater area of active sites exposed to surface reactions and, therefore, superior catalytic activity in Hy- drogen Evolution Reaction (HER). These findings show an interesting strategy for avoiding rapid electron-hole recombination and, consequently, CuO corrosion. For Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), samples treated thermally in O2 atmosphere at 500&amp;deg;C and 600&amp;deg;C appear to be more effective.</description>
      <author>E. Silva, F&#225;bio Viadanna Serr&#227;o, Gustavo Henrique dos Santos Domingos, Thiago M.B.F. Oliveira, Marco A. L. Cordeiro</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.1556.v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocrystalline CuOx Thin Films for Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.1556.v1</link>
      <description>E. Silva, F&#225;bio Viadanna Serr&#227;o, Gustavo Henrique dos Santos Domingos, Thiago M.B.F. Oliveira, Marco A. L. Cordeiro, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398782624

                New advances in creating effective and affordable copper-based catalysts for water splitting represent a promising strategy for driving sustainable energy technologies. However, ma- terials containing copper are susceptible to corrosion and agglomeration. In this study, we describe a synthesis route to produce olamine-functionalized CuO nanoparticles using the Hot Injection method. Nanoparticles were obtained and subsequently deposited on FTO substrates, undergoing thermal treatment at 500&amp;deg;C and 600&amp;deg;C in atmospheres containing O2 and N2, aiming to enhance the adhesion of the active material to the substrate and modify its oxidation state. Microstructural properties were analyzed using XRD, SEM, and TEM, while electrochemical properties were studied using CV, LSV, and EIS. Electrodes treated thermally in an N2 atmosphere at 600&amp;deg;C exhibited higher ESCA, indicating a greater area of active sites exposed to surface reactions and, therefore, superior catalytic activity in Hy- drogen Evolution Reaction (HER). These findings show an interesting strategy for avoiding rapid electron-hole recombination and, consequently, CuO corrosion. For Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), samples treated thermally in O2 atmosphere at 500&amp;deg;C and 600&amp;deg;C appear to be more effective.</description>
      <author>E. Silva, F&#225;bio Viadanna Serr&#227;o, Gustavo Henrique dos Santos Domingos, Thiago M.B.F. Oliveira, Marco A. L. Cordeiro</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202405.1556.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Covalent organic framework&#8208;derived Fe, Co&#8208;nitrogen codoped carbon as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable efficient Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.145</link>
      <description>Zhanpeng Chen, Jiabi Jiang, Mingjun Jing, Yiming Bai, Xiaoyan Zhang, Wenhui Deng, Yufeng Wu, Fang Chen, Mingguang Yi, Meixia Yang, Xinkai Xu, Tianjing Wu, Zhiwei Yang, Xianyou Wang, Carbon neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050151

                Abstract The development of cathode materials with controllable physicochemical structures and explicit catalytic sites is important in rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Covalent organic frameworks (COFs) have garnered increasing attention owing to their facile synthesis methods, ordered pore structure, and selectivity of functional groups. However, the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) or oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) inhibit their practical applications in ZABs. Herein, nucleophilic substitution is adopted to synthesize pyridine bi&#8208;triazine covalent organic framework (denoted as O&#8208;COF), and meanwhile, ionothermal conversion synthesis is employed to load MO x (M=Fe, Co) onto carbon nanosheet (named as FeCo@NC) to modulate the electronic structure. The Fe, Co&#8208;N codoped carbon material possesses a large portion of pyridinic N and M&#8208;N, high graphitization, and a larger BET surface area. An outstanding bifunctional activity has been exhibited in FeCo@NC, which provides a small voltage at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER (E 10 = 1.67 V) and a remarkable half&#8208;wave voltage for ORR (E 1/2 = 0.86 V). More impressively, when assembling ZABs, it displays notable rate performance, significant specific capacity (783.9 mAh g Zn &#8722;1 ), and satisfactory long&#8208;term endurance. This method of regulating covalent organic framework and ionothermal synthesis can be extended to design diverse catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhanpeng Chen, Jiabi Jiang, Mingjun Jing, Yiming Bai, Xiaoyan Zhang, Wenhui Deng, Yufeng Wu, Fang Chen, Mingguang Yi, Meixia Yang, Xinkai Xu, Tianjing Wu, Zhiwei Yang, Xianyou Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrocatalytic water splitting activity by using Ni0.85Se anchored on amorphous Ni4Mo alloy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.300</link>
      <description>Renjie Li, Lili Cui, Dou Zhang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398792265

                To design and construct bifunctional electrocatalyst with high activity is important to the commercial development of electrochemical water splitting (EWS) technology. The carbon clothe (CC) supported on Ni(OH)2 nanosheet is used as template to tune the morphology of Ni0.85Se. To improve the activity of Ni0.85Se, amorphous Ni4Mo alloy is anchored on the Ni0.85Se to obtain the Ni0.85Se/Ni4Mo catalyst (NS/NM) by electrodeposition method. The electron state and conductivity of NS/NM are modulated compared to that of the NS sample. It is found that the electron transfers from Ni4Mo to Ni0.85Se. Benefiting from the tuned electron state of Ni0.85Se and Ni4Mo, the enhanced number of exposed active sites and lower Rct value, the NS/NM heterostructure electrode requires low overpotentials of 51 and 206 mV to obtain 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The optimized electrode shows fast kinetics and exhibits near to 100% Faraday efficiency for HER and OER in 1 M KOH. Importantly, it is noted that the electrocatalytic activity of NS/NM catalyst for both HER and OER is enhanced obviously in comparison with NS sample. With heterostructure catalyst, the EWS only proceeds at 1.48 V to yield 10 mA cm&#8722;2, which is reduced about 110 mV compared to NS electrode. Here, a novel kind of bifunctional heterostructure electrocatalyst is constructed.</description>
      <author>Renjie Li, Lili Cui, Dou Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.300</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Ultrastable Iodide Oxidation Reaction Over Defect&#8208;Passivated Perovskite Photoanode for Unassisted Solar Fuel Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401055</link>
      <description>Juwon Yun, Young Sun Park, Hyungsoo Lee, Wooyong Jeong, Chang&#8208;Seop Jeong, Chan Uk Lee, Jeongyoub Lee, Subin Moon, Euna Kwon, Soo Bin Lee, Sumin Kim, Junghwan Kim, Seungho Yu, Jooho Moon, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399044053

                Abstract Recently, lead halide perovskites have emerged as promising photoanode materials for efficient hydrogen production. However, the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and interfacial defect&#8208;mediated charge accumulation inevitably result in efficiency loss and degradation of perovskite photoanodes. Herein, a defect&#8208;passivated electron transport layer&#8208;based perovskite photoanode combined with a catalyst layer favorable is introduced for iodide oxidation reaction bearing a small thermodynamic barrier and rapid kinetics compared to OER for efficient solar fuel generation. The resulting perovskite photoanode revealed a saturated photocurrent density of 22.4 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0.3 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (V RHE ) with an impressive onset potential of &#8722;0.2 V RHE as well as durability for 225 h in a neutral electrolyte. In addition, an unbiased hydrogen&#8208;production device comprising a perovskite photoanode and Pt coil electrocatalyst is demonstrated, achieving a remarkable solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion efficiency of 11.45% and stable operation for 25 h. Moreover, a wireless artificial leaf&#8208;structured device realizing solar&#8208;driven hydrogen generation in natural sea water under outdoor sunlight is presented.</description>
      <author>Juwon Yun, Young Sun Park, Hyungsoo Lee, Wooyong Jeong, Chang&#8208;Seop Jeong, Chan Uk Lee, Jeongyoub Lee, Subin Moon, Euna Kwon, Soo Bin Lee, Sumin Kim, Junghwan Kim, Seungho Yu, Jooho Moon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe, Co-induced hydrolysis to prepare &#945;-Ni (OH)2/&#946;-Ni(OH)2 interfaces for improved overall water splitting efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144484</link>
      <description>Guoxu Zhou, Zining Wang, Xichun Zhang, Shan Ji, Rongfang Wang, Xianguo Ma, Xuyun Wang, Vladimir Linkov, Rongfang Wang, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399142500

                The development of effective bifunctional electrode materials is necessary for worldwide adoption of large-scale hydrogen production by water electrolysis. Nickel hydroxide - based transition metal materials are among the most promising electrodes for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). While Ni(OH)2 exists in two crystalline states, namely &#945;-Ni(OH)2 and &#946;-Ni(OH)2, neither can meet requirements for effective bifunctional electrode materials on their own, due to relatively low catalytic activity. In this study, bifunctional catalysts with &#945;-Ni(OH)2/&#946;-Ni(OH)2 interfaces, prepared using Fe, Co-induced hydrolysis, have been successfully applied for electrolytic water splitting. According to physical characterization, Fe3+ and Co2+ are incorporated into Ni(OH)2 layers, where Fe doping leads to the formation of a regular flake structure, while Co doping facilitates surface electron transfer, enhancing electrocatalytic activity towards HER and OER. Overpotentials of the obtained catalysts at 100 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 are as low as 224 mV for HER and 324 mV for OER. Both HER and OER overpotentials remained almost unchanged after 24 h operation at a high current density of 1 A&#183;cm&#8722;2, demonstrating excellent stability of the newly prepared materials during water electrolysis. The synthesis of &#945;-Ni(OH)2/&#946;-Ni(OH)2 interfaces is a new direction for the manufacturing of industrially applicable water splitting electrocatalysts suitable for high current density operation.</description>
      <author>Guoxu Zhou, Zining Wang, Xichun Zhang, Shan Ji, Rongfang Wang, Xianguo Ma, Xuyun Wang, Vladimir Linkov, Rongfang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Noble Metal-free Ternary Chalcogenide Electrocatalysts for
  Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.14187</link>
      <description>Shantanu Singh, Ahamed Irshad, Germany Diaz De la Cruz, Boyang Zhao, Billal Zayat, Qiaowan Chang, S. R. Narayanan, Jayakanth Ravichandran, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398796735

                Hydrogen has been identified as a clean, zero carbon, sustainable, and promising energy source for the future, and electrochemical water splitting for hydrogen production is an emission-free, efficient energy conversion technology. A major limitation of this approach is the unavailability of efficient, abundant, inexpensive catalysts, which prompts the need for new catalytic materials. Here, we report the synthesis and electrocatalytic properties of a novel transition metal-based ternary chalcogenide family, LaMS$_3$ (M = Mn, Fe, Co, Ni). Powder X-ray diffraction confirms the phase purity of these materials, while composition analysis using energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDS) confirms the presence of the stoichiometric ratio of elements in these compounds. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) were used to study the chemical states on the surface and in bulk, respectively. These materials exhibit bifunctional catalytic activity towards the two half-reactions of the water-splitting process, with LaNiS$_3$ being the most active material for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The LaMS$_3$ compounds show long-term stability with negligible change in the overpotential at a constant current density of 10 mA cm$^{-2}$ over 18 hours of measurements. As compared to the corresponding ternary oxides, the LaMS$_3$ materials exhibit higher activity and significantly lower Tafel slopes. The ability to catalyze both half-reactions of water electrolysis makes these materials promising candidates for bifunctional catalysts and presents a new avenue to search for high-efficiency electrocatalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Shantanu Singh, Ahamed Irshad, Germany Diaz De la Cruz, Boyang Zhao, Billal Zayat, Qiaowan Chang, S. R. Narayanan, Jayakanth Ravichandran</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.14187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of Biphasic Boride Electrocatalysts on Dealloyed Bulk Ni&#8211;Mo Alloy as Self-Supporting Electrode for Water Splitting at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04157</link>
      <description>Guangyao Yang, Weiliang Peng, Zhipeng Chen, Shaobo Li, Han Qin, Renzong Hu, Bin Yuan, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399050071

                Nickel&#8211;molybdenum&#8211;boron (Ni&#8211;Mo&#8211;B)-based catalysts with biphasic interfaces are highly advantageous in bifunctional electrocatalytic activity in alkaline water-splitting. However, it remains an ongoing challenge to obtain porous Ni&#8211;Mo alloy substrates that provide stable adhesion to catalysts, ensuring the long-term performance of bifunctional self-supporting electrodes at a high current density. Herein, a porous Ni&#8211;Mo alloy substrate was effectively obtained by a cost-effective dealloying process on a commercial Ni&#8211;Mo alloy with high-energy crystal planes. Subsequently, the Mo2NiB2/Ni3B bifunctional catalyst was in situ synthesized on this substrate via boriding heat treatment, resulting in outstanding catalytic activity and stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the abundant biphasic interfaces and surface-reconstructed sites of the Mo2NiB2/Ni3B catalyst can decrease the energy barriers for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively. Thus, the designed self-supporting electrodes show bifunctional catalytic activity with overpotentials of 151 mV for HER and 260 mV for OER at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2. Markedly, the assembled water electrolyzer can be driven up to 10 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.64 V and maintain catalytic activity at a high current density of 1000 mA cm&#8211;2 for 100 h. The new strategy is expected to provide a low-cost scheme for designing self-supporting bifunctional electrodes with high activity and excellent stability and contribute to the development of hydrogen energy technology.</description>
      <author>Guangyao Yang, Weiliang Peng, Zhipeng Chen, Shaobo Li, Han Qin, Renzong Hu, Bin Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Pyrolysis Mechanism of Binuclear Chromium-Based Complexes for Superior OER Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04688</link>
      <description>Meixing Gan, Li Li, Xixian Yang, Hongwei Rong, Zheng Wang, Yuebin Li, Yuexing Zhang, Xueli Chen, Peng Xu, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398775852

                Transition metal oxides are widely pursued as potent electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, single-metal chromium catalysts remain underexplored due to their intrinsic activity limitations. Herein, we successfully synthesize mixed-valence, nitrogen-doped Cr2O3/CrO3/CrN@NC nanoelectrocatalysts via one-step targeted pyrolysis techniques from a binuclear Cr-based complex (Cr2(Salophen)2(CH3OH)2), which is strategically designed as a precursor. Comprehensive pyrolysis mechanisms were thoroughly delineated by using coupled thermogravimetric analysis and mass spectrometry (TG&#8211;MS) alongside X-ray diffraction. Below 800 &#176;C, the generation of a reducing atmosphere was noted, while continuous pyrolysis at temperatures exceeding 800 &#176;C promoted highly oxidized CrO3 species with an elevated +6 oxidation state. The optimized catalyst pyrolyzed at 1000 &#176;C (Cr2O3/CrO3/CrN@NCs-1000) demonstrated remarkable OER activity with a low overpotential of 290 mV in 1 M KOH and excellent stability. Further density functional theory (DFT) calculations revealed a much smaller reaction energy barrier of CrO3 than the low oxidation state species for OER reactivity. This work reveals fresh strategies for rationally engineering chromium-based electrocatalysts and overcoming intrinsic roadblocks to enable efficient OER catalysis through a deliberate oxidation state and compositional tuning.</description>
      <author>Meixing Gan, Li Li, Xixian Yang, Hongwei Rong, Zheng Wang, Yuebin Li, Yuexing Zhang, Xueli Chen, Peng Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c04688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MnO2 anchored N&#8211;Ti3C2 MXene as a bifunctional electrode for enhanced water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.323</link>
      <description>Sandra Mathew, K.R. Sunaja Devi, International journal of hydrogen energy. 71(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398978119

                The domain of energy research is vigorously exploring a wide array of materials, from advanced carbon-based substances like graphene and carbon nanotubes to emerging contenders like MXenes. Ti3C2 MXene offers exceptional performance in electrochemistry, benefiting from its remarkable electronic conductivity, considerable surface area, chemical stability, cost-effectiveness, hydrophilicity, and eco-friendliness. However, it undergoes self-accumulation, which diminishes the number of electrochemically active sites, resulting in decreased performance. In this study, MnO2 particles are intricately anchored onto the surfaces and within the layers of nitrogen-doped Ti3C2 (N&#8211;Ti3C2), resulting in the creation of innovative interface engineered N&#8211;Ti3C2/MnO2 nanosheets. Due to its distinctive heterostructure and favourable interfacial interaction, the N&#8211;Ti3C2/MnO2 electrode shows better performance in both the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions, exhibiting low overpotentials of 130 mV and 289 mV, respectively, at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Furthermore, it requires a cell voltage of 1.7 V to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 during the overall water splitting process. The N&#8211;Ti3C2/MnO2 composite also maintains sustained durability for a period of 4 h. This enhanced electrochemical activity of N&#8211;Ti3C2/MnO2 can be due to the synergistic effects resulting from the intricate contact between N&#8211;Ti3C2 and MnO2. This research presents a simple methodology for designing MXenes-based multicomponent electrodes for electrochemical water splitting reactions and its potential application for electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Sandra Mathew, K.R. Sunaja Devi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.323</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin transition metal oxychalcogenides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4432594/v1</link>
      <description>Manish Chhowalla, Wenshuo Xu, Yi-Ming Wu, Shibo Xi, Yan Wang, Ye Wang, Yuxuan Ke, L. K. Ding, Xiao Wang, Jieun Yang, Wenjing Zhang, Kian Ping Loh, Feng Ding, Zheng Liu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398773932

                Abstract Two-dimensional (2D) transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) exfoliated from bulk layered materials possess interesting properties. Most transition metal oxides (TMOs) are not layered and therefore cannot be exfoliated. Here we report the synthesis of a new family of ultrathin materials &#8211; transition metal oxychalcogenides (TMOCs) and demonstrate their unique properties. Specifically, 2D TMOCs such as HfSxOy, ZrSxOy, TiSxOy, TaSxOy, NbSxOy, VSexOy, HfSexOy, ZrSexOy, TaTexOy (x, y ~ 0&#8211;2) from bulk TMDs (HfS2, ZrS2, TiS2, TaS2, NbS2, VSe2, HfSe2, ZrSe2, TaTe2) have been fabricated using tetrabutylammonium intercalation. The stoichiometry of TMOCs can be adjusted, which enables control of their optical band gaps and tunability of electrical conductivity by more than 8 orders of magnitude. Our results show that by tuning the chalcogen to oxygen ratio along with local atomic structure in TMOCs, it is possible to impart unexpected properties. For example, in contrast to conventional TMDs, the hybrid structure renders TMOCs surprisingly stable and electrochemically active in strong acids, which allows them to be used as proof-of-concept catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at pH &#8776; 0. The HfS0.52O1.09 catalysts show high mass activity (10,3000 A g&#8211;1 at an overpotential of 0.5 V) and exhibit durability in proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysers.</description>
      <author>Manish Chhowalla, Wenshuo Xu, Yi-Ming Wu, Shibo Xi, Yan Wang, Ye Wang, Yuxuan Ke, L. K. Ding, Xiao Wang, Jieun Yang, Wenjing Zhang, Kian Ping Loh, Feng Ding, Zheng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4432594/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physiological and Proteome Analysis of the Effects of Chitosan Oligosaccharides on Salt Tolerance of Rice Seedlings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25115953</link>
      <description>Xiaohua Qian, Yaqing He, Lu Zhang, Xianzhen Li, Wei Tang, International journal of molecular sciences. 25(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399155713

                Rice (Oryza sativa L.) is an important social-economic crop, and rice seedlings are easily affected by salt stress. Chitosan oligosaccharide (COS) plays a positive role in promoting plant growth and development. To gain a better understanding of the salt tolerance mechanism of rice under the action of COS, Nipponbare rice seedlings were selected as the experimental materials, and the physiological and biochemical indexes of rice seedlings in three stages (normal growth, salt stress and recovery) were measured. Unlabelled quantitative proteomics technology was used to study differential protein and signaling pathways of rice seedlings under salt stress, and the mechanism of COS to improve rice tolerance to salt stress was elucidated. Results showed that after treatment with COS, the chlorophyll content of rice seedlings was 1.26 times higher than that of the blank group (CK). The root activity during the recovery stage was 1.46 times that of the CK group. The soluble sugar in root, stem and leaf increased by 53.42%, 77.10% and 9.37%, respectively. The total amino acid content increased by 77% during the stem recovery stage. Furthermore, the malondialdehyde content in root, stem and leaf increased by 21.28%, 26.67% and 32.69%, respectively. The activity of oxide dismutase (SOD), peroxidase (POD) and oxygenase (CAT) were increased. There were more differentially expressed proteins in the three parts of the experimental group than in the CK group. Gene Ontology (GO) annotation of these differentially expressed proteins revealed that the experimental group was enriched for more entries. Then, through the Kyoto Encyclopedia of Genes and Genomes (KEGG), the top ten pathways enriched with differentially expressed proteins in the two groups (COS and CK groups) were utilized, and a detailed interpretation of the glycolysis and photosynthesis pathways was provided. Five key proteins, including phosphofructokinase, fructose bisphosphate aldolases, glycer-aldehyde-3-phosphate dehydrogenase, enolase and pyruvate kinase, were identified in the glycolysis pathway. In the photosynthesis pathway, oxygen evolution enhancement proteins, iron redox proteins and ferredoxin-NADPH reductase were the key proteins. The addition of COS led to an increase in the abundance of proteins, a response of rice seedlings to salt stress. COS helped rice seedlings resist salt stress. Furthermore, using COS as biopesticides and biofertilizers can effectively increase the utilization of saline-affected farmland, thereby contributing to the alleviating of the global food crisis.</description>
      <author>Xiaohua Qian, Yaqing He, Lu Zhang, Xianzhen Li, Wei Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25115953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal hematocrit theory - A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00034.2024</link>
      <description>Michal &#352;itina, Heiko Stark, Stefan Schuster, Journal of applied physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399159807

                In humans and higher animals, a trade-off between a sufficiently high concentration of erythrocytes (hematocrit), to bind oxygen and sufficiently low blood viscosity to allow rapid blood flow has been achieved during evolution. The optimal value lies between the extreme cases of pure blood plasma, which cannot practically transport any oxygen, and 100\% hematocrit, which would imply very slow blood flow or none at all. As oxygen delivery to tissues is the main task of the cardiovascular system, it is reasonable to expect that maximum oxygen delivery has been achieved during evolution. Optimal hematocrit theory, based on this optimality principle, has been successful in predicting hematocrit values of about 0.3-0.5, which are indeed observed in humans and many animal species. Similarly, the theory can explain why higher than normal hematocrit, ranging from 0.5 to 0.7, can promote better exertional performance. Here we present a review of theoretical approaches to the calculation of the optimal hematocrit value under different conditions and discuss them in a broad physiological context. Several physiological and medical implications are outlined, e.g. in view of blood doping, temperature adaptation, and life at high altitudes.</description>
      <author>Michal &#352;itina, Heiko Stark, Stefan Schuster</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1152/japplphysiol.00034.2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Densely Accessible Fe/Co-Nx Dual-atom Sites Coupled Core-shell Co3Fe7@C as an Efficient Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Rechargeable Zinc-air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02444c</link>
      <description>Katam Srinivas, Hesheng Yu, Changhui Zhou, Anran Chen, Ming-Qiang Zhu, Yuanfu Chen, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399144923

                The urgent demand for stable and highly efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction/evolution reactions (ORR/OER) is pivotal in advancing energy conversion and storage technologies. Herein, we introduce a metal-organic...</description>
      <author>Katam Srinivas, Hesheng Yu, Changhui Zhou, Anran Chen, Ming-Qiang Zhu, Yuanfu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02444c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Widespread adaptive evolution in the photosystems of angiosperms provides new insight into the evolution of photosystem II repair.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.23.595573</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Hannah Joan Robbins, Steven Kelly, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399019908

                Oxygenic photosynthesis generates the initial energy source which fuels nearly all life on earth. At the heart of the process are the photosystems, pigment binding multi-protein complexes that catalyse the first step of photochemical conversion of light energy into chemical energy. Here, we investigate the molecular evolution at single residue resolution of the plastid-encoded subunits of the photosystems across 773 angiosperm species. We show that despite an extremely high level of conservation, 7% of residues in the photosystems, spanning all photosystem subunits, exhibit hallmarks of adaptive evolution. Through in silico modelling of these adaptive substitutions we uncover the impact of these changes on the properties of the photosystems, focussing on their effects on co-factor binding and the formation of inter-subunit interfaces. We further reveal that evolution has repeatedly destabilised the interaction photosystem II and its D1 subunit, thereby reducing the energetic barrier for D1 turn-over and photosystem repair. Together, these results provide new insight into the trajectory of photosystem evolution during the radiation of the angiosperms.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Hannah Joan Robbins, Steven Kelly</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.05.23.595573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LinG3D: visualizing the spatio-temporal dynamics of clonal evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-024-05813-7</link>
      <description>Alan J. Hu, Awino Maureiq Edith Ojwang, Kayode D. Olumoyin, Katarzyna A. Rejniak, BMC bioinformatics. 25(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399044258

                Abstract Background Cancers are spatially heterogenous, thus their clonal evolution, especially following anti-cancer treatments, depends on where the mutated cells are located within the tumor tissue. For example, cells exposed to different concentrations of drugs, such as cells located near the vessels in contrast to those residing far from the vasculature, can undergo a different evolutionary path. However, classical representations of cell lineage trees do not account for this spatial component of emerging cancer clones. Here, we propose routines to trace spatial and temporal clonal evolution in computer simulations of the tumor evolution models. Results The LinG3D (Lineage Graphs in 3D) is an open-source collection of routines (in MATLAB, Python, and R) that enables spatio-temporal visualization of clonal evolution in a two-dimensional tumor slice from computer simulations of the tumor evolution models. These routines draw traces of tumor clones in both time and space, and may include a projection of a selected microenvironmental factor, such as the drug or oxygen distribution within the tumor, if such a microenvironmental factor is used in the tumor evolution model. The utility of LinG3D has been demonstrated through examples of simulated tumors with different number of clones and, additionally, in experimental colony growth assay. Conclusions This routine package extends the classical lineage trees, that show cellular clone relationships in time, by adding the space component to show the locations of cellular clones within the 2D tumor tissue patch from computer simulations of tumor evolution models.</description>
      <author>Alan J. Hu, Awino Maureiq Edith Ojwang, Kayode D. Olumoyin, Katarzyna A. Rejniak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12859-024-05813-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulate local chemical order to achieve high strength and ductility in TiZrNbVAl lightweight high entropy alloys via adding oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2024.146721</link>
      <description>Jiaxiang Cui, Bang Dou, Manling Sui, Nan Cui, Benpeng Wang, Shihai Sun, Hongnian Cai, Liang Wang, Yunfei Xue, Materials science and engineering. A, Structural materials: proporties, microstructures and processing/Materials science &amp; engineering. A, Structural materials: properties, microstructure and processing. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399035862

                TiZrNbVAl lightweight high-entropy alloys (LHEAs) with body-centered cubic (BCC) structure have received extensive attention due to their low density and considerable mechanical properties. And the mechanical properties of these LHEAs can be further improved by adjusting the local chemical order (LCO). Here, we report a strategy for regulating LCOs in TiZrNbVAl LHEAs by adding oxygen. The results showed that the yield strength of LHEA increased from 787.8 MPa to 1029.5 MPa after oxygen addition. Moreover, the microstructure evolution proves that LCOs is conducive to promoting the transition of dislocation from plane slip, which is easy to produce stress concentration, to multistage slip, which improves the homogenizing deformation ability, and increasing the ductility from 12.8% to 20.9%, which is an increase of &#8764;63%. Our work provides a paradigm for achieving outstanding strength-ductility tradeoff in BCC-LHEAs via O doping.</description>
      <author>Jiaxiang Cui, Bang Dou, Manling Sui, Nan Cui, Benpeng Wang, Shihai Sun, Hongnian Cai, Liang Wang, Yunfei Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.msea.2024.146721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 in three waves in a tertiary referral hospital in Belgium: a comparison of patient characteristics, management, and outcome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12985-024-02360-8</link>
      <description>A De Paepe, Erika Vlieghe, Nele Brusselaers, Patrick Soentjens, Caroline Theunissen, Isabel Brosius, Jeroen Grouwels, Lida van Petersen, Hanne Van Tiggelen, Walter Verbrugghe, Philippe G. Jorens, Th&#233;r&#232;se S. Lapperre, Kristel Peeters, Griet Vermeulen, Sabrina H. van Ierssel, Virology journal. 21(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399160099

                Abstract Purpose Few studies have compared patient characteristics, clinical management, and outcome of patients with COVID-19 between the different epidemic waves. In this study, we describe patient characteristics, treatment, and outcome of patients admitted for COVID-19 in the Antwerp University Hospital over the first three epidemic waves of 2020&#8211;2021. Methods Retrospective observational study of COVID-19 patients in a Belgian tertiary referral hospital. All adult patients with COVID-19, hospitalized between February 29, 2020, and June 30, 2021, were included. Standardized routine medical data was collected from patient records. Risk factors were assessed with multivariable logistic regression. Results We included 722 patients, during the first ( n = 179), second ( n = 347) and third ( n = 194) wave. We observed the lowest disease severity at admission during the first wave, and more elderly and comorbid patients during the second wave. Throughout the subsequent waves we observed an increasing use of corticosteroids and high-flow oxygen therapy. In spite of increasing number of complications throughout the subsequent waves, mortality decreased each wave (16.6%,15.6% 11.9% in 1st, 2nd and 3rd wave respectively). C-reactive protein above 150 mg/L was predictive for the need for intensive care unit admission (odds ratio (OR) 3.77, 95% confidence interval (CI) 2.32&#8211;6.15). A Charlson comorbidity index &#8805; 5 (OR 5.68, 95% CI 2.54&#8211;12.70) and interhospital transfers (OR 3.78, 95% CI 2.05&#8211;6.98) were associated with a higher mortality. Conclusions We observed a reduction in mortality each wave, despite increasing comorbidity. Evolutions in patient management such as high-flow oxygen therapy on regular wards and corticosteroid use may explain this favorable evolution.</description>
      <author>A De Paepe, Erika Vlieghe, Nele Brusselaers, Patrick Soentjens, Caroline Theunissen, Isabel Brosius, Jeroen Grouwels, Lida van Petersen, Hanne Van Tiggelen, Walter Verbrugghe, Philippe G. Jorens, Th&#233;r&#232;se S. Lapperre, Kristel Peeters, Griet Vermeulen, Sabrina H. van Ierssel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12985-024-02360-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal and chemical expansion of layered oxygen-deficient double perovskites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29235/1561-8331-2024-60-2-95-104</link>
      <description>&#1040;. I. Klyndyuk, Ya. Yu. Zhuravleva, Vesc&#236; Nacy&#226;nal&#697;naj akad&#232;m&#236;&#236; navuk Belarus&#236;. Sery&#226; h&#236;m&#236;&#269;nyh navuk. 60(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399139045

                Layered oxygen-deficient double perovskites (ODP) based on the rare-earth elements (REE), barium and 3 d -metals (Fe, Co, Cu etc.) are characterized by high values of electrical conductivity and high electrochemical activity in oxygen reduction reaction, and are considered as prospective cathode materials for intermediate-temperature solid oxide fuel cells (SOFC) on the base of proton- and oxygen-ion conducting solid electrolytes (SE). Effective cathode materials should be thermomechanically compatible with materials of SE, which t&#1072;kes place when the values of their thermal expansion coefficients (TEC) are close to each other. Due to this the study of thermal expansion of ODP as well as the isotation of different contributions in it (thermal, chemical, spin etc.), is of considerable interest. In this work using dilatometric method the thermal expansion of NdBa 1&#8211;x SrxFeCo 0,5 Cu0,5O 6&#8722;&#948; (0.0 &#8804; &#1093; &#8804; 1.0) (NBSFCC) ODP was studied using dilatometric method. It was established that the values of average linear thermal expansion coefficient (LTEC) (&#945;) of the samples sharply increased from (15.1&#8211;16.2) &#183; 10 &#8211;6 K &#8211;1 at &#1058; &lt; 630&#8211;920 K to (18.9&#8211;23.5) 10 &#8211;6 K &#8211;1 at &#1058; &gt; 630&#8211;920 K due to the evolution of weaklybonded oxygen from the samples. Values of &#945; in the low-temperature region increase with increasing of values of their oxygen nonstoichiometry index (&#948;), and in the high-temperature one increase with the x increasing due to the increment of chemical contribution in the samples expansion. Based of the results of dilatometry, thermogravimetry, and iodometry, the thermal and chemical contributions in the expansion &#1086;n NBSFCC were isolated, and the effect of crystal structure, cationic and anionic composition of NBSFCC ODP on the values of their thermal and linear chemical expansion coefficient (LCEC, &#945; &#948; ) was investigated. It was found, that LCEC values of the samples sharply increased from (8.6&#8211;11.8) &#183; 10 &#8211;3 at (&#1093; &lt; 0.5) to (12.6&#8211;15.8) &#183; 10 &#8211;3 at (&#1093; &gt; 0.5) when transition from ordered tetragonal (&#1093; &lt; 0.5) to disordered cubic (&#1093; &gt; 0.5) phase took place. It was shown, that dependences of LTEC and LCEC of NBSFCC phases on their crystal structure and chemical compositions obtained in this work are in good accordance with the analogous dependences determined earlier for the ODP of other types.</description>
      <author>&#1040;. I. Klyndyuk, Ya. Yu. Zhuravleva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29235/1561-8331-2024-60-2-95-104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROS-Resistant Redox Mediator in Lithium-Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4370577/v1</link>
      <description>Won&#8208;Jin Kwak, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Jisun Hwang, J.-H. Kim, Gabriel N. Morais, Kunlin Tang, Min Sun Choi, Hee Joung Choi, Hwa Shik Youn, Seoung&#8208;Tae Kim, Ju-Young Ha, Seok Ju Kang, Shuming Chen, Sung-Eun Suh, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398780276

                Abstract The utilization of redox mediators (RMs) in lithium-oxygen batteries (LOBs) have underscored their utility in addressing the challenge of the elevated overpotential during the charging process. Nonetheless, the generation of highly electrophilic singlet oxygen (1O2) throughout the battery cycles leads to adverse reactions with RMs, thereby impeding their effectiveness. In the quest for enhanced RM durability, this study unveils a novel RM, 7,7'-bi-7-azabicyclo[2.2.1]heptane (BAC), incorporating N&#8211;N interconnected aza-bicycles, and assesses its efficacy and robustness relative to those of other N&#8211;N non-bicyclic RMs. Unlike non-bicyclic RMs, which exhibit diminished O2 evolution after exposure to 1O2, BAC maintains consistent O2 profiles during charging, indicating its superior 1O2 resistance and steady redox-catalyst performance in LOBs. Theoretical analyses align with the experimental findings that the bicyclic structural design of BAC confers a superior ability to resist oxidative degradation through cleavage of the C&#8211;H bonds adjacent to nitrogen atoms.</description>
      <author>Won&#8208;Jin Kwak, Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Jisun Hwang, J.-H. Kim, Gabriel N. Morais, Kunlin Tang, Min Sun Choi, Hee Joung Choi, Hwa Shik Youn, Seoung&#8208;Tae Kim, Ju-Young Ha, Seok Ju Kang, Shuming Chen, Sung-Eun Suh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4370577/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Face&#8208;Dependent Behavior of Single&#8208;Atom Pt: Construct of SA&#8208;FLP Dual Active Sites for Efficient NO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Detection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402038</link>
      <description>Yucheng Ou, B. L. Wang, Nana Xu, Quzhi Song, Tian&#8208;Qing Liu, Hui Xu, Hualong Wang, Kunjie Wang, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399141399

                Abstract The strong potential of platinum single atom (Pt SA ) in gas sensor technology is primarily attributed to its high atomic economy. Nevertheless, it is imperative to conduct further exploration to understand the impact of Pt SA on the active sites. In this study, the evolution of Pt SA on (100)CeO 2 and (111)CeO 2 is examined, revealing notable disparities in the position and activity of surface Pt SA on different crystal planes. The Pt SA in (100)CeO 2 surface can enhance the stability of Ce 3+ and construct a frustrated Lewis pair (FLP) to form a double active site by combining the steric hindrance effect of oxygen vacancies, which increases the response value from 1.8 to 27 and reduce the response&#8208;recovery time from 140&#8211;192 s to 25&#8211;26 s toward five ppm NO 2 at room temperature. Conversely, Pt SA tends to bind to terminal oxygen on the surface of (111)CeO 2 and become an independent reaction site. The response value of Pt SA &#8208;(111)CeO 2 surface only increased from 1.6 to 3.8. This research underscores the correlation between single atoms and crystal plane effects, laying the groundwork for designing and synthesizing ultra&#8208;stable and efficient gas sensors.</description>
      <author>Yucheng Ou, B. L. Wang, Nana Xu, Quzhi Song, Tian&#8208;Qing Liu, Hui Xu, Hualong Wang, Kunjie Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202402038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exciton Dissociation into Charge Carriers in Porphyrinic Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Light&#8208;Assisted Li&#8208;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405440</link>
      <description>Bo Wen, Yaohui Huang, Zhuoliang Jiang, Yuzhe Wang, Weibo Hua, Sylvio Indris, Fujun Li, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399041581

                Abstract Light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries exhibit a high round&#8208;trip efficiency attributable to the assistance of light&#8208;generated electrons and holes in oxygen reduction and evolution reactions. Nonetheless, the excitonic effect arising from Coulomb interaction between electrons and holes impedes carrier separation, thus hindering efficient utilization of photo&#8208;energy. Herein, porphyrinic metal&#8208;organic frameworks with (Fe 2 Ni)O(COO) 6 clusters were used as photocathodes to accelerate exciton dissociation into charge carriers for light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries. The coupling of Ni 3d and Fe 3d orbitals boosts ligand&#8208;to&#8208;metal cluster charge transfer, and hence drives exciton dissociation and activates O 2 for superoxide ( &#8226; O 2 &#8722; ) radicals, rather than singlet oxygen ( 1 O 2 ) under photoexcitation. These enable the light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries with a low total overvoltage of 0.28 V and round&#8208;trip efficiency of 92% under light irradiation of 100 mW cm &#8722;2 . This work highlights the excitonic effect in photoelectrochemical processes and provides insights into photocathode design for light&#8208;assisted Li&#8208;O 2 batteries. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Bo Wen, Yaohui Huang, Zhuoliang Jiang, Yuzhe Wang, Weibo Hua, Sylvio Indris, Fujun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magmatic and hydrothermal evolution of the superlarge Dashui goldfield in the West Qinling Orogen, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106095</link>
      <description>Haotian Yang, Fan Yang, Gilby Jepson, Leon Bagas, Jian Tu, Hongying Li, Zesheng Qian, Ore geology reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399030419

                Gold (Au) is a precious metal that has played an important role in the development of the global economy. It is therefore important to better define the genesis of Au mineralisation as an aid to focus exploration as the consumption of Au increases. The Dashui goldfield contains a super large Au resource of over 120 t (tonnes) in the West Qinling Orogen, central China. Despite several studies have focused on the genesis of the Dashui goldfield, the original physico&#8211;chemical natures of the magmatic and hydrothermal evolution remain unclear. Biotite and apatite in the mineralised diorite porphyry in the goldfield are sensitive to the changes in the physico&#8211;chemical conditions and the evolution of magmatic and hydrothermal fluids, and thus provide important keys to address these issues. Hence, we conducted detailed in&#8211;situ major and trace element studies of biotite and apatite from the ore&#8211;bearing diorite porphyry in the Dashui goldfield. Our aim is to elucidate the physico&#8211;chemical conditions, magma source, and the magmatic and hydrothermal evolution processes during the deposition of the gold, and to enhance the understanding of the Au genesis in the West Qinling Au province. Using the geochemistry of magmatic apatite, and magmatic and hydrothermal biotite, we have found that the crystallisation temperature and pressure along with emplacement depth of diorite porphyry were constrained at &#8764; 737&#8211;791 &#176;C, 1.08&#8211;1.73 kbar, and 3.94&#8211;6.30 km. The diorite porphyry has the geochemical affinities with calcium alkaline orogenic suites derived from a mixed crustal and mantle source. During the early emplacement of the diorite porphyry, the melt had a high oxygen fugacity and was highly enriched in Au. During the late magma crystallisation of the diorite porphyry, the magma was enriched continuously in most elements with the Ba/Rb ratios in the biotite varying from 10 to 5, and most of the Au was hosted by pyrite. Additionally, elements were continuously dissolved into fluids generating Cl&#8211;rich hydrothermal fluids during the evolution of the magma. During hydrothermal evolution, Au is migrated with As and Sb in the vapour phases of fluids, whereas Au migrated with Cl in the liquid phase. When temperatures dropped to &#8764; 200&#8211;400 &#176;C, Au started to combine with S and Si in the liquid phase of fluids. Subsequently, hydrothermal fluids interacted with host carbonate to form the Dashui goldfield, the Au during this stage was also transported and hosted in magnetite, hematite, and quartz within the carbonate rocks.</description>
      <author>Haotian Yang, Fan Yang, Gilby Jepson, Leon Bagas, Jian Tu, Hongying Li, Zesheng Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Highly Reversible Sn&#8208;Air Battery Possessing the Ultra&#8208;Low Charging Potential with the Assistance of Light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407856</link>
      <description>Mingze Gao, Ruiya Wang, Xinxin L&#252;, Yanchen Fan, Ziyang Guo, Yonggang Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399011189

                Aqueous Sn&#8208;air batteries are attracting a great deal of interest in recent years due to the ultra&#8208;high safety, low cost, dendrite&#8208;free and highly reversible Sn anode. However, the slurry oxygen reduction/evolution reaction (ORR/OER) kinetics on the air cathodes seriously affect the Sn&#8208;air battery performances. Although various advanced catalysts have been developed, the charge overpotentials (~1000 mV) of these Sn&#8208;air batteries are still not satisfactory. Herein, iron oxide (Fe2O3) modified titanium dioxide (TiO2) nanorods with heterogeneous structure are firstly synthesized on Ti mesh (Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti), and the obtained Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti is further applied as catalytic electrodes for Sn&#8208;air batteries. The core&#8208;shell heterogeneous structure of Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti can effectively facilitate the conversion of electrochemical intermediates and separation of photo&#8208;excited electrons and holes to active oxygen&#8208;related reaction processes. DFT and experimental results also confirm that Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti can not only act as the electrocatalysts to improve ORR/OER properties, but also exhibit the superior photo&#8208;catalytic activity to promote charge kinetics. Hence, the Fe2O3@TiO2/Ti&#8208;based Sn&#8208;air batteries show ultra&#8208;low overpotential of ~40 mV, excellent rate capability and good cycling stability under light irradiation. This work will shed light on rational photo&#8208;assisted catalytic cathode design for new&#8208;type metal&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Mingze Gao, Ruiya Wang, Xinxin L&#252;, Yanchen Fan, Ziyang Guo, Yonggang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202407856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing sulfur redox state and geochemical implications in deep-time using mineral chemistry network analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.024</link>
      <description>Elizabeth Hern&#225;ndez Moore, Joseph Diedolf, S. M. Morrison, Daniel R. Hummer, Geochimica et cosmochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398794660

                Sulfur (S) is a central element in global biogeochemical cycling and Earth's redox evolution. Minerals that contain S are an important record of local environmental conditions at the time of their formation based on chemical speciation and redox. However, the oxidation state of S for hundreds of different S-containing minerals and thousands of S-containing mineral localities is unknown, largely sulfides and sulfosalts, and the redox state alone does not fully capture mineral chemistry diversity, thus limiting understanding of S redox evolution. Here, we use mineral chemistry network analysis and the weighted Mineral Element Electronegativity Coefficient of Variation (wMEECV) metric to investigate the element interactions and localities of S-containing minerals from the Mineral Evolution Database (MED) to infer the redox state of S in minerals where the redox state is unknown (SU). Louvain community detection of the S mineral chemistry redox network reveals that there are three main network communities that are separated by redox state. The S6+ community includes minerals that contain the S6+ redox state and a small number of S4+ and S2+ minerals, the S2&#8722; community includes S2&#8722;-containing minerals, and the SU community includes minerals in which the redox state of S is unknown. The wMEECV values of the SU community closely overlap with the wMEECV values of the S2&#8722; community, and do not overlap with the wMEECV values of the S6+ community, indicating the SU community minerals contain predominately reduced S. Assuming that SU community minerals contain reduced S, as supported by their network chemical associations and wMEECV values, then reduced S-containing minerals make up approximately 81 % of S-containing mineral localities in the S mineral chemistry network, even though the majority of all mineral localities (S-containing and non-S-containing) are oxygen (O)-containing minerals. Additionally, reduced S-containing minerals make up the majority (&#8764;75 %) of all non-O containing mineral localities in the MED, representing the importance of reduced S as an electron source and substrate in the evolution of microbial metabolic networks. The range wMEECV values of S6+ community minerals expands through time due primarily to formation of chemically diverse sulfate minerals, coinciding with crustal oxidation from the late Proterozoic to Phanerozoic and the expansion of the marine sulfate reservoir. The intersection of shared constituent elements among reduced and oxidized S in the mineral chemistry network represents redox convergence of weathered S in the geosphere that was crucial in the formation of natural resource deposits and the evolution of biogeochemical cycles.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth Hern&#225;ndez Moore, Joseph Diedolf, S. M. Morrison, Daniel R. Hummer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Arousal as a universal embedding for spatiotemporal brain dynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.njvyzq</link>
      <description>Ryan V. Raut, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4399071520

                Neural activity in awake organisms shows widespread and spatiotemporally diverse correlations with behavioral and physiological measurements. We propose that this covariation reflects in part the dynamics of a unified, arousal-related process that regulates brain-wide physiology on the timescale of seconds. Taken together with theoretical foundations in dynamical systems, this interpretation leads us to a surprising prediction: that a single, scalar measurement of arousal (e.g., pupil diameter) should suffice to reconstruct the continuous evolution of multimodal, spatiotemporal measurements of large-scale brain physiology. To test this hypothesis, we perform multimodal, cortex-wide optical imaging and behavioral monitoring in awake mice. We demonstrate that spatiotemporal measurements of neuronal calcium, metabolism, and blood-oxygen can be accurately and parsimoniously modeled from a low-dimensional state-space reconstructed from the time history of pupil diameter. Extending this framework to behavioral and electrophysiological measurements from the Allen Brain Observatory, we demonstrate the ability to integrate diverse experimental data into a unified generative model via mappings from an intrinsic arousal manifold. Our results support the hypothesis that spontaneous, spatially structured fluctuations in brain-wide physiology&#8212;widely interpreted to reflect regionally-specific neural communication&#8212;are in large part reflections of an arousal-related process. This enriched view of arousal dynamics has broad implications for interpreting observations of brain, body, and behavior as measured across modalities, contexts, and scales.</description>
      <author>Ryan V. Raut</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.52843/cassyni.njvyzq</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Catalytic Activity of Magnetic Surfaces</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/magnetochemistry10060040</link>
      <description>Ian Shuttleworth, Magnetochemistry. 10(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399073281

                High-performance catalysts for the oxygen reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions (ORR and HER, respectively) are highly sought-after, particularly with the commitment of numerous agencies to the removal of conventional gas vehicles in the next few decades. Surprisingly little focus has been placed on the development of magnetic models to describe these systems. The current work will review the current understanding of surface heterogeneous catalysis across select magnetic surfaces, with attention focused on studies involving extended surfaces, which inherently are more accessible to fundamental analysis than the more applied nanoparticle systems. However, even the most up-to-date magnetic variants of this theory have focused on the tight binding limit of the d-band model. In this limit, the reactivity of the surface is governed by the position of the center of the d-band, and the model does not account for the higher moments of the d-band, such as the width, asymmetry, and modality. A summary of the theory supporting this analysis will be presented, along with a summary of the current literature on this level of analysis. The review will then conclude with a discussion of suggested directions for future investigations.</description>
      <author>Ian Shuttleworth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/magnetochemistry10060040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct estimates of nitrogen abundance for Seyfert 2 nuclei</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.13906</link>
      <description>O. L. Dors, M. V. Cardaci, G. F. H&#228;gele, M. Valerdi, Gabriele da Silva Ilha, C. B. Oliveira, Rogemar A. Riffel, Sophia R. Flury, K. Z. Arellano-C&#243;rdova, T. Storchi-Bergmann, Rogemar A. Riffel, Guilherme C. Almeida, I. N. Morais, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399026240

                We derive the nitrogen and oxygen abundances in the Narrow Line Regions (NLRs) of a sample of 38 local ($z \: &lt; \: 0.4$) Seyfert~2 nuclei. For that, we consider narrow optical emission line intensities and direct estimates of the electron temperatures ($T_{\rm e}$-method). We find nitrogen abundances in the range $7.6 \: &lt; \: \rm 12+log(N/H) \: &lt; \: 8.6$ (mean value $8.06\pm0.22$) or $\rm 0.4 \: &lt; \: (N/N_{\odot}) \: &lt; 4.7$, in the metallicity regime $8.3 \: &lt; \: \rm 12+log(O/H) \: &lt; \: 9.0$. Our results indicate that the dispersion in N/H abundance for a fixed O/H value in AGNs is in agreement with that for disc \ion{H}{ii} regions with similar metallicity. We show that Seyfert~2 nuclei follow a similar (N/O)-(O/H) relation to the one followed by star-forming objects. Finally, we find that active galaxies called as 'nitrogen-loud' observed at very high redshift ($z \: &gt; \: 5$) show N/O values in consonance with those derived for local NLRs. This result indicates that the main star-formation event is completed in the early evolution stages of active galaxies.</description>
      <author>O. L. Dors, M. V. Cardaci, G. F. H&#228;gele, M. Valerdi, Gabriele da Silva Ilha, C. B. Oliveira, Rogemar A. Riffel, Sophia R. Flury, K. Z. Arellano-C&#243;rdova, T. Storchi-Bergmann, Rogemar A. Riffel, Guilherme C. Almeida, I. N. Morais</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.13906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anatomy, 3D micro-CT and Semiquantitative Elemental Microanalysis in Common carp vertebrae (Cyprinus carpio; Linnaeus, 1758)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4442332/v1</link>
      <description>Paulo Salinas, Antonia Naciff, Felipe Navarro, Florencia Vicencio, Carlos Sandoval, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399159696

                Abstract The study describes the anatomy vertebrae of Common Carp (Cyprinus carpio; Linnaeus, 1758) using 3D micro-CT and Semiquantitative Elemental Microanalysis (EDX), which helps to understand the ontogeny and factors that determine the biomechanics of bones in wild fish. The study of Common carp vertebrae revealed a complex and heterogeneous structure, with a variety of components contributing to their function and stability. The vertebral bodies were composed of lamellar trabeculae and internal hollow spaces, while the neural and hemal arches were composed of bony trabeculae and connected by a lace-like structure. The results of EDX analysis demonstrated the presence of oxygen, nitrogen, sodium, carbon, magnesium, and chlorine, among others. The calcium to phosphorus ratio was within the ranges described in teleost, suggesting good bone health. The presence of magnesium, sodium, potassium, chlorine, and nitrogen is due to their essential role in different biological processes. In addition, a difference was observed between the trabeculae present in the vertebrae of the abdominal and caudal segments, suggesting a relationship between the density of each bone and its function. These findings contribute to the understanding of the structure and function of vertebrae in wild Common carp and may have implications for understanding the evolution of the vertebral column in fish in general.</description>
      <author>Paulo Salinas, Antonia Naciff, Felipe Navarro, Florencia Vicencio, Carlos Sandoval</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4442332/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An earliest Ediacaran oxygenation episode in the Wilpena Group, Adelaide Superbasin, South Australia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.precamres.2024.107433</link>
      <description>Kelsey G. Lamothe, Malcolm W. Wallace, Ashleigh v.S. Hood, Catherine Rose, Precambrian research. 409(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399149629

                The first appearance of animals during the Ediacaran is arguably related to an increase in oceanic oxygenation during this time. However, there is considerable ambiguity in the global record of Ediacaran oxygenation, making it difficult to assess the potential links between oxygen and metazoan evolution. Here, we examine the earliest Ediacaran Nuccaleena Formation cap dolomite and basal Brachina Formation of the Adelaide Superbasin, South Australia, to determine the redox landscape in which these units were deposited. Red shales are present at the base of the Brachina Formation (lower Moolooloo Siltstone Member) over much of the Adelaide Superbasin but these transition laterally into green shales in the north, correlating with a facies transition into a deeper water setting. Fibrous dolomite cements within sheet cavities of the Nuccaleena Formation cap dolomite display evidence of a primary marine origin. Cathodoluminescence microscopy and laser ablation ICP-MS trace element analysis of these marine dolomite cements indicates a transition from an oxic environment in the south (with low Fe, Mn, and a Ce anomaly) to an anoxic (ferruginous) setting in the north (with high Fe, Mn and no Ce anomaly). This cap carbonate trace element geochemistry is spatially consistent with the overlying red to green shale transition in the basal Brachina Formation. Together, these data suggest the existence of a deep-water chemocline in this basin, separating an oxic upper water column from a ferruginous deeper water mass. This oxic interval directly post-dates the end-Cryogenian Marinoan Glaciation and is synchronous with an earliest Ediacaran oxygenation event previously described from South China. This evidence from the Adelaide Superbasin provides direct evidence for an earliest Ediacaran oxic water mass penetrating to a substantial paleodepth. The synchronous development of oxic intervals in both Australia and South China supports the notion of a globally developed oceanic oxygenation event and is consistent with the hypothesis that Ediacaran continental margin settings were periodically bathed in oxic water, conducive to the evolution of metazoans.</description>
      <author>Kelsey G. Lamothe, Malcolm W. Wallace, Ashleigh v.S. Hood, Catherine Rose</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.precamres.2024.107433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics of orbital ordering in cooperative Jahn-Teller models:
  Machine-learning enabled large-scale simulations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.14776</link>
      <description>S. K. Ghosh, Sheng Zhang, Chun&#8208;Yu Cheng, Gia-Wei Chern, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398886343

                We present a scalable machine learning (ML) force-field model for the adiabatic dynamics of cooperative Jahn-Teller (JT) systems. Large scale dynamical simulations of the JT model also shed light on the orbital ordering dynamics in colossal magnetoresistance manganites. The JT effect in these materials describes the distortion of local oxygen octahedra driven by a coupling to the orbital degrees of freedom of $e_g$ electrons. An effective electron-mediated interaction between the local JT modes leads to a structural transition and the emergence of long-range orbital order at low temperatures. Assuming the principle of locality, a deep-learning neural-network model is developed to accurately and efficiently predict the electron-induced forces that drive the dynamical evolution of JT phonons. A group-theoretical method is utilized to develop a descriptor that incorporates the combined orbital and lattice symmetry into the ML model. Large-scale Langevin dynamics simulations, enabled by the ML force-field models, are performed to investigate the coarsening dynamics of the composite JT distortion and orbital order after a thermal quench. The late-stage coarsening of orbital domains exhibits pronounced freezing behaviors which are likely related to the unusual morphology of the domain structures. Our work highlights a promising avenue for multi-scale dynamical modeling of correlated electron systems.</description>
      <author>S. K. Ghosh, Sheng Zhang, Chun&#8208;Yu Cheng, Gia-Wei Chern</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.14776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molecular and Evolution In Silico Studies Unlock the h4-HPPD C-Terminal Tail Gating Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines12061196</link>
      <description>Alfonso Trezza, Ancuta Birgauan, Michela Geminiani, Anna Visibelli, Annalisa Santucci, Biomedicines. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399105635

                The enzyme 4-hydroxyphenylpyruvate dioxygenase (4-HPPD) is involved in the catabolism of the amino acid tyrosine in organisms such as bacteria, plants, and animals. It catalyzes the conversion of 4-hydroxyphenylpyruvate to a homogenisate in the presence of molecular oxygen and Fe(II) as a cofactor. This enzyme represents a key step in the biosynthesis of important compounds, and its activity deficiency leads to severe, rare autosomal recessive disorders, like tyrosinemia type III and hawkinsinuria, for which no cure is currently available. The 4-HPPD C-terminal tail plays a crucial role in the enzyme catalysis/gating mechanism, ensuring the integrity of the active site for catalysis through fine regulation of the C-terminal tail conformation. However, despite growing interest in the 4-HPPD catalytic mechanism and structure, the gating mechanism remains unclear. Furthermore, the absence of the whole 3D structure makes the bioinformatic approach the only possible study to define the enzyme structure/molecular mechanism. Here, wild-type 4-HPPD and its mutants were deeply dissected by applying a comprehensive bioinformatics/evolution study, and we showed for the first time the entire molecular mechanism and regulation of the enzyme gating process, proposing the full-length 3D structure of human 4-HPPD and two novel key residues involved in the 4-HPPD C-terminal tail conformational change.</description>
      <author>Alfonso Trezza, Ancuta Birgauan, Michela Geminiani, Anna Visibelli, Annalisa Santucci</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biomedicines12061196</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase Engineering and Dispersion Stabilization of Cobalt toward Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310499</link>
      <description>Chao Zhang, Yihang Luo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399069290

                Abstract Phase engineering is promising to increase the intrinsic activity of the catalyst toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). However, the polymorphism interface is unstable due to the presence of metastable phases. Herein, phase engineering and dispersion stabilization are applied simultaneously to boost the HER activity of cobalt without sacrificing the stability. A fast and facile approach (plasma cathodic electro deposition) is developed to prepare cobalt film with a hetero&#8208;phase structure. The polymorphs of cobalt are realized through reduced stacking fault energy due to the doping of Mo, and the high temperature treatment resulted from the plasma discharge. Meanwhile, homogeneously dispersed oxide/carbide nanoparticles are produced from the reaction of plasma&#8208;induced oxygen/carbon atoms with electro&#8208;deposited metal. The existence of rich polymorphism interface and oxide/carbide help to facilitate H 2 production by the tuning of electronic structure and the increase of active sites. Furthermore, oxide/carbide dispersoid effectively prevents the phase transition through a pinning effect on the grain boundary. As&#8208;prepared Co&#8208;hybrid/CoO_MoC exhibits both high HER activity and robust stability (44 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , Tafel slope of 53.2 mV dec &#8722;1 , no degradation after 100 h test). The work reported here provides an alternate approach to the design of advanced HER catalysts for real application.</description>
      <author>Chao Zhang, Yihang Luo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310499</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modeling of multiple-defect conducting, planar protonic ceramic electrolysis cells using a Nernst&#8211;Planck formulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234706</link>
      <description>Amogh Thatte, Michael Pastula, Anthony Wood, Huayang Zhu, Robert J. Kee, Robert J. Braun, Journal of power sources. 611(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398793528

                Advancing protonic ceramic electrochemical cell (PCEC) technology offers promise for a variety of energy applications, including membrane reactors, fuel cells, and electrolyzers. Computational modeling of PCECs requires tracking the movement of three mobile charge carriers: protons, oxygen vacancies, and small polarons to adequately predict the cell operating characteristics. This paper develops an experimentally validated, quasi-2D (1+ 1D), transient, dual-channel cell model based on a multiple-charged defect-conducting electrolyte. The new model advances predictive capabilities on a number of fronts. First, it reduces empiricism, simplifies integration of experimentally derived modeling parameters, and enables rapid model scale-up to large cell platforms. Additionally, it predicts the distribution of properties in the streamwise gas flow direction and cell faradaic efficiency over a wide range of operating cell conditions helping to establish the inlet gas conditions needed to produce a dry hydrogen product gas. Model simulation reveals that the evolution of steady-state, thermal-neutral voltages in a PCEC can significantly change from initial operating values due to a dynamic, complex interaction which arises from local decreases in faradaic efficiency. Insights from model-based performance predictions touch upon thermal management considerations and the means for regulating cell temperature when trying to achieve either adiabatic or quasi-isothermal PCEC operation.</description>
      <author>Amogh Thatte, Michael Pastula, Anthony Wood, Huayang Zhu, Robert J. Kee, Robert J. Braun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecological and Health Risks of Vanadium in the Biogeosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44169-024-00065-1</link>
      <description>Mengnan Wang, Baogang Zhang, Han Zhang, Rongyue Geng, Yi Huang, Wenyan He, Yanguo Teng, Reviews of environmental contamination and toxicology. 262(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398774327

                Vanadium (V) is ubiquitously distributed in environmental media, imposing toxic hazards to organisms in biogeosphere. This review focuses on a comprehensive summary of the ecological and human health risks ascribed to V pollution, based on existing V toxicity relevant publications. Lower doses of V (&lt; 2 mg/L) is beneficial to plant growth, however, V reduces plant biomass, induces toxic effects on plant morphology and adversely affects the absorption of essential plant elements at higher levels (&#8805; 2 mg/L). Oxidative stress induced by reactive oxygen species (ROS) produced under V stress may be the main reason for V toxicity to terrestrial and aquatic organisms. Although V contributes to high-efficient biological nitrogen fixation as a co-factor, V alters microbial community structures and drives its evolution. V can also accumulate in and harm human bodies. Knowledge gaps and further perspectives in aspects of V risks are thereby proposed, such as more toxic data reports for deriving V environmental quality criteria, elucidating the molecular mechanisms of detoxification and tolerance of organisms to V for bioremediation applications, and exploring the medical potential of V with the prevention of V toxicity to humans. This review advances our understanding of the toxic effects of V in the ecosystem and inspires future efforts on V management as well as application.</description>
      <author>Mengnan Wang, Baogang Zhang, Han Zhang, Rongyue Geng, Yi Huang, Wenyan He, Yanguo Teng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44169-024-00065-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ore-forming fluid evolution of the Yechangping Mo-W deposit, Qinling Orogen: A case study of the Dabie-type porphyry system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106101</link>
      <description>Po-Cheng Huang, Nan Qi, Jie Yu, Jincao Yao, Zhiwei Qiu, Yanjing Chen, Ore geology reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399142809

                Dabie-type porphyry Mo deposits have recently emerged as a distinct subtype of porphyry Mo deposits, but questions remain about the magmatic-hydrothermal fluid evolution in the formation of this type deposit. Here, well-developed fluid inclusions in quartz phenocrysts, unidirectional solidification textures (UST) and quartz veins in the Yechangping porphyry Mo-W deposit, Qinling Orogen, completely record the magmatic-hydrothermal mineralization process. The characteristics and evolution of the ore-forming fluid in this deposit are investigated through petrography, microthermometry, and laser Raman spectroscopy analysis of fluid inclusions at different stages in order to improve our understanding of the fluid evolution in the genesis of Dabie-type porphyry Mo deposit. The mineralization process in the porphyry-type orebody can be divided into three periods and five stages: (1) magmatic period, including quartz phenocrysts (stage 1); (2) magmatic-hydrothermal transition period, including UST (stage 2); (3) hydrothermal period, including quartz &#177; K-feldspar veins (stage 3), quartz-molybdenite veins (stage 4), and calcite &#177; quartz veins (stage 5), where stage 4 is the main ore-forming stage. The fluid inclusions in quartz and calcite can be recognized as pure CO2 (PC type), CO2-H2O (C type), daughter minerals-bearing (S type), and H2O (WV type and WL type) inclusions. Ore-forming fluid is initially high temperature, high salinity, and CO2-rich, belonging to the H2O-CO2-NaCl (&#177;KCl) system suggested by the fluid inclusions identified in UST. The estimated lithostatic pressures of stage 1 range from 284&#8211;362 MPa, corresponding to depths of 10.3 to 13.2 km, which are consistent with the formation depth of the underlying magma chamber. The presence of UST in stage 2 indicates that the magma was saturated with fluid. Due to the fluctuating pressure (123&#8211;260 MPa) in UST of stage 2, fluid immiscibility happened soon after the fluid exsolution and is inferred to occur between the CO2-rich and aqueous phases. Then, the fluid boiling and mixing occurred in stages 3 and 4, respectively. The estimated pressures of stage 4 which represent the main mineralization stage range from 45&#8211;175 MPa, corresponding to depths of 4.6&#8211;6.4 km. The immiscibility of CO2, along with the fluid mixing-induced cooling and dilution, caused an increase in pH and a decrease in oxygen fugacity, which serves as a crucial mechanism for Mo mineralization at the Yechangping deposit. Stage 5 is characterized by low temperature (185&#8211;309 &#176;C) and low salinity (2.9&#8211;8.7 wt% NaCl equiv.). The primary high temperature, high salinity, CO2-rich fluids, and relatively deep ore-forming depth suggest that the Yechangping deposit is a typical example of Dabie-type porphyry deposits. The characteristics of fluids and the variation in estimated depth at each stage record the evolutionary process of a magmatic-hydrothermal system extending to depths of nearly 10 km in the Yechangping deposit.</description>
      <author>Po-Cheng Huang, Nan Qi, Jie Yu, Jincao Yao, Zhiwei Qiu, Yanjing Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oregeorev.2024.106101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphological assessment of oocyte quality during assisted reproductive technology cycle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5935/1518-0557.20240034</link>
      <description>Romualdo Sciorio, Luca Tramontano, Pierfrancesco Greco, Ermanno Greco, JBRA. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398763901

                Following the advancement of medically assisted reproduction (MAR) technology, and the rationale to extend the culture to the blastocyst stage, performing elective single embryo transfer (eSET), gamete quality and assessment have acquired large relevance in ART. Embryo quality is strictly correlated with gametes quality and culture conditions. Oocyte maturity assessment is therefore imperative for fertilization and embryo evolution. Mature oocytes at the metaphase II stage result in a higher fertilization rate compared to immature oocytes. Indeed, oocyte morphology evaluation represents an important and challenging task that may serve as a valuable prognostic tool for future embryo development and implantation potential. Different grading systems have been reported to assess human embryos, however, in many cases, it is still a major challenge to select the single embryo to transfer with the highest implantation potential. Further, eSET has conferred a challenge to embryologists, who must try to enhance embryo culture and selection to provide an adequate success rate, whilst reducing the overall number of embryos transferred. Above the standard morphological assessment, there are several invasive or non-invasive approaches for embryo selection such as preimplantation genetic testing, time-lapse technology, proteomics and metabolomics, as well as oxygen utilization and analysis of oxidative stress in culture medium. This short review is not designed to be a comprehensive review of all possible features that may influence oocyte quality. It does give, however, a brief overview and describes the prognostic value of the morphological characteristics of human oocytes on their developmental capacity following ART treatments.</description>
      <author>Romualdo Sciorio, Luca Tramontano, Pierfrancesco Greco, Ermanno Greco</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5935/1518-0557.20240034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of oxide inclusions and cleanliness control in Al-killed GCr15SiMn bearing steel during secondary refining process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233231222113</link>
      <description>Guolei Zhang, Guoguang Cheng, Tao&#65533; Zhang, Hongsheng Miao, Zhong Xu, Ironmaking &amp; steelmaking. 51(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399057676

                The evolution of oxide inclusions and cleanliness control in Al-killed GCr15SiMn bearing steel was investigated using a combination of industrial tests and thermodynamic calculations during the secondary refining process. Three different refining conditions were employed in the LF process. With varying ranges of slag basicity (about 5.6&#8211;5.7, 4.8&#8211;4.9 and 3.9&#8211;4.3) and Al content (0.028&#8211;0.035 mass%, 0.023&#8211;0.025 mass% and 0.014&#8211;0.02 mass%), the total oxygen content in the steel after VD refining was measured as 0.0019 mass%, 0.0017 mass% and 0.0008 mass%, respectively. Throughout the refining process, the inclusions underwent a transformation from MgO-Al 2 O 3 (or Al 2 O 3 ) into CaO-Al 2 O 3 (-MgO), and eventually to CaO-Al 2 O 3 -SiO 2 inclusions. Furthermore, it was observed that under high Al content and slag basicity refining conditions, a significant number of inclusions in VD treatment were formed and transformed into CaO&#183;Al 2 O 3 &#183;SiO 2 inclusions enriched with 60 mass% CaO. This indicated that when the proportion of CaO in calcium aluminates exceeded 45 mass%, there was an increased risk of larger-sized inclusions. Conversely, refining conditions with a slag basicity of 3.9&#8211;4.3 and an Al content of 0.014&#8211;0.02 mass% demonstrated effective inclusion control, resulting in lower number density, smaller sizes within 10 &#956;m and an average composition located in the liquid region. This study carries important practical significance for the smelting of high cleanliness GCr15SiMn bearing steel.</description>
      <author>Guolei Zhang, Guoguang Cheng, Tao&#65533; Zhang, Hongsheng Miao, Zhong Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233231222113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot synthesis of C/N co-doped TiO2 with rich oxygen vacancy for efficient photoreduction CO2-to-CO in pure water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113212</link>
      <description>N. Zhang, Jiwen Li, Xin Sun, Junying Ma, Shijie Li, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399143264

                Photocatalytic technology has emerged as a promising approach for addressing global energy and environmental challenges by enabling the conversion of CO2 into valuable chemicals. In this study, we successfully synthesized TiO2 co-doped with C and N, along with an abundant oxygen vacancy (referred to as C/N-TiO2-VO), utilizing a hydrothermal method. Through various characterization techniques, it has been confirmed that the C and N originated from N, N'-dimethylformamide (DMF), while the VO was mainly generated by isopropyl alcohol (IPA), acting as a reducing agent. These techniques also verified that C/N-TiO2-VO has the strong light absorption ability and longer fluorescence lifetime, all of which contribute to enhancing photocatalytic performance. More importantly, C/N-TiO2-VO exhibited exceptional performance in the photoreduction of CO2 to CO, achieving nearly 100% selectivity in pure water, with a CO evolution rate of 53.97 &#956;mol g-1 h-1. This rate was 10.8 and 8.1 times higher than that of TiO2 and C/N-TiO2, respectively. Further theoretical calculations illustrated that stronger local charges and defect levels are formed on the surface of C/N-TiO2-VO compared with TiO2(101), facilitating the dissociation of CO2 and the conversion of CO2 into *COOH intermediates. Furthermore, in situ DRIFTS results confirmed the formation of crucial intermediate *COOH during CO2 photoreduction. This study presents a viable approach for designing highly active photocatalysts through the synergistic effects of doping and vacancies.</description>
      <author>N. Zhang, Jiwen Li, Xin Sun, Junying Ma, Shijie Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mineral chemistry of chrome- diopside bearing lamprophyre from Mesoproterozoic Settupalle complex of Prakasam Alkaline Province: Insights on the magma dynamics at shallow lithospheric mantle beneath the NE margin of the Cuddapah Basin, Southern India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1144/sp551-2024-35</link>
      <description>N. Sridhar, Ragi Mallikarjuna Reddy, Rohit Pandey, Sourav Naskar, Kirtikumar Randive, Kuldeep Singh, Special publication - Geological Society of London/Geological Society, London, special publications. 551(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399129107

                Abstract The Eastern Dharwar Craton (EDC) shows considerable variations in the activity of Kimberlite, lamproite, and lamprophyre and their related lithospheric thickness, thermal structure, and magmatic source characteristics from the innermost core to the margin. These variations have been revealed through seismic studies and the analysis of xenoliths, and xenocrysts carried in alkaline magmas, particularly kimberlites. This study reports the occurrence of chrome diopside phenocrysts from a lamprophyre of the Settupalle pluton, located on the northeastern margin of the Cuddapah basin, Prakasam Alkaline Province (PAP) in South India. Studied lamprophyre characterized by phenocrystic clinopyroxene (Cpx) and biotite, embedded in a groundmass of amphibole, biotite, opaques, calcite, feldspar, nepheline, and sodalite, with the latter minerals forming ocellar structures. Clinopyroxene displays normal zoning, with a high Mg-Cr rich diopside core (up to 1.92 wt%) and a Na 2 O, Al 2 O 3 , FeO, and TiO 2 -enriched salite rim. These chemical variations, along with elemental substitutions from core to rim, indicate the significant role of fractionation in the evolution of lamprophyre magma. The lack of chemical disparity among the studied Cpx, suggests closed-system fractionation, under high oxygen fugacity conditions. Thermobarometry results indicate polybaric crystallization for the Cpx (1206&#8211;1269 &#176;C, 11.82&#8211;18.04 kbar) and biotite (825&#8211;856 &#176;C, 3.49&#8211;6.94 kbar). The gradient inferred from the pressure of the Cpx suggests that its crystallization occurred at a depth of 43-66 km, implying shallow lithospheric magma contribution for the genesis of the lamprophyre magma. Supplementary material at https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.c.7249493</description>
      <author>N. Sridhar, Ragi Mallikarjuna Reddy, Rohit Pandey, Sourav Naskar, Kirtikumar Randive, Kuldeep Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1144/sp551-2024-35</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrochemical characteristics of abandoned coal mines derived acid mine drainage in a typical karst basin (Wuma river basin, Guizhou China)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31963</link>
      <description>Yang Lei, Yuegang Tang, Hongbing Sun, Li He, Ruiqing Li, Heliyon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399143242

                The hydrochemical characteristics of acid mine drainage (AMD) were investigated in Wuma River Basin, China. AMD was sampled from nine closed coal mine (CCM) sites to study the temporal and spatial evolution of pH, dissolved oxygen (DO), electrical conductivity (ED), total hardness (THR), total dissolved salt (TDS), and trace elements. The surface water (river) and groundwater surrounding mine sites were sampled to evaluate the potential pollution derived from AMDs. The TDS content of AMD was higher than that of surface water and groundwater. The dominant factors influencing TDS were the pH, temperature, and wet or dry season (which played a role in controlling microbial activity), HCO3- balance, and REDOX during the evolutionary process. The hydrochemical type of AMD was dependent on the evolutionary stage. From observations, most AMDs were in the form of the SO42--Ca2+&#8226;Mg2+ type that was characterized by a low pH, low [HCO3-], high [SO42-], and high [Fe]. In addition, the AMD samples were undergoing stage I and II processes, in which SO42- and trace elements were generated. The surface water and groundwater were primarily classified as the HCO3--Ca2+&#8226;Mg2+ type, which accounted for their self-cleaning capacity, as indicated by the high [HCO3-]. The surface water and groundwater could be affected by the surrounding AMD depending on the geographical location. The surface water and groundwater sites that were located downstream of subsurface and surface runoff were obviously affected by AMD. After being polluted by AMD, surface water and groundwater contained higher levels of trace elements and emerged as the HCO3-&#8226;SO42--Ca2+&#8226;Mg2+ type.</description>
      <author>Yang Lei, Yuegang Tang, Hongbing Sun, Li He, Ruiqing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e31963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sub&#8208;2 Nm Micro&#8208;Strained High&#8208;Entropy&#8208;Alloy Nanoparticles Boosts Hydrogen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403674</link>
      <description>Heng Luo, L&#252; Li, Fangxu Lin, Q. Zhang, Kai Wang, Dawei Wang, Lin Gu, Mingchuan Luo, Fan Lv, Shaojun Guo, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399019008

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy alloys (HEAs) confine multifarious elements into the same lattice, leading to intense lattice distortion effect. The lattice distortion tends to induce local microstrain at atomic level and thus affect surface adsorptions towards different adsorbates in various electrocatalytic reactions, yet remains unexplored. Herein, we report a class of sub&#8208;2 nm IrRuRhMoW HEA nanoparticles (NPs) with distinct local microstrain induced by lattice distortion for boosting alkaline hydrogen oxidation (HOR) and evolution reactions (HER). We demonstrate that the distortion&#8208;rich HEA catalysts with optimized electronic structure can downshift the d&#8208;band center and generate uncoordinated oxygen sites to enhance the surface oxophilicity. As a result, the IrRuRhMoW HEA NPs show a remarkable HOR kinetic current density of 8.09 mA &#956;g &#8208;1 PGM at 50 mV versus RHE, 8.89, 22.47 times higher than those of IrRuRh NPs without internal strain and commercial Pt/C, respectively, which is the best value among all the reported non&#8208;Pt based catalysts. IrRuRhMoW HEA NPs also display great HER performances with a TOF value of 5.93 H 2 s &#8208;1 at 70 mV versus RHE, 4.6&#8208;fold higher than that of Pt/C catalyst, exceeding most noble metal&#8208;based catalysts. Experimental characterizations and theoretical studies collectively confirm that weakened hydrogen (H ad ) and enhanced hydroxyl (OH ad ) adsorption are achieved by simultaneously modulating the hydrogen adsorption binding energy and surface oxophilicity originated from intensified ligand effect and microstrain effect over IrRuRhMoW HEA NPs, which guarantees the remarkable performances toward HOR/HER. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Heng Luo, L&#252; Li, Fangxu Lin, Q. Zhang, Kai Wang, Dawei Wang, Lin Gu, Mingchuan Luo, Fan Lv, Shaojun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403674</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of Electrochemical Nitrogen Reduction Activity and Suppression of Hydrogen Evolution Reaction for Transition Metal Oxide Catalysts: The Role of Proton Intercalation and Heteroatom Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00223</link>
      <description>Qingdong Li, Oguz Kaan Kucukosman, Qingquan Ma, Junjie Ouyang, Pavel Kucheryavy, Hengfei Gu, Conor Long, Z. Y. Zhang, Joshua Young, Jenny V. Lockard, Eric Garfunkel, Jianan Gao, Zhang Wen, Huixin He, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398764852

                During the electrochemical nitrogen reduction reaction (eNRR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), interstitial proton intercalation readily occurs in some transition metal oxide (TMO) catalysts and changes their d-band electronic structure. This work fabricated phosphorus (P)-doped tungsten oxide (WO3) with enriched oxygen vacancies (OVs) to study the impact of proton intercalation and heteroatom doping on eNRR and HER. Our results demonstrated that the electronic structure of the P-OV-WO3 catalyst was altered by in situ proton intercalation as indicated by the greater negative onset potential of eNRR at &#8722;0.05 V compared to the proton intercalation potential of 0.3 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). Compared to the non-P-doped WO3, the introduction of P doping in WO3 (e.g., 4.8 at. %) led to a reduction of more than 36% in proton intercalation. As a result, the HER activity of the P-OV-WO3 was significantly suppressed, as demonstrated by a considerably negative shift of the onset HER potential from &#8722;0.06 to &#8722;0.15 V and a slower HER kinetics with the Tafel slope increased from 129.0 to 343.1 mV/dec. Density functional theory calculations revealed the synergy of the proton intercalation, substitutional P doping, and the associated OVs in the improvement of N2 activation and hydrogenation in eNRR. The increased eNRR and the suppressed HER led to a high Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 64.1% and the NH3 yield of 24.5 &#956;g&#183;mg cat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 at &#8722;0.15 V versus RHE in H2SO4 (pH = 2) as the electrolyte. The specific NH3 yield is more than 20 times higher than that of C-WO3 (1.1 &#956;g&#183;mg cat&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 with a FE of 20%). The results exceed most of the reported eNRR performances for TMO-based catalysts. Thus, the synergistic proton intercalation and P doping could lead to newer designs and applications of TMO-based catalysts for improved eNRR while suppressing the competing HER.</description>
      <author>Qingdong Li, Oguz Kaan Kucukosman, Qingquan Ma, Junjie Ouyang, Pavel Kucheryavy, Hengfei Gu, Conor Long, Z. Y. Zhang, Joshua Young, Jenny V. Lockard, Eric Garfunkel, Jianan Gao, Zhang Wen, Huixin He</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c00223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferric iron in eclogitic garnet and clinopyroxene from the V. Grib kimberlite pipe (NW Russia): evidence of a highly oxidized subducted slab</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/petrology/egae054</link>
      <description>Marras Giulia, Martine Denis, Arvieux Catherine, Agasheva Elena, Vincenzo Stagno, Journal of petrology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4398782767

                Abstract Estimates of oxygen fugacity of eclogitic rocks are linked to the redox evolution of the oceanic protolith during subduction and its residence in the lithospheric mantle, and, based on knowledge of pressures and temperatures, allow modelling of the speciation of volatile elements and diamond (or graphite) versus carbonate stability. To date, the oxygen fugacity of mantle eclogites has been shown to vary between -6 (Kasai, Congo and Udachnaya, Siberia) and -0.1 (Udachnaya, Siberia) log units (relative to the fayalite-magnetite-quartz buffer, FMQ), linked to the low Fe3+ contents of garnets. In this study we investigated the Fe oxidation state of coexisting garnet and clinopyroxene hand-picked out of 17 diamond-free high-MgO and low-MgO mantle eclogites (dated at 2.84 Ga) from the V. Grib kimberlite pipe (East-European platform). Measured Fe3+/&#8721;Fe values range between 0.03 and 0.19 for garnet and 0.18 to 0.38 for clinopyroxene, the former being higher than what was measured previously in garnets equilibrated at mantle conditions. The Fe3+/&#8721;Fe of the reconstructed bulk rock ranges between 0.10 and 0.15 for high-MgO eclogites and 0.10 and 0.24 for low-MgO eclogites (with uncertainties of &#177; 0.02 and &#177; 0.03 in both cases). Thermobarometric calculations result in equilibration pressures and temperatures of 3.0 - 5.2 (&#177; 0.4) GPa and 720 - 1050 (&#177; 60) &#176;C for both high-MgO and low-MgO eclogites, slightly lower than previous P-T estimates of mantle eclogites from the Udachnaya kimberlite pipe (Siberian craton). At these conditions, &#8710;logfo2 (FMQ) calculated using the available oxythermobarometric model varies from -1.7 to -0.6 log units for high-MgO eclogites and from -2.9 to 0.9 log units for low-MgO eclogites. Samples recording &#8710;logfo2 (FMQ) &#8804; -1 log units overlap with North Slave, West Africa and Udachnaya eclogites, with no difference among eclogite types. The average values of -1.2 (&#177; 0.4) log units for high-MgO and -0.6 (&#177; 1.1) log units for low-MgO eclogites suggest different redox conditions of basaltic protoliths during subduction worldwide. Previous geochemical studies on the same rock samples reported evidence of cryptic metasomatism in both garnet and clinopyroxene that we demonstrate being not recorded by their major elements, while modal metasomatism evidenced by the presence of phlogopite as a product of interaction with a kimberlitic melt only affects the MgO of the bulk rock. Therefore, we suggest that high Fe3+/&#8721;Fe ratios for garnet (&amp;gt; 0.10) and for reconstructed bulk rocks in the case of both low-MgO and high-MgO samples cannot be due to metasomatic interaction with an oxidized fluid, but rather are the consequence of Fe3+ redistribution in an unusually oxidized mafic protolith upon metamorphism. Our results highlight the redox variability of eclogites of Archaean age at conditions more oxidized than present-day MORBs and imply an oxidizing nature of the convective mantle source where magma was formed with consequent speciation of C in the form of carbonate fluid explaining, therefore, the lack of diamonds in V. Grib kimberlite pipe.</description>
      <author>Marras Giulia, Martine Denis, Arvieux Catherine, Agasheva Elena, Vincenzo Stagno</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/petrology/egae054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage of Diabetic Retinopathy with Blood Antioxidants and Gut Microbiota in Type Two Diabetes Mellitus Saudi Patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.46889/joar.2024.5202</link>
      <description>Rania Fahmy, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399096455

                Background: The retina is a light-sensitive nerve layer located at the back of the eye that creates images of objects. These cells kept alive by getting oxygen and nutrients from tiny blood vessels in the eye. Retinopathy is a disease of the retina that is more prevalent in type 2 diabetes mellitus patients. Diabetic retinopathy is a leading cause of blindness because hyperglycemia weakens retinal capillaries, resulting in leakage of blood into the surrounding space. This bleeding can result in formation of scar tissue, which can cause traction retinal detachment and maculopathy. The development of a panel of blood biomarkers to monitor diabetic retinopathies is essential for both diagnosis and prognosis. Proteomics as a powerful tool for the analysis of complex mixtures of proteins and the identification of biomarkers can be of great importance. Purpose: To detect early nerve fiber layer changes around macula and optic disc in diabetic patients and to correlate diabetic retinopathy with blood antioxidants and gut microbiota in T2DM in Saudi patients. Materials and Methods: In this cross-sectional case-control study, a total of 77 eyes of 39 subjects aged 40-60 years who did not have any history of eye injuries or eye diseases affecting fundus viewing, were recruited from King Saud University Campus and the department of ophthalmology in King Abdul Aziz university hospital in Riyadh. All subjects underwent full ophthalmic examination including Peripapillary retinal nerve fiber layer thickness and macular profile, Proteomic approach of collected overnight fasting plasma and Microbial stool examination. Results: The nerve fiber layer thickness around the optic disc was measured for all groups and there was no statistically significant difference in all quadrants between groups. The total retinal thickness at the macular area was different among all groups and tends to increase in group 3 due to diabetic retinopathy. The macular thickness in the 4 quadrants revealed no statistical difference except in the inferior quadrant. Glutathione S transferase and lipid peroxides showed no significant difference between the three studied groups; vitamin C and Glutathione were surprisingly higher in controlled diabetic patients relative to controls. Moreover, over growth of bacteroids participated to the evolution of retinopathy in diabetic patients. Conclusion: As hyperglycemia and oxidative stress are implicated in the pathogenesis of diabetic retinopathy, the present study certified that the progressive damage can be delayed in controlled type 2 diabetic patients using different treatment modalities that subside oxidative stress.</description>
      <author>Rania Fahmy</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.46889/joar.2024.5202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smooth muscle cell-specific deletion of S100A4 modifies smooth muscle cell fate and inflammation in murine atherosclerotic lesions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvae088.166</link>
      <description>P Azar, L M Cardoso Dos Santos, Marta Correia de Sousa, ML Bochaton-Piallat, Cardiovascular research. 120(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399136901

                Abstract Funding Acknowledgements Type of funding sources: Public grant(s) &#8211; National budget only. Main funding source(s): Swiss National Science Foundation (SNSF) S100A4, a calcium-binding protein, is crucial in smooth muscle cell (SMC) phenotypic switch, yet its role in atherosclerotic plaque development and SMC plasticity remains unclear. Our previous experiments using an S100A4 neutralizing antibody approach in ApoE-/- atherosclerotic-prone mice showed reduced atherosclerotic burden but did not establish a direct link between the various S100A4-expressing cells and atherosclerosis. Herein, we show that aortic Oil RedO staining in ApoE-/-; S100A4-/- mice subjected to a 12-week high-cholesterol-diet (HCD) revealed reduced lesion areas compared to ApoE-/- mice (Figure 1, from 21.29% of the total aorta in ApoE-/-; S100A4+/+ mice to 13.27% in ApoE-/-; S100A4-/- mice), highlighting a pivotal role for S100A4 in atherosclerotic plaque development. We then used a lineage tracing ApoE-/- mouse model, in which we induced an SMC-specific deletion of S100A4 (SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916;). After 12 weeks of HCD, SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; and control mice (SMC-S100A4wt/wt) were sacrificed, and aortas were processed for en face Oil Red O staining, immunohistochemistry, and single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq). SMC-specific deletion of S100A4 reduced the necrotic core area (from 29.75% of total plaque area in SMC-S100A4wt/wt to 18.23% in SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; mice) without affecting total atherosclerotic plaque size suggesting a more potent impact on plaque composition. ScRNA-seq analysis from SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; and SMC-S100A4wt/wt mice showed that the inflammatory macrophage-like SMC phenotype was highly suppressed in the plaque and associated with increased SMC repair phenotypes as well as a global reduction of myeloid inflammatory cells. SMCs also retained specific contractile SMC markers, namely Acta2 and Myh11 (fold change of 2.285 and 2.492, respectively) hinting towards a more stable fibrous cap. Immunofluorescence staining on aortic roots plaque (Figure 2) confirmed those results with an increase of SMCs (from 11.02% to 16.18%) as well as a-smooth muscle actin (a-SMA, Acta2)-positive SMCs (from 3.25% to 5.1%) in SMC-S100A4 &#916;/&#916; mice. Furthermore, the Gene Set Enrichment Analysis (GSEA) of scRNAseq data revealed that, in SMC-S100A4&#916;/&#916; mice, genes related to mitochondrial metabolism and oxidative respiration were highly downregulated in all SMC clusters. We investigated SMC mitochondrial fitness in vitro and showed that S100A4-/- SMCs have an increased basal oxygen consumption rate and an increased proton leak (fold change of 1.37 and 1.96 respectively) suggestive of differences in cellular metabolic adaptability. In conclusion, our research emphasizes the significant role of S100A4 in plaque development, demonstrating how SMC-derived S100A4 knockdown affects plaque evolution, reducing inflammation, and promoting stability likely through influencing SMC phenotypic switch through metabolic pathways.</description>
      <author>P Azar, L M Cardoso Dos Santos, Marta Correia de Sousa, ML Bochaton-Piallat</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/cvr/cvae088.166</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
