<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 01:22:58 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Redox Induced Localized Charge Accumulation Accelerating Proton Exchange Membrane Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405447</link>
      <description>Bin Chang, Yuanfu Ren, Nan Mu, Shouwei Zuo, Chen Zou, Wei Zhou, Linrui Wen, Hua Bing Tao, Weijia Zhou, Zhiping Lai, Yoji Kobayashi, Huabin Zhang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405997932

                The sluggish anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolysis necessitates applied bias to facilitate electron transfer as well as bond cleavage and formation. Traditional electrocatalysis focuses on analyzing the effects of electron transfer, while the role of charge accumulation induced by the applied overpotential has not been thoroughly investigated. To explore the influence mechanism of bias-driven charge accumulation, capacitive Mn is incorporated into IrO</description>
      <author>Bin Chang, Yuanfu Ren, Nan Mu, Shouwei Zuo, Chen Zou, Wei Zhou, Linrui Wen, Hua Bing Tao, Weijia Zhou, Zhiping Lai, Yoji Kobayashi, Huabin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202405447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the correlation between spintronic structure and oxygen evolution reaction mechanism of cobalt-ruthenium-based electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55688-8</link>
      <description>Chen Wang, Chaoyuan Deng, Panlong Zhai, Xiaoran Shi, Wei Liu, Dingfeng Jin, Bing Shang, Junfeng Gao, Licheng Sun, Jungang Hou, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406001145

                Regulating the spintronic structure of electrocatalysts can improve the oxygen evolution reaction performance efficiently. Nonetheless, the effects of tuning the spintronic structure for the oxygen evolution reaction mechanisms have rarely been discussed. Here, we show a ruthenium-cobalt-tin oxide with optimized spintronic structure due to the quantum spin interaction of Ru and Co. The specific spintronic structure of ruthenium-cobalt-tin oxide promotes the charge transfer kinetics and intermediates evolution behavior under applied potential, generating long-lived active species with higher spin density sites for the oxygen evolution reaction after the reconstruction process. Moreover, the ruthenium-cobalt-tin oxide possesses decoupled proton-electron transfer procedure during the oxygen evolution reaction process, demonstrating that the electron transfer procedure of O-O bond formation between *O intermediate and lattice oxygen in Co-O-Ru is the rate-determining step of the oxygen evolution reaction process. This work provides rational perspectives on the correlation between spintronic structure and oxygen evolution reaction mechanism. Tuning the spintronic structure in oxygen evolution reactions is underexplored, despite its potential to enhance catalytic performance. Here, the authors report a ruthenium-cobalt-tin oxide with an optimized spintronic structure, highlighting its improved performance and reaction mechanisms.</description>
      <author>Chen Wang, Chaoyuan Deng, Panlong Zhai, Xiaoran Shi, Wei Liu, Dingfeng Jin, Bing Shang, Junfeng Gao, Licheng Sun, Jungang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55688-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Reconstruction of Metal-Organic Frameworks via Coordination Environment Tuning as Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt03348e</link>
      <description>J.S. Gong, Qianglong Qi, Zhiyuan Wang, Guangxin Zhao, Jinliang Yuan, Chengxu Zhang, Jue Hu, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406003308

                During the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) catalysts undergo structural reorganization, a phenomenon that is still not fully comprehended. Additionally, designing MOFs that undergo structural reconstruction to produce...</description>
      <author>J.S. Gong, Qianglong Qi, Zhiyuan Wang, Guangxin Zhao, Jinliang Yuan, Chengxu Zhang, Jue Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt03348e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b</link>
      <description>Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Hongrui Zhu, Guixiang Ding, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, V. Yu. Fominski, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406045737

                The regulation of catalyst surface structure in catalytic process is the basis of regulating catalytic performance. For spinel materials, the common active phases on their surfaces in the oxygen evolution...</description>
      <author>Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Hongrui Zhu, Guixiang Ding, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, V. Yu. Fominski</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-reconstructed FeOOH@CoFeOS/NF architectures: leveraging nano-layered stacking for accelerated oxygen evolution kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04690k</link>
      <description>Xuelei Wang, Xiang Li, Baohua Li, Wenchun Wang, Shizhen Bai, Shifeng Zai, Zhenhua Ni, Chao Meng, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406050068

                The two-step surface reconstruction method was used to prepare FeOOH@CoFeOS/NF, which exhibits a low overpotential of 212 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Xuelei Wang, Xiang Li, Baohua Li, Wenchun Wang, Shizhen Bai, Shifeng Zai, Zhenhua Ni, Chao Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04690k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Electrochemical Reduction Cell Model of Photosynthesis for Carbon Dioxide Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5083012</link>
      <description>Tamunosaki Graham Douglas, Okpara Obinna Michael, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406063550

                Since carbon dioxide levels in the atmosphere have increased at unprecedented rate over the last ten years, global warming has become an increasingly pressing concern for humanity. This work suggests a sustainable solution to this issue by employing a unique mechanism that uses sunlight and electricity to transform CO2 into useful fuel. To construct the device, a Simulink model of the electrochemical reduction cell was created. The model essentially transforms photovoltaic power, CO2 and water into other chemical products. Using the reversible, activation and ohmic equations, the voltage needed to run the CO2 reduction cell was determined. As the anode, cathode, and voltage source blocks are the three main models that make up the CO2 electrolyser cell, the production flow rates of formic acid and oxygen were also evaluated based on molar and charge balances, as well as continuity equations at operating conditions of 1 atm and 298 K. The simulation predicts about 176 kg of CO2 consumption in 10 seconds of the electrochemical conversion. Therefore, the implication of this study is to justify photosynthesis as electrochemical reduction process to efficiently mitigate the accumulation of CO2 in the atmosphere.</description>
      <author>Tamunosaki Graham Douglas, Okpara Obinna Michael</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5083012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Properties of Gold and Cobalt Oxyhydroxide in Plasmon-Mediated Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06632</link>
      <description>Janet Zhen, Timothy Lin, Tucker Forbes, Mark Engelhard, Jingjing Qiu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084303

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Janet Zhen, Timothy Lin, Tucker Forbes, Mark Engelhard, Jingjing Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Modulation Doping in Van der Waals Layered Iridium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422740</link>
      <description>Ke Jia, Wenxiang Zhu, Yujin Ji, Jinxin Chen, Chenchen Li, Yue Wang, Qun Wang, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Zhiwei Hu, Youyong Li, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084440

                Anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) exhibits a sluggish four&#8208;electron transfer process, necessitating catalysts with exceptional catalytic activity to enhance its kinetic rate. Van der Waals layered oxides are ideal materials for catalyst design, yet its stability for acidic OER remains large obstacle. Doping provides a crucial way to improve the activity and stability simultaneously. However, doping in Van der Waals layered oxides remains a great challenge since it easily leads to lattice distortion or even the crystal structure damage. In this work, we successfully doping acid&#8208;resistant niobium (Nb) into Van der Waals layered edge&#8208;shared 1T phase iridium oxide (1T&#8208;IrO2) via alkali&#8208;assisted thermal method. 1T&#8208;IrO2 with a 5% Nb doping (Nb0.05Ir0.95O2) only required an overpotential of 191 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4, 56 mV lower than that of 1T&#8208;IrO2. When applied in a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer, Nb0.05Ir0.95O2 achieved a current density of 1.2 A cm&#8208;2 at a cell voltage of 1.7 V for 50 days. Density functional theory calculation reveals that doping Nb changes the potential&#8208;determining step from the *OOH deprotonation process in 1T&#8208;IrO2 to the *O&#8208;OH coupling process in Nb0.05Ir0.95O2.</description>
      <author>Ke Jia, Wenxiang Zhu, Yujin Ji, Jinxin Chen, Chenchen Li, Yue Wang, Qun Wang, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Zhiwei Hu, Youyong Li, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Modulation Doping in Van der Waals Layered Iridium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422740</link>
      <description>Ke Jia, Wenxiang Zhu, Yujin Ji, Jinxin Chen, Chenchen Li, Yue Wang, Qun Wang, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Zhiwei Hu, Youyong Li, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084475

                Anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) exhibits a sluggish four&#8208;electron transfer process, necessitating catalysts with exceptional catalytic activity to enhance its kinetic rate. Van der Waals layered oxides are ideal materials for catalyst design, yet its stability for acidic OER remains large obstacle. Doping provides a crucial way to improve the activity and stability simultaneously. However, doping in Van der Waals layered oxides remains a great challenge since it easily leads to lattice distortion or even the crystal structure damage. In this work, we successfully doping acid&#8208;resistant niobium (Nb) into Van der Waals layered edge&#8208;shared 1T phase iridium oxide (1T&#8208;IrO2) via alkali&#8208;assisted thermal method. 1T&#8208;IrO2 with a 5% Nb doping (Nb0.05Ir0.95O2) only required an overpotential of 191 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4, 56 mV lower than that of 1T&#8208;IrO2. When applied in a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer, Nb0.05Ir0.95O2 achieved a current density of 1.2 A cm&#8208;2 at a cell voltage of 1.7 V for 50 days. Density functional theory calculation reveals that doping Nb changes the potential&#8208;determining step from the *OOH deprotonation process in 1T&#8208;IrO2 to the *O&#8208;OH coupling process in Nb0.05Ir0.95O2.</description>
      <author>Ke Jia, Wenxiang Zhu, Yujin Ji, Jinxin Chen, Chenchen Li, Yue Wang, Qun Wang, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Zhiwei Hu, Youyong Li, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electron Accumulation of Ir-Co3o4 Toward Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084021</link>
      <description>Aiying Song, Chao Cai, Ming Jiang, Pengcheng Li, Ping Liao, Yue Huang, L. Chen, Xuming He, Yuanmin Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406085792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aiying Song, Chao Cai, Ming Jiang, Pengcheng Li, Ping Liao, Yue Huang, L. Chen, Xuming He, Yuanmin Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Oxygen Vacancies Properties in B-Tio2 Photocatalyst Induced by Rare-Earth Decorating (Re: Nd, Sm, EU, Er, Tm)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084087</link>
      <description>Yanzi Wang, Jianan Dai, Jing Ma, Tengyue Zhang, Zili Liang, Liangsheng Qiang, Rui Liu, Shu&#8208;Hao Chang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406086218

                Enhancing the properties of titanium dioxide (TiO&#8322;) through modification with rare earth metals has become a significant area of research. This study focuses on synthesizing hollow core-shell nanostructured RE-B-TiO&#8322; (RE: Nd, Sm, Eu, Er, Tm) catalysts using solvothermal technology and evaluating their visible-light catalytic efficiency in degrading tetracycline hydrochloride (TCH) and generating H&#8322;. Findings indicate that rare earth element doping enhances oxygen vacancies, minimizes electron-hole recombination, improves electron transfer rates in hollow TiO&#8322; structures, and broadens light absorption from ultraviolet to visible ranges. Under visible light, the Er-B-TiO&#8322; catalyst achieved a 93.2% TCH degradation rate after 120 min. Upon further examination of the effects of catalyst dosage, initial pH, various anions, TCH concentration, and different antibiotics, it was found that pH levels and specific anions significantly impacted the photocatalytic degradation of TCH. An strong absorption band of visible light is achieved in RE-B-TiO&#8322; by intentionally introducing oxygen vacancies, leading to active photochemical oxidation under visible light. Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations and HPLC-MS analyses helped outline the photodegradation pathway and mechanism, while Toxicity predictions indicated a progressive reduction in toxicity during TCH degradation. The enhanced photocatalytic performance is attributed to a slight band gap reduction resulting from the RE 4f-level introduction, offering a promising strategy for designing high-performance photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yanzi Wang, Jianan Dai, Jing Ma, Tengyue Zhang, Zili Liang, Liangsheng Qiang, Rui Liu, Shu&#8208;Hao Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced reconstruction of RuCoNiCuMn high entropy MOF for excellent alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.510</link>
      <description>Jingting Hou, Ningning Chen, Da Bi, Zhi Long Liu, Yanyu Liang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406086882

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingting Hou, Ningning Chen, Da Bi, Zhi Long Liu, Yanyu Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced reactive oxygen species generation: Synergic process of three-electron oxygen reduction and electrochemical ozone production by bimetallic La-Nb oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.039</link>
      <description>Xiaoge Peng, Xu Liu, Xiaosa Wang, Yuanan Li, Suiqin Li, Yuhang Wang, Zhikang Bao, Hao-Qiang Cao, Yue Cao, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406092443

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoge Peng, Xu Liu, Xiaosa Wang, Yuanan Li, Suiqin Li, Yuhang Wang, Zhikang Bao, Hao-Qiang Cao, Yue Cao, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood&#8208;Inspired Electrode for Sustainable Electrocatalytic Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smm2.1326</link>
      <description>Weijia Guo, Yawen Wang, Shunyu Shen, Han Wang, Kai Shao, Zhenjie Wang, Yao Shi, Caicai Li, Qingfeng Sun, Huiqiao Li, SmartMat. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406101616

                ABSTRACT Electrocatalysis plays a central role in electrochemical energy storage and conversion systems, providing a number of sustainable processes for future technologies. As a green, renewable, and abundant natural polymer material, the unique structure and physicochemical properties of wood and its derivatives provide a unique application advantage in the field of electrocatalysis, which has aroused intense attention from researchers. At present, researchers have developed many wood&#8208;based catalytic electrodes by taking advantage of the anisotropic hierarchical porous structure of wood and abundant active functional groups on the cell wall surface of wood. Here, a comprehensive review of recent progress in the design and synthesis of wood&#8208;inspired electrodes for electrocatalytic reactions is summarized. Starting from the role and importance of the electrocatalytic process in the whole energy conversion system, this review highlights the composition and structure of wood, analyzes the mechanisms of electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), urea oxidation reaction (UOR), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and discusses the structure&#8208;activity relationship between the structural properties and electrochemical activity of wood&#8208;inspired electrodes. Finally, the opportunities, challenges, and future directions in the application of wood and its derivatives in the field of electrocatalysis are prospected.</description>
      <author>Weijia Guo, Yawen Wang, Shunyu Shen, Han Wang, Kai Shao, Zhenjie Wang, Yao Shi, Caicai Li, Qingfeng Sun, Huiqiao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smm2.1326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal atoms embedded in monolayer C&lt;sub&gt;13&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; as OER/ORR bifunctional electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01160k</link>
      <description>Xiaoxue Yu, Junkai Xu, Yunhao Wang, Jianjun Fang, Xian-Fang Yue, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, Jing Li, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406107125

                Developing bifunctional electrocatalysts for efficiently catalyzing the oxygen evolution/reduction reaction (OER/ORR) is essential for water electrolysis and other processes. Herein, we have investigated the OER and ORR performance of monolayered...</description>
      <author>Xiaoxue Yu, Junkai Xu, Yunhao Wang, Jianjun Fang, Xian-Fang Yue, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01160k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligands Defect Engineered NH2-MIL-88B(Fe) for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in alkaline seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00968a</link>
      <description>Dongling Xie, Jianan Wang, Bo Huang, Yiyi Yang, Dunmin Lin, Chenggang Xu, Fengyu Xie, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406110150

                Rational design of viable routes to develop affordable and efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is essential for advancing electrochemical water splitting, yet significant challenges remain, particularly in seawater. Here,...</description>
      <author>Dongling Xie, Jianan Wang, Bo Huang, Yiyi Yang, Dunmin Lin, Chenggang Xu, Fengyu Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00968a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Modified Titanium Using Cobalt as Dimensionally Stable Electrodes for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085439</link>
      <description>Raguvaran Ponnurasu, P. Ganesan, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406115684

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Raguvaran Ponnurasu, P. Ganesan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Bimetal Nanoparticles Anchored Hierarchical Carbon Nanospheres with Abundant Active Sites for High-Performance Liquid/Flexible Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085813</link>
      <description>Dingsheng Yuan, Li-Juan Peng, Dan Zhu, Ruchun Li, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406117188

                The development of highly active bifunctional electrocatalysts is crucial to the sluggish oxygen reduction reaction/oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER) for efficient wearable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZAB). The Fe-Nx-C moieties anchored on carbon supports emerge as a desirable alternative as ORR catalysts but its OER activity suffers from low catalytic performance and stability. Herein, a N-doped carbon-encapsulated Fe3C and MnO nanoparticles composite (FeMn-NC) was developed using a simple one-step pyrolysis of the self-sacrificial template. The obtained FeMn-NC possess a hierarchical porous structure with a large specific surface area and rich pyridinic N, which are favorable for the exposure of the active sites. The introduction of the Fe3C/MnO interface can regulate the charge redistribution to promote ORR/OER kinetics, which is confirmed by theoretical calculations. The obtained FeMn-NC exhibits an excellent bifunctional ORR/OER activity in alkaline electrolytes.The assembled liquid ZAB with the FeMn-NC as the cathode can achieve ultrahigh specific capacity of 831.7 mAh g-1 and charge-discharged stability up to 800 h at 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; (2400 cycles). Furthermore, the corresponding flexible solid-state ZAB provides a stable open-circuit voltage of 1.50 V and a specific capacity of 676.1 mAh g&#8722;1 at 1.0 mA cm-2 with good cycling stability. This work offers a simple strategy to synthesize hierarchical porous materials with highly active bifunctional properties, which can be applied in other electrochemical energy devices.</description>
      <author>Dingsheng Yuan, Li-Juan Peng, Dan Zhu, Ruchun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;Zn&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(PO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;&#183;&lt;scp&gt;4H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;/scp&gt;/&lt;scp&gt;TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; Structure for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Energy Storage Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/est2.70112</link>
      <description>Mohammad Wahiduzzaman Khan, Ritu Raj, Mange Ram, Anju Rani, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Energy Storage. 7(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406118645

                ABSTRACT In this study, we present the synthesis and characterization of a high&#8208;performance Zn 3 (PO 4 ) 2 &#183;4H&#8322;O/TiO 2 nanocomposite, designed as a versatile electrocatalyst for advanced energy storage and conversion applications. The synthesis of the Zn 3 (PO 4 ) 2 &#183;4H&#8322;O/TiO 2 nanocomposite was confirmed using various sophisticated analytical techniques such as powder x&#8208;ray diffraction, FTIR, UV spectroscopy, FESEM imaging, EDX, and XPS etc. Notably, the nanocomposite demonstrates exceptional performance in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), with a low overpotential of 250 mV at a current density of 50 mV/cm 2 and a Tafel slope of 129 mV/dec, indicating superior kinetics. Furthermore, it demonstrates a specific capacitance of 112 F/g at a scan rate of 20 mV/s and remarkable cyclic stability, retaining 91% capacitance over 1000 cycles in supercapacitor applications. Additionally, in a practical application, the nanocomposite successfully powered a red light&#8208;emitting diode (LED) for 11 min. The combined effect of Zn 3 (PO 4 ) 2 &#183;4H&#8322;O 2 and TiO 2 contributes to its outstanding electrochemical properties. This makes it a promising candidate for sustainable energy solutions, with the potential to enhance the efficiency and durability of energy storage and conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Wahiduzzaman Khan, Ritu Raj, Mange Ram, Anju Rani, Krishna Kanta Haldar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/est2.70112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h</link>
      <description>Weiguang Hu, Qinghua Xia, Lian Ying Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Qinggang He, Weiyong Yuan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406122704

                Amorphous MOFs (a-MOFs) could be highly promising cocatalysts of 3-D &#945;-Fe 2 O 3 to greatly improve its photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution performance, but their effective synthesis and assembly on 3-D &#945;-Fe 2 O 3 presents formidable...</description>
      <author>Weiguang Hu, Qinghua Xia, Lian Ying Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Qinggang He, Weiyong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of In Situ and Postsynthetic Formation of MOF-Carbon Composites as Electrocatalysts for the Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020208</link>
      <description>Linda Sondermann, Laura Maria Voggenauer, Annette Vollrath, Till Strothmann, Christoph Janiak, Molecules. 30(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126560

                Mixed-metal nickel-iron, NixFe materials draw attention as affordable earth-abundant electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, nickel and mixed-metal nickel-iron metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) composites with the carbon materials ketjenblack (KB) or carbon nanotubes (CNT) were synthesized in situ in a one-pot solvothermal reaction. As a direct comparison to these in situ synthesized composites, the neat MOFs were postsynthetically mixed by grinding with KB or CNT, to generate physical mixture composites. The in situ and postsynthetic MOF/carbon samples were comparatively tested as (pre-)catalysts for the OER, and most of them outperformed the RuO2 benchmark. Depending on the carbon material and metal ratio, the in situ or postsynthetic composites performed better, showing that the method to generate the composite can influence the OER activity. The best material Ni5Fe-CNT was synthesized in situ and achieved an overpotential (&#951;) of 301 mV (RuO2 &#951; = 354 mV), a Tafel slope (b) of 58 mV/dec (RuO2 b = 91 mV/dec), a charge transfer resistance (Rct) of 7 &#8486; (RuO2 Rct = 39 &#8486;), and a faradaic efficiency (FE) of 95% (RuO2 FE = 91%). Structural changes in the materials could be seen through a stability test in the alkaline electrolyte, and chronopotentiometry over 12 h showed that the derived electrocatalysts and RuO2 have good stability.</description>
      <author>Linda Sondermann, Laura Maria Voggenauer, Annette Vollrath, Till Strothmann, Christoph Janiak</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymetallic Sulfides Based on Co-Bdc/Nf for High Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085458</link>
      <description>Nana Gao, Zhengyuan Liu, Yaqiong Gong, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126664

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nana Gao, Zhengyuan Liu, Yaqiong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nabh4 Modified Cobalt Gallium Bimetallic Hydroxide Nanosheets: A High-Performance Amorphous Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085451</link>
      <description>Fangping Wang, Yuee Zhao, Guizhen Xian, Shiyan Zhao, Haidong Yang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126816

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fangping Wang, Yuee Zhao, Guizhen Xian, Shiyan Zhao, Haidong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differentiated Modulating the Electronic Structure of NiFe@Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOx via Phase Transformation Engineering to Synergy Promote Bifunctional Water Splitting Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410752</link>
      <description>Min Feng, Yu Tang, Zhimin Li, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Jianhong Yi, Jiangzhao Chen, Jinsong Wang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406127033

                Abstract Modulating electronic structure to balance the requirement of both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for developing bifunctional catalysts. Herein, phase transformation engineering is utilized to separately regulate catalyst structure, and the designed NiFe@Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOOH schottky heterojunction exhibits remarkable bifunctional electrocatalytic activity with low overpotentials of 19 and 230 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for HER and OER in 1M KOH, respectively. Meanwhile, an anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolyzer employing NiFe@Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOOH as electrodes shows low voltages of 1.487/1.953 V at 10/1000 mA cm &#8722;2 , and operating over 200 h at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 . Combining theoretical calculations and experiments reveal that phase transformation engineering can differentially regulate the active phases of HER/OER. In the HER, Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOOH and metallic NiFe act as the *OH and *H acceptors respectively to accelerates the water dissociation and subsequent Heyrovsky/Tafel step. While in the OER, the significant Jahn&#8208;Teller effect of Mn 3+ induces the surface reconstruction from Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOOH to Ni/Fe&#8208;MnO 2 . The formative high value Mn 4+ can modify the M&#8208;O hybridization and activate the lattice oxygen mechanism, which is pivotal for breaking the restriction of volcanic relationship and reducing OER overpotential. These findings provide valuable design guidelines for high&#8208;performance multi&#8208;functional electrocatalysts via phase transformation engineering.</description>
      <author>Min Feng, Yu Tang, Zhimin Li, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Jianhong Yi, Jiangzhao Chen, Jinsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction Three-Dimensional Fe-Based Electrodes for Oxygen Evolution at Large Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085359</link>
      <description>Shuai Niu, Feng Wu, Jing Zhang, Tao Luo, Ying Yuan, Jing Guo, Hao Luo, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406128382

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Niu, Feng Wu, Jing Zhang, Tao Luo, Ying Yuan, Jing Guo, Hao Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt/cobalt phosphide/nitrogen-doped carbon derived from zeolitic imidazolate framework-11@zeolitic imidazolate framework-12 core-shell structure as efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.014</link>
      <description>Chen-Han Lin, Yin-Chen Lin, Chia&#8208;Lin Yeh, L. Lin, Kuo&#8208;Chuan Ho, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406133976

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen-Han Lin, Yin-Chen Lin, Chia&#8208;Lin Yeh, L. Lin, Kuo&#8208;Chuan Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances and Perspectives on Coupled Water Electrolysis for Energy&#8208;Saving Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411964</link>
      <description>Jiachen Li, Yuqiang Ma, Xiaogang Mu, Xuanjun Wang, Yang Li, Haixia Ma, Zhengxiao Guo, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406146049

                Abstract Overall water splitting (OWS) to produce hydrogen has attracted large attention in recent years due to its ecological&#8208;friendliness and sustainability. However, the efficiency of OWS has been forced by the sluggish kinetics of the four&#8208;electron oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The replacement of OER by alternative electrooxidation of small molecules with more thermodynamically favorable potentials may fundamentally break the limitation and achieve hydrogen production with low energy consumption, which may also be accompanied by the production of more value&#8208;added chemicals than oxygen or by electrochemical degradation of pollutants. This review critically assesses the latest discoveries in the coupled electrooxidation of various small molecules with OWS, including alcohols, aldehydes, amides, urea, hydrazine, etc. Emphasis is placed on the corresponding electrocatalyst design and related reaction mechanisms (e.g., dual hydrogenation and N&#8211;N bond breaking of hydrazine and C&#9552;N bond regulation in urea splitting to inhibit hazardous NCO &#8722; and NO &#8722; productions, etc.), along with emerging alternative electrooxidation reactions (electrooxidation of tetrazoles, furazans, iodide, quinolines, ascorbic acid, sterol, trimethylamine, etc.). Some new decoupled electrolysis and self&#8208;powered systems are also discussed in detail. Finally, the potential challenges and prospects of coupled water electrolysis systems are highlighted to aid future research directions.</description>
      <author>Jiachen Li, Yuqiang Ma, Xiaogang Mu, Xuanjun Wang, Yang Li, Haixia Ma, Zhengxiao Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient bifunctional V&#8208;doped NiCoP/Ni2P electrocatalysts for overall water splitting achieved through a simple heterointerfaces construction strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202402006</link>
      <description>Zhong-Hang Xing, Wenfang Cai, Yun&#8208;Hai Wang, Qing&#8208;Yun Chen, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406146246

                Developing efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst with oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is imperative for water electrolysis. Herein, the construction of heterointerfaces was achieved through the simple phosphating treatment, and a unique chrysanthemum&#8208;like V&#8208;doped NiCoP/Ni2P/NF was synthesized for the efficient water splitting. The prepared V&#8208;doped NiCoP/Ni2P/NF demonstrated favorable bifunctional catalytic performance, requiring low overpotentials of 82 mV and 245 mV to achieve current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for the HER and OER, respectively. At a current density of 50 mA cm&#8208;2, the cell voltage for overall water splitting (OWS) is only 1.66 V, with no significant degradation after 60 hours of operation. The characterization and DFT calculations revealed that the heterointerfaces between NiCoP and Ni2P significantly enhanced the catalytic performance by facilitating electron transfer and optimizing charge distribution. Vanadium doping further changed the electronic properties at the interfaces and optimized the adsorption of intermediates. Due to the synergistic effect of heterointerfaces and vanadium doping, V&#8208;doped NiCoP/Ni2P/NF exhibited excellent bifunctional properties, with more reaction sites, high conductivity, and stability. This strategy could open up new possibilities for designing high&#8208;performance catalysts for renewable energy production and sustainable hydrogen generation.</description>
      <author>Zhong-Hang Xing, Wenfang Cai, Yun&#8208;Hai Wang, Qing&#8208;Yun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202402006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Radial Ligand Effect of Biomimetic Amino Acid toward Stable Alkaline Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04889</link>
      <description>Jianye Wang, Zengxuan Chen, Xiaojing Lin, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaodong Chen, Xingheng Zhang, Jiao Li, Jinpeng Liu, Siyuan Liu, Shuxian Wei, Daofeng Sun, Xiaoqing L&#252;, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianye Wang, Zengxuan Chen, Xiaojing Lin, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaodong Chen, Xingheng Zhang, Jiao Li, Jinpeng Liu, Siyuan Liu, Shuxian Wei, Daofeng Sun, Xiaoqing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering pH Mismatching at the Electrified Electrode&#8211;Electrolyte Interface towards Understanding Intrinsic Water Molecule Oxidation Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419823</link>
      <description>Miao Wang, Ken Sakaushi, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151168

                Abstract Unveiling the key influencing factors towards electrode/electrolyte interface control is a long&#8208;standing challenge for a better understanding of microscopic electrode kinetics, which is indispensable to building up guiding principles for designer electrocatalysts with desirable functionality. Herein, we exemplify the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) via water molecule oxidation with the iridium dioxide electrocatalyst and uncovered the significant mismatching effect of pH between local electrode surface and bulk electrolyte: the intrinsic OER activity under acidic or near&#8208;neutral condition was deciphered to be identical by adjusting this pH mismatching. This result indicates that the local pH effect at the electrified solid&#8211;liquid interface plays the main role in the &#8220;fake&#8221; OER performance. This local pH effect on the OER electrode process is further verified by integrating a wide spectrum of analytical approaches. This study will accelerate the understanding of the local proton&#8208;induced effect on electrode interface processes and the development of advanced electrochemical activity.</description>
      <author>Miao Wang, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering pH Mismatching at the Electrified Electrode&#8211;Electrolyte Interface towards Understanding Intrinsic Water Molecule Oxidation Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419823</link>
      <description>Miao Wang, Ken Sakaushi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151788

                Abstract Unveiling the key influencing factors towards electrode/electrolyte interface control is a long&#8208;standing challenge for a better understanding of microscopic electrode kinetics, which is indispensable to building up guiding principles for designer electrocatalysts with desirable functionality. Herein, we exemplify the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) via water molecule oxidation with the iridium dioxide electrocatalyst and uncovered the significant mismatching effect of pH between local electrode surface and bulk electrolyte: the intrinsic OER activity under acidic or near&#8208;neutral condition was deciphered to be identical by adjusting this pH mismatching. This result indicates that the local pH effect at the electrified solid&#8211;liquid interface plays the main role in the &#8220;fake&#8221; OER performance. This local pH effect on the OER electrode process is further verified by integrating a wide spectrum of analytical approaches. This study will accelerate the understanding of the local proton&#8208;induced effect on electrode interface processes and the development of advanced electrochemical activity.</description>
      <author>Miao Wang, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eco-Friendly Synthesis of Rod-Like Hydroxyapatite on Spherical Carbon: A Dual-Function Composite for Selective Cobalt Removal and Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.137164</link>
      <description>Ali Mohammadi, Santosh Kumar Tamang, Muruganantham Rethinasabapathy, Kugalur Shanmugam Ranjith, Moein Safarkhani, Cheol Hwan Kwak, Changhyun Roh, Yun Suk Huh, Youngkyu Han, Journal of Hazardous Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406160939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ali Mohammadi, Santosh Kumar Tamang, Muruganantham Rethinasabapathy, Kugalur Shanmugam Ranjith, Moein Safarkhani, Cheol Hwan Kwak, Changhyun Roh, Yun Suk Huh, Youngkyu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.137164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Dispersed Ni-Fe Active Sites on Fullerene based Electron Buffer to boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06990k</link>
      <description>Qin Tang, Lingyue Wang, Shenglong Zhang, Pengfei Xue, Yuye Zhang, Hongbo Li, Dongdong Zhu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406162345

                It is critical to develop highly efficient electrocatalysts for water splitting to achieve energy-saving hydrogen production. Recently, fullerene-based electrocatalysts have been widely reported for cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), while...</description>
      <author>Qin Tang, Lingyue Wang, Shenglong Zhang, Pengfei Xue, Yuye Zhang, Hongbo Li, Dongdong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06990k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TM-N4 doped in 4,6,8-biphenylene as an efficient trifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction reaction, oxygen evolution reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162279</link>
      <description>Feng Chen, Xinhui Zhang, Baonan Jia, Chunling Zhang, Ge Wu, Yazhao Yuan, Yirong Ma, Yuanzi Li, Jinkang Yu, Xiaoning Guan, Jinbo Hao, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405987379

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feng Chen, Xinhui Zhang, Baonan Jia, Chunling Zhang, Ge Wu, Yazhao Yuan, Yirong Ma, Yuanzi Li, Jinkang Yu, Xiaoning Guan, Jinbo Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.162279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Engineering of Pillared Co(II) Metal&#8211;Organic Framework@NiMn-Layered Double Hydroxide Nanocomposite for Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04683</link>
      <description>Reza Abazari, Zahra Ahmadi Torkamani, Aleksander Ejsmont, Anna Krawczuk, Joanna Go&#347;cia&#324;ska, Rajender S. Varma, Soheila Sanati, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405997679

                Clean energy conversion and storage require simple, economical, and effective electrode materials to achieve promising results. The development of high-performance electrocatalysts with adequate stability and cost-effectiveness is essential to ensure low overpotentials toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, a cobalt-based metal-organic framework with 4,4,4-6T14 topology in combination with various ratios of NiMn-layered double hydroxide (Co-MOF@</description>
      <author>Reza Abazari, Zahra Ahmadi Torkamani, Aleksander Ejsmont, Anna Krawczuk, Joanna Go&#347;cia&#324;ska, Rajender S. Varma, Soheila Sanati</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe&#9472;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and Fe&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoalloy Dual&#8208;Site Modulation by Skeleton Defect in N&#8208;Doped Graphene Aerogel for Enhanced Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst in Zinc&#8208;air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410264</link>
      <description>Ruihe Tang, Xiaona Yuan, Wenxin Yang, Haiyan Zhang, Yan Lu, Renjie Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405997900

                Abstract The dual&#8208;site electrocatalysts formed by metal single atoms combines with metal nanoparticles represent a promising strategy to enhance both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Herein, defect engineering is applied to dual&#8208;site ORR and OER electrocatalysts. Its design, synthesis, structural properties, and catalytic performance experimentally and theoretically are insightfully studied for the single&#8208;atomic Fe&#9472;N 4 and the adjacent Fe 7 Co 3 nanoalloy (FeCo NA ) as dual&#8208;site loading on nitrogen&#8208;doped graphene aerogel (Fe&#9472;N/FeCo@NGA). The high&#8208;density dual&#8208;sites, together with the good electronic conductivity of NGA, synergistically improve the electronic structure for superior electrocatalytic activity. The half&#8208;wave potential of Fe&#9472;N/FeCo@NGA in ORR is 0.92 V and the overpotential of it in OER is 1.58 V. Corresponding all&#8208;solid&#8208;state Zn&#8208;air battery demonstrates a peak power density of 147.6 mW cm &#8722;2 and charge/discharge durability for over 140 h. Theoretical calculations reveal that the single&#8208;atomic Fe&#8208;N 4 and FeCo NA dual&#8208;site on the skeleton defect optimized NGA, further refine the local electronic structure, modulating the tensile force on the O&#9472;O bond in * OOH intermediate, leading to its spontaneous dissociation and facilitating a significantly reduced energy barrier. This work takes a promising shortcut in the application of defect engineering for the development of highly efficient dual&#8208;site bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts with single atoms.</description>
      <author>Ruihe Tang, Xiaona Yuan, Wenxin Yang, Haiyan Zhang, Yan Lu, Renjie Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cyano-Bridged Bimetallic Polymer Network-Derived Pd&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Fe Intermetallic for Aqueous Rechargeable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c19095</link>
      <description>Santanu Ghora, Biswarup Satpati, Bikash Kumar Jena, C. Retna Raj, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405989638

                The rational design and synthesis of bifunctionally active and durable oxygen electrocatalysts have garnered significant attention for electrochemical energy conversion and storage. Intermetallic nanostructures are particularly promising for these applications due to their unique catalytic properties and exceptional durability. In this study, we present a fascinating synthetic approach for the direct synthesis of a bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst based on nitrogen-doped carbon-encapsulated ordered Pd</description>
      <author>Santanu Ghora, Biswarup Satpati, Bikash Kumar Jena, C. Retna Raj</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c19095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin transition metal oxychalcogenide catalysts for oxygen evolution in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00694-3</link>
      <description>Wenshuo Xu, Yao Wu, Shibo Xi, Yan Wang, Ye Wang, Yuxuan Ke, Lingtong Ding, Xiao Wang, Jieun Yang, Wenjing Zhang, Kian Ping Loh, Feng Ding, Zheng Liu, Manish Chhowalla, Nature Synthesis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405995859

                Abstract Two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) exfoliated from bulk layered materials possess interesting properties. Most transition metal oxides are not layered and therefore cannot be exfoliated. Here we report the synthesis of a family of ultrathin materials&#8212;transition metal oxychalcogenides (TMOCs)&#8212;and demonstrate their unique properties. Two-dimensional TMOCs (MX x O y , M = group IV or V transition metal, X = chalcogen, O = oxygen; x , y = 0&#8211;2) from bulk transition metal dichalcogenides (MX 2 ) have been fabricated using tetrabutylammonium intercalation. The stoichiometry of TMOCs can be adjusted, which enables control of their optical bandgaps and tunability of electrical conductivity by more than eight orders of magnitude. By tuning the chalcogen-to-oxygen ratio along with local atomic structure in TMOCs, it is possible to impart unexpected properties. For example, in contrast to conventional TMDs, the hybrid structure of TMOCs renders them surprisingly stable and electrochemically active in strong acids, allowing them to be used as proof-of-concept catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction at pH &#8776; 0. The HfS 0.52 O 1.09 catalyst shows high mass activity (103,000 A g &#8722;1 at an overpotential of 0.5 V) and exhibits durability in proton exchange membrane water electrolysers.</description>
      <author>Wenshuo Xu, Yao Wu, Shibo Xi, Yan Wang, Ye Wang, Yuxuan Ke, Lingtong Ding, Xiao Wang, Jieun Yang, Wenjing Zhang, Kian Ping Loh, Feng Ding, Zheng Liu, Manish Chhowalla</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00694-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing Oxygen Evolution Catalysis with Dual-Phase Nickel Sulfide Nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05182</link>
      <description>Neelakandan M. Santhosh, Suraj Gupta, Vasyl Shvalya, Martin Ko&#353;i&#269;ek, Janez Zava&#353;nik, Uro&#353; Cvelbar, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406000228

                The production, conversion and storage of energy based on electrocatalysis, mainly assisted by oxygen evolution reaction (OER), plays a crucial role in alkaline water electrolyzers (AWEs) and fuel cells. Nevertheless, the insufficient availability of highly efficient catalyst materials at a reasonable cost that overcome the sluggish electrochemical kinetics of the OER is one of the significant obstacles. Herein, we report a fast and facile synthesis of vapor phase deposition of dual-phase nickel sulfide (Ni-sulfide) using low-temperature annealing in the presence of H2S and demonstrated as an efficient catalyst for OER to address the issues with sluggish electrochemical kinetics. The dual-phase Ni-sulfide structures consist of densely packed 10&#8211;50 &#956;m microcrystals with 40&#8211;50 individual dual-phase layers, such as NiS and Ni7S6. As an electrocatalyst, the dual-phase Ni-sulfide exhibits excellent OER activity by achieving a current density of 10 mA/cm2 at an overpotential (&#951;10) of 0.29 V and excellent electrochemical stability over 50 h. Besides, the Ni-sulfide displays considerable electrochemical robustness in alkaline conditions and forms OER-active Ni-oxide/hydroxide species during the process. Using an energy-efficient synthesis method, the fabricated unique crystalline nanodesign of dual-phase Ni-sulfide could open new pathways for the controlled synthesis of a high-efficiency group of electrocatalysts for a long-time stable electrochemical catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Neelakandan M. Santhosh, Suraj Gupta, Vasyl Shvalya, Martin Ko&#353;i&#269;ek, Janez Zava&#353;nik, Uro&#353; Cvelbar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05182</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir-O-Mn embedded in porous nanosheets enhances charge transfer in low-iridium PEM electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54646-8</link>
      <description>Dawei Wang, Fangxu Lin, Heng Luo, Jinhui Zhou, Wenshu Zhang, Lu Li, Yi Wei, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Yanfei Wang, Mingchuan Luo, Fan Lv, Shaojun Guo, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406000695

                Using metal oxides to disperse iridium (Ir) in the anode layer proves effective for lowering Ir loading in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE). However, the reported low-Ir-based catalysts still suffer from unsatisfying electrolytic efficiency and durability under practical industrial working conditions, mainly due to insufficient catalytic activity and mass transport in the catalyst layer. Herein we report a class of porous heterogeneous nanosheet catalyst with abundant Ir-O-Mn bonds, achieving a notable mass activity of 4 A mgIr&#8722;1 for oxygen evolution reaction at an overpotential of 300 mV, which is 150.6 times higher than that of commercial IrO2. Ir-O-Mn bonds are unraveled to serve as efficient charge-transfer channels between in-situ electrochemically-formed IrOx clusters and MnOx matrix, fostering the generation and stabilization of highly active Ir3+ species. Notably, Ir/MnOx-based PEMWE demonstrates comparable performance under 10-fold lower Ir loading (0.2 mgIr cm&#8722;2), taking a low cell voltage of 1.63 V to deliver 1 A cm&#8722;2 for over 300 h, which positions it among the elite of low Ir-based PEMWEs. Building an efficient proton-exchange membrane water electrolyzer with low Ir loading remains important but challenging. Here, the authors report an Ir/MnOx catalyst with rich Ir-O-Mn bonds that serve as charge-transfer channels to generate and stabilize active Ir3+ species, enhancing both activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Dawei Wang, Fangxu Lin, Heng Luo, Jinhui Zhou, Wenshu Zhang, Lu Li, Yi Wei, Qinghua Zhang, Lin Gu, Yanfei Wang, Mingchuan Luo, Fan Lv, Shaojun Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-54646-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the durability of RuO2 via confinement effect for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55747-0</link>
      <description>W. Zheng, Xuanxuan Cheng, Ping-Ping Chen, Linlin Wang, Ying Duan, Guojin Feng, Xiaoran Wang, Jingjing Li, Chao Zhang, Ziyou Yu, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406017235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>W. Zheng, Xuanxuan Cheng, Ping-Ping Chen, Linlin Wang, Ying Duan, Guojin Feng, Xiaoran Wang, Jingjing Li, Chao Zhang, Ziyou Yu, Tong&#8208;Bu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-55747-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Properly Modulating Co Incorporation in Nife-Ldh to Suppress Fe-Rich and Ni-Rich Phase Formation for Enhanced Alkaline Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5080239</link>
      <description>Hanyu Xu, Quan Li, Jiawen Zhou, Jianchen Pu, Jiajie Tang, Jinhan Chen, Xingxing Gu, Rong Peng, Xingyan Liu, Jiaqiang Yang, Youzhou He, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406018795

                Water splitting is a promising approach to producing eco-friendly and high-energy-density hydrogen, addressing both energy shortages and environmental challenges. However, the development of efficient non-noble electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains challenging due to the sluggish kinetics of four sequential proton-coupled electron transfer steps. In this study, nickel-cobalt-iron layered double hydroxide nanosheets on nickel foam (NiCoFe@LDH/NF) are synthesized via a straightforward one-step solvothermal method. Unlike traditional Co doping, our work found that the proper introduction of Co could improve the lattice tolerance and inhibit the formation of Ni-rich or Fe-rich phase simultaneously. Both experimental and theoretical data collaboratively demonstrated that the proper incorporation of cobalt in NiFe-LDH optimized its electronic structure and tuned the Gibbs free energy of oxygen intermediates (*O) to an optimal value (~2.5 eV). This reduced the energy barrier of the rate-determining step, resulting in enhanced active site utilization and improved catalytic efficiency at the interface between LDH materials and water. Consequently, NiCoFe@LDH/NF exhibited excellent OER activity, with overpotentials of 149 and 246 mV at 10 and 100 mA cm&#8722;1 in 1 mol&#8729;L&#8722;1 KOH, surpassing noble metal-based catalysts like RuO2. In addition, the synthesis process was completed within four hours, enabling its potential for industrial-scale production. This work provides a novel strategy for optimizing catalytic activity of LDH interface through adjusting the O adsorption behavior on Fe sites, lays the foundation for LDH catalyst development with outstanding activity.</description>
      <author>Hanyu Xu, Quan Li, Jiawen Zhou, Jianchen Pu, Jiajie Tang, Jinhan Chen, Xingxing Gu, Rong Peng, Xingyan Liu, Jiaqiang Yang, Youzhou He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5080239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active and Stable Al-Doped NiFe Self-Supported Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrode for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04393</link>
      <description>Byung&#8208;Jo Lee, Sang&#8208;Mun Jung, Guoliang Yu, Hyun-Yup Kim, Jaesub Kwon, Kyu&#8208;Su Kim, Jaeik Kwak, Wooseok Lee, Dong Hyeon Mok, Seoin Back, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406022367

                Alkaline water electrolysis (AWE), a predominant technology for large-scale industrial hydrogen production, faces limitations in commercialization owing to the inadequate catalytic activity and stability of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. This study introduces a NiFeAl self-supported electrode characterized by high activity and stability for the OER and outlines a rational design strategy for NiFe (oxy)hydroxide-based self-supported electrodes. The introduction of Al, a ternary dopant with relatively low electronegativity and a small ionic radius, into the NiFe electrode effectively controls the adsorption energy of O-intermediates and facilitates the deprotonation of adsorbed OH*, thereby accelerating the OER. Remarkably, the NiFeAl self-supported electrode demonstrates approximately 50% enhanced operational activity (0.71 A cm&#8211;2 at 1.8 V) compared to NiFe alongside exceptional stability (&gt;72 h at 0.6 A cm&#8211;2) in OER within an AWE single cell. These findings highlight the significant potential of the NiFeAl electrode for application in AWE for efficient, large-scale hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Byung&#8208;Jo Lee, Sang&#8208;Mun Jung, Guoliang Yu, Hyun-Yup Kim, Jaesub Kwon, Kyu&#8208;Su Kim, Jaeik Kwak, Wooseok Lee, Dong Hyeon Mok, Seoin Back, Yong&#8208;Tae Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-Dependent Electronic Structure Modulation of Nickel Selenides by Fe Doping for Enhanced Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04047c</link>
      <description>A. S. Vigneshraaj, Siva Kumar Ramesh, Jinkwon Kim, Kavita Pandey, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406037523

                Bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis is a pivotal process that underpins a diverse array of sustainable energy technologies, including electrolyzers and fuel cells. Metal selenides have been identified as highly promising candidates...</description>
      <author>A. S. Vigneshraaj, Siva Kumar Ramesh, Jinkwon Kim, Kavita Pandey</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr04047c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic geometric and electronic optimized Mo@Mo-Bo electrocatalyst for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction and value-added electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01613k</link>
      <description>Kuldeep Kumar, Dhanasingh Thiruvengadam, M.R. Suresh Kumar, Kuppusamy Rajan, Jayaraman Jayabharathi, Manoharan Padmavathy, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406037935

                Metal borates have long-lasting uses due their high electrical conductivity and stability.</description>
      <author>Kuldeep Kumar, Dhanasingh Thiruvengadam, M.R. Suresh Kumar, Kuppusamy Rajan, Jayaraman Jayabharathi, Manoharan Padmavathy</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01613k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual&#8208;Driven Activation of High&#8208;Valence States in Prussian Blue Analogues Via Graphene&#8208;Quantum Dots and Ozone&#8208;Induced Surface Restructuring for Superior Hydrogen Evolution Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401708</link>
      <description>Angelina Melanita Tarigan, Mia Rinawati, Sofiannisa Aulia, Ling&#8208;Yu Chang, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Wei&#8208;Nien Su, Shu&#8208;Chih Haw, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Heru Setyawan, Min&#8208;Hsin Yeh, Small Methods. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406038900

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting is a pivotal process for sustainable hydrogen energy production, relying on efficient hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalysts, particularly in acidic environments, where both high activity and durability are crucial. Despite the favorable kinetics of platinum (Pt)&#8208;based materials, their performance is hindered under harsh conditions, driving the search for alternatives. Due to their unique structural characteristic, Prussian blue analogs (PBAs) emerge as attractive candidates for designing efficient HER electrocatalysts. However, modulating their properties and functionalities is crucial to overcome their conductivity issue. Herein, a reconfiguration strategy for the dual&#8208;driven surface restructuring of the CoFe PBA involving graphene quantum dots (GQD) and UV/ozone is proposed. X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) analysis revealed that dual&#8208;driven reconstruction plays a pivotal role in promoting the high&#8208;valence metal ions, effectively reducing charge transfer resistance&#8212;a key limitation in HER. The optimized CoFe PBA/GQD&#8208;UV exhibits remarkable electrocatalytic performance toward HER, with a low overpotential of 77 mV to reach a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with excellent durability for 12 h under an extremely high current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 in an acidic solution. This dual&#8208;combination strategy offering a new pathway to develop highly active electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Angelina Melanita Tarigan, Mia Rinawati, Sofiannisa Aulia, Ling&#8208;Yu Chang, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Wei&#8208;Nien Su, Shu&#8208;Chih Haw, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Heru Setyawan, Min&#8208;Hsin Yeh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401708</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j</link>
      <description>Linqing Liao, Wangyan Gou, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu, Nanoscale Horizons. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406045722

                Over-oxidation of surface ruthenium active sites of RuOx-based electrocatalysts leads to the formation of soluble high-valent Ru species and subsequent structural collapse of electrocatalysts, which results in their low stability...</description>
      <author>Linqing Liao, Wangyan Gou, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogel Electrolyte-Mediated In Situ Zn-Anode Modification and the Ru-RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/NGr-Coated Cathode for High-Performance Solid-State Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14231</link>
      <description>Geeta Pandurang Kharabe, Tushar Verma, Sidharth Barik, Rajashri Urkude, Ayasha Nadeema, Biplab Ghosh, Sa&#239;laja Krishnamurty, Sreekumar Kurungot, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406049021

                This work aims to deal with the challenges associated with designing complementary bifunctional electrocatalysts and a separator/membrane that enables rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (RZABs) with nearly solid-state operability. This solid-state RZAB was accomplished by integrating a bifunctional electrocatalyst based on Ru-RuO2 interface nanoparticles supported on nitrogen-doped (N-doped) graphene (Ru-RuO2/NGr) and a dual-doped poly(acrylic acid) hydrogel (d-PAA) electrolyte soaked in KOH with sodium stannate additive. The catalyst shows enhanced activity and stability toward the two oxygen reactions, i.e., oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER), with a very low potential difference (&#916;E) of 0.64 V. The computational insights bring out the electronic factors contributing to the enhanced catalytic activity of Ru-RuO2/NGr based on the charge density difference (CDD) between the interfaces. The disadvantages of the existing solid-state RZABs, such as their limited lifespan brought on by passivation, dendritic growth, corrosion, and shape change, have also been taken into account. The introduction of the stannate additive to the electrolyte induced an in situ Zn-anode modification, which subsequently improved the interfacial stability of the ZABs and, hence, the battery life cycles. The experimental observations reveal that, during the charging process, the Sn nanoparticles enable the homogeneous Zn deposition on the surface of the anode. Thus, the in situ Zn-anode surface modification assisted in achieving a high-rate cycle capability, viz., the homemade catalyst-based system exhibited continuous charge&#8211;discharge cycles for 20 h at a current density of 2.0 mA cm&#8211;2, with each cycle lasting for 5 min.</description>
      <author>Geeta Pandurang Kharabe, Tushar Verma, Sidharth Barik, Rajashri Urkude, Ayasha Nadeema, Biplab Ghosh, Sa&#239;laja Krishnamurty, Sreekumar Kurungot</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Self-Assembled Multi-Level Nife-Ldhs Integrated Super-Hydrophilic Diaphragms Enabling Efficient Alkaline Water Electrolysis for High Current Density and Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5081103</link>
      <description>Xi Luo, Xiaohui Yang, Yongnan Zhou, Nengneng Xu, Nianjun Yang, Quan Zhang, Yuyu Liu, Daniil I. Kolokolov, Jinli Qiao, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406049322

                Alkaline water electrolysis is one of most potential techniques for green hydrogen production, offering high energy conversion and storage. High current density and durability diaphragms are crucial for electrochemical performance. Here we have developed a high-performance composite diaphragm based on in-situ self-assemble of nickel-iron layered double hydroxides (NiFe-LDHs) loaded on Zirfon-type substrate, and at the same time catalytic NiFe-LDHs integrated the anode side for high-performance alkaline water electrolysis. By modulating the microstructure, a unique surficial feature with high surface free energy and super-hydrophilicity to address the issue of high ohmic resistance is established and achieves rapid OH&#8722;conduction and high catalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Consequently, the prepared ZLDH-&#967; series diaphragm affords excellent application properties, with ZLDH-10 diaphragm an ultra-short wetting time of 0.23s and a reduction of 120 mV over-voltage in single electrolytic cell. Electrolyzer with ZLDH-10 diaphragm provides exceptional current density of 1400 mA cm-2 at 2.0 V in 80oC 30wt% KOH. Importantly, large-scale ZLDH-10 diaphragm with 37 &#215; 37 cm2 can be readily made and reaches an unprecedented durability at 1000 mA cm-2@1.8 V over 240 hours. Both simple in-situ self-assemble approach and excellent performance of ZLDH-&#967; series diaphragm pave a new way for manufacturing diaphragm in advanced alkaline water electrolysis. A partial polarization method was first invented to figure out the contribution ratio for cell voltage reduction between NiFe-LDHs catalytic effect and hydrophilic improving effect.</description>
      <author>Xi Luo, Xiaohui Yang, Yongnan Zhou, Nengneng Xu, Nianjun Yang, Quan Zhang, Yuyu Liu, Daniil I. Kolokolov, Jinli Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5081103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous pseudocapacitive oxidation and oxygen evolution reaction: reciprocity or incompatibility?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02666g</link>
      <description>Xinpeng Huang, Yingnan Yan, Xuehua Yan, Qianzuo Liu, Feng Zhang, Jili Wu, Jianmei Pan, Zohreh Shahnavaz, Jamile Mohammadi Moradian, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406049642

                Based on the excellent performance of novel high-entropy hydroxides, we investigate the relationship between pseudocapacitive performance and catalytic oxygen evolution in alkaline aqueous electrolyte systems.</description>
      <author>Xinpeng Huang, Yingnan Yan, Xuehua Yan, Qianzuo Liu, Feng Zhang, Jili Wu, Jianmei Pan, Zohreh Shahnavaz, Jamile Mohammadi Moradian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02666g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CeF3-Accelerated surface reconstruction of MoO2 nanosheets into coral-like CeF3/MoO2 composites enhances the oxygen evolution reaction for efficient water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.232</link>
      <description>Jia Liu, Chenglin Liu, Xianglin Qiu, Tianshuo Zhang, Shanshan Gao, Xiaoming Song, Fushan Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406053535

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jia Liu, Chenglin Liu, Xianglin Qiu, Tianshuo Zhang, Shanshan Gao, Xiaoming Song, Fushan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.12.232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous Cation Exchange-Induced Iron Doping in Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01960</link>
      <description>Xin Chen, Linwei Jiang, Weijia Guo, Shunyu Shen, Ziteng Wang, Kai Shao, Zhenjie Wang, Caicai Li, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406058132

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Chen, Linwei Jiang, Weijia Guo, Shunyu Shen, Ziteng Wang, Kai Shao, Zhenjie Wang, Caicai Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01960</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe ion doping as an effective strategy to enhance oxygen evolution reaction activity in NiCo2O4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.236159</link>
      <description>Xiaoxue Fu, Juan Yu, Han Li, Yongxing Zhang, Shencheng Pan, Yongsheng Fu, Bing Li, Journal of Power Sources. 630(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406062474

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxue Fu, Juan Yu, Han Li, Yongxing Zhang, Shencheng Pan, Yongsheng Fu, Bing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.236159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface/interface regulation of Ni0.85Se via tungsten-doping for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178478</link>
      <description>Xiao Fu, Xu Liu, Yi Wang, Yujia Wang, Xiaoxiao Yin, Zhongqing Liu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406064051

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao Fu, Xu Liu, Yi Wang, Yujia Wang, Xiaoxiao Yin, Zhongqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping La into NiFe LDH/NiS heterostructure achieving high-current-density oxygen evolution for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157526</link>
      <description>Qi Song, Kangnan Li, Zhenhua Cao, Mi Yang, Qian Kong, Gang He, Hongyu Liu, Qian Qiao, Liangzhong Yao, Yufan Wang, Xiaoping Dai, Xin Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Song, Kangnan Li, Zhenhua Cao, Mi Yang, Qian Kong, Gang He, Hongyu Liu, Qian Qiao, Liangzhong Yao, Yufan Wang, Xiaoping Dai, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Benchmark for Pure Nickel-Based Oxygen-Evolution Electrocatalyst: Tailored Large NiMoO4&#183;xH2O Monocrystals for Complete Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125024</link>
      <description>Xin Cui, Tang Tang, Feiyang Zhang, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Cui, Tang Tang, Feiyang Zhang, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406064935

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065107

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065133

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Hongrui Zhu, Guixiang Ding, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, V. Yu. Fominski, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065138

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Hongrui Zhu, Guixiang Ding, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, V. Yu. Fominski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065175

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065181

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065198

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Linqing Liao, Wangyan Gou, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065405

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linqing Liao, Wangyan Gou, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065411

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065420

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065439

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065442

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065466

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065471

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electro-Activated Ni3s2-Nio Modified by Amorphous Nifeox as Superior Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5081208</link>
      <description>Baojiang Jiang, Xiaohua Yang, Huiyuan Meng, Mingyang Liu, Qi Li, Jiamei Guo, Kun Lang, Huiquan Gu, Xudong Xiao, Ruihong Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406048299

                The electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) as a rapid control step in water splitting for hydrogen production can utilise FeNi-based catalysts to reduce the reaction overpotential. In considering the disparate effects of crystalline and amorphous phases on the stability and activity of the catalyst, amorphous/crystalline heterojunctions were formed by FeNi-based metal oxides and employed as catalysts. In this work, the amorphous NiFeOx-modified Ni3S2-NiO/NF* heterojunction nanosheets (NiFe@Ni3S2-NiO/NF*) with a three-dimensional structural configuration were successfully prepared through a two-stage process involving hydrothermal and electrical treatments. In NiFe@Ni3S2-NiO/NF*, the electrically activated Ni3S2-NiO/NF* in-stiu nanosheets exhibit a stable crystal structure and regular morphology, which enhances catalytic stability and facilitates exposure of active sites. Meanwhile, amorphous nickel-iron oxides modified by electrodeposition methods exhibit a robust bond with the substrate, coupled with structural flexibility, low contact resistance and high electrocatalytic activity. The NiFe@Ni3S2-NiO/NF* electrode exhibits remarkable catalytic activity towards OER in alkaline media, particularly at low potential of 1.49 V to reach large current density of 50 mA cm-2, along with excellent long-term stability. These findings are of significant importance in providing novel insights for the design and construction of FeNi-based metal oxide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Baojiang Jiang, Xiaohua Yang, Huiyuan Meng, Mingyang Liu, Qi Li, Jiamei Guo, Kun Lang, Huiquan Gu, Xudong Xiao, Ruihong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5081208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Calcined Ni/Fe Layered Double Hydroxide for the Anode Electrode of an Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5082120</link>
      <description>Yao&#8208;Tung Lin, Jun-Yen Uan, Nitika Devi, Amornchai Arpornwichanop, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406052943

                Hydrogen energy has the potential to mitigate the adverse environmental effects of fossil fuels and address the growing need for energy. Water electrolysis is an environmentally friendly process of hydrogen production compared to the more widely used steam methane reforming. Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) is a type of electrolysis that combines the advantages of both alkaline water electrolysis (AWE) and proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE), operating in an alkaline solution and zero-gap configuration, respectively. During the reaction of water splitting, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) determines the reaction kinetics. In this study, we developed Ni/Fe layered double hydroxide (LDH), a cost-effective catalyst for AEMWE. Optimum operating conditions, such as temperature, membrane pretreatment, catalyst loadings, and GDL characteristics, are evaluated through polarization testing and scanning electron microscopy (SEM) analysis. Results show that membrane pretreatments with KOH and NaCl have similar effects with an optimum 1-hour immersion. A cathode gas diffusion layer with a hydrophobic surface for efficient bubble removal and hydrophilic internal properties for effective electrolyte exchange offered an increase in current density of 68.4% at 2 V. Pt loading of 1.0 mg cm&#8722;2 with ultrasonic spraying is the most favorable, and increasing the temperature from 25 to 60 &#176;C also increases the current density from 200 mA cm&#8722;2 to 600 mAcm&#8722;2 at 1.8 V.</description>
      <author>Yao&#8208;Tung Lin, Jun-Yen Uan, Nitika Devi, Amornchai Arpornwichanop, Yong&#8208;Song Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5082120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High content Fe(III) electrocatalyst for the oxygen reduction and evolution reactions. Spectroscopic, electrochemical, and theoretical insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.385</link>
      <description>C&#233;sar Z&#250;&#241;iga Loyola, Andrea Zitolo, Nicol&#225;s Troncoso, Jesus Carrasco, Sergio Choque, Gabriel Abarca, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Walter Orellana, Federico Tasca, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074461

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C&#233;sar Z&#250;&#241;iga Loyola, Andrea Zitolo, Nicol&#225;s Troncoso, Jesus Carrasco, Sergio Choque, Gabriel Abarca, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Walter Orellana, Federico Tasca</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the photosynthesis process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59783/aire.2023.18</link>
      <description>Blanka Balyi, Nela Marinovi&#263;, Nata&#353;a Nikoli&#263;-Lukovska, AIDASCO Reviews. 1(1)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4406142614

                In this Review, some fascinating and essential concepts of photosynthesis were described. There is much information about photosynthesis, which is widely known, considering the importance of this process. However, there is also a range of information about photosynthesis that is unknown and not often mentioned. Photosynthesis is the name given to the set of biochemical reactions that change carbon dioxide and water into sugar, glucose, and oxygen. Sunlight is often harnessed by chlorophyll, which is green because it reflects green light. This Review will give a deeper insight into some parts of the photosynthesis process.</description>
      <author>Blanka Balyi, Nela Marinovi&#263;, Nata&#353;a Nikoli&#263;-Lukovska</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59783/aire.2023.18</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical behavior of WO3 and TiO2 films modified with cobalt-based oxygen evolution catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2014.25.3.4</link>
      <description>Simona Ostachavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Rasa Mardosait&#279;, Eugenijus Valatka, Chemija. 25(3)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4406095564

                Continuous tungsten trioxide (WO3) and porous titanium dioxide (TiO2) films on AISI304 type steel were prepared by electrochemical methods. The morphology and structure of the obtained films were studied by X-ray diffraction analysis and scanning electron microscopy. Oxygen evolution catalyst containing cobalt&#8211;phosphate compound was deposited photochemically onto the surface of semiconductor particles. The photoelectrochemical properties of the prepared electrodes were investigated in neutral 0.1 M phosphate buffer solutions. The voltammetric characteristics revealed that the presence of cobalt-based catalyst effectively changes the photoelectrocatalytic activity of WO3 and TiO2 particles. The influence of some synthesis parameters (type of cobalt(II) salt, photodeposition time) on the electrochemical properties of the prepared electrodes was evaluated experimentally.</description>
      <author>Simona Ostachavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Rasa Mardosait&#279;, Eugenijus Valatka</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2014.25.3.4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability and activity of organometallic phthalocyanine sheets for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145602</link>
      <description>Walter Orellana, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406012283

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Walter Orellana</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145602</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarization switching-controlled oxygen evolution and reduction reactions for ferroelectric single-atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159247</link>
      <description>Wenqing Li, Hongyu Zhang, Ruoyan Xu, Xingxing Jiang, Haiyu Meng, Xiong&#8208;Xiong Xue, Shengli Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqing Li, Hongyu Zhang, Ruoyan Xu, Xingxing Jiang, Haiyu Meng, Xiong&#8208;Xiong Xue, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing surface segregation by introducing lanthanides to enhance high-temperature oxygen evolution reaction activity and durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/ada4dc</link>
      <description>Jingwei Li, Zichao Wu, Yuxiang Shen, Yuefeng Song, Houfu Lv, Xiaomin Zhang, Guoxiong Wang, Journal of Physics Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406006571

                Abstract Ba0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3-&#948; (BSCF) is a conventional anode material for solid oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs) to catalyze oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the inferior chemical stability of BSCF results in severe surface segregation and performance degradation under high temperatures. A critical challenge lies in alleviating surface segregation and preserving the high OER performance of BSCF anode. Herein, lanthanides are introduced to substitute Ba of BSCF, labeled as Ln0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3-&#948; (LnSCF, Ln=La, Pr, Nd, Sm), to regulate its stability and performance. The introduction of La and Pr effectively enhances stability, suppresses surface segregation, and maintains high OER activity. The continuous lattice oxygen loss and Co ions oxidation of LnSCF are demonstrated upon annealing in oxidizing atmosphere, thus we propose that surface segregation is a self-regulation mechanism of perovskite lattice to tolerant oxidizing atmosphere and maintain structurally stable via decreasing A-site valence state and forming surface segregation. SOEC with La0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3-&#948; (LSCF) anode delivers the optimal current density of 1.69 A cm-2 at1.6 V and stability for CO2 electrolysis at 800 &#176;C, shedding light on designing advanced catalysts for high-temperature OER.&amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Jingwei Li, Zichao Wu, Yuxiang Shen, Yuefeng Song, Houfu Lv, Xiaomin Zhang, Guoxiong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2515-7655/ada4dc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of NiSe /Mo3O8 heterogeneous structure with obvious polarity difference for promoted oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134282</link>
      <description>Xiao Fu, Lang Qin, Yujia Wang, Xiaoxiao Yin, Xu Liu, Zhongqing Liu, Fuel. 386(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406119533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao Fu, Lang Qin, Yujia Wang, Xiaoxiao Yin, Xu Liu, Zhongqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406065416

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidation of the Electrocatalytic Function of Composite Metal Carbides Co&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;W&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;C and Co&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;Mo&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;C with Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5796/electrochemistry.24-00123</link>
      <description>Ikki Yanagimoto, Masashi Wada, Satoko Takase, Toshiyuki Takizawa, Youichi Shimizu, Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406159303

                Metal-air secondary batteries have attracted attention as a next-generation energy storage system due to their high energy density and environmentally friendly characteristics.However, it is important to develop a catalyst that can rapidly promote both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).We have found that Co3W3C and Co3Mo3C composite metal carbides prepared by a wet method have high bifunctional electrode performance, but the mechanism of action has not been elucidated.In this study, we comprehensively evaluated the adsorption behavior of oxygen molecules and surface hydroxyl groups, the charge density difference, and the effects of surface structure and chemical composition on catalytic activity by combining DFT (density functional theory) calculations and instrumental analysis.In particular, we found that Co3Mo3C optimizes the adsorption of oxygen molecules by metal compositing, contributing to the improvement of electrode catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Ikki Yanagimoto, Masashi Wada, Satoko Takase, Toshiyuki Takizawa, Youichi Shimizu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5796/electrochemistry.24-00123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406170086

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406170150

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406170151

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406169724

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406170174

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406158323

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/Crystalline ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Oxygen Vacancies Anchored Nano&#8208;Ru Enhance Reverse Hydrogen Spillover in Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410436</link>
      <description>Jingyang Niu, Huimei Duan, Ting Sun, Zelun Zhi, Daohao Li, Xiaokun Fan, Lijie Zhang, Dongjiang Yang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406085038

                Abstract Hydrogen spillover&#8208;based binary (HSBB) system has attracted significant attention in alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Accelerating hydrogen spillover in the HSBB system is crucial for the HER activity. Herein, a highly efficient HSBB system is developed by anchoring nano&#8208;Ru on oxygen vacancy (Vo) rich amorphous/crystal ZrO 2 . Theoretical and experimental results reveal that the water molecules dissociate on the Vo of ZrO 2 into protons, which then couple with electrons to form H * , and the produced H * are spilled over to the nano&#8208;Ru to evolve H 2 . The amorphous regions enhance the adsorption and desorption rates of hydrogen while exposing a greater number of active sites; meanwhile, the Vo significantly reduce the work function of ZrO 2 , facilitates electron transfer from ZrO 2 to Ru, and thereby accelerates hydrogen spillover. As a result, the Ru/ac&#8208;ZrO 2 delivers a low overpotential of 14 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a high mass activity of 46.47 A mg metal &#8722;2 at 300 mV for alkaline HER, bypass those of commercial Pt/C (19 mV and 0.09 A mg metal &#8722;2 , respectively).</description>
      <author>Jingyang Niu, Huimei Duan, Ting Sun, Zelun Zhi, Daohao Li, Xiaokun Fan, Lijie Zhang, Dongjiang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrogen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction on OH/F-Terminated Titanium Nitride MXene Reveal the Role of the Surface Termination Group in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05247</link>
      <description>Eugenie Pranada, Bright Ngozichukwu, Ray Yoo, Denis Johnson, Mark A. Barteau, Ahmed Abdel&#8208;Wahab, Abdoulaye Djire, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405994823

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eugenie Pranada, Bright Ngozichukwu, Ray Yoo, Denis Johnson, Mark A. Barteau, Ahmed Abdel&#8208;Wahab, Abdoulaye Djire</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c05247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace Cobalt Inserted Platinum Lattice Gap to Enable Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07260j</link>
      <description>Jie Yang, Shilong Song, Bo Zhang, Zhanwei Chen, Yuyu Guo, Ying Guo, Hepeng Zhang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406107149

                Platinum-based materials are generally considered as efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysts but worse for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), limiting their applications in zinc-air batteries (ZABs). Therefore, it is of...</description>
      <author>Jie Yang, Shilong Song, Bo Zhang, Zhanwei Chen, Yuyu Guo, Ying Guo, Hepeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07260j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au-Ni synergy for enhanced electrochemical oxidation of ethanol over Au/Ni foam electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01490a</link>
      <description>Xing Tan, Ruixing Du, Qitong Zhong, Longfei Liao, Huanhao Chen, Zhenchen Tang, Dafeng Yan, Shiming Chen, Feng Zeng, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406093305

                Replacing the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction with ethanol oxidation can reduce the overpotential while generating value-added products. In this study, a highly active and stable catalyst was synthesized via electrochemical...</description>
      <author>Xing Tan, Ruixing Du, Qitong Zhong, Longfei Liao, Huanhao Chen, Zhenchen Tang, Dafeng Yan, Shiming Chen, Feng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01490a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic aldehyde oxidation: An emerging anodic reaction for efficient electrolytic systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01515k</link>
      <description>Fen Hu, Peng&#8208;Yuan Wang, Z. L&#252;, Kai Chen, Yichun Ding, Wang Li, Zhenhai Wen, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406108597

                Conventional electrolytic systems (e.g., water electrolysis), which rely on the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), are hindered by sluggish anodic kinetics and high energy demands. Electrocatalytic aldehyde oxidation, which has...</description>
      <author>Fen Hu, Peng&#8208;Yuan Wang, Z. L&#252;, Kai Chen, Yichun Ding, Wang Li, Zhenhai Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01515k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A self-supported nickel pseudo-intermetallic alloy electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102369</link>
      <description>Naznin Shaikh, Supriya Sau, Sagar Mitra, Indrajit Mukhopadhyay, Abhijit Ray, Cell Reports Physical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406143605

                Highlights&#8226;Self-supported, binder-free Ni surface alloy bifunctional electrocatalyst for hydrogen&#8226;Electrodes with industrial current density at low applied electrical bias&#8226;No significant loss of current after 30 h of testingSummaryDeveloping non-noble electrocatalysts for efficient water splitting remains a significant challenge. This study reports a selenized intermetallic-like surface alloy, Ni0.91Mo0.09, directly grown on Ni foam (NF), as a highly active electrode. A hierarchical stack of Ni3Se4/Ni0.91Mo0.09 interfaces is fabricated on porous NF (NiMoSe/NF) through Se diffusion into an electrodeposited (Ni-Mo) alloy via rapid thermal annealing. Experimental studies, supported by theoretical calculations, reveal that these interfaces provide abundant active sites, optimize hydrogen and oxygen absorption free energy, and facilitate efficient electron transfer for hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. The porous structure enhances mass transport, further boosting performance. The Ni3Se4/Ni0.91Mo0.09@NF heterostructure achieves 50 and 100 mA cm&#8315;2 at overpotentials of 62 and 116 mV for hydrogen evolution and 208 and 348 mV for oxygen evolution, respectively, in 0.5 M H&#8322;SO&#8324;, with stability over 60 h of continuous H&#8322; evolution.Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Naznin Shaikh, Supriya Sau, Sagar Mitra, Indrajit Mukhopadhyay, Abhijit Ray</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secondary Coordination Effects of Adjacent Metal Center in Metal-Nitrogen-Carbon Improve Scaling Relation of Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3mjc9-v2</link>
      <description>Ke Ye, Yulan Han, Min Hu, P. Hu, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084263

                Heterogenous single-atom catalysts (SACs) are reminescent of homogenous catalysts because of similarity of structural motif of active sites, showing the potential of using the advantage of homogenous catalysts to tackle challenges in hetereogenous catalysis. In heterogeneous oxygen electrocatalysis, the homogeneity of adsorption patterns of reaction intermediates leads to scaling relationships that limit their activities. In contrast, homogeneous catalysts can circumvent such limits by selectively altering the adsorption of intermediates through secondary coordination effects (SCE). This inspired us to explored potential SCE in metal-nitrogen-carbon (M-N-C), a promising type of oxygen evolution electrocatalysts. We introduced SCE with a neighboring metal site, which can modulate the adsorption strengths of oxygen-containing intermediates. First-principles calculations show that the second site in heteronuclear duo four-nitrogen-coordinated metal-center can induce SCE that selectively stabilize the OOH intermediate, but with minor effects on the OH intermediate, and thereby, disrupt scaling relation between oxygen-species, and eventually increase the catalytic activity in oxygen evolution reactions. Additionally, the activity of oxygen reduction reaction of selected M-N-C is also enhanced by such SCE. Our computational work underscored the critical role SCE can have in shaping activities of SACs, particularly in altering scaling relationships favorably, and demonstrated its potential of addressing catalytic challenges in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Ke Ye, Yulan Han, Min Hu, P. Hu, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3mjc9-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approaching Theoretical Limit of &lt;scp&gt;T&lt;/scp&gt;a&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;scp&gt;N&lt;/scp&gt;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanode via Photothermal&#8208;Accelerating Kinetics with Full&#8208;Spectrum Utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12868</link>
      <description>Yi Liu, Yanwei Zhang, Yicheng Wang, Xiaopeng Zhan, Peng&#8208;Fei Sui, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Chenyu Xu, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406133714

                Tantalum nitride is widely considered as a promising photoanode material for its suitable band structure as well as the high theoretical conversion efficiency in solar water splitting. However, it is limited to inefficient photoinduced electron&#8211;hole pair separation and interfacial dynamics in the photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution reaction. Herein, multiple layers including Ti x Si y and NiFeCoO x were fabricated based on band engineering to regulate tandem electric states for efficient transfer of energy carriers. Besides, photothermal local surface plasmon resonance was introduced to accelerate the kinetics of photoelectrochemical reactions at the interface when the special Ag nanoparticles were loaded to extend the absorbance to near infrared light. Consequently, a recordable photocurrent density of 12.73 mA cm &#8722;2 has been achieved at 1.23 V versus RHE, approaching a theoretical limit of the tantalum nitride photoanode with full&#8208;spectrum solar utilization. Meanwhile, compared to the applied bias photon&#8208;to&#8208;current efficiency of 1.36% without photothermal factor, a high applied bias photon&#8208;to&#8208;current efficiency of 2.27% could be raised by applying local surface plasmon resonance to photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution reaction. The efficient design could maximize the use of solar light via the classification of spectrum and, therefore, may spark more innovative ideas for the future design and development of the next&#8208;generation photoelectrode.</description>
      <author>Yi Liu, Yanwei Zhang, Yicheng Wang, Xiaopeng Zhan, Peng&#8208;Fei Sui, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Chenyu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Confined Mo Doped Cop for Alkali Overall Water Splitting with Enhanced Catalytic Activity and Durability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5081107</link>
      <description>Jiabing Luo, Yongxiao Tuo, Jianchao Zhang, Wenle Li, Shutao Wang, Yanpeng Li, Yuan Pan, Yan Zhou, Jun Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406049491

                The development of efficient and low-cost overall water splitting electrocatalysts for an anion exchange membrane (AEM) electrolyzer is desirable for hydrogen production. The control of geometrical and electronical structure of electrocatalysts can improve the catalytic efficiency in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and durability in oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Spacially confined growth and heteroatom doping can achieve this prospection of the target electrocatalysts. Herein, we prepared a carbon-shell confined Mo-doped CoP electrocatalyst (Mo-CoP@C) via anion adsorption coupled pyrolytic phosphorization method. A Metal-Organic Framework (MOF) of Co was used to achieve Mo6+ doping and carbon-shell-confined-growth. Mo ion doping significantly altered the electronic structure of CoP, which produced a local polarized environment for water dissociation during alkali HER process. Meanwhile, the carbon framework confined the growth of Mo-CoP and provide protective layer to durable OER process. Consequently, Mo-CoP@C exhibits attractive alkaline electrocatalytic HER and OER activities with the overpotentials of 122 and 280 mV at 0.01 A cm-2. Finally, the assembled Mo-CoP@C-CP&#8214;Mo-CoP@C-TFF AEM electrolyzer could operate for 500 h at 0.1 A cm-2.</description>
      <author>Jiabing Luo, Yongxiao Tuo, Jianchao Zhang, Wenle Li, Shutao Wang, Yanpeng Li, Yuan Pan, Yan Zhou, Jun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5081107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Regulation by Fe-Doped CoP&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Hydrophilic Self-Supported Nanorod Arrays as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Superior Overall Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c09394</link>
      <description>Bo Sun, Luchen Wang, Chunhu Li, Xiangchao Meng, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406025901

                To address the challenge of designing a highly reactive and stable bifunctional electrocatalyst for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), a hydrophilic Fe-CoPx nanorod array on nickel foam (NF) was designed and prepared in this work. The modulation of a d-band center of Co by adding Fe effectively optimized the adsorption energy of intermediates. The synergistic effect of the bimetallic active sites significantly enhanced the electrocatalytic performance for both reactions. In alkaline seawater, Fe-CoPx/NF exhibited excellent HER (&#8722;32 mV at &#8722;10 mA cm&#8211;2) and OER (216 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2) activities, maintaining stability for over 100 h at 100 mA cm&#8211;2. For overall seawater electrolysis, the catalyst achieved a low cell voltage of 1.54 V at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, outperforming the conventional RuO2&#8741;Pt/C electrode (1.58 V at 10 mA cm&#8211;2). Additionally, in a simulated industrial flow cell, the catalyst operated stably for over 200 h at 100 mA cm&#8211;2, indicating its strong potential for practical applications. This study introduced a simple synthesis method for bimetallic phosphides, providing a new avenue for the design of high-performance bifunctional catalysts for seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Bo Sun, Luchen Wang, Chunhu Li, Xiangchao Meng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c09394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Synthesis of Ternary Ni-Fe-Mo Nanosheet Arrays for OER in Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30010177</link>
      <description>Zhi L&#252;, Yifan Guo, Shilin Li, Jiaqi Ding, Yingzi Ren, Kun Tang, Jiefeng Wang, Chang&#8208;Jiu Li, Zhan Shi, Ziqi Sun, Hongbo Meng, Guangxin Wang, Molecules. 30(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084377

                Water electrolysis is a promising path to the industrialization development of hydrogen energy. The exploitation of high-efficiency and inexpensive catalysts become important to the mass use of water decomposition. Ni-based nanomaterials have exhibited great potential for the catalysis of water splitting, which have attracted the attention of researchers around the world. Here, we prepared a novel Mo-doped NiFe-based layered double hydroxide (LDH) with a nanoarray microstructure on Ni foam. The doping amount of Mo can significantly change the microstructure of the electrocatalysis, which will further affect the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of water splitting. This novel nanomaterial required only an overpotential of 227 mV for 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 54.8 mV/dec in 1 M KOH. Meanwhile, there was no Mo, and the NiFe-LDH needed 233 mV to attain to 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Compared to the NiFe-LDH without Mo, the NiFeMo-LDH nanosheet arrays exhibited enhanced activities with 17.1 mV/dec less Tafel in OER. The good performance of the electrocatalyst is ascribed to the special nanosheet arrays and the heterostructure of the Ni-Fe-Mo system. These features help to increase the active surface, enhancing the efficient charge transfer and the reactive activity in OER.</description>
      <author>Zhi L&#252;, Yifan Guo, Shilin Li, Jiaqi Ding, Yingzi Ren, Kun Tang, Jiefeng Wang, Chang&#8208;Jiu Li, Zhan Shi, Ziqi Sun, Hongbo Meng, Guangxin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30010177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D Co&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;C&#8208;Based Heterojunctional Nanowires from Pyrolytically &#8220;Squeezing&#8221; PMo&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;/ZIF&#8208;67 Cubes for Efficient Overall Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409703</link>
      <description>Xinhui Zhang, Aiping Wu, Dongxu Wang, Ying Xie, Alexander I. Gubanov, Gennadiy &#1040;. &#1050;&#1086;stin, Chungui Tian, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406115361

                Abstract The bi&#8208;transition&#8208;metal interstitial compounds (BTMICs) are promising for water electrolysis. The previous BTMICs are usually composed of irregular particles. Here, this work shows the synthesis of novel 1D Co 6 Mo 6 C&#8208;based heterojunction nanowires (1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C) with diameters about 50 nm and a length&#8208;to&#8208;diameter ratio about 20 for efficient water electrolysis. An interesting growth process based on pyrolytically &#8220;squeezing&#8221; PMo 12 (Phosphomolybdic acid)/ZIF&#8208;67 (Zeolitic Imidazolate Framework&#8208;67) cube precursor is demonstrated. The &#8220;squeezing&#8221; growth is related to the role of Mo species for isolating Co species. A series of tests and theoretical calculation show the mutual regulation of Co and Mo to optimize the electronic structure, accelerating H 2 O dissociation and the reduction kinetics of H + . Additionally, the nanowires provide pathways for electron transfer and the transmission of reactants. Consequently, the 1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C exhibits high activity for hydrogen evolution reaction ( &#951; 10 of 31 mV) and oxygen evolution reaction ( &#951; 10 of 210 mV) in 1 m KOH. The electrolytic cell based on 1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C requires a low voltage of 1.43 V to drive 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . The catalyst also exhibits good HER performance in 1 m phosphate&#8208;buffered saline solution, exceeding Pt/C at a current density &gt;42 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Xinhui Zhang, Aiping Wu, Dongxu Wang, Ying Xie, Alexander I. Gubanov, Gennadiy &#1040;. &#1050;&#1086;stin, Chungui Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Spin&#8208;Polarized Nanosheet Array for Boosting Ampere&#8208;Level Water Oxidation Under Magnetic Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420810</link>
      <description>Haifan Li, Quan Quan, Hongliang Dong, Yuxuan Zhang, Pengshan Xie, Dong Chen, Di Yin, Chun&#8208;Yuen Wong, Johnny C. Ho, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126967

                Abstract The spin&#8208;polarization strategy by manipulating magnetic electrocatalysts can promote the spin&#8208;sensitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER) while developing efficient spin&#8208;polarized materials toward ampere&#8208;level OER is still challenging. Herein, a hierarchical inter&#8208;doped (Ru&#8208;Ni)O x nanosheet array in situ grown on nickel foam is designed, which exhibits a distinguished overpotential of 286 mV at 1 A cm &#8722;2 under 0.4 T magnetic field and a steady lifespan of 200 h at the ampere current density (i.e., 1 A cm &#8722;2 ), outperforming most reported state&#8208;of&#8208;art spin&#8208;selective OER catalysts in alkaline electrolytes Integrating intrinsic and interfacial spin&#8208;polarization on the inter&#8208;doped (Ru&#8208;Ni)O x nanosheet array can significantly boost the catalytic activity for ampere&#8208;level OER under a magnetic field. Specifically, the spin&#8208;aligned Ru sites optimize the rate&#8208;determined O&#9472;O coupling step to reduce the thermodynamic barrier of OER. Meanwhile, the charge transfer kinetics is promoted due to the accelerating spin&#8208;selective electron transfer via spin pinning at the ferromagnetic&#8208;antiferromagnetic interface. The design of a hierarchical spin&#8208;polarized structure that integrates intrinsic and interfacial spin&#8208;polarization strategies provides an additional route to developing a spin&#8208;polarized OER catalyst capable of serving ampere current densities.</description>
      <author>Haifan Li, Quan Quan, Hongliang Dong, Yuxuan Zhang, Pengshan Xie, Dong Chen, Di Yin, Chun&#8208;Yuen Wong, Johnny C. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420810</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage Regulation of &#946;-Ketoamine Covalent Organic Frameworks for Boosting Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20472</link>
      <description>Yiwen Yang, Hong&#8208;Da Ren, Hanyu Zhang, Yingnan Zhao, Huaqiao Tan, Zhongling Lang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406134747

                Two dimensional &#946;-ketoamine covalent organic frameworks (2D TP-COFs) are one category of promising metal-free catalysts for photocatalytic overall water splitting (OWS) because of their unusual stability and versatile electronic/optical properties. However, none of the currently reported TP-COFs can accomplish the hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER) simultaneously without adding any sacrificial agents and cocatalysts. To address this challenging issue, we rationally designed 23 2D TP-COFs by regulating the linkage groups and comprehensively evaluated their OWS activity by using the first-principles method. First, the electronic band structure calculations at the HSE06 level reveal that the band gap can be reasonably adjusted with values ranging from 1.67&#8211;3.16 eV. Among these 23 systems, 10 TP-COFs are realized to match well with both the chemical potentials of H2/H+ and O2/H2O, which are capable of visible-light-driven OWS from an electronic perspective. Further thermal activity results on OWS demonstrate that only Hep-BDA (heptazine-aniline) and Bpy-4 (bipyrimidinamine) based COFs can satisfy the completely spontaneous of HER and OER under light irradiation and neutral conditions. Importantly, the calculated small exciton binding energies and high carrier mobility for Hep-BDA and Bpy-4 TP-COFs propose they are potentially applied in photocatalytic OWS. We also achieved the theoretical energy conversion efficiency of Hep-BDA can reach as high as 13.01%. Because there are very few successful applications of TP-COFs on OWS, this theoretical work not only offers valuable insights and innovative ideas for the exploration of novel metal-free photocatalysts for OWS but also supplies a direction for the development of new TP-COF derivatives.</description>
      <author>Yiwen Yang, Hong&#8208;Da Ren, Hanyu Zhang, Yingnan Zhao, Huaqiao Tan, Zhongling Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Nitrate&#8208;to&#8208;Ammonia Conversion and Sulfion Oxidation Reaction Over Hierarchical Porous Spinel MFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; (M&#9552;Ni, Co, Fe, Mn) in Wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411317</link>
      <description>Junyang Ding, Lang Zhang, Zihao Wei, Zhifeng Wang, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Jun Luo, Xijun Liu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406127030

                Abstract The construction of coupled electrolysis systems utilizing renewable energy sources for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction and sulfion oxidation reactions (NO 3 RR and SOR), is considered a promising approach for environmental remediation, ammonia production, and sulfur recovery. Here, a simple chemical dealloying method is reported to fabricate a hierarchical porous multi&#8208;metallic spinel MFe 2 O 4 (M&#9552;Ni, Co, Fe, Mn) dual&#8208;functional electrocatalysts consisting of Mn&#8208;doped porous NiFe 2 O 4 /CoFe 2 O 4 heterostructure networks and Ni/Co/Mn co&#8208;doped Fe 3 O 4 nanosheet networks. The excellent NO 3 RR with high NH 3 Faradaic efficiency of 95.2% at &#8208;0.80 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs RHE) and NH 3 yield rate of 608.9 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 at &#8722;1.60 V vs RHE, and impressive SOR performance (100 mA cm &#8722;2@0.98 V vs RHE) is achieved for MFe 2 O 4 . Key intermediates such as * NO, * NH 2 , and NH 3 are identified in the NO 3 RR process by in situ Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (in situ FTIR). The MFe 2 O 4 &#8208;assembled two&#8208;electrode coupling system (NO 3 RR||SOR) shows an ultra&#8208;low cell voltage of 1.14 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , much lower than the NO 3 RR||OER (oxygen evolution reaction, 10 mA cm &#8722;2@2.62 V), simultaneously achieving two expected targets of value&#8208;added ammonia generation and sulfur recovery, and also demonstrating high durability of 18 h. This work also demonstrates the great potential of spinel ferrite&#8208;based catalysts for environmental remediation.</description>
      <author>Junyang Ding, Lang Zhang, Zihao Wei, Zhifeng Wang, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Jun Luo, Xijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work-biased path-sampling calculations of chemical potentials: Principles and applications to uranium oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229575</link>
      <description>Orane Barbour, Jean-Paul Crocombette, Theo Beigbedder, Julien Tranchida, Manuel Ath&#232;nes, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406153043

                We present the work-biased path-sampling scheme to calculate chemical potentials in atomic scale simulations. This scheme is based on a series of chained insertion and deletion paths from N to N + 1 to N atom systems, the sampling being performed on the paths themselves rather than on the final configurations. Equations for parallel path generations as well as geometrically biased insertions or deletions are presented. We then present two applications of our approach for the uranium dioxide crystal. The first is a test case validation of our approach for the insertion of a Xe atom in UO2. The second explores the relationship between cluster structure stability and oxygen chemical potential in overstoichiometric UO2+x oxide as a function of temperature from 800 to 2000 K and composition, from UO2 to UO2.16, using two different empirical potentials. We find that the evolution of the oxygen chemical potential is irregular, with dips for specific numbers of added oxygen atoms. Five oxygen clusters are stable at 800 K and are associated with strong dips in the chemical potential values. At intermediate temperatures, clusters of four and five oxygen atoms compete in stability. They become unstable at the highest temperatures, and the evolution of the chemical potential is then monotonous with composition.</description>
      <author>Orane Barbour, Jean-Paul Crocombette, Theo Beigbedder, Julien Tranchida, Manuel Ath&#232;nes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure formed by Y2O3-doping in lithium position assists improvement of charging-voltage for high-nickel cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52768-7</link>
      <description>Shijie Wang, Kang Liang, Hongshun Zhao, Min Wu, Junfeng He, Peng Wei, Zhengping Ding, Jianbin Li, Xiaobing Huang, Yurong Ren, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406003536

                High-capacity power battery can be attained through the elevation of the cut-off voltage for LiNi0.83Co0.12Mn0.05O2 high-nickel material. Nevertheless, unstable lattice oxygen would be released during the lithium deep extraction. To solve the above issues, the electronic structure is reconstructed by substituting Li+ ions with Y3+ ions. The dopant within the Li layer could transfer electrons to the adjacent lattice oxygen. Subsequently, the accumulated electrons in the oxygen site are transferred to nickel of highly valence state under the action of the reduction coupling mechanism. The modified strategy suppresses the generation of oxygen defects by regulating the local electronic structure, but more importantly, it reduces the concentration of highly reactive Ni4+ species during the charging state, thus avoiding the evolution of an unexpected phase transition. Strengthening the coupling strength between the lithium layers and transition metal layers finally realizes the fast-charging performance improvement and the cycling stability enhancement under high voltage. Authors report on restructuring the electronic structure of a high-nickel material by substituting Li+ ions with Y3+ ions. This strategy suppresses the generation of oxygen defects with a reduction coupling mechanism improving high-voltage stability.</description>
      <author>Shijie Wang, Kang Liang, Hongshun Zhao, Min Wu, Junfeng He, Peng Wei, Zhengping Ding, Jianbin Li, Xiaobing Huang, Yurong Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52768-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cocktail Effect of 4&lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;/5&lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt; Band Twisted High&#8208;Entropy Alloys on Carbon Nanotube for Hydrazine Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410304</link>
      <description>Chae Eun Park, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, V. Maheskumar, Anuj Kumar, Gyoung Hwa Jeong, Myong Yong Choi, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406112406

                Herein, multi-walled carbon nanotubes (CNT) embedded with RuPdIrPtAu-high entropy alloys (HEA) via pulsed laser irradiation in liquids are successfully fabricated. The resultant composite synergistically enhances hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR)-boosted water electrolysis. Notably, HEA with &#8776;2-5 nm size, are uniformly distributed across the surface of the CNTs. An optimized HEA/CNT-10 demonstrates exceptional performance in oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions (OER and HER), depicted by ultralow overpotentials of 30.7 and 330 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Chae Eun Park, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, V. Maheskumar, Anuj Kumar, Gyoung Hwa Jeong, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactive Oxygen Species Resistive Redox Mediator in Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202415805</link>
      <description>Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Jiwon Hwang, Ja&#8208;Yeong Kim, Gabriel N. Morais, Katie S. Tang, Myungsoo Choi, Haeun Choi, H. S. Youn, Seoung&#8208;Tae Kim, Jee Ho Ha, Seok Ju Kang, Shuming Chen, Sung&#8208;Eun Suh, Won&#8208;Jin Kwak, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406020532

                Abstract The utilization of redox mediators (RMs) in lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries (LOBs) has underscored their utility in high overpotential during the charging process. Among the currently known RMs, it is exceptionally challenging to identify those with a redox potential capable of attenuating singlet oxygen ( 1 O 2 ) generation while resisting degradation by reactive oxygen species (ROS), such as 1 O 2 and superoxide (O 2 &#8226;&#8722; ). In this context, computational and experimental approaches for rational molecular design have led to the development of 7,7&#8242;&#8208;bi&#8208;7&#8208;azabicyclo[2.2.1]heptane (BAC), a newly suggested RM incorporating N&#8211;N interconnected aza&#8208;bicycles. BAC harnesses the advantages of falling within the potential range that suppresses 1 O 2 generation, as previously reported N&#8211;N embedded non&#8208;bicyclic RMs, and effectively defends against ROS&#8208;induced degradation due to the incorporation of a novel bicyclic moiety. Unlike the non&#8208;bicyclic RMs, which exhibit reduced O 2 evolution after exposure to 1 O 2 , BAC maintains consistent O 2 profiles during charging, indicating its superior 1 O 2 resistance and steady redox&#8208;catalyst performance in LOBs. This study introduces a precise and rational design strategy for low&#8208;molecular&#8208;weight RMs, marking a significant step forward in advancing LOB development by improving efficiency, stability, and practical applicability.</description>
      <author>Hyun&#8208;Wook Lee, Jiwon Hwang, Ja&#8208;Yeong Kim, Gabriel N. Morais, Katie S. Tang, Myungsoo Choi, Haeun Choi, H. S. Youn, Seoung&#8208;Tae Kim, Jee Ho Ha, Seok Ju Kang, Shuming Chen, Sung&#8208;Eun Suh, Won&#8208;Jin Kwak</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202415805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation and evolution of inclusions in Q355B steel deoxidised with silicon and manganese</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233241307463</link>
      <description>Chao Xue, Weili Xu, Fengchun Fan, Lihua Zhao, Yanping Bao, Yueqin Xu, Ironmaking &amp; Steelmaking Processes Products and Applications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406019759

                Q355B is extensively utilised owing to its superior mechanical properties. Nevertheless, the inclusions generated during the deoxidation process with aluminium and the treatment with calcium in steelmaking can profoundly influence these properties. Consequently, this study explores the inclusions formed during the manufacturing process of Q355B utilising silicon&#8211;manganese deoxidation alloys in an industrial setting. Furthermore, this research evaluates the deoxidation efficacy of the silicon&#8211;manganese alloy and elucidates the fluctuations in oxygen and nitrogen concentrations throughout the entire process. This study further investigates the types, number density, size, morphology and transformation processes of the inclusions generated throughout the Q355B production using silicon&#8211;manganese deoxidation alloy; additionally, electrolytic treatment was performed on the cast billets to extract large inclusions. The findings reveal that the deoxidation efficiency of the SiMn alloy is enhanced at relatively low temperatures and with a high manganese-to-silicon ratio. The predominant cause for the increase in total oxygen content in the molten steel during the smelting process is the exposure of the molten steel to secondary oxidation. Manganese&#8211;silicon deoxidation adequately fulfils the production requirements for Q355B. Oxide inclusions predominantly comprise Si&#8211;Mn-type oxides and their evolved inclusions; during the evolution process, aluminium-containing spinels generate calcium aluminium silicates in conjunction with CaO present in the slag. The number density of inclusions consistently decreases; however, it may subsequently increase due to secondary oxidation and slag entrapment. Throughout the evolution process, inclusions continuously aggregate and grow, resulting in an increasing proportion of large inclusions, while small-sized sulphide inclusions precipitate during the continuous casting process. The analysis of the isothermal ternary phase diagram of the slag system, in conjunction with the electrolytic results of the cast billets, confirms the occurrence of secondary oxidation and slag entrapment during the smelting process. Thermodynamic software calculations elucidate the formation and evolution of composite inclusions, offering critical insights for composition control to mitigate the associated hazards of composite inclusions. Thermodynamic and kinetic calculations of precipitates clarify the solidification conditions and temperature required for the precipitation of MnS, demonstrating that the size of the precipitates is negatively correlated with the cooling rate and positively correlated with the concentration of the strongly segregated element sulphur.</description>
      <author>Chao Xue, Weili Xu, Fengchun Fan, Lihua Zhao, Yanping Bao, Yueqin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/03019233241307463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the iodine cycle and the late stabilization of the Earth&#8217;s ozone layer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2412898121</link>
      <description>Jingjun Liu, Dalton Hardisty, James F. Kasting, Mojtaba Fakhraee, Noah J. Planavsky, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406110855

                The origin of complex life and the evolution of terrestrial ecosystems are fundamental aspects of the natural history on Earth. Here, we present evidence for a protracted stabilization of the Earth&#8217;s ozone layer. The destruction of atmospheric ozone today is inherently linked to the cycling of marine and atmospheric iodine. Supported by multiple independent lines of geological evidence and examined through an iodine mass balance model, we find that elevated marine iodide content prevailed through most of Earth&#8217;s history. Since the rise of oxygen ~2.4 billion years ago, high marine iodide concentrations would have led to significant inorganic iodine emissions to the atmosphere, facilitating catalytic ozone destruction and resulting in atmospheric ozone instability with periodic or persistently lower ozone levels. At a global scale, unstable and low ozone levels likely persisted for about two billion years until the early Phanerozoic, roughly 0.5 billion years ago. The delayed stabilization of the Earth&#8217;s ozone layer holds significant implications for the tempo and direction of the evolution of life, in particular life on land.</description>
      <author>Jingjun Liu, Dalton Hardisty, James F. Kasting, Mojtaba Fakhraee, Noah J. Planavsky</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2412898121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of returning a sample of the Martian atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2404258121</link>
      <description>T. D. Swindle, Andreas Pack, S. P. Schwenzer, Edward Young, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406110845

                The elemental and isotopic abundances of major species in the Martian atmosphere have been determined, but analyses often lack sufficient precision, and those of minor and trace species are frequently not well known. Many important questions about the evolution and current state of Mars require the kind of knowledge that can be gained from analysis of a returned sample of the Martian atmosphere. Key target species include the noble gases, nitrogen, and various species containing carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen, such as methane. More detailed analyses will no doubt provide measurements of other species that will allow insights of their own. These volatiles can constrain the origin of the Martian atmosphere, exchange of volatiles between the surface and interior, polar processes, and (in the case of methane) the possibility of extant biology on Mars.</description>
      <author>T. D. Swindle, Andreas Pack, S. P. Schwenzer, Edward Young</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2404258121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of cancer cell volatile organic compounds: their metabolism and evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmolb.2024.1499104</link>
      <description>Takeshi Furuhashi, Kanako Toda, Wolfram Weckwerth, Frontiers in Molecular Biosciences. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406129860

                Cancer is ranked as the top cause of premature mortality. Volatile organic compounds (VOCs) are produced from catalytic peroxidation by reactive oxygen species (ROS) and have become a highly attractive non-invasive cancer screening approach. For future clinical applications, however, the correlation between cancer hallmarks and cancer-specific VOCs requires further study. This review discusses and compares cellular metabolism, signal transduction as well as mitochondrial metabolite translocation in view of cancer evolution and the basic biology of VOCs production. Certain cancerous characteristics as well as the origin of the ROS removal system date back to procaryotes and early eukaryotes and share commonalities with non-cancerous proliferative cells. This calls for future studies on metabolic cross talks and regulation of the VOCs production pathway.</description>
      <author>Takeshi Furuhashi, Kanako Toda, Wolfram Weckwerth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmolb.2024.1499104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Oxidation Mechanisms of High&#8208;entropy Carbides Through Atomic&#8208;scale Dynamic Observation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417846</link>
      <description>Lei Zhuang, Zihao Wen, Yiwen Liu, Jing Yang, Hulei Yu, Yanhui Chu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405994380

                Abstract Understanding the behavior of high&#8208;entropy carbides (HECs) under oxygen&#8208;containing environments is of particular importance for their promising applications in structural components, catalysis, and energy&#8208;related fields. Herein, the structural evolution of (Ta, Ti, Cr, Nb)C (HEC&#8208;1) nanoparticles (NPs) is tracked in situ during the oxidation at the atomic scale by using an open&#8208;cell environmental aberration&#8208;corrected scanning transmission electron microscope. Three key stages are clearly discerned during the oxidation of HEC&#8208;1 NPs at the atomic level below 900 &#176;C: i) increased amorphization of HEC&#8208;1 NPs from 300 to 500 &#176;C due to the energetically favorable formation of carbon vacancies and substitution of carbon with oxygen atoms; ii) nucleation and subsequent growth of locally ordered nanocluster intermediates within the generated amorphous oxides from 500 to 800 &#176;C; and iii) final one&#8208;step crystallization of non&#8208;equimolar MeO 2 and Me 2 O 5 (Me = metallic elements, Ta, Ti, Cr, and Nb) high&#8208;entropy oxides above 800 &#176;C, accompanied with the reduction in atomic defects. This result is further confirmed by theoretical calculations that these observed high&#8208;entropy oxide phases are thermodynamically preferable to generate above 830 &#176;C. The study provides direct evidence of the ordered&#8211;disordered&#8211;ordered structural transition of HECs during oxidation.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhuang, Zihao Wen, Yiwen Liu, Jing Yang, Hulei Yu, Yanhui Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202417846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Effect of Shape Anisotropy of Plasmonic Tungsten Oxide Nanostructures for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02233</link>
      <description>G. A. Davis, Brian C. Wyatt, Barry B. Muhoberac, Rajesh Sardar, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406094095

                Platinum is the most efficient electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER); however, the lack of earth abundance and high cost restrict its widespread use. Herein, we report electrocatalytic HER efficacy of oxygen-deficient, localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR)-active tungsten-oxide (WO3&#8211;x) nanocrystals (NCs) as a function of free conduction electron density and metal oxidation states. These plasmonic, anisotropic WO3&#8211;x NCs display &#8764;160 mV overpotential at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and a Tafel slope of 54 mV/dec. Ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopic measurements support the HER electrocatalytic properties attributed to the Fermi energy pinning as a function of the NC shape (i.e., nanowires, nanorods, and nanoplatelets) and chemical composition of the inorganic WO3&#8211;x lattice. Furthermore, our experimental data show that increasing the number of coordinatively unsaturated tungsten sites, which are generated from the ionization of surface oxygen atoms in WO3&#8211;x NCs, improves the surface reactivity and thus, enhances the catalytic performance. Together, structure&#8211;property relationship delineating the NC morphology and the resulting optoelectronic properties studied here provide the opportunity to unravel the correlation between the NC shape, free conduction electron density and the HER kinetics of this unique class of NC and to potentially initiate the designer principle of noble metal-free, highly active, but not limited to HER catalysts to produce an energy-dense fuel.</description>
      <author>G. A. Davis, Brian C. Wyatt, Barry B. Muhoberac, Rajesh Sardar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factors influencing osteoradionecrosis progression during hyperbaric oxygen therapy: A case study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.155112.2</link>
      <description>Sameh Mezri, Chaima Zitouni, Khadija Bahrini, Mounir Haggui, Wiem Boughzala, H&#233;di Gharsallah, F1000Research. 13(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405989792

                Introduction Although relatively uncommon, osteoradionecrosis (ORN) remains a serious complication following radiotherapy. Various therapeutic approaches, including hyperbaric oxygen therapy (HBOT), are utilized in managing ORN. This study aims to evaluate the role of HBOT in ORN management and to identify predictive factors influencing the evolution of head and neck ORN after HBOT. Methods This retrospective study includes 46 patients who received HBOT for head and neck ORN between 2017 and 2020. The patients were divided into two groups: Group 1 (n=36) included those with regression or stabilization of ORN, while Group 2 (n=10) comprised patients with worsening lesions. We performed a statistical study in order to identify factors influencing ORN progression under treatment. Results ORN affected the mandible in 93.5% of patients, the maxilla in 2 cases, and the skull base in 4 cases. All patients received HBOT, with an average of 44.65 sessions. Pre-operative HBOT was administered in 17% of cases, and post-operative HBOT was given in 42% of cases. After at least 20 sessions, ORN regressed in 33% of cases, stabilized in 45%, and worsened in 22%. Analysis of factors influencing ORN progression on the univariate study revealed significant associations with high blood pressure (p=0.046), larger tumor size (p=0.004), advanced tumor stages (p=0.048), mean radiation dose (p=0.002), delays between dental care and radiotherapy (p=0.045), and the location of ORN within the mandible (p=0.049). Additionally, the number of HBOT sessions significantly affected ORN evolution, with more sessions correlating with better outcomes (p=0.001). In the multivariate analysis, variables such as the average interval between dental care and radiotherapy (p=0.043) as well as the number of HBOT sessions (p=0.040) emerged as significant influencers of ORN evolution. Conclusion Our study provides valuable insights into the management of ORN by identifying key predictors that influence the post-therapeutic evolution of head and neck ORN after HBOT.</description>
      <author>Sameh Mezri, Chaima Zitouni, Khadija Bahrini, Mounir Haggui, Wiem Boughzala, H&#233;di Gharsallah</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12688/f1000research.155112.2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of FLASH dose-rate and oxygen concentration in the production of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in cellular-like media versus water: a Monte Carlo track-structure study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6560/ada517</link>
      <description>J Naoki D-Kondo, Damian Borys, Antoni Ruci&#324;ski, B. Brzozowska, Thongchai A. M. Masilela, Magdalena Grochowska-Tatarczak, Magdalena W&#281;grzyn, Jos&#233; Ramos&#8208;M&#233;ndez, Physics in Medicine and Biology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406024564

                Abstract To study the effect of dose-rate in the time evolution of chemical yields produced in pure water versus a cellular-like environment for FLASH radiotherapy research. &amp;#xD;A version of TOPAS-nBio with Tau-Leaping algorithm was used to simulate the homogenous chemistry stage of water radiolysis using three chemical models: 1) liquid water model that considered scavenging of eaq-, H&#9679; by dissolved oxygen; 2) Michaels &amp; Hunt model that considered scavenging of &#9679;OH, eaq-, and H&#9679; by biomolecules existing in cellular environment; 3) Wardman model that considered model 2) and the chemical repair enzyme glutathione (GHS). H2O2 concentrations at conventional and FLASH dose-rates were compared with published measurements. Model 3) was used to estimate DNA single-strand break (SSB) yields and compared with published data. SSBs were estimated from simulated yields of DNA hydrogen abstraction and attenuation factors to account for the scavenging capacity of the medium. The simulation setup consisted of monoenergetic protons (100 MeV) delivered in pulses at conventional (0.2857Gy s&#8315;&#185;) and FLASH (500Gy s&#8315;&#185;) dose rates. Dose varied from 5-20Gy, and oxygen concentration from 10&#181;M-1mM.&amp;#xD;At the steady state, for model 1), H2O2 concentration differed by 81.5%&#177;4.0% between FLASH and conventional dose-rates. For models 2) and 3) the differences were within 8.0%&#177;4.8%, and calculated SSB yields agreed with published data within 3.8%&#177;1.2%. A maximum oxygen concentration difference of 60% and 50% for models 2) and 3) between conventional and FLASH dose-rates was found between 2&#61620;106 and 9&#61620;1013 ps for 20 Gy of absorbed dose.&amp;#xD;The findings highlight the importance of developing more advanced cellular models to account for both the chemical and biological factors that comprise the FLASH effect. It was found that differences between pure water and cellular environment models were significant and extrapolating results between the two should be avoided. Observed differences call for further experimental investigation.</description>
      <author>J Naoki D-Kondo, Damian Borys, Antoni Ruci&#324;ski, B. Brzozowska, Thongchai A. M. Masilela, Magdalena Grochowska-Tatarczak, Magdalena W&#281;grzyn, Jos&#233; Ramos&#8208;M&#233;ndez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6560/ada517</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient Oxygen Vacancy-Enriched MD-NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;: A Surface Reactivity Descriptor for Energy-Saving Green Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02622</link>
      <description>Arokiadoss Davidrichetson, Dhanasingh Thiruvengadam, Ravichandran Nithiasri, Kuldeep Kumar, Jayaraman Jayabharathi, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406021633

                Herein, we report a simple mechanochemical dehydration (MD) method to synthesize MD-NiMoO4, which is treated with NaBH4 to generate oxygen vacancy-enriched MD-NiMoO4&#8211;SBH to understand the role of oxygen defects on water splitting performance. Among the as-prepared catalysts, MD-NiMoO4&#8211;SBH, MD-NiMoO4, MD-NiO, and MD-MoO, MD-NiMoO4&#8211;SBH exhibits superior activity by demanding a small overpotential (OER/HER) of 241/108 mV with a Tafel slope of 97/85 mV dec&#8211;1 (MD-NiMoO4: 293/156 mV; Tafel slope: 114/93 mV dec&#8211;1) and is stable for &#8764;100 h. The activation energies were calculated for electrolysis using MD-NiMoO4&#8211;SBH (32 kJ/mol) and MD-NiMoO4 (28 kJ/mol). The calculated integrated areas of 5.41 &#215; 10&#8211;5 AV (MD-NiMoO4&#8211;SBH) and 3.61 &#215; 10&#8211;5 AV (MD-NiMoO4) confirmed MOOH* formation, and the number of active sites was found to be 3.484 &#215; 10&#8211;16 (MD-NiMoO4) and 6.540 &#215; 10&#8211;16 (MD-NiMoO4&#8211;SBH). The superaerophobicity of MD-NiMoO4&#8211;SBH was corroborated by rapid gas bubble growth as well as fast evolution from the catalyst surface. The bifunctional electrolyzer with MD-NiMoO4&#8211;SBH (1.48 V) and MD-NiMoO4 (1.59 V) released vigorous gas bubbles in the alkaline electrolyte and exhibits robust durability, which could be employed in water splitting devices for practical utility. As observed from the electrochemical results, the MO theory reveals that the band gap state-assisted antibonding state formation, having low electron occupancy to favor OER and HER kinetics.</description>
      <author>Arokiadoss Davidrichetson, Dhanasingh Thiruvengadam, Ravichandran Nithiasri, Kuldeep Kumar, Jayaraman Jayabharathi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of superconductivity in &lt;mml:math xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML"&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;Sr&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;1&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;&#8722;&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;Eu&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;x&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:msub&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mi mathvariant="normal"&gt;CuO&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mrow&gt;&lt;mml:mn&gt;2&lt;/mml:mn&gt;&lt;mml:mo&gt;+&lt;/mml:mo&gt;&lt;mml:mi&gt;y&lt;/mml:mi&gt;&lt;/mml:mrow&gt;&lt;/&#8230;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.035405</link>
      <description>Hang Yan, Ze-Xian Deng, Xue-Qing Yu, Yanling Xiong, Qun Zhu, Ding Zhang, Can&#8208;Li Song, Xucun Ma, Qi-Kun Xue, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(3)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406049044

                We report transport measurements of infinite-layer cuprate Sr1&#8722;xEuxCuO2+y films with controlled electron (by trivalent europium) and hole (by interstitial apical oxygen) carriers grown on SrTiO3(001) with molecular beam epitaxy. An unusual enhancement of superconductivity upon the moderate coexistence of electron and hole carriers in the films is found, which spans over the whole superconducting phase diagram and becomes more prominent in the underdoped regime. The superconductivity exhibits a two-dimensional nature with a thickness of approximately 5.2 nm, irrespective of the varying carriers, confirmed by angle-resolved magnetoresistance measurements and the Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless transition. Nevertheless, the coexisting electron and hole carriers enlarge the thermal activation energy of vortex motion that deviates obviously from the usual logarithmic evolution with the magnetic field. Our results offer a promising perspective to understand and enhance the high-temperature superconductivity in cuprates. locked icon locked icon locked icon locked icon locked icon locked icon locked icon locked icon Physics Subject Headings (PhySH)MagnetoresistanceSuperconductivityCupratesSuperconductorsThin filmsResistivity measurements</description>
      <author>Hang Yan, Ze-Xian Deng, Xue-Qing Yu, Yanling Xiong, Qun Zhu, Ding Zhang, Can&#8208;Li Song, Xucun Ma, Qi-Kun Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.035405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of small RNAs under abiotic stress in plants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32523/2616-7034-2024-149-4-50-62</link>
      <description>Ahmad Asri Abd Samat, K.Ye. Zhanassova, Aigerim Soltabayeva, K. Syzdyk, A. Akbassova, S. Zhangazin, Aizat Bekturova, M. Beisekova, R.Zh. Yermukhambetova, Zh. Nurbekova, Zh. Masalimov, A. Kurmanbayeva, BULLETIN of the L N Gumilyov Eurasian National University BIOSCIENCE Series. 149(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406054208

                Small RNAs (sRNA) play an essential role in the epigenetic modulation of the genome. They are implicated in numerous processes, encompassing factors that mitigate both abiotic and biotic stressors. Notable among these are heat shock proteins (HSP), enzymes involved in reactive oxygen species (ROS) scavenging, and nuclear factor Y (NF-Y). Molecularly, sRNAs are characterized by sequences of approximately 21&#8211;23 nucleotides in length. Based on contemporary understandings in plant science, numerous abiotic constraints have the potential to curtail crop yield, growth, and reproductive potential in plants. These constraints exert their deleterious effects by undermining cellular homeostasis, perturbing ionic equilibrium, and impinging upon essential physiological processes. However, evolution has endowed certain plant species with the ability to adapt to elevated thermal conditions through the nuanced regulation of genes and proteins, notably heat shock factors (HSF) and HSP. While there has been an incremental growth in literature concerning microRNA (miRNA) functionality in plants, the emergent targets of miRNA and their intricate relationship with the HSF-HSP complex remain underexplored. In this scholarly review, we delve into the thermal responses of HSF-HSP in both Hordeum vulgare and Arabidopsis thaliana, emphasizing their regulation by miRNA under conditions of heat stress.</description>
      <author>Ahmad Asri Abd Samat, K.Ye. Zhanassova, Aigerim Soltabayeva, K. Syzdyk, A. Akbassova, S. Zhangazin, Aizat Bekturova, M. Beisekova, R.Zh. Yermukhambetova, Zh. Nurbekova, Zh. Masalimov, A. Kurmanbayeva</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32523/2616-7034-2024-149-4-50-62</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response Analysis of Microbial Community Structures and Functions Under Water and Sediment Changes in the Middle and Lower Yellow River</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/d17010041</link>
      <description>Ji Wu, Quan Hong, Jin Zhang, Chen Xie, Yang Liu, Dandan Li, Hao Liu, Ziwu Fan, Diversity. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406119047

                Safety and ecological health are restricted by the high amount of suspended sediment in the Yellow River. To solve the problems of the high sediment content and siltation in the Yellow River, the Xiaolangdi Reservoir (XLDR) has been carrying out water&#8211;sediment regulation (WSR) since 2002. To clarify the effects of the water and sediment changes caused by WSR on microbial communities, we analysed the composition of the microbial communities and functional groups in surface water and sediments before and after WSR using high-throughput sequencing and microbial functional annotation. Proteobacteria, Actinobacteria, Bacteroidetes, and Firmicutes were detected as the main microbial communities in the Yellow River&#8217;s middle and lower reaches. The water temperature (WT), dissolved oxygen (DO), total nitrogen (TN), total phosphorus (TP), and evolution of the microbial communities were all correlated (p &lt; 0.05). The biodiversity indices of the surface water and sediment microbes, respectively, greatly declined. The WSR programme broke down nutrients that had been adsorbed on the sediments, which diminished microbial metabolic activity and impaired the water bodies&#8217; capacity to purify themselves. In summary, this study provides the biological information needed for the ecological conservation of the Yellow River basin, as well as insights into the changes in and response characteristics of microorganisms following severe disturbances in rivers with high sediment concentrations.</description>
      <author>Ji Wu, Quan Hong, Jin Zhang, Chen Xie, Yang Liu, Dandan Li, Hao Liu, Ziwu Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/d17010041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Alpha&#8211;Proton Relative Drift: Implications for the Origins and Dynamics of the Solar Wind</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ad9ddd</link>
      <description>Joseph H. Wang, T. S. Horbury, Lorenzo Matteini, Domenico Trotta, The Astrophysical Journal Letters. 978(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4405992946

                Abstract Helium nuclei (alpha particles) strongly influence the momentum and energy balance in the solar wind, comprising up to 20% of the solar wind mass density. In fast Alfv&#233;nic wind at heliocentric distances greater than 0.3 au, the alpha particles&#8217; bulk flow speed is systematically different to that of the protons. This relative drift speed is of unknown origin and is often close to the local Alfv&#233;n wave speed. Novel Parker Solar Probe measurements of the solar wind below 0.3 au show that, closer to the Sun, the alpha&#8211;proton drift speed remains on the order of 100&#8211;200 km s &#8722;1 , even where the Alfv&#233;n speed is greater than 600 km s &#8722;1 . This relative speed is quantitatively similar to oxygen&#8211;hydrogen drift speeds observed in the transition region by remote sensing, suggesting similar selective acceleration processes in the corona. Due to the relative speed of the Alfv&#233;n wave to each particle population close to the Sun, the alphas fluctuate with velocity amplitudes comparable to those of the protons, altering the energy balance of the wave. As a result, alpha particles carry a significant fraction of the total kinetic energy in Alfv&#233;nic fluctuations in the near-Sun solar wind. The alpha&#8211;proton drift speed is comparable to the proton speed in the near-Sun wind, making the bulk flow of the alpha particles a significant contribution to the kinetic energy flux. These heavy-ion dynamics provide new observational constraints on quantifying the energy budget of the solar wind and the magnetic field evolution through the heliosphere.</description>
      <author>Joseph H. Wang, T. S. Horbury, Lorenzo Matteini, Domenico Trotta</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/2041-8213/ad9ddd</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving the mass transfer in the symbiotic recurrent nova T Coronae
  Borealis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.02984</link>
      <description>L. Planquart, A. Jorissen, H. Van Winckel, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406123341

                T Coronae Borealis (T CrB) is a symbiotic recurrent nova with an 80-year recurrence interval whose next eruption is imminent. We aim to resolve the accretion mechanism of the binary system governing the mass transfer during its super-active phase. Using phase-resolved high-resolution spectroscopy, we analyze the zoo of spectral-line profiles arising from the symbiotic activity. We perform Doppler tomography of selected emission lines to resolve the system's gaseous components and their different velocity regimes. We find evidence of enhanced accretion through Roche lobe overflow during the super-active phase, as traced by the oxygen, helium, and hydrogen lines. The accretion disc is found to be fully viscously evolved and extends up to its maximal radius. By mapping the kinematics of lines probing different excitation energies, we can identify distinct interaction sites. These include the bright spot at the stream impact on the accretion disc outer radius, the irradiation at the red-giant facing side, the stream-disc overflow, the accretion disk wind, and an expanding bipolar nebula. The bipolar jet emerged at the rise of the super-active phase and underwent an acceleration phase of about five years. The temporal evolution of the lines supports the scenario where the departure from quiescence started in the disc, likely triggered by a disc instability similar to what occurs in dwarf novae outburst, leading to an increased mass accretion and causing important irradiation of the giant that has further enhanced the mass-transfer rate during the super-active phase. Conclusions. Symbiotic recurrent novae, such as T CrB, are governed by similar mass-transfer mechanisms as found in cataclysmic variables despite their different orbital properties (longer orbital periods imposing larger accretion discs) and evolutionary pathways.</description>
      <author>L. Planquart, A. Jorissen, H. Van Winckel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.02984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambipolar doping of a charge-transfer insulator in the Emery model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.045117</link>
      <description>G. Sordi, G. L. Reaney, Nicolas Kowalski, P. S&#233;mon, A.&#8211;M. S. Tremblay, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406142806

                Understanding the similarities and differences between adding or removing electrons from a charge-transfer insulator may provide insights about the origin of the electron-hole asymmetry found in cuprates. Here we study with cellular dynamical mean-field theory the Emery model set in the charge-transfer insulator regime, and dope it with either electrons or holes. We consider the normal state only and focus on the doping evolution of the orbital character of the dopants and on the nature of the doping-driven transition. Regarding the orbital character of the dopants, we found an electron-hole asymmetry: doped electrons mostly enter the copper orbitals, whereas doped holes mostly enter the oxygen orbitals. Regarding the nature of the doping-driven transition, we found no qualitative electron-hole asymmetry: On either electron or hole doping, there is a two-stage transition from a charge-transfer insulator to a strongly correlated pseudogap and then to a metal. This shows that a strongly correlated pseudogap is an emergent feature of doped correlated insulators in two dimensions, in qualitative agreement with recent experiments on ambipolar Sr1&#8722;xLaxCuO2+y cuprate films. Our results indicate that merely doping with holes or electrons a charge-transfer insulator is not sufficient for explaining the electron-hole asymmetry observed in the normal state phase diagram of cuprates. Our work reinforces the view that actual hole-doped cuprates are more correlated than their electron-doped counterparts. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>G. Sordi, G. L. Reaney, Nicolas Kowalski, P. S&#233;mon, A.&#8211;M. S. Tremblay</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.045117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Area Evolution and Coal Spontaneous Combustion Prevention Method Induced by Air Leakage in Goaf of Ultra-Long Working Face</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00102202.2024.2448245</link>
      <description>Ma Li, Wenjun Zhang, Qingshan Zhao, Gaoming Wei, Ying Guo, Fang Lou, Shikui Jin, Longlong Tuo, Combustion Science and Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406070613

                Coal spontaneous combustion in goaf seriously affects the safety of mine production, and air leakage is one of the prerequisites for coal spontaneous combustion. Taking the ultra-long working face with a length of 410 m as an example, due to the insufficient compaction degree of the goaf, the high development of large-scale cracks, and the large air flow pressure difference between the intake and return air, the air leakage law in the goaf is not clear, and the risk of spontaneous combustion of broken residual coal increases. Based on the physical and mechanical parameters of coal rock, this paper studies the plastic failure and fracture development in the goaf under various stress disturbances in ultra-long working faces. The laws of gas migration and air leakage in goaf of ultra-long working face was studied by means of field test and numerical simulation. Based on the theory of coal-oxygen composite in goaf, the dangerous areas of coal spontaneous combustion in goaf with different mining sequence evolution of ultra-long working face were determined. Based on the distribution of air leakage flow field and coal spontaneous combustion danger zone in goaf, the comprehensive fire prevention and extinguishing technology of nitrogen injection inerting, plugging and leakage reduction was applied in field demonstration, and the application effect was verified. The research results show that the plastic failure range of overlying strata in goaf presents "saddle shape." The permeability and porosity increase gradually from the middle to the surrounding direction, showing "O-ring" distribution. The main air leakage channels are concentrated at the intake air tunnel corner of the goaf and 160&#8211;200 m of the working face. The air leakage sinks are located at a distance of 20&#8211;80 m along the dip direction of the working face and at the return corner of the working face, respectively. The average air leakage is 268 m3/min and 153 m3/min, and the maximum width of the coal spontaneous combustion danger zone in the goaf during the dynamic advancement of the ultra-long working face is 107 m. Through comprehensive fire prevention and extinguishing techniques such as nitrogen injection for inerting and filling with high-molecular-weight gel for sealing and leakage reduction, the prevention and control of coal spontaneous combustion in ultra-long working faces at different mining sequences under corresponding engineering backgrounds are effectively ensured.</description>
      <author>Ma Li, Wenjun Zhang, Qingshan Zhao, Gaoming Wei, Ying Guo, Fang Lou, Shikui Jin, Longlong Tuo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00102202.2024.2448245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation of global primary production model to the Greenland Sea conditions: parameterization and monitoring for 1998-2022</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1491180</link>
      <description>Alexandra Cherkasheva, Rustam Manurov, Piotr Kowalczuk, Alexandra Loginova, Monika Zab&#322;ocka, Astrid Bracher, Frontiers in Marine Science. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151632

                Phytoplankton are responsible for releasing half of the world&#8217;s oxygen and for removing large amounts of carbon dioxide from surface waters. Despite many studies on the topic conducted in the past decades, we are still far from a good understanding of ongoing rapid changes in the Arctic Ocean and how they will affect phytoplankton and the whole ecosystem. An example is the difference in net primary production modelling estimates, which differ twice globally and fifty times when only the Arctic region is considered. Here, we aim to improve the quality of Greenland Sea primary production estimates, by testing different versions of primary production model against in situ data and then calculating regional estimates and trends for 1998-2022 for those performing best. As a baseline, we chose the commonly used global primary production model and tested it with different combinations of empirical relationships and input data. Local empirical relationships were taken from measurements by the literature and derived from the unpublished data of Institute of Oceanology of Polish Academy of Sciences across the Fram Strait. For validation, we took historical net primary production 14 C data from literature and added to it our own gross primary production O 2 measurements. Field data showed good agreement between primary production measured with 14 C and O 2 evolution methods. From all the model setups, those including local chlorophyll a profile and local absorption spectrum best reproduced in situ data. Our modelled regional annual primary production estimates are equal to 346 TgC/year for the Nordic Seas region and 342 TgC/year for the Greenland Sea sector of the Arctic defined as 45&#176;W-15&#176;E, 66&#176;33&#8242;N-90&#176;N. These values are higher than those previously reported. Monthly values show a seasonal cycle with less monthly variability than previously reported. No significant increase or decrease in primary production was observed when studying regionally averaged trends. The accuracy of the selected here model setups to reproduce the field data in terms of Root Mean Square Difference is better than in the related Arctic studies. The improved primary production estimates strengthen researchers&#8217; ability to assess carbon flux and understand biogeochemical processes in the Greenland Sea.</description>
      <author>Alexandra Cherkasheva, Rustam Manurov, Piotr Kowalczuk, Alexandra Loginova, Monika Zab&#322;ocka, Astrid Bracher</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1491180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ancestral architecture of the immune system in simplest animals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2024.1529836</link>
      <description>Daria Y. Romanova, Leonid L. Moroz, Frontiers in Immunology. 15(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406128604

                ~520 million years ago, the long biogeochemical history of our planet Earth resulted in a biodiversity burst. The rapid diversification of animals known as the Cambrian explosion (Mangano et al., 2014;Ahang et al., 2022;) transformed planetary ecosystems with novel habitats and food chains (Vannier et al., 2005(Vannier et al., ,2007)). However, this emergence of Paleozoic biodiversity (Harper et al., 2020) is still mysterious due to limited information about basal metazoans and their immune systems.The representatives of the phylum Placozoa with the simplest known body plan attract the attention of ecological physiologists seeking to understand integrative responses to environmental stress, often associated with climate changes, temperature, and oxygen levels, including complex symbiotic relationships over eons (Rognov, 2009;Sperling and Vinther, 2010;Spelling et al., 2013;Pruss and Gill, 2024). The simplicity of the cellular architecture in placozoans might correlate with a relatively small genome of 106 Mb (Srivastava et al., 2008). Placozoa do not have nervous and muscle systems or organs (Schulze, 1883;Rassat and Ruthmann, 1979;Malakhov, 1990;Smith et al., 2014). Still, these animals have an alternative integrating system of effector cells and a number of secretory cells that, by acting on the ciliated epithelium, control locomotion (Armon et al., 2018). In this architecture, the tetraploid fiber cell type, with a significantly high DNA context, is of utmost interest since these cells potentially perform three integrative functions (Behrendt and Ruthmann, 1986): (i) making a distributed functional network of the middle and epithelial layers (analogous to neurons), (ii) immune protection and growth control of endosymbiotic bacteria (immunity), and (iii) dynamic contractile functions (analogous to muscles) in responses to chemical environment and pH.The combination of all three functions within one cell type is relatively rare, even in other basal metazoan lineages such as comb jellies, sponges, and cnidarians. Here, we summarize the role of systemic and cellular functions as a unique window to illuminate the origins of immune architecture in early animals using a top-down approach, from organisms to cells to molecules, including novel insights into the critical master regulators of systemic immune responses.There is evidence for four distinct systemic immunity responses in Placozoa: (1) population aging, often associated with (2) infection; (3) resistance to radiation (next section); and (4) feeding, including interactions with pathogens and endosymbiosis. Below, we summarize the features of each of these responses.Population aging under long-term cultivation conditions is associated with various disease-like stages (Romanova et al., 2022). It includes the development of abnormal morphological changes (e.g., highly elongated body shapes) and the characteristic appearance of spherical formations on the upper epithelium with occasional rupture of the upper and middle layers. All of these can be reversed by fresh seawater and a dense substrate of microalgae as juvenilization (Romanova et al., 2022). The 'spheres' are analogs of the encapsulation of larger foreign objects for non-specific protection. If unfavored conditions are not changed, placozoan populations are transformed into the deterioration stage of irreversible spherical formations and death without a chance of recovery.Animals from the 'sick', with abundant spheres, population decrease locomotion and exploratory behaviors, as well as stop asexual reproduction. The 'spheres' with cavities consist of dorsal epithelium, fiber cells with multiple intracellular bacteria, and, probably, adjacent to the dorsal layer with 'shiny' cells containing large lipophilic inclusions with autofluorescent granules of unclear etiology but without bacteria (Romanova et al., 2022, Fig.7h-k). Animals can shed 'infected cells' encapsulated by the upper epithelium. Besides, there are morphological differences between the fiber cells of animals with endosymbionts (control) and ampicillin-treated animals (Romanova et al., 2022) without bacteria. This may indicate the ability to control the reproduction of bacterial endosymbionts by the complementary activation of phagocytosis and digest bacteria as a systemic innate immunity mechanism. Combined, this dynamic organismal-level architecture provided a landscape for exploring cellular and molecular innovations in the Placozoa lineage, potentially with cross-kingdom signaling between bacterial and their hosts.The process of shaping spherical formations involves the shiny cells of the upper epithelium (potentially releasing toxins (Jakson and Buss, 2009)) and the middle layer cells, represented by the fiber cells (Fig. 1A). The fiber cells represent the unique cell type associated with both integrative immune and feeding functions (Mayorova et al., 2021). The Gruber-Vodicka group (Berndt et al., 2024) showed multiple new organelles with lysozymes in Trichoplax -lysozymes as widespread components of metazoan immune and digestive enzymes (Mukherjee and Moroz, 2024). These enzymes provide antibacterial protection by hydrolyzing the peptide glycans of bacterial cell walls and participating in the digestion process. Interestingly, it was in the fiber cells that endosymbiotic Rickettsiales bacteria were originally found in H1 and H2 haplotypes (Driscoll et al., 2013;Kamm et al., 2019).Cellular immunity caused by phagocytosis (discovered by Metchnikov, 1892; Thiemann and Ruthmann, 1990) is the most ancient and common mechanism across eukaryotes; it includes chemotaxis, attachment of a foreign agent to the phagocyte membrane, and intracellular lysis. Chemoattractants can be signaling molecules from bacterial microorganisms, a change in the gradient of nitric oxide (NO) and related redox species (Moroz et al., 2020a), or a change in the amino acid composition (Moroz et al., 2020b). As a result of multifunctionality, fiber cell type is characterized by the presence of a massive mitochondrial cluster (Grell et al., 1991;Smith et al., 2014;Romanova et al., 2021), which may indicate high-energy costs for metabolic processes.In addition, fiber cells have exceptional intercellular contacts, found only in this cell type (Grell and Ruthman, 1991), which join all fiber cells into a network within the middle layer (Moroz and Romanova, 2022), and with multiple vesicles in the extracellular space (Moroz,Romanova,Kohn,2021). Thus, these are also neural-like cells that establish physiological connectivity from the middle to the dorsal layers (Moroz et al., 2021;Romanova et al., 2021;Moroz and Romanova, 2022). This 'network' can enable systemic immunity responses by immobilizing and consuming bacteria. Consequently, fiber cells are not fixed in their position and can be mobile as a result of chemoattraction, and be contractable.The Trichoplax ventral layer is formed by cell types with adherent junctions, which tightly hold cells facing biofilm substrates. The opposite is true for the dorsal layer, where the cells are elastic (Armon et al., 2018). Such epithelia are evolutionary innovative structures to protect early metazoans against bacterial infection as inherent parts of innate immunity system architectures.Opsonization, with the formation of distinct compartments, had been observed inside fiber cells (Romanova et al., 2021;Moroz et al., 2021;Romanova et al., 2022;Moroz and Romanova, 2022), and we detected bacteria in lysosomes. In some cases, bacterial cells were located in the perinuclear space (Romanova et al., 2021, Fig.5a), in close proximity to the cell nucleus. However, these are isolated cases with only 3-5% of the total number of fiber cells with bacteria. But the question remains openwhy do bacteria need such close proximity to the nucleus? Is this a metabolic symbiosis?MOLECULAR LEVEL OF IMMUNITY Distinctive insights into placozoan immunity were obtained by Fortunato et al. (2021), who exposed Trichoplax to a range of X-ray doses from 143.6 to 332.5 Gy. Surprisingly, placozoans can survive and restore their populations even after 218.6 Gy exposure with immune-related adaptive morphology -the appearance of spherical formations (Fortunato et al., 2021, Fig.3), which is similar to those shown in the description 'diseased' in animals (Romanova et al., 2022).Transcriptome analyses after 2 hrs of exposure of animals to a dose of 218.6 Gy revealed a cascade of inducible genes coupled with genome-wide immunity responses, including genes responsible for protection against double-strand breaks, such as RAD52, LIG4, DCLRE1C, RECQL5, XRCC6. Other radiation-induced genes (such as POLB, POLL and LIG3) also control various DNA repair mechanisms (Fortunato et al., 2021).Presumed immune regulatory gene networks of Toll-like receptors and scavenger receptors have been identified (Kamm et al., 2019). However, these authors did not find a homolog for the nuclear factor kappa B gene. In contrast, Porifera and Cnidaria have a complete homolog of the NF-&#954;B gene (Gauthier and Degnan, 2008;Song et al., 2012). It raises the question of whether placozoans have a highly modified/truncated NF-&#954;B (Kamm et al., 2019) or represent an ancestral stage before the acquisition of this transcription factor in immunity mechanisms.We performed a genome screening and found partial similarity of the human NF-&#954;B gene with the TriadITZ_000500 gene of the H1 haplotype with a large divergence between their sequences. AlphaFold2 reliably reconstructs the three-dimensional architecture of these protein orthologs across phyla. Intriguingly, both proteins from Placozoa and Chordata are mirror images of each other with preservation in Trichoplax all functional domains necessary for the activity of the NF-&#954;B (Fig. 1B). This finding illuminates the remarkable parallelism, modularity, and perhaps convergent evolution of immunity master regulators.What might be ancestral immunity architecture? Why does the simplest, a three-layer animal of one millimeter in size, employs the astonishing diversity of immune-related genes? Trichoplax genome encodes 5 genes of interleukins, 4 interferons, a number of immunoglobulins, two classes of the main histocompatibility complex, secretins, tetraspannins, and other genes necessary for intercellular information transmission from cell to cell, as in the canonical chordate immune system. According to single-cell transcriptomics (Sebe-Pedros et al., 2018), their expression is not cluster-specific, suggesting a broad distribution of innate immunity functions across cell populations in Placozoa.More likely, this situation reflects a great ancestral diversity of immune molecular toolkits as a result of a long history of holozoan-bacterial interactions. The early origins of multifunctional cell types with subsequent division of labor in large tetraploid fiber cells with elongated processes are morphologically and functionally similar to neurons and dendritic cells of the vertebrate immune system as well as muscle cells. These cells developed a powerful mitochondrial cluster and the largest nucleus among all Trichoplax cell types. Combined, these traits are associated with the omnipresence of bacteria both as food sources and pathogens with a dual role of bioenergetically demanding phagocytosis. Bacteria encapsulation might also be an ancestral immune strategy by making 'shells' of the 'friend-or-foe' recognition system with the recruitment of opsonin-like genes (Bang, 1975;Lackie, 1980;Bayne, 1990;Musser et al., 2021).Finally, fiber cells might be viewed as functional analogs of interneurons, with distributed connectivity and their localization uniting all cell layers.They forma highly distributed 'network' created by long processes of fiber cells for more efficient and rapid intercellular communications, integrating neural, hormonal, and contractive integrative systems. It would not be surprising if fiber cells were excitable with low-frequency oscillations (e.g., 100-150 ms) capable of secretion and chemical connectivity (Moroz et al., 2021).In sum, the multifunctionality of fiber cells can be the main operational module of the immune system for Placozoa and likely an example of exaptation for other emerging properties as dynamic links between immune and neural functions, which are responsible for organism-level integration. We would not be surprised if fiber cells could have epigenetic machinery for immune 'cellular memory' as the predecessor of acquired immunity.</description>
      <author>Daria Y. Romanova, Leonid L. Moroz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2024.1529836</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
