<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 01:05:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Anion Structure Regulation of Cobalt Silicate Hydroxide Endowing Boosted Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401394</link>
      <description>Yang Wang, Longmei Li, Sheng-Guo Wang, Xueliang Dong, Chongtao Ding, Yang Mu, Miao Cui, Tao Hu, Changgong Meng, Yifu Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396659240

                Abstract Transition metal silicates (TMSs) are attempted for the electrocatalyst of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their special layered structure in recent years. However, defects such as low theoretical activity and conductivity limit their application. Researchers always prefer to composite TMSs with other functional materials to make up for their deficiency, but rarely focus on the effect of intrinsic structure adjustment on their catalytic activity, especially anion structure regulation. Herein, applying the method of interference hydrolysis and vacancy reserve, new silicate vacancies (anionic regulation) are introduced in cobalt silicate hydroxide (CoSi), named SV&#8208;CoSi, to enlarge the number and enhance the activity of catalytic sites. The overpotential of SV&#8208;CoSi declines to 301 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 compared to 438 mV of CoSi. Source of such improvement is verified to be not only the increase of active sites, but also the positive effect on the intrinsic activity due to the enhancement of cobalt&#8208;oxygen covalence with the variation of anion structure by density functional theory (DFT) method. This work demonstrates that the feasible intrinsic anion structure regulation can improve OER performance of TMSs and provides an effective idea for the development of non&#8208;noble metal catalyst for OER.</description>
      <author>Yang Wang, Longmei Li, Sheng-Guo Wang, Xueliang Dong, Chongtao Ding, Yang Mu, Miao Cui, Tao Hu, Changgong Meng, Yifu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solidophobic Surface for Electrochemical Extraction of High-Valued Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Coupled with H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production from Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01484</link>
      <description>Yi Li, Chen Xu, Yingjie Wen, Haocheng Chen, Sixie Zhang, Hao Yang, Wenbo Li, Lihui Zhou, Bo Xu, Wenwen Xu, Wenjie Guan, Sheng Dai, Zhiyi Lu, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396660312

                A significant challenge in direct seawater electrolysis is the rapid deactivation of the cathode due to the large scaling of Mg(OH)2. Herein, we synthesized a Pt-coated highly disordered NiCu alloy (Pt-NiCu alloy) electrode with superior solidophobic behavior, enabling stable hydrogen generation (100 mA cm&#8211;2, &gt;1000 h durability) and simultaneous production of Mg(OH)2 (&gt;99.0% purity) in electrolyte enriched with Mg2+ and Ca2+. The unconventional solidophobic property primarily stems from the high surface energy of the NiCu alloy substrate, which facilitates the adsorption of surface water and thereby compels the bulk formation of Mg(OH)2 via homogeneous nucleation. The discovery of this solidophobic electrode will revolutionarily simplify the existing techniques for seawater electrolysis and increase the economic viability for seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Yi Li, Chen Xu, Yingjie Wen, Haocheng Chen, Sixie Zhang, Hao Yang, Wenbo Li, Lihui Zhou, Bo Xu, Wenwen Xu, Wenjie Guan, Sheng Dai, Zhiyi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CoSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles Incorporated Nitrogen-Doped Carbon as Efficient Trifunctional Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries and Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02766</link>
      <description>Lubing Li, Jia-Tong Qu, Lei Zhang, Liting Wei, Jinzhan Su, Liejin Guo, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396674690

                The development of affordable, highly active, and stable trifunctional electrocatalysts is imperative for sustainable energy applications such as overall water splitting and rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery. Herein, we report a composite electrocatalyst with RuSe2 and CoSe2 hybrid nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen-doped carbon (RuSe2CoSe2/NC) synthesized through a carbonization&#8211;adsorption&#8211;selenylation strategy. This electrocatalyst is a trifunctional electrocatalyst with excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activities. An in-depth study of the effect of Se on the electrocatalytic process was conducted. Notably, the incorporation of Se moderately adjusted electronic structure of Ru and Co, enhancing all three types of catalytic performance (HER, &#951;10 = 31 mV; OER, &#951;10 = 248 mV; ORR, E1/2 = 0.834 V) under alkaline condition with accelerated kinetics and improved stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculation reveals that the (210) crystal facet of RuSe2 is the dominant HER active site as it exhibited the lowest &#916;GH* value. The in situ Raman spectra unravel the evolution process of the local electronic environment of Co&#8211;Se and Ru&#8211;Se bonds, which synergistically promotes the formation of CoOOH as the active intermediate during the OER. The superior catalytic efficiency and remarkable durability of RuSe2CoSe2/NC as an electrode for water splitting and zinc&#8211;air battery devices demonstrate its great potential for energy storage and conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Lubing Li, Jia-Tong Qu, Lei Zhang, Liting Wei, Jinzhan Su, Liejin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Energy Facet Engineering for Electrocatalytic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401546</link>
      <description>Rui Wu, Jong&#8208;Min Lee, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396675515

                Abstract The design of high&#8208;energy facets in electrocatalysts has attracted significant attention due to their potential to enhance electrocatalytic activity. In this review, the significance of high&#8208;energy facets in various electrochemical reactions are highlighted, including oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR), and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CRR). Their importance in various electrochemical reactions and present strategies for constructing high&#8208;energy facets are discussed, including alloying, heterostructure formation, selective etching, capping agents, and coupling with substrates. These strategies enable control over crystallographic orientation and surface morphology, fine&#8208;tuning electrocatalytic properties. This study also addresses future directions and challenges, emphasizing the need to better understand fundamental mechanisms. Overall, high&#8208;energy facets offer exciting opportunities for advancing electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Rui Wu, Jong&#8208;Min Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain boundary defect engineering in rutile iridium oxide boosts efficient and stable acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400651</link>
      <description>Ning Zhang, Yunyun Fan, Depeng Wang, Yan Yu, Jianwei Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Di Bao, Haixia Zhong, Xinbo Zhang, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396675555

                PEMWE is considered a promising technology for coupling with renewable energy sources to achieve clean hydrogen production. However, constrained by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic OER and the acidic abominable environment render the grand challenges in developing the active and stable OER electrocatalyst, leading to low efficiency of PEMWE. Herein, we develop the rutile&#8208;type IrO2 nanoparticles with abundant grain boundaries and the continuous nanostructure through the joule heating and sacrificial template method. DFT calculations verified that grain boundaries can modulate the electronic structure of Ir sites and optimize the adsorption of oxygen intermediates, resulting in the accelerated kinetics. The 350&#8208;IrO2 affords a rapid OER process with 20 times higher mass activity (0.61 A mgIr&#8208;1) than the commercial IrO2 at 1.50 V vs. RHE. Benefiting from the reduced overpotential and the preservation of the stable rutile structure, 350&#8208;IrO2 exhibits the stability of 200 h test at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 with only trace decay of 11.8 mV. Moreover, the assembled PEMWE with anode 350&#8208;IrO2 catalyst outputs the current density up to 2 A cm&#8208;2 with only 1.84 V applied voltage, long&#8208;term operation for 100 h without obvious performance degradation at 1 A cm&#8208;2.</description>
      <author>Ning Zhang, Yunyun Fan, Depeng Wang, Yan Yu, Jianwei Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Di Bao, Haixia Zhong, Xinbo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Doping of B and Fe Activated Lattice Oxygen Participation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity in Alkaline Freshwater and Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402264</link>
      <description>Yanhong Pan, Zhichong Wang, Kaixuan Wang, Qing Ye, B. G. Shen, Fuwei Yang, Yongliang Cheng, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396677401

                Abstract The exploitation of highly activity oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is critical for the application of electrocatalytic water splitting. Triggering the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) is expected to provide a promising pathway to overcome the sluggish OER kinetics, however, effectively enhancing the involvement of lattice oxygen remains challenging. In this study, the fabrication of B, Fe co&#8208;doped CoP (B, Fe&#9472;CoP) nanofibers is reported, which serve as highly efficient OER electrocatalyst through phosphorization and boronation treatment of Fe&#8208;doped Co 3 O 4 nanofibers. Experimental results combined with theoretical calculations reveal that simultaneous incorporation of both B and Fe can more effectively trigger the participation of lattice oxygen in CoFe oxyhydroxides reconstructed from B, Fe&#9472;CoP nanofibers compared to incorporating only B or Fe. Therefore, the optimized B, Fe&#9472;CoP nanofibers exhibit superb OER activity with low overpotentials of 361 and 376 mV at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline freshwater and alkaline natural seawater, respectively. The present work provides significant guidelines and innovative design concepts for the development of OER electrocatalysts following the LOM pathway.</description>
      <author>Yanhong Pan, Zhichong Wang, Kaixuan Wang, Qing Ye, B. G. Shen, Fuwei Yang, Yongliang Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Lattice Oxygen Participation of NiFe Stack Anode for Sustainable Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4818766</link>
      <description>Sinwoo Kang, Dong-yeol Lee, Yeongin Kim, Sooan Bae, Jae Kwang Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691473

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sinwoo Kang, Dong-yeol Lee, Yeongin Kim, Sooan Bae, Jae Kwang Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4818766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isomerization Engineering of Oxygen&#8208;Enriched Carbon Quantum Dots for Efficient Electrochemical Hydrogen Peroxide Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401253</link>
      <description>Xie Le-ping, Caihong Liang, Yao Wu, Kang Wang, Wei Hou, Hongwei Guo, Zeming Wang, Yeng Ming Lam, Zheng Liu, Liang Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691493

                Abstract Hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) has emerged as a kind of multi&#8208;functional green oxidants with extensive industrial utility. Oxidized carbon materials exhibit promises as electrocatalysts in the two&#8208;electron (2e &#8722; ) oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) for H 2 O 2 production. However, the precise identification and fabrication of active sites that selectively yield H 2 O 2 present a serious challenge. Herein, a structural engineering strategy is employed to synthesize oxygen&#8208;doped carbon quantum dots (o&#8208;CQD) for the 2e &#8722; ORR. The surface electronic structure of the o&#8208;CQDs is systematically modulated by varying isomerization precursors, thereby demonstrating excellent electrocatalyst performance. Notably, o&#8208;CQD&#8208;3 emerges as the most promising candidate, showcasing a remarkable H 2 O 2 selectivity of 96.2% (n = 2.07) at 0.68 V versus RHE, coupled with a low Tafel diagram of 66.95 mV dec &#8722;1 . In the flow cell configuration, o&#8208;CQD&#8208;3 achieves a H 2 O 2 productivity of 338.7 mmol g catalyst &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 , maintaining consistent production stability over an impressive 120&#8208;hour duration. Utilizing in situ technology and density functional theory calculations, it is unveil that edge sites of o&#8208;CQD&#8208;3 are facilely functionalized by C&#8208;O&#8208;C groups under alkaline ORR conditions. This isomerization engineering approach advances the forefront of sustainable catalysis and provides a profound insight into the carbon&#8208;based catalyst design for environmental&#8208;friendly chemical synthesis processes.</description>
      <author>Xie Le-ping, Caihong Liang, Yao Wu, Kang Wang, Wei Hou, Hongwei Guo, Zeming Wang, Yeng Ming Lam, Zheng Liu, Liang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The current state of transition metal-based electrocatalysts (oxides, alloys, POMs, and MOFs) for oxygen reduction, oxygen evolution, and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1373522</link>
      <description>H. M. Ara&#250;jo, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Sandra Gago, Diogo M.F. Santos, Frontiers in energy research. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396695394

                Climate change is showing its impacts now more than ever. The intense use of fossil fuels and the resulting CO 2 emissions are mainly to blame, accentuating the need to develop further the available energy conversion and storage technologies, which are regarded as effective solutions to maximize the use of intermittent renewable energy sources and reduce global CO 2 emissions. This work comprehensively overviews the most recent progress and trends in the use of transition metal-based electrocatalysts for three crucial reactions in electrochemical energy conversion and storage, namely, the oxygen evolution (OER), oxygen reduction (ORR), and hydrogen evolution (HER) reactions. By analyzing the state-of-the-art polyoxometalates (POMs) and metal-organic frameworks (MOFs), the performance of these two promising types of materials for OER, ORR, and HER is compared to that of more traditional transition metal oxides and alloy-based electrocatalysts. Both catalytic activity and stability are highly influenced by the adsorption energies of the intermediate species formed in each reaction, which are very sensitive to changes in the microstructure and chemical microenvironment. POMs and MOFs allow these aspects to be easily modified to fine-tune the catalytic performances. Therefore, their chemical tunability and versatility make it possible to tailor such properties to obtain higher electrocatalytic activities, or even to obtain derived materials with more compelling properties towards these reactions.</description>
      <author>H. M. Ara&#250;jo, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Sandra Gago, Diogo M.F. Santos</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1373522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen evolution reaction performance of Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper perovskite oxide through heteroatom incorporation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151912</link>
      <description>Shu&#8208;Fang Li, Baoqin Zhang, Zhen&#8208;Bo Wang, Dong Yan, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396696534

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shu&#8208;Fang Li, Baoqin Zhang, Zhen&#8208;Bo Wang, Dong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N/P-doped NiFeV oxide nanosheets with oxygen vacancies as an efficient electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00943f</link>
      <description>Jingyuan Zhang, Zhenqiang Ma, Lanqi Wang, Ni Hui, Juanjuan Yu, Bin Zhao, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396696656

                An N/P-doped NiFeV oxide nanosheet catalyst (N/P-NiFeVO) is constructed by plasma treatment as an efficient electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Jingyuan Zhang, Zhenqiang Ma, Lanqi Wang, Ni Hui, Juanjuan Yu, Bin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00943f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Evolution and Reverse Evolution of Graphene Vacancy Defects in the Oxygen Plasma Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4819861</link>
      <description>Shu Xiao, Yinong Chen, Shuyu Fan, Yi Wu, Jian Wu, Guangze Tang, Xinyu Meng, Fenghua Su, Xuepeng Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713726

                The phenomenon of friction increase in graphene coatings during prolonged treatment in an oxygen plasma environment has been widely recognized. In this study, we report a newly discovered oxidation state that leads to decreased friction during oxygen plasma treatment of vacancy graphene and propose a simple, clean, and efficient method for the controlled oxidation. Through density-functional theory calculations, we suggest the possibility of evolution from vacancies to oligo-oxygen and poly-oxygen structures during the oxygen plasma treatment, confirming sequential friction decrease and increase. Furthermore, molecular dynamics simulations indicate that the oligo-oxygen structure exhibits excellent in-plane stiffness in addition to low surface friction, making it an ideal friction interface. Notably, conditional friction can induce the reverse evolution of the poly-oxygen structures back to the oligo-oxygen structures. Experimental results demonstrate that the friction of oligo-oxygen and poly-oxygen structures decreased by 30.6% and increased by 130.1%, respectively, compared to the initial graphene vacancy structures. Moreover, the induced friction by 0.1 N in the presence of hydrogen makes the friction performance of the induced poly-oxygen structures, especially in the initial friction phase, almost comparable to that of the oligo-oxygen structures. These findings reveal the structural evolution and reverse evolution laws of graphene coatings in high-energy oxygen plasma environments, which are of great significance for the lubrication of moving component devices in the oxygen plasma environment, including in the plasma industry and space.</description>
      <author>Shu Xiao, Yinong Chen, Shuyu Fan, Yi Wu, Jian Wu, Guangze Tang, Xinyu Meng, Fenghua Su, Xuepeng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4819861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium-doped bimetallic organic framework self-supported electrodes as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.318</link>
      <description>Li Jing, Ya nan Wang, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Bo Liu, Chunbo Liu, Xianyu Chu, Guangbo Che, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396716177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Jing, Ya nan Wang, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Bo Liu, Chunbo Liu, Xianyu Chu, Guangbo Che</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten doping-Induced electronic structure modulation in NiFe-based metal-organic frameworks for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.355</link>
      <description>Dazhi Shen, Wenchang Ke, Gulimire Balati, Yunhua Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396716607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dazhi Shen, Wenchang Ke, Gulimire Balati, Yunhua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Derived Trends of the Oxygen Adsorption Energy Using the Simplistic Model of the Thermodynamic Potential for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821664</link>
      <description>Isabela C. Man, Ionut Tranc&#259;, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396718825

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Isabela C. Man, Ionut Tranc&#259;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821664</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KIr&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; Nanowires with Rich Hydroxyl Promote Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202402643</link>
      <description>Zhenyu Li, Xiang Li, Mengna Wang, Qi Wang, Pengfei Wei, Subhajit Jana, Ziqi Liao, Jingcheng Yu, Fang Lu, Liu Tian-fu, Guoxiong Wang, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720387

                The sluggish kinetics for anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and insufficient catalytic performance over the corresponding Ir-based catalysts are still enormous challenges in proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE). Herein, we report that KIr</description>
      <author>Zhenyu Li, Xiang Li, Mengna Wang, Qi Wang, Pengfei Wei, Subhajit Jana, Ziqi Liao, Jingcheng Yu, Fang Lu, Liu Tian-fu, Guoxiong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202402643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;-Type Active Sites Grown on Fe-Doped Ni Core Surfaces during the Initial Oxygen Evolution Reactions: Fe-Doping Effect?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08462</link>
      <description>Sung Soo Lim, Chang Weon Choi, Arumugam Sivanantham, Sangaraju Shanmugam, Yves Lansac, Yun Hee Jang, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721754

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sung Soo Lim, Chang Weon Choi, Arumugam Sivanantham, Sangaraju Shanmugam, Yves Lansac, Yun Hee Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c08462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron-incorporated IrO2-Ta2O5 coating as an efficient electrocatalyst for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152040</link>
      <description>Qikai Huang, Shaojie Zhuang, Yuexi Zheng, Xuerong Peng, Zhiguo Ye, Duosheng Li, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396722006

                The Ir-based electrocatalysts for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) have demonstrated remarkable durability. Enhancing the Ir-based electrocatalytic activity still remains crucial owing to the scarcity of iridium. Here, a high-temperature sintering technique is employed to fabricate a boron (B)-incorporated IrO2-Ta2O5 coating with an almost perfect rutile-type crystal structure on a corrosion-resistant titanium substrate, ensuring exceptional stability for the acidic OER. The B-incorporated IrO2-Ta2O5 electrode fabricated in a mixed solution of 0.6 M H3BO3, exhibits an overpotential of 210 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a lower Tafel slope of 34.2 mV dec&#8722;1 in a 0.5 M H2SO4 solution, which is far lower than the 272 mV overpotential and the 45.3 mV dec&#8722;1 of the IrO2-Ta2O5/Ti electrode. The electrode possesses a minimal potential increase even after undergoing continuous OER for 400 h at a high current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in a 0.5 M H2SO4 solution. The incorporation of B species into IrO2-Ta2O5 effectively fine-tunes the electronic structure of Ir active sites, leading to a substantial enhancement of the intrinsic electrocatalytic activity. This study provides promising prospects for reducing the energy consumption of noble IrO2-based electrocatalysts in the practical application of electrochemical industry for the acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Qikai Huang, Shaojie Zhuang, Yuexi Zheng, Xuerong Peng, Zhiguo Ye, Duosheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nife Layered Double Hydroxide Nanosheets Self Assembled and Etched by Phosphotungstic Acid for the Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821856</link>
      <description>Xiaoyan Zhu, Minghe Du, Haijun Deng, Yi Liu, Jieyu Chen, Shengping Wang, Huixi Li, Chunjie Yan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396725293

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyan Zhu, Minghe Du, Haijun Deng, Yi Liu, Jieyu Chen, Shengping Wang, Huixi Li, Chunjie Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4821856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin High-Entropy Layered Double Hydroxide Electrocatalysts for Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820628</link>
      <description>Xianxu Chu, Ting Wang, Haoyuan Wang, Bin Du, Guanqun Guo, Ying Zhou, Xuelin Dong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396726076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xianxu Chu, Ting Wang, Haoyuan Wang, Bin Du, Guanqun Guo, Ying Zhou, Xuelin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel amorphous FeOOH-modified Co9S8 nanosheets with enhanced catalytic activity in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.033</link>
      <description>Chong Wang, Huanlu Tu, Zeyu Hao, Yaxin Li, Jian Xu, Xiaoying Hu, Shansheng Yu, Hongwei Tian, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396730938

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chong Wang, Huanlu Tu, Zeyu Hao, Yaxin Li, Jian Xu, Xiaoying Hu, Shansheng Yu, Hongwei Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.033</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ge&#8208;Doped Hematite with FeCoNi&#8208;B&lt;sub&gt;i&lt;/sub&gt; as Cocatalyst for High&#8208;Performing Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400316</link>
      <description>Yueyang Wang, Shibo Cui, Zhenyu Tian, Meisheng Han, Tianshou Zhao, Wenjia Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396746263

                Abstract Hematite is a promising photoanode material for photoelectrochemical water&#8208;splitting technology. However, the low current density associated with the low conductivity, low charge carrier mobility, and poor oxygen evolution catalytic activity is a challenging issue for the material. In this study, the challenge is addressed by introducing Germanium (Ge) doping, coupled with the use of FeCoNi&#8208;B i as a co&#8208;catalyst. Ge doping not only increases the conductivity and charge carrier concentration of the hematite photoanode, but also induces nanopores, thereby expanding its electrochemical reactive surface area to facilitate the oxygen evolution reaction. In the meantime, the FeCoNi&#8208;B i cocatalyst electrodeposited onto the surface of Ge&#8208;doped hematite, improves the oxygen evolution reaction performance. As a result, the obtained photoanode achieves a photocurrent density of 2.31 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V RHE , which is three times higher than that of hematite (0.72 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Moreover, a new analytical method is introduced to scrutinize both the positive and negative effects of Ge doping and FeCoNi&#8208;B i cocatalyst on the photoanode performance by decoupling the photoelectrochemical process steps. Overall, this study not only enhances the performance of hematite photoanodes but also guides their rational design and systematic assessment.</description>
      <author>Yueyang Wang, Shibo Cui, Zhenyu Tian, Meisheng Han, Tianshou Zhao, Wenjia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400316</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Redistribution Through the Interface of MnCo2O4-Ni3N Nano-Urchins Prompted Rapid In-Situ Phase Transformation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00560k</link>
      <description>Ashish Gaur, _ Aashi, Joel Mathew John, Vikas Pundir, Rajdeep Kaur, Jyoti Sharma, Karthick Babu Sai Sankar Gupta, Chandan Bera, Vivek Bagchi, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396752932

                One of the most coveted objectives in the realm of energy conversion technologies is the development of highly efficient and economically viable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction. The commercialization...</description>
      <author>Ashish Gaur, _ Aashi, Joel Mathew John, Vikas Pundir, Rajdeep Kaur, Jyoti Sharma, Karthick Babu Sai Sankar Gupta, Chandan Bera, Vivek Bagchi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00560k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and electrocatalytic oxygen evolution of bimetallic phosphates (NiFe)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P/NF</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2023-0266</link>
      <description>Bo Yu, Yan Li, Xinmin Fu, Lei Yu, Hao Fu, Yang Cao, Zhihong Chen, Green processing and synthesis. 13(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396754054

                Abstract The energy and environmental crisis pose a great challenge to human development in the 21st century. The design and development of clean and renewable energy and the solution for environmental pollution have become a hotspot in the current research. Based on the preparation of transition metal phosphates, transition metals were used as raw materials, Prussian blue-like NiFe(CN) 6 as a precursor, which was in situ grown on nickel foam (NF) substrate. After low temperature phosphating treatment, a bimetallic phosphide electrocatalyst (NiFe) 2 P/NF was prepared on NF substrate. Using 1 mol&#183;L &#8722;1 KOH solution as a basic electrolyte, based on the electrochemical workstation of a three-electrode system, the electrochemical catalytic oxygen evolution performance of the material was tested and evaluated. Experiments show that (NiFe) 2 P/NF catalyst has excellent oxygen evolution performance. In an alkaline medium, the overpotential required to obtain the catalytic current density of 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 is only 220 mV, and the Tafel slope is 67 mV&#183;dec &#8722;1 . This is largely due to: (1) (NiFe)2p/NF nanocatalysts were well dispersed on NF substrates, which increased the number of active sites exposed; (2) the hollow heterostructure of bimetallic phosphates promotes the electron interaction between (NiFe) 2 P and NF, increased the rate of charge transfer, and the electrical conductivity of the material is improved; and (3) theoretical calculations show that (NiFe) 2 P/NF hollow heterostructure can effectively reduce the dissociation barrier of water, promote the dissociation of water; furthermore, the kinetic reaction rate of electrocatalytic oxygen evolution is accelerated. Meanwhile, the catalyst still has high activity and high stability in 30 wt% concentrated alkali solution. Therefore, the construction of (NiFe) 2 P/NF electrocatalysts enriches the application of non-noble metal nanomaterials in the field of oxygen production from electrolytic water.</description>
      <author>Bo Yu, Yan Li, Xinmin Fu, Lei Yu, Hao Fu, Yang Cao, Zhihong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/gps-2023-0266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Assembled Conjugated Coordination Polymer Nanorings: Role of Morphology and Redox Sites for the Alkaline Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00609</link>
      <description>Vishwakarma Ravikumar Ramlal, Kinjal B. Patel, Savan K. Raj, Divesh N. Srivastava, Amal Kumar Mandal, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760067

                Electrocatalytic water splitting provides a sustainable method for storing intermittent energies, such as solar energy and wind, in the form of hydrogen fuel. However, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), constituting the other half-cell reaction, is often considered the bottleneck in overall water splitting due to its slow kinetics. Therefore, it is crucial to develop efficient, cost-effective, and robust OER catalysts to enhance the water-splitting process. Transition-metal-based coordination polymers (CPs) serve as promising electrocatalysts due to their diverse chemical architectures paired with redox-active metal centers. Despite their potential, the rational use of CPs has faced obstacles including a lack of insights into their catalytic mechanisms, low conductivity, and morphology issues. Consequently, achieving success in this field requires the rational design of ligands and topological networks with the desired electronic structure. This study delves into the design and synthesis of three novel conjugated coordination polymers (CCPs) by leveraging the full conjugation of terpyridine-attached flexible tetraphenylethylene units as electron-rich linkers with various redox-active metal centers [Co(II), Ni(II), and Zn(II)]. The self-assembly process is tuned for each CCP, resulting in two distinct morphologies: nanosheets and nanorings. The electrocatalytic OER performance efficiency is then correlated with factors such as the nanostructure morphology and redox-active metal centers in alkaline electrolytes. Notably, among the three morphologies studied, nanorings for each CCP exhibit a superior OER activity. Co(II)-integrated CCPs demonstrate a higher activity between the redox-active metal centers. Specifically, the Co(II) nanoring morphology displays exceptional catalytic activity for OER, with a lower overpotential of 347 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Vishwakarma Ravikumar Ramlal, Kinjal B. Patel, Savan K. Raj, Divesh N. Srivastava, Amal Kumar Mandal</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00609</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface plasmon enhancement of 1D Ag nanowires modified electro-treated BiVO4 photoanode with abundant oxygen vacancies for solar water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131847</link>
      <description>Song Zhang, Hongjun Zhang, Yuantong Gu, Xiangling Mao, Xiaoying Gao, Dongbo Xu, Fuel. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396764166

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Song Zhang, Hongjun Zhang, Yuantong Gu, Xiangling Mao, Xiaoying Gao, Dongbo Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131847</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#945;-Mn2O3 porous fibers synthesized by air-heated solution blow spinning (A-HSBS) technique: electrochemical assessment for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112086</link>
      <description>Rondinele N. Araujo, Rafael A. Raimundo, Gelmires de Ara&#250;jo Neves, Valmor Roberto Mastelaro, Daniel A. Macedo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, Marco A. Morales, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396768572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rondinele N. Araujo, Rafael A. Raimundo, Gelmires de Ara&#250;jo Neves, Valmor Roberto Mastelaro, Daniel A. Macedo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, Marco A. Morales, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Incorporated Metal-Organic Cobalt Hydroxide Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00871-0</link>
      <description>Tao Jiang, Yuechao Yao, Feiyan Wu, Iram Aziz, Wenjing Zhang, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396769418

                Abstract Metal-organic cobalt hydroxide emerges as a cost-effective electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in energy conversion. However, the limited active sites and poor conductivity hinder their large-scale application. This study employed salicylate as a bridging ligand to synthesize iron-incorporated metal-organic cobalt hydroxide. The influence of Fe intercalation on Co(OH)(Hsal) (where Hsal denotes o -HOC 6 H 4 COO &#8722; ) was investigated using X-ray diffraction (XRD) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). Fe 0.2 Co 0.8 (OH)(Hsal) demonstrates remarkable electrocatalytic activity, displaying an OER overpotential of 298 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 57.46 mV dec &#8722;1 . This enhancement can be attributed to improved charge transfer kinetics and increased active sites. This work highlights the crucial role of Fe in improving the efficiency of Co-based oxygen-evolving catalysts (OECs) and its potential for boosting efficient hydrogen generation in alkaline environments. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Jiang, Yuechao Yao, Feiyan Wu, Iram Aziz, Wenjing Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00871-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Design and Insights into Lanthanum and Strontium Perovskite Oxides for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions (Small 19/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202470144</link>
      <description>Sagar Ingavale, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Carolin Mercy Enoch, Chanon Pornrungroj, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Kasadit Nootong, Rojana Pornprasertsuk, Soorathep Kheawhom, Small. 20(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396770128

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sagar Ingavale, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Carolin Mercy Enoch, Chanon Pornrungroj, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Kasadit Nootong, Rojana Pornprasertsuk, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202470144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge Redistribution of Lattice&#8208;Mismatched Co&#9472;Cu&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;P Boosting pH&#8208;Universal Water/Seawater Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400244</link>
      <description>Yu Zhang, Kun Li, Yongkang Li, Jianli Mi, Caixia Li, Hongdong Li, Lei Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396771909

                Abstract Practical applications of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) rely on the development of highly efficient, stable, and low&#8208;cost catalysts. Tuning the electronic structure, morphology, and architecture of catalysts is an important way to realize efficient and stable HER electrocatalysts. Herein, Co&#8208;doped Cu 3 P&#8208;based sugar&#8208;gourd structures (Co&#9472;Cu 3 P/CF) are prepared on copper foam as active electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution. This hierarchical structure facilitates fast mass transport during electrocatalysis. Notably, the introduction of Co not only induces a charge redistribution but also leads to lattice&#8208;mismatch on the atomic scale, which creates defects and performs as additional active sites. Therefore, Co&#9472;Cu 3 P/CF requires an overpotential of only 81, 111, 185, and 230 mV to reach currents of 50, 100, 500, and 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline media and remains stable after 10 000 CV cycles in a row and up to 110 h i&#8211;t stability tests. In addition, it also shows excellent HER performance in water/seawater electrolytes of different pH values. Experimental and DFT show that the introduction of Co modulates the electronic and energy level structures of the catalyst, optimizes the adsorption and desorption behavior of the intermediate, reduces the water dissociation energy barrier during the reaction, accelerates the Volmer step reaction, and thus improves the HER performance.</description>
      <author>Yu Zhang, Kun Li, Yongkang Li, Jianli Mi, Caixia Li, Hongdong Li, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400244</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Substantial Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Performances of Activated Carbon-Decorated Vanadium Pentoxide Nanocomposites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9953038</link>
      <description>Sejoon Lee, P. Ilanchezhiyan, Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Youngmin Lee, Seung Joo Lee, International journal of energy research. 2024(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396777489

                Developing the ecofriendly and high-fidelity electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential to foster effective production of environmentally friendly hydrogen. Herein, we fabricated the highly efficient OER electrocatalysts of the activated carbon-decorated vanadium pentoxide (AC-V2O5) nanocomposites using a facile hydrothermal technique. The AC-V2O5 nanocomposites displayed an aggregated structure of the AC nano-sheet-anchored orthorhombic V2O5 nanorods. When performing the OER process in an alkaline electrolyte at 10 mA/cm2, AC-V2O5 exhibited the low overpotential (~230 mV), small Tafel slope (~54 mV/dec), and excellent stability. These substantial OER performances of AC-V2O5 could be ascribed to the synergistic effects from both the electrochemically active V2O5 nanorods and the highly conductive AC nanosheets. The results infer that the AC-V2O5 nanocomposites possess a substantial aptitude as a high-performance OER electrocatalyst for production of the future green energy source&#8212;hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Sejoon Lee, P. Ilanchezhiyan, Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Youngmin Lee, Seung Joo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9953038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoSe2 and MoSe2 co-assembled durable bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction and urea oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.001</link>
      <description>Li Zhu, Youwei Cheng, Yaqiong Gong, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396785571

                The development of dual-function electrocatalysts has a very broad application prospect in renewable energy conversion technology. Herein, bifunctional Co0&#183;9Mo0.1-Se/Cu7Se4 heterojunction electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR) were prepared. Notably, selenization by strong reducibility triggered the generation of abundant Co3+ active sites and heterogeneous structures, as well as improved electrical conductivity. The Co0&#183;9Mo0.1-Se/Cu7Se4 electrocatalyst showed excellent OER activity, requiring only 202 mV overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and the Tafel slope was only 78.91 mV dec&#8722;1. Overpotential of the catalyst did not change significantly during the 38 h stability test, indicating that the electrocatalyst had excellent long-term stability. Moreover, when Co0&#183;9Mo0.1-Se/Cu7Se4 was used as the UOR electrode, the heterojunction required 1.29 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The cost-effective bifunctional metal selenide heterojunctions introduced in this study provide a research strategy for the prepared green electrode materials for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Li Zhu, Youwei Cheng, Yaqiong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field Enhanced Cobalt Iridium Alloy Catalyst for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01623</link>
      <description>Lamei Li, Wei Wang, Renat R. Nazmutdinov, Rustem Zairov, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396789802

                Magnetic field mediated magnetic catalysts provide a powerful pathway for accelerating their sluggish kinetics toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) but remain great challenges in acidic media. The key obstacle comes from the production of an ordered magnetic domain catalyst in the harsh acidic OER. In this work, we form an induced local magnetic moment in the metallic Ir catalyst via the significant 3d&#8211;5d hybridization by introducing cobalt dopants. Interestingly, CoIr nanoclusters (NCs) exhibit an excellent magnetic field enhanced acidic OER activity, with the lowest overpotential of 220 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and s long-term stability of 120 h under a constant magnetic field (vs 260 mV/20 h without a magnetic field). The turnover frequency reaches 7.4 s&#8211;1 at 1.5 V (vs RHE), which is 3.0 times higher than that without magnetization. Density functional theory results show that CoIr NCs have a pronounced spin polarization intensity, which is preferable for OER enhancement.</description>
      <author>Lamei Li, Wei Wang, Renat R. Nazmutdinov, Rustem Zairov, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe site regulation and activity deciphering by selective phase transformation in the confined FeNi nanoparticles for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152113</link>
      <description>Zongyuan Ma, Jiawei Wu, Feng Yang, Shuli Wang, Huan Wen, Ligang Feng, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396796451

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zongyuan Ma, Jiawei Wu, Feng Yang, Shuli Wang, Huan Wen, Ligang Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing a potential electrocatalyst: highly multi-porous Co3O4 nanostructures to enhance electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05576-4</link>
      <description>Sathyanarayanan Shanmugapriya, Aneesha Singh, Ratiram Gomaji Chaudhary, Sudip Mondal, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Pranali Hadole, Aniruddha Mondal, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396801878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sathyanarayanan Shanmugapriya, Aneesha Singh, Ratiram Gomaji Chaudhary, Sudip Mondal, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Pranali Hadole, Aniruddha Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05576-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Attaining Substantially Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Rates on Ni Foam Catalysts in a Gas Diffusion Electrode Setup</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400050</link>
      <description>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz, Advanced energy and sustainability research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396806504

                Water electrolysis plays a central role in the transition to a fossil&#8208;free society, but there are significant challenges to overcome in order to increase its availability on a large scale. Alkaline water electrolysis is a mature and scalable technology, although it has several disadvantages compared to electrolyzers working in acidic environments. In particular, the use of highly alkaline aqueous electrolytes can lead to corrosion, and the achieved current densities are relatively low. This study addresses the latter limitation by introducing a gas diffusion electrode (GDE) setup as a novel development tool that bridges the gap between research and practical applications in commercial devices such as fuel cells and electrolyzers. A high surface area Ni foam catalyst that can sustain exceptional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) current densities of up to 4 A cm &#8722;2 in a quasi&#8208;steady&#8208;state within our GDE setup operating in an alkaline environment is presented. The high performance of this Ni&#8208;based benchmark catalyst is attributed to its deposition onto a mesh&#8208;like porous transport layer (PTL) via hydrogen&#8208;templated electrodeposition. This forms a porous foam&#8208;like structure that augments the mass transport of the gaseous reactants at the GDE.</description>
      <author>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co3O4 derived ZnO: An effective electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.087</link>
      <description>Abdul Hanan, Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Rashmi Walvekar, Mohd Ubaidullah, Abdullah A. Al&#8208;Kahtani, Mohammad Khalid, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396809600

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdul Hanan, Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Rashmi Walvekar, Mohd Ubaidullah, Abdullah A. Al&#8208;Kahtani, Mohammad Khalid</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cerium doping modulates the surface electronic structure of IrOx/TiN to promote the stability of acid oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144418</link>
      <description>Xingxing Duan, Huiyuan Liu, Weiqi Zhang, Qiang Ma, Qian Xu, Lindiwe Khotseng, Huaneng Su, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396812876

                The stability of supported Ir-based catalysts in acid oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a pressing challenge, which hinders the commercial viability of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) technology. Herein, we propose a cerium doping strategy to enhance the stability of supported Ir-based catalyst toward OER. The Ce-doped supported catalysts, designated as Ce-IrOx/TiN, were synthesized using an organic colloidal method. Transmission Electron Microscopy (TEM) analysis reveals highly dispersed IrOx nanoparticles averaging 1.5 nm on the TiN support. X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS) investigations further elucidate that Ce doping effectively stabilizes the Ir species predominantly in states below 4+, crucial for modulating the surface electronic structure and thereby improving both the activity and stability of the catalysts. Electrochemical characterization highlights the superior performance of the optimized catalyst, 6%-Ce-IrOx/TiN, with an impressively low overpotential of 242 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 57.5 mV dec&#8722;1, showcasing its significance in facilitating OER. Moreover, its mass activity surpasses that of commercial IrO2 by 5.1 times at 1.7 V. Prolonged constant current testing further demonstrates the exceptional stability of the catalyst, affirming the critical role of Ce doping as a pivotal strategy for enhancing the stability of supported Ir-based catalysts and advancing the prospects for robust OER performance in PEMWE systems.</description>
      <author>Xingxing Duan, Huiyuan Liu, Weiqi Zhang, Qiang Ma, Qian Xu, Lindiwe Khotseng, Huaneng Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-Induced Electronic Structure Modulation of Self-Evolved Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets for the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01051</link>
      <description>Liujun Jin, Chengying Yang, Shuyi Chen, Jili Hou, P. Liu, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396815156

                Modulating the electronic structure of the electrocatalyst plays a vital role in boosting the electrocatalytic performance of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this work, we introduced a one-step solvothermal method to fabricate 1,1-ferrocene dicarboxylic acid (FcDA)-decorated self-evolved nickel sulfide (Ni3S2) nanosheet arrays on a nickel foam (NF) framework (denoted as FcDA-Ni3S2/NF). Benefiting from the interconnected ultrathin nanosheet architecture, ligand dopants induced and facilitated in situ structural reconstruction, and the FcDA-decorated Ni3S2 (FcDA-Ni3S2/NF) outperformed its singly doped and undoped counterparts in terms of OER activity. The optimized FcDA-Ni3S2/NF self-supported electrode presents a remarkably low overpotential of 268 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 for the OER and demonstrates robust electrochemical stability for 48 h in a 1.0 M KOH electrolyte. More importantly, in situ electrochemical Raman spectroscopy reveals the generation of catalytically active oxyhydroxide species (NiOOH) derived from the surface construction during the OER of pristine FcDA-Ni3S2/NF, contributing significantly to its superior electrocatalytic performance. This study concerns the modulation of electronic structure through ligand engineering and may provide profound insight into the design of cost-efficient OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Liujun Jin, Chengying Yang, Shuyi Chen, Jili Hou, P. Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Oxygen Vacancies in In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; with Enhanced Polysulfides Immobilization and Selective Catalytic Capability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401567</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Huanhuan Li, Jie Ji, Jingjie Liu, Qing Zhang, Sheng Ma, Jun L&#252;, Zhengyu Bai, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396827079

                Abstract Lithium&#8211;sulfur (Li&#8211;S) battery is identified as an ideal candidate for next&#8208;generation energy storage systems in consideration of its high theoretical energy density and abundant sulfur resources. However, the shuttling behavior of soluble polysulfides (LiPSs) and their sluggish reaction kinetics severely limit the practical application of the current Li&#8211;S battery. In this work, a series of In 2 O 3 nanocubes with different oxygen vacancy concentrations are designed and prepared via a facile self&#8208;template method. The introduced oxygen vacancy on In 2 O 3 can effectively rearrange the charge distribution and enhance sulfiphilic property. Moreover, the In 2 O 3 with high oxygen vacancy concentration (H&#8208;In 2 O 3 ) can slightly slow down the solid&#8211;liquid conversion process and significantly accelerate the liquid&#8211;solid conversion process, thus reducing the accumulation of LiPSs in electrolyte and inhibiting the shuttle effect. Contributed by the unique selective catalytic capability, the prepared H&#8208;In 2 O 3 exhibits excellent electrochemical performance when used as sulfur host. For instance, a high reversible capacity of 609 mAh g &#8722;1 is obtained with only 0.044% capacity decay per cycle over 1000 cycles at 1.0 C. This work presents a typical example for designing advanced sulfur hosts, which is crucial for the commercialization of Li&#8211;S battery.</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Huanhuan Li, Jie Ji, Jingjie Liu, Qing Zhang, Sheng Ma, Jun L&#252;, Zhengyu Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401567</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultra-High Performance of In Situ Constructed Trimetallic (Pd, Fe, Co) Nanoparticles on Carbon Paper as an Electrocatalyst for Large Current Density Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4a0c</link>
      <description>Theophile Niyitanga, Gyawali Ghanashyam, Dieudonne Tanue Nde, Haekyoung Kim, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396830767

                Abstract Seawater electrocatalysis holds significant promise as a technology for hydrogen production. A simple and low-cost impregnation-hydrothermal and thermal reduction strategy was used to synthesis in-situ constructed three-dimensional porous trimetallic (Pd, Fe, and Co) anchored on a cheap and high-conducting carbon paper (CP) electrode for water electrolysis in alkaline media. The fabricated PdFeCo1&#8722;xONPs@CP electrode had superhydrophilic and superaerophobic properties, allowing for efficient removal of oxygen bubbles from the electrode surface due to the close interaction between the electrode and electrolyte. Furthermore, the synergistic effect of trimetallics and CP-fibers significantly increased OER intrinsic activity. PdFeCo1&#8722;xONPs@CP catalyst demonstrated critical low overpotentials of 220 and 300 mV, resulting in an extraordinarily high current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2. For the full cell overall water splitting performance, cell overpotentials as low as 140 and 151 mV were needed to drive 10 mA cm-2 in seawater and alkaline solution electrolytes.</description>
      <author>Theophile Niyitanga, Gyawali Ghanashyam, Dieudonne Tanue Nde, Haekyoung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4a0c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finite element modeling simulation of oxygen evolution during charging in lithium-oxygen batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107752</link>
      <description>Shuji Hanada, Shuji Nakanishi, Yoshiharu Mukouyama, Electrochemistry communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834585

                The quest for advanced energy storage solutions has intensified the focus on developing next-generation secondary batteries, with lithium-oxygen batteries (LOB) standing out for their superior theoretical gravimetric energy density. This study introduces a novel model-based approach to battery development, enabling the detailed analysis of charge&#8211;discharge cycles and oxygen evolution efficiency within a virtual environment. Our model distinctively simulates the oxidative decomposition of lithium peroxide (Li2O2) and differentiates between its formation through solution and surface pathways, addressing the complexities of the charging process and its multiple elementary steps. The developed model further categorizes the oxidative decomposition species into four distinct types, facilitating a comprehensive understanding of their interactions, voltage profile changes, and O2 evolution within the battery's porous cathode. This approach not only enhances the understanding of battery behavior but also aids in refining the design of component materials, thereby propelling forward the development of LOBs with improved energy density and cycle performance.</description>
      <author>Shuji Hanada, Shuji Nakanishi, Yoshiharu Mukouyama</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.elecom.2024.107752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Electrocatalytic Activity Of Selenide Nanoparticle For Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174797</link>
      <description>H.H. Somaily, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835403

                Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) plays a vital role in water electrolysis, but its slow kinetics and expensive catalysts are obstacles to widespread use. To improve the OER activity, it is crucial to create a well-structured design for electrocatalysts based on transition metals, which may be applied to a conducting polymer substrate. This research reports a facile hydrothermal synthesis and remarkable catalytic behavior of NbSe2/g-CN as an OER catalyst in an alkaline condition. The fabricated electrocatalysts were examined utilizing numerous analytical techniques to assess their crystallinity, oxidation states and morphology. NbSe2/g-CN shows enhanced electro-catalytic behavior to OER in alkaline solution (1.0 KOH) with minor overpotential (196 mV) and Tafel slop (38 mV/dec) than pristine NbSe2 electrocatalyst was associated with the exceptional conductivity of NF and its highly porous structure, along with a greater SSA. In addition, the durability of the electrocatalyst was examined via cyclic stability and chronoamperometry study over 40 h. This study demonstrates that TMSe with specific morphology can improve electrocatalytic activity when combined with g-CN, demonstrating its potential for reliable and eco-friendly energy generation</description>
      <author>H.H. Somaily</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Morphology Structures on Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performances of Mo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Mxene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/1674-0068/cjcp2401006</link>
      <description>, Chinese Journal of Chemical Physics/Chinese journal of chemical physics. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4396798559

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/1674-0068/cjcp2401006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doped Cobalt Oxide Catalysts for Aqueous, Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution and Alcohol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7302/4739</link>
      <description>Samuel E. Michaud, Deep Blue (University of Michigan). None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4396759591

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Samuel E. Michaud</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7302/4739</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Tailoring of Cuco2o4 for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820433</link>
      <description>Qi Dong, Bin Wen, Xin Zhao, Peiyi Wang, Xiao Lyu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713715

                Electronic structure tuning in metal oxides is a facile and effective strategy on boosting their catalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Here, we demonstrate the electronic structure tuning of CuCo2O4 by phosphorus (P) doping via in-situ diffusion method. The results found that due to more electrons transferred from P to the neighboring Co3+, the tuned Co was served as OER active sites, which contributes to an extraordinary OER performance. The synthesized P3.85-CCO/NF exhibits an overpotential of 250 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm-2, and a Tafel slope of 27 mV dec-1, which performs an enhanced OER activity than that of IrO2/NF. Moreover, the P3.85-CCO/NF presents stable electrochemical performances upon long-time running for 30 h. Thus, the electronic structure tuning strategy by in-situ P diffusion method emerges as an effective approach on enhancing the catalytic OER performance for metal oxide electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Qi Dong, Bin Wen, Xin Zhao, Peiyi Wang, Xiao Lyu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Systematic exploration of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</link>
      <description>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng, Computational and theoretical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396807019

                The reaction rate of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an important factor restricting its application. In this work, we have systematic explorated of N, O coordination number on the catalytic performance for ORR and OER. Firstly, a variety of stability analysis methods show that most of the catalysts have excellent stability. Secondly, a series of excellent bifunctional catalysts are screened by volcanic maps, ORR overpotential (&#951;ORR), OER overpotential (&#951;OER), and bifunctional index (BI), such as, RhN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.28 V, &#951;OER = 0.34 V, BI = 0.62 V) and CoN3O1-1 (&#951;ORR = 0.33 V, &#951;OER = 0.37 V, BI = 0.70 V). In particular, RhN3O1-1 has the smallest BI value, indicating that it has the best bifunctional catalytic activity. This study offers insights into how the coordination environment affects the activity of OER/ORR.</description>
      <author>Xianjun Chen, Chao Zhang, X X Li, Tao Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.comptc.2024.114642</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction by in situ growth PMo12@ZIF-67 on MWCNTs via perylene bisimide-based dispersant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174762</link>
      <description>Xinlun Song, Junshuo Cui, Zhenning Lou, Wei Shan, Hai Yu, Xiaogeng Feng, Yuejiao Wang, Ying Xiong, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396797177

                The combination of metal organic frameworks (MOFs) and multi-walled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) can significantly improve their electrochemical performance. However, in most cases, chemical pre-treatment of MWCNTs is inevitable, which may compromise the ideal performance of the final composites. Herein, via a noncovalent functionalization method, PMo12@ZIF-67 was in situ grown on the surfaces of MWCNTs with the assistance of a new dispersant containing two triethylenetetramine (TETA) segments. In order to enhance the coordination of Co metal ions with the surface of MWCNTs, phenolic hydroxyl groups were incorporated into the dispersant through reaction with gallic acid (GA). After annealing, homogeneous CNT/Co6Mo6C2/Co composites were obtained, and they showed excellent performance on oxygen evolution reaction (OER). At a current density of 10 mA cm-2, the lowest overpotential is 263 mV, of which the performance is superior to that achieved by other in situ growth methods. The uniform distribution of coordination sites and subsequent in situ growth of MOFs on MWCNTs improved the electrical conductivity of the derivatives, thereby enhanced the utilization of catalytic active sites. This study presents a novel approach for synthesizing carbon-doped electrocatalytic materials, which demonstrates significant potential in various electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Xinlun Song, Junshuo Cui, Zhenning Lou, Wei Shan, Hai Yu, Xiaogeng Feng, Yuejiao Wang, Ying Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174762</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically dispersed hexavalent iridium oxide from MnO &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction for oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adg5193</link>
      <description>Ailong Li, Shiao&#8208;Tong Kong, Kiyohiro Adachi, Hideshi Ooka, Kazuna Fushimi, Qike Jiang, Hironori Ofuchi, Satoru Hamamoto, M. Oura, Kentaro Higashi, Takuma Kaneko, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura, Science. 384(6696)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396759836

                Hexavalent iridium (Ir</description>
      <author>Ailong Li, Shiao&#8208;Tong Kong, Kiyohiro Adachi, Hideshi Ooka, Kazuna Fushimi, Qike Jiang, Hironori Ofuchi, Satoru Hamamoto, M. Oura, Kentaro Higashi, Takuma Kaneko, Tomoya Uruga, N. Kawamura, Daisuke Hashizume, Ryuhei Nakamura</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1126/science.adg5193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instability of Cobalt-Substituted Polyoxometalates during the Oxygen Evolution Reaction: An &lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01265</link>
      <description>Benjamin Rotonnelli, Benedikt Lassalle&#8208;Kaiser, Antoine Bonnefont, S&#233;verine Renaudineau, Delphine Garnier, Anna Proust, Fabrice Bournel, Jean&#8208;Jacques Gallet, Tristan Asset, Elena R. Savinova, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396669935

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benjamin Rotonnelli, Benedikt Lassalle&#8208;Kaiser, Antoine Bonnefont, S&#233;verine Renaudineau, Delphine Garnier, Anna Proust, Fabrice Bournel, Jean&#8208;Jacques Gallet, Tristan Asset, Elena R. Savinova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZnCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/NC Hollow Polyhedra for Bisphenol A Disposal and the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01442</link>
      <description>Jiao Wang, Xizhi Huang, Lei Bai, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396804842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiao Wang, Xizhi Huang, Lei Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrO2-ZrO2-SiO2 ternary oxide composites- based DSAs: Activity toward oxygen evolution reaction with long-term stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105548</link>
      <description>Mir Majid Hosseini, Mir Ghasem Hosseini, Iraj Ahadzadeh, Reza Najjar, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 161(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822732

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mir Majid Hosseini, Mir Ghasem Hosseini, Iraj Ahadzadeh, Reza Najjar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet Dependence of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;, CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;, and Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Epitaxial Film Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13595</link>
      <description>Earl Matthew Davis, Arno Bergmann, H. Kuhlenbeck, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721089

                The main obstacle for the electrocatalytic production of "green hydrogen" is finding suitable electrocatalysts which operate highly efficiently over extended periods of time. The topic of this study is the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), one of the half-reactions of water splitting. It is complex and has intricate kinetics, which impairs the reaction efficiency. Transition metal oxides have shown potential as electrocatalysts for this reaction, but much remains unknown about the atomic scale processes. We have investigated structure-composition-reactivity correlations for Co</description>
      <author>Earl Matthew Davis, Arno Bergmann, H. Kuhlenbeck, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure and Texture Evolution in Cold-Rolled and Annealed Oxygen-Free Copper Sheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102202</link>
      <description>Jing Qin, Xun Li, Dongsheng Wang, Chen Zhou, Tao Hu, Jingwen Wang, Youwen Yang, Yujun Hu, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721951

                Commercial oxygen-free copper sheets were cold-rolled with reduction rates ranging from 20% to 87% and annealed at 400, 500 and 600 &#176;C. The microstructure and texture evolution during the cold-rolling and annealing processes were studied using optical microscopy (OM), scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and electron back-scattered diffraction (EBSD). The results show that the deformation textures of {123}&lt;634&gt; (S), {112}&lt;111&gt; (Copper) and {110}&lt;112&gt; (Brass) were continuously enhanced with the increase in cold-rolling reduction. The orientations along the &#945;-oriented fiber converged towards Brass, and the orientation density of &#946; fiber obviously increased when the rolling reduction exceeded 60%. The recrystallization texture was significantly affected by the cold-rolling reduction. After 60% cold-rolling reduction, Copper and S texture components gradually decreased, and the {011}&lt;511&gt; recrystallization texture component formed with the increase in annealing temperature. After 87% cold-rolling reduction, a strong Cube texture formed, and other textures were inhibited with the increase in annealing temperature. The strong Brass and S deformation texture was conducive to the formation of a strong Cube annealing texture. The density of the annealing twin boundary decreased with the increase in annealing temperature, and more annealing twin boundaries formed in the oxygen-free copper sheets with the increase in cold-rolling reduction.</description>
      <author>Jing Qin, Xun Li, Dongsheng Wang, Chen Zhou, Tao Hu, Jingwen Wang, Youwen Yang, Yujun Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The oxygen fugacity of intermediate shergottite NWA 11043: implications for Martian mantle evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.008</link>
      <description>J F Chen, Yuyan Zhao, Qin Shu, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Du, Jian Yang, Geochimica et cosmochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835137

                Shergottite meteorites, classified as depleted, intermediate, or enriched based on incompatible trace elements and specific radiogenic isotope compositions (Sr, Nd, and Hf isotope ratios), point to multiple Martian mantle source regions. The oxygen fugacity (fO2) of these mantle regions, determined from early crystallizing minerals using the olivine-pyroxene-spinel oxybarometer, appears to correlate with incompatible trace element enrichment and isotope compositions. However, values derived from the vanadium-in-olivine oxybarometer challenge this correlation, hinting at potential biases in oxybarometry or complexities in the redox conditions of the Martian mantle. By analyzing the intermediate shergottite Northwest Africa (NWA) 11043 with various oxybarometers, this study deduced its origin from a reduced mantle source, with an average fO2 value of &#8722;0.77 &#177; 0.35 relative to the iron-w&#252;stite (IW) buffer. Notably, these values coincide with those of depleted shergottites, which represent the depleted Martian mantle region. This redox similarity between intermediate and depleted shergottites contrasts with earlier notions that postulated intermediate shergottites as a mix of depleted and enriched mantle derivatives. Moreover, intermediate shergottites such as NWA 11043, Elephant Moraine (EETA) 79001A, and Allan Hills (ALH) 77005 display 176Hf/177Hf values akin to those of depleted shergottites, suggesting that intermediate mantle components can be separated from the depleted mantle source at approximately 2.2 Ga based on model age calculations. Therefore, there presents a consistent redox state between mantle magma sources of both intermediate and depleted shergottites since the Hesperian period, while enriched shergottites lean toward more oxidized conditions past source formation. This study prompts a reassessment of conventional theories, emphasizing the nuanced redox evolution of the Martian mantle across distinct mantle source regions and underscoring the complexity of the redox evolution of the Martian mantle. The emergence of chemically diverse mantle reservoirs might predominantly arise from early magma ocean differentiation processes, albeit with inherent oxidation nuances. The differences in fO2 observed between intermediate and depleted shergottites underscore the need for more in-depth studies to decipher Martian mantle differentiation and evolution.</description>
      <author>J F Chen, Yuyan Zhao, Qin Shu, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Du, Jian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.gca.2024.05.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Engineering of Pt&#8211;Ni Alloy NPs by Coupling of Gold Single Atoms on N&#8208;Doped Carbon for Highly Efficient Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311971</link>
      <description>Tuyen D. Le, Dong&#8208;Seog Kim, Tuong Van Tran, U. Bharagav, Gi&#8208;Seung Shin, Geun&#8208;Jae Oh, Yeon&#8208;Tae Yu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396799524

                Abstract Improving the catalytic activity and durability of platinum&#8208;based alloy catalysts remains a formidable challenge in the context of renewable energy electrolysis applications. Herein, a facile and rapid photochemical deposition strategy for the synthesis of gold single atoms (Au SAs) anchored on N&#8208;doped carbon is presented. These Au SAs serve as a charge redistribution support for Pt&#8211;Ni alloy nanoparticles (PtNi NPs /Au SA &#8208;NDC), creating an extended electron&#8208;donating interface with Pt&#8211;Ni alloy sites. Consequently, the PtNi NPs /Au SA &#8208;NDC hybrid catalyst manifests exceptional catalytic performance and durability in both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) under acidic conditions. Specifically, in ORR, it exhibits a half&#8208;wave potential (0.92 V vs RHE), with a mass activity 20.4 times superior to Pt/C at 0.9 V. In HER, PtNi NPs /Au SA &#8208;NDC demonstrates a notably reduced overpotential of 19.1 mV vs RHE at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a mass activity 38 times higher than Pt/C (at 0.25 mV). Furthermore, this hybrid catalyst displays outstanding durability, with only an 8.0 mV decay observed for ORR and a 6.9 mV decay for HER after 10 000 cycles. Theoretical calculations provide insight into the mechanism, demonstrating that isolated Au sites effectively modulate the electronic structure of Pt&#8211;Ni alloy sites, facilitating intermediate adsorption and enhancing reaction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Tuyen D. Le, Dong&#8208;Seog Kim, Tuong Van Tran, U. Bharagav, Gi&#8208;Seung Shin, Geun&#8208;Jae Oh, Yeon&#8208;Tae Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311971</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Light Absorption and Photo&#8208;Generated Charge Separation Efficiency for Boosting Photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Evolution through TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Quantum Dots with N&#8208;Doping and Concomitant Oxygen Vacancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311861</link>
      <description>Ziwei Pan, Zhu Xi, Yuxin Liu, Long Yang, Mingyang Jiao, Shichang Kang, Junhai Luo, Xiangkai Fu, Wenqiang Lu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396676929

                Low-range light absorption and rapid recombination of photo-generated charge carriers have prevented the occurrence of effective and applicable photocatalysis for decades. Quantum dots (QDs) offer a solution due to their size-controlled photon properties and charge separation capabilities. Herein, well-dispersed interstitial nitrogen-doped TiO</description>
      <author>Ziwei Pan, Zhu Xi, Yuxin Liu, Long Yang, Mingyang Jiao, Shichang Kang, Junhai Luo, Xiangkai Fu, Wenqiang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the origin of Co-based bimetallic catalysts with para-structure exhibiting ORR and OER bifunctional activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00793j</link>
      <description>Yixin Zhu, Han Cui, Zhenqian Chen, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396754301

                The development of non-precious metal catalysts with oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) bifunctional activities is of great significance for the development of fuel cells. In this...</description>
      <author>Yixin Zhu, Han Cui, Zhenqian Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi00793j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchored Ru Clusters on lignin/algae carbon aerogel as efficient bifunctional catalysts for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00409d</link>
      <description>Pengfei Li, Zhenping Cheng, Weidong Chai, Yao Ya, Ning Zhang, Yi Hong, Yanping Wang, Yi Luo, Liang Zhou, Lulu Zhou, Jianming Zhang, Z Wang, Tian-shun Dong, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396663512

                As a dual-functional catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), Ru clusters have great potential, but there are certain difficulties in their stability on the substrate...</description>
      <author>Pengfei Li, Zhenping Cheng, Weidong Chai, Yao Ya, Ning Zhang, Yi Hong, Yanping Wang, Yi Luo, Liang Zhou, Lulu Zhou, Jianming Zhang, Z Wang, Tian-shun Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00409d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-noble metal coordinated hypercrosslinked polymers based on porphyrin for efficient electrocatalytic OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01234h</link>
      <description>Xin&#8208;Ming Hu, Penglei Cui, Hong Zhang, Zhongli He, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396711175

                The electrochemical catalysts for Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with abundant reserves, high catalytic activity, and robust stability are highly crucial for efficient electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, we designed and synthesized...</description>
      <author>Xin&#8208;Ming Hu, Penglei Cui, Hong Zhang, Zhongli He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01234h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PtAu alloying-modulated hydroxyl and substrate adsorptions for glycerol electrooxidation to C3 products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee00485j</link>
      <description>Yan Li, Xinfa Wei, Rui Pan, Y. Wang, Juanjuan Luo, Lanxin Li, Li&#8208;Song Chen, Jianlin Shi, Energy &amp; environmental science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396771467

                Substituting for oxygen evolution reaction with the thermodynamically favorable glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) in water splitting offers a promising approach to produce high-value chemicals in addition to hydrogen, which, however,...</description>
      <author>Yan Li, Xinfa Wei, Rui Pan, Y. Wang, Juanjuan Luo, Lanxin Li, Li&#8208;Song Chen, Jianlin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee00485j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong and Hierarchical Ni(OH)2/Ni/rGO Composites as Multifunctional Catalysts for Excellent Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14050309</link>
      <description>Lixin Wang, Ailing Song, Yonglai Lu, Manman Duanmu, Zhipeng Ma, Xiujuan Qin, Guangjie Shao, Catalysts. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691959

                The lack of efficient and non-precious metal catalysts poses a challenge for electrochemical water splitting in hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions. Here, we report on the preparation of growing Ni(OH)2 nanosheets in situ on a Ni and graphene hybrid using supergravity electrodeposition and the hydrothermal method. The obtained catalyst displays outstanding performance with small overpotentials of 161.7 and 41 mV to acquire current densities of 100 and 10 mA cm&#8722;2 on hydrogen evolution reaction, overpotentials of 407 and 331 mV to afford 100 and 50 mA cm&#8722;2 on oxygen evolution reaction, and 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 at a cell voltage of 1.43 V for water splitting in 1 M KOH. The electrochemical activity of the catalyst is higher than most of the earth-abundant materials reported to date, which is mainly due to its special hierarchical structure, large surface area, and good electrical conductivity. This study provides new tactics for enhancing the catalytic performance of water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Lixin Wang, Ailing Song, Yonglai Lu, Manman Duanmu, Zhipeng Ma, Xiujuan Qin, Guangjie Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14050309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F-regulated Ni2P-F3 nanosheets as efficient electrocatalysts for full-water-splitting and urea oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00615a</link>
      <description>Xiaoduan Sun, Shenhua Song, Guoying Yan, Yingchun Liu, Haojie Ding, Xiaojie Zhang, Yuanping Feng, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396680349

                Heteroatomic anion doping represents a powerful approach for manipulating the electronic configuration of the active metal locus in electrocatalysts, resulting in enhanced multifunctional electrocatalytic properties in hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER). Here, fluorine-tailored Ni</description>
      <author>Xiaoduan Sun, Shenhua Song, Guoying Yan, Yingchun Liu, Haojie Ding, Xiaojie Zhang, Yuanping Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00615a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three&#8208;dimensional interconnected graphene network&#8208;based high&#8208;performance air electrode for rechargeable zinc&#8210;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sus2.201</link>
      <description>Jiajia An, Yu Meng, Hong&#8208;Bo Zhang, Yuanzhi Zhu, Xiaohua Yu, Ju Rong, Peng&#8208;Xiang Hou, Chang Liu, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Li, SusMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396732299

                Abstract Although zinc&#8210;air batteries (ZABs) are regarded as one of the most prospective energy storage devices, their practical application has been restricted by poor air electrode performance. Herein, we developed a free&#8208;standing air electrode that is fabricated on the basis of a multifunctional three&#8208;dimensional interconnected graphene network. Specifically, a three&#8208;dimensional interconnected graphene network with fast mass and electron transport ability, prepared by catalyzing growth of graphene foam on nickel foam and then filling reduced graphene oxide into the pores of graphene foam, is used to anchor iron phthalocyanine molecules with atomic Fe&#8210;N 4 sites for boosting the oxygen reduction during discharging and nanosized FeNi hydroxides for accelerating the oxygen evolution during charging. As a result, the obtained air electrode exhibited an ultra&#8208;small electrocatalytic overpotential of 0.603 V for oxygen reactions, a high peak power density of 220.2 mW cm &#8210;2 , and a small and stable charge&#8210;discharge voltage gap of 0.70 V at 10 mA cm &#8210;2 after 1136 cycles. Furthermore, in situ Raman spectroscopy together with theoretical calculations confirmed that phase transformation of FeNi hydroxides takes place from &#945;&#8208;Ni(OH) x to &#946;&#8208;Ni(OH) x to &#947;&#8208;Ni (3+&#948;)+ OOH for the oxygen evolution reaction and Ni is the active center while Fe enhances the activity of Ni active sites.</description>
      <author>Jiajia An, Yu Meng, Hong&#8208;Bo Zhang, Yuanzhi Zhu, Xiaohua Yu, Ju Rong, Peng&#8208;Xiang Hou, Chang Liu, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sus2.201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toxicity of the sunscreen UV filter benzophenone-3 (OBZ) to the microalga Selenastrum capricornutum: An insight into OBZ&#8217;s damage to photosynthesis and respiration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.116441</link>
      <description>Yongfu Li, Tian Zhao, Meng Qin, Xingkai Che, Aihua Zhang, Ecotoxicology and environmental safety. 278(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396791907

                Oxybenzone (OBZ; benzophenone-3, CAS# 131&#8211;57&#8211;7), as a new pollutant and ultraviolet absorbent, shows a significant threat to the survival of phytoplankton. This study aims to explore the acute toxic effects of OBZ on the growth of the microalga Selenastrum capricornutum, as well as the mechanisms for its damage to the primary metabolic pathways of photosynthesis and respiration. The results demonstrated that the concentrations for 50 % of maximal effect (EC50) of OBZ for S. capricornutum were 9.07 mg L&#8722;1 and 8.54 mg L&#8722;1 at 72 h and 96 h, respectively. A dosage of 4.56 mg L&#8722;1 OBZ significantly lowered the photosynthetic oxygen evolution rate of S. capricornutum in both light and dark conditions for a duration of 2 h, while it had no effect on the respiratory oxygen consumption rate under darkness. OBZ caused a significant decline in the efficiency of photosynthetic electron transport due to its damage to photosystem II (PSII), thereby decreasing the photosynthetic oxygen evolution rate. Over-accumulated H2O2 was produced under light due to the damage caused by OBZ to the donor and acceptor sides of PSII, resulting in increased peroxidation of cytomembranes and inhibition of algal respiration. OBZ's damage to photosynthesis and respiration will hinder the conversion and reuse of energy in algal cells, which is an important reason that OBZ has toxic effects on S. capricornutum. The present study indicated that OBZ has an acute toxic effect on the microalga S. capricornutum. In the two most important primary metabolic pathways in algae, photosynthesis is more sensitive to the toxicity of OBZ than respiration, especially in the dark.</description>
      <author>Yongfu Li, Tian Zhao, Meng Qin, Xingkai Che, Aihua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoenv.2024.116441</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolysis &#8211; Alkaline electrolyzer with anion-exchange membrane | Alkaline anion exchange membrane electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00241-3</link>
      <description>S. Ramakrishnan, Mohamed Mamlouk, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713567

                This chapter examines alkaline anion exchange membrane (AAEM) electrolysis, exploring both its advantages and challenges. A comprehensive overview of the fundamentals of water electrolyzers is provided. This is followed by a detailed discussion on the advantages and challenges faced by AEM electrolyzers in comparison to alkaline water electrolyzers (AWE) and proton exchange membrane electrolyzers (PEMWE). AEM chemistry and degradation mechanism was reviewed. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysis is discussed in terms of the activity descriptors, mechanism, and performance across a wide range of pH levels. Conclusion and recommendation were made on the advancement required in AEM water electrolyzers performance, durability and scale up challenges to enable rapid deployment and competitive green hydrogen production to meet global NetZero hydrogen ambitions.</description>
      <author>S. Ramakrishnan, Mohamed Mamlouk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00241-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the Role of the Ionomer at the Triple-Phase Boundary in a Proton-Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00851</link>
      <description>Shu Yuan, Congfan Zhao, Junliang Zhang, Cehuang Fu, Junliang Zhang, Lu An, Xiuwen Cheng, Shuiyun Shen, Jiewei Yin, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721802

                In the anodic catalyst layer of a proton-exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolyzer, the triple-phase boundary (TPB) is mainly distributed on the surface of ultrafine iridium-based catalysts encapsulated by the ionomer within the catalyst-ionomer agglomerate. It is found that the ionomer at the TPB acts as a barrier to mass transport and a buffer for the bubble coverage during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The barrier effect can decrease the OER performance of the catalysts inside the agglomerate by &#8804;23%, while the buffer effect can separate the bubble evolution sites from the OER sites, turning the instant deactivation caused by the bubble coverage into a gradual performance loss caused by local water starvation. However, this local water starvation still deteriorates the catalyst performance because of the affinity of the ionomer surface for bubbles. Introducing additional transport paths into the agglomerate can reduce the barrier effect and regulate the bubble behavior, reducing the overpotential by 0.308 V at 5 A cm</description>
      <author>Shu Yuan, Congfan Zhao, Junliang Zhang, Cehuang Fu, Junliang Zhang, Lu An, Xiuwen Cheng, Shuiyun Shen, Jiewei Yin, Xiaohui Yan, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c00851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acanthosphere-like bimetallic sulfide Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF as bifunctional catalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118338</link>
      <description>Na Qin, Feifei Dai, Yanxue Xue, Da Gao, Y.-S Liu, Yayuan Zhang, Jianhua Chen, Qian Yang, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835212

                Reducing the overpotential of water splitting is an important strategy for achieving low-cost and large-scale production of hydrogen (H2) and oxygen (O2). It is shown that bimetallic sulfide combines the advantages of a single component and an ideal structure for efficient electrocatalysis. Hence, an acanthosphere-like bimetallic sulfide electrocatalyst Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF with high catalytic performance and superior durability was prepared by a simple one-pot method. In the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF achieved a Tafel slope of 62.7 mV dec-1, and an overpotential of 224 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Concomitantly, it also possesses a small overpotential of 96 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and low Tafel slope of 81.6 mV dec-1 at the used of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst. Moreover, the two-electrode system Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF||Cu9S5/Mo2S3/NF single cell requires only 1.55 V to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in overall water splitting. This work highlights the advantages of bimetallic sulfide combines structural for overpotential of water splitting and provides an idea for modifying the catalytic performance of single metal sulfides and preparing high-performance bimetallic sulfide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Na Qin, Feifei Dai, Yanxue Xue, Da Gao, Y.-S Liu, Yayuan Zhang, Jianhua Chen, Qian Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Ni&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; Content in Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; to Boost Hydrogen Peroxide Production for Electrochemical Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00436</link>
      <description>Wenjing Wang, Huaizhong Shi, Haizhou Huang, Hongying Liu, Chengxiang Li, Ya-jie Han, Industrial &amp; engineering chemistry research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396779118

                Hydrogen peroxide is a green oxidizing chemical with wide applications in industry. Its production heavily relies on the industrial anthraquinone process, which involves a large number of organic pollutants, challenging green and sustainable development. The recently developed pulsed electrochemical approach holds great potential for the green synthesis of hydrogen peroxide, but it is limited by the absence of highly efficient catalysts. Here, we report a strategy to improve the performance of Ni3S2 catalyst by tuning the content of Ni3+ species. The Ni3S2 catalyst exhibits good performance in oxygen evolution and oxygen reduction processes at the same time, leading to the formation of hydrogen peroxide. The enrichment of Ni3+ ensures the adsorption of reaction intermediates *O, *OH, and *OOH and promotes electron transfer during the reaction, thus facilitating hydrogen peroxide generation. By tuning the Ni3+ ratio in the Ni3S2 catalyst, the productivity of hydrogen peroxide was enhanced. The prepared hydrogen peroxide was used for propylene oxidation, resulting in pH-dependent products. This study highlights the significance of the design and rational synthesis of electrochemical catalysts for synthesizing hydrogen peroxide, which may be used for the electrochemical synthesis of chemicals.</description>
      <author>Wenjing Wang, Huaizhong Shi, Haizhou Huang, Hongying Liu, Chengxiang Li, Ya-jie Han</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c00436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photoelectrochemical water splitting coupled with pharmaceutical pollutants degradation on Zr:BiVO4 photoanodes by synergetic catalytic activity of NiFeOOH nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2024.05.012</link>
      <description>Prabhakarn Arunachalam, Maged N. Shaddad, Mabrook S. Amer, Abdulhadi AL-Qadi, Alexandria Engineering Journal /Alexandria Engineering Journal. 99(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396841236

                Globally, the emergence of drug-resistant bacteria has created an urgent need for an effective method to remove antibiotics from pharmaceutical wastewater. Engineering Bismuth vanadate (BiVO4) with an oxygen evolution cocatalyst (OEC) holds a promising potential for enhancing water splitting efficiency in the production of hydrogen (H2) using free solar energy. Here, we successfully developed a Zr:BiVO4/NiFeOOH heterojunction by electrodeposition and photoelectrochemical transformation. Zr:BiVO4/NiFeOOH photoanodes exhibit 5 fold superior photocurrent response at 1.23 V compared with Zr:BiVO4 electrodes, since NiFeOOH acts as an oxygen-releasing catalyst. Furthermore, the attained heterojunctioned electrode can effectively degrade TCH, riboflavin, and streptomycin in PEC. The degradation rate of TCH acquired 96% within 1 h, which is 3 times superior than the efficiency reported for pristine Zr:BiVO4 photoelectrodes. By introducing NiFeOOH into BiVO4, electron life-time was increased and electron-hole recombination was suppressed. In this study, we present a solar-driven, sustainable and effective way of treating wastewater and provide new insights into the process.</description>
      <author>Prabhakarn Arunachalam, Maged N. Shaddad, Mabrook S. Amer, Abdulhadi AL-Qadi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.aej.2024.05.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Doped carbon supported nickel selenide heterogeneous materials for Dual-Function water electrolysis catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160233</link>
      <description>Aixin Feng, Jiangtao Ma, H. Li, Tengfei Meng, Zhu Yu-jun, Kuo-Jung Huang, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396745401

                Developing efficient, economical, and resource-abundant dual-function electrocatalysts for water splitting is crucial. In this study, uniform growth of NiSex nanocrystals on Fe-doped XC-72 carbon (NS/XC-Fe) was achieved through a solvothermal method, resulting in the formation of a composite material with outstanding performance. NS/XC-Fe exhibits excellent catalytic performance for both oxygen evolution reaction (OER) (261 mV, 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) (275 mV, 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2) under alkaline conditions, owing to the introduction of iron and the construction of heterogeneous interfaces. Additionally, NS/XC-Fe exhibited excellent stability during the 24 h polarization test. Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations indicated that the introduction of iron optimized the catalyst's H adsorption capability, while the construction of heterogeneous interfaces lowered the energy barrier of the rate-determining step. This demonstrates the significant potential of NS/XC-Fe as an electrocatalyst, providing new insights for the design and synthesis of efficient bifunctional electrochemical water splitting catalysts.</description>
      <author>Aixin Feng, Jiangtao Ma, H. Li, Tengfei Meng, Zhu Yu-jun, Kuo-Jung Huang, Peng Wang, Yupei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Glucaric Acid Using Electrocatalyst Glucose Oxidation by the Ta NiFe LDH Electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02260</link>
      <description>Meysam Tayebi, Zohreh Masoumi, Bongkuk Seo, Choong&#8208;Sun Lim, Chae Hwan Hong, Hye Jin Kim, Daeseung Kyung, Hyeon&#8208;Gook Kim, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396805281

                The slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) significantly limits electrocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen production. We proposed the electrocatalyst for glucose oxidation by Ta-doping NiFe LDH nanosheets to simultaneously obtain glucaric acid (GRA) and hydrogen gas as a useful byproduct. Superior glucose oxidation reaction (GOR) activity is demonstrated by the optimized Ta&#8211;NiFe LDH, which has a low overpotential of 192 mV, allowing for a small Tafel slope of 70 mV dec&#8211;1 and a current density of 50 mA cm&#8211;2. The Ta NiFe LDH-oxidized glucose to GRA with a 72.94% yield and 64.3% Faradaic efficiency at 1.45 VRHE. Herein, we report the Ta NiFe LDH/NF electrode for the GOR&amp;hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), which exhibits a cell voltage of 1.62 V to reach a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2, which is 250 mV lower compared to OER&amp;HER (1.87 V). This study reveals that GOR is an energy-efficient and cost-effective method for producing H2 and valorizing biomass.</description>
      <author>Meysam Tayebi, Zohreh Masoumi, Bongkuk Seo, Choong&#8208;Sun Lim, Chae Hwan Hong, Hye Jin Kim, Daeseung Kyung, Hyeon&#8208;Gook Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-supported Ru-Fe-Ox nanospheres as efficient electrocatalyst to boost overall water-splitting in acid and alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.049</link>
      <description>Minjing Shang, Bowen Zhou, Huiqian Xiang, Yuecheng Gong, Liantao Xin, Weiping Xiao, Guangrui Xu, Chunlong Dai, Huadong Zhang, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396744195

                Developing electrocatalysts with high activity and durability for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in both acidic and alkaline electrolytes remains challenging. In this study, we synthesize a self-supported ruthenium-iron oxide on carbon cloth (Ru-Fe-Ox/CC) using solvothermal methods followed by air calcination. The morphology of the nanoparticle exposes numerous active sites vital for electrocatalysis. Additionally, the strong electronic interaction between Ru and Fe enhances electrocatalytic kinetics optimization. The porous structure of the carbon cloth matrix facilitates mass transport, improving electrolyte penetration and bubble release. Consequently, Ru-Fe-Ox/CC demonstrates excellent catalytic performance, achieving low overpotentials of 32 mV and 28 mV for HER and 216 mV and 228 mV for OER in acidic and alkaline electrolytes, respectively. Notably, only 1.48 V and 1.46 V are required to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for efficient water-splitting in both mediums, exhibiting remarkable stability. This research offers insights into designing versatile, highly efficient catalysts suitable for varied pH conditions.</description>
      <author>Minjing Shang, Bowen Zhou, Huiqian Xiang, Yuecheng Gong, Liantao Xin, Weiping Xiao, Guangrui Xu, Chunlong Dai, Huadong Zhang, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape&#8211;Preserved CoFeNi&#8211;MOF/NF Exhibiting Superior Performance for Overall Water Splitting across Alkaline and Neutral Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102195</link>
      <description>Yu Liu, Panpan Li, Zegao Wang, Liangjuan Gao, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691543

                This study reported a multi&#8211;functional Co0.45Fe0.45Ni0.9&#8211;MOF/NF catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and overall water splitting, which was synthesized via a novel shape&#8211;preserving two&#8211;step hydrothermal method. The resulting bowknot flake structure on NF enhanced the exposure of active sites, fostering a superior electrocatalytic surface, and the synergistic effect between Co, Fe, and Ni enhanced the catalytic activity of the active site. In an alkaline environment, the catalyst exhibited impressive overpotentials of 244 mV and 287 mV at current densities of 50 mA cm&#8722;2 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. Transitioning to a neutral environment, an overpotential of 505 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 was achieved with the same catalyst, showing a superior property compared to similar catalysts. Furthermore, it was demonstrated that Co0.45Fe0.45Ni0.9&#8211;MOF/NF shows versatility as a bifunctional catalyst, excelling in both OER and HER, as well as overall water splitting. The innovative shape&#8211;preserving synthesis method presented in this study offers a facile method to develop an efficient electrocatalyst for OER under both alkaline and neutral conditions, which makes it a promising catalyst for hydrogen production by water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yu Liu, Panpan Li, Zegao Wang, Liangjuan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Electrodeposition of Iron-Doped Nimo Alloys as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824059</link>
      <description>Ting Ren, Chen Tang, Xiao-Hui Huang, Jiangjin Chen, Guodong Feng, Fuxi Bao, Wen Guo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396817268

                Nickel-molybdenum (NiMo) alloy has been widely concerned in the field of electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution because of its excellent hydrogen evolution performance, but at the same time, NiMo alloy also faces the problem of poor oxygen evolution activity and molybdenum dissolution. Unlike other processes involving high-temperature and high-pressure reactions, electrodeposition has the advantages of a simple preparation device, controllable synthesis conditions and a shorter synthesis time. Herein, NiMo alloys with different iron content were prepared by a simple one-step electrodeposition method. The results of XRD and TEM demonstrate the successful doping of Fe. Doping Fe affects the electronic structure of NiMo, accelerates electron transfer and increases the number of active sites. Fe0.2-NiMo shows the best catalytic performance with HER/OER overpotential of 85 mV and 269 mV respectively at 10 mA cm-2. Fe0.2-NiMo can also be applied in large current, and HER/OER overpotential is only 319 mV and 316 mV when the current density is 500 mA cm-2. The resulting cell requires only 1.9 V voltage to achieve a current density of 500 mA cm-2. This work proves that Fe doping strategy is an efficient and feasible strategy for designing bifunctional NiMo alloy based electrocatalysts with high activity.</description>
      <author>Ting Ren, Chen Tang, Xiao-Hui Huang, Jiangjin Chen, Guodong Feng, Fuxi Bao, Wen Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4824059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Bifunctional NiFe-LDH@Co&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;8&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoflower Electrocatalysts Anchored with Pt Nanocrystal for Flexible Quasi-solid Rechargeable Zinc Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00988</link>
      <description>Jiongyu Chen, Li Zhi, Yuchen Liu, Zhe Cheng, Jingze Zhang, Qinghong Zhang, Yaogang Li, Chengyi Hou, Kerui Li, Hongzhi Wang, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396750416

                Efficient and affordable electrocatalysts are a crucial part of rechargeable zinc air batteries (ZAB) to address the problems caused by the sluggish activity of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on the cathode. Anchoring noble metals on transition-metal-based substances is a promising strategy to reinforce electrochemical activity and reduce the cost. Herein, we have developed a subsequent spontaneous-redox strategy to load Pt nanoparticles with 3.75% containing NiFe-LDH nanoflakes to boost the ORR activity. After that, NiFe-LDH@ Co9S8 is constructed as a rational design for bifunction catalysis. In the ORR process, the half-wave potential of the obtained catalyst, Pt-anchored NiFe-LDH@Co9S8, is 0.83 V vs RHE, showing better catalytic activity than Pt/C. In the OER process, the obtained catalyst exhibits a low overpotential of 280 mV, which is superior to that of RuO2. Notably, aqueous ZAB and quasi-solid-state ZAB achieve peak power densities of 164.3 and 78.4 mW cm&#8211;2, respectively. Furthermore, quasi-solid-state ZAB exhibits a long cycle lifespan for 240 cycles in 80 h, and a remarkable stability after bending for 50 cycles. This work paves the way for the design of the NiFe-LDH nanostructure by vacancy engineering.</description>
      <author>Jiongyu Chen, Li Zhi, Yuchen Liu, Zhe Cheng, Jingze Zhang, Qinghong Zhang, Yaogang Li, Chengyi Hou, Kerui Li, Hongzhi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-assembly of NiFe-LDH@Ni3S2 sub-nanosheets catalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114197</link>
      <description>Xiaotian Li, Si Tang, Qiang Han, Huiming Li, J.X. Wang, Molecular catalysis. 562(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396758980

                The development of water splitting catalysts for generating high-purity hydrogen in large-scale is still facing challenges in terms of improving efficiency and stability. Herein, Ni3S2-coated NiFe layered double hydroxides sub-nanosheets with a hierarchical heterostructure (NiFe-LDH@Ni3S2) were prepared on nickel foam (NF) by a strategy of continuous hydrothermal synthesis. The introduction of S2&#8722; broke the hydrogen bonds between NiFe-LDH layers and separated into sub-nanosheets with a thickness of only about 1 nm, which enlarged the active areas of NiFe-LDH@Ni3S2/NF by a factor of 5.7. The coexisting charge channels Ni-O-Ni and Ni-S-Ni in the material enhanced the electrochemical activity, resulting in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) overpotentials as low as 179 mV and 116 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1.0 M KOH. Moreover, after a 50-hour chronopotentiometry test at 50 mA cm&#8722;2, the overpotential for OER and HER decreased only 0.013 V and 0.059 V, respectively. Furthermore, under the conditions of simulating industrial hydrogen production with an electrolyte of 6.0 M KOH and a temperature of 75 &#176;C, after a 140-hour test for durability, the current density decreased only 0.75% at the cell voltage of 1.70 V.</description>
      <author>Xiaotian Li, Si Tang, Qiang Han, Huiming Li, J.X. Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Field Redistribution Triggered Surface Adsorption and Mass Transfer to Boost Electrocatalytic Glycerol Upgrading Coupled with Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400851</link>
      <description>Zhefei Zhao, Xinyi Shen, Xingyu Luo, Minhao Chen, M. Zhang, Ruipeng Yu, Renxi Jin, Huajun Zheng, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396685384

                Abstract Electrocatalytic glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) stands out as an economical and prospective technology to replace oxygen evolution reaction for co&#8208;producing high&#8208;valued chemicals and hydrogen (H 2 ). Regulating the adsorption of glycerol (GLY) and hydroxyl (OH) species is of great significance for improving the GOR performance. Herein, a hierarchical p&#8211;n heterojunction by combining Co&#8208;metal organic framework (MOF) nanosheets with CuO nanorod arrays (CuO@Co&#8208;MOF) is developed to realize the optimization on GOR. Specifically, CuO@Co&#8208;MOF electrode exhibits superior performance with a conversion of 98.4%, formic acid (FA) selectivity of 87.3%, and Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 98.9%. The flow&#8208;cell system with the bifunctional CuO@Co&#8208;MOF electrode for pairing GOR with the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) reveals better energy conversion efficiency. Experimental results and theoretical calculations unravel the redistributed electric field by introducing Co&#8208;containing species that contribute to the improved performance, which not only enhances the OH adsorption but also modulates the excessive GLY adsorption of CuO, thus reducing reaction energy barriers of FA desorption. Simultaneously, finite element analysis reveals that the novelty hierarchical structure can increase the concentration of OH &#8722; and facilitate the mass transfer of OH &#8722; in the solution.</description>
      <author>Zhefei Zhao, Xinyi Shen, Xingyu Luo, Minhao Chen, M. Zhang, Ruipeng Yu, Renxi Jin, Huajun Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of MOF-derived hollow sugar gourd-like Ni-Co-S@NiMoO4&#8226;xH2O nanocage arrays for efficient solar-powered overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115540</link>
      <description>Zhongtang Gao, Tengfei Zhang, Dianguo Xu, Ping Liu, Huan Liu, Huanhuan Li, Yanyan Liu, Feng Ye, Gang Wang, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396708238

                In situ growth of nanoarrays on conductive substrates is an efficient strategy for designing electrocatalysts. However, preparing array with excellent catalytic activities for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a challenge. Here, we construct a novel hollow sugar gourd-like Ni-Co-S@NiMoO4&#183;xH2O/NF nanocage array through MOF derivation strategy for stable solar-driven overall water splitting. Due to the hollow core&#8211;shell structure and multi-component advantages, the Ni-Co-S@NiMoO4&#183;xH2O/NF presents high density of active sites and fast charge transfer rate. Therefore, Ni-Co-S@NiMoO4&#183;xH2O/NF exhibits attractive electrocatalytic activity in alkaline electrolytes for HER (90 mV@10 mA cm&#8722;2) and OER (208 mV@10 mA cm&#8722;2, 245 mV@100 mA cm&#8722;2). The corresponding two-electrode electrolytic cell demonstrates small cell voltage (1.515 V @ 10 mA cm&#8722;2) and shows durability over 50 h at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, exhibiting excellent overall water splitting performance. It is worth noting that the solar-assisted electrolysis cell reaches a high solar-to-hydrogen (STH) conversion rate of 19.4 %. The construction of this unique hollow structure gives a fascinating method for improving the HER and OER performance of transition metal sulfide electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhongtang Gao, Tengfei Zhang, Dianguo Xu, Ping Liu, Huan Liu, Huanhuan Li, Yanyan Liu, Feng Ye, Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prussian blue analogue-derived Co-Ni5P4 porous nanosheet arrays composite coal-based carbon nanofibers as efficient self-supported electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111189</link>
      <description>Xiaolan Fan, Tingting Huang, Hui Ding, Xia Liu, Xiao Yan Liu, Guancheng Xu, Li Zhang, Diamond and related materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831350

                The development of economical, earth-rich, and high-performance transition metal phosphides electrocatalysts is crucial for water splitting. Herein, the NiCo PBA/Ni(OH)2 hierarchical nanostructure arrays are in situ grown on the coal-based carbon nanofibers (C-CNFs) using hydrothermal and co-precipitation methods. Subsequently, the Co-doped Ni5P4 porous nanosheet arrays composite coal-based carbon nanofibers electrocatalyst (Co-Ni5P4@C-CNFs) is obtained through low-temperature phosphorization process. Benefiting from cation-doped, porous nanosheet arrays structure and self-supported conductive substrates, the Co-Ni5P4@C-CNFs has excellent electrocatalytic performance for overall water splitting. It provides low overpotentials of 75 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 231 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to achieve the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 M KOH electrolyte. Furthermore, the Co-Ni5P4@C-CNFs demonstrates a low overall water splitting cell voltage of 1.537 V at current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and remarkable long-term stability for over 160 h. It outperforms the most transition metal phosphide bifunctional electrocatalysts reported to date. This research provides a novel strategy for synthesizing high-performance transition metal phosphides bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaolan Fan, Tingting Huang, Hui Ding, Xia Liu, Xiao Yan Liu, Guancheng Xu, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique sandwich-cookie-like nanosheet array heterojunction bifunctional electrocatalyst towards efficient overall water/seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.061</link>
      <description>Qian Long, Yao Zhu, Huiting Hu, Yunhua Zheng, Zhulin Yuan, Yutang Dai, Tao Zhang, Dongya Yang, Songlin Xue, Fengxian Qiu, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831354

                Construction of multi-component heterostructures is an effective strategy for electrocatalysts to improve both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity at the anode. Herein, an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst towards overall water/seawater splitting (OW/SS) is reported with strategy of heterostructure construction (ruthenium/nickel phosphorus) on nickel hydroxide (Ni(OH)2). With the unique hydrolysis layer (Ni(OH)2), the processes of H2O hydrolysis and the adsorption/desorption of H*/O-containing intermediates (OH, O, OOH) were greatly boosted by Ru and P sites, which acted as the catalytic active centers of OER and HER, respectively. In addition, the electronic structure reconfiguration was realized through the strong interaction between multi-interfaces. For alkaline HER at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, the overpotential of Ru-P-Ni(OH)2/NF (denoted as RNPOH/NF) was 98 mV, whereas just 230 mV of overpotential was essential to stimulate alkaline OER at the current density of 20 mA cm&#8722;2. Specifically, as a bifunctional electrocatalyst towards overall water splitting, RNPOH/NF deserves cell voltages of 1.7/1.92 V and 1.75/1.94 V, respectively, to activate current densities of 50/100 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline water/seawater systems, together with a good durability of 12 h. This work contributes insights to the development of bifunctional electrocatalysts for overall water/seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>Qian Long, Yao Zhu, Huiting Hu, Yunhua Zheng, Zhulin Yuan, Yutang Dai, Tao Zhang, Dongya Yang, Songlin Xue, Fengxian Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Synthesis of Electrocatalysts Base on Catalysis&#8208;Unit Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403549</link>
      <description>Zhe Zhang, Ziqi Zhang, Cailing Chen, Rong Xu, Xiaobo Chen, Haiyan Lu, Zhan Shi, Yangyang Han, Shouhua Feng, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780553

                It is a pressing need to develop new energy materials to address the existing energy crisis. However, screening optimal targets out of thousands of materials candidates remains a great challenge. Herein, we propose and validate an alternative concept for highly effective materials screening based on dual-atom salphen catalysis units. Such an approach simplifies the design of catalytic materials and reforms the trial-and-error experimental model into a building-blocks-assembly like process. Firstly, density functional theory (DFT) calculations were performed on a series of potential catalysis units which were possible to synthesize. Then, machine learning (ML) was employed to define the structure-performance relationship and acquire chemical insights. Afterwards, the projected catalysis units were integrated into covalent organic frameworks (COFs) to validate the concept Electrochemical tests confirm that Ni-SalphenCOF and Co-SalphenCOF are promising conductive agent-free oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts. This work provides a fast-tracked strategy for design and development of functional materials, which serves as a potentially workable framework for seamlessly integrating DFT calculations, ML, and experimental approaches. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Zhe Zhang, Ziqi Zhang, Cailing Chen, Rong Xu, Xiaobo Chen, Haiyan Lu, Zhan Shi, Yangyang Han, Shouhua Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202403549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-Metal-Oxygen Moieties Enriched Surface Reconstruction in Cofe Electrocatalysts for Stabilizing High-Valence Co Sites Enable Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820462</link>
      <description>Yingwei Li, Wang Meng'en, Jie Tian, Xudong Song, Baojun Ma, Wei Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713732

                Despite the potential of heterostructure construction and surface reconstruction strategies to significantly enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of transition metal compounds, integrating these approaches into a single material system remains a significant challenge. In this work, we report an efficient CoFe-LDH catalyst with multi-metal nitrides on the surface through simple and tunable N2-plasma treatment. Structural and chemical state characterization indicates a high concentration of defective sites in PL CoFe-LDH, which facilitates the exposure of a greater number of active N-Fe-O and N-Co-O centers. During the initial stage of the OER process, there is a rapid phase transition of Fe and Co, leading to the formation of metal (oxy)hydroxides. Meanwhile, Co3+ species gradually accumulate on the surfaces, which is responsible for the excellent OER catalytic activity. Then, the neighboring N atoms function as electron reservoirs, donating electrons to the Co sites to prevent overoxidation and dissolution of Co in the electrolyte, thus significantly enhancing the stability of the OER. The catalysts enable the achievement of ultralow OER overpotential, measuring 161.1 and 205.5 mV at current densities of 10 mA cm-2 and 200 mA cm-2, respectively, while exhibiting exceptional stability.</description>
      <author>Yingwei Li, Wang Meng'en, Jie Tian, Xudong Song, Baojun Ma, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A highly-stable and low-energy-barrier photoelectrocatalyst (NiFe-LDH@Ti-MOF) for water splitting at high current densities via breaking the atomic structure symmetry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.05.005</link>
      <description>Azam Pirkarami, Arash Javanmard, Ebrahim Ghasemi, Journal of industrial and engineering chemistry/Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry - Korean Society of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396678627

                There is a flurry of interest in enhancing the stability and efficiency of photoelectrocatalysts in water splitting at high current densities. In the present study, nickel&#8211;iron layered double hydroxide (NiFe-LDH) was decorated with MIP-177-LT (Ti-metal organic framework (MOF)) to fabricate a heteroatom electrocatalyst (NiFe-LDH@Ti-MOF). The overpotentials of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) turned out to be very low: 199 and 232 mV at current densities of 200 and 600 mA cm&#8722;2, in that order. Then, current densities of 1,000 mA cm&#8722;2 were applied to the modified electrode over a long period of 800 h, and this generated a higher stability than that of the commercial IrO2. Further, its mass activity proved &#8764;2 and 7 times as high as those of IrO2 and NiFe-LDH, in that order. Furthermore, for water splitting, the produced photoelectrocatalyst obtained a current density of 1,000 mA cm&#8722;2 using only 1.6 V, and this performance remained changeless for 800 h, which can be considered the most superb performance ever reported. The experimental characterization revealed that during the process of doping Ti-MOF on NiFe-LDH, symmetry breaking takes place in the atomic structure of the LDH surface, which increases the active sites in the photoelectrocatalyst. The presence of oxygen in the Ti-MOF active sites improves the efficiency of OER at high current densities and also contributes to the higher stability of multiple heteroatomic interfaces for water splitting. The propounded strategy enables the generation of oxygen and hydrogen from water splitting at high current densities on an industrial scale by changing the symmetry of the atomic structure of heteroatomic photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Azam Pirkarami, Arash Javanmard, Ebrahim Ghasemi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.05.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-Driven Methanol to Formate Conversion Coupled with Energy-Efficient Hydrogen Production Through Cr Dopant-Induced Charge Transfer Modulation at the In-Situ Formed Feooh/Feco-Ldhs Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820518</link>
      <description>Mayur Gaikwad, Vishal Burungale, Deepak S. Gavali, D.B. Malavekar, Sang Woo Park, Fang Zheng, Seunghyun Jang, KULDEEP SINGH GOUR, Mar&#237;a Roc&#237;o Alfaro-Cruz, Jihun Kim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396752578

                The goal of developing efficient electrocatalysts that can effectively accelerate both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) is essential. Additionally, overcoming the sluggish anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) also presents a considerable challenge for achieving energy-efficient hydrogen (H2) production. Herein, we report the synthesis of self-supported hierarchical FeOOH/Fe0.5CoCr0.5-LDHs as an advanced electrocatalyst by employing simultaneous engineering strategies for producing the formate from MOR at the anode while simultaneously generating H2 at the cathode. Both the experimental and theoretical studies demonstrate the superior charge transfer enabled by the in-situ formed heterostructure. Additionally, electronic modulation due to Cr intercalation, and the presence of a superhydrophilic hybrid surface morphology promote the remarkable electrocatalytic activity and stability of the FeOOH/Fe0.5CoCr0.5-LDHs electrocatalyst. The overall water splitting process required a cell voltage of 2.01 V to achieve a current density of 50 mA cm-2, whereas a lower cell voltage of 1.76 V was sufficient for overall methanol oxidation. Remarkably, a solar-driven system prototype, consisting of a commercial Si cell combined with a methanol splitting electrolyzer comprising FeOOH/Fe0.5CoCr0.5-LDHs electrodes, achieved a photocurrent density of 8.1 mA cm-2 over 2h. This work demonstrates the capability of earth-abundant elements-based electrocatalysts for sustainable and selective electrochemical synthesis. As a result, it enables the energy-efficient generation of clean H2 and valuable chemicals byproducts.</description>
      <author>Mayur Gaikwad, Vishal Burungale, Deepak S. Gavali, D.B. Malavekar, Sang Woo Park, Fang Zheng, Seunghyun Jang, KULDEEP SINGH GOUR, Mar&#237;a Roc&#237;o Alfaro-Cruz, Jihun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820518</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of an Internal Charge Field: CoS&lt;sub&gt;1.097&lt;/sub&gt;/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction Promotes Efficient Urea Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402776</link>
      <description>Mingliang Du, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396702405

                Abstract Urea oxidation reaction (UOR) features a lower overpotential compared to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) during electrolysis, facilitating the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode. The distribution of charge plays a pivotal role in promoting the adsorption and cleavage of chemical groups in urea molecules, which can be modulated by introducing a heterostructure. Herein, a CoS 1.097 /Ni 3 S 2 heterojunction grown on nickel foam is designed, serving simultaneously for UOR and HER. Based on density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the spontaneous charge transfer at the CoS 1.097 /Ni 3 S 2 heterointerface induces the formation of localized electrophilic/nucleophilic regions, intelligently adsorbing electron&#8208;donating/electron&#8208;withdrawing groups in urea molecules, activating chemical bonds, thereby triggering urea decomposition. CoS 1.097 /Ni 3 S 2 exhibits excellent catalytic activity for urea, requiring only a potential of 1.22 V (with an overpotential of 0.85 V) to achieve a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in UOR, and potentials of 1.27 and 1.57 V to reach current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively, in a UOR//HER electrolysis cell, maintaining good stability at high current density for 60 h. Tests in real urine have demonstrated performance similar to that in urea electrolyte. This work represents nearly the best catalytic performance of transition metal&#8208;based materials in UOR applications, promising for both efficient hydrogen production and urea decomposition.</description>
      <author>Mingliang Du, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environmentally benign synthesis and characterization of Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Sb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; nanocomposite: Investigation of its potential as electrode material in energy storage and generation applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7516</link>
      <description>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Lin Wang, Ram K. Gupta, Essam A. Al&#8208;Ammar, Ghulam Abbas Ashraf, Applied organometallic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396775304

                A shift to alternate energy sources is needed at the present time to address rising environmental concerns. The current research work aims to use a chemical&#8208;free and green route to synthesize nanocomposite for their application as an electrode in the generation as well as storage of energy. Subsequently, the green synthesis of Bi 2 O 3 &#8208;Sb 2 O 3 nanocomposite was carried out using the leaf extract of Amaranthus viridis . The synthesized nanocomposite revealed a well&#8208;arranged pattern of spherical nanoparticles with a crystal size of 29.43 nm and a band gap value of 2.5 eV. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) potentials of Bi 2 O 3 &#8208;Sb 2 O 3 were studied through linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), whereas the energy storage studies were performed using cyclic voltammetry (CV) and galvanostatic charge discharge (GCD) techniques. The synthesized nanomaterial showed promising results for HER with an overpotential value of 205 mV as compared with OER, where an overpotential value of 450 mV was observed. However, excellent cyclic stability was witnessed for both reactions up to 1000 cycles. CV studies revealed an outstanding capacitance value of 348 F/g at a scan rate of 2 mV/s, whereas a specific capacitance of 269.5 F/g at a current density of 0.5 A/g was observed using GCD. The 15 h of electrode stability further endorsed the potential of synthesized material for energy&#8208;based applications.</description>
      <author>Sundus Azhar, Khuram Shahzad Ahmad, Isaac Abrahams, Lin Wang, Ram K. Gupta, Essam A. Al&#8208;Ammar, Ghulam Abbas Ashraf</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aoc.7516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into the Catalytic Mechanism of Ni-Alloyed Co4n Nanowire Arrays Towards Photo-Assisted Electrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823059</link>
      <description>Chengming Long, Sirui Liu, Di Wang, Zhaoqi Lu, Qiulan Zhang, Qiong Gao, Mingyi Zhang, Xinzhi Ma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396783208

                Photoelectrochemical hydrogen production technology holds promise for directly and swiftly generating green hydrogen, which is pivotal for human welfare; however, it faces challenges posed by the energetically sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Cobalt-based nitrides are considered excellent photoelectrochemical OER (PEOER) catalysts, and their conductivity and photoconversion efficiency remain relatively low. Additionally, the role of nitrogen elements in the OER process is often overlooked. This paper presents the fabrication of Ni-alloyed Co4N nanowire arrays on carbon cloth ((Co1-xNix)4N NWAs/CC) as PEOER catalysts. By analyzing advanced in-situ Raman and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) results, we discovered that Ni not only enhances the conductivity of the catalyst but, more importantly, also creates more photoexcited Co2+ OER centers and favors its reconstruction to CoOOH to charge PEOER. Furthermore, nitrogen plays a critical role in transforming pyridinic nitrogen into other forms of nitrogen to stabilize the catalyst's structure. These advantages endow (Co0.7Ni0.3)4N NWAs/CC with remarkable PEOER enhancement (988%), which drives the standard current density of 10 mA cm-2 with only 283 mV overpotential along with good durability. This research provides insights into the PEOER mechanisms of cobalt-based transition metal nitrides, providing a way for designing next-generation PEOER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Chengming Long, Sirui Liu, Di Wang, Zhaoqi Lu, Qiulan Zhang, Qiong Gao, Mingyi Zhang, Xinzhi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4823059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induced Diffusion Effect Realizes Heterogeneous Separation/Aggregation for In Situ Fabrication of Heterostructure with Enhanced Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405339</link>
      <description>Hang Li, Xinyu Ding, Mengfei Su, Chunyan Zhang, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396688368

                Abstract Space charge transfer, which can be provided by heterogeneous structure, is the key to efficient electrocatalytic processes. However, difficulty in controlling the relative atomic diffusion rates due to different atomic radii and affinity makes heterogeneous nanostructures difficult to be accurately designed. Herein, an induced diffusion strategy based on affinity differences between elements is proposed to direct the separation/aggregation of different components in the precursor. The key to strategy in this study is the different affinity of Cu and Co to S/P in the precursor of CuCo Prussian blue analogue (PBA). By controlling the molar ratio of S and P during the phosphorization/vulcanization process, induced diffusion can be achieved and leads to directional separation/aggregation of Cu and Co species. As a result, a heterogeneous yolk&#8208;shell Cu 2 S@CoP 2 &#8208;C&#8208;N&#8208;S structure is successfully synthesized with a reticular CoP2&#8208;C&#8208;N&#8208;Cu&#8208;S as the shell and a Cu 2 S nanocrystal as the core. The space charge effect of the semiconductor heterojunction resulting from component separation/aggregation significantly promotes oxygen evolution reaction, resulting in an ultralow overpotential of 180 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 . This work not only provides a simple method for efficient separation of key components in gas&#8208;solid systems but also provides a method for fine&#8208;tuning the active site in an active&#8208;site&#8208;engineering approach.</description>
      <author>Hang Li, Xinyu Ding, Mengfei Su, Chunyan Zhang, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Glycerol Conversion: A Low-Voltage Pathway to Efficient Carbon-Negative Green Hydrogen and Value-Added Chemical Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02392</link>
      <description>Inderjeet Chauhan, Himanshu Bajpai, Bishakha Ray, Sadhu Kolekar, Suwarna Datar, Kshirodra Kumar Patra, Chinnakonda S. Gopinath, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396720992

                Electrochemical glycerol oxidation reaction (GLYOR) could be a promising way to use the abundantly available glycerol for production of value-added chemicals and fuels. Completely avoiding the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with GLYOR is an evolving strategy to reduce the overall cell potential and generate value-added chemicals and fuels on both the anode and cathode. We demonstrate the morphology-controlled palladium nanocrystals, afforded by colloidal chemistry, and their established morphology-dependent GLYOR performance. Although it is known that controlling the morphology of an electrocatalyst can modulate the activity and selectivity of the products, still it is a relatively underexplored area for many reactions, including GLYOR. Among nanocube (Pd-NC), truncated octahedron (Pd-TO), spherical and polycrystalline (Pd-PC) morphologies, the Pd-NC electrocatalyst deposited on a Ni foam exhibits the highest glycerol conversion (85%) along with 42% glyceric acid selectivity at a low applied potential of 0.6 V (vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE)) in 0.1 M glycerol and 1 M KOH at ambient temperature. Owing to the much favorable thermodynamics of GLYOR on the Pd-NC surface, the assembled electrolyzer requires an electricity input of only &#8764;3.7 kWh/m3 of H2 at a current density of 100 mA/cm2, in contrast to the requirement of &#8805;5 kWh/m3 of H2 with an alkaline/PEM electrolyzer. Sustainability has been successfully demonstrated at 10 and 50 mA/cm2 and up to 120 h with GLYOR in water and simulated seawater.</description>
      <author>Inderjeet Chauhan, Himanshu Bajpai, Bishakha Ray, Sadhu Kolekar, Suwarna Datar, Kshirodra Kumar Patra, Chinnakonda S. Gopinath</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Assisted Study of REN&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;C&lt;sub&gt;6&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-Doped Graphene as Potential Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Electrode Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00803</link>
      <description>Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Chao He, Daomiao Wang, Meiling Liu, Chao Liu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396747083

                In the application of renewable energy, the oxidation&#8211;reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are two crucial reactions. Single-atom catalysts (SACs) based on metal-doped graphene have been widely employed due to their high activity and high atom utilization efficiency. However, the catalytic activity is significantly influenced by different metals and local coordination, making it challenging to efficiently screen through either experimental or density functional theory (DFT) calculations. To address this issue, this study employed a combination of DFT calculations and machine learning (DFT-ML) to investigate rare earth-modified carbon-based (RENxC6&#8211;x) electrocatalysts. Based on computational data from 75 catalysts, we trained two ML models to capture the underlying patterns of physical properties and overpotential. Subsequently, the candidate catalysts were screened, leading to the discovery of four ORR catalysts, nine OER catalysts, and five bifunctional electrocatalysts, all of which were thoroughly validated for their stability. Lastly, by integrating the ML models with the SHAP analysis framework, we revealed the influence of atomic radius, Pauling electronegativity, and other features on the catalytic activity. Additionally, we analyzed the physicochemical properties of potential catalysts through DFT calculations. The revolutionary DFT-ML approach provides a crucial driving force for the design and synthesis of potential catalysts in subsequent studies.</description>
      <author>Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Chao He, Daomiao Wang, Meiling Liu, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c00803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Nano&#8208;Interlayer Inhibiting Interfacial Degradation toward High&#8208;Voltage PEO&#8208;Based All&#8208;Solid&#8208;State Lithium Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310547</link>
      <description>Pengfei Zhai, Shuangquan Qu, Niaz Ahmad, Ze Hua, Ruiwen Shao, Wen Yang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396705586

                Abstract The interfacial instability between PEO&#8208;based solid electrolyte (SPE) and high&#8208;voltage cathode materials inhibits the longevity of high&#8208;energy&#8208;density all&#8208;solid&#8208;state polymer lithium metal batteries (ASSPLBs). Herein, for the first time it is demonstrated, that contact loss caused by gas generation from interfacial side reactions between the high&#8208;voltage cathode and solid polymer electrolyte (SPE) can also arise in ASSPLBs. To alleviate the interfacial side reactions, a LiNb 0.6 Ti 0.5 O 3 (LNTO) layer is well coated on LiNi 0.83 Co 0.07 Mn 0.1 O 2 (NCM83), denoted as (CNCM83). The LNTO layer with low electronic conductivity reduces the decomposition drive force of SPE. Furthermore, Ti and Nb in the LNTO layer spontaneously migrate inside the NCM83 surface to form a strong Ti/Nb&#9472;O bond, stalling oxygen evolution in high&#8208;voltage cathodes. The interfacial degradation phenomena, including SPE decomposition, detrimental phase transition and intragranular cracks of NCM83, and void formation between cathode and SPE, are effectively mitigated by the LNTO layer. Therefore, the growth rate of interfacial resistance (R CEI ) decreases from 37.6 &#937; h &#8722;0.5 for bare NCM83 to 2.4 &#937; h &#8722;0.5 for CNCM83 at 4.2 V. Moreover, 4.2 V PEO&#8208;based ASSPLBs achieve impressive cyclability with high capacity retention of 135 mAh g &#8722;1 (75%) even after 300 cycles at 0.5 C.</description>
      <author>Pengfei Zhai, Shuangquan Qu, Niaz Ahmad, Ze Hua, Ruiwen Shao, Wen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Nitric Oxide as a Regulator in Salt Tolerance: Insights into Photosynthetic Efficiency in Maize</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13101312</link>
      <description>Georgi D. Rashkov, Martin Stefanov, Ekaterina Yotsova, Preslava Borisova, Anelia G. Dobrikova, Emilia Apostolova, Plants. 13(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396801950

                The growing issue of salinity is a significant threat to global agriculture, affecting diverse regions worldwide. Nitric oxide (NO) serves as an essential signal molecule in regulating photosynthetic performance under physiological and stress conditions. The present study reveals the protective effects of different concentrations (0&#8211;300 &#181;M) of sodium nitroprusside (SNP, a donor of NO) on the functions of the main complexes within the photosynthetic apparatus of maize (Zea mays L. Kerala) under salt stress (150 mM NaCl). The data showed that SNP alleviates salt-induced oxidative stress and prevents changes in the fluidity of thylakoid membranes (Laurdan GP) and energy redistribution between the two photosystems (77K chlorophyll fluorescence ratio F735/F685). Chlorophyll fluorescence measurements demonstrated that the foliar spray with SNP under salt stress prevents the decline of photosystem II (PSII) open reaction centers (qP) and improves their efficiency (&#934;exc), thereby influencing QA&#8722; reoxidation. The data also revealed that SNP protects the rate constants for two pathways of QA&#8722; reoxidation (k1 and k2) from the changes caused by NaCl treatment alone. Additionally, there is a predominance of QA&#8722; interaction with plastoquinone in comparison to the recombination of electrons in QA QB&#8722; with the oxygen-evolving complex (OEC). The analysis of flash oxygen evolution showed that SNP treatment prevents a salt-induced 10% increase in PSII centers in the S0 state, i.e., protects the initial S0&#8211;S1 state distribution, and the modification of the Mn cluster in the OEC. Moreover, this study demonstrates that SNP-induced defense occurs on both the donor and acceptor sides of the PSII, leading to the protection of overall photosystems performance (PIABS) and efficient electron transfer from the PSII donor side to the reduction of PSI end electron acceptors (PItotal). This study clearly shows that the optimal protection under salt stress occurs at approximately 50&#8211;63 nmoles NO/g FW in leaves, corresponding to foliar spray with 50&#8211;150 &#181;M SNP.</description>
      <author>Georgi D. Rashkov, Martin Stefanov, Ekaterina Yotsova, Preslava Borisova, Anelia G. Dobrikova, Emilia Apostolova</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants13101312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the electric, dielectric and optical properties of template-free hydrothermally synthesized CuO nanostructures via Co doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.051</link>
      <description>M.P. Monis, H. A. A. Saadallah, Yuda Prima Hardianto, Mohamed Khairy, N. M. A. Hadia, A.M. Abdel Hakeem, E.M.M. Ibrahim, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396694255

                Facile template-free hydrothermal method was utilized for preparing CuO nanostructures (NSs) doped with Co element (Cu1-xCoxO (x=0.0, 0.02, 0.04, 0.06 and 0.08)). A single-phase monoclinic crystal with changing in morphology from rod- to sphere-like nanoparticles was observed. . The temperature dependency of DC electrical conductivity revealed that the shallow and deep donor levels are responsible for the DC conduction in low and high temperature ranges, respectively. The Ac electrical conductivity, dielectric constant and dielectric loss were also measured as functions in frequency and temperature. The frequency dependence of the AC conductivity was well represented by the Jonscher's universal power law. The AC conduction was governed by the Correlated Barrier Hopping model where the inter-well and intra-well hopping mechanisms contribute to the electrical conduction in the low and high frequency ranges, respectively. The activation energies and the barrier height decreased while the dielectric constant and dielectric loss increased with increasing the Co content. The relaxation and deformational polarizations predominate and the overall behavior of dielectric constant fits well with the Koops' model. The Cole-Cole plots indicated a decrease in the sample resistance with increasing temperatures and Co concentrations. UV-vis absorption spectra exhibited two peaks at wavelengths 252 and 323 nm. The optical energy gap was calculated using Tauc's equation and decrease from 2.24 to 2.1 eV with increasing the Co concentrations. The effect of Co-doping on CuO was explored for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and found a decrease in the overvoltage (&#956;) about 50 mV at 0.08 ratios, which declares that the doping of Co element enhances the electrical conductivity and feasibility for further electrocatalytic improvement.</description>
      <author>M.P. Monis, H. A. A. Saadallah, Yuda Prima Hardianto, Mohamed Khairy, N. M. A. Hadia, A.M. Abdel Hakeem, E.M.M. Ibrahim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Implications of Thermal Hydrodynamic Atmospheric Escape on the
  TRAPPIST-1 Planets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.02401</link>
      <description>Megan T. Gialluca, R. Barnes, Victoria Meadows, Rodolfo Garc&#237;a, Jessica Birky, Eric Agol, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396715330

                JWST observations of the 7-planet TRAPPIST-1 system will provide an excellent opportunity to test outcomes of stellar-driven evolution of terrestrial planetary atmospheres, including atmospheric escape, ocean loss and abiotic oxygen production. While most previous studies use a single luminosity evolution for the host star, we incorporate observational uncertainties in stellar mass, luminosity evolution, system age, and planetary parameters to statistically explore the plausible range of planetary atmospheric escape outcomes. We present probabilistic distributions of total water loss and oxygen production as a function of initial water content, for planets with initially pure water atmospheres and no interior-atmosphere exchange. We find that the interior planets are desiccated for initial water contents below 50 Earth oceans. For TRAPPIST-1e, f, g, and h, we report maximum water loss ranges of 8.0$^{+1.3}_{-0.9}$, 4.8$^{+0.6}_{-0.4}$, 3.4$^{+0.3}_{-0.3}$, and 0.8$^{+0.2}_{-0.1}$ Earth oceans, respectively, with corresponding maximum oxygen retention of 1290$^{+75}_{-75}$, 800$^{+40}_{-40}$, 560$^{+30}_{-25}$, and 90$^{+10}_{-10}$ bars. We explore statistical constraints on initial water content imposed by current water content, which could inform evolutionary history and planet formation. If TRAPPIST-1b is airless while TRAPPIST-1c possesses a tenuous oxygen atmosphere, as initial JWST observations suggest, then our models predict an initial surface water content of 8.2$^{+1.5}_{-1.0}$ Earth oceans for these worlds, leading to the outer planets retaining $&gt;$1.5 Earth oceans after entering the habitable zone. Even if TRAPPIST-1c is airless, surface water on the outer planets would not be precluded.</description>
      <author>Megan T. Gialluca, R. Barnes, Victoria Meadows, Rodolfo Garc&#237;a, Jessica Birky, Eric Agol</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.02401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on the epitaxial direction control and mechanism of polycrystalline diamond grains</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/26941112.2024.2346083</link>
      <description>Junpeng Li, Zeyang Ren, Jinfeng Zhang, Jincheng Zhang, Shoichi Kai, Juan Meng, Zhu Liaoliang, Yijiang Li, Junfei Chen, Wang Hanxue, Yue Hao, Functional diamond. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396831403

                The control of diamond film growth is crucial for the application of diamond films. In this article, different diamond film samples were prepared by adding nitrogen and oxygen in different proportions during the growth process. The key conditions for controlling the growth of diamond film with preferred orientation were obtained using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and Raman spectroscopy characterizations. During the growth process, the growth of the diamond film with (100) preferred orientation could be achieved by adjusting nitrogen content. It was necessary to introduce nitrogen and oxygen in the growth process, and precisely regulate the ratio of the two to obtain the (111) preferred orientation of the diamond film. When only oxygen was introduced during growth, the preferred orientation of the diamond could not be achieved, leading to a smaller grain size and poorer crystal quality. From the perspective of grain morphology to film morphology evolution, this study obtained the crystal orientation control conditions during the diamond film growth, which has important guiding significance for the application of the diamond film. This study seeks to drive progress in the large-scale growth of readily machinable diamond and the evolution of diamond-grain optical fiber sensing through comprehensive investigations into the correlation between the preferred orientation in polycrystalline diamonds and reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Junpeng Li, Zeyang Ren, Jinfeng Zhang, Jincheng Zhang, Shoichi Kai, Juan Meng, Zhu Liaoliang, Yijiang Li, Junfei Chen, Wang Hanxue, Yue Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/26941112.2024.2346083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Activities Governing Structural Reversibility in Industrial Ni-Rich Layered Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-n507z</link>
      <description>Gi&#8208;Hyeok Lee, Suwon Lee, Jiliang Zhang, Bernardine L. D. Rinkel, Matthew J. Crafton, Zengqing Zhuo, Yong Choi, Junghoon Yang, Jongwook W. Heo, Byungchun Park, Bryan D. McCloskey, Maxim Avdeev, Wanli Yang, Yong&#8208;Mook Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396740942

                The chemical reactions and phase transitions at high voltages determine the electrochemical properties of high voltage layered cathodes such as Ni-rich rhombohedral materials. Here, we performed a comprehensive and comparative study of the cationic and anionic redox reactions, as well as the structural evolution of a series of industrial Ni-rich layered cathode materials with and without Al doping, which are being utilized in the cells made by LG Energy Solutions Co.. We combined the results from X-ray spectroscopy, operando electrochemical mass spectrometry, and neutron diffraction with electrochemical properties, and revealed the different oxygen activities associated with structural and electrochemical degradations. We show that Al doping suppresses the irreversible oxygen release thereby enhancing the reversible lattice oxygen redox resulting from the interplay between static (doped Al) and dynamic disorders (reversible oxygen redox). With this modulated oxygen activity, the Ni-rich cathode's notorious H2-H3 structural phase transition becomes highly reversible. Our findings disentangle the different oxygen activities during high-voltage cycling and clarify the role of dopants in the Ni-rich layered cathodes in terms of structural and electrochemical stability finally making all the cell makers get back to the fundamental investigation regarding whether high-Ni NCM chemistry (NCM811 or NCM 91/2 1/2) is substantially beneficial compared to its mid-Ni homologues (NCM622).</description>
      <author>Gi&#8208;Hyeok Lee, Suwon Lee, Jiliang Zhang, Bernardine L. D. Rinkel, Matthew J. Crafton, Zengqing Zhuo, Yong Choi, Junghoon Yang, Jongwook W. Heo, Byungchun Park, Bryan D. McCloskey, Maxim Avdeev, Wanli Yang, Yong&#8208;Mook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-n507z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Fabrication of SrTiO3/In2O3 on Carbon Fibers via a Self-Assembly Strategy for Enhanced Photocatalytic Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16103988</link>
      <description>Jiantao Niu, Qi Hu, Sustainability. 16(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396803765

                Photocatalytic water splitting by semiconductors is considered a promising and cost-effective method for achieving sustainable hydrogen production. In this study, a CF/SrTiO3/In2O3 photocatalytic material with a double-layer core&#8211;shell structure was developed. The experimental results indicated that the produced CF/SrTiO3/In2O3 composite fiber displayed superior photocatalytic hydrogen production performance, achieving a hydrogen evolution rate of approximately 320.71 &#956;mol/g&#183;h, which is roughly seven times higher than that of the CF/SrTiO3 fiber alone. The enhanced photocatalytic activity of the CF/SrTiO3/In2O3 fiber can be attributed to the heterojunction structure enriched with oxygen vacancies. It was found that these oxygen vacancies created defective states that served as traps for photogenerated electrons, facilitating their migration to the surface defect states and enabling the reduction of H+ in water to produce hydrogen. Furthermore, the synergy between the heterojunction structure and the conductivity of the carbon fiber promoted the generation and migration of photogenerated electrons, reduced the recombination of photogenerated electron&#8211;hole pairs, and ultimately improved photocatalytic hydrogen production. This study presents a new approach for designing efficient photocatalysts with surface oxygen vacancies on carbon fibers, providing new insights into the sustainable application of photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiantao Niu, Qi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16103988</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defective Tungsten Oxides with Stacking Faults for Proton Exchange Membrane Green&#8208;Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401159</link>
      <description>Meng Qu, Youwei Cheng, Hengli Duan, Ying&#65533; Qin, Sihua Feng, Xiaozhi Su, Yifei Yuan, Wensheng Yan, Liang Cao, Jie Xu, Rui Wu, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396724392

                Abstract Defects can introduce atomic structural modulation and tailor performance of materials. Herein, it demonstrates that semiconductor WO 3 with inert electrocatalytic behavior can be activated through defect&#8208;induced tensile strains. Structural characterizations reveal that when simply treated in Ar/H 2 atmosphere, oxygen vacancies will generate in WO 3 and cause defective structures. Stacking faults are found in defects, thus modulating electronic structure and transforming electrocatalytic&#8208;inert WO 3 into highly active electrocatalysts. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations are performed to calculate * H adsorption energies on various WO x surfaces, revealing the oxygen vacancy composition and strain predicted to optimize the catalytic activity of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Such defective tungsten oxides can be integrated into commercial proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyser with comparable performance toward Pt&#8208;based PEM. This work demonstrates defective metal oxides as promising non&#8208;noble metal catalysts for commercial PEM green&#8208;hydrogen generation.</description>
      <author>Meng Qu, Youwei Cheng, Hengli Duan, Ying&#65533; Qin, Sihua Feng, Xiaozhi Su, Yifei Yuan, Wensheng Yan, Liang Cao, Jie Xu, Rui Wu, Shu&#8208;Hong Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; 3D-ED in gas and liquid environments for following structural evolutions during reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1107/s2053273323095840</link>
      <description>D. Vandemeulebroucke, Amirhossein Hajizadeh, M. Batuk, J. Hadermann, Acta crystallographica. Section A, Foundations and advances. 79(a2)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4396818151

                Many functional materials are applied in the form of nanosized particles.To follow their structural evolution during reactions, in situ X ray powder diffraction or in situ neutron powder diffraction can miss out on details due to this small particle size.In such cases, in situ 3DED (three dimensional electron diffraction) would allow to gather single crystal type information on the structural changes.However, currently there are still many open questions on how the results from in situ 3DED relate to ex situ results and results from bulk experiments.Using closed cell environmental holders (gas, liquid, electrochemistry), combined with heating and cooling holders, we have studied their structural evolutions during redox reactions during heating in O2 and H2 versus vacuum of a range of perovskite based materials and have systematically related the resulting reduced structures to those obtained by other techniques.For Sr2Fe2O5 (Pcmb), investigated for solid oxide fuel cells, chemical looping and heterogeneous catalysis, in situ XRD and in situ NPD in gas environments only observed transformations between brownmillerite and perovskite type (Pm-3m) structures, while in situ 3DED allowed to also observe an intermediate Cmmm phase known from ex situ and electrochemistry experiments before reaching the perovskite type phase.In situ 3DED also showed the manifestation of nanotwins upon oxidation.After reducing the oxidized phase again in hydrogen at 700&#176;C, the ordering of the tetrahedral chains between planes was lost but the order within planes remained.Cooling instead the oxidized phase in oxygen resulted in an intergrowth of brownmillerite and perovskite.[1] The reduction of the Ruddlesden-Popper structure La0.5Sr1.5MnO4,also a candidate for solid oxide fuel cell cathodes, resulted in the creation of a perovskite layer at the surface which was not noticed before in bulk in situ experiments involving redox reactions in gas.Parallel ex situ reductions showed also faint superstructure reflections in the 3DED datasets pointing towards a surface reconstruction with ordered oxygen vacancies, which could not be detected in the in situ 3DED experiments.Differences in surface layers are important as they are the most active parts in catalytic reactions.Sr2MnO 4 could not be reduced using an in situ reaction with H2 into the supercell with oxygen-vacancy order from literature, while this did succeed during parallel ex situ reduction experiments as well as during in situ heating in vacuum.CaMnO3, a material for chemical looping applications, was successfully reduced using in situ reduction both by heating in hydrogen gas as well as by heating in vacuum, achieving not only the well characterized CaMnO2.5 phase, but also the intermediate CaMnO2.75, which was thus far not solved and had contradicting models in literature.Using the results from the in situ 3DED experiments, the CaMnO2.75 was solved in a Pmmm space group.These results were then compared to in situ 3DED results on the evolution of the Fe and Sr doped compounds which show better chemical looping properties.In situ 3DED in gas environments has thus already given new, complementary information to what was observed with in situ XRD and in situ NPD for each perovskite based material we have studied so far.We therefore believe that in future studies in situ 3DED will unlock a vast amount of new information on functional materials in general.</description>
      <author>D. Vandemeulebroucke, Amirhossein Hajizadeh, M. Batuk, J. Hadermann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1107/s2053273323095840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Halite-Structured (MgCoNiMnFe)O High Entropy Oxide (HEO) for Chemical Looping Dry Reforming of Methane</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124191</link>
      <description>Yu Shao, Chao Wu, Shibo Xi, Preston Tan, Xia Wu, Syed Saqline, Wen Liu, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396835290

                The configurational disorder of high entropy oxides (HEOs) promotes the reversible exsolution&#8211;redissolution of constituent metal species. This unique feature could be exploited to facilitate cyclic lattice oxygen storage and exchange. Herein, we report an in situ generated, halite-structured (MgCoNiMnFe)Ox HEO, which simultaneously functions as a redox catalyst and an oxygen carrier for dry reforming of methane in a chemical looping process (CL&#8211;DRM). Accordingly, the (MgCoNiMnFe)Ox/ZrO2 HEO catalyst exhibits outstanding DRM activity, syngas selectivity and cyclic stability compared to medium-entropy oxides and bimetallic oxides over 100 CL&#8211;DRM cycles at 800 &#176;C. XRD analysis verified the entropy-mediated preservation of the alloy/HEO/ZrO2 catalytic structure over CL&#8211;DRM cycles. XAFS studies revealed the reversible and cyclic evolution&#8211;dissolution of Ni, Fe, Co over redox cycles. The exsolved NiFeCo nanoalloy exhibited high efficiency in activating CH4. This study has demonstrated the potential applications of HEO-based catalysts in efficient chemical looping processes.</description>
      <author>Yu Shao, Chao Wu, Shibo Xi, Preston Tan, Xia Wu, Syed Saqline, Wen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124191</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buoyancy control and air breathing in royal knifefish (&lt;i&gt;Chitala blanci&lt;/i&gt;) and a new hypothesis for the early evolution of vertebrate air&#8208;breathing behaviors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.25460</link>
      <description>Elska B Kaczmarek, Elizabeth L. Brainerd, &#152;The &#156;anatomical record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396704495

                Abstract We present the first description of inspiration&#8208;first air breaths in royal knifefish, Chitala blanci , a ray&#8208;finned fish known to use four&#8208;stroke air breaths. Four&#8208;stroke breaths are used by nearly all ray&#8208;finned fish species that use their gas bladder to breathe air and are the ancestral breath type of ray&#8208;finned fishes. Interestingly, one such species, Amia calva , is known to perform two distinct breath types. Amia use four&#8208;stroke breaths when they need more oxygen and performs inspiration&#8208;first breaths to restore buoyancy. We observed that C. blanci also performs inspiration&#8208;first breaths and tested whether the two breath types are performed for the same functions in C. blanci as they are in Amia . We recorded the frequency of each breath type when exposed to aquatic hypoxia and two conditions of oxygen availability. We found that C. blanci performed more four&#8208;stroke breaths (81% &#177; 15% of total breaths) than inspiration&#8208;first breaths when exposed to aerial normoxia but performed more inspiration&#8208;first breaths (72% &#177; 40%) than four&#8208;stroke breaths when exposed to aerial hyperoxia. These patterns match those described for Amia and indicate that C. blanci performs four&#8208;stroke breaths in response to oxygen depletion and performs inspiration&#8208;first breaths to maintain buoyancy. Few studies have examined the role of air&#8208;breathing in buoyancy regulation. Decreasing buoyancy, rather than oxygen availability, to stimulate air breaths may reveal that inspiration&#8208;first breaths are more common among fishes than we are aware. We consider this possibility and present a new hypothesis for the origin and early evolution of air breathing in vertebrates.</description>
      <author>Elska B Kaczmarek, Elizabeth L. Brainerd</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.25460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Elevated Inflammatory Status of Neutrophils Is Related to In-Hospital Complications in Patients with Acute Coronary Syndrome and Has Important Prognosis Value for Diabetic Patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25105107</link>
      <description>Elena Barbu, Andreea Cristina Mihaila, Ana&#8208;Maria Gan, Leti&#539;ia Ciortan, Razvan Daniel Macarie, Monica M&#259;d&#259;lina Tucureanu, Alexandru Filippi, Andra Ioana Stoenescu, S Petrea, Maya Simionescu, Serban-Mihai Balanescu, Elena Butoi, International journal of molecular sciences. 25(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396732348

                Despite neutrophil involvement in inflammation and tissue repair, little is understood about their inflammatory status in acute coronary syndrome (ACS) patients with poor outcomes. Hence, we investigated the potential correlation between neutrophil inflammatory markers and the prognosis of ACS patients with/without diabetes and explored whether neutrophils demonstrate a unique inflammatory phenotype in patients experiencing an adverse in-hospital outcome. The study enrolled 229 ACS patients with or without diabetes. Poor evolution was defined as either death, left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) &lt;40%, Killip Class 3/4, ventricular arrhythmias, or mechanical complications. Univariate and multivariate analyses were employed to identify clinical and paraclinical factors associated with in-hospital outcomes. Neutrophils isolated from fresh blood were investigated using qPCR, Western blot, enzymatic assay, and immunofluorescence. Poor evolution post-myocardial infarction (MI) was associated with increased number, activity, and inflammatory status of neutrophils, as indicated by significant increase of Erythrocyte Sedimentation Rate (ESR), C-reactive protein (CRP), fibrinogen, interleukin-1&#946; (IL-1&#946;), and, interleukin-6 (IL-6). Among the patients with complicated evolution, neutrophil activity had an important prognosis value for diabetics. Neutrophils from patients with unfavorable evolution revealed a pro-inflammatory phenotype with increased expression of CCL3, IL-1&#946;, interleukin-18 (IL-18), S100A9, intracellular cell adhesion molecule-1 (ICAM-1), matrix metalloprotease (MMP-9), of molecules essential in reactive oxygen species (ROS) production p22phox and Nox2, and increased capacity to form neutrophil extracellular traps. Inflammation is associated with adverse short-term prognosis in acute ACS, and inflammatory biomarkers exhibit greater specificity in predicting short-term outcomes in diabetics. Moreover, neutrophils from patients with unfavorable evolution exhibit distinct inflammatory patterns, suggesting that alterations in the innate immune response in this subgroup may exert detrimental effects on disease progression.</description>
      <author>Elena Barbu, Andreea Cristina Mihaila, Ana&#8208;Maria Gan, Leti&#539;ia Ciortan, Razvan Daniel Macarie, Monica M&#259;d&#259;lina Tucureanu, Alexandru Filippi, Andra Ioana Stoenescu, S Petrea, Maya Simionescu, Serban-Mihai Balanescu, Elena Butoi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijms25105107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapidly rotating Population III stellar models as a source of primary nitrogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449156</link>
      <description>Sophie Tsiatsiou, Yves Sibony, Devesh Nandal, Luca Sciarini, Yutaka Hirai, Sylvia Ekstr&#246;m, Eoin Farrell, Laura Bennett Murphy, Arthur Choplin, Rapha&#235;l Hirschi, Cristina Chiappini, Boyuan Liu, Volker Bromm, J. H. Groh, Georges Meynet, Astronomy &amp; astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396820935

                The first stars might have been fast rotators. This would have important consequences for their radiative, mechanical, and chemical feedback. We discuss the impact of fast initial rotation on the evolution of massive Population III models and on their nitrogen and oxygen stellar yields. We explore the evolution of Population III stars with initial masses in the range of 9 msol ini msol starting with an initial rotation on the zero-age main sequence equal to 70&lt;!PCT!&gt; of the critical one. We find that with the physics of rotation considered here, our rapidly rotating Population III stellar models do not follow a homogeneous evolution. They lose very little mass in the case in which mechanical winds are switched on when the surface rotation becomes equal to or larger than the critical velocity. The impact on the ionising flux appears to be modest when compared to moderately rotating models. Fast rotation favours, in models with initial masses above sim 20 msol the appearance of a very extended intermediate convective zone around the H-burning shell during the core He-burning phase. This shell has important consequences for the sizes of the He- and CO-cores, and thus impacts the final fate of stars. Moreover, it has a strong impact on nucleosynthesis, boosting the production of primary 14N. Fast initial rotation significantly impacts the chemical feedback of Population III stars. Observations of extremely metal-poor stars and/or starbursting regions are essential to provide constraints on the properties of the first stars.</description>
      <author>Sophie Tsiatsiou, Yves Sibony, Devesh Nandal, Luca Sciarini, Yutaka Hirai, Sylvia Ekstr&#246;m, Eoin Farrell, Laura Bennett Murphy, Arthur Choplin, Rapha&#235;l Hirschi, Cristina Chiappini, Boyuan Liu, Volker Bromm, J. H. Groh, Georges Meynet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiscale Gas&#8211;Solid Reaction Dynamics of Hematite Oxygen Carrier in Chemical Looping Combustion from Fluidized Bed Thermogravimetric Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00853</link>
      <description>Tianxu Shen, Laihong Shen, Tao Song, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396749549

                The pursuit of precise and detailed kinetic characteristics continues to drive advancements in both modeling and measurement methodologies. A multiscale kinetic model was developed to analyze the redox behaviors of the hematite oxygen carrier (OC), characterized by a fluidized bed thermogravimetric analyzer (FB-TGA). This multiscale model integrates bulk diffusion of lattice oxygen, discrete growth of product islands, particle-scale gas diffusion, and interphase gas exchange, offering a comprehensive insight into the evolution of reaction rate and mass transfer. The investigation revealed that the surface diffusion rates of gas molecules are the crucial determinant in the Fe2O3 reactivity, with rapid surface diffusion delaying the formation of an enclosed product layer. The exceptional diffusion conditions and precise weight measurement capability of FB-TGA yielded faster reaction rate constants than conventional methods, facilitating transformative insights into rate-limiting factors. External diffusion and bulk lattice oxygen diffusion were identified as rapid and insufficient in imposing limitations on the overall reaction. Conversely, intraparticle diffusion emerged as the primary rate-limiting step in kinetic experiments even involving 0.1&#8211;0.15 mm hematite OC particles, especially during the initial oxidation of Fe3O4, where the mass transfer efficiency dropped below 85%. In actual chemical looping combustion environments utilizing 0.3&#8211;0.45 mm hematite OC particles, the resistance of intraparticle diffusion significantly intensified, inhibiting gas&#8211;solid reaction rates to an extent comparable to interphase mass transfer. Based on the insights derived from the multiscale model analysis, strategies for optimizing OC particle structure and reactor design have been proposed to enhance gas&#8211;solid reactions.</description>
      <author>Tianxu Shen, Laihong Shen, Tao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphite-N reinforced sludge biochar electrode: A experimental and DFT theoretical analysis of efficient evolution and in-situ utilization of H2O2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2024.124107</link>
      <description>Chenxi Li, Xiaojie Qiu, Huilin Wan, Zehao Ma, Ruotong Jin, Yan Zhao, Environmental pollution. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396745336

                Rational reuse of municipal sludge to produce electro-Fenton electrode can not only save resources, but also produce superior peroxide and degradation pollutants simultaneously. Herein, a novel electro-Fenton electrode derived from sludge biochar loaded on Ni foam (SBC@Ni) was constructed via high temperature pyrolysis and chemical coating for efficient H2O2 evolution and pollutant degradation. Systematic experiments and density functional theory calculations (DFT calculation) explained that the production of graphite C and graphite N during high-temperature pyrolysis of municipal sludge can greatly enhance the oxygen reduction reaction of SBC@Ni electrode and promote the evolution of H2O2. And the hybrid heterojunctions, such as FeP, also played a key role in electrocatalytic processes. Notably, the electrode still exhibited excellent performance after 1000 linear scans and 12 hours of continuous current stimulation, which demonstrated the excellent stability of the electrode. Moreover, SBC@Ni electrode can not only effectively oxidize 4-chlorophenol through the electro-Fenton effect, but also fully mineralize organic matter, indicating promising environmental application. The free radical quenching experiment also revealed that the &#183;OH is the main active species for 4-CP degradation in SBC@Ni electro-Fenton system.</description>
      <author>Chenxi Li, Xiaojie Qiu, Huilin Wan, Zehao Ma, Ruotong Jin, Yan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2024.124107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Factors responsible for Witwatersrand gold mineralisation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.25131/sajg.127.0023</link>
      <description>Axel Hofmann, South African journal of geology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780236

                Abstract The exceptional gold mineralisation in quartz pebble conglomerates of the Witwatersrand Basin is attributed to a combination of factors. These factors are linked to the co-evolution of the atmosphere, hydrosphere, lithosphere and biosphere, at a very specific time in Archaean geological history and the evolution of the Kaapvaal Craton. Following craton stabilisation and its subaerial emergence, intense chemical weathering and erosion of large volumes of granitoid-greenstone basement released detrital and dissolved gold. Shallow-marine reworking in a long-lived and slowly subsiding basin subjected to episodic compressional deformation and relative sea-level oscillations led to sedimentary concentration of detrital gold. The interaction between acidic, anoxic, and sulfurous surface runoff and more oxidizing marine waters in a near-coastal oxygen oasis supported microbially mediated diagenetic pyrite formation and incorporation of dissolved gold in the pyrite crystal lattice. Erosion and reworking of diagenetic pyrite gave rise to detrital pyrite that characterise most reefs. Abundance of detrital uraninite in conglomerates, derived from erosion of Mesoarchaean granites, and episodes of hydrocarbon migration through sedimentary strata during deep burial set the scene for further enhancement of gold grades in the reefs. Granular and seam pyro-bitumen formed by radiation-induced polymerisation of hydrocarbons around detrital uraninite. Gold dissolved in migrating hydrothermal fluids was then reduced and precipitated upon interaction with the reef pyro-bitumen during hydrothermal placer modification.</description>
      <author>Axel Hofmann</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.25131/sajg.127.0023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The special adaptation to hypoxia facilitated the expansion of the Asian house rat (&lt;i&gt;Rattus tanezumi&lt;/i&gt;) into Tibet but not other &lt;i&gt;Rattus&lt;/i&gt; species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1749-4877.12829</link>
      <description>Rongxuan Cao, Ming Zhang, Yi Chen, Guanghui Hou, Qianying Liu, Jinhua Zhang, Y. Zhang, Integrative Zoology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396811676

                Abstract Rattus species are thought to live only at altitudes less than 2500 m, but the Asian house rat ( R. tanezumi ) (RT) has recently expanded to altitudes greater than 3500 m in China. Other Rattus species, especially brown rats ( R. norvegicus ) (RN), still reach only low altitudes on the Tibetan Plateau. Comparative genomics revealed the positive selection of hypoxia&#8208;inducible transcription factors 1 and 2 (HIFs) in RT, with the rapid evolution of HIF pathway genes in RT and Mus musculus (MM) but not RN or R. rattus . Population genomics revealed that genes associated with energy metabolism and oxygen transport were positively selected in RT compared with the other four Rattus species, and two specific substitutions (arginine 31 serine and leucine 33 methionine) were identified in the hemoglobin subunit beta (HBB) in RT. The above results suggested that RT possesses unique genetic adaptations to hypoxia, which was further confirmed by behavioral experiments on RT and RN. Normobaric hypoxia significantly reduced locomotion in RN but not in RT. Moreover, through intraspecific transcriptome analysis, the expression of Hbb and genes related to angiogenesis, oxygen transport, and glycolysis was upregulated, and the expression of genes associated with immunological functions in the liver, lungs, and/or sperm was downregulated in RT compared to those in RN. Interspecific transcriptome analysis further revealed that HIF&#8208;1&#945; plays a role in modulating the hypoxic adaptation of RT rather than RN. Our work provides genomic, behavioral, and physiological insights into why RT, but not other Rattus species, could invade the Tibetan Plateau.</description>
      <author>Rongxuan Cao, Ming Zhang, Yi Chen, Guanghui Hou, Qianying Liu, Jinhua Zhang, Y. Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1749-4877.12829</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overlooked shelf sediment reductive sinks of dissolved rhenium and uranium in the modern ocean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48297-y</link>
      <description>Qingquan Hong, Yuehua Cheng, Yegao Qu, Wei Lin, Y. Liu, Jianfeng Gao, Pinghe Cai, Tianyu Chen, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396792600

                Abstract Rhenium (Re) and uranium (U) are essential proxies in reconstructing past oceanic oxygenation evolution. However, their removal in continental shelf sediments, hotspots of early diagenesis, were previously treated as quantitatively unimportant sinks in the ocean. Here we examine the sedimentary reductive removal of Re and U and their coupling with organic carbon decomposition, utilizing the 224 Ra/ 228 Th disequilibria within the East China Sea shelf. We identified positive correlations between their removal fluxes and the rates of sediment oxygen consumption or organic carbon decomposition. These correlations enable an evaluation of global shelf reductive sinks that are comparable to (for Re) or higher than (~4-fold for U) previously established suboxic/anoxic sinks. These findings suggest potential imbalances in the modern budgets of Re and U, or perhaps a substantial underestimation of their sources. Our study thus highlights shelf sedimentary reductive removal as critical yet overlooked sinks for Re and U in the modern ocean.</description>
      <author>Qingquan Hong, Yuehua Cheng, Yegao Qu, Wei Lin, Y. Liu, Jianfeng Gao, Pinghe Cai, Tianyu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-48297-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A promising strontium and cobalt-free Ba1-xCaxFeO3-&#948; air electrode for reversible protonic ceramic cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124176</link>
      <description>Guangjun Zhang, Ting Chen, Jizhao Zou, Chenxiao Wang, Xiaonan Bao, Guozhu Zheng, Zuzhi Huang, Wei Zhang, Kui Liu, Li&#8208;Yan Xu, Yucun Zhou, Shaorong Wang, Applied catalysis. B, Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396812202

                The air electrode with strontium and cobalt elements has the elemental diffusion or delamination issue on the air electrode/electrolyte interface in reversible protonic ceramic cells (RPCCs). Hence the development of strontium and cobalt-free triple conducting (H+/O2-/e-) air electrodes with high electrochemical activity and stability is urgent. Here, we report a strontium and cobalt-free Ba0.8Ca0.2FeO3-&#948; (BCF82) air electrode with high catalytic activity and electrochemical stability for oxygen reduction/evolution reactions. A RPCC with the BCF82 air electrode shows a high peak power density of 1.14 W cm-2 in the fuel cell mode and a current density of 3.49 A cm-2 under 1.3 V in the electrolysis mode at 700 &#176;C. Furthermore, the cell demonstrates suitable stability in the fuel cell, electrolysis and reversible modes at 600 &#176;C for hundreds of hours without elemental segregation and delamination issue. This work offers an efficient approach to develop low-cost and durable air electrodes for RPCCs.</description>
      <author>Guangjun Zhang, Ting Chen, Jizhao Zou, Chenxiao Wang, Xiaonan Bao, Guozhu Zheng, Zuzhi Huang, Wei Zhang, Kui Liu, Li&#8208;Yan Xu, Yucun Zhou, Shaorong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124176</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charting the Electronic Structure for Discovering Low-cost Intermetallic Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-fq66l</link>
      <description>Zhengda He, Bin Ouyang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396799859

                Discovering affordable, high-performance, and stable catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is essential for the commercialization of clean hydrogen technology. In this study, we utilized a high-throughput screening approach combined with electronic structure descriptors to identify new intermetallic catalysts that minimize noble metal contents while maintaining high performance and stability. We screened 2,358 binary and ternary intermetallic compounds constructed from 31 common transition metal elements. From the 462 bulk compositions that are synthetically accessible, we enumerated all possible low-Miller-index surfaces (12,057 surfaces in total) with density functional theory calculations. Seven electronic-structure-based descriptors are then applied to pinpoint aqueously stable surfaces offering performance comparable to the renowned Pt (111) and Ir (111) surfaces. This process led to the identification of several previously known noble-metal-containing catalysts, as well as a selection of new intermetallic catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhengda He, Bin Ouyang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-fq66l</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monocyte bioenergetics: An immunometabolic perspective in metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrm.2024.101564</link>
      <description>Moris Sangineto, Martina Ciarnelli, Tommaso Colangelo, Archana Moola, Vidyasagar Naik Bukke, Loren Duda, Rosanna Villani, Antonino Davide Romano, Stefania Giandomenico, Hina Kanwal, Gaetano Serviddio, Cell reports medicine. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396813576

                Monocytes (Mos) are crucial in the evolution of metabolic dysfunction-associated steatotic liver disease (MASLD) to metabolic dysfunction-associated steatohepatitis (MASH), and immunometabolism studies have recently suggested targeting leukocyte bioenergetics in inflammatory diseases. Here, we reveal a peculiar bioenergetic phenotype in circulating Mos of patients with MASH, characterized by high levels of glycolysis and mitochondrial (mt) respiration. The enhancement of mt respiratory chain activity, especially complex II (succinate dehydrogenase [SDH]), is unbalanced toward the production of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and is sustained at the transcriptional level with the involvement of the AMPK-mTOR-PGC-1&#945; axis. The modulation of mt activity with dimethyl malonate (DMM), an SDH inhibitor, restores the metabolic profile and almost abrogates cytokine production. Analysis of a public single-cell RNA sequencing (scRNA-seq) dataset confirms that in murine models of MASH, liver Mo-derived macrophages exhibit an upregulation of mt and glycolytic energy pathways. Accordingly, the DMM injection in MASH mice contrasts Mo infiltration and macrophagic enrichment, suggesting immunometabolism as a potential target in MASH.</description>
      <author>Moris Sangineto, Martina Ciarnelli, Tommaso Colangelo, Archana Moola, Vidyasagar Naik Bukke, Loren Duda, Rosanna Villani, Antonino Davide Romano, Stefania Giandomenico, Hina Kanwal, Gaetano Serviddio</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrm.2024.101564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electromagnetic observables of open-shell nuclei from coupled-cluster
  theory</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05608</link>
      <description>Francesca Bonaiti, Sonia Bacca, G. Hagen, G. R. Jansen, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822211

                We develop a new method to describe electromagnetic observables of open-shell nuclei with two nucleons outside a closed shell. This approach combines the equation-of-motion coupled-cluster method for such systems and the Lorentz integral transform technique, expanding the applicability of coupled-cluster theory for these properties beyond closed-shell nuclei. To validate this new approach, we compute the non-energy-weighted dipole sum rule and the dipole polarizability of $^{16,24}$O in both the closed-shell and the new equation-of-motion coupled-cluster frameworks, finding agreement within error bars. We then analyze the evolution of the dipole polarizability along the oxygen and calcium isotopic chains. Our predictions agree well with available experimental data and other available theoretical calculations for the closed-shell $^{16,22}$O and the open-shell $^{18}$O. In the calcium isotopes, we observe that our dipole polarizability predictions for open-shell nuclei are lower than those of closed-shell nuclei. Our predictions for $^{24}$O and $^{54,56}$Ca will motivate future experimental studies at the dripline.</description>
      <author>Francesca Bonaiti, Sonia Bacca, G. Hagen, G. R. Jansen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05608</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas Adsorption Mechanism on 2D Materials: The Hyperpolarizability Evolution Analyzed by Nonlinear Optics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406005</link>
      <description>Ting&#8208;Yu Yen, Yang&#8208;Hao Hung, Y. C. Lee, Yingchieh Ho, Yann&#8208;Wen Lan, Chau-Chung Wu, Kuan&#8208;Ming Hung, Kuang Yao Lo, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396813213

                Abstract While understanding the competitive adsorption behavior of gas sensor is important, it is yet to be unraveled. Especially for the influence of water molecules to the gas adsorbed on 2D materials. This study explores the potential of layered 2D materials as a candidate material for gas sensing, employing non&#8208;destructive measurement, and second harmonic generation (SHG). The investigation focuses on analyzing oxygen, ammonia, and water vapor adsorbed on a WS 2 surface by studying the evolutions in electric dipole and electric field. Leveraging the simplified bond hyperpolarizability model (SBHM), a foundation is established for gas sensors utilizing high&#8208;quality 2D materials. This approach facilitates the detection of material modifications in response to environmental influences, including the inevitable water molecules. The obtained hyperpolarizability from SBHM exhibits remarkable consistency with Langmuir's adsorption model, confirming the physical adsorption in the system. In addition, the competitive effects between gases are explored by comparing experimental results with theoretical predictions based on Boltzmann distribution and density functional theory (DFT) calculations. This highlights the effectiveness of SHG and SBHM in studying gas adsorption on layered van der Waals materials.</description>
      <author>Ting&#8208;Yu Yen, Yang&#8208;Hao Hung, Y. C. Lee, Yingchieh Ho, Yann&#8208;Wen Lan, Chau-Chung Wu, Kuan&#8208;Ming Hung, Kuang Yao Lo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202406005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Trends in Therapeutic and Electroanalytical Applications of Boron-Doped Diamond Sensors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2174/0115734110304322240430053410</link>
      <description>Anuj Soni, Prabhjot Kaur, Rohit Bhatia, Naresh Kumar Rangra, Current analytical chemistry. 20(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396744651

                Abstract:: In recent years, research and development efforts have been heavily focused on conductive diamond electrodes for electrochemical applications. Such initiatives may have been spurred by their broad potential window, low background current, chemical inertness, and mechanical robustness. Compared to other carbon-based materials, conducting diamond can oxidize several analytes before the breakdown of water in aqueous electrolytes. Since the evolution of oxygen and hydrogen does not obstruct the analysis, this is significant for the detection and/or identification of species in solution. As a result, conductive diamond electrodes expand the application of electrochemical detection and make it possible to use them for analytes that are incompatible with traditional electrode materials. Fabricating boron-doped diamond films via chemical vapor deposition on different substrates is of special interest. This article highlights the therapeutic and electroanalytical applications of boron-doped diamond electrodes in various aspects in addition to the synthetic strategies to obtain Boron Doped Diamond Electrodes (BDDE), the cost-effectiveness of BDD and its in-vivo compatibility that will help the analytical researchers to learn almost everything about the previous studies done on BDDE and encourage them to work more efficiently in this research field.</description>
      <author>Anuj Soni, Prabhjot Kaur, Rohit Bhatia, Naresh Kumar Rangra</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2174/0115734110304322240430053410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of stress evolution in environmental barrier coatings considering the presence of crack channels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.072</link>
      <description>Jinkang Du, Guoqiang Yu, Beichen Xue, &#21843;&#26230; &#26085;&#39640;, Jiaming Li, Xiguang Gao, Yang Song, Fang Wang, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396706248

                The roles of crack channel transitions and thermally grown oxides (TGO) in the failure of environmental barrier coatings (EBCs) should be clarified. Hence, in this study, the laws of penetration and delamination crack evolution were investigated using a virtual crack extension method for multilayer materials to gain insights into the transformation conditions with a framework for a coupled thermal/mechanical/chemical numerical model of TGO containing channel cracks developed based on this law. The framework integrates diffusion, TGO growth, and phase transformation of the oxides. A theoretical model for high-temperature gas corrosion of EBCs coupled with deformation, mass diffusion, and chemical reactions was proposed, with the results indicating that the cracks transitioned from vertical to exfoliation cracks in the ytterbium dibasic silicate (YbDS) layer. The coupling effect of cracks and stresses led to non-uniform growth of the TGO by affecting the oxygen diffusion and inflow rates. The y-direction stresses at the YbDS/TGO interface near the crack channel changed from compressive to tensile stresses after cooling, making the first location to undergo delamination failure. The proposed model can provide better guidance for designing EBCs systems and supporting the life prediction of EBCs in service environments.</description>
      <author>Jinkang Du, Guoqiang Yu, Beichen Xue, &#21843;&#26230; &#26085;&#39640;, Jiaming Li, Xiguang Gao, Yang Song, Fang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>White dwarf eccentricity fluctuation and dissipation by AGB convection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.03745</link>
      <description>Yair Cohen, Sivan Ginzburg, M. Levy, Tal Bar Shalom, Yoav Siman Tov, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396786787

                Millisecond pulsars with white dwarf companions have typical eccentricities $e\sim 10^{-6}-10^{-3}$. The eccentricities of helium white dwarfs are explained well by applying the fluctuation-dissipation theorem to convective eddies in their red giant progenitors. We extend this theory to more massive carbon-oxygen (CO) white dwarfs with asymptotic giant branch (AGB) progenitors. Due to the radiation pressure in AGB stars, the dominant factor in determining the remnant white dwarf's eccentricity is the critical residual hydrogen envelope mass $m_{\rm env}$ required to inflate the star to giant proportions. Using a suite of MESA stellar evolution simulations with $\Delta m_{\rm c}=10^{-3}\,{\rm M}_\odot$ core-mass intervals, we resolved the AGB thermal pulses and found that the critical $m_{\rm env}\propto m_{\rm c}^{-6}$. This steep dependence causes the $e(m_{\rm c})$ relation to turn over, such that $e\sim 3\times 10^{-3}$ almost independently of the remnant CO white dwarf's mass $m_{\rm c}$. Nearly all of the measured eccentricities lie below this robust theoretical limit, indicating that the eccentricity is damped during the common-envelope inspiral that follows the unstable Roche-lobe overflow of the AGB star. Specifically, we focused on white dwarfs with median masses $m_{\rm c}&gt;0.6\,{\rm M}_\odot$. These massive white dwarfs begin their inspiral with practically identical orbital periods and eccentricities, eliminating any dependence on the initial conditions. For this sub-sample, we find an empirical relation $e\propto P^{3/2}$ between the final period and eccentricity that is much tighter than previous studies - motivating theoretical work on the eccentricity evolution during the common envelope phase.</description>
      <author>Yair Cohen, Sivan Ginzburg, M. Levy, Tal Bar Shalom, Yoav Siman Tov</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.03745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depth-resolved Characterization of Meissner Screening Breakdown in
  Surface Treated Niobium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05451</link>
      <description>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. Andrew MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822030

                We report direct measurements of the magnetic field screening at the limits of the Meissner phase for two superconducting Nb samples. The samples are processed with two different surface treatments that have been developed for superconducting radio-frequency cavity applications -- a "baseline" treatment and an oxygen-doping ("O-doping") treatment. The measurements show: 1) that the screening length is significantly longer in the "O-doping" sample compared to the "baseline" sample; 2) that the screening length near the limits of the Meissner phase increases with applied field; 3) the evolution of the screening profile as the material transitions from the Meissner phase to the mixed phase; and 4) a demonstration of the absence of any screening profile for the highest applied field, indicative of the full flux entering the sample. Measurements are performed utilizing the $\beta$-detected nuclear magnetic resonance ($\beta$-NMR) technique that allows depth resolved studies of the local magnetic field within the first 100 nm of the surface. The study takes advantage of the $\beta$-SRF beamline, a new facility at TRIUMF, Canada, where field levels up to 200 mT are available parallel to the sample surface to replicate radio frequency (RF) fields near the Meissner breakdown limits of Nb.</description>
      <author>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. Andrew MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopy and Photochemistry of [Al, N, C, O, H]: Connectivity to Aluminium&#8208;Bearing Species in the Universe</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401397</link>
      <description>Lina Wang, Xin Jiang, Beibei Sun, Tarek Trabelsi, Joseph S. Francisco, Xiaoqing Zeng, Mingfei Zhou, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396669343

                Aluminium is one of the most abundant metals in the universe and impacts the evolution of various astrophysical environments. Currently detected Al&#8208;bearing molecules represent only a small fraction of the aluminium budget, suggesting that aluminium may reside in other species. AlO and AlOH molecules are abundant in the oxygen&#8208;rich supergiant stars such as VY Canis Majoris, a stellar molecular factory with 60+ molecules including the prebiotic NC&#8208;bearing species. Additional Al&#8208;bearing molecules with N, C, O, and H may form in O&#8208;rich environments with radiation&#8208;accelerated chemistry. Here, we present spectroscopic identification of novel aluminium&#8208;bearing molecules composed of [Al, N, C, O, H] and [Al, N, C, O] from the reactions of Al atoms and HNCO in solid argon matrix, which are potential Al&#8208;bearing molecules in space. Photoinduced transformations among six [Al, N, C, O, H] isomers and three [Al, N, C, O] isomers, along with their dissociation reactions forming the known interstellar species, have been disclosed. These results provide new insight into the chemical network of astronomically detected Al&#8208;bearing species in space.</description>
      <author>Lina Wang, Xin Jiang, Beibei Sun, Tarek Trabelsi, Joseph S. Francisco, Xiaoqing Zeng, Mingfei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored Core&#8211;Shell Au/ZnO Hybrid Nanostars for Photochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01015</link>
      <description>Gagandeep Kaur, Rathindranath Biswas, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Tapasi Sen, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834693

                Nanostructured hybrids that combine metals and semiconductors exhibit significant potential as photocatalysts for various reactions. Among these, core&#8211;shell plasmonic noble metal&#8211;semiconductor nanostructures, such as Au/ZnO nanostars (NSs), are highly effective catalysts for photocatalytic water splitting. This study presents a simple method for synthesizing Au/ZnO NSs and comprehensively characterizes them by using various spectroscopic and microscopic techniques. The synthesized Au/ZnO NSs exhibit very high efficiencies in hydrogen (H2) and oxygen (O2) evolution when used as a catalyst for photocatalytic water splitting. This heightened photocatalytic activity can be attributed to the efficient suppression of the scavenging activity of Au nanoparticles. Additionally, the anisotropic star-shaped morphology of the Au component in the catalyst contributes to an increased surface area that promotes an enhanced interaction between the catalyst's components. This interaction facilitates facile interfacial charge transfer at the interface, resulting in an improved performance. Moreover, the plasmonic response of the Au core surrounded by ZnO nanostructures enhances the catalyst's light utilization capability, contributing to its superior performance. This synthesis method represents a significant advancement and paves the way for future developments in the design of plasmon-semiconductor nanostructures for energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Gagandeep Kaur, Rathindranath Biswas, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Tapasi Sen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycogen synthesis prevents metabolic imbalance and disruption of photosynthetic electron transport from photosystem &lt;scp&gt;II&lt;/scp&gt; during transition to photomixotrophy in &lt;i&gt;Synechocystis&lt;/i&gt; sp. &lt;scp&gt;PCC&lt;/scp&gt; 6803</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19793</link>
      <description>Pablo Ortega&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Lauri Nikkanen, Laura T. Wey, Francisco J. Florencio, Yagut Allahverdiyeva, Sandra D&#237;az&#8208;Troya, New phytologist. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396662875

                Summary Some cyanobacteria can grow photoautotrophically or photomixotrophically by using simultaneously CO 2 and glucose. The switch between these trophic modes and the role of glycogen, their main carbon storage macromolecule, was investigated. We analysed the effect of glucose addition on the physiology, metabolic and photosynthetic state of Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803 and mutants lacking phosphoglucomutase and ADP&#8208;glucose pyrophosphorylase, with limitations in glycogen synthesis. Glycogen acted as a metabolic buffer: glucose addition increased growth and glycogen reserves in the wild&#8208;type (WT), but arrested growth in the glycogen synthesis mutants. Already 30 min after glucose addition, metabolites from the Calvin&#8211;Benson&#8211;Bassham cycle and the oxidative pentose phosphate shunt increased threefold more in the glycogen synthesis mutants than the WT. These alterations substantially affected the photosynthetic performance of the glycogen synthesis mutants, as O 2 evolution and CO 2 uptake were both impaired. We conclude that glycogen synthesis is essential during transitions to photomixotrophy to avoid metabolic imbalance that induces inhibition of electron transfer from PSII and subsequently accumulation of reactive oxygen species, loss of PSII core proteins, and cell death. Our study lays foundations for optimising photomixotrophy&#8208;based biotechnologies through understanding the coordination of the crosstalk between photosynthetic electron transport and metabolism.</description>
      <author>Pablo Ortega&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Lauri Nikkanen, Laura T. Wey, Francisco J. Florencio, Yagut Allahverdiyeva, Sandra D&#237;az&#8208;Troya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The microRNA408&#8211;plantacyanin module balances plant growth and drought resistance by regulating reactive oxygen species homeostasis in guard cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/plcell/koae144</link>
      <description>Yan&#8208;Fei Yang, Lijia Xu, Chunxiang Hao, Miaomiao Wan, Yihan Tao, Yan Zhuang, Yanning Su, Lei Li, &#152;The &#156;Plant cell. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396759807

                The conserved microRNA (miRNA) miR408 enhances photosynthesis and compromises stress tolerance in multiple plants, but the cellular mechanism underlying its function remains largely unclear. Here, we show that in Arabidopsis (Arabidopsis thaliana), the transcript encoding the blue copper protein PLANTACYANIN (PCY) is the primary target for miR408 in vegetative tissues. PCY is preferentially expressed in the guard cells, and PCY is associated with the endomembrane surrounding individual chloroplasts. We found that the MIR408 promoter is suppressed by multiple abscisic acid (ABA)-responsive transcription factors, thus allowing PCY to accumulate under stress conditions. Genetic analysis revealed that PCY elevates reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels in the guard cells, promotes stomatal closure, reduces photosynthetic gas exchange, and enhances drought resistance. Moreover, the miR408-PCY module is sufficient to rescue the growth and drought tolerance phenotypes caused by gain- and loss-of-function of MYB44, an established positive regulator of ABA responses, indicating that the miR408-PCY module relays ABA signaling for regulating ROS homeostasis and drought resistance. These results demonstrate that miR408 regulates stomatal movement to balance growth and drought resistance, providing a mechanistic understanding of why miR408 is selected during land plant evolution and insights into the long-pursued quest of breeding drought-tolerant and high-yielding crops.</description>
      <author>Yan&#8208;Fei Yang, Lijia Xu, Chunxiang Hao, Miaomiao Wan, Yihan Tao, Yan Zhuang, Yanning Su, Lei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/plcell/koae144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modification of WS2 thin film properties using high dose gamma irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad4901</link>
      <description>Pravin Jadhav, P. T. Kolhe, V.S. Ghemud, P. N. Shelke, Shashikant P. Patole, S.D. Dhole, S.S. Dahiwale, Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396760690

                The tunability of the Transition Metal Dichalcogenide (TMD) properties has gained attention from numerous researchers due to their wide application in various fields including quantum technology. In the present work, WS2 has been deposited on fluorine doped tin oxide (FTO) substrate and its properties have been studied systematically. These samples were irradiated using gamma radiation for various doses, and the effect on structural, morphological, optical and electrical properties has been reported. The crystallinity of the material is observed to be decreased, and the results are well supported by X-ray diffraction, Raman spectroscopy techniques. The increase in grain boundaries has been supported by the agglomeration observed in the scanning electron microscopy micrographs. The XPS results of WS2 after gamma irradiation show evolution of oxygen, carbon, C=O, W-O and SO42- peaks, confirming the addition of impurities and formation of point defect. The gamma irradiation creates point defects, and their density increases considerably with increasing gamma dosage. These defects crucially altered the structural, optical and electrical properties of the material. The reduction in the optical band gap with increased gamma irradiation is evident from the absorption spectra and respective Tauc plots. The I-V graphs show a 1000-fold increase in the saturation current after 100 kGy gamma irradiation dose. This work has explored the gamma irradiation effect on the WS2 and suggests substantial modification in the material and enhancement in electrical properties. 
.</description>
      <author>Pravin Jadhav, P. T. Kolhe, V.S. Ghemud, P. N. Shelke, Shashikant P. Patole, S.D. Dhole, S.S. Dahiwale</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6528/ad4901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive interacting binaries as an enrichment source for multiple
  populations in star clusters</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05687</link>
      <description>Michelle Nguyen, Alison Sills, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396822298

                We present a suite of binary evolution models with massive primaries (10 $\leq$ M$_1$ $\leq$ 40 M$_\odot$) and periods and mass ratios chosen such that the systems undergo non-conservative mass transfer while the primaries have helium cores. We track the total mass and chemical composition of the ejecta from these systems. This material shows the abundance signatures of hot hydrogen burning which are needed to explain the abundance patterns seen in multiple populations in massive star clusters. We then calculate the total yield of a population of binary stars with masses, mass ratios, and periods consistent with their distribution in a field population. We show that the overall abundance of this material is enriched in helium, nitrogen, sodium, and aluminum, and depleted in carbon, oxygen, and magnesium, by amounts that are consistent with observations. We also show that such a population of binaries will return approximately 25% of its mass in this ejecta (compared to 4% if all the stars were single), over a characteristic timescale of about 12 Myr. We argue that massive binaries must be seriously considered as a contributor to the source of enriched material needed to explain the multiple populations in massive clusters, since essentially all massive stars are formed in binaries or higher order multiples, massive binaries are primarily formed in clusters, and massive binaries naturally produce material of the right composition.</description>
      <author>Michelle Nguyen, Alison Sills</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05687</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Redox Patterns at the Transcriptional and Systemic Levels in Newly Diagnosed Acute Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29328/journal.jhcr.1001029</link>
      <description>Alina Ag&#252;ero, M&#243;naco Mar&#237;a Eugenia, Lazarte Sandra, A. Ledesma, Alvarez Carmona A, Ter&#225;n Magdalena Mar&#237;a, Iss&#233; Blanca Alicia, Medina Marcela, Haro Cecilia, Journal of hematology and clinical research. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396704095

                Background: Acute leukemia is the result of clonal transformation and proliferation of a hematopoietic progenitor giving rise to poorly differentiated neoplastic cells. Reactive oxygen species play a role in maintaining the quiescence, self-renewal, and long-term survival of hematopoietic stem cells, but it is unclear how they would affect disease onset and progression. The aim is to evaluate, at the transcriptional and systemic level, the oxidative-inflammatory status in newly diagnosis acute leukemia patients. Methods: Seventy acute leukemia patients [26 acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), 13 Acute Promyelocytic Leukemia (APL), and 31 Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML)] and forty-one healthy controls were analyzed. Malondialdehyde and catalase activity were evaluated. Gene expression of NRF2, SOD, PRDX2, CAT, IL-6, and TNF-&#945; was analyzed by real-time PCR. Results: Malondialdehyde concentration was similar in all groups studied. Catalase activity was significantly higher in AML and APL patients compared to controls, while ALL showed similar activity to the healthy group. NRF2, CAT, and PRDX2 expression levels were similar between groups, SOD expression was downregulated in all acute leukemia patients. TNF-&#945; expression was lower in AML groups than in healthy individuals, and IL-6 mRNA expression was downregulated in ALL and APL. Conclusion: This is the first report that correlates transcriptional and systemic parameters associated with the oxidative inflammatory status in newly diagnosed acute leukemia. Some of the parameters evaluated could be used as biomarkers in the selection of an effective therapeutic strategy and will open new directions for the follow-up and evolution of this disease.</description>
      <author>Alina Ag&#252;ero, M&#243;naco Mar&#237;a Eugenia, Lazarte Sandra, A. Ledesma, Alvarez Carmona A, Ter&#225;n Magdalena Mar&#237;a, Iss&#233; Blanca Alicia, Medina Marcela, Haro Cecilia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29328/journal.jhcr.1001029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-roughness effect on the interfacial thermal oxidation and surface catalytical recombination characteristics for silicon carbide based materials under non-equilibrium flow</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160263</link>
      <description>He Li, Jin Zhao, Guice Yao, Jianzhou Tang, Yunpeng Cao, Dongsheng Wen, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396834745

                With the rapid development of high-speed aircraft, the demanding for light, strong, reliable and high temperature resistive thermal protection material (TPM) is becoming urgent. High temperature material interface, such as silicon carbide (SiC) ceramic matrix composite, has received strong interest recently due to its high mechanical and thermochemical stability. For reactive interface development with nano-roughness under extremely hyperthermal non-equilibrium flow conditions for TPM applications, however, has not been reported yet. This work performs a systematic reactive molecular dynamics (RMD) study of the SiC surface morphology effect withstanding hyperthermal atomic oxygen (AO) impact via a gas&#8211;solid interface reaction model. The results show that a self-healing trend of the defect-rich silicon carbide surface with original nano-roughness is revealed towards a flatter interface accompanying with the oxidation process. The surface catalytic recombination coefficient is more sensitivity to the surface defects when wall temperature Tw &gt; 500 K. Nano-roughness structure can also vary the main thermochemical reaction path at the thermochemical reactive interface: For the nano-groove surface model, the thermal oxidation reaction becomes dominant, while more pronounced surface catalytic recombination characteristics are revealed for the flat surface model. The mechanisms of roughness effect, surface temperature and gas impacting angle on the surface catalytic recombination, surface oxidation, and interface evolution are revealed, which advance our microscopic understanding of SiC interfacial performance with nano-roughness under non-equilibrium flow conditions.</description>
      <author>He Li, Jin Zhao, Guice Yao, Jianzhou Tang, Yunpeng Cao, Dongsheng Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160263</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First detection of CO isotopologues in a high-redshift main-sequence
  galaxy: evidence of a top-heavy stellar initial mass function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05317</link>
      <description>Ziyi Guo, Zhi-Yu Zhang, Zhiqiang Yan, Eda Gjergo, Allison Man, R. J. Ivison, Xiaoting Fu, Yong Shi, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396821932

                Recent observations and theories have presented a strong challenge to the universality of the stellar initial mass function (IMF) in extreme environments. A notable example has been found for starburst conditions, where evidence favours a top-heavy IMF, i.e. there is a bias toward massive stars compared to the IMF that is responsible for the stellar mass function and elemental abundances observed in the Milky Way. Local starburst galaxies have star-formation rates similar to those in high-redshift main-sequence galaxies, which appear to dominate the stellar mass budget at early epochs. However, the IMF of high-redshift main-sequence galaxies is yet to be probed. Since $^{13}$CO and C$^{18}$O isotopologues are sensitive to the IMF, we have observed these lines towards four strongly-lensed high-redshift main-sequence galaxies using the Atacama Large Millimeter/sub-millimeter Array. Of our four targets, SDSS J0901+1814, at $z \approx 2.26$, is seen clearly in $^{13}$CO and C$^{18}$O, the first detection of CO isotopologues in the high-redshift main-sequence galaxy population. The observed $^{13}$C/$^{18}$O ratio, $2.4 \pm 0.8$, is significantly lower than that of local main-sequence galaxies. We estimate the isotope ratio, oxygen abundance and stellar mass using a series of chemical evolution models with varying star-formation histories and IMFs. All models favour an IMF that is more top-heavy than that of the Milky Way. Thus, as with starburst galaxies, main-sequence galaxies in the high-redshift Universe have a greater fraction of massive stars than a Milky-Way IMF would imply.</description>
      <author>Ziyi Guo, Zhi-Yu Zhang, Zhiqiang Yan, Eda Gjergo, Allison Man, R. J. Ivison, Xiaoting Fu, Yong Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.05317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mystery of rich human gut antibiotic resistome in the Yellow River with hyper-concentrated sediment-laden flow</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121763</link>
      <description>Yuan Gao, Qian Chen, Shufeng Liu, Jiawen Wang, Alistair Borthwick, Jinren Ni, Water research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396780510

                Human gut antibiotic resistome widely occur in anoxic environments characterized by high density of bacterial cells and frequent transmission of antibiotic resistance genes (ARGs). Such resistome is greatly diluted, degraded, and restrained in the aerobic habitats within most natural rivers (regarded as "terrestrial guts") connecting continents and the oceans. Here we implemented a large-scale monitoring campaign extending 5,200 km along the Yellow River, and provide the first integral biogeographic pattern for both ARGs and their hosts. We identified plentiful ARGs (24 types and 809 subtypes) and their hosts (24 phyla and 757 MAGs) in three media (water, suspended particulate matter (SPM), and sediment). Unexpectedly, we found diverse human gut bacteria (HGB) acting as supercarriers of ARGs in this oxygen-rich river. We further discovered that numerous microhabitats were created within stratified biofilms that surround SPMs, particularly regarding the aggregation of anaerobic HGB. These microhabitats provide numerous ideal sinks for anaerobic bacteria and facilitate horizontal transfer of ARGs within the stratified biofilms, Furthermore, the stratification of biofilms surrounding SPMs has facilitated synergy between human gut flora and denitrifiers for propagation of ARGs in the anoxic atmospheres, leading to high occurrence of human gut antibiotic resistome. SPMs play active roles in the dynamic interactions of river water and sediment, thus accelerating the evolution of riverine resistome and transmission of human gut antibiotic resistome. This study revealed the special contribution of SPMs to the propagation of ARGs, and highlighted the necessity of making alternative strategies for sustainable management of large rivers with hyper-concentrated sediment-laden flows.</description>
      <author>Yuan Gao, Qian Chen, Shufeng Liu, Jiawen Wang, Alistair Borthwick, Jinren Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.121763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification and characterization of the CRK gene family in the wheat genome and analysis of their expression profile in response to high temperature-induced male sterility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.17370</link>
      <description>Hongzhan Liu, Xiaoyi Li, Zujun Yin, Junmin Hu, Liuyong Xie, Huanhuan Wu, Seung Hoon Han, Bing Li, Huifang Zhang, Chaoqiong Li, Lili Li, Fuli Zhang, Guangxuan Tan, PeerJ. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396704694

                Cysteine-rich receptor-like kinases (CRKs) play many important roles during plant development, including defense responses under both biotic and abiotic stress, reactive oxygen species (ROS) homeostasis, callose deposition and programmed cell death (PCD). However, there are few studies on the involvement of the CRK family in male sterility due to heat stress in wheat ( Triticum aestivum L.). In this study, a genome-wide characterization of the CRK family was performed to investigate the structural and functional attributes of the wheat CRKs in anther sterility caused by heat stress. A total of 95 CRK genes were unevenly distributed on 18 chromosomes, with the most genes distributed on chromosome 2B. Paralogous homologous genes with Ka/Ks ratios less than 1 may have undergone strong purifying selection during evolution and are more functionally conserved. The collinearity analysis results of CRK genes showed that wheat and Arabidopsis ( A. thaliana ), foxtail millet, Brachypodium distachyon ( B. distachyon ), and rice have three, 12, 15, and 11 pairs of orthologous genes, respectively. In addition, the results of the network interactions of genes and miRNAs showed that five miRNAs were in the hub of the interactions map, namely tae-miR9657b-5p, tae-miR9780, tae-miR9676-5p, tae-miR164, and tae-miR531. Furthermore, qRT-PCR validation of the six TaCRK genes showed that they play key roles in the development of the mononuclear stage anthers, as all six genes were expressed at highly significant levels in heat-stressed male sterile mononuclear stage anthers compared to normal anthers. We hypothesized that the TaCRK gene is significant in the process of high-temperature-induced sterility in wheat based on the combination of anther phenotypes, paraffin sections, and qRT-PCR data. These results improve our understanding of their relationship.</description>
      <author>Hongzhan Liu, Xiaoyi Li, Zujun Yin, Junmin Hu, Liuyong Xie, Huanhuan Wu, Seung Hoon Han, Bing Li, Huifang Zhang, Chaoqiong Li, Lili Li, Fuli Zhang, Guangxuan Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.17370</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the expression of the unspecific peroxygenase in Komagataella phaffii through a combination strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00253-024-13166-7</link>
      <description>Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Shu&#8208;Ping Zou, Qi Shen, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Feng Cheng, Applied microbiology and biotechnology. 108(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396676995

                The unspecific peroxygenase (UPO) from Cyclocybe aegerita (AaeUPO) can selectively oxidize C-H bonds using hydrogen peroxide as an oxygen donor without cofactors, which has drawn significant industrial attention. Many studies have made efforts to enhance the overall activity of AaeUPO expressed in Komagataella phaffii by employing strategies such as enzyme-directed evolution, utilizing appropriate promoters, and screening secretion peptides. Building upon these previous studies, the objective of this study was to further enhance the expression of a mutant of AaeUPO with improved activity (PaDa-I) by increasing the gene copy number, co-expressing chaperones, and optimizing culture conditions. Our results demonstrated that a strain carrying approximately three copies of expression cassettes and co-expressing the protein disulfide isomerase showed an approximately 10.7-fold increase in volumetric enzyme activity, using the 2,2'-azino-bis(3-ethylbenzothiazoline-6-sulfonic acid) as the substrate. After optimizing the culture conditions, the volumetric enzyme activity of this strain further increased by approximately 48.7%, reaching 117.3 U/mL. Additionally, the purified catalytic domain of PaDa-I displayed regioselective hydroxylation of R-2-phenoxypropionic acid. The results of this study may facilitate the industrial application of UPOs. KEY POINTS: &#8226; The secretion of the catalytic domain of PaDa-I can be significantly enhanced through increasing gene copy numbers and co-expressing of protein disulfide isomerase. &#8226; After optimizing the culture conditions, the volumetric enzyme activity can reach 117.3 U/mL, using the 2,2'-azino-bis(3-ethylbenzothiazoline-6-sulfonic acid) as the substrate. &#8226; The R-2-phenoxypropionic acid can undergo the specific hydroxylation reaction catalyzed by catalytic domain of PaDa-I, resulting in the formation of R-2-(4-hydroxyphenoxy)propionic acid.</description>
      <author>Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Shu&#8208;Ping Zou, Qi Shen, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Feng Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00253-024-13166-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Insights on Zebrafish Larvae as Experimental Model for Studying Liver Diseases</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003359388-6</link>
      <description>Subhash G. Vasudevan, T. Sachin, V. P. Venkateish, Karan Madan, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396736554

                Zebrafish (Danio rerio) are a species of small freshwater fish native to South Asia belonging to the minnow family, Cyprinidae. Zebrafish are typically used as experimental organism due to its small size, short generation time and the availability of a well-characterized genome. In biomedical research, zebrafish are commonly employed as model organism due to their genetic similarities to humans (sharing 70-80% of their genes) and their rapid development. Zebrafish model have several advantages over other modeling of human diseases such as large-scale genetic mutants, therapeutic compounds screening, live imaging, and tissue specific transgenic animal generation. The zebrafish is an invaluable model for studying development and organogenesis due to external fertilization and the transparency of larvae is best suited for studying early stages of development (Carten et al. 2011, Li and Luo 2013b). The option to generate transgenic and mutant lines makes zebrafish suitable for studying the genetic and molecular basis of physiological processes such as metabolism, excretion and endocrinology. In addition, zebrafish has been used to study the effects of environmental pollutants and to investigate the effects of environmental stress on physiology, such as changes in temperature, pH and oxygen levels. Zebrafish is also a perfect model for studying the effects of natural selection and adaptation, as it is capable of rapid evolution in response to environmental change. Zebrafish larvae can be readily infected with a variety of bacterial, viral and fungal pathogens, making them useful for studying infection biology. In early 1980s, George Streisinger used zebrafish as the first biological model due to its simplicity over mouse models since they were easy to manipulate genetically (Streisinger et al. 1981). Zebrafish models are used to study a wide variety of human diseases, including developmental disorder, metabolic diseases, cardiovascular disorders, inflammation, cancer, ageing, and neurological disorders (Li and Luo 2013b, Rahman Khan and Sulaiman Alhewairini 2019, Fazio et al. 2020, Zanandrea et al. 2020, Choi et al. 2021).</description>
      <author>Subhash G. Vasudevan, T. Sachin, V. P. Venkateish, Karan Madan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003359388-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase evolution during solid-state synthesis of disordered rocksalt cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1107/s205327332309575x</link>
      <description>Kevin H. Stone, Yijin Liu, Dimosthenis Sokaras, William C. Chueh, Johanna Nelson Weker, Acta crystallographica. Section A, Foundations and advances. 79(a2)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4396818227

                Cation-disordered rocksalt (DRX) materials have recently garnered attention for their potential as cathodes in lithiumion batteries.These materials are lithium transition metal oxides which assume a rocksalt type structure with a disordering of the lithium and one or more transition metals on the cation sublattice.The disordering results in several desirable properties such as good lithium transport and small volume changes with cycling.Unlike layered transition metal oxides that are inherently unstable when significant lithium is removed, limiting practical compositions to combinations of cobalt, nickel, and manganese, DRX cathodes can also be synthesized with widely available transition metals to avoid expensive or critical materials.[1]Additional fluorine substitution for oxygen can increase stability for higher lithium content and improve long term capacity retention during cycling.[2,3]Solid-state synthesis, where solid precursors are mixed together, sometimes through ball-milling, then heated either in air or inert gas to high temperatures (typically ~1000&#730;C), has been one of the chief methods for fabricating disordered or partially disordered cathod e materials.For solid-state synthesis, the reaction can go through multiple intermediates before the reaction is completed.These intermediates are not always known and could be desirable end products in themselves, however, without in situ methods, only the endpoints of the synthesis can be studied.X-ray diffraction is a powerful approach for tracking crystalline structures in situ during solid state synthesis.At the Stanford Synchrotron Radiation Lightsource (SSRL), we have used in situ X-ray diffraction to study the solidstate synthesis of disordered rocksalt cathode materials.After careful preparation of the precursor mixture, it is possible to monitor the reaction as the sample is heated to and held at the reaction temperature.From this data it is possible to monitor the phase evolution of the precursors and the formation of the disordered rocksalt product.This in situ data provides important mechanistic insight into the formation reaction of the disordered rocksalt material and allows for easy determination of the impact of changes to the precursor materials or the annealing process.In combination with detailed structural characterization of the product ex situ, we accurately determine the final product composition, level of order/disorder, and performance as a cathode material for lithium-ion batteries.</description>
      <author>Kevin H. Stone, Yijin Liu, Dimosthenis Sokaras, William C. Chueh, Johanna Nelson Weker</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1107/s205327332309575x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What if youth is not enough? Acute coronary syndrome in young patients</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ehjacc/zuae036.032</link>
      <description>Manuel V&#225;zquez, E Minguez De La Guia, Nuria Vallejo Calcerrada, A Abell&#225;n, S. Lopez, P. Ca&#241;eque Garc&#237;a, Felipe Mart&#237;nez, Miguel Corb&#237; Pascual, Laura Exp&#243;sito Calamardo, R Ramos Martinez, Mariano Pastor, Alejandro Lobato, JJ. Portero Portaz, Jes&#250;s Jim&#233;nez Mazuecos, S Diaz Lancha, European heart journal. Acute cardiovascular care. 13(Supplement_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396782016

                Abstract Funding Acknowledgements None. Background Acute Coronary Syndromes (ACS) are the leading cause of mortality in Spain. Further research is needed in order to know risk factors and outcomes in young patients so that medicians could optimize their management and prevention. Purpose Identifying risk factors, clinical characteristics and short-term outcomes in Acute Coronary Syndrome in patients aged 40 and under. Methods A retrospective analysis of patients under 40 years of age who were admitted for ACS, out of 3,859 ACS admissions in Cardiology Intensive Care Unit (CICU) in our hospital between 2012 and 2022. Results 67 patients (1.73%) were included, most of them were males (83.6%). Baseline characteristics are summarized in Table 1. 77.6% had hypertension (HTA), 22.4% had diabetes (DM) and 34.3% had dyslipidemia (DLP). 79.1% were smokers, 9.1% had a history of alcoholism and 29.9% were cocaine users. None of them had a history of stroke, atrial fibrillation (AF). Only 3% had ischemic heart disease. 68.7% of them were ST-elevation myocardial infarction (STEMI) and inferior STEMI was the most common (38.7%). In anterior STEMI (22 patients), 15 had a severe lesion in the mid-left anterior descending artery (LAD), and 6 in the left main stem (LM). Single-vessel disease was the most common (70.8%), with 3-vessel disease in 4.6%. 75.8% received percutaneous coronary intervention (PCI), and 3% underwent bypass surgery. During admission, 10.5% progressed to Killip class III-IV. The ICU mortality was 1.5%. 9% received vasoactive drugs and 4.5% were intubated. Non-invasive ventilation was used in 3% and high-flow nasal cannula oxygen therapy in 5.3%. 3% received intra-aortic balloon pump support and 1.5% underwent dialysis or ultrafiltration. 4.5% received an implantable cardioverter-defibrillator (ICD), although none of them developed bundle branch block or atrioventricular node block, nor AF. After discharge, 11.1% had recurrent ACS, and up to 5.6% underwent PCI again, with a mortality rate of 11.8%. Conclusion Approximately 2% of ACS occur in people younger than 40 years of age. Substance abuse (smoking, cocaine and alcoholism) becomes more prevalent in this group. Prevalence of comorbidities (such as diabetes and nephropathy) are lower, making them less prone to short-term heart failure. However, they are more susceptible to recurrent ischemic events. There is a high incidence of inferior STEMI and LM-STEMI. For these reasons, medicians may need to find out a substance abuse in this group and further research into other risk factors, such as coronary disease family history.Basal characteristicsClinical evolution of patients</description>
      <author>Manuel V&#225;zquez, E Minguez De La Guia, Nuria Vallejo Calcerrada, A Abell&#225;n, S. Lopez, P. Ca&#241;eque Garc&#237;a, Felipe Mart&#237;nez, Miguel Corb&#237; Pascual, Laura Exp&#243;sito Calamardo, R Ramos Martinez, Mariano Pastor, Alejandro Lobato, JJ. Portero Portaz, Jes&#250;s Jim&#233;nez Mazuecos, S Diaz Lancha</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ehjacc/zuae036.032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial nitrogen transformation processes across environments: more than just a cycle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tim.2024.04.006</link>
      <description>Jennifer B. Glass, Kathrin Rousk, Trends in microbiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396709074

                Nitrogen (N) is unique amongst the bioessential elements in that its major reservoir is in the atmosphere, as triple-bonded N2, which comprises 78% of the atmosphere. Breaking the extremely strong triple bond of N2 is challenging; in nature, only the microbial nitrogenase enzyme is known to be capable of this reaction, and nitrogenase is by far the dominant source of N2 fixation on the modern Earth. Abiotic N2 fixation is found only in extremely high energy situations, namely lightning bolts, and industrial N2 fixation for fertilizer production. Indeed, N is one of the elemental cycles most influenced by human activities; in a little over a century, humans have more than doubled fixed N2 in the environment due to industrial N2 fixation via the Haber&#8211;Bosch process. Excess fertilizer use and subsequent runoff contributes to eutrophication of waterways and emissions of greenhouse gases, namely nitrous oxide. While humans have radically changed the N cycle in the Anthropocene, it was single-celled microorganisms that established the nitrogen cycle and its enzymatic processes over Earth's history [1.St&#252;eken E.E. et al.The evolution of Earth's biogeochemical nitrogen cycle.Earth Sci. Rev. 2016; 160: 220-239Crossref Scopus (0) Google Scholar]. Once fixed into 'reactive' N (the term for all forms of N in the environment except N2), N cycles through dozens of inorganic and organic nitrogenous forms on the Earth's surface [2.Zhang X. et al.Global nitrogen cycle: critical enzymes, organisms, and processes for nitrogen budgets and dynamics.Chem. Rev. 2020; 120: 5308-5351Crossref PubMed Scopus (167) Google Scholar]. With every passing year, it becomes clearer that the so-called N cycle, often drawn as a circle, is instead a tangled web. While relatively stable chemical species like nitrate and ammonium are often the focus of attention, highly reactive intermediates &#8211; such as nitric oxide, hydroxylamine, and even hydrazine (rocket fuel) &#8211; are increasingly recognized as the linchpins in the N web but often experience cryptic cycling due to their reactivity. Even more complexity is introduced when one considers the fact that the N web is woven by biotic&#8211;abiotic couplings, such as chemodenitrification, in which products of microbial metabolism react with ferrous iron to produce gaseous N. Biotic transformations in the N cycle are primarily catalyzed by metalloenzymes, many of which contain iron, molybdenum, and/or copper cofactors [3.Lycus P. et al.Structural biology of proteins involved in nitrogen cycling.Curr. Opin. Chem. Biol. 2023; 74102278Crossref Scopus (0) Google Scholar]. For instance, alternative forms of nitrogenase (vanadium&#8211;iron or iron&#8211;iron) have been detected, but they are rare in natural environments. Intriguingly, molybdenum&#8211;iron nitrogenase is by far the dominant form, even in environments in which vanadium is present at higher concentrations than molybdenum [4.Warren M.J. et al.Molybdenum-based diazotrophy in a sphagnum peatland in northern Minnesota.Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 2017; 83e01174&#8211;17Crossref Scopus (43) Google Scholar]. In some environments, such as the low-chlorophyll, high-nitrate regions of the oceans, scarcity of trace metals, particularly iron, limits photosynthesis and nitrate assimilation by phytoplankton. Scientific disciplines separate the N cycle/web into soil, freshwater, marine, and anthropogenic compartments; microbial life, of course, ignores all such designations and N freely flows across such artificial boundaries. While challenging, enhanced communication across disciplinary spheres is vital for expediting scientific discoveries and applications. Towards that end, Trends in Microbiology has joined forces with iScience to present a special issue on 'Nitrogen Cycling Across Environments' that explores microbial N processes across aquatic and terrestrial environments, with a focus on lessons that can be gained from cross-communication across the fields. The N cycle is replete with examples of how processes discovered in one environment have informed another. This is particularly common in the study of wastewater engineering, in which a large priority is conversion of reactive N from human and animal waste to N gas while minimizing greenhouse gas emissions, also known as biological N removal [5.Winkler M.K. Straka L. New directions in biological nitrogen removal and recovery from wastewater.Curr. Opin. Biotechnol. 2019; 57: 50-55Crossref PubMed Scopus (184) Google Scholar]. Anaerobic oxidation of ammonium (anammox) was first characterized in samples of wastewater sludge but has since been discovered in soil as well. More recently, the pathway of complete nitrification, thus far restricted to terrestrial environments, was discovered in other samples from engineered, aquatic systems. Crosstalk between fields can also bring new ideas about potential interactions between species in the N cycle. Interactions between diazotrophic bacteria and photosynthetic eukaryotes in root nodules (e.g., in legumes and alder trees) have long been studied in soils but remained relatively unknown in the ocean until the discovery of UCYN-A unicellular cyanobacteria in symbiosis with haptophyte algae. Likewise, while non-cyanobacterial diazotrophs have long been known to be key for terrestrial N2 fixation, they were only relatively recently discovered in the ocean. The role of viruses in the nitrogen cycle remains understudied across ecosystems. Many technological challenges hinder progress, such as challenges cultivating and genetic systems for environmentally key species and applying limited rate measurements across scales. Methods for microbial cultivation and pathway characterization are increasingly complex, which poses problems for widespread access to study of the cycle. This special issue tackles these questions and more. Three of the articles focus on the entry of N into the cycle via N2 fixation catalyzed by nitrogenase. Chakraborty et al. discuss engineering N2-fixing bacteria to increase N yield to crops, Zehr and Capone highlight recent developments and challenges in marine N2 fixation research, and Rucker and Ka&#231;ar describe interconnections between metal cycles and N cycles. Bowen et al. highlight salt marshes as an interface between terrestrial and marine realms, both subject to anthropogenic disturbances, which remove excess N prior to its entry into marine habitats. Deutsch and colleagues tackle the temperature dependence of biological N2 fixation and uncover a relationship that is similar across terrestrial and marine environments. Beeckman et al. critically examine the role of nitrification inhibitors that are used to relieve the deleterious effects associated with excess nitrification, providing insights into their applicability in the field. Sagha&#239; and Hallin review ammonifiers in terrestrial and aquatic environments. The article looks at enzymes involved in the reduction of nitrate and nitrite to ammonia with a particular focus on the widely used marker, NrfA. The special issue also highlights two recently published articles on the influence of tillage practices on the rhizosphere [6.Behr J.H. et al.Long-term conservation tillage with reduced nitrogen fertilization intensity can improve winter wheat health via positive plant&#8211;microorganism feedback in the rhizosphere.FEMS Microb. Ecol. 2024; 100fiae003Crossref Scopus (1) Google Scholar] and the identification of Methylomirabilis bacterium capable of methane-dependent complete denitrification [7.Yao X. et al.Methane-dependent complete denitrification by a single Methylomirabilis bacterium.Nat. Microbiol. 2024; 9: 464-476Crossref PubMed Scopus (5) Google Scholar]. Finally, our Microbe of the Month for this special issue is the diazotrophic Gram-negative bacterium, Bradyrhizobium japonicum (diazoefficiens), covered by Ong and O'Brian. We would also like to draw your attention to the articles published in iScience that are part of this interdisciplinary collection (https://www.cell.com/cp/collections-microbial-nitrogen-transformation). Christensen and Rousk review global sources of N2O emissions, identifying those which are influenced by anthropogenic activities, and highlighting agricultural systems with the potential for mitigation. Derikvand and colleagues focus on the microbial ecology of engineered aquaponic systems, investigating microbial community dynamics and ammonia removal in response to ammonia-oxidizing inocula and changing pH. While dozens of microbial reactions in the N cycle have been discovered, many more exergonic and disproportionation reactions, and the enzymes that catalyze them, await unearthing [8.Kuypers M.M.M. et al.The microbial nitrogen-cycling network.Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2018; 16: 263-276Crossref PubMed Scopus (2225) Google Scholar]. Crystal structures of membrane proteins such as ammonia monooxygenase have been notoriously difficult to solve but are essential for mechanistic understanding of nitrogen cycle processes [9.Bradely B.T. et al.Integrated structural biology and molecular ecology of N-cycling enzymes from ammonia-oxidizing archaea.Environ. Microbiol. 2017; 5: 484-491Google Scholar]. Forms of oxygen-resistant enzymes previously thought to be extremely oxygen sensitive have also been discovered, such as the atypical form of nitrous oxide reductase, and surely many more remain to be found [10.Simon J. Klotz M.G. Diversity and evolution of bioenergetic systems involved in microbial nitrogen compound transformations.BBA-Bioenergetics. 2013; 2: 114-135Crossref Scopus (259) Google Scholar]. As we venture even further into the Anthropocene, the importance of studying N cycling across environments subject to global climate change becomes ever more important. Nitrogen is a bioessential element with an almost limitless supply from the atmosphere, yet conversion to reactive N currently relies on fossil fuels and results in eutrophication and greenhouse emissions. Harnessing insights from microbes that drive the N cycle to tackle these environmental challenges will be increasingly key going forward [11.Stein L.Y. Klotz M.G. The nitrogen cycle.Curr. Biol. 2016; 26: R94-R98Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (327) Google Scholar].</description>
      <author>Jennifer B. Glass, Kathrin Rousk</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tim.2024.04.006</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
