<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 01:26:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Co vacancy at tetrahedral site in spinel Co3O4 to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction performance in alkaline and neutral electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132863</link>
      <description>Chen Guang-Yi, Qiushi Yin, Xiang Li, Xiaoqiang Han, Chunxia Qin, Ji Yun, Yu&#8208;Li Chen, Wenzhuo Zhang, Fuel. 378(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401837737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Guang-Yi, Qiushi Yin, Xiang Li, Xiaoqiang Han, Chunxia Qin, Ji Yun, Yu&#8208;Li Chen, Wenzhuo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132863</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled synthesis of Sn doped Cu&#8211;Ni3S2 on Ni foam as efficient electrocatalyst for urea oxidation reaction and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.280</link>
      <description>Wei Wen, Xiaoqiang Du, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 85(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401837738

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wen, Xiaoqiang Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Identification of Electrocatalyst Layer Generated on Lead Electrode Under Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4935657</link>
      <description>Naoto Todoroki, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401843155

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naoto Todoroki</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4935657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous heterojunction CoSe2&#8211;MoSe2 nanosheet arrays for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.296</link>
      <description>Shuaiqiang Liu, Yu Li, Yinghua Yan, Xingxing Jiang, Chuanmin Ding, Junwen Wang, Donghong Duan, Qinbo Yuan, Xiaogang Hao, Shibin Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 85(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401843643

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuaiqiang Liu, Yu Li, Yinghua Yan, Xingxing Jiang, Chuanmin Ding, Junwen Wang, Donghong Duan, Qinbo Yuan, Xiaogang Hao, Shibin Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Surface Ru&lt;sub&gt;oct&lt;/sub&gt;&#9472;O&#9472;Co&lt;sub&gt;oct&lt;/sub&gt; Units With Optimized Co&lt;sub&gt;oct&lt;/sub&gt; Spin States for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405865</link>
      <description>Can&#8208;Wen Yu, Zi&#8208;Qiang Chen, Hongyi Xu, Ting Ouyang, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401844947

                Abstract The introduction of noble metal into spinel structure is an effective strategy to develop efficient oxygen evolution/reduction reaction (OER/ORR) catalysts. Herein, surface Co oct is substituted by Ru oct in Ru x &#8208;Mn 0.5 Co 2.5&#8208;x O 4 /NCNTs by ion&#8208;exchange, where presence of Ru oct &#9472;O&#9472;Co oct unit facilitates electron transfer. This strong electron coupling effect leads downward shift in d&#8208;band center and a narrowing of d&#8208;p bandgap. The increased charge density of Co oct bridged with Ru oct dioxygen optimizes adsorption of oxygen intermediates ( * OH) and occupation of electrons in e g &#8208;orbital octahedral. The measured ORR/OER voltage difference is only 0.71 V. The peak power density of assembled zinc&#8211;air battery reaches 148.8 mW h cm &#8722;2 , and energy density at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 reaches 813.6 mA h g Zn &#8722;1 , approaching a theoretical value of 820 mA h g Zn &#8722;1 . The catalyst demonstrates stable operation for over 500 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and over 200 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work provides new insights to guide fabrication of advanced oxygen electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Can&#8208;Wen Yu, Zi&#8208;Qiang Chen, Hongyi Xu, Ting Ouyang, Zhao&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Co-containing polyoxogemanotungstate for alkaline electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01680g</link>
      <description>Dahuan Li, Lei Jia, Yixin Liu, Cai Sun, Xin&#8208;Xiong Li, Pingwei Cai, Yan&#8208;Qiong Sun, Shou&#8208;Tian Zheng, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401847508

                Efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are paramount to the development of electrochemical devices for clean energy and fuel conversion. However, due to the complicated structure of heterogeneous...</description>
      <author>Dahuan Li, Lei Jia, Yixin Liu, Cai Sun, Xin&#8208;Xiong Li, Pingwei Cai, Yan&#8208;Qiong Sun, Shou&#8208;Tian Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01680g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of multilayered transition metal MOF/Ni3N/NF composites for efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176142</link>
      <description>Xiangyu Meng, Zengyan Wei, Liang Ma, Rongfeng Chen, Xiaoxiao Huang, Peigang He, Dechang Jia, Yu Zhou, Xiaoming Duan, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401852808

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangyu Meng, Zengyan Wei, Liang Ma, Rongfeng Chen, Xiaoxiao Huang, Peigang He, Dechang Jia, Yu Zhou, Xiaoming Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Key role of nonprecious oxygen-evolving active site in NiOOH electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161066</link>
      <description>Qi Zhang, Na Song, Ming Fang, Yixing Li, Xuedi Chen, Yue Li, Lei He, Wenbiao Zhang, Xiaoyu Ma, Xianzhang Lei, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401858995

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Zhang, Na Song, Ming Fang, Yixing Li, Xuedi Chen, Yue Li, Lei He, Wenbiao Zhang, Xiaoyu Ma, Xianzhang Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Ni-doped dual MOF-derived urchin-like Co-Fe layered double hydroxides for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176155</link>
      <description>Zikang Tang, Lin Hao, Mingjie Hu, Gao Y, Yufan Zhang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401862575

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zikang Tang, Lin Hao, Mingjie Hu, Gao Y, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of interface electric field over CoMoP-CoMoP2 heterostructure for high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155184</link>
      <description>Shaoshuai Xu, Wenjing Cui, Yudong Feng, Chunping Li, Xingwei Sun, J. Bai, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401862923

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaoshuai Xu, Wenjing Cui, Yudong Feng, Chunping Li, Xingwei Sun, J. Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Electrochemical Catalytic Performance of Novel Bifunctional Oxygen Vacancy-Enriched Silver Niobate (Agnbo3) Through Electrochemical Activation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4936286</link>
      <description>Deepak R. Patil, Harish S. Chavan, A. F. Lee, Geon Lee, Deepak R. Patil, Ki&#8208;Young Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401863282

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deepak R. Patil, Harish S. Chavan, A. F. Lee, Geon Lee, Deepak R. Patil, Ki&#8208;Young Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4936286</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallated graphynes as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions: A DFT study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114489</link>
      <description>Ting Yao, Huohai Yang, Xiaoyue Fu, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Qiang Ke, Xin Chen, Molecular Catalysis. 567(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401844774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Yao, Huohai Yang, Xiaoyue Fu, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Qiang Ke, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterointerface engineering of yolk-shell-structured Mn2O3/RuO2 for boosting oxygen electrocatalysis in rechargeable liquid and flexible zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155118</link>
      <description>Xuena Ma, Mingyang Liu, Ziqiang Xu, Panzhe Qiao, Chao Li, Ruihong Wang, Qian Zhang, Jinlong Zou, Baojiang Jiang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401852103

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuena Ma, Mingyang Liu, Ziqiang Xu, Panzhe Qiao, Chao Li, Ruihong Wang, Qian Zhang, Jinlong Zou, Baojiang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Feature: Self&#8208;Modification of Defective TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; under Controlled H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Ar Gas Environment and Dynamics of Photoinduced Surface Oxygen Vacancies (ChemSusChem 16/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202481603</link>
      <description>Tim Tjardts, Marie Elis, Josiah Shondo, Lennart Vo&#223;, Ulrich Sch&#252;rmann, Franz Faupel, Lorenz Kienle, Salih Veziro&#287;lu, Oral Cenk Aktas, ChemSusChem. 17(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401881215

                The Cover Feature abstractly depicts the influence of a mixture of argon (symbolized by pink) and hydrogen (symbolized by blue) on a TiO2 pellet sample in the hydrogenation process. The blue cylinder in the center shows a defective TiO2 pellet sample with an enhanced photocatalytic activity. The green and yellow corona around the cylinder embodies this activity. The grey ellipse to the right shows the induced defects; the Ti3+ site and the oxygen vacancy Vo. More information can be found in the Research Article by S. Veziroglu, O. C. Aktas and co-workers.</description>
      <author>Tim Tjardts, Marie Elis, Josiah Shondo, Lennart Vo&#223;, Ulrich Sch&#252;rmann, Franz Faupel, Lorenz Kienle, Salih Veziro&#287;lu, Oral Cenk Aktas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202481603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Ca2+&#8594;Sr2+ substitution on the mechanism of O-O bond formation in photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01117-2</link>
      <description>Gabriel Bury, Yulia Pushkar, Photosynthesis Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401884144

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gabriel Bury, Yulia Pushkar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01117-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient CoFeP Nanoparticle Catalysts for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14171384</link>
      <description>Abhishek Meena, Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Aditya Narayan Singh, Vijaya Gopalan Sree, Hyunsik Im, S. K. Cho, Nanomaterials. 14(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401891652

                Developing effective and long-lasting electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical for increasing sustainable hydrogen production. This paper describes the production and characterization of CoFeP nanoparticles (CFP NPs) as high-performance electrocatalysts for OER. The CFP NPs were produced using a simple hydrothermal technique followed by phosphorization, yielding an amorphous/crystalline composite structure with improved electrochemical characteristics. Our results reveal that CFP NPs have a surprisingly low overpotential of 284 mV at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2, greatly exceeding the precursor CoFe oxide/hydroxide (CFO NPs) and the commercial RuO2 catalyst. Furthermore, CFP NPs demonstrate exceptional stability, retaining a constant performance after 70 h of continuous operation. Post-OER characterization analysis revealed transformations in the catalyst, including the formation of cobalt&#8211;iron oxides/oxyhydroxides. Despite these changes, CFP NPs showed superior long-term stability compared to native metal oxides/oxyhydroxides, likely due to enhanced surface roughness and increased active sites. This study proposes a viable strategy for designing low-cost, non-precious metal-based OER catalysts, which will help advance sustainable energy technology.</description>
      <author>Abhishek Meena, Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Aditya Narayan Singh, Vijaya Gopalan Sree, Hyunsik Im, S. K. Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14171384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated MXenes and Metal Oxide Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Synthesis, Mechanisms, and Advances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc04141k</link>
      <description>Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Abdul Hanan, Yuan Wang, Hiang Kwee Lee, Hamidreza Arandiyan, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401893313

                Electrochemical water splitting is a promising approach to produce H2 through renewable electricity, but its energy efficiency is severely constrained by the kinetically slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which...</description>
      <author>Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Abdul Hanan, Yuan Wang, Hiang Kwee Lee, Hamidreza Arandiyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc04141k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of novel FeSe&#8211;GO composite: a highly efficient electro-catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00434-5</link>
      <description>Khadim Hussain, Ali Junaid, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Muhammad Shoaib, Nigarish Bano, Razan A. Alshgari, Nosheen Blouch, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Journal of the Korean Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401893438

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Khadim Hussain, Ali Junaid, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Muhammad Shoaib, Nigarish Bano, Razan A. Alshgari, Nosheen Blouch, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00434-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co&#8211;Mn Bimetallic Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks Nanosheets for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202401049</link>
      <description>Yongchao Hao, Sheng Wang, Shuling Cheng, Huiya Cheng, Qianyun He, Lizhi Yi, Energy Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401911685

                Developing an efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst is the footstone of many electrochemical energy conversion devices. Herein, a cobalt&#8211;manganese bimetallic metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) is developed as an efficient OER catalyst (denoted as Co 3 Mn 1 BDC). The Co 3 Mn 1 BDC nanosheets demonstrate advantages in specific surface area, pore size distribution comparing with monometallic Co BDC and Mn BDC. The performance investigations demonstrate that the doping of Mn in Co&#8208;based MOFs facilitates the electrochemical area, charge transfer efficiency, reaction kinetics, and turnover frequency. As a consequence, the Co 3 Mn 1 BDC exhibits a low overpotential of 289 mV at current of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a favorable Tafel slope of 56.8 mV dec &#8722;1 on glassy carbon electrode, which is better than IrO 2 . When the catalyst is loaded on Ni foam, the overpotential and Tafel slope are further decreased to 231 mV and 50.8 mV dec &#8722;1 . Moreover, the Raman spectrum confirms that the Co 3 Mn 1 BDC can be transformed into active CoOOH, suggesting the bright prospect in electrocatalysis devices as &#8220;precatalyst&#8221;.</description>
      <author>Yongchao Hao, Sheng Wang, Shuling Cheng, Huiya Cheng, Qianyun He, Lizhi Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202401049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasonic-Induced Surface Disordering Promotes Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution of TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10977</link>
      <description>Chunyao Liu, Changhua Wang, Sheng Wang, Dashuai Li, Dexin Jin, Bunsho Ohtani, Baoshun Liu, He Ma, Jinglun Du, Yichun Liu, Xintong Zhang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401933572

                Surface disordering has been considered an effective strategy for tailoring the charge separation and surface chemistry of semiconductor photocatalysts. A simple but reliable method to create surface disordering is, therefore, urgently needed for the development of high-performance semiconductor photocatalysts and their practical applications. Herein, we report that the ultrasonic processing, which is commonly employed in the dispersion of photocatalysts, can induce the surface disordering of TiO2 and significantly promote its performance for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution. A 40 min ultrasonic treatment of TiO2 (Degussa P25) enhances the photocatalytic hydrogen production by 42.7 times, achieving a hydrogen evolution rate of 1425.4 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 without any cocatalyst. Comprehensive structural, spectral, and electrochemical analyses reveal that the ultrasonic treatment induces the surface disordering of TiO2, and consequently reduces the density of deep electron traps, extends the separation of photogenerated charges, and facilitates the hydrogen evolution reaction relative to oxygen reduction. The ultrasonic treatment manifests a more pronounced effect on disordering the surface of anatase than rutile, agreeing well with the enhanced photocatalysis of anatase rather than rutile. This study demonstrates that ultrasonic-induced surface disordering could be an effective strategy for the activation of photocatalysts and might hold significant implications for the applications in photocatalytic hydrogen evolution, small molecule activation, and biomass conversion.</description>
      <author>Chunyao Liu, Changhua Wang, Sheng Wang, Dashuai Li, Dexin Jin, Bunsho Ohtani, Baoshun Liu, He Ma, Jinglun Du, Yichun Liu, Xintong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935618

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935662

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935697

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935698

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935802

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937743

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937824

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937912

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937913

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938081

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938123

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938303

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v4/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938401

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v4/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938503

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scale-Up, Continuous and Low-Temperature Production of Multimetal Based Electrocatalysts toward Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08677</link>
      <description>Pak Kin Wong, Jun Zhang, Jia&#8208;qi Bai, Yong Jiang, Jingshuai Chen, Mingyuan Wu, Song Sun, Jingshuai Chen, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401942075

                Electrocatalytic water splitting is a crucial strategy for advancing hydrogen energy and addressing the global energy crisis. Despite its significance, the need for a straightforward and swift method to synthesize electrocatalysts with exceptional performance remains pressing. In this study, we demonstrate a novel approach for the preparation of multimetal-based electrocatalysts in a continuous flow reactor, enabling the quick synthesis of a large number of products through a streamlined process. The resultant NiFe-LDH comprises nanoflakes with a high specific surface area and requires only 255.4 mV overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 in 1 M KOH, surpassing samples fabricated by conventional hydrothermal methods. Our method can also be applied to craft a spectrum of other multimetal-based electrocatalysts, including CoFe-LDH, CoAl-LDH, NiMn-LDH, and NiCoFe-LDH. Additionally, the NiFe-LDH electrocatalyst is further applied to anodic methanol electrooxidation coupled with cathodic hydrogen evolution. Moreover, the simplicity and generality of our fabrication method render it applicable for the facile preparation of various multimetal-based electrocatalysts, offering a scalable solution to the quest for high-performance catalysts in advancing sustainable energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Pak Kin Wong, Jun Zhang, Jia&#8208;qi Bai, Yong Jiang, Jingshuai Chen, Mingyuan Wu, Song Sun, Jingshuai Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the potential application of Cr2AlC MAX phase as an emerging electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00815-w</link>
      <description>R Madhushree, K.R. Sunaja Devi, Emergent Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401958081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R Madhushree, K.R. Sunaja Devi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00815-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocarbon-based Bifunctional Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00297</link>
      <description>Shouvik Mete, Kushagra Goel, Santosh K. Singh, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401959818

                For the sustainable development of green and clean electrochemical energy technologies, the advancement of high-performance electrode materials is essential. Precious metal catalysts such as those based on Pt, Ir, and Ru show high catalytic performance, but their scarcity and high cost restrict their application in energy technologies. Hence nanocarbon-based bifunctional electrocatalysts have emerged as a promising class of materials that hold the key to addressing critical challenges in energy conversion and storage technologies. Nanocarbon materials, such as carbon nanotubes, graphene, and their derivatives, have shown remarkable electrical conductivity, high surface area, and exceptional chemical stability, making them ideal candidates for electrocatalysis. However, these nanocarbon materials as such are electroneutral and catalytically inactive. Heteroatom doping and functionalization change the electronic properties of the nanocarbons and permit multifunctional electrocatalytic activity. These modified nanocarbons can catalyze the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in electrochemical systems, making them applicable in fuel cells, water electrolyzers, metal&#8211;air batteries, etc. This dual functionality of the materials in energy devices enhances the overall efficiency of energy conversion devices. Applications of nanocarbon-based bifunctional electrocatalysts extend beyond energy storage and conversion, encompassing electrochemical sensors, environmental remediation, etc. The multifunctional nature of nanocarbon materials, coupled with their versatility, holds great promise for developing efficient, durable, and cost-effective electrochemical devices. This chapter provides an insight into the promising field of nanocarbon-based bifunctional electrocatalysts and underscores their significance in shaping a sustainable energy future.</description>
      <author>Shouvik Mete, Kushagra Goel, Santosh K. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Aggregation of M&#8722;N&#8722;C Single&#8208;Atom Electrocatalysts into Highly Efficient MOOH Nanoclusters during Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413308</link>
      <description>Shanshan Lu, Zhipu Zhang, Chuanqi Cheng, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401970934

                M&#8722;N&#8722;C&#8208;type single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) are highly efficient for the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). And the isolated metal atoms are usually considered real active sites. However, the oxidative structural evolution of coordinated N during the OER will probably damage the structure of M&#8722;N&#8722;C, hence resulting in a completely different reaction mechanism. Here, we reveal the aggregation of M&#8722;N&#8722;C materials during the alkaline OER. Taking Ni&#8722;N&#8722;C as an example, multiple characterizations show that the coordinated N on the surface of Ni&#8208;N&#8208;C is almost completely dissolved in the form of NO3&#8722;, accompanied by the generation of abundant O functional groups on the surface of the carbon support. Accordingly, the Ni&#8722;N bonds are broken. Through a dissolution&#8208;redeposition mechanism and further oxidation, the isolated Ni atoms are finally converted to NiOOH nanoclusters supported by carbon as the real active sites for the enhanced OER. Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C and Co&#8722;N&#8722;C also have similar aggregation mechanism. Our findings provide unique insight into the structural evolution and activity origin of M&#8722;N&#8722;C&#8208;based catalysts under electrooxidative conditions.</description>
      <author>Shanshan Lu, Zhipu Zhang, Chuanqi Cheng, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Individual Marcus-type kinetics controls singlet and triplet oxygen evolution from superoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3vrzz</link>
      <description>Soumyadip Mondal, Hung Duc Nguyen, Robert Hauschild, Stefan A. Freunberger, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401955824

                Oxygen evolution from superoxide is a critical aspect of oxygen redox chemistry. However, the factors determining the formation of often harmful singlet oxygen are unclear. Here, we report that the release of triplet or singlet oxygen is governed by individual Marcus normal and inverted region behavior. Using a wide range of chemical oxidants, we found that as the driving force increases, the initially dominant evolution of triplet oxygen slows down, and singlet oxygen evolution becomes predominant with higher maximum kinetics. This behavior also applies to superoxide disproportionation, the oxidation of one superoxide by another, in both non-aqueous and aqueous systems, where Lewis and Br&#248;nsted acidity control driving forces. Our findings suggest ways to understand and control spin states and kinetics in oxygen redox chemistry.</description>
      <author>Soumyadip Mondal, Hung Duc Nguyen, Robert Hauschild, Stefan A. Freunberger</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3vrzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inducing Oxygen Vacancies Using Plasma Etching to Enhance the Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity of the CoMn2O4 Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.08.364</link>
      <description>Lezhuo Li, Ruifeng Xu, Xu Dong Zhang, Wenbo Wang, Bingjun Yang, Juan Yang, Tianhong Zhou, Pengjun Ma, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401852511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lezhuo Li, Ruifeng Xu, Xu Dong Zhang, Wenbo Wang, Bingjun Yang, Juan Yang, Tianhong Zhou, Pengjun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.08.364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cholate Extraction of a Heme-Protein from Spinach Thylakoids and its Possible Involvement in PS-II Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00190-9</link>
      <description>H.Y. Nakatani, James Barber, No host. 2(1-2)] 1981. https://openalex.org/W4402020885

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H.Y. Nakatani, James Barber</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 1981 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00190-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrastable monolithic electrodes with single-atom platinum-oxygen sites for efficient hydrogen evolution in acidic conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.198</link>
      <description>Bowen Ren, Jhang-Fu Haung, Jia Li, Wen Wu Xu, Bin Dong, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401841705

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bowen Ren, Jhang-Fu Haung, Jia Li, Wen Wu Xu, Bin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.198</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidation behavior of SiC&#8208;AlN ceramics exposed to dry oxygen and water oxygen environments at 1100&#8211;1300&#176;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14903</link>
      <description>Xiaofan Sun, Xiao&#8208;Wu Chen, Min Tan, Yanmei Kan, Xihai Jin, Zhen Wang, Haibo Liu, Jianbao Hu, Jinshan Yang, Shaoming Dong, International Journal of Applied Ceramic Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401864334

                Abstract The corrosion of SiC f /SiC composites in gas environment threatens their long&#8208;term service in aeroengines as hot&#8208;end structure components. Addition of corrosion&#8208;resistant phases into SiC matrix is a potential strategy to improve the service performance of SiC f /SiC materials. Here, AlN added SiC ceramics were prepared by reactive melt infiltration, and the effect of AlN phase on the oxidation resistance of the ceramics was emphasized. The oxidation tests were performed in dry oxygen and water oxygen atmospheres at 1100&#176;C&#8211;1300&#176;C, respectively. The oxidation mechanism was discussed based on the microstructure evolution of the oxide layer. The results show that the oxide layer is composed of aluminum silicate glass and Al 2 O 3 flakes dispersedly distributed in the glass phase. As the temperature rises, the oxide layer gradually grows and thickens. Finally, a smooth and dense protective layer could be formed on the surface of ceramics to resist oxidation. This study can provide a profound insight to construct SiC f /SiC composites with excellent oxidation resistance.</description>
      <author>Xiaofan Sun, Xiao&#8208;Wu Chen, Min Tan, Yanmei Kan, Xihai Jin, Zhen Wang, Haibo Liu, Jianbao Hu, Jinshan Yang, Shaoming Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/ijac.14903</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of ultrafiltration membranes based on methacrylate copolymers containing quaternary ammonium and PEG units for dye removal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/polyeng-2024-0085</link>
      <description>Zihao Zhao, Yunyun Xue, Yani Jiang, Qianwei Su, Tong Sun, Wu-Shang Yang, Ze&#8208;Lin Qiu, Liheng Zhu, Li&#8208;Feng Fang, Bao&#8208;Ku Zhu, Journal of Polymer Engineering. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401852494

                Abstract Phase inversion involves in a complex process due to numerous factors affecting the membrane formation. Among them, polymer chain entanglement from polymeric membrane materials plays a critical role in regulating membrane structure and is still worth further exploration. Herein, a series of methacrylate copolymers with different contents of poly(ethylene glycol) methacrylate (PEGMA) were designed and synthesized, and ultrafiltration membranes cast from these copolymers were systematically investigated regarding structural evolution and filtration performance. Surface zeta potential of membranes gradually transformed from positive to negative with the increasing PEGMA content due to nonsolvent-induced surface migration of element oxygen, and meanwhile the transformation from finger-like pore structure to sponge-like pore structure in the support layer was observed, which could be attributed to chain entanglement of the PEGMA-rich copolymer. Filtration experiments indicated that sponge-like membranes possessed better separation effect of Victoria blue B compared with finger-like membranes, and the optimized mPP40-15 % showed a retention rate of 99.55 % and permeance of 110.26 L m &#8722;2 h &#8722;1 bar &#8722;1 and displayed good selective separation of dye/salt mixture. Besides, sponge-like membranes also exhibited easy regeneration, anti-fouling property and filtration stability. This work will provide guidance for modulating membrane structure and offer an alternative material for membrane separation in handling dye wastewater.</description>
      <author>Zihao Zhao, Yunyun Xue, Yani Jiang, Qianwei Su, Tong Sun, Wu-Shang Yang, Ze&#8208;Lin Qiu, Liheng Zhu, Li&#8208;Feng Fang, Bao&#8208;Ku Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/polyeng-2024-0085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Antioxidant-Ciprofloxacin Combinations on the Evolution of Antibiotic Resistance in Pseudomonas aeruginosa Biofilms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4756544/v1</link>
      <description>Oana Ciofu, Doaa Higazy, Marwa Ahmed, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401881589

                Abstract Antibiotic resistance in biofilms is a critical challenge driven by mechanisms such as increased oxidative stress, which could lead to enhanced mutagenesis. Experimental evolution studies have shown that biofilm growth fosters antimicrobial resistance and tolerance. The bactericidal antibiotic ciprofloxacin (CIP) exacerbates oxidative stress, enhancing reactive oxygen species (ROS) production and mutagenesis at sub-inhibitory concentrations. This study tests the hypothesis that antioxidants (AOs) such as N-acetyl-cysteine (NAC), and Edaravone (ED) could serve as anti-evolutionary drugs to prevent or reduce antimicrobial resistance in P. aeruginosa biofilms exposed to sub-inhibitory concentrations of ciprofloxacin (CIP), with Thiourea (THU) used as a control. In vitro experimental evolution studies using the monitor strain PAO1-mCherry-PCD-gfp + were conducted in flow cells and glass beads biofilm models. The harvested biofilm populations underwent population analysis and the flow-cell populations were also whole genome sequenced (WGS). The results showed that the CIP-AO combination of CIP-THU could reduce the fast increase of mutagenic resistance in both biofilm models. The confocal laser microscopy of flow cells biofilms showed a reduction in the percentage of nfxB mutants in biofilms treated with all the three CIP-AO combinations compared to the CIP treatment alone following 24h of treatment. The population analysis revealed a significant reduction of the subpopulations growing on 0.5 mg/L of CIP-supplemented plates in all the combined treatments of CIP-AO as compared to CIP populations. The WGS results showed CIP-specific mutants in the CIP-treated populations including nfxB and nalC mutations which were not observed in CIP-AO-treated ones. Flagellar gene mutations appeared in CIP-ED (fliG) and CIP-NAC (flhA) treatments. Additionally, wspA, which regulates biofilm formation, had a transversion mutation in CIP-ED and a deletion mutation in CIP-NAC. The minimum inhibitory concentrations (MICs) level for CIP-treated isolates was significantly higher than all isolates from CIP-AO treatments in both tested biofilm models of flow cells and glass beads. Overall, these findings suggest that the two clinical antioxidants may have a potential role in mitigating the development of antibiotic resistance in biofilms.</description>
      <author>Oana Ciofu, Doaa Higazy, Marwa Ahmed</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4756544/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bansk&#225; &#352;tiavnica ore district</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5382/gb.31.09</link>
      <description>Jaroslav Lexa, J. &#352;tohl, Vlastimil Kone&#269;n&#253;, No host. None(None)] 1999. https://openalex.org/W4401944450

                Abstract The Bansk&#225; &#352;tiavnica ore district is in the central zone of the largest stratovolcano in the Central Slovakia Neogene Volcanic Field, which is situated at the inner side of the Carpathian arc over the Hercynian basement with the Late Paleozoic and Mesozoic sedimentary cover. Volcanic rocks of the High-K orogenic suite are of the Badenian through Pannonian age (16.5&#8211; 8.5 Ma). Their petrogenesis is closely related to subduction of flysch belt oceanic basement underneath the advancing Carpathian arc and to back-arc extension processes. The stratovolcano includes a large caldera 20 km in diameter and a late-stage resurgent horst in its centre, exposing a basement and extensive subvolcanic intrusive complex. The following stages have been recognized in the evolution of the stratovolcano: (1) formation of a large pyroxene/hornblende-pyroxene andesite stratovolcano; (2) denudation, emplacement of a diorite intrusion; (3) emplacement of a large granodiorite bell-jar pluton within the basement; (4) emplacement of granodiorite/quartz-diorite porphyry stocks and dyke clusters around the pluton; (5) caldera subsidence and its filling by biotite-hornblende andesite volcanics, emplacement of quartz-diorite porphyry sills and dykes at the subvolcanic level; (6) renewed activity of andesites from dispersed centres on slopes of the volcano; (7) uplift of a resurgent horst accompanied by rhyolite volcanics and granite porphyry dykes. The following types of ore deposits (mineralizations) have been identified in the Bansk&#225; &#352;tiavnica ore district: 1. Quartz-pyrophyllite-pyrite high-sulphidation system at &#352;obov, related to the diorite intrusion. 2. Magnetite skarn deposits and occurrences at contacts of the granodiorite pluton with Mesozoic carbonate rocks. Magnetite ores occur as lenses in the calcic skarns. 3. Stockwork/disseminated base metal deposit along an irregular network of fractures in apical parts of the granodiorite pluton and in remnants of basement rocks. Mineral paragenesis is simple, with leading sphalerite and galena and minor chalcopyrite and pyrite. In overlying andesites the mineralization is accompanied by metasomatic quartzites and argillites with pyrophyllite, kaolinite, illite and pyrite. 4. Porphyry /skarn copper deposits and occurrences related to granodiorite/quartz-diorite porphyry dyke clusters and stocks around the granodiorite intrusion. The mineralized zone is represented by accumulations of chalcopyrite in exo- and endo-skarns, usually of the magnesian type affected by serpentinization. Besides chalcopyrite, pyrhotite, minor bornite, chalcosite, tennantite and magnetite, rare molybdenite and gold are present. The alteration pattern around productive intrusions includes an external zone of propylitization, a zone of argillitic alteration (kaolinite &#8212; illite &#8212; pyrite) and an internal zone of phyllic alteration (quartz &#8212; sericite &#8212; pyrite). Biotitization is rare and limited to porphyry intrusions. 5. Intrusion related &#8220;mesothermal&#8221; gold deposit in an andesitic environment just above the granodiorite intrusion. Gold of high fineness with base metal mineralization is contained in brecciated and/or banded quartz veins of subhorizontal orientation, parallel to the surface of granodiorite pluton. At least the first phase of mineralization is older than quartz-diorite porphyry sills, which separate granodiorite and blocks of mineralized andesite. 6. Hot spring type advanced argillic systems in the caldera filling. Silicites and opalites accompanied by kaolinite, alunite and pyrite grade downward into smectite dominated argillites. 7. Vein type epithermal precious/base metal deposits and occurrences as a result of the long lasting interaction among structural evolution of the resurgent horst and evolving hydrothermal system, extensive intrusive complex and deep seated siliceous magma chamber serving as heat and magmatic fluid source. Three types of epithermal veins occur in a zonal arrangement: (a) base metal veins &#177; Au with transition to Cu &#177; Bi mineralization at depth in the east/central part of the horst, (b) Ag &#8212; Au veins with minor base metal mineralization and (c) Au &#8212; Ag veins located at marginal faults of the horst. Isotopic composition of oxygen and hydrogen in hydrothermal fluids indicate mixing of magmatic and meteoric component (with generally increasing proportion of meteoric component towards younger mineralization periods?). Veins are accompanied by zones of silicification, adularization and sericitization, indicating a low sulphidation environment. 8. Replacement base metal mineralization of a limited extent in the Mesozoic carbonate rocks next to sulphide rich epithermal base metal veins.</description>
      <author>Jaroslav Lexa, J. &#352;tohl, Vlastimil Kone&#269;n&#253;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1999 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5382/gb.31.09</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
