<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 18:49:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Excellent Bifunctional Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Electrocatalysts (5A&lt;sub&gt;1/5&lt;/sub&gt;)Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and Their Tunability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.3c00088</link>
      <description>Xin Wang, Harcharan Singh, Manashi Nath, Kurt Lagemann, Katharine Page, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391017352

                Hastening the progress of rechargeable metal&#8211;air batteries and hydrogen fuel cells necessitates the advancement of economically feasible, earth-abundant, inexpensive, and efficient electrocatalysts facilitating both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Herein, a recently reported family of nano (5A1/5)Co2O4 (A = combinations of transition metals, Mg, Mn, Fe, Ni, Cu, and Zn) compositionally complex oxides (CCOs) [Wang et al., Chemistry of Materials, 2023, 35 (17), 7283&#8211;7291.] are studied as bifunctional OER and ORR electrocatalysts. Among the different low-temperature soft-templating samples, those subjected to 600 &#176;C postannealing heat treatment exhibit superior performance in alkaline media. One specific composition (Mn0.2Fe0.2Ni0.2Cu0.2Zn0.2)Co2O4 exhibited an exceptional overpotential (260 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2) for the OER, a favorable Tafel slope of 68 mV dec&#8211;1, excellent onset potential (0.9 V) for the ORR, and lower than 6% H2O2 yields over a potential range of 0.2 to 0.8 V vs the reversible hydrogen electrode. Furthermore, this catalyst displayed stability over a 22 h chronoamperometry measurement, as confirmed by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy analysis. Considering the outstanding performance, the low cost and scalability of the synthesis method, and the demonstrated tunability through chemical substitutions and processing variables, CCO ACo2O4 spinel oxides are highly promising candidates for future sustainable electrocatalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Xin Wang, Harcharan Singh, Manashi Nath, Kurt Lagemann, Katharine Page</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.3c00088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pre-implanting metal oxides to endow the N-doped carbon with boosted bifunctional catalytic activities towards oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173590</link>
      <description>Lei Yu, Yang Xiang, Chuanlan Xu, Rong Jin, Lingtao Sun, Haifeng Chen, Mei Yang, Yujun Si, Changguo Chen, Chaozhong Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 980(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391022876

                Nitrogen-doped carbon-based materials exhibit promising prospect as the catalysts to oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Incorporating transition metal oxides with the catalysts can endow them with oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity to construct bifunctional catalysts for rechargeable zinc-air batteries. In this work, a catalyst (named as 300NiFe-Mi-C) was prepared by a metal oxide-implanting strategy. The mixed metal salts of Ni and Fe were first heated to produce metal oxides, and then blended with 2-methylimidazole and carbon black, and subsequently pyrolyzed at a high temperature. In the pyrolysis, a part of metal oxides was reduced to metallic state to facilitate the doping of nitrogen atoms into carbon to form the ORR active sites while a part of metal oxides was retained to afford OER activity. Benefiting from the pre-implanting strategy of metal oxides, the resultant 300NiFe-Mi-C presents enhanced OER performance with 1.56 V of OER potential at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, outperforming the 1.68 V of the controlled sample NiFe-Mi-C (without pre-implanting) and 1.70 V of RuO2. The 0.83 V of ORR half-wave potential of 300NiFe-Mi-C is also comparable to the 0.82 V of NiFe-Mi-C and 0.86 V of Pt/C, revealing satisfactory bifunctional catalytic activities. The rechargeable zinc-air battery equipped with 300NiFe-Mi-C can stably operate at ~1.25 V with 10 mA cm&#8722;2, being higher than ~1.21 V of Pt/C+RuO2. The battery also presents outstanding durability and rechargeability, demonstrating the bifunctional activities of 300NiFe-Mi-C can be realized in practical applications.</description>
      <author>Lei Yu, Yang Xiang, Chuanlan Xu, Rong Jin, Lingtao Sun, Haifeng Chen, Mei Yang, Yujun Si, Changguo Chen, Chaozhong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173590</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-Pot Formation of an rGO-Based ZnAl&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocomposite for Electrochemical Studies toward Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04297</link>
      <description>Mohamed H. Helal, Hamdy Khamees Thabet, Salma Aman, Naseeb Ahmad, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391025659

                Electrocatalysts for water (H2O) splitting to give oxygen (O2) and hydrogen (H2) fuels are challenging to build, but mixing carbon materials with transition-metal-based compounds offers an intriguing and innovative method for the development of environment-friendly fuel. Hydrothermal synthesis is a cheap and effective catalyst based on a ZnAl2O4 nanocomposite anchored over reduced graphene oxide (rGO) and is presented here, along with characterization by microscopy and spectroscopy. As a possible oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalyst on nickel foam&#8217;s surface (NF), the electrochemical properties of this catalyst were also studied. The electrochemical studies showed that the ZnAl2O4 anchored on rGO sample exhibited high stability for the OER and an enhanced surface area, ionic conductivity, and active zones of the electrocatalyst was observed compared to that of the other investigated composites. It also exhibited an overpotential of 244 mV achieved at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and lowered solution resistance (Rs = 0.63 &#937;) and charge transfer resistance (Rct = 0.6 &#937;). This catalyst has a wide operating current range and, therefore, may function for long periods of time at both high and low current densities. High electrical conductivity, a larger surface area, and enriched active zones are responsible for enhancing the ZnAl2O4@rGO composite&#8217;s multifunctional qualities, as shown by the results. The electrocatalytic properties of ZnAl2O4@rGO composites were enhanced, and they exhibited a high cycling stability of 50 h even after the 5000th cycle due to the combined influence of these surface features. The present investigation has revealed that the ZnAl2O4@rGO nanocomposite demonstrates significant versatility, making it highly suitable for various fields related to sustainable and renewable energy. This suggests that it could be employed in developing an efficient and promising electrode for the OER, thereby paving the way for new possibilities.</description>
      <author>Mohamed H. Helal, Hamdy Khamees Thabet, Salma Aman, Naseeb Ahmad, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessible Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;Oxalate Framework for Electrochemical Urea Oxidation with Radically Enhanced Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315625</link>
      <description>Jiseon Kim, Min Cheol Kim, Sang Soo Han, Kangwoo Cho, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391031743

                Abstract Urea oxidation reaction (UOR) has been utilized to substitute the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), to escalate the energy conversion efficiency in electrochemical hydrogen generation processes with denitrification of widespread urea in wastewater. This study reports breakthroughs in Ni&#8208;based UOR electrocatalysts, particularly with NiFe oxalate (O&#8208;NFF), derived from Ni 3 Fe alloy foam with prismatic nanostructures and elevated surface area. The O&#8208;NFF achieves cutting&#8208;edge performances, representing 500 mA cm &#8722;2 of current density at 1.47 V RHE and exceptionally low Tafel slope of 12.1 mV dec &#8722;1 (in 1 m KOH with 0.33 m urea). X&#8208;ray photoelectron/absorption spectroscopy (XPS/XAS) coupled with density functional theory calculations unveil that oxalate ligands induce charge deficient Ni center, promoting stable urea&#8208;O adsorption. Furthermore, Fe dopants enhance oxalate&#8208;O charge density and H&#8208;bond strength, facilitating C&#8208;N cleavage for N 2 and NO 2 &#8722; formation. The extraordinary UOR kinetics by the tandem effects of oxalate and Fe prevent Ni over&#8208;oxidation, corroborated by operando XAS, minimizing OER interference. It agrees with an adaptive reconstruction to Fe&#8208;doped &#946;&#8208;NiOOH on top surface in extended urea electrolysis with marginal loss in UOR kinetics. This findings shed light to bimetal&#8208;organic&#8208;framework as (pre)catalysts to improve industrial electrolytic H 2 production.</description>
      <author>Jiseon Kim, Min Cheol Kim, Sang Soo Han, Kangwoo Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315625</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe3C/Fe Decorated N&#8208;doped Carbon Derived from Tetrabutylammonium tetrachloroferrate Complex as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for ORR, OER and Zn&#8208;Air Batteries in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202300933</link>
      <description>Debojit Ghosh, Rumeli Banerjee, Samanka Narayan Bhaduri, Rupak Chatterjee, Abhisek Brata Ghosh, Samarpita Das, Indrani Pramanick, Asim Bhaumik, Papu Biswas, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391035614

                The emergence of non-precious metal-based robust and economic bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts for both oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for the rational design of commercial rechargeable Zn-air batteries (RZAB) with safe energy conversion and storage systems. Herein, a facile strategy to fabricate a cost-efficient, bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst Fe3C/Fe decorated N doped carbon (FeC-700) with a unique structure has been developed by carbonization of a single source precursor, tetrabutylammonium tetrachloroferrate(III) complex. The ORR and OER activity revealed excellent performance (&#916;E = 0.77 V) of the FeC-700 electrocatalyst, comparable to commercial Pt/C and RuO2, respectively. The designed temperature-tuneable structure provided sufficiently accessible active sites for the continuous passage of electrons by shortening the mass transfer pathway, leading to extremely durable electrocatalysts with high ECSA and amazing charge transfer performance. Remarkably, the assembled Zn-air batteries with the FeC-700 catalyst as the bifunctional air electrode delivers gratifying charging-discharging ability with an impressive power density of 134 mW cm-2 with a long lifespan, demonstrating prodigious possibilities for practical application.</description>
      <author>Debojit Ghosh, Rumeli Banerjee, Samanka Narayan Bhaduri, Rupak Chatterjee, Abhisek Brata Ghosh, Samarpita Das, Indrani Pramanick, Asim Bhaumik, Papu Biswas</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202300933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulse electrodeposition synthesis of Ti/PbO2-IrO2 nano-composite electrode to restrict the OER in the zinc electrowinning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111985</link>
      <description>Fateme Hakimi, Masoumeh Ghalkhani, Fereshteh Rashchi, Abolghasem Dolati, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. 12(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391035928

                Pulsed and constant direct current electrodepositions were applied to synthesize PbO2-IrO2 nano-composites on Ti substrate. By compositing PbO2 with nano-sized IrO2 particles, a suitable anode was prepared for zinc electrowinning that decreases the electrocatalytic activity for oxygen evolution reaction overpotential (OER) while increasing the electrochemical active surface area and the electrocatalytic activity for OER. To provide PbO2-IrO2 nano-composites on Ti substrate with Sb2O3 interlayer, current density, temperature, and time of anodization are optimized using the one-at-the-time method. The optimal condition for the anode involves a DC time of 1 hour, incorporating 2 g L-1 of IrO2 nanoparticles, maintaining a current density of 50 mA/cm2 for the DC mode, and setting the pulse off-time (toff) to 770 ms. Based on the electrochemical evaluations in a simulated zinc electrowinning electrolyte, the effect of IrO2 nanoparticles on the catalytic activity of Ti/&#946;-PbO2 anode for OER was determined. Anodic polarization curves showed that the OER overpotential of PbO2-IrO2 micro-composite and PbO2-IrO2 nano-composites at a current density of 10 mA cm-2 decreased to 0.471 V, respectively, compared to 0.711 V for pure PbO2. The Nyquist plots in the OER zone confirm that the PbO2-IrO2 nano-composite anode exhibits the lowest Rct 2.79 &#937; compared to 6.0 &#937; and 9.46 &#937; for PbO2-IrO2 micro-composite and pure PbO2, which can be attributed to the presence of electro-catalytic IrO2 nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>Fateme Hakimi, Masoumeh Ghalkhani, Fereshteh Rashchi, Abolghasem Dolati</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111985</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-4f as an Electron-Modulation Reservoir Weakening Fe-O Bond to Induce Iron Vacancies in Cefevni Hydroxide for Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4699906</link>
      <description>Le Gao, Yue Yao, Yun Chen, Jiajun Huang, Y. Ma, Wenbin Chen, Huan Li, Yu Wang, Lishan Jia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391036096

                Designing novel rare earth-transition metal composites is frontier electrocatalyst research. However, rare earths modulating the electronic structure of the transition metal with the aim of inducing vacancy defects to enhance the electrochemical performance has rarely been reported. Herein, the mechanism of Ce-4f electron-modulation reservoir induced weakening of Fe-O bond to modulate the electronic structure in CeFevNi hydroxide to improve oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance has been systematically investigated. Theoretical calculations and characterization results demonstrate that the Ce-4f orbitals, working as an electron-modulation reservoir, play a crucial role in not only retaining or donating electrons, but also in modulating the electronic structure of the material. Furthermore, Ce-4f bands optimize the Fe lower Hubbard bands (LHB) and O-2p bands, resulting in the weakening of the Fe-O bond to form cationic vacancies for upshifting the d-band center of the active site Ni, which favors the reaction energy barrier of the oxygen intermediate for OER. The synthesized catalyst exhibited a low overpotential of 201 mV at 10 mA cm-2 and demonstrated a lifetime of more than 200 hours at 100 mA cm-2 under alkaline conditions. This work serves as a proof-of-concept for the application of the mechanism of rare earth-induced transition metal vacancy defects, which can provide a generalized guideline for the design and development of novel highly efficient catalysts.</description>
      <author>Le Gao, Yue Yao, Yun Chen, Jiajun Huang, Y. Ma, Wenbin Chen, Huan Li, Yu Wang, Lishan Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4699906</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser assisted oxygen vacancy engineering on Fe doped CoO nanoparticles for oxygen evolution at large current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143841</link>
      <description>Min Zhu, Zong&#8208;Qiang Sheng, Zhifen Fu, Yang Li, Juan Gao, Chao Zhang, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391037653

                Exploring cost-effective non-noble metal-based catalysts with high activity and stability is of great significance for energy conversion and storage involving oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, we employed a laser irradiation technique to synthesis Fe doped CoO nanoparticles with ultrafine size (&#8776; 5.4 nm) and abundant oxygen vacancies (Fe-Ov-CoO). The ultrafine size of Fe-Ov-CoO nanoparticles provides more active sites to be exposed. Fe doping and oxygen vacancy promote the intrinsic activity and electron transfer rates of Fe-Ov-CoO, giving rise to high activity and stability catalyst for OER. Fe-Ov-CoO delivers a large current density of 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 at an overpotential of 548 mV, which is much better than commercial RuO2. Moreover, Fe-Ov-CoO presents a remarkable long-term stability with negligible degeneration at a high current density of 500 mA cm&#8722;2 for 120 h. This work provides a new route to develop OER electrocatalyst with high activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Min Zhu, Zong&#8208;Qiang Sheng, Zhifen Fu, Yang Li, Juan Gao, Chao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Grain Boundaries Promoted Hydrogen Production for Industrial&#8208;Grade Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202313156</link>
      <description>Yu Cheng, Huanyu Chen, Lifang Zhang, Xinnan Xu, Haobo Cheng, Chenglin Yan, Tao Qian, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391042365

                The development of efficient and durable high-current-density hydrogen production electrocatalysts is crucial for the large-scale production of green hydrogen and the early realization of hydrogen economic blueprint. Herein, we have successfully driven the evolution of grain boundaries through Cu-mediated NiMo bimetallic oxides (MCu-BNiMo), which leading to the high efficiency of electrocatalyst for hydrogen evolution process (HER) in industrial-grade current density. The optimal MCu0.10 -BNiMo demonstrated ultrahigh current density (&gt; 2 A cm-2 ) at a smaller overpotential in 1 M KOH (572 mV), than that of BNiMo, which does not have lattice strain. Experimental and theoretical calculations revealed that MCu0.10 -BNiMo with optimal lattice strain generated more electrophilic Mo sites with partial oxidation owing to accelerated charge transfer from Cu to Mo, which lowers the energy barriers for H* adsorption. These synergistic effects led to the enhanced HER performance of MCu0.10 -BNiMo. More importantly, industrial application of MCu0.10 -BNiMo operated in alkaline electrolytic cell was also determined, with its current density reached 0.5 A cm-2 at 2.12 V and 0.1 A cm-2 at 1.79 V, which is nearly five-fold that of the state-of-the-art HER electrocatalyst Pt/C. Our strategy provides valuable insights for achieving industrial-scale hydrogen production through a highly efficient HER electrocatalyst. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Yu Cheng, Huanyu Chen, Lifang Zhang, Xinnan Xu, Haobo Cheng, Chenglin Yan, Tao Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202313156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morphology Engineering of Self-Assembled Porous Bimetallic Ptco Alloy Nanofoams as Efficient Multifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reduction and Alcohol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4700801</link>
      <description>Meida Chen, Liuxuan Luo, Chong Wu, Qingmei Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391042860

                The exploration of high properties of electrocatalysts is imperative for the commercialization application of fuel cells. The catalytic activity and stability of Pt-based catalysts can be effectively enhanced by rationally designing their morphology and composition. Here, we synthesized self-assembled PtCo alloy nanofoams (ANs) catalysts with controllable surface composition and porous network. The experimental results show that prepared PtxCo1-ANs catalysts display excellent electrochemical performance in oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) and ethanol oxidation reaction (EOR). Interestingly, the mass activities of Pt2Co1-ANs with optimized surface composition for ORR, MOR, and EOR are 6.41, 6.64, and 7.71-fold higher than commercial Pt/C catalysts, respectively. Meantime, it also maintains high electrocatalytic durability in ORR, MOR, and EOR. Such results ascribe to the modified surface composition, optimized electronic structure, and porous interconnected nanofoam structure. These findings are insight of designing highly active and durable multifunctional electrocatalysts with controllable shapes and composition</description>
      <author>Meida Chen, Liuxuan Luo, Chong Wu, Qingmei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4700801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bi-Doped Nico2o4 Catalyst for Electrocatalysis Glucose Oxidation Accompanied Hydrogen Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4700856</link>
      <description>Yu Xiong, Fengchao Sun, Liangbing Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391042964

                The slow dynamics of oxygen evolution reaction and the use of the proton exchange membrane have been troubling the hydrogen production from electrolytic water splitting. Reducing the electrolytic voltage and avoiding the utilization of proton exchange membranes are crucial targets for electrolytic hydrogen evolution. Bi doped NiCo2O4 catalyst is prepared and applied in electrocatalysis glucose oxidation coupled hydrogen generation. Structural characterizations confirm the successful preparation of NiCo2O4 and the existence of Bi. Bi leads to the electrons transfer from Co to Ni, increasing the content of Co3+, and lowers the oxidation potential of Co and Ni. Electrochemical experiments indicate that NiCo2O4-Bi has good electrocatalytic activity and stability toward electrochemical glucose oxidation, with a potential of 1.13 V vs. RHE at 10 mA cm-2 current density. The asymmetric electrolysis of two electrodes requires just 1.26 V to achieve a 10 mA cm-2 current density. The design of NiCo2O4-Bi is an exploration for electrocatalytic glucose oxidation coupled hydrogen production with low voltage and no proton exchange membrane.</description>
      <author>Yu Xiong, Fengchao Sun, Liangbing Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4700856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the stability of NiFe-layered double hydroxide nanosheet array for alkaline seawater oxidation by Ce doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.011</link>
      <description>Yongchao Yao, Shengjun Sun, Hui Zhang, Zixiao Li, Chaoxin Yang, Zhengwei Cai, Xun He, Kai Dong, Yonglan Luo, Yan Wang, Yuchun Ren, Qian Liu, Dongdong Zheng, Wei Zhuang, Bo Tang, Xuping Sun, Walter Hu, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391043029

                Electrocatalytic hydrogen production from seawater holds enormous promise for clean energy generation. Nevertheless, the direct electrolysis of seawater encounters significant challenges due to poor anodic stability caused by detrimental chlorine chemistry. Herein, we present our recent discovery that the incorporation of Ce into NiFe layered double hydroxide nanosheet array on Ni foam (Ce-NiFe LDH/NF) emerges as a robust electrocatalyst for seawater oxidation. During the seawater oxidation process, CeO2 is generated, effectively repelling Cl&#8722; and inhibiting the formation of ClO&#8722;, resulting in a notable enhancement in the oxidation activity and stability of alkaline seawater. The prepared Ce-NiFe LDH/NF requires only overpotential of 390 mV to achieve the current density of 1 A cm&#8722;2, while maintaining long-term stability for 500 h, outperforming the performance of NiFe LDH/NF (430 mV, 150 h) by a significant margin. This study highlights the effectiveness of a Ce-doping strategy in augmenting the activity and stability of materials based on NiFe LDH in seawater electrolysis for oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Yongchao Yao, Shengjun Sun, Hui Zhang, Zixiao Li, Chaoxin Yang, Zhengwei Cai, Xun He, Kai Dong, Yonglan Luo, Yan Wang, Yuchun Ren, Qian Liu, Dongdong Zheng, Wei Zhuang, Bo Tang, Xuping Sun, Walter Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Faradically Dominant Pseudocapacitive Manganese Cobalt Oxide Electrode Materials for Hybrid Supercapacitors and Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03444</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zahir Iqbal, Misbah Shaheen, Umair Aftab, Zubair Ahmad, Muhammad Yameen Solangi, Muhammad Ishaque Abro, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044383

                Owing to their potential usage and great electrochemical performance, transition metal oxides (TMOs) are attracting enormous interest to be scrutinized for the energy-storage and conversion domain. Our work describes the electrochemical response of spinel transition metal oxides (Co3O4 and MnCo2O4) for electrochemical water splitting (oxidation evolution reaction (OER)) and hybrid energy-storage devices. After a comprehensive study of the structure and morphology, the synthesized materials were initially evaluated for the OER performance. Mn-doped Co3O4 performed better for OER due to the inclusion of Mn ions in the spinel structure. For the OER activity, the fabricated electrode showed an overpotential of 311 mV and a Tafel slope of 71 mV/dec upon obtaining the good performance of Mn-doped Co3O4 for OER; it was further utilized for energy-storage application by fabricating its hybrid supercapacitor device with activated carbon. The hybrid supercapacitor showed a better energy (36 W h/kg) and power density (4274 W/kg) relatively. Moreover, the semiempirical approach was adapted to further elaborate the experimental results obtained. The significant response of the developed electrodes enhances their potential for future energy-storage and conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zahir Iqbal, Misbah Shaheen, Umair Aftab, Zubair Ahmad, Muhammad Yameen Solangi, Muhammad Ishaque Abro, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c03444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strongly Coupled Heterostructured CoP/MoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as an Advanced Electrocatalyst for Urea-Assisted Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c04342</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Liu, Zhenjiang Lu, Yali Cao, Jing Xie, Jindou Hu, Aize Hao, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044400

                Developing low-cost electrocatalysts with excellent activity and durability in urea-assisted water splitting is urgently needed in order to achieve sustainable hydrogen production. Herein, we in situ synthesized a robust coupled heterostructured electrocatalyst (CoP/MoO2) on a nickel foam (NF) substrate and explored its electrocatalytic performances in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and urea oxidation reaction (UOR). The overpotential of CoP/MoO2/NF is found to be only 11 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 during the HER process, which is significantly lower than that of commercial Pt/C. Meanwhile, the UOR catalytic performance of CoP/MoO2/NF indicates fast reaction kinetics, along with a considerable low driving potential (1.26 V) compared to that of the OER (1.51 V). In situ and ex situ techniques demonstrate that these excellent electrocatalytic properties are mainly ascribed to the effective synergistic coupled effect and strong electronic interactions between single-component CoP and MoO2, which can tune electronic states of Co and Mo, expose more active sites, enhance intrinsic catalytic activity, and accelerate charge transfer. Moreover, when used in electrochemical overall water splitting and urea-assisted water electrolysis, CoP/MoO2/NF can reach a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 at only 1.46 and 1.32 V. This outperforms Pt/C||RuO2 and numerous nonprecious metal electrocatalysts and maintains a stable long-term electrolytic operation for 84 h. This work provides a promising pathway for the development of efficient catalysts during urea-assisted water electrolysis for hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Liu, Zhenjiang Lu, Yali Cao, Jing Xie, Jindou Hu, Aize Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c04342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Niche partitioning in a cyanobacterium through divergence of its novel chlorophyll&lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;-based light-harvesting system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.01.17.576076</link>
      <description>Nikea Ulrich, Gaozhong Shen, Donald A. Bryant, Scott R. Miller, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391044416

                The evolution of novel traits can have important consequences for biological diversification. New ecological opportunities provided by a novel trait can trigger subsequent trait modification or niche partitioning; however, the underlying mechanisms of novel trait diversification are still poorly understood. Here, we report that the innovation of a new chlorophyll (Chl) pigment, Chl d , by the cyanobacterium Acaryochloris marina was followed by the functional divergence of its light-harvesting complex. We identified three major photosynthetic spectral types based on Chl fluorescence properties for A. marina laboratory strains, with shorter and longer wavelength types more recently derived from an ancestral intermediate phenotype. Members of the different spectral types exhibited extensive variation in the Chl-binding proteins as well as the Chl energy levels of their photosynthetic complexes. This spectral type divergence is associated with differences in the wavelength dependence of both growth rate and photosynthetic oxygen evolution. We conclude that the divergence of the light-harvesting apparatus has consequently impacted A. marina ecological diversification through specialization on different far-red photons for photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Nikea Ulrich, Gaozhong Shen, Donald A. Bryant, Scott R. Miller</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.01.17.576076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>P-doped Fe-N-C catalysts as advanced bifunctional electrocatalyst for ORR, OER and Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.135976</link>
      <description>Weifeng Huang, Hai Bai, Guozhong Su, Haili Mao, Jiefei Li, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391046242

                Developing highly active bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is of great significance in the field of energy conversion and energy storage. Currently, the Fe-N-C catalyst has emerged as an ideal material to replace platinum-based catalysts for ORR. However, its OER performance falls short of meeting the requirements. In this study, we prepared a P-doped Fe-N-C catalyst through a simple phosphating process. This catalyst retains excellent ORR performance (half-wave potential of 0.851 V), significantly improves OER performance (overpotential of 396 mV at 20 mA cm&#8722;2), and exhibits favorable performance in zinc-air batteries (peak power density of 158.1 mW cm&#8722;2). These findings present a new avenue for the further applications of Fe-N-C catalysts.</description>
      <author>Weifeng Huang, Hai Bai, Guozhong Su, Haili Mao, Jiefei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.135976</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen and Sulfur Co&#8208;Doped Carbon&#8208;Coated Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/MoO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanowires as Bifunctional Catalysts for Alkaline Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309655</link>
      <description>Xiaocheng Fan, Bei Li, Chunling Zhu, Feng Yan, Xitian Zhang, Yujin Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391050864

                Abstract Bifunctional catalysts have inherent advantages in simplifying electrolysis devices and reducing electrolysis costs. Developing efficient and stable bifunctional catalysts is of great significance for industrial hydrogen production. Herein, a bifunctional catalyst, composed of nitrogen and sulfur co&#8208;doped carbon&#8208;coated trinickel disulfide (Ni 3 S 2 )/molybdenum dioxide (MoO 2 ) nanowires (NiMoS@NSC NWs), is developed for seawater electrolysis. The designed NiMoS@NSC exhibited high activity in alkaline electrolyte with only 52 and 191 mV overpotential to attain 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively. Significantly, the electrolyzer (NiMoS@NSC||NiMoS@NSC) based on this bifunctional catalyst drove 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at only 1.71 V along with a robust stability over 100 h in alkaline seawater, which is superior to a platinum/nickel&#8208;iron layered double hydroxide couple (Pt||NiFe LDH). Theoretical calculations indicated that interfacial interactions between Ni 3 S 2 and MoO 2 rearranged the charge at interfaces and endowed Mo sites at the interfaces with Pt&#8208;like HER activity, while Ni sites on Ni 3 S 2 surfaces at non&#8208;interfaces are the active centers for OER. Meanwhile, theoretical calculations and experimental results also demonstrated that interfacial interactions improved the electrical conductivity, boosting reaction kinetics for both HER and OER. This study presented a novel insight into the design of high&#8208;performance bifunctional electrocatalysts for seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>Xiaocheng Fan, Bei Li, Chunling Zhu, Feng Yan, Xitian Zhang, Yujin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309655</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimization of Interfacial OH&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt; Accessibility by Constructing a Delayed&#8211;Release Membrane Electrode for Ampere&#8211;Level Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202313233</link>
      <description>Yu Cheng, Huanyu Chen, Xinnan Xu, Junjie Dong, Mengfan Wang, Chenglin Yan, Tao Qian, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391052873

                Abstract Achieving a high current density during electrochemical overall water splitting is a promising strategy for industrial energy conversion. The mass diffusion rate of OH &#8722; ions from the electrolyte to the interfacial active sites strongly influences the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) . Herein, the delayed&#8208;release of OH &#8722; ions modulated by a proper organic polymer membrane on the electrode surface can optimize the OH &#8722; accessibility to the active sites (as indicated by the molecular dynamics simulations) is demonstrated and that van der Waals interaction force modulates the OH &#8722; residence time in the reaction system. The remarkable performance of the membrane&#8208;modified electrode is achieved at ultra&#8208;high current densities of 1.9 A cm &#8722;2 (with an HER overpotential of 602 mV) and 2 A cm &#8722;2 (with an OER overpotential of 459 mV) in 1 M KOH solution. Consequently, a super&#8208;high current density of 1.3 A cm &#8722;2 is obtained for overall water splitting (at a voltage of only 2.2 V), which is 1.9&#8208;fold higher than that of a benchmarked Pt/C&#8208;IrO 2 (684 mA cm &#8722;2 ). Therefore, the delayed&#8208;release of OH &#8722; has optimized the mass conversion efficiency of the active sites, thus improving the electrochemical performance of overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yu Cheng, Huanyu Chen, Xinnan Xu, Junjie Dong, Mengfan Wang, Chenglin Yan, Tao Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202313233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforcing oxygen electrocatalytic activity via selective dual-phase heterointerface engineering for rechargeable Zn&#8211;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02531-6</link>
      <description>Chao Cheng, Chunyi Zhi, Zhongti Sun, Yongqiang Ming, T. Xiang, Qian Zhu, Zirui Wu, Bing Li, Yang Li, Cheng Jin, Yong Cao, Juan Yang, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391053486

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Cheng, Chunyi Zhi, Zhongti Sun, Yongqiang Ming, T. Xiang, Qian Zhu, Zirui Wu, Bing Li, Yang Li, Cheng Jin, Yong Cao, Juan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-023-02531-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Mg Thermal Evaporation-Assisted Alloying/Dealloying Route for the Fabrication of Self-Supporting Nanostructured Metals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4701091</link>
      <description>Jian&#8208;Bin Lin, Weitao Zheng, Wenxue Ke, Xin He, Pei Liang, Chi Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391053773

                Nanostructured metal-based materials exhibit significant promise as catalysts in applications involving oxygen catalysis. The surface alloying-dealloying combined strategy serves as a practical approach for creating a nanostructured layer on metal foils. In this study, we employed a magnesium (Mg) thermal evaporation-assisted method to establish a Mg-based alloy layer on corresponding metal foils (Cu, Ni, and Ag). Subsequent dealloying resulted in the formation of nanoporous Ag, Cu, and Ni on the ductile metal substrate. The dealloyed nanoporous Ni foil underwent additional treatment in an alkaline solution to produce a Ni(OH)2/Ni foil for catalyzing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The as-obtained self-supporting catalyst requires a 349 mV overpotential at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and exhibits a Tafel slope of 84.52 mV dec&#8211;1 in 1 M KOH. After a 10-hour OER test under a constant potential, the catalyst shows negligible activity decrease. The distinctive thermal evaporation-assisted alloying/dealloying process is envisioned as a promising route for fabricating nanostructured self-supporting metal foils.</description>
      <author>Jian&#8208;Bin Lin, Weitao Zheng, Wenxue Ke, Xin He, Pei Liang, Chi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4701091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Growth of Nimoo4-C Nanocomposite and Electrodeposition of Multi-Metal Selenide to Enhance Oxygen Evolution Efficiency in Alkaline Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4701118</link>
      <description>Jin Liang, Zhen Yang, Liangliang Tian, Yaxi Zhang, Zhao Yin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391053808

                The present study involves the in-situ preparation of a NiMoO4-C@NiFeMoSe composite electrocatalyst on a nickel foam (NF) substrate, achieved through the combined use of hydrothermal and electrodeposition techniques. After the hydrothermal process, the NF substrate was enveloped by a notably rugged composite structure composed of carbon sub-micron spheres uniformly dispersed and interlinked with NiMoO4 nanorods. To further enhance the electrocatalytic efficiency, a NiFeMo-based selenide was electrodeposited onto the surface of the NiMoO4-C/NF composite electrode. The NiMoO4-C@NiFeMoSe/NF composite electrode exhibited exceptional OER catalytic activity in a 1 M KOH solution, displaying an overpotential of merely 228 mV at a current density of 50 mA&#183;cm-2 and a Tafel slope of 35.9 mV&#183;dec-1, significantly lower than that of the blank NF. Moreover, for overall water splitting, the two-electrode NiMoO4-C@NiFeMoSe/NF||Pt-C/NF electrolyzer required a low potential of 1.48 V to achieve a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm-2 and displayed exceptional long-term durability.</description>
      <author>Jin Liang, Zhen Yang, Liangliang Tian, Yaxi Zhang, Zhao Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4701118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Lanthanum-Stabilized Low Crystallinity Metal Oxide Electrocatalysts with Superior Activity for Oxygen Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143858</link>
      <description>M. Garc&#237;a-Rodr&#237;guez, D. Cazorla&#8208;Amor&#243;s, Emilia Morall&#243;n, Electrochimica Acta. 479(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391057954

                Oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are key electrochemical reactions for the development of rechargeable Zn-air batteries. However, due to the high cost of commercial noble metal-based catalysts and their limited bifunctionality, it is necessary the design of new electrocatalysts. In this study, stable electrocatalysts have been synthesized through a hydrothermal method and further low-temperature thermal treatment. The materials consist of La stabilized low crystallinity Mn and Co metal (hydro-)oxides. The electrocatalytic performance of these materials has been compared with counterparts calcined at higher temperatures. The findings demonstrate that materials synthesized at lower temperatures and with low crystallinity exhibit superior electrocatalytic activity for both ORR and OER. Moreover, the research highlights the favorable influence of the lanthanum cation, which enhances changes of surface morphology and oxidation states of other cations (Mn and Co). Additionally, the positive contribution of the carbon component to electrochemical activity and electrical conductivity has been elucidated. The best electrocatalyst was studied in a rechargeable Zn-air battery with a durability of up to 120 hours. They exhibited better stability and performance than the commercial Pt/C + RuO2 catalyst currently used.</description>
      <author>M. Garc&#237;a-Rodr&#237;guez, D. Cazorla&#8208;Amor&#243;s, Emilia Morall&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing highly efficient bifunctional catalysts for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution by modifying MXene with transition metal</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.089</link>
      <description>Dai Yu, Xiuyun Zhao, Desheng Zheng, Qingrui Zhao, Jing Feng, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 660(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391063505

                Exploring highly active electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has become a growing interest in recent years. Herein, an efficient pathway for designing MXene-based ORR/OER catalysts is proposed. It involves introducing non-noble metals into Vo (vacancy site), H1 and H2 (the hollow sites on top of C and the metal atom, respectively) sites on M2CO2 surfaces, named TM-VO/H1/H2-M2CO2 (TM = Fe, Co, Ni, M = V, Nb, Ta). Among these recombination catalysts, Co-H1-V2CO2 and Ni-H1-V2CO2 exhibit the most promising ORR catalytic activities, with low overpotential values of 0.35 and 0.37 V, respectively. Similarly, Fe-H1-V2CO2, Co-VO-Nb2CO2, and Ni-H2-Nb2CO2 possess low OER overpotential values of 0.29, 0.39, and 0.44 V, respectively, suggesting they have enormous potential as effective catalysts for OER. Notably, Co-H2-Ta2CO2 possesses the lowest potential gap value of 0.53 V, demonstrating it has an extraordinary bifunctional catalytic activity. The excellent catalytic performance of these recombination catalysts can be elucidated through an electronic structure analysis, which primarily relies on the electron-donating capacity and synergistic effects between transition metals and sub-metals. These results provide theoretical guidance for designing new ORR and OER catalysts using 2D MXene materials.</description>
      <author>Dai Yu, Xiuyun Zhao, Desheng Zheng, Qingrui Zhao, Jing Feng, Yingjie Feng, Xingbo Ge, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast nanomanufacturing via high-temperature shock of La0.6Sr0.4CoO3 catalysts for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2023.11.067</link>
      <description>Xiaoya Cui, Wenyu Li, Yanchang Liu, Yumei Zhu, Yanan Chen, Cairong Gong, Gang Xue, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391063536

                Electrochemical water splitting, as an effective sustainable and eco-friendly energy conversion strategy, can produce high-purity hydrogen (H2) and oxygen (O2) via hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively, altering the nonrenewable fossil fuels. Here, La0.6Sr0.4CoO3 perovskite oxide nanoparticles with an orthorhombic phase were synthesized within 2 minutes in a one-step reaction, using a rapid and efficient high-temperature shock (HTS) method. Impressively, the as-prepared La0.6Sr0.4CoO3 with orthorhombic phase (HTS-2) exhibited better OER and HER performance than the hexagonal phase counterpart prepared using the traditional muffle furnace calcination method. The electrocatalytic performance enhancement of orthorhombic La0.6Sr0.4CoO3 can be attributed to the novel orthorhombic structure, such as confined strontium segregation, a higher percentage of highly oxidative oxygen species, and more active sites on the surface. This facile and rapid synthesis technique shows great potential for the rational design and crystal phase engineering of nanocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xiaoya Cui, Wenyu Li, Yanchang Liu, Yumei Zhu, Yanan Chen, Cairong Gong, Gang Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2023.11.067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functionality Modulation Towards Thianthrene&#8208;based Metal&#8208;Free Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202310938</link>
      <description>Arnab Sadhukhan, Arun Karmakar, Kalipada Koner, Shayan Karak, Rahul Kumar Sharma, Avishek Roy, Prince Sen, Krishna Kishor Dey, Venkataramanan Mahalingam, Biswarup Pathak, Subrata Kundu, Rahul Banerjee, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391064426

                The development of metal-free bifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER) is of significant importance but has been rarely demonstrated. Porous organic polymers (POPs) with well-defined electroactive functionalities show superior performance in HER and OER. Precise control of the active sites' local environment requires careful modulation of linkers through the judicious selection of building units. Here, we have introduced a systematic strategy for modulating functionality to design and synthesize a series of thianthrene-based bifunctional sp2 C = C bonded POPs with hollow spherical morphologies exhibiting superior electrocatalytic activity. This precise structural tuning allowed us to gain insight into the effects of heteroatom incorporation, hydrophilicity, and variations in linker length on electrocatalytic activity. The most efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst THT-PyDAN achieved a current density of 10 mAcm&#9472;2 at an overpotential (&#951;10 ) of approximately 65 mV (in 0.5 M H2 SO4 ) and around 283 mV (in 1 M KOH) for HER and OER, respectively. THT-PyDAN exhibited superior activity to all previously reported metal-free bifunctional electrocatalysts in the literature. Furthermore, our investigations demonstrated that THT-PyDAN maintains its performance even after 36 hours of chronoamperometry and 1000 CV cycling. Post-catalytic characterization using FT-IR, XPS, and microscopic imaging techniques underscores the long-term durability of THT-PyDAN. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved.</description>
      <author>Arnab Sadhukhan, Arun Karmakar, Kalipada Koner, Shayan Karak, Rahul Kumar Sharma, Avishek Roy, Prince Sen, Krishna Kishor Dey, Venkataramanan Mahalingam, Biswarup Pathak, Subrata Kundu, Rahul Banerjee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202310938</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing oxygen evolution electrocatalysis with human-machine intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100868</link>
      <description>Liping Liu, Siwen Wang, Chen Ling, Hongliang Xin, Chem Catalysis. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391043168

                In this article, Hongliang Xin (associate professor at Virginia Tech), Chen Ling (senior principal research scientist at Toyota), and their colleagues discuss the critical challenges in developing high-performance electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), particularly by emphasizing the role of artificial intelligence (AI) in materials exploration and discovery. They highlight the necessity of a collaborative human-machine intelligence approach to overcome the complexities of OER catalysis and accelerate the advancement of sustainable energy solutions.</description>
      <author>Liping Liu, Siwen Wang, Chen Ling, Hongliang Xin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.checat.2023.100868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00012-4</link>
      <description>Ajit Singh, B. N. Singh, Arindam Indra, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488890

                In recent years, a series of noble metals and transition metal-based single-atom catalysts (SACs) have been explored for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The unique structural and electronic features of the SACs facilitate the OER with maximum atomic utilization. As a result, a high turnover frequency is achieved with SACs. In this chapter, we have summarized the fundamentals of the SACs and their design strategies for electrochemical OER. The detailed characterization of the SACs and its utilization in OER has been discussed with suitable examples. The principles and reaction mechanism of electrochemical OER with SACs have been discussed looking at the structure of the active catalyst and reaction intermediates.</description>
      <author>Ajit Singh, B. N. Singh, Arindam Indra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00012-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface effect of MXene/CoP2 on oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136024</link>
      <description>Xiu Juan Du, Yan Wang, Zicong Ye, Wei Wang, Yuqiao Wang, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391345030

                Zero/two-dimension MXene/CoP2 was fabricated by hydrothermal and chemical vapor deposition phosphate. MXene nanosheets were employed as substrate to increase dispersion and stability of the multicomponent catalyst. The morphology of CoP2 was regulated by the addtion of Co precursor in hydrothermal process. The catalyst prepared by 40 mg MXene with 0.5 mmol Co precursor (MXene/CoP2-0.5) showed a uniform growth of CoP2 and formed aboundant reaction sites. The interfacial electron transfer between MXene and CoP2 modulated the electron structure of CoP2 and stimulated the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. The optimized MXene/CoP2-0.5 exhibited the OER overpotential of 263 mV and a long-term stability over 16 h. Modulating the interfacial electron transfer of multicomponent catalysts provided a guidance for electrocatalyst design and synthesis.</description>
      <author>Xiu Juan Du, Yan Wang, Zicong Ye, Wei Wang, Yuqiao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights on MOF-derived metal&#8211;carbon nanostructures for oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt04263d</link>
      <description>Junliang Chen, Jinjie Qian, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391225155

                Electrochemical water splitting has been regarded a promising method for the production of green hydrogen, addressing the need for efficient energy conversion and storage. However, it is severely hindered by the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) because of its multi-step four-electron transfer pathway with sluggish reaction kinetics. Microporous metal-organic-frameworks (MOFs), by virtue of large specific surface area, high porosity, tunable composition and morphology, find widespread use as precursors of metal-carbon nanostructures. The resulting carbon nanomaterials can well inherit the characteristics and advantages of the crystalline MOF precursors, and exhibit versatile application prospects in the fields of environment and energy, particularly in OER. Herein, a meticulous overview of the synthesis strategy for MOF-derived metal-carbon nanostructures and the origins of their enhanced OER properties has been demonstrated. We comprehensively illustrate these aspects across three dimensions: MOF selection, metal introduction, and carbon structures. Finally, the challenges and future prospects for this emerging field will be presented.</description>
      <author>Junliang Chen, Jinjie Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt04263d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing Hydrogen&#8208;Bond Network for Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202319462</link>
      <description>Shicheng Zhu, Ruoou Yang, Huangjingwei Li, Sirui Huang, Haozhi Wang, Youwen Liu, Huiqiao Li, Tianrui Zhai, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391328163

                Developing highly active oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts in acidic conditions is a pressing demand for proton&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolysis. Manipulating proton character at the electrified interface, as the crux of all proton&#8208;coupled electrochemical reactions, is highly desirable but elusive. Herein we present a promising protocol, which reconstruct a connected hydrogen&#8208;bond network beween the catalyst&#8208;electrolyte interface by coupling hydrophilic units to boost acidic OER activity. Modelling on N&#8208;doped&#8208;carbon&#8208;layer clothed Mn&#8208;doped&#8208;Co3O4 (Mn&#8208;Co3O4@CN), we unravel that the hydrogen&#8208;bond interaction between CN units and H2O molecule not only drags the free water to enrich the surface of Mn&#8208;Co3O4 but also serves as a channel to promote the dehydrogenation process. Meanwhile, the modulated local charge of the Co sites from CN units/Mn dopant lowers the OER barrier. Therefore, Mn&#8208;Co3O4@CN surpasses RuO2 at high current density (100 mA cm&#8208;2 @ ~538 mV).</description>
      <author>Shicheng Zhu, Ruoou Yang, Huangjingwei Li, Sirui Huang, Haozhi Wang, Youwen Liu, Huiqiao Li, Tianrui Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202319462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing Hydrogen&#8208;Bond Network for Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202319462</link>
      <description>Shicheng Zhu, Ruoou Yang, Huangjingwei Li, Sirui Huang, Haozhi Wang, Youwen Liu, Huiqiao Li, Tianrui Zhai, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391329795

                Developing highly active oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts in acidic conditions is a pressing demand for proton&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolysis. Manipulating proton character at the electrified interface, as the crux of all proton&#8208;coupled electrochemical reactions, is highly desirable but elusive. Herein we present a promising protocol, which reconstruct a connected hydrogen&#8208;bond network beween the catalyst&#8208;electrolyte interface by coupling hydrophilic units to boost acidic OER activity. Modelling on N&#8208;doped&#8208;carbon&#8208;layer clothed Mn&#8208;doped&#8208;Co3O4 (Mn&#8208;Co3O4@CN), we unravel that the hydrogen&#8208;bond interaction between CN units and H2O molecule not only drags the free water to enrich the surface of Mn&#8208;Co3O4 but also serves as a channel to promote the dehydrogenation process. Meanwhile, the modulated local charge of the Co sites from CN units/Mn dopant lowers the OER barrier. Therefore, Mn&#8208;Co3O4@CN surpasses RuO2 at high current density (100 mA cm&#8208;2 @ ~538 mV).</description>
      <author>Shicheng Zhu, Ruoou Yang, Huangjingwei Li, Sirui Huang, Haozhi Wang, Youwen Liu, Huiqiao Li, Tianrui Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202319462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced catalytic activity of ZnWO4 by nickel-doping in oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108151</link>
      <description>Meng Li, Deijun Xiong, Jinxing Wang, Xiaoyang Dong, Peiyang Zhang, Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing. 173(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391197664

                The development of efficient and low-cost metal materials is indispensable in clean energy technology. Metal tungstates have previously been reported as catalysts for oxygen evolution reactions (OER). However, ZnWO4 alone does not exhibit significant catalytic activity for OER, it requires 330 mV to drive the reaction at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. To address this issue, a self-supporting electrode mixed with tungstate is synthesized by a hydrothermal method. Notably, the Ni-doped ZnWO4 self-supporting material demonstrates improved OER catalytic activity. Specifically, when comparing ZnWO4 to ZnNiWO4, it exhibits a reduced Tafel slope by 190 mV&#183;dec&#8722;1, resulting in an overpotential of only 110 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, with long-term stability for at least 20 h. Furthermore, the d-band center of ZnNiWO4 is modeled using Materials Studio and simulated through projected density of states (PDOS) calculations. These calculations reveal that the presence of Ni activates the metal ion as an OER active site with strong orbital overlap with the reaction intermediate. This adjustment in the electronic structure of the Ni&#8211;Zn metal active site during the oxygen evolution reaction alters the adsorption energy. Consequently, doping of Ni enhances the metal's ability to adsorb *OOH radical, shifting the d-band center of ZnNiWO4 further away from the Fermi level, and facilitates rapid oxygen release.</description>
      <author>Meng Li, Deijun Xiong, Jinxing Wang, Xiaoyang Dong, Peiyang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mssp.2024.108151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Promotion of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Programmable Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-gs6zn</link>
      <description>Sallye Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar Abdel&#8208;Rahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391172933

                Hydrogen gas is a promising renewable energy storage medium when produced via water electrolysis, but this process is limited by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we used a microkinetic model to investigate promoting the OER using programmable oxide catalysts (i.e., forced catalyst dynamics). We found that programmable catalysts could increase current density at a fixed overpotential (100X to 600X over static rates) or reduce the overpotential required to reach a fixed current density of 10 mA/cm^2 (45 &#8211; 140% reduction vs. static). In our kinetic parameterization, the key parameters controlling the quality of the catalytic ratchet were the O*-to-OOH* and O*-to-OH* activation barriers. Our findings indicate that programmable catalysts may be a viable strategy for accelerating the OER or enabling lower-overpotential operation, but a more accurate kinetic parameterization is required for precise predictions of performance, ratchet quality, and resulting energy efficiency.</description>
      <author>Sallye Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar Abdel&#8208;Rahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-gs6zn</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of A-sites in pyrochlore lanthanide ruthenate for electrocatalysis of oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmat.2023.12.009</link>
      <description>Hengyu Guo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang, Journal of Materiomics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391450654

                Developing highly stable and efficient catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is extremely important to sustainable energy conversion and storage, but improved efficiency is largely hindered by sluggish reaction kinetics. Dense and bimetal ruthenates have emerged as one of the promising substitutes to replace single-metal ruthenium or iridium oxides, but the fundamental understanding the role of A-site cations is still blurring. Herein, a family of lanthanides (Ln = all the lanthanides except Pm) are applied to synthesize pyrochlore lanthanide ruthenates (Ln2Ru2O7), and only Ln2Ru2O7 (Ln = Sm, Eu, Gd, Tb, Dy, Ho, Er, Tm, Yb, or Lu) with pure phase can be obtained by the ambient-pressure calcination. Compared with the perovskite ruthenates (SrRuO3) and rutile RuO2, the [RuO6] units in these Ln2Ru2O7 present the largely distorted configurations and different energy level splitting to prevent the excessive Ru oxidation and dissolution, which leads the primary improvement in the electrocatalytic OER performance. In the similar crystalline field split states, the charge transfer between [RuO6] units and Ln3+ cations also affect catalytic activities, even in the Ln2Ru2O7 surface reconstruction during the OER process. Consequently, Tb2Ru2O7 showed the highest OER performance among all the prepared Ln2Ru2O7 with similar morphologies and crystallization. This systematic work gives fundamental cognition to rational design of high-performance OER electrocatalysts in proper water electrolysis technologies.</description>
      <author>Hengyu Guo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmat.2023.12.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of hexagonal Cu2O nanocrystals on CNTs for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2023.111853</link>
      <description>Salma Aman, Meznah M. Alanazi, Shaimaa A. M. Abdelmohsen, Saeed D. Alahmari, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Suleman Waheed, A.M.A. Henaish, Zubair Ahmad, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid, Journal of Physics and Chemistry of Solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391179968

                Electrocatalytic water (H2O) splitting relies heavily on the rational formation of most effective, long-lasting catalysts that should be cheaper and earth abundant. Therefore, an effective electrocatalyst is the need of the hour that may effectively pursue both electrocatalytic OER and HER. This study paves the way for the straightforward preparation of conductive polymer tailored metal oxide nanocomposite Cu2O/CNTs by a facile hydrothermal approach to be employed as overall water splitting electrocatalyst. The techniques comprising SEM, XRD, EDX and the BET test were employed to characterize the synthesized Cu2O/CNTs electrocatalyst. The generated Cu2O/CNTs electrocatalysts exhibited a Tafel value of 39 mV/dec, an overpotential of 267 mV@10 mA/cm2, and stability of OER activity that lasted for at least 70 hours. The electrocatalytic results show that the combination of Cu2O and CNTs has a synergistic impact to reduce the overpotential value. In an effort to pinpoint the rate determining processes for OER, the voltage of OER is connected to the electrolyte pH and exhibits a non-proton concerted approach. The above designed nanocomposite is quite promising for modern hydrogen production systems due to their quick electron transfer mechanism, remarkable durability, and good activity for OER.</description>
      <author>Salma Aman, Meznah M. Alanazi, Shaimaa A. M. Abdelmohsen, Saeed D. Alahmari, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Suleman Waheed, A.M.A. Henaish, Zubair Ahmad, Hafiz Muhammad Tahir Farid</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2023.111853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Design and Insights into Lanthanum and Strontium Perovskite Oxides for Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308443</link>
      <description>Sagar Ingavale, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Carolin Mercy Enoch, Chanon Pornrungroj, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Kasadit Nootong, Rojana Pornprasertsuk, Soorathep Kheawhom, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391142464

                Abstract Perovskite oxides exhibit bifunctional activity for both oxygen reduction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER), making them prime candidates for energy conversion in applications like fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries. Their intrinsic catalytic prowess, combined with low&#8208;cost, abundance, and diversity, positions them as compelling alternatives to noble metal and metal oxides catalysts. This review encapsulates the nuances of perovskite oxide structures and synthesis techniques, providing insight into pivotal active sites that underscore their bifunctional behavior. The focus centers on the breakthroughs surrounding lanthanum (La) and strontium (Sr)&#8208;based perovskite oxides, specifically their roles in zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). An introduction to the mechanisms of ORR and OER is provided. Moreover, the light is shed on strategies and determinants central to optimizing the bifunctional performance of La and Sr&#8208;based perovskite oxides.</description>
      <author>Sagar Ingavale, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Carolin Mercy Enoch, Chanon Pornrungroj, Meena Rittiruam, Supareak Praserthdam, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Kasadit Nootong, Rojana Pornprasertsuk, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient oxygen evolution using conductive cobalt-based metal-organic framework</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131044</link>
      <description>Munzir H. Suliman, Lolwah Tawfiq Alfuhaid, Mohd Yusuf Khan, Muhammad Usman, Aasif Helal, Fuel. 363(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391143814

                The electrically conductive Cobalt-benzene-1,3,5-tribenzoate metal&#8211;organic framework (Co-BTB) was easily synthesized using the hydrothermal synthesis process. The framework showed a low overpotential (only 170 mV to obtain 10 mA cm&#8722;2) for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) surpassing the benchmark electrocatalyst IrO2 which showed an overpotential of 250 mV at the same obtained current density. Moreover, the Co-BTB possesses good kinetics with an estimated Tafel slope of only 46.5 mV dec&#8722;1. It provided a high density of catalytic centers with electrically conductive characteristics, as suggested by ECSA. The framework was identified as a promising MOF electrocatalyst for the OER due to its performance as well as its chemical and electrochemical robustness.</description>
      <author>Munzir H. Suliman, Lolwah Tawfiq Alfuhaid, Mohd Yusuf Khan, Muhammad Usman, Aasif Helal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo2O4/MXene hybrid as an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution and reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301250</link>
      <description>Ashalatha Vazhayil, Vazhayal Linsha, Shyamli Ashok C, Jasmine Thomas, Nygil Thomas, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391296391

                For the advancement of energy conversion and storage technologies, bifunctional electrocatalysts are crucial for efficiently driving both the oxygen evolution (OER) and reduction reactions (ORR). Cobalt&#8208;based spinel oxides are a class of promising bifunctional electrocatalysts. However their low electrical conductivity and stability may hinder further improvement. A novel composite material composed of NiCo2O4(NCO) nanoparticles integrated with emerging two dimensional MXene nanosheets (NCO/MXene) was developed. The successful integration of NCO with MXene brings about a number of attractive structural features. This includes synergistic effects between NCO and MXene, highly accessible surface areas, complete exposure of numerous active sites, and excellent electronic conductivity, all of which collectively contribute to the desirability of composite material for OER and ORR. The synthesized NCO/MXene composite showed extraordinary OER electrocatalytic activity with a lower overpotential of 360 mV at a current density of 10 mA/cm2, and a small Tafel slope of 64.63 mV/dec compared to NCO, MXene and NCO+MXene (physically mixed). Additionally, it displays a superior ORR limiting current density (&#8208;4 mA/cm2). In particular, it exhibited highest onset potential and half wave potential of 0.92 V and 0.72 V vs. RHE, respectively, for the ORR in alkaline media</description>
      <author>Ashalatha Vazhayil, Vazhayal Linsha, Shyamli Ashok C, Jasmine Thomas, Nygil Thomas</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Metal-Ion-Doped Carbon Nitrides for Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05961</link>
      <description>Shanping Liu, Valentin Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Dong Fan, Peixiang Lu, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Guillaume Maurin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391486029

                Poly(heptazine imides) (PHIs) have emerged as prominent layered carbon nitride-based materials with potential oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic activity owing to their strong VIS light absorption, long excited-state lifetimes, high surface-to-volume ratios, and the possibility of tuning their properties via hosting different metal ions in their pores. A series of metal-ion-doped PHI-M (M = K+, Rb+, Mg2+, Zn2+, Mn2+, and Co2+) were first systematically explored using density functional theory calculations. These simulations led an in-depth understanding of the microscopic OER mechanism in these systems and identified PHI-Co2+ as the best OER catalyst of this family of PHIs, whereas PHI-Mn2+ can be an alternative promising OER catalyst. This level of performance was attributed to a thermodynamically favorable formation of the reaction intermediates as well as its red-shifted absorption in the VIS region involving the population of long-lived states, as revealed by time-dependent density functional theory calculations. We further demonstrated that the electronic properties of the *OH intermediates (Bader population, crystal orbital Hamilton population analysis, and adsorption energies) are reliable descriptors to anticipate the OER activity of this family of PHIs. This rational analysis paved the way toward the prediction of the OER performance of another PHI-M derivative, i.e., PHI-Fe2+. The computationally explored PHI-Fe2+, PHI-Mn2+, and PHI-Co2+ systems were then synthesized alongside PHI-K+, and their photocatalytic OER activities were assessed. These experimental findings confirmed the best photocatalytic OER performance for PHI-Co2+ with an oxygen production of 31.2 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1 that is 60 times higher than the pristine g-C3N4 (0.5 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1), whereas PHI-Fe2+ and PHI-Mn2+ are seen as alternative OER catalysts with attractive oxygen production of 11.20 and 4.69 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1, respectively. Decisively, this joint experimental&#8211;computational study reveals PHI-Co2+ to be among the best of the OER catalysts so far reported in the literature including some perovskites.</description>
      <author>Shanping Liu, Valentin Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Dong Fan, Peixiang Lu, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Guillaume Maurin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel-type high-entropy oxide nanotubes for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133315</link>
      <description>Yanbin Zhu, Qing Xiang, Guo Le, Shuanglong Lu, Fang Duan, Mingliang Du, Han Zhu, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391177777

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) involved 4-electron transfers is generally considered as the bottleneck for electrocatalytic water splitting. High-entropy oxides (HEO) show promising potential for OER due to their flexible structures and tunable compositions. Herein, we report a facile strategy to synthesize spinel-type (FeCoNiMnCr)3O4 HEO nanotubes (NTs) with unique hollow structures by combining electrospinning process and calcination treatment. The (FeCoNiMnCr)3O4 HEO NTs prepared at 400 &#176;C exhibit the low overpotential of 353 mV at 50 mA cm-2 and small Tafel slope of 55.6 mV dec-1 in 1 M KOH electrolyte. The three-dimensional (3D) nanofiber-based architecture ensure the superior stability, as evidenced by the stable current density under continuous OER process for more than 60 h. Meanwhile, the hollow structure provides abundant exposed active sites, which could significantly improve the OER activity. This work provides new design of low-cost and high-efficient HEO with ensemble active sites for OER.</description>
      <author>Yanbin Zhu, Qing Xiang, Guo Le, Shuanglong Lu, Fang Duan, Mingliang Du, Han Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nanotubes immobilized copper(salen) nanocomposite for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i1.2312</link>
      <description>, Indian Journal of Chemistry. 63(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391174987

                An efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts are widely required in the realm of water electrolysis and rechargeable metal-air batteries. This work describes an easy and simple method for the synthesis of copper salen (Cu(Salen))-functionalized multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) nanocomposite materials (Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs). It was used for OER in the basic medium (0.1 M KOH). The resulting nanocomposite, Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs, was studied using spectroscopic and microscopic techniques. For example, Fourier transform infrared (FT-IR), UV-visible spectroscopy, powder X-ray diffraction (p-XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), and energy dispersive X-ray analysis (EDAX). The electrochemical characterization of prepared Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs nanocomposite based modified glassy carbon (GC) electrodes (GC/Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs) and their application towards OER were performed using an electrochemical method. The Tafel slope of nanocomposite material is 159.6 mv/dec in 0.1 M KOH solution, indicating that GC/Cu(Salen)/MWCNTs could be a promising and cost-effective electrode material for the OER. This study demonstrates a novel way for creating an active nanocomposite catalyst for OER in alkaline media.</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56042/ijc.v63i1.2312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Amorphous Feooh-Modified Co9s8 Nanosheets with Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4711575</link>
      <description>Chong Wang, Huanlu Tu, Zeyu Hao, Yaxin Li, Jing Xu, Xiaoying Hu, Shansheng Yu, Hongwei Tian, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391405828

                Efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is important for water electrolysis and advanced hydrogen production energy. However, the sluggish kinetics of this reaction require significant overpotentials, leading to high energy consumption. Therefore, developing OER electrocatalysts with exceptional performance and long-term durability is crucial for enhancing the energy efficiency and cost-effectiveness of the hydrogen production process. In this paper, novel FeOOH/Co9S8 catalysts were prepared through a two-step hydrothermal reaction followed by one-step electrodeposition on nickel foam substrates for an alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The as-obtained catalysts possessed abundant non-homogeneous interfaces between FeOOH and Co9S8 nanosheets, conducive to optimized coordination environments of Fe and Co sites through the redistribution of interfacial charges. This strengthened the chemisorption of oxygenated intermediates, leading to accelerated reaction kinetics, abundant active sites, and enhanced OER properties. The optimized electrocatalyst FeOOH/Co9S8 achieved a current density of 10 mA cm-2 at an overpotential of 248 mV coupled with good stability for over 140 h. Overall, a novel approach for producing effective and durable alkaline dielectric OER electrocatalysts was proposed, useful for future manufacturing of advanced energy devices.</description>
      <author>Chong Wang, Huanlu Tu, Zeyu Hao, Yaxin Li, Jing Xu, Xiaoying Hu, Shansheng Yu, Hongwei Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4711575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning-Based Optimization Method for the Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reaction of the High-Entropy Alloy Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.17762/ijritcc.v11i9.9214</link>
      <description>Et al. Jagannath Jijaba Kadam, International Journal on Recent and Innovation Trends in Computing and Communication. 11(9)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391330920

                In recent times, high-entropy alloys (HEAs) have found application in heterogeneous catalysis, capitalizing on their vast chemical potential. Yet, this extensive chemical landscape presents significant challenges when attempting a comprehensive exploration of HEAs through traditional trial-and-error approaches. Therefore, the machine learning (ML) approach is offered to appearance into the catalytic activity (CA) of countless sensitive sites on HEA surfaces in the oxygen-lessening response (ORR) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER). In this research, a Density Functional Theory (DFT) with a supervised ML model is assembled and founded on the gradient boosting regression (GBR) algorithm that predicted the O2 adsorption energies with a high overpotential of all surface sites on the two HEAs. Initially, the HEAs Co-Fe-Ga-Ni-Zn and Al-Cu-Pd-Pt offer a framework for adjusting the composition of disordered multi-metallic alloys to regulate the activity and selectivity of the reduction of oxygen to extremely reduced compounds. This attains generalizability, high accuracy and simplicity with the proposed technique. For fine-tuning such features, HEAs provide a huge compositional space. Consequently, the research reports the custom of the Bayesian optimization model based on HEA active compositions to suppress the formation of Oxygen (O2) and with strong O2 adsorption to favour the lessening of O2. The GBR approach is applied to build a highly accurate, easily generalizable, and effective ML model. The proposed work is analysed using Python software. The findings show that the separate charities of correlated metal atoms close to the responsive site are mixed to form the adsorption energy, which is clear from a thorough analysis of the data. It is suggested that a highly effective HEA catalyst composed of Co-Fe-Ga-Ni-Zn and Al-Cu-Pd-Pt be exploited, which is an effective method for further enhancing the ORR CA of potential HEA catalysts. An instruction manual for the logical design and synthesis of HEA catalysts' nanostructures is provided by the proposed research.</description>
      <author>Et al. Jagannath Jijaba Kadam</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.17762/ijritcc.v11i9.9214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medium-Entropy Co&#8211;Fe&#8211;Cr&#8211;Mo Spinel Nanoflowers as Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05568</link>
      <description>Yuhang Sun, Tianmi Tang, Liyuan Xiao, Jingyi Han, Xue Bai, Mingyuan Shi, Siyu Chen, Jingru Sun, Yuanyuan Ma, Jingqi Guan, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391464648

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays an important role in many electrocatalysis-related fields. However, the slow kinetics of the OER seriously hinders energy efficiency. Here, we synthesize flower-like Co&#8211;Fe&#8211;Cr&#8211;Mo medium-entropy spinel (MES) nanosheets on nickel foam (NF) using one-step solvothermal method for the OER. Due to high stability and compositional diversity, the CoFeCrMoOx/NF catalyst exhibits excellent electrocatalytic OER performance with an overpotential of only 196 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH solution, much lower than CoFeCrMnOx/NF, CoFeCrCeOx/NF, CoFeCrSnOx/NF, CoFeCrAlOx/NF, and commercial IrO2 catalysts, reflecting that the formation of flower-like MES has a positive effect on the improvement of OER performance. The introduction of Mo increases active sites, promotes electron transfer, accelerates the adsorption and desorption of the OER intermediates, reduces the energy barrier, and thus improves the performance of the OER. In situ Raman spectra indicate that the surface CoOOH and FeOOH species are important active components for the OER.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Sun, Tianmi Tang, Liyuan Xiao, Jingyi Han, Xue Bai, Mingyuan Shi, Siyu Chen, Jingru Sun, Yuanyuan Ma, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten-doped cobalt-iron bimetallic phosphide nanoparticles for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105356</link>
      <description>Yaoxia Yang, Dangxia Wang, Xingwei Guo, Fengyao Guo, Zhang Lan, Dongfei Sun, Xiaozhong Zhou, Zhiwang Yang, Ziqiang Lei, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 156(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391057421

                Hydrogen obtained from electrochemical water splitting is an efficient method for hydrogen production, which is urgent to develop high efficiency electrocatalyst and commercialize the process. In our work, we used coprecipitation, doping and phosphating strategies to report the trimetallic Prussian blue analogue precursors (W-CoFe PBA) were prepared by doping sodium tungstate into cobalt-iron-Prussian blue analogues (CoFe PBA), and then by a low temperature phosphating treatment to obtain tungsten doped cobalt-iron phosphide (W-CoP/FeP) heterostructures. This strategy of doping and then phosphating can allow the charge distribution is adjusted, the conductivity is increased, the electron transport to the surface is accelerated, and the synergistic effect between CoP and FeP is enhanced. The experimental results show that the mass ratio of tungsten source to CoFe-PBA is 0.5 (0.5W-CoP/FeP), which shows outstanding activity with overpotentials of 282 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in 1 M KOH at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and Tafel slope of 29.14 mV dec&#8722;1. Simultaneously, it also exhibits excellent stability for 24 h in the chronopotentiometry test. This work provides a simple improvement for the application of Prussian blue analogues in the electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yaoxia Yang, Dangxia Wang, Xingwei Guo, Fengyao Guo, Zhang Lan, Dongfei Sun, Xiaozhong Zhou, Zhiwang Yang, Ziqiang Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105356</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mixed-valent cobalt phosphate/borophene nanohybrids for efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.188</link>
      <description>Bitan Pratihar, Omkar Roy, Arijit Jana, Sirshendu De, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391319509

                Developing efficient, low-cost, non-precious and stable electrocatalyst is necessary for sustainable electrocatalytic water splitting. Recently, borophene has emerged as a novel two-dimensional material with exciting properties. Although several researchers have theoretically predicted its applicability towards effective electrocatalytic water splitting, studies on its practical applications are still limited. In this regard, a mixed-valent cobalt phosphate/borophene nanohybrid (BCoPi) was synthesized using hydrothermal method, and its activity towards oxygen evolution reaction (OER) was systematically studied. The electron-deficient nature of borophene enables activation of catalytic sites and facilitates electron transport owing to its highly conductive nature. It can act as a proton acceptor along with phosphate groups, as well as provide multiple secondary active sites in addition to Co, breaking the scaling relation of OER. For BCoPi, achieving a current density of 50 mA cm&#8722;2, 100 mA cm&#8722;2 and 500 mA cm&#8722;2 requires an overpotential of 337 mV, 357 mV and 401 mV, respectively, in an alkaline medium, that are superior to pristine cobalt phosphate (CoPi). It also exhibits low Tafel slope of 61.81 mV dec&#8722;1, suggesting faster OER kinetics and excellent long-term stability. This study will extend the development and application of borophene-based heterostructures for highly active and stable electrocatalysts for various applications.</description>
      <author>Bitan Pratihar, Omkar Roy, Arijit Jana, Sirshendu De</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co atom-doped NiMoO4 Hierarchical hollow nanosheet-based-nanosphere for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.22541/au.170664116.61933326/v1</link>
      <description>Zhuoxun Yin, Min Zhou, Xinping Li, Xiangcun Liu, Xinzhi Ma, Yang Zhou, Wei Chen, Jinlong Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391343114

                Hollow structures with hierarchical architecture and multi-composition have attracted extensive interest because of their fascinating physicochemical properties as well as wide applications. to improve the efficiency of overall water splitting, highly active and stable electrocatalysts are highly desirable. A novel high-efficiency Hierarchical hollow nanosheet-based-nanosphere Co-NiMoO4-HNS electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution was arranged by doping Co on Ni-MoEG yolk/shelll nanosphere. Remarkably, the hierarchical hollow Co2-NiMoO4-HNS catalyst exhibits favorable catalytic performance toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with a receivable overpotential of 270 mV achieving a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 65 mV dec&#8722;1. In expansion, as a electrocatalyst, Co2-NiMo4-HNS appeared to have great long-term steadiness in the electrolyte. This work may give broad hypothetical and specialized back for the plan of cost-effective bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhuoxun Yin, Min Zhou, Xinping Li, Xiangcun Liu, Xinzhi Ma, Yang Zhou, Wei Chen, Jinlong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.22541/au.170664116.61933326/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the role of iron in Fe5Ni4S8 toward oxygen evolution through modulation of electronic orbital occupancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.028</link>
      <description>Zhengyan Du, Zeshuo Meng, H. Sun, Yifan Li, Chao Jiang, Yaxin Li, Xiaoying Hu, Yi Cui, Shansheng Yu, Hongwei Tian, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391152145

                Ni-Fe-based catalysts are considered to be among the most active catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under alkaline conditions, with Fe playing a crucial role. However, Fe leaching occurs during the reaction due to thermodynamic instability, which has resulted in conflicting reports within the literature regarding its role. To clarify this point, we propose a strategy consisting of modulating the electronic orbital occupancy to suppress the extensive loss of Fe atoms during the OER process. Theoretical calculations, in-situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, molecular dynamics simulations, and a series of characterization showed that the stable presence of Fe not only accelerates the electron transfer process but also optimizes the reaction barriers of the oxygen evolution intermediates, promoting the phase transition of Fe5Ni4S8 to highly active catalytic species. The modulated Fe5Ni4S8-based pre-catalysts exhibit improved OER activity and long-term durability. This study provides a novel perspective for understanding the role of Fe in the OER process.</description>
      <author>Zhengyan Du, Zeshuo Meng, H. Sun, Yifan Li, Chao Jiang, Yaxin Li, Xiaoying Hu, Yi Cui, Shansheng Yu, Hongwei Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.01.028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A rational strategy for CoFe layered double hydroxide oxygen evolution catalysts with high activity and stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133360</link>
      <description>Linfeng Yang, Shuang Yu, Feng Luo, Yang Liu, Xiaoqiang Wu, Xiao&#8208;Nan Liu, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391311547

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyzed by non-precious metals and their compounds in alkaline environments are regarded as a key research topic for the use of water for hydrogen production to alleviate the global energy crisis. Cobalt-iron layered double hydroxide (CoFe-LDH) has attracted much attention as a potential high-performance oxygen evolution reaction catalyst. In this paper, we report a strategy to introduce metal elements M (M = Cu, K, Al, Cr and Zn) into CoFe-LDH to further enhance the OER performance. The experimental results show that CoFeK-15 exhibits the lowest overpotential (203 mV to reach 10 mA cm-2) and Tafel slope (77.1 mV dec-1) and maintains excellent catalytic activity after 50 h i-t test. Through the introduction of potassium ions, the electronic structure inside the catalyst underwent lattice distortion, resulting in a larger active surface area and exposure of more oxygen vacancies, which in turn accelerated the OER reaction. This study reveals the important influence of potassium doping on the electronic structure modification strategy to enhance the performance of OER and provides new ideas for the development of more efficient catalysts in the future.</description>
      <author>Linfeng Yang, Shuang Yu, Feng Luo, Yang Liu, Xiaoqiang Wu, Xiao&#8208;Nan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133360</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
