<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 01:14:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing ruthenium oxide with bimetallic Co2CrO4 for highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.260</link>
      <description>Mengyue Qi, Xinyu Zheng, Huamei Tong, Haibo Liu, Di Li, Zaoxue Yan, Deli Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 677(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4401375873

                Designing efficient and stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst is the basis for the development of sustainable electrolytic water energy techniques. In this work, we presented a heterogeneous-structured electrocatalyst composed of bimetallic oxides-modified RuO</description>
      <author>Mengyue Qi, Xinyu Zheng, Huamei Tong, Haibo Liu, Di Li, Zaoxue Yan, Deli Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Oxygen&#8208;Defect Bismuth Catalyst toward Concerted Production of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with over 150% Cell Faradaic Efficiency in Continuously Flowing Paired&#8208;Electrosynthesis System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408341</link>
      <description>Qiqi Zhang, Changsheng Cao, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjie Xu, Xintao Wu, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401308478

                Abstract The electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) from O 2 or H 2 O via the two&#8208;electron (2e &#8722; ) oxygen reduction (2e &#8722; ORR) or water oxidation (2e &#8722; WOR) reaction provides a green and sustainable alternative to the traditional anthraquinone process. Herein, a paired&#8208;electrosynthesis tactic is reported for concerted H 2 O 2 production at a high rate by coupling the 2e &#8722; ORR and 2e &#8722; WOR, in which the bifunctional oxygen&#8208;vacancy&#8208;enriched Bi 2 O 3 nanorods (O v &#8208;Bi 2 O 3 &#8208;EO), obtained through electrochemically oxidative reconstruction of Bi&#8208;based metal&#8211;organic framework (Bi&#8208;MOF) nanorod precursor, are used as both efficient anodic and cathodic electrocatalysts, achieving concurrent H 2 O 2 production at both electrodes with high Faradaic efficiencies. Specifically, the coupled 2e &#8722; ORR//2e &#8722; WOR electrolysis system based on such distinctive oxygen&#8208;defect Bi catalyst displays excellent performance for the paired&#8208;electrosynthesis of H 2 O 2 , delivering a remarkable cell Faradaic efficiency of 154.8% and an ultrahigh H 2 O 2 production rate of 4.3 mmol h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 . Experiments combined with theoretical analysis reveal the crucial role of oxygen vacancies in optimizing the adsorption of intermediates associated with the selective two&#8208;electron reaction pathways, thereby improving the activity and selectivity of the 2e &#8722; reaction processes at both electrodes. This work establishes a new paradigm for developing advanced electrocatalysts and designing novel paired&#8208;electrolysis systems for scalable and sustainable H 2 O 2 electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Qiqi Zhang, Changsheng Cao, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjie Xu, Xintao Wu, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo-LDH sheets and Ag3PO4 nanoparticles decorated on graphitic carbon nitride for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175860</link>
      <description>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Younghwan Im, Misook Kang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401311945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Younghwan Im, Misook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/Crystalline Ni-Fe Based Electrodes with Rich Oxygen Vacancies Enable Highly Active Oxygen Evolution in Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916694</link>
      <description>Jingcheng Zhang, Xiulin Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401323219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingcheng Zhang, Xiulin Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress and challenges in engineering the atomic structure of oxygen electrocatalysts for zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154561</link>
      <description>Jinyeong Choi, Hyeokjun Jang, Jihan Park, Duho Han, Abhishek Lahiri, Pilgun Oh, Joohyuk Park, Minjoon Park, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326374

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinyeong Choi, Hyeokjun Jang, Jihan Park, Duho Han, Abhishek Lahiri, Pilgun Oh, Joohyuk Park, Minjoon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional &#960;&#8211;d-Conjugated Cobalt-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02588</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Zhe Chuan Feng, Yantao Wang, Junfeng Huang, Cailing Xu, Hua Li, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326994

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Zhe Chuan Feng, Yantao Wang, Junfeng Huang, Cailing Xu, Hua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon cloth supporting (CrMnFeCoCu)3O4 high entropy oxide as electrocatalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175874</link>
      <description>Xuanmeng He, Zeqin Zhang, Xianwei Jiang, Haibo Liu, Tengfei Xing, Xinzhen Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401327382

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuanmeng He, Zeqin Zhang, Xianwei Jiang, Haibo Liu, Tengfei Xing, Xinzhen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure regulation of Fe-doped Ni2P nanocrystals towards durable electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02845-z</link>
      <description>Ya Liu, Xing Cao, Jia Li, Meisheng Han, Gaowei Zhang, Yubin Zhao, Huanhui Chen, Liang Yu, Junrong Zeng, Zhenbo Chen, Ya Liu, Lijuan Song, Yejun Qiu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401329786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya Liu, Xing Cao, Jia Li, Meisheng Han, Gaowei Zhang, Yubin Zhao, Huanhui Chen, Liang Yu, Junrong Zeng, Zhenbo Chen, Ya Liu, Lijuan Song, Yejun Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02845-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the electrocatalytic efficiency of hydrothermally developed ZnMnO3 with rGO for oxygen evolution reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.372</link>
      <description>Mukhtiar Hussain, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, B.M. Alotaibi, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Imran Saleem, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401331983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukhtiar Hussain, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, B.M. Alotaibi, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Imran Saleem</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Ozone Pollutant Elimination in N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis to Produce Nitrate with Reduced Reaction Steps</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405918</link>
      <description>Yaodong Yu, Jiao Liu, Mingzi Sun, Jiani Han, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Bolong Huang, Jianping Lai, Sheng Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337627

                Abstract The synthesis of nitrate by the electrochemical N 2 oxidation reaction (NOR) is currently one of the most promising routes. However, the traditional generation of nitrate depends on the oxidation reaction between N 2 and H 2 O (or &#183;OH), which involves complex reaction steps and intermediates, showing strong competition from oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, an effective NOR method is proposed to directly oxidize N 2 by using O 3 as a reactive oxygen source to reduce the reaction step. Electrochemical tests demonstrate that the nitrate yield of Pd&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 /CNT electrocatalyst reaches the milligram level, which is the highest yield reported so far for electrocatalytic NOR. Quantitative characterization is employed to establish a comprehensive set of benchmarks to confirm the intrinsic nature of nitrogen activation and test the O 3 &#8208;mediated reaction mechanism. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that the heterostructure Pd&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 leads to a strong adsorption preference for N 2 and O 3 , which greatly reduces the activation energy barrier for N 2 . This accelerates the synthesis of nitrate based on the direct formation mechanism, which reduces energy barriers and the reaction steps, thus increasing the performance of electrocatalytic nitrate production. The techno&#8208;economic analysis underscores the promising feasibility and sustainable economic value of the presented method.</description>
      <author>Yaodong Yu, Jiao Liu, Mingzi Sun, Jiani Han, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Bolong Huang, Jianping Lai, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontispiz: Amorphous MnRuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202483361</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li, Angewandte Chemie. 136(33)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401340700

                Heterogeneous Catalysis. In their Research Article (e202405641), Gang Wu, Gao Li et al. report a MnRuOx catalyst exhibiting a unique structure, combining microcrystalline and amorphous regions. This design enables the catalyst to showcase excellent performance in water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202483361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontispiece: Amorphous MnRuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202483361</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. 63(33)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401341005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202483361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review on chemisorbed oxyanions on electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110089</link>
      <description>Han-Ming Zhang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401344088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Han-Ming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong electronic coupling between Ni-based MOF and Ni2P enables high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction for various application scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154483</link>
      <description>Yirong Wang, Xuan Yu, Zhonghong Xia, Xuanrong Li, Ya Gao, Jing Zhang, Wuliang Feng, Xingli Zou, Yufeng Zhao, Chemical Engineering Journal. 497(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401344671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yirong Wang, Xuan Yu, Zhonghong Xia, Xuanrong Li, Ya Gao, Jing Zhang, Wuliang Feng, Xingli Zou, Yufeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating lattice oxygen in local amorphous S-modified NiFe-LDH ultrathin nanosheets toward superior alkaline/natural seawater oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.031</link>
      <description>Shiwei Song, Yanhui Wang, Pengfei Tian, Jianbing Zang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiwei Song, Yanhui Wang, Pengfei Tian, Jianbing Zang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermally Synthesized rGO/MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanohybrids as Superior Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02192</link>
      <description>Simiyon Denisdon, P. Senthil Kumar, B. Chitra, R. Gayathri, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352112

                This investigation delved into the field of bifunctional electrocatalyst water splitting, aimed at advancing sustainable energy by addressing the scarcity of efficient nonprecious electrocatalysts capable of facilitating both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This study focused on nanohybrids consisting of hydrothermally synthesized rGO/MnO</description>
      <author>Simiyon Denisdon, P. Senthil Kumar, B. Chitra, R. Gayathri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Water-Lotus-like Iridium&#8211;Cobalt Carbonate Hydroxides on Plasma-Treated Carbon Fibers for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02591</link>
      <description>Yingpeng Xie, Jinfeng Qiu, Guangliang Chen, Yingchun Guo, Peisong Tang, Bin He, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352734

                The sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline water electrolysis remains a significant challenge for developing high-efficiency electrocatalytic systems. In this study, we present a three-dimensional, micrometer-sized iridium oxide (IrO</description>
      <author>Yingpeng Xie, Jinfeng Qiu, Guangliang Chen, Yingchun Guo, Peisong Tang, Bin He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional (2D) Oxysulfide nanosheets with sulfur-rich vacancy as an visible-light-driven difunctional photocatalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175898</link>
      <description>Hui Liang, Han Sun, Shuyu Jiang, Shu Cui, Fujiao Song, Lan Fan, Jia Gao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354256

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Liang, Han Sun, Shuyu Jiang, Shu Cui, Fujiao Song, Lan Fan, Jia Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni/Ni-MoS2/Ni-MoS2-Fe3O4 multilayer electrode for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175901</link>
      <description>Wei Jiang, Junjie Li, Yuanlong Chen, Fankai Zhu, Jing Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Jiang, Junjie Li, Yuanlong Chen, Fankai Zhu, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel&#8217;s Effect on Iron Oxide for Oxygen-Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04258</link>
      <description>Zahra Zand, Fatemeh Jafari, Maryam Gharedaghloo, Subhajit Nandy, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358416

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahra Zand, Fatemeh Jafari, Maryam Gharedaghloo, Subhajit Nandy, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring In Situ Kinetics of Oxygen Vacancy-Rich B/P-Incorporated Cobalt Oxide Nanowires for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00816</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Maulik Patel, Henry Charlton, Rinkoo Bhabal, R. Fernandes, Rupali Patel, N. Patel, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Maulik Patel, Henry Charlton, Rinkoo Bhabal, R. Fernandes, Rupali Patel, N. Patel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of oxygen via water oxidation using PANI@CuMn2O4 nanocomposite electrocatalyst for OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129803</link>
      <description>Hala M. Abo-Dief, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401360175

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hala M. Abo-Dief</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Catalytic Performances of Metal-doped Ta2O5 Catalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction with Computations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03554b</link>
      <description>Congcong Han, Tao Wang, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401361496

                The design of stable and active alternative catalysts to iridium oxide for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been a long pursuit in acidic water splitting. Tantalum pentoxide (Ta2O5)...</description>
      <author>Congcong Han, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03554b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j</link>
      <description>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401365414

                We firstly investigate the electrochemical dealloying effect and mechanism of a high-chromium alloy in alkaline NaNO3 solution under oxygen evolution potential. The electrochemical treatment can form dealloyed layers with Cr-enriched...</description>
      <author>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nimn2o4 Nanoflower Grown on Activated Carbon Derived from Tamarind Seed as Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reactions and Energy Storage by Three-Electrode Measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917324</link>
      <description>Anas Ramadan, Hamouda Adam Hamouda, N Al-Subaie, Yousif Shoaib Mohammed, Murtada Mohamed Edris, Nijuan Liu, Ruibin Guo, Anwar I. Alduma, Hebing Pei, Zunli Mo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373593

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anas Ramadan, Hamouda Adam Hamouda, N Al-Subaie, Yousif Shoaib Mohammed, Murtada Mohamed Edris, Nijuan Liu, Ruibin Guo, Anwar I. Alduma, Hebing Pei, Zunli Mo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376553

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core&#8208;shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores&#8217; local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells&#8217; surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k</link>
      <description>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376763

                Trade-off between activity and durability of acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is of key concern in the field of electrocatalysis. RuO2 delivers good activity but displays poor stability due...</description>
      <author>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Spin&#8208;Modulated Electrocatalysis of Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401073</link>
      <description>Tabassum Taspya, Rowshan Yeasmin Snigdha, Md. Mominul Islam, ChemistrySelect. 9(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401379797

                Abstract Electrochemical splitting of water for hydrogen generation has emerged as a potential strategy for transitioning towards renewable energy sources and mitigating the environmental impact of fossil fuel dependence. However, the efficiency of water splitting is mainly hindered by oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode side, which involves kinetically sluggish four proton&#8208;coupled electron&#8208;transfer steps. Recent studies on OER demonstrate that a spin&#8208;dependent mechanism governs the reaction kinetics, wherein the electronic exchange interactions in the catalytic activity of transition metals can provide a spin&#8208;selective channel to filter out electron spins with the right orientation during the formation of O 2 . Maximizing efficiency and stability of such catalysts require optimization the geometric and electrical structures of transition metal systems. In addition, it is vital to understand the OER mechanism with spin considerations to be familiar with the connection between spin, charge, orbital, and lattice characteristics. This review focuses on current developments in understanding and the use of the spin&#8208;related effect in the OER mechanism.</description>
      <author>Tabassum Taspya, Rowshan Yeasmin Snigdha, Md. Mominul Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381907

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381929

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381979

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381996

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382194

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382356

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382382

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382447

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382481

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382599

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Synergistic Effect of Two-Dimensional Heterostructure NiFeP@FeOOH as Stable Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080511</link>
      <description>Qinglong Hou, Zhigang Jiang, Chen Wang, Shuhan Yang, Haizhen Liu, Bo Xing, Honghui Cheng, Kuikui Wang, Catalysts. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401388575

                Introducing multiple active sites and constructing a heterostructure are efficient strategies to develop high-performance electrocatalysts. Herein, two-dimensional heterostructure NiFeP@FeOOH nanosheets supported by nickel foam (NF) are prepared by a hydrothermal&#8211;phosphorization&#8211;electrodeposition process. The synthesis of self-supporting heterostructure NiFeP@FeOOH nanosheets on NF increases the specific surface region, while bimetallic phosphide realizes rapid charge transfer, improving the electron transfer rate. The introduction of FeOOH and the construction of a heterostructure result in a synergistic effect among the components, and the surface-active sites are abundant. In situ Raman spectroscopy showed that the excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance was due to reconstruction-induced hydroxyl oxide, which achieved a multi-active site reaction. The NiFeP@FeOOH/NF electrocatalytic activity was then significantly improved. The findings indicate that in a 1.0 M KOH alkaline solution, NiFeP@FeOOH/NF showed an OER overpotential of 235 mV at 100 mA cm&#8722;2, a Tafel slope of 46.46 mV dec&#8722;1, and it worked stably at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 for 80 h. This research proves that constructing heterostructure and introducing FeOOH are of great significance to the study of the properties of OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Qinglong Hou, Zhigang Jiang, Chen Wang, Shuhan Yang, Haizhen Liu, Bo Xing, Honghui Cheng, Kuikui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Activity of Sr-Doped Lanthanum Cobaltate for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700253</link>
      <description>Basant Lal, Pankaj Chauhan, Russian Journal of Electrochemistry. 60(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401393531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Basant Lal, Pankaj Chauhan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Joule heating-induced formation of amorphous CoFeNi phosphate for efficient and stable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03130j</link>
      <description>Junhao Ma, Chonghan Xia, Teddy Salim, Yee Yan Tay, Lydia Helena Wong, Kwan Wee Tan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401395320

                A facile, rapid Joule heating protocol for forming amorphous-structured transition metal phosphate electrocatalysts with low overpotentials, fast kinetics, and long-term stability for oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Junhao Ma, Chonghan Xia, Teddy Salim, Yee Yan Tay, Lydia Helena Wong, Kwan Wee Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03130j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Hydroxide Ion Enrichment at Inner Surface of Lacunaris Perovskite Nanotubes Facilitates Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02783c</link>
      <description>Lin-Bo Liu, Shuo Liu, Yufeng Tang, Yifei Sun, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing-Li Luo, Subiao Liu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401395881

                Numerous strategies have been devised to optimize the intrinsic activity of perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, conventional synthetic routes typically yield limited active sites and low mass...</description>
      <author>Lin-Bo Liu, Shuo Liu, Yufeng Tang, Yifei Sun, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing-Li Luo, Subiao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02783c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field-enhanced photoelectrochemical water splitting of Co3O4/TiO2 for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3029-5</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Zhou, Yi L&#252;, Yixuan Liu, Shang Cao, Ge Tian, Zhi-Yi Hu, Ling Shen, Si-Ming Wu, Jie Ying, Wei Geng, Xiaoyu Yang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401396775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Zhou, Yi L&#252;, Yixuan Liu, Shang Cao, Ge Tian, Zhi-Yi Hu, Ling Shen, Si-Ming Wu, Jie Ying, Wei Geng, Xiaoyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3029-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Effect of Sm dopant on electrocatalytic activity of AgNbO3 perovskite fabricated by sonication method for Oxygen Evaluation Reaction (OER)&#8221; [Int J Hydrogen Energy, 69, 5 June (2024), Pages 974&#8211;981]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.454</link>
      <description>Mukhtiar Hussain, Meznah M. Alanazi, Saeed D. Alahmari, Muhammad Abdullah, Khurshid Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Gul N. Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401406087

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukhtiar Hussain, Meznah M. Alanazi, Saeed D. Alahmari, Muhammad Abdullah, Khurshid Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Gul N. Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Co-Ni3b/Gdy Heterostructured Electrocatalyst for Boosting Oxygen Evolution in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917532</link>
      <description>Fuxiang Jing, Shixin Zhang, Honglei Shao, S Zhang, Pengfei Shi, Zhaomei Sun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401407957

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuxiang Jing, Shixin Zhang, Honglei Shao, S Zhang, Pengfei Shi, Zhaomei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Stable Rechargeable Aqueous Zn&#8211;Oxygen Battery with Mn-based Bifunctional Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01506</link>
      <description>Jorge Gonz&#225;lez-Morales, M. Aparicio, Nataly Carolina Rosero&#8208;Navarro, Jadra Mosa, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401412269

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jorge Gonz&#225;lez-Morales, M. Aparicio, Nataly Carolina Rosero&#8208;Navarro, Jadra Mosa</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing Dynamic Surface and Subsurface Reconstruction of High-Entropy Alloy Electrocatalysts during the Oxygen Evolution Reaction at the Atomic Scale</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02792</link>
      <description>Chenglong Luan, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Ulrich Hagemann, Aleksander Kostka, Guillaume Laplanche, Dongshuang Wu, Serhiy Cherevko, Tong Li, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401414586

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenglong Luan, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Ulrich Hagemann, Aleksander Kostka, Guillaume Laplanche, Dongshuang Wu, Serhiy Cherevko, Tong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02792</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling of Spent LiFePO4 Cathodes to Heterostructured Electrocatalysts for Stable Direct Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410396</link>
      <description>Zhen Li, Mengting Li, Yiqun Chen, Xucun Ye, Mengjie Liu, Lawrence Yoon Suk Lee, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401421568

                The pursuit of carbon&#8208;neutral energy has intensified the interest in green hydrogen production from direct seawater electrolysis, given the scarcity of freshwater resources. While Ni&#8208;based catalysts are known for their robust activity in alkaline water oxidation, their catalytic sites are prone to rapid degradation in the chlorine&#8208;rich environments of seawater, leading to limited operation time. Herein, we report a Ni(OH)2 catalyst interfaced with laser&#8208;ablated LiFePO4 (Ni(OH)2/L&#8208;LFP), derived from spent Li&#8208;ion batteries (LIBs), as an effective and stable electrocatalyst for direct seawater oxidation. Our comprehensive analyses reveal that the PO43&#8211; species, formed around L&#8208;LFP, effectively repels Cl&#8722; ions during seawater oxidation, mitigating corrosion. Simultaneously, the interface between in situ generated NiOOH and Fe3(PO4)2 enhances OH&#8211; adsorption and electron transfer during the oxygen evolution reaction. This synergistic effect leads to a low overpotential of 237 mV to attain a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and remarkable durability, with only a 3.3 % activity loss after 600 h at 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline seawater. Our findings present a viable strategy for repurposing spent LIBs into high&#8208;performance catalysts for sustainable seawater electrolysis, contributing to the advancement of green hydrogen production technologies.</description>
      <author>Zhen Li, Mengting Li, Yiqun Chen, Xucun Ye, Mengjie Liu, Lawrence Yoon Suk Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Generation from Seawater Deploying a Bifunctional Hetero&#8208;Interfaced CoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;CoFe&#8208;Layered Double Hydroxide in an Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406431</link>
      <description>Gul Afshan, Suhana Karim, Kothandaraman Ramanujam, Tengku Norazman Tengku Abd Aziz, Sukanta Saha, Soumyabrata Roy, Arnab Dutta, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401422799

                Abstract This work illustrates the practicality and economic benefits of employing a hetero&#8208;interfaced electrocatalyst (CoS 2 @CoFe&#8208;LDH), containing cobalt sulphide and iron&#8208;cobalt double&#8208;layer hydroxide for large&#8208;scale hydrogen generation. Here, the rational synthesis and detailed characterization of the CoS 2 @CoFe&#8208;LDH material to unravel its unique heterostructure are essayed. The CoS 2 @CoFe&#8208;LDH operates as a bifunctional electrocatalyst to trigger both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline seawater (pH 14.0) while showcasing low overpotential requirement for HER (311 mV) and OER (450 mV) at 100 mA cm &#8722; 2 current density. The identical CoS 2 @CoFe&#8208;LDH on either electrode in an H&#8208;cell setup results in simultaneous H 2 and O 2 production from seawater with a &#8776;98% Faradaic efficiency with an applied potential of 1.96V@100 mA cm &#8722; 2 . Next, this CoS 2 @CoFe&#8208;LDH catalyst is deployed on both sides of a membrane electrode assembly in a one&#8208;stack electrolyzer, which retains the intrinsic bifunctional reactivity of the catalyst to generate H 2 and O 2 in tandem from alkaline seawater with an impeccable energy efficiency (50 kWh kg &#8722;1 &#8208;of&#8208;H 2 ). This electrolyzer assembly can be directly linked with a Si&#8208;solar cell to produce truly green hydrogen with a solar&#8208;to&#8208;hydrogen generation efficiency of 15.88%, highlighting the potential of this converting seawater to hydrogen under solar irradiation.</description>
      <author>Gul Afshan, Suhana Karim, Kothandaraman Ramanujam, Tengku Norazman Tengku Abd Aziz, Sukanta Saha, Soumyabrata Roy, Arnab Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Substitution on SnS-rGO Composites for Efficient Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02676</link>
      <description>Chandan Kumar, Pinky Saharan, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Ashish Gupta, Jogender Singh, Mandeep Singh, Sanjay R. Dhakate, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401422807

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chandan Kumar, Pinky Saharan, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Ashish Gupta, Jogender Singh, Mandeep Singh, Sanjay R. Dhakate</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c02676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Fe(III) Ions Improving Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity and Dynamic Stability of Anodized Nickel Foam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02646</link>
      <description>Zanling Huang, Peipei Li, Minyan Feng, Weiwei Zhu, Abebe Reda Woldu, Qing&#8208;Xiao Tong, Liangsheng Hu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401425299

                Fe has been reported to play a crucial role in improving the catalytic activity and stability of Ni/Co-based electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), while the Fe effect remains intangible. Here, we design several experiments to identify the activity and stability improvement using porous anodized nickel foam (ANF) as the electrode and 1.0 M KOH containing 1000 &#956;M Fe(III) ions as the electrolyte. Systematic investigations reveal that Ni sites serve as hosts to capture Fe ions to create active FeNi-based intermediates on the surface of ANF to improve the OER activity significantly, and Fe ions regulate catalytic equilibrium and maintain the stability for a long time. The system exhibits 242 and 343 mV overpotentials to reach 10 and 1000 mA cm</description>
      <author>Zanling Huang, Peipei Li, Minyan Feng, Weiwei Zhu, Abebe Reda Woldu, Qing&#8208;Xiao Tong, Liangsheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Efficient Oxygen Evolution on High&#8208;Entropy Sulfide Utilizing Low Electronegativity of Al</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404689</link>
      <description>Yi Wan, Wei Wang, Shengqi Ding, Liang Wu, Xianxia Yuan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401427428

                Abstract Efficient and stable catalysts are in high demand for accelerating the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, a high&#8208;entropy sulfide (HES) of (FeCoNiCrCuAl)S@HCS with a 3D structure is successfully prepared by utilizing a simple one&#8208;step solvothermal method and employed as catalyst toward OER. The lower electronegativity of Al compared to the other metal elements and its anti&#8208;corrosion character enable an outstanding OER performance of (FeCoNiCrCuAl)S@HCS with an overpotential of 253 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and an excellent durability after 20 000 CV cycles, outperforming the commercial RuO 2 and most reported metal&#8208;sulfide catalysts. Experiments coupled with theoretical calculations reveal that Al atom primarily serves as electron donor and promotes a redistribution of local electrons from Co and Cr toward adjacent Fe, Ni, and Cu sites. As a result, the Cr&#8208;Al site possesses a lowest energy barrier during the rate&#8208;determining step and works as the dominant active site for OER process. This study provides a novel insight and strategy into structural design and performance enhancement for HES materials.</description>
      <author>Yi Wan, Wei Wang, Shengqi Ding, Liang Wu, Xianxia Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404689</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valence band&#8208;tunable NiFe electrocatalyst triggered by the dynamic Mo exudation and re&#8208;deposition for superior high current density oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401091</link>
      <description>Zhichao Wang, Tiandong Qiu, Rui Jian, Yufeng Zhang, Junjie Feng, Li Gong, Siyi Yin, Luming Li, Yachao Zhu, Si Chen, Jie Deng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401428813

                Developing energy&#8208; and time&#8208;efficient strategies to derive high&#8208;performance non&#8208;precious electrocatalysts for anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), especially stably working at industrial&#8208;demanding current density, is still a big challenge. In this work, a concise molten salt erosion scenario was devised to rapidly modulate the smooth surface of the commercial NiMo foam substrate into the rough, electronically coupled, and hierarchically porous Ni/Fe/Mo(oxy)hydroxide catalyst layer assembled by the nanosphere array. This self&#8208;supported catalyst is super&#8208;hydrophilic for the alkaline electrolyte and distinguished by a balanced Mo leaching/surface&#8208;readsorption process to tune the metal d band center and electronic perturbation. The altered electronic environment with the favored OER intermediate adsorption behavior attains the outstanding OER activity in terms of a very small overpotential of 230.21 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and an ultra&#8208;long stability for 1179.45 h to sustain the initial commercial&#8208;level current density of ca. 1000 mA cm&#8208;2. This superb performance transcends most of the edge&#8208;cutting transition metal peers reported recently and can satisfy the standards of industrial applications. This industrial&#8208;compatible synthesis technology holds profound implications for hydrogen production via water splitting and other electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Zhichao Wang, Tiandong Qiu, Rui Jian, Yufeng Zhang, Junjie Feng, Li Gong, Siyi Yin, Luming Li, Yachao Zhu, Si Chen, Jie Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Iridium on Polyimide Support for Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c05377</link>
      <description>Longsheng Zhang, Jing Bai, S. Zhang, Yunxia Liu, Jinyu Ye, Wei Fan, Elke Debroye, Tianxi Liu, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401428846

                Designing a high-performing iridium (Ir) single-atom catalyst is desired for acidic water electrolysis, which shows enormous potential given its high catalytic activity toward acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with minimum usage of precious Ir metal. However, it still remains a substantial challenge to stabilize the Ir single atoms during the OER operation without sacrificing the activity. Here, we report a high-performing OER catalyst by immobilizing Ir single atoms on a polyimide support, which exhibits a high mass activity on a carbon paper electrode while simultaneously achieving outstanding stability with negligible decay for 360 h. The resulting electrode (denoted as Ir</description>
      <author>Longsheng Zhang, Jing Bai, S. Zhang, Yunxia Liu, Jinyu Ye, Wei Fan, Elke Debroye, Tianxi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c05377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Synthesis of Ruthenium&#8211;Copper Nanocomposites as High&#8208;Performance Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404729</link>
      <description>Dingjie Pan, Qiming Liu, Bingzhe Yu, Davida Briana DuBois, John Tressel, Sisheng Yu, Noah Kaleekal, Sophia Trabanino, Yongseok Jeon, F. Bridges, Shaowei Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401430002

                Abstract Development of high&#8208;performance, low&#8208;cost catalysts for electrochemical water splitting is key to sustainable hydrogen production. Herein, ultrafast synthesis of carbon&#8208;supported ruthenium&#8211;copper (RuCu/C) nanocomposites is reported by magnetic induction heating, where the rapid Joule's heating of RuCl 3 and CuCl 2 at 200 A for 10 s produces Ru&#8211;Cl residues&#8208;decorated Ru nanocrystals dispersed on a CuCl x scaffold, featuring effective Ru to Cu charge transfer. Among the series, the RuCu/C&#8208;3 sample exhibits the best activity in 1 m KOH toward both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), with an overpotential of only &#8722;23 and +270 mV to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. When RuCu/C&#8208;3 is used as bifunctional catalysts for electrochemical water splitting, a low cell voltage of 1.53 V is needed to produce 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , markedly better than that with a mixture of commercial Pt/C+RuO 2 (1.59 V). In situ X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy measurements show that the bifunctional activity is due to reduction of the Ru&#8211;Cl residues at low electrode potentials that enriches metallic Ru and oxidation at high electrode potentials that facilitates the formation of amorphous RuO x . These findings highlight the unique potential of MIH in the ultrafast synthesis of high&#8208;performance catalysts for electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Dingjie Pan, Qiming Liu, Bingzhe Yu, Davida Briana DuBois, John Tressel, Sisheng Yu, Noah Kaleekal, Sophia Trabanino, Yongseok Jeon, F. Bridges, Shaowei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanocatalyst with Multilayered Structure for Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407717</link>
      <description>Yuannan Wang, Hao Chen, Yukui Zhang, Xiao Zhao, Xiyang Wang, Subhajit Jana, Yimin A. Wu, Yongcun Zou, Lu Li, Hui Chen, Xiaoxin Zou, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401434887

                Abstract The design of a low&#8208;iridium&#8208;loading anode catalyst layer with high activity and durability is a key challenge for a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE). Here, the synthesis of a novel supported IrO 2 nanocatalyst with a tri&#8208;layered structure, dubbed IrO 2 @TaO x @TaB that is composed of ultrasmall IrO 2 nanoparticles anchored on amorphous TaO x overlayer of TaB nanorods is reported. The composite electrocatalyst shows great activity and stability toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acid, thanks to its dual&#8208;interface structural feature. The electronic interaction in IrO 2 /TaO x interface can regulate the coverage of surface hydroxyl groups, the Ir 3+ / Ir 4+ ratio, and the redox peak potential of IrO 2 for enhancing OER activity, while the dense TaO x overlayer can prevent further oxidation of TaB substrate and stabilize the IrO 2 catalytic layers for improving structural stability during OER. The IrO 2 @TaO x @TaB can be used to fabricate an anode catalyst layer of PEMWE with an iridium&#8208;loading as low as 0.26 mg cm &#8722;2 . The low&#8208;iridium&#8208;loading PEMWE delivers high current densities at low cell voltages (e.g., 3.9 A cm &#8722;2 @2.0 V), and gives excellent activity retention for more than 1500 h at 2.0 A cm &#8722;2 current density.</description>
      <author>Yuannan Wang, Hao Chen, Yukui Zhang, Xiao Zhao, Xiyang Wang, Subhajit Jana, Yimin A. Wu, Yongcun Zou, Lu Li, Hui Chen, Xiaoxin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202407717</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous RuCo nanoclusters by rapid Joule-heating for enhanced alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.137172</link>
      <description>Yixiao Zhang, Xinyu Xie, Zhichuan Zheng, He Xian, Peng Du, Yukui Zhang, Hongyi Liu, Ru Zhang, Kai Huang, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401437971

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yixiao Zhang, Xinyu Xie, Zhichuan Zheng, He Xian, Peng Du, Yukui Zhang, Hongyi Liu, Ru Zhang, Kai Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.137172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic engineering of heterostructure and oxygen vacancy in cobalt hydroxide/aluminum oxyhydroxide as bifunctional electrocatalysts for urea-assisted hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.239</link>
      <description>Minglei Yan, Junjie Zhang, Sheng Wang, Lang Gao, Xinyang Wang, Jiahao Zhang, Chunquan Liu, Zhiwei Lu, Lijun Yang, Cheng&#8208;Lu Jiang, Jing Wang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401438216

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minglei Yan, Junjie Zhang, Sheng Wang, Lang Gao, Xinyang Wang, Jiahao Zhang, Chunquan Liu, Zhiwei Lu, Lijun Yang, Cheng&#8208;Lu Jiang, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First-Principles Study of the Doping Mechanism of the Electrochemical Oxygen Pump Electrolyte in Liquid Lead-Bismuth Eutectic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4919560</link>
      <description>Jing Du, Zulong Hao, Fenglei Niu, Huiping Zhu, Lu Sun, Fang Liu, Runqi Tu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401438650

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Du, Zulong Hao, Fenglei Niu, Huiping Zhu, Lu Sun, Fang Liu, Runqi Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4919560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-doped Strontium Metal-Organic Framework: Dual-Function Active Material for Supercapacitor and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144857</link>
      <description>Abdullah Al Mahmud, Azad H. Alshatteri, Huda S. Alhasan, Wail Al Zoubi, Khalid M. Omer, Mohammad R. Thalji, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401438850

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdullah Al Mahmud, Azad H. Alshatteri, Huda S. Alhasan, Wail Al Zoubi, Khalid M. Omer, Mohammad R. Thalji</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144857</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and characterization of Co3O4/Ti3C2 MXene nanocomposite: Efficient catalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/epjap/2024240077</link>
      <description>P. Kamakshi, C. Joshitha, Chella Santhosh, K. Ganesh Kumar, The European Physical Journal Applied Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401441729

                In this investigation, cube-shaped Co3O4 nanoparticles and Co3O4/Ti3C2 MXene nanocomposite were successfully prepared through the solvothermal method. XRD analysis substantiated the cubic structure formation in Co3O4. Morphological and compositional analyses were conducted using FESEM and EDS analysis. The chemical states and surface properties of the materials were explored through XPS analysis. The characterized pristine and composite electro-catalysts were evaluated for oxygen evolution reaction. Co3O4/Ti3C2 MXene nanocomposite catalyst showed reduced over potential of 454 mV. The parameters of Co3O4/Ti3C2 MXene nanocomposite significantly enhanced the kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction than the bare Co3O4 nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>P. Kamakshi, C. Joshitha, Chella Santhosh, K. Ganesh Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/epjap/2024240077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A one-pot hydrothermal synthesis of morphologically controllable yolk-shell structured CoFe glycerate spheres for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.046</link>
      <description>Lingyu Kong, Lin Hao, Mingjie Hu, Ming Su, Qinggang Meng, Yufan Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401447309

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lingyu Kong, Lin Hao, Mingjie Hu, Ming Su, Qinggang Meng, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Nanoporous Semi-transparent La0.8Sr0.2CoO3 Coatings: Stability and Mechanism in Neutral Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-024-02002-x</link>
      <description>Divya Vyas, Shikha Dhakar, Aditi Singhal, Sudhanshu Sharma, Topics in Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401449645

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Divya Vyas, Shikha Dhakar, Aditi Singhal, Sudhanshu Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11244-024-02002-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multicomponent Interface and Electronic Structure Engineering in Ir-Doped CoMO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Co(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; (M = W and Mo) Enable Promoted Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02603</link>
      <description>Hui Xu, Yang Liu, Kun Wang, Lei Jin, Jie Chen, Guangyu He, Haiqun Chen, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401451139

                The core principles of multicomponent interface and electronic structure engineering are essential in designing high-performance catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, combining these aspects within a catalyst is a significant challenge. In this investigation, a novel approach involving the development of hybrid Ir-doped CoMO</description>
      <author>Hui Xu, Yang Liu, Kun Wang, Lei Jin, Jie Chen, Guangyu He, Haiqun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A dynamically stable self-assembled CoFe (oxy)hydroxide-based nanocatalyst with boosted electrocatalytic performance for oxygen-evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01848f</link>
      <description>Ming Zhu, Hengyue Xu, Jie Dai, Daqin Guan, Zhiwei Hu, Sixuan She, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Ran Ran, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401456893

                Surface reconstruction or elemental leaching is generally involved in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process on transition metal-based oxides during alkaline water electrolysis, which gives rise to both opportunities and...</description>
      <author>Ming Zhu, Hengyue Xu, Jie Dai, Daqin Guan, Zhiwei Hu, Sixuan She, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Ran Ran, Wei Zhou, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01848f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Electrocatalyst Design Strategies for Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202401975</link>
      <description>Dongdong Zhang, Qilong Wu, Liyun Wu, Lina Cheng, Keke Huang, Jun Chen, Xiangdong Yao, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401459180

                Abstract Hydrogen, a clean resource with high energy density, is one of the most promising alternatives to fossil. Proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers are beneficial for hydrogen production because of their high current density, facile operation, and high gas purity. However, the large&#8208;scale application of electrochemical water splitting to acidic electrolytes is severely limited by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic reaction and the inadequate development of corrosion&#8208; and highly oxidation&#8208;resistant anode catalysts. Therefore, anode catalysts with excellent performance and long&#8208;term durability must be developed for anodic oxygen evolution reactions (OER) in acidic media. This review comprehensively outlines three commonly employed strategies, namely, defect, phase, and structure engineering, to address the challenges within the acidic OER, while also identifying their existing limitations. Accordingly, the correlation between material design strategies and catalytic performance is discussed in terms of their contribution to high activity and long&#8208;term stability. In addition, various nanostructures that can effectively enhance the catalyst performance at the mesoscale are summarized from the perspective of engineering technology, thus providing suitable strategies for catalyst design that satisfy industrial requirements. Finally, the challenges and future outlook in the area of acidic OER are presented.</description>
      <author>Dongdong Zhang, Qilong Wu, Liyun Wu, Lina Cheng, Keke Huang, Jun Chen, Xiangdong Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202401975</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Cubic Spinel Co2mno4 Anchored Cobalt-Manganese Hybrids for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Catalysis in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4920631</link>
      <description>Mengwei Guo, Qibo Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401459433

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengwei Guo, Qibo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4920631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in the development of single atom catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.026</link>
      <description>Sai Li, Zeyi Xin, Yue Luo, Jianxin Pan, Guangning Liao, Qi Li, Youyi Sun, Zhiming Feng, Rui Tan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401461268

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sai Li, Zeyi Xin, Yue Luo, Jianxin Pan, Guangning Liao, Qi Li, Youyi Sun, Zhiming Feng, Rui Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual&#8208;Site Bridging Mechanism for Bimetallic Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411683</link>
      <description>Wen Zhang, Hongshuai Cao, Xue Wen, Linlin Ma, Zhonghai Zhang, Zhiai Xu, Yuezhong Xian, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401461725

                Heterogeneous dual&#8208;site electrocatalysts are emerging cutting&#8208;edge materials for efficient electrochemical water splitting. However, the corresponding oxygen evolution reaction (OER) mechanism on these materials is still unclear. Herein, based on a series of in&#8208;situ spectroscopy experiments and density function theory (DFT) calculations, a new heterogeneous dual&#8208;site O&#8208;O bridging mechanism (DSBM) is proposed. This mechanism is to elucidate the sequential appearance of dual active sites through in&#8208;situ construction (hybrid ions undergo reconstruction initially), determine the crucial role of hybrid dual sites in this mechanism (with Ni sites preferentially adsorbing hydroxyls for catalysis followed by proton removal at Fe sites), assess the impact of O&#8208;O bond formation on the activation state of water (inducing orderliness of activated water), and investigate the universality (with Co doping in Ni(P4O11)). Under the guidance of this mechanism, with Fe&#8208;Ni(P4O11) as pre&#8208;catalyst, the in&#8208;situ formed Fe&#8208;Ni(OH)2 electrocatalyst has reached a record&#8208;low overpotential of 156.4 mV at current density of 18.0 mA cm&#8208;2. Successfully constructed Fe&#8208;Ni(P4O11)/Ti uplifting the overall efficacy of the phosphate from moderate to superior, positioning it as an innovative and highly proficient electrocatalyst for OER.</description>
      <author>Wen Zhang, Hongshuai Cao, Xue Wen, Linlin Ma, Zhonghai Zhang, Zhiai Xu, Yuezhong Xian</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202411683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual&#8208;Site Bridging Mechanism for Bimetallic Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411683</link>
      <description>Wen Zhang, Hongshuai Cao, Xue Wen, Linlin Ma, Zhonghai Zhang, Zhiai Xu, Yuezhong Xian, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401463211

                Heterogeneous dual&#8208;site electrocatalysts are emerging cutting&#8208;edge materials for efficient electrochemical water splitting. However, the corresponding oxygen evolution reaction (OER) mechanism on these materials is still unclear. Herein, based on a series of in&#8208;situ spectroscopy experiments and density function theory (DFT) calculations, a new heterogeneous dual&#8208;site O&#8208;O bridging mechanism (DSBM) is proposed. This mechanism is to elucidate the sequential appearance of dual active sites through in&#8208;situ construction (hybrid ions undergo reconstruction initially), determine the crucial role of hybrid dual sites in this mechanism (with Ni sites preferentially adsorbing hydroxyls for catalysis followed by proton removal at Fe sites), assess the impact of O&#8208;O bond formation on the activation state of water (inducing orderliness of activated water), and investigate the universality (with Co doping in Ni(P4O11)). Under the guidance of this mechanism, with Fe&#8208;Ni(P4O11) as pre&#8208;catalyst, the in&#8208;situ formed Fe&#8208;Ni(OH)2 electrocatalyst has reached a record&#8208;low overpotential of 156.4 mV at current density of 18.0 mA cm&#8208;2. Successfully constructed Fe&#8208;Ni(P4O11)/Ti uplifting the overall efficacy of the phosphate from moderate to superior, positioning it as an innovative and highly proficient electrocatalyst for OER.</description>
      <author>Wen Zhang, Hongshuai Cao, Xue Wen, Linlin Ma, Zhonghai Zhang, Zhiai Xu, Yuezhong Xian</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202411683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nb Doping Induced the Formation of Protective Layer to Improve the Stability of Fe&#8208;Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402852</link>
      <description>Minghui Xing, Shitao Wang, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401464318

                Abstract The seawater electrolysis to produce hydrogen is a significant topic on alleviating the energy crisis. Here, the Fe, Nb&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 catalyst is prepared by metal&#8208;doping strategy, and it shows high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity in alkaline medium, and only needs 1.491 V to deliver a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in simulated seawater. Using Fe, Nb&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 as a bifunctional catalyst, the two&#8208;electrode electrolyzer only requires a voltage of 1.751 V (without impedance compensation) to drive the current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 , and can run over 150 h stably in the simulated seawater. Importantly, In situ Raman test demonstrates that the outstanding performance of Fe, Nb&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 in simulated seawater is ascribed to the in situ formed sulfate protective layer induced by Nb doping, which can effectively inhibit the corrosion of chloride ion, while the protective layer is absent for Fe&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 . The stable operation of simulated seawater electrolysis under industrial current density further confirms the stability improvement mechanism of forming protective layer. In short, this study provides a new strategy of using Nb dopants inducing the formation of protective layer to enhance the stability of seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Minghui Xing, Shitao Wang, Jimmy Yun, Dapeng Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic performances of high-entropy spinel oxide (Cr1/5Mn1/5Ni1/5Fe1/5Co1/5)3O4 for oxygen reduction/evolution reactions in alkaline electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175923</link>
      <description>Yunzhu Du, F. Yang, Jing&#8208;Feng Li, Min Jiang, Wei Wang, Qiaodan Hu, Junliang Zhang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401474663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunzhu Du, F. Yang, Jing&#8208;Feng Li, Min Jiang, Wei Wang, Qiaodan Hu, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175923</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single Atomic Fe-dispersed hollow carbon spheres coated with Co3O4 synergistically catalyze oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144871</link>
      <description>Zhuang Shi, Wei Yan, Feng Hao, Hao Song, Zhen Fu, Hongyan Zhuo, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401474676

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhuang Shi, Wei Yan, Feng Hao, Hao Song, Zhen Fu, Hongyan Zhuo, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144871</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlating atomic-scale structural and compositional details of perovskite nanoparticles with activity and stability towards the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115697</link>
      <description>Fan Bai, Jonas Schulwitz, Tatiana Priamushko, Ulrich Hagemann, Aleksander Kostka, Markus Heidelmann, Serhiy Cherevko, Martin Muhler, Tong Li, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401475402

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan Bai, Jonas Schulwitz, Tatiana Priamushko, Ulrich Hagemann, Aleksander Kostka, Markus Heidelmann, Serhiy Cherevko, Martin Muhler, Tong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115697</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-Mn pair-site triggers key oxygen intermediate for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154724</link>
      <description>Yuanzhe Wang, Kuo Wei, Yanli Song, Adekunle Adedapo Obisanya, Heen Li, Jing Wang, Hongguan Li, Faming Gao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401477377

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanzhe Wang, Kuo Wei, Yanli Song, Adekunle Adedapo Obisanya, Heen Li, Jing Wang, Hongguan Li, Faming Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Facile Strategy to Prepare Single-Atom Catalysts Anchored on Tio2 with Multiple Oxygen Vacancies for Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4922167</link>
      <description>Jianji Wang, Cailing Wu, Mingming Sun, Xinyang Gao, Qifei Huang, Zhaojun Min, yanxing zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401478663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianji Wang, Cailing Wu, Mingming Sun, Xinyang Gao, Qifei Huang, Zhaojun Min, yanxing zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4922167</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the oxygen electrocatalytic performance of metal-doped graphitic carbon nitride for the development of zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12039-024-02295-1</link>
      <description>Arpan Samanta, Mopidevi Manikanta Kumar, Santanu Ghora, Arnab Ghatak, Somnath Bhattacharya, Vivek Kumar, C. Retna Raj, Journal of Chemical Sciences. 136(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401478800

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Arpan Samanta, Mopidevi Manikanta Kumar, Santanu Ghora, Arnab Ghatak, Somnath Bhattacharya, Vivek Kumar, C. Retna Raj</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12039-024-02295-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effects of water content and synthesis temperature on tailoring oxalate-derived nickel&#8211;iron (Oxy)hydroxide for improving oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.036</link>
      <description>Youngji Kim, K.-S. Lee, Jin Young Choi, Jung Sang Cho, Seunghwa Lee, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 83(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401479090

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youngji Kim, K.-S. Lee, Jin Young Choi, Jung Sang Cho, Seunghwa Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring electronic structure of stretchable freestanding single-crystal LaNiO3 thin film for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124495</link>
      <description>Huan Liu, Bin He, Yue Han, Jinrui Guo, Jie Wang, Sha Zhou, Jiaqing Wang, Wenqi Gao, Yong Zhang, Zhihong Wang, Zhengjia Wang, Shishen Yan, Weiming L&#252;, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480104

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huan Liu, Bin He, Yue Han, Jinrui Guo, Jie Wang, Sha Zhou, Jiaqing Wang, Wenqi Gao, Yong Zhang, Zhihong Wang, Zhengjia Wang, Shishen Yan, Weiming L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancy-rich H-TiO2/Pt with enhanced interfacial hydrogen spillover effect for wide pH range hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132693</link>
      <description>B. Liu, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Shouxin Zhang, Guihua Liu, Lanlan Wu, Jingde Li, Fuel. 376(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401480965

                No abstract</description>
      <author>B. Liu, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Shouxin Zhang, Guihua Liu, Lanlan Wu, Jingde Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Facile synthesis of CoFePO4 on eggshell membrane for oxygen evolution reaction and supercapacitor applications&#8221; [Ceram. Int. 48 (2022) 36975&#8211;36982]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.07.468</link>
      <description>Sumaira Manzoor, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Salma Aman, Muhammad Abdullah, Abdul Rashid, Hazim M. Ali, Tarik E. Ali, Mohammed A. Assiri, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, T.A. Taha, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401486952

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sumaira Manzoor, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Salma Aman, Muhammad Abdullah, Abdul Rashid, Hazim M. Ali, Tarik E. Ali, Mohammed A. Assiri, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, T.A. Taha</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.07.468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Binary ruthenium dioxide and nickel oxide ultrafine particles loaded on carbon nanotubes for high-stability oxygen evolution reaction at high current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.047</link>
      <description>Chen Yang, Qing Zhang, Ting Li, Xiaohong Chen, Xiao Lin Li, Hong Qun Luo, Nian Bing Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401487165

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen Yang, Qing Zhang, Ting Li, Xiaohong Chen, Xiao Lin Li, Hong Qun Luo, Nian Bing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reconfiguration of iron-modified Ni3S2 surface induced oxygen vacancies to immobilize sulfate for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.052</link>
      <description>Zuoyu Qin, Zebin Yu, Zimu Zhang, Xuanning Qin, Jing Liu, Ben Fan, Boge Zhang, Ronghua Jiang, Yanping Hou, Jiayi Qu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401487180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zuoyu Qin, Zebin Yu, Zimu Zhang, Xuanning Qin, Jing Liu, Ben Fan, Boge Zhang, Ronghua Jiang, Yanping Hou, Jiayi Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.052</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Oxygen Evolution Activity for FeCoMn Oxide Catalysts via Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080513</link>
      <description>Lei Zhang, Jiayi Hou, Haiyuan Ji, Dan Meng, Jian Qi, Xiaoguang San, Catalysts. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401411499

                Electrolytic hydrogen production from water is a promising approach for obtaining clean energy. The development of efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is crucial for the generation of hydrogen through water electrolysis. Transition metal oxides, such as Fe, Co, and Mn, have shown potential as efficient OER electrocatalysts for water splitting. However, accurately predicting their electrocatalytic performance in complex compositional spaces remains a challenge, impeding the precise design of compositions and processes for optimal performance. Herein, a machine learning-based method is proposed for predicting the OER activity of (FeCoMn)Ox catalysts across a wide range of compositions. Physical features that are highly relevant to the OER overpotential (OP) are identified and analyzed. The random forest algorithm is successfully used to establish the relationship between composition and overpotential. The model demonstrates good accuracy in predicting the outcomes of new experiments, with a mean relative error (MRE) of 9.3%. The features based on covalent radius (RC) and the number of electrons in the outermost d orbitals (DEs) are the primary factors. Their variances (&#948;RC and &#948;DE) exhibit a linearly decreasing relationship with the overpotential (OP), providing direct guidance for designing OP-oriented components. This work presents an effective and innovative approach for predicting and analyzing the physical factors of transition metal oxide electrocatalysts, which can enhance the design of highly catalytic materials for electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Lei Zhang, Jiayi Hou, Haiyuan Ji, Dan Meng, Jian Qi, Xiaoguang San</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080513</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via the Reconstruction of M(OH)x/Fe3O4 Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01574f</link>
      <description>Xiaoqu Wang, Limin Wang, Yongchun Liu, Raj Kumar, Jia Li, Qiulan Huang, Dujuan Huang, Youjun Fan, Du&#8208;Hong Chen, Wei Chen, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401375578

                For large-scale hydrogen production from electrocatalysis of water, the Ni- and/or Fe-based catalysts were commonly used but limited by the ultrahigh overpotential and poor stability at high current density (&gt;500...</description>
      <author>Xiaoqu Wang, Limin Wang, Yongchun Liu, Raj Kumar, Jia Li, Qiulan Huang, Dujuan Huang, Youjun Fan, Du&#8208;Hong Chen, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01574f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoluminescence, Cytotoxic and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics studies of Silver doped Hematite Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112865</link>
      <description>S. Deepthi, Y.S. Vidya, H.C. Manjunatha, K.N. Sridhar, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, T. Ganesh, M. Shivanna, Suman Kumar, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401434677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Deepthi, Y.S. Vidya, H.C. Manjunatha, K.N. Sridhar, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, T. Ganesh, M. Shivanna, Suman Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112865</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381838

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Proton Transfer in Asymmetric Active Units for Sustainable Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05070</link>
      <description>Liming Deng, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Shuyi Liu, Sheng Zhao, Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Ai&#8208;Yin Wang, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Jian Peng, Rongpeng Ma, Lifang Jiao, Feng Hu, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401392192

                The poor durability of Ru-based catalysts limits the practical application in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). Here, we report that the asymmetric active units in Ru</description>
      <author>Liming Deng, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Shuyi Liu, Sheng Zhao, Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Ai&#8208;Yin Wang, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Jian Peng, Rongpeng Ma, Lifang Jiao, Feng Hu, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373364

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non-magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core-shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores' local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells' surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen-containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm-2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382190

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Znal2se4/Xse2 (X= Ti, Zr, Hf) Heterostructures for the Efficient Photocatalytic Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolutions with Z-Schemes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4918293</link>
      <description>Hao Sun, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, Xiaohu Li, Yuliang Liu, Wenkai Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Sun, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, Xiaohu Li, Yuliang Liu, Wenkai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4918293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Defects, Ni3+ Species, Charge Transfer Resistance, and Surface Area dictate the Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity of Mesoporous NiCo2O4 Thin Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400242</link>
      <description>Erik Dubai, Qingyang Wu, Stefan Lauterbach, Jan P. Hofmann, Marcus Einert, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401393340

                NiCo2O4 has been proven to show high electrocatalytic activity, however facile and inexpensive techniques for preparation of this compound as mesostructured thin film is lacking. In this study, the sol&#8208;gel synthesis of nanocrystalline mesoporous spinel NiCo2O4 thin films by dip&#8208;coating and soft&#8208;templating using the evaporation&#8208;induced self&#8208;assembly approach is reported. The morphology and crystallographic structure were thoroughly probed by various physicochemical characterization techniques collectively validating the development of uniform mesoporous NiCo2O4 architectures crystallizing exclusively in the cubic spinel phase after calcination in air. The surface area of the thin films depended on the calcination temperature. XPS investigations showed that the amount of Ni3+ and defective oxygen species increased for decreasing calcination temperatures. The overall electrochemical surface area, Ni3+ content, charge transfer resistance, and amount of defective oxygen sites were found to collectively control the oxygen evolution reaction performance. After an optimized annealing procedure at 300&#176;C and chronopotentiometric analysis at 10 mA/cm2 for 1.5 h, a low overpotential of 330 mV vs. RHE at 10 mA/cm2 in alkaline solution was achieved. The results highlight the necessity of precise selection of the appropriate calcination temperature and electrochemical pre&#8208;treatment conditions for adjusting the concentration of electrocatalytically active reaction sites of sol&#8208;gel&#8208;derived NiCo2O4 thin films.</description>
      <author>Erik Dubai, Qingyang Wu, Stefan Lauterbach, Jan P. Hofmann, Marcus Einert</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in mitigating oxygen evolution, phase transformation, and voltage fading in Li/Mn-rich cathode materials via cationic doping and surface modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113144</link>
      <description>John Karuga, Xolile Fuku, Thabo T.I. Nkambule, Bhekie B. Mamba, Mesfin Abayneh Kebede, Journal of Energy Storage. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401454600

                No abstract</description>
      <author>John Karuga, Xolile Fuku, Thabo T.I. Nkambule, Bhekie B. Mamba, Mesfin Abayneh Kebede</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113144</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel Ba&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&#8722;&lt;i&gt;&#948;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; and CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; hybrid electrocatalyst for both the oxygen evolution and methanol oxidation reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc02215g</link>
      <description>Fuyue Liu, Liang Chen, Ran Guo, Jiaxin Dang, Haoqi Qiu, Qiuju Zhang, Chao Yang, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan, Green Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401462508

                We synthesize a hybrid catalyst of BSCF@CeO 2 -10 with superior OER and MOR catalytic properties, which can be ascribed to the stable phase structure of BSCF, enhanced OH &#8722; adsorption ability, reduced RDS energy barrier, and increased Co/Fe valence.</description>
      <author>Fuyue Liu, Liang Chen, Ran Guo, Jiaxin Dang, Haoqi Qiu, Qiuju Zhang, Chao Yang, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc02215g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Synthesis of Novel NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Co&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Cr&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; (0 &#8804; &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; &#8804; 0.8) Composites for Electrolytic Oxygen Evolution and Methanol Oxidation in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02832</link>
      <description>Reena Parihar, Prakhar Mishra, Yamini Singh, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Narendra Kumar Singh, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401460914

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Reena Parihar, Prakhar Mishra, Yamini Singh, Pradeep Kumar Yadav, Narendra Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c02832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Oxygen Content of Graphene Oxide for Humidity Sensing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163741</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Guocheng Zhang, Fuke Wang, Hong Chi, Molecules. 29(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401390527

                Graphene oxide (GO) has shown significant potential in humidity sensing. It is well accepted that the oxygen-containing functional groups in GO significantly influence its humidity sensing performance. However, the relationship between the content of these groups and the humidity sensing capability of GO-based sensors remains unclear. In the present work, we investigate the role of oxygen-containing functional groups in the humidity sensing performance by oxidizing graphite with mesh numbers 80&#8211;120, 325, and 8000 using the Hummers method, resulting in GO-80, GO-325, and GO-8000. Infrared spectroscopy (IR) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) were used to identify the types and quantification of oxygen-containing functional groups. Molecular dynamics simulation is used to simulate the adsorption energy, intercalation dynamics, and hydrogen bonding of water molecules. Electrochemical tests were used to compare the adsorption/desorption time and response sensitivity of graphene oxide to humidity. It is proposed that hydroxyl and carboxyl groups are the main contributing groups to humidity sensing. GO-8000 shows a relatively fast response time, but the large number of carboxyl groups will hinder intercalation of water molecules, thus exhibiting lower sensitivity. This research provides a reference for the future development of graphene-based sensors, catalysts, and environmental materials.</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Guocheng Zhang, Fuke Wang, Hong Chi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presence of oxygen in catalytic pyrolysis of lignin impacts evolution of both coke and aromatic hydrocarbons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101774</link>
      <description>Chao Li, Bo Gao, Zhihui Pan, Yuxuan Liu, Yunyu Guo, Mortaza Gholizadeh, Bin Li, Li Wang, Xun Hu, Journal of the Energy Institute. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401475054

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chao Li, Bo Gao, Zhihui Pan, Yuxuan Liu, Yunyu Guo, Mortaza Gholizadeh, Bin Li, Li Wang, Xun Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joei.2024.101774</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructural evolution of the inner oxide layer of a Si-modified austenitic stainless steel exposed to oxygen-saturated lead-bismuth eutectic (LBE): toward the origin of LBE penetration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112350</link>
      <description>Ang Xie, Shenghu Chen, Lichang Yin, Neng He, Chunlin Chen, Lijian Rong, Corrosion Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376089

                Microstructural evolution of inner oxide layer of a Si-modified austenitic stainless steel exposed to oxygen-saturated static lead-bismuth eutectic (LBE) at 550 &#176;C up to 3000 h has been investigated. A dual-phase separated structure consisting of Fe-Cr spinel and (Fe, Cr)1-xNix phase is formed in inner oxide layer, attributed to partitioning of Ni and Cr associated with Fe-Cr spinel formation. SiO2 is preferentially formed preceding the Fe-Cr spinel at internal oxidation frontier, leading to dispersed SiO2 nanoparticles within Fe-Cr spinel. The mechanism of LBE penetration into inner oxide layer is further developed based on preferable dissolution process of (Fe, Cr)1-xNix phase.</description>
      <author>Ang Xie, Shenghu Chen, Lichang Yin, Neng He, Chunlin Chen, Lijian Rong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel structure Ti/Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S/Co(OH)&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; enhances the photoelectrochemical water splitting performance of iron oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2023.68</link>
      <description>Hao-Yan Shi, Yanxin Chen, Ming-Hao Ji, Qian-Qian Zhou, K. Li, Sheng Wang, Rui Chen, Xiu&#8208;Mei Lin, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu, Chemical Synthesis. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401402237

                The slow oxygen evolution kinetics of iron oxide nanorod arrays have limited their applications in photocatalytic water splitting. Herein, we introduce p-type semiconductor cuprous oxide and further cover cobalt hydroxide ultrathin nanosheets on the surface of both by electrochemical deposition; these methods obviously enhanced the photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting performance of iron oxide nanorods on titanium sheet substrate. The photocurrent of this heterostructure reached 4.8 mA/cm2 at 1.23 V (vs. reversible hydrogen electrode) in a 1 M KOH aqueous solution under AM 1.5G illumination, which is much higher than the currently reported photocatalytic water splitting performance of iron oxide nanoarrays. The construction of Fe2O3/Cu2S p-n heterojunction accelerates the separation of photogenerated carriers in the main body of Fe2O3 nanorod arrays; as an excellent oxygen evolution catalyst (OEC), the introduction of Co(OH)x accelerates the kinetic process of interfacial water oxidation leading to the rapid depletion of photogenerated holes, which further improves the charge separation on the photoanode surface. Thus, the synergistic effect between Fe2O3/Cu2S p-n heterojunctions and oxygen evolution catalysts enhanced the iron oxide nanorod array photoanodes.</description>
      <author>Hao-Yan Shi, Yanxin Chen, Ming-Hao Ji, Qian-Qian Zhou, K. Li, Sheng Wang, Rui Chen, Xiu&#8208;Mei Lin, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2023.68</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal Oxide Clusters: Advanced Electrocatalysts for a Sustainable Energy Future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02722a</link>
      <description>Piracha Sanwal, Yifei Zhang, Ali Raza, Li Gao, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401439027

                The comprehensive utilization of sustainable green energy is essential to face the global energy and environmental crisis. The oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution of hydrogen (OER), and electrocatalytic urea...</description>
      <author>Piracha Sanwal, Yifei Zhang, Ali Raza, Li Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc02722a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosted Urea Electrooxidation Activity by Dynamic Steady Blending CoOOH-Ni(OH)2 Nanoclusters for H2 Production in a pH-asymmetric Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04241g</link>
      <description>Shih-Mao Peng, Shu&#8208;Ting Chang, Chia&#8208;Che Chang, Priyadarshini HN, Chun&#8208;Chih Chang, Kuan&#8208;Chang Wu, Yung-Hung Huang, Yi&#8208;Chia Chen, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Di&#8208;Yan Wang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401408847

                Electrochemical urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is a promising alternative to the oxygen evolution reaction for reducing the overall potential of the hydrogen evolution reaction during water electrolysis. The theoretical potential...</description>
      <author>Shih-Mao Peng, Shu&#8208;Ting Chang, Chia&#8208;Che Chang, Priyadarshini HN, Chun&#8208;Chih Chang, Kuan&#8208;Chang Wu, Yung-Hung Huang, Yi&#8208;Chia Chen, Tsung&#8208;Rong Kuo, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Di&#8208;Yan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04241g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Highly Efficient Electrocatalyst for ORR and OER Based on Nb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; MXene: The Role of Transition Metals and N-Doping Content</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02337</link>
      <description>Dai Yu, Yahui Li, Xingbo Ge, Xiaoyue Fu, Yingjie Feng, Xin Chen, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401353181

                Finding efficient and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is imperative for advancing zinc-air batteries. Herein, the effect of transition metal anchored on Nb</description>
      <author>Dai Yu, Yahui Li, Xingbo Ge, Xiaoyue Fu, Yingjie Feng, Xin Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen Doped Carbon Layer Coated Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;MnO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst for Efficient Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400369</link>
      <description>Zhi Wang, Zhaokun Wang, Wenxin Li, Jiashuai Wang, Haofeng Shi, Chengdeng Wang, Zhiming Bai, Jing Wang, Chuang Zhu, Xiaoqin Cheng, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481634

                Abstract Electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution process must be both active and stable in order to make hydrogen from water using renewable power. Nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon layer coated cobalt manganate particles were synthesized on carbon cloth using calcination method. The catalysts exhibited small particle sizes and graphitized carbon layer that covered the cobalt manganate, facilitating electron flow. Moreover, the nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon layer enhanced the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) rate by reducing the potential required for surface reconstruction and optimizing electron distribution on the cobalt manganate surface. This electrocatalyst demonstrated a current density of 100 mA/cm 2 at 1.56 V vs. RHE. Thus, this electrocatalyst shows promise as a novel OER catalyst for water oxidation in acidic aqueous solutions.</description>
      <author>Zhi Wang, Zhaokun Wang, Wenxin Li, Jiashuai Wang, Haofeng Shi, Chengdeng Wang, Zhiming Bai, Jing Wang, Chuang Zhu, Xiaoqin Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Tuning of BiVO4/MnFe-MOF Photoanodes Boosts Hole Extraction for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00836g</link>
      <description>Chenchen Feng, L.L. Liu, Houyu Fu, Faqi Zhan, Henan Jia, Xiang Cheng, Fucheng Yu, Qi Zhou, Zheng Bian, Beibei Zhang, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373580

                To achieve extremely effective photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting, it is imperative to suppress charge recombination at the interfaces between the oxygen evolution cocatalyst (OEC) and BiVO4. In view of this,...</description>
      <author>Chenchen Feng, L.L. Liu, Houyu Fu, Faqi Zhan, Henan Jia, Xiang Cheng, Fucheng Yu, Qi Zhou, Zheng Bian, Beibei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00836g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of nanoscale stabilized oxide catalysts for OER with OC22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01390e</link>
      <description>Richard Tran, Liqiang Huang, Yuan Zi, Lars C. Grabow, Benjamin M. Comer, Xuqing Wu, Stefan J. Raaijman, Nishant K. Sinha, Sajanikumari Sadasivan, Shibin Thundiyil, Kuldeep Mamtani, Ganesh Iyer, Lars C. Grabow, Ligang Lu, Jiefu Chen, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401379356

                The efficiency of H 2 production via water electrolysis is typically limited to the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As such, significant emphasis has been placed upon improving the rate of...</description>
      <author>Richard Tran, Liqiang Huang, Yuan Zi, Lars C. Grabow, Benjamin M. Comer, Xuqing Wu, Stefan J. Raaijman, Nishant K. Sinha, Sajanikumari Sadasivan, Shibin Thundiyil, Kuldeep Mamtani, Ganesh Iyer, Lars C. Grabow, Ligang Lu, Jiefu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01390e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Alkaline Water Splitting Efficiency: NiOOH-MnOOH Heterojunctions via In Situ Anodic Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00512k</link>
      <description>Yuru Zhou, Jing Hu, You&#8208;Nian Liu, Wen Fan, panpan tao, Jing Wang, Haitao Huang, Xun Cao, Haijin Li, Siwei Li, Materials Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401357428

                Designing noble metal-free electrocatalysts remains a challenge for oxygen evolution reactions (OER) in alkaline solutions. In this study, we present a facile electrodeposition approach coupled with an in-situ anodic oxidation...</description>
      <author>Yuru Zhou, Jing Hu, You&#8208;Nian Liu, Wen Fan, panpan tao, Jing Wang, Haitao Huang, Xun Cao, Haijin Li, Siwei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00512k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering of VO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/Ni/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N Heterostructures for Electrochemical Urea-Assisted Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01822</link>
      <description>Jie Wang, Cheng Wang, Xiaorong Zhang, Shiye Li, Chao Yang, Jinli Zhang, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401459567

                Electrocatalytic hydrogen generation driven by renewable energy sources is severely limited by the slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Urea-assisted alkaline hydrogen production offers a perspective approach. However, the construction of efficient and robust anode catalysts is still challenging. Herein, an amorphous/crystalline VO</description>
      <author>Jie Wang, Cheng Wang, Xiaorong Zhang, Shiye Li, Chao Yang, Jinli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01822</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Iron Active Sites of FeOOH via Al&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; and Heteroatom Doping&#8208;Induced Asymmetric Oxygen Vacancy Electronic Structure for Efficient Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404552</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Lv, Ying&#8208;Fei Chang, Xinyu Chen, Jinyu Guo, Jing Sun, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Hong&#8208;Ying Zang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358383

                Oxygen evolution reaction is the essential anodic reaction for water splitting. Designing tunable electronic structures to overcome its slow kinetics is an effective strategy. Herein, the molecular ammonium iron sulfate dodecahydrate is employed as the precursor to synthesize the C, N, S triatomic co-doped Fe(Al)OOH on Ni foam (C,N,S-Fe(Al)OOH-NF) with asymmetric electronic structure. Both in situ oxygen vacancies and their special electronic configuration enable the electron transfer between the d-p orbitals and get the increase of OER activity. Density functional theory calculation further indicates the effect of electronic structure on catalytic activity and stability at the oxygen vacancies. In alkaline solution, the catalyst C,N,S-Fe(Al)OOH-NF shows good catalytic activity and stability for water splitting. For OER, the overpotential of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Lv, Ying&#8208;Fei Chang, Xinyu Chen, Jinyu Guo, Jing Sun, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Hong&#8208;Ying Zang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Half&#8208;metallization Atom&#8208;Fingerprints Achieved at Ultrafast Oxygen&#8208;Evaporated Pyrochlores for Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404787</link>
      <description>Zhuangzhuang Xu, Ming Meng, Gang Zhou, Chenglong Liang, Xing&#8208;Tao An, Yuxuan Jiang, Yongcai Zhang, Yong Zhou, Lizhe Liu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401485806

                Abstract The stability and catalytic activity of acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are strongly determined by the coordination states and spatial symmetry among metal sites at catalysts. Herein, an ultrafast oxygen evaporation technology to rapidly soften the intrinsic covalent bonds using ultrahigh electrical pulses is suggested, in which prospective charged excited states at this extreme avalanche condition can generate a strong electron&#8211;phonon coupling to rapidly evaporate some coordinated oxygen (O) atoms, finally leading to a controllable half&#8208;metallization feature. Simultaneously, the relative metal (M) site arrays can be orderly locked to delineate some intriguing atom&#8208;fingerprints at pyrochlore catalysts, where the coexistence of metallic bonds (M&#9472;M) and covalent bonds (M&#9472;O) at this symmetry&#8208;breaking configuration can partially restrain crystal field effect to generate a particular high&#8208;spin occupied state. This half&#8208;metallization catalyst can effectively optimize the spin&#8208;related reaction kinetics in acidic OER, giving rise to 10.3 times (at 188 mV overpotential) reactive activity than pristine pyrochlores. This work provides a new understanding of half&#8208;metallization atom&#8208;fingerprints at catalyst surfaces to accelerate acidic water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Zhuangzhuang Xu, Ming Meng, Gang Zhou, Chenglong Liang, Xing&#8208;Tao An, Yuxuan Jiang, Yongcai Zhang, Yong Zhou, Lizhe Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rod&#8208;Shaped Au@Ce Nano&#8208;Platforms for Enhancing Photodynamic Tumor Collaborative Therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400945</link>
      <description>Yuxiang Sun, Ziqi Cao, Xiaoli Zhang, Xingchen Zhu, Zhenyang Xu, Huaichun Zhou, Xiaoer Wei, Wenxian Du, Li Xu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401308457

                Abstract Tumor photodynamic therapy (PDT) relies on intratumoral free radicals, while the limited oxygen source and the depletion of tissue oxygen may exacerbate the hypoxia. As the treatment progresses, there will eventually be a problem of insufficient free radicals. Here, it is found that Au@CeO 2 nano&#8208;rods (Au@Ce NRs), assembled by gold nano&#8208;rods (Au NRs) and ceria nanoparticles (CeO 2 NPs), can efficaciously absorb near&#8208;infrared light (NIR) to promote the release of oxygen and free radicals. Au@Ce NRs exhibit a higher proportion of Ce 3+ (Ce 2 O 3 ) after oxygen release, while Ce 3+ is subsequently oxidized to Ce 4+ (CeO 2 ) by trace H 2 O 2 . Interestingly, Au@Ce NRs re&#8208;oxidized by trace H 2 O 2 can re&#8208;releasing oxygen and free radicals again upon NIR treatment, achieving oxygenation/oxygen evolution, similar to charging/discharging. This loop maximizes the conversion of limited oxygen source into highly cytotoxic free radicals. As a result, when B16&#8208;F10 cells are treated by NIR/Au@Ce NRs, more tumor cells undergo apoptosis, consistent with the higher level of free radicals. Importantly, NIR/Au@Ce NRs successfully suppresses tumor growth and promotes the generation of epidermal collagen fibers in the transplanted tumor model. Therefore, the rod&#8208;shaped Au@Ce NRs provide an ideal platform for maximizing the utilization of intratumoral oxygen sources and improving the treatment of melanoma.</description>
      <author>Yuxiang Sun, Ziqi Cao, Xiaoli Zhang, Xingchen Zhu, Zhenyang Xu, Huaichun Zhou, Xiaoer Wei, Wenxian Du, Li Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-Tungsten Oxide Nanostructures on Nickel Foam as High Efficient Electrocatalysts for Benzyl Alcohol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163734</link>
      <description>Yizhen Zhu, Xiangyu Chen, Yuanyao Zhang, Zhifei Zhu, Handan Chen, Kejie Chai, Weiming Xu, Molecules. 29(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401394143

                Electrocatalytic alcohol oxidation (EAO) is an attractive alternative to the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction in electrochemical hydrogen evolution cells. However, the development of high-performance bifunctional electrocatalysts is a major challenge. Herein, we developed a nitrogen-doped bimetallic oxide electrocatalyst (WO-N/NF) by a one-step hydrothermal method for the selective electrooxidation of benzyl alcohol to benzoic acid in alkaline electrolytes. The WO-N/NF electrode features block-shaped particles on a rough, inhomogeneous surface with cracks and lumpy nodules, increasing active sites and enhancing electrolyte diffusion. The electrode demonstrates exceptional activity, stability, and selectivity, achieving efficient benzoic acid production while reducing the electrolysis voltage. A low onset potential of 1.38 V (vs. RHE) is achieved to reach a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1.0 M KOH electrolyte with only 0.2 mmol of metal precursors, which is 396 mV lower than that of water oxidation. The analysis reveals a yield, conversion, and selectivity of 98.41%, 99.66%, and 99.74%, respectively, with a Faradaic efficiency of 98.77%. This work provides insight into the rational design of a highly active and selective catalyst for electrocatalytic alcohol oxidation.</description>
      <author>Yizhen Zhu, Xiangyu Chen, Yuanyao Zhang, Zhifei Zhu, Handan Chen, Kejie Chai, Weiming Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Light and Electrode Polarization on BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanodes for Glycerol Oxidation.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6bc3</link>
      <description>Mart&#237; Molera, M. Sarret, Cristian F&#225;brega, Teresa Andreu, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351802

                Abstract In recent years, there has been a growing interest in the photoelectrochemical oxidation of glycerol to produce high-value products. Most studies have focused solely on the photocatalytic properties of the electrodes, overlooking their electrocatalytic properties and the different products obtained under dark conditions. Our work aims to address this gap by comparing the electrocatalytic activity under dark and light conditions to determine whether light influences the reactivity of the electrodes or if it just reduces the overpotential of the reaction. To achieve this, we employed two model semiconductors, TiO2 and BiVO4. We have analyzed their polarization curves under both dark and light conditions and evaluated the competence of glycerol oxidation reaction with the oxygen evolution reaction. Furthermore, we conducted long-term (photo)electrolysis revealing the beneficial role of light on the electrolytic process, as it enables the obtention of C3 products on illuminated TiO2 photoanodes at low electrode polarization, comparable to the performance of BiVO4.</description>
      <author>Mart&#237; Molera, M. Sarret, Cristian F&#225;brega, Teresa Andreu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6bc3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Temperature Water Electrolysis Properties of Membrane Electrode Assemblies with Nafion and Crosslinked Sulfonated Polyphenylsulfone Membranes by Using a Decal Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/membranes14080173</link>
      <description>Je&#8208;Deok Kim, Membranes. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401415302

                To improve the stability of high-temperature water electrolysis, I prepared membrane electrode assemblies (MEAs) using a decal method and investigated their water electrolysis properties. Nafion 115 and crosslinked sulfonated polyphenylsulfone (CSPPSU) membranes were used. IrO2 was used as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst, and Pt/C was used as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst. The conductivity of the CSPPSU membrane at 80 &#176;C and 90% RH (relative humidity) is about four times lower than that of the Nafion 115 membrane. Single-cell water electrolysis was performed while measuring the current density and performing electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) at cell temperatures from 80 to 150 &#176;C and the stability of the current density over time at 120 &#176;C and 1.7 V. The current density of water electrolysis using Nafion 115 and CSPPSU membranes at 150 &#176;C and 2 V was 1.2 A/cm2 for both. The current density of the water electrolysis using the CSPPSU membrane at 120 &#176;C and 1.7 V was stable for 40 h. The decal method improved the contact between the CSPPSU membrane and the catalyst electrode, and a stable current density was obtained.</description>
      <author>Je&#8208;Deok Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/membranes14080173</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spontaneous Heterophase Atomic Structure Engineering of NiMo(S)/NiMoP for Enhanced Overall Electrochemical Water Splitting in Neutral Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124469</link>
      <description>Yihan Zhang, Jeong Min Baik, Hyesung Park, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354267

                Hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions catalyzed by transition metals have sluggish kinetics during prolonged water electrolysis in neutral media. Covering the surface with an amorphous protecting layer can improve the reactivity and stability of these catalysts; however, the rational design of crystalline&#8211;amorphous electrocatalysts for efficient and stable water electrolysis in neutral media has been challenging. Here, we present a unique and facile strategy for the in situ synthesis of the heterophase-structured cNiMo(S)/aNiMoP catalyst with a crystalline&#8211;amorphous phase boundary. The high-density active sites present on the surface and at the interface of the heterophase is responsible for the excellent electrochemical activity and operational stability of water electrolysis in neutral media. For the overall water splitting reaction, the cNiMo(S)/aNiMoP || cNiMo(S)/aNiMoP system displays a low cell voltage of 1.67 V to achieve a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2. Moreover, negligible performance degradation was observed during a continuous long-term stability test for 100 h.</description>
      <author>Yihan Zhang, Jeong Min Baik, Hyesung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124469</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Self-Assembled Multiphasic Thin Film as an Oxygen Electrode for Enhanced Durability in Reversible Solid Oxide Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06290</link>
      <description>Fjorelo Buzi, Kosova Kreka, Jos&#233; Santiso, La&#235;titia Rapenne, Zijie Sha, James O. Douglas, Francesco Chiabrera, &#192;lex Morata, M&#243;nica Burriel, Stephen J. Skinner, Lucile Bernadet, Federico Baiutti, Albert Taranc&#243;n, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401392275

                The implementation of nanocomposite materials as electrode layers represents a potential turning point for next-generation of solid oxide cells in order to reduce the use of critical raw materials. However, the substitution of bulk electrode materials by thin films is still under debate especially due to the uncertainty about their performance and stability under operando conditions, which restricts their use in real applications. In this work, we propose a multiphase nanocomposite characterized by a highly disordered microstructure and high cationic intermixing as a result from thin-film self-assembly of a perovskite-based mixed ionic-electronic conductor (lanthanum strontium cobaltite) and a fluorite-based pure ionic conductor (samarium-doped ceria) as an oxygen electrode for reversible solid oxide cells. Electrochemical characterization shows remarkable oxygen reduction reaction (fuel cell mode) and oxygen evolution activity (electrolysis mode) in comparison with state-of-the-art bulk electrodes, combined with outstanding long-term stability at operational temperatures of 700 &#176;C. The disordered nanostructure was implemented as a standalone oxygen electrode on commercial anode-supported cells, resulting in high electrical output in fuel cell and electrolysis mode for active layer thicknesses of only 200 nm (&gt;95% decrease in critical raw materials with respect to conventional cathodes). The cell was operated for over 300 h in fuel cell mode displaying excellent stability. Our findings unlock the hidden potential of advanced thin-film technologies for obtaining high-performance disordered electrodes based on nanocomposite self-assembly combining long durability and minimized use of critical raw materials.</description>
      <author>Fjorelo Buzi, Kosova Kreka, Jos&#233; Santiso, La&#235;titia Rapenne, Zijie Sha, James O. Douglas, Francesco Chiabrera, &#192;lex Morata, M&#243;nica Burriel, Stephen J. Skinner, Lucile Bernadet, Federico Baiutti, Albert Taranc&#243;n</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c06290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quantitative description of light-limited cyanobacterial growth using flux balance analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012280</link>
      <description>Rune H&#246;per, Daria Komkova, Tom&#225;&#353; Zav&#345;el, Ralf Steuer, PLoS Computational Biology. 20(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401328669

                The metabolism of phototrophic cyanobacteria is an integral part of global biogeochemical cycles, and the capability of cyanobacteria to assimilate atmospheric CO2 into organic carbon has manifold potential applications for a sustainable biotechnology. To elucidate the properties of cyanobacterial metabolism and growth, computational reconstructions of genome-scale metabolic networks play an increasingly important role. Here, we present an updated reconstruction of the metabolic network of the cyanobacterium Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803 and its quantitative evaluation using flux balance analysis (FBA). To overcome limitations of conventional FBA, and to allow for the integration of experimental analyses, we develop a novel approach to describe light absorption and light utilization within the framework of FBA. Our approach incorporates photoinhibition and a variable quantum yield into the constraint-based description of light-limited phototrophic growth. We show that the resulting model is capable of predicting quantitative properties of cyanobacterial growth, including photosynthetic oxygen evolution and the ATP/NADPH ratio required for growth and cellular maintenance. Our approach retains the computational and conceptual simplicity of FBA and is readily applicable to other phototrophic microorganisms.</description>
      <author>Rune H&#246;per, Daria Komkova, Tom&#225;&#353; Zav&#345;el, Ralf Steuer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noble Metal&#8208;Free High Entropy Perovskite Oxide with High Cationic Dispersion Enhanced Oxygen Redox Reactivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401836</link>
      <description>Arindam Chatterjee, Dipsikha Ganguly, S. Ramaprabhu, Subramshu S. Bhattacharya, ChemistrySelect. 9(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401363653

                Abstract High entropy perovskite oxide (HEPO) materials have received significant interest as efficient electrocatalysts owing to their chemical and structural stability, effective interaction of multiple metal active sites with the reaction intermediate species resulting in enhanced catalytic activity. The effect of high&#8208;entropy strategy could achieve the regulation of the structural durability by tailoring the composition. Herein, we design a novel transition metal and rare&#8208;earth metal based high entropy perovskite oxide (Co 0.11 Mn 0.11 Ni 0.11 Fe 0.14 La 0.13 Nd 0.13 Gd 0.13 Pr 0.13 )O 3, showing superior catalytic activity in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and also promising electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction (OER). High degree of cationic dispersion in the lattice and multiple electrocatalytic active sites enhance the oxygen ion migration at the surface and facilitate electron transfer, manifesting good ORR performance. Notably, the as&#8208;prepared high entropy material exhibits onset and half&#8208;wave potential of 1.02 V and 0.89 V versus RHE, respectively, exceeding the performance of the benchmarked Pt/C catalyst in the ORR process with reasonable redox kinetics. Moreover, the material also presents faster kinetics with reasonably low overpotential and excellent electrochemical stability in the OER process as well. This study shows the viability of designing non&#8208;precious high entropy materials as highly efficient oxide electrocatalyst by utilizing its broad compositional space.</description>
      <author>Arindam Chatterjee, Dipsikha Ganguly, S. Ramaprabhu, Subramshu S. Bhattacharya</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;efficient electrocatalytic CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; reduction to HCOOH coupling with 5&#8208;hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation using flow cell</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18562</link>
      <description>Jing Ren, Zixian Li, Chenjun Ning, Shaoquan Li, Luming Zhang, Hengshuo Huang, Lirong Zheng, Young Soo Kang, Mingchuan Luo, Yufei Zhao, AIChE Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401444002

                Abstract Among various products from electrocatalytic CO 2 reduction (CO 2 ER), HCOOH is highly profitable one. However, the slow kinetics of anodic oxygen evolution reaction lowers overall energy efficiency, which can be replaced by an electro&#8208;oxidation reaction with low thermodynamic potential and fast kinetics. Herein, we report an electrolysis system coupling CO 2 ER with 5&#8208;hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation reaction (HMFOR). A BiOCl&#8211;CuO catalyst was designed to sustain CO 2 ER to HCOOH at partial current density of 500 mA/cm 2 with FE HCOOH above 90% and 700 mA/cm 2 with FE HCOOH above 80%. In situ and ex situ x&#8208;ray absorption fine structure was used to capture the structure transform of BiOCl&#8211;CuO into metallic Bi and Cu during CO 2 ER process, and the presence of CuO will promote this transformation which are supported by DFT calculations. Coupling HMFOR with CO 2 ER, we realize both FE HCOOH and FE FDCA above 95% simultaneously, providing new prospects vista for the electrosynthesis of value&#8208;added products from paired system.</description>
      <author>Jing Ren, Zixian Li, Chenjun Ning, Shaoquan Li, Luming Zhang, Hengshuo Huang, Lirong Zheng, Young Soo Kang, Mingchuan Luo, Yufei Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aic.18562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing the Operation Current Density of Alkaline Water Oxidation above 1 A cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; via Electrocatalyst Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402034</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Yan Zhang, Kunyan Wang, Lei Tan, Faiza Meharban, Sheng Wang, Xiaopeng Li, Chao Lin, Wei Luo, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358181

                Abstract Rapid cost reduction of green hydrogen is essential for the large&#8208;scale deployment of hydrogen&#8208;based energy system. A major component in achieving this is the development of advanced water electrolyzers. Sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the bottleneck for water electrolysis, and tremendous efforts have been devoted to develop electrocatalysts that accelerate the OER kinetics. Recent advances have highlighted the potential of precious metal&#8208;free OER electrocatalyst capable of stable operation at current densities above 1 A cm 2 . This brings an opportunity of constructing new&#8208;generation electrolyzer with lower cost and higher productivity. However, achieving such high operating current densities presents new challenges. This review summarize the recent progress of high&#8208;performance OER catalysts, and identifies key factors that can be leveraged to enhance catalyst activity. These factors include interface/surface engineering, amorphous and crystal phase coupling, hierarchical structure design, structural reconstruction and phase conversion, high entropy catalyst, and defect engineering. Additionally, the pressing challenges that have been largely ignored in previous research is addressed, such as sustaining long&#8208;term stability under crucial conditions, disadvantages of immobilized powder electrocatalysts, electrode scale design, the necessity of designing innovative electrolyzer cell designs and advance characterization techniques.</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Yan Zhang, Kunyan Wang, Lei Tan, Faiza Meharban, Sheng Wang, Xiaopeng Li, Chao Lin, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upcycling of Spent LiFePO4 Cathodes to Heterostructured Electrocatalysts for Stable Direct Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410396</link>
      <description>Zhen Li, Mengting Li, Yiqun Chen, Xucun Ye, Mengjie Liu, Lawrence Yoon Suk Lee, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401421267

                The pursuit of carbon&#8208;neutral energy has intensified the interest in green hydrogen production from direct seawater electrolysis, given the scarcity of freshwater resources. While Ni&#8208;based catalysts are known for their robust activity in alkaline water oxidation, their catalytic sites are prone to rapid degradation in the chlorine&#8208;rich environments of seawater, leading to limited operation time. Herein, we report a Ni(OH)2 catalyst interfaced with laser&#8208;ablated LiFePO4 (Ni(OH)2/L&#8208;LFP), derived from spent Li&#8208;ion batteries (LIBs), as an effective and stable electrocatalyst for direct seawater oxidation. Our comprehensive analyses reveal that the PO43&#8211; species, formed around L&#8208;LFP, effectively repels Cl&#8722; ions during seawater oxidation, mitigating corrosion. Simultaneously, the interface between in situ generated NiOOH and Fe3(PO4)2 enhances OH&#8211; adsorption and electron transfer during the oxygen evolution reaction. This synergistic effect leads to a low overpotential of 237 mV to attain a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and remarkable durability, with only a 3.3 % activity loss after 600 h at 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline seawater. Our findings present a viable strategy for repurposing spent LIBs into high&#8208;performance catalysts for sustainable seawater electrolysis, contributing to the advancement of green hydrogen production technologies.</description>
      <author>Zhen Li, Mengting Li, Yiqun Chen, Xucun Ye, Mengjie Liu, Lawrence Yoon Suk Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410396</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Active&#8208;Site Engineering of Low&#8208;Noble&#8208;Metal&#8208;Alloyed Metallic Glass Catalyst for Boosting Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410379</link>
      <description>Yanan Zhang, Rui Li, Xu Wang, Qingjie Guo, Qinghui Zhang, Yi He, Weihong Liu, Zhibin Li, Xiongjun Liu, Xiongjun Liu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401483652

                Abstract The development of efficient, robust, and cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts remains a significant challenge for practical water electrolysis. Here, a metallic glass (MG)&#8208;based catalyst with surface&#8208;enriched Ir and Pt&#8208;alloyed active sites, demonstrating superior electrocatalytic performance, is reported. The dealloyed catalyst, characterized by an Ir and Pt&#8208;rich honeycombed nanoporous surface and an interior flexible MG substrate, can directly serve as a bifunctional electrode, enabling efficient hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions with low overpotentials of 19 and 223 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. Notably, the mass activity of the catalyst surpasses that of commercial Pt/C and Ir/C catalysts by 13.9 and 16.5 times, respectively. Additionally, the catalyst exhibits exceptional stability with negligible activity decay even under an ampere&#8208;level current density (i.e., &#8805;1 A cm &#8722;2 ). Theoretical calculations reveal the optimization of atomic configuration and regulation of electronic interactions through lattice strain induced by the co&#8208;alloying of Ir and Pt, contributing to superior electrocatalytic performance. Furthermore, the unique honeycombed nanoporous architecture, shaped by the surface migration and enrichment of the noble metals, offers abundant active sites for accelerating the electrocatalytic reactions. This work presents a novel approach to cost&#8208;effectively design high&#8208;performance alloy catalysts by engineering surface catalytically active sites.</description>
      <author>Yanan Zhang, Rui Li, Xu Wang, Qingjie Guo, Qinghui Zhang, Yi He, Weihong Liu, Zhibin Li, Xiongjun Liu, Xiongjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress and perspective of transition metal layered double hydroxides with oxygen vacancies for enhancing water splitting applications: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113773</link>
      <description>Kai Chen, Dung Van Dao, Sunny Yadav, Hoki Son, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401371252

                As an energy-sustainable and environmentally friendly technology, electrochemical water splitting is a highly recognized approach for the production of clean energy and overcoming the energy crisis. However, this method faces a series of challenges, such as low catalyst activity, slow kinetics, poor stability, and high cost. Many reports showed that transition metal layered double hydroxides (TM-LDHs) with unique oxygen vacancy (Ov) defects are a significant new type of candidate nanomaterials to replace precious metal catalysts. This is mainly attributed to their unique physicochemical properties, as well as the tuning of the electronic and lattice structure of the catalyst and optimization of the catalyst surface desorption/adsorption reactions achieved through the introduction of oxygen vacancies, thereby accelerating the oxygen/hydrogen evolution reaction (OER/HER) processes in water splitting. Herein, the preparation methods for engineering oxygen vacancies, and advanced techniques for characterizing oxygen vacancies in catalysts are systematically reviewed, with the aim of clarifying the role of oxygen vacancies in TM-LDHs. The effects of oxygen vacancies on regulating electronic structure, optimizing adsorption energy for intermediates, activating surrounding atomic sites, and generating new active species in TM-LDHs for efficient catalytic HER/OER and decomposition of water are analyzed. More importantly, we discuss the mechanism by which oxygen vacancies promote efficient water splitting in TM-LDHs and outline opportunities and challenges for future development.</description>
      <author>Kai Chen, Dung Van Dao, Sunny Yadav, Hoki Son</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of the Fire Point on the Thermal Dynamic Disaster in the Goaf</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7080270</link>
      <description>Xiaokun Chen, Chao Song, Zhipeng Zhang, Fire. 7(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326784

                A thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf is one of the most serious coal mine disasters formed by coal spontaneous combustion and gas interweaving. However, the influence of the high-temperature hidden fire source formed in the goaf on the evolution law of thermal dynamic disasters is not clear, and effective prevention and control measures cannot be taken. Therefore, this paper uses the experimental platform of thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf to study the influence of different fire point positions on the development of thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf through a similar simulation experiment of thermal dynamic disaster evolution in the goaf and analyzes the corresponding relationship between temperature and CO concentration in the upper corner. The results show that under different locations of heat source, the high-temperature heat source of coal spontaneous combustion migrates to the air leakage side with sufficient oxygen supply, and an oxygen-poor circle is formed near the ignition point. Under the action of air leakage flow, CH4 accumulates in the deep part of the goaf on the return air side. Due to the increase in coal, part of CH4 is produced, which leads to the increase in concentration of CH4 at the ignition point. Under the action of different heat sources, the changing trend of concentration of CO and temperature in the return air corner is the same, but the temperature change in the return air corner shows a lag compared with the change in the concentration of CO, so concentration monitoring of CO can reflect the evolution process of the fire field in the goaf more quickly than temperature monitoring.</description>
      <author>Xiaokun Chen, Chao Song, Zhipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7080270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally&#8208;Induced Reentrant Order&#8208;Disorder&#8208;Order Transitions in ALa&lt;sub&gt;9&lt;/sub&gt;(GeO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Apatites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202401520</link>
      <description>Alexander Yu. Chufarov, &#1040;. P. Tyutyunnik, Nadezda V. Tarakina, A. Dominic Fortes, Marina A. Melkozerova, Andrey N. Enyashin, Olga A. Lipina, Yana V. Baklanova, A. N. Kiryakov, Ludmila L. Surat, &#1042;. &#1043;. &#1047;&#1091;&#1073;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;, Advanced Optical Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401428372

                Abstract Oxyapatites A 10 (GeO 4 ) 6 O 2 (A &#8211; alkaline, rare&#8208;earth elements) are considered promising materials for applications in solid&#8208;state lighting and non&#8208;contact thermometry. The temperature dynamics of the oxygen sublattice have a crucial influence on the luminescent properties of these optical hosts. Here, the structural evolution with temperature of germanates with the general formula ALa 9 (GeO 4 ) 6 O 2 (A &#8211; Li, Na, K, Rb) is investigated, using X&#8208;ray and neutron powder diffraction methods. These compounds crystallize in space&#8208;group P 6 3 / m . NPD experiments helped to determine the oxygen and alkaline metal positions. Thermally&#8208;induced reentrant structural transitions relating to the oxygen in the apatite channel are discovered for the first time. In the example of Eu&#8208;doped RbLa 9 (GeO 4 ) 6 O 2 and KLa 9 (GeO 4 ) 6 O 2 , it is demonstrated that the luminescence of the Eu 3+ ion is influenced by small changes in the crystal structure.</description>
      <author>Alexander Yu. Chufarov, &#1040;. P. Tyutyunnik, Nadezda V. Tarakina, A. Dominic Fortes, Marina A. Melkozerova, Andrey N. Enyashin, Olga A. Lipina, Yana V. Baklanova, A. N. Kiryakov, Ludmila L. Surat, &#1042;. &#1043;. &#1047;&#1091;&#1073;&#1082;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adom.202401520</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced vanadium redox reaction catalytic properties enabled by tunning oxygen vacancy in rutile tio&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; coated graphite felt electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2814/1/012022</link>
      <description>Yancai Liu, Xiaobo Duan, Haonan Wang, Jiaao Yu, Jian Zhu, Birou Lu, Ming Zhu, Bin Zheng, Lei Zhang, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2814(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333780

                Abstract Catalyzing vanadium redox reactions in VRFBs with transition metal oxides is an effective and affordable approach. In this study, the surface electron distribution of TiO 2 was regulated by introducing oxygen vacancies into its lattice, enabling the electrode to exhibit outstanding catalytic efficacy in VO 2 + /VO 2+ and V 3+ /V 2+ redox transformations and suppress the detrimental side reaction (HER and OER) simultaneously. Benefiting from the enhanced catalytic activity and selectivity, the 1000-TiO 2 -GF electrode sustained a stable operation for 100 cycles at 120 mA cm &#8722;2 with no discernible efficiency degradation. The DFT results indicate that oxygen vacancy in TiO 2 provides more extra electrons to its neighboring titanium, further strengthening the interaction between the electron-rich titanium and oxygen in VO 2 + /VO 2+ , thus enhancing its catalytic performance. The enhanced catalytic activity for V 3+ /V 2+ on oxygen vacancy-rich TiO 2 coating can be attributed to the effective suppression of hydrogen evolution reaction, which can occupy active sites exclusively and produce detrimental H 2 bubbles. This insight provides valuable guidance for the innovative design of catalysts in vanadium redox flow batteries.</description>
      <author>Yancai Liu, Xiaobo Duan, Haonan Wang, Jiaao Yu, Jian Zhu, Birou Lu, Ming Zhu, Bin Zheng, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2814/1/012022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Pyrolysis and Incineration of Lewisite by Thermodynamic Equilibrium Calculation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202400055</link>
      <description>X.K. Liu, Yuanpeng Zhang, Lin Yang, Weiwei Song, Haitao Wang, ChemistrySelect. 9(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401379683

                Abstract Lewisite is a representative chemical warfare agent that contains arsenic. Thermal decomposition is an essential method for Lewisite destruction, and appropriate destruction conditions can enhance the environmental friendliness of this method by minimizing the hazards of destruction products. In this study, the variation of Lewisite during pyrolysis and incineration was calculated, with particular emphasis on the evolution behaviors of arsenic and chloride with temperature, pressure, and molar ratio. The main products identified during pyrolysis were HCl(g), C, As, and AsCl 3 (g). Under anoxic conditions, AsCl 3 (g) and As were the dominant species. In oxygen&#8208;enriched conditions, arsenic existed primarily as AsCl 3 (g), As 2 O 5 , As 2 O 4 , and AsOCl. Below 600 &#176;C, arsenic predominantly existed in high valence forms such as As 2 O 5 . Above 600 &#176;C, the binding capacity of chlorine and arsenic was stronger than that of oxygen, resulting in an AsCl 3 (g) molar fraction exceeding 75 % at 1200 &#176;C. The primary chlorides in oxygen&#8208;enriched conditions were Cl 2 (g), HCl(g), AsCl 3 (g), and Cl(g). Lower incineration temperatures (around 500 &#176;C), sufficient oxygen conditions (molar ratio above 4 : 1), and positive pressures were conducive to reducing the toxicity of destruction products. The results are in good agreement with the experimental data.</description>
      <author>X.K. Liu, Yuanpeng Zhang, Lin Yang, Weiwei Song, Haitao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202400055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupled Numerical Simulation of Coal Failure Caused by Thermal Impacting in Underground Coal Gasification Zone</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0373</link>
      <description>Yufeng Zhao, Shouxin Zhang, Yanpeng Chen, Zhen Dong, Hao Chen, Shanshan Chen, Junjie Xue, Heinz Konietzky, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401481130

                ABSTRACT: Underground Coal Gasification (UCG) is an environmentally friendly way to utilize coal resources. The cavity evolution process, especially the thermal impact on coal rock, is an important topic of UCG. The thermally induced coal rock failure processes in gasification environment are rarely investigated, but they are important to the gas production space and the flow from the injection well to the production well. In this study, a coupled numerical simulation program based on PFC3D and FLAC3D was established to realize multi-field coupled thermal impact conditions. The numerical model of burning-induced coal surface failure was established, and the basic cavity evolution mechanism was revealed. The main results show that (1) the redistributed temperature field in the coal rock is the most important parameter for the coupling model. The mechanical properties of the model element are assigned in accordance with its temperature state. (2) Taking into account the effects of heating, microscopic fracture and deformation are generated through PFC3D model, inhomogeneous temperature distribution is simultaneously achieved through FLAC3D model. (3) The evolution law of the expansion of the gasification cavity has been obtained by the coupled numerical simulation. (4) Eventually, the height of the gasification cavity increases, and the upper coal seams expand to an approximate equilibrium, the height affected by the temperature field becomes stable, and the vertical expansion rate of the gasification cavity gradually decreases. 1. INTRODUCTION Underground Coal Gasification (UCG) is a revolutionary technology for clean coal utilization that integrates the three key processes of well construction, coal mining and gasification for efficient gas production. This technology allows coal to undergo controlled in-situ combustion, pyrolysis and gasification reactions to produce syngas with methane, hydrogen, carbon monoxide, carbon dioxide and other components for surface recovery by injecting air, oxygen-enriched air, oxygen/water and other gasification agents into underground coal seams[1&#8211;4]. Currently, the underground gasification of middle-deep coal seams has no practical experience, especially for the dynamic study of the deforming and destroying process of the surrounding stone (coal) in the gasification cavity under high temperature and high pressure. The numerical simulation technology of gasification cavity development dynamics is still in the initial stage. The simulation technology of gasification cavity controllable development control is not deep enough, and the analysis of the effect of dynamic process parameters in the process of cavity formation is still insufficient.</description>
      <author>Yufeng Zhao, Shouxin Zhang, Yanpeng Chen, Zhen Dong, Hao Chen, Shanshan Chen, Junjie Xue, Heinz Konietzky</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56952/arma-2024-0373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Challenges in Analytical Strategies for Fruity Thiol Profiling in Beer: From Sensitivity Optimization to Ecologically Responsible Methodologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61935/acetr.3.1.2024.p204</link>
      <description>H.L. Liu, Jianghua Zhao, Delin Han, F. Deng, Advances in Computer and Engineering Technology Research. 1(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401378525

                The fruity thiols in beer, such as 3SH, 3SHA, 4MMP, and 3S4MP, constitute significant components of its volatile profile, playing a pivotal role in shaping the overall flavor alongside hydrocarbons and oxygen-containing compounds. This paper, drawing extensively on relevant literature, presents a comprehensive summary of the composition, aroma contribution, challenges in thiol detection, and advancements in analytical methods and technologies for these compounds. It outlines the limitations and attempted improvements of direct measurement approaches, the innovations and evolution of derivatization methods, and the integration of various specific sample preparation techniques (e.g., SPE, SPME, LLE, and derivatization) with modern, advanced detection equipment, accompanied by an evaluation of the precision and inclusivity of these methods. Concluding the discussion, the article offers a perspective on the future refinement of thiol determination in the brewing industry. This review aims to serve the objective of more precise beer flavor modulation.</description>
      <author>H.L. Liu, Jianghua Zhao, Delin Han, F. Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61935/acetr.3.1.2024.p204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studying on the in vivo pathological evolution of spinal cord injury with the rat model by the method of integrated multispectral imaging and Raman spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.talanta.2024.126672</link>
      <description>Yixin Lu, Zhuowen Liang, Wei Xing Zheng, Jing Liu, Rende Mu, Jiahui Chu, Jie Xu, Haishan Zeng, Zhe Wang, Shuang Wang, Talanta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401325035

                Spinal cord injury (SCI) is a debilitating neurological and pathological condition that results in significant impairments in motor, sensory, and autonomic functions. By integrating multispectral imaging (MSI) with Raman spectroscopy, a label-free optical methodology was developed for achieving a non-invasive in vivo understanding on the pathological features of SCI evolution. Under the guidance of captured the spectral imaging data cube with a rigid endoscope based MSI system, a special designed fiber probe passed through the instrumental channel for acquiring the finger-print spectral information from compression rat SCI models. After identifying the main visual features of injured spinal cord tissue in all Sham, 0-, 3- and 7-days post injury (0 DPI, 3 DPI, and 7 DPI) groups, the blood volume and oxygen content were visualized to describe hemorrhage, hypoxia and inflammatory state after acute injury. The averaged reflectance spectra, which were deduced from MSI data cubes, were utilized for describing oxygen saturation and hemoglobin concentration in living tissue. The results of Raman spectroscopy addressed complex compositional and conformational phenomena during SCI progression, correlated with the well-known event like neuronal apoptosis, hemorrhage, demyelination, and even the upregulation of chondroitin sulfate proteoglycans (CSPGs). A principal component analysis and linear discriminate algorithm (PCA-LDA) based discriminate model was introduced for categorizing spectral features in different injury stages, which was applicable for intraoperative interpretations on the complex pathological courses of SCI and therapeutic outcomes.</description>
      <author>Yixin Lu, Zhuowen Liang, Wei Xing Zheng, Jing Liu, Rende Mu, Jiahui Chu, Jie Xu, Haishan Zeng, Zhe Wang, Shuang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.talanta.2024.126672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights on the Formation Conditions of Uranus and Neptune from Their Deep Elemental Compositions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/psj/ad58d8</link>
      <description>O. Mousis, Antoine Schneeberger, T. Cavali&#233;, K. E. Mandt, Artyom Aguichine, J. I. Lunine, Tom Benest Couzinou, Vincent Hue, R. Moreno, The Planetary Science Journal. 5(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401426122

                Abstract This study, placed in the context of the preparation for the Uranus Orbiter Probe mission, aims to predict the bulk volatile compositions of Uranus and Neptune. Using a protoplanetary disk model, it examines the evolution of trace species through vapor and solid transport as dust and pebbles. Due to the high carbon abundance found in their envelopes, the two planets are postulated to have formed at the carbon monoxide ice line within the protosolar nebula. The time evolution of the abundances of the major volatile species at the location of the CO ice line is then calculated to derive the abundance ratios of the corresponding key elements, including the heavy noble gases, in the feeding zones of Uranus and Neptune. Supersolar metallicity in their envelopes likely results from accreting solids in these zones. Two types of solids are considered: pure condensates (Case 1) and a mixture of pure condensates and clathrates (Case 2). The model, calibrated to observed carbon enrichments, predicts deep compositions. In Case 1, argon is deeply depleted, while nitrogen, oxygen, krypton, phosphorus, sulfur, and xenon are significantly enriched relative to their protosolar abundances in the two planets. Case 2 predicts significant enrichments for all species, including argon, relative to their protosolar abundances. Consequently, Case 1 predicts near-zero Ar/Kr or Ar/Xe ratios, while Case 2 suggests that these ratios are 0.1 and 0.5&#8211;1 times their protosolar ratios, respectively. Both cases predict a bulk sulfur-to-nitrogen ratio consistent with atmospheric measurements.</description>
      <author>O. Mousis, Antoine Schneeberger, T. Cavali&#233;, K. E. Mandt, Artyom Aguichine, J. I. Lunine, Tom Benest Couzinou, Vincent Hue, R. Moreno</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/psj/ad58d8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mineral chemistry, petrography and crystallization conditions of the Middle Eocene Kaz&#305;kbeli Pluton (Eastern Pontides, NE T&#252;rkiye)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.19111/bulletinofmre.1529525</link>
      <description>Zikrullah Samet G&#252;lo&#287;lu, Abdullah Kaygusuz, Emre Ayd&#305;n&#231;ak&#305;r, Cem Y&#252;cel, Bulletin Of The Mineral Research and Exploration. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401401513

                The Eastern Pontides host a diverse suite of plutonic rocks spanning a wide range of ages and compositions. Among these, the Middle Eocene Kaz&#305;kbeli pluton, located in the K&#252;rt&#252;n district of G&#252;m&#252;&#351;hane, stands out due to its distinctive petrological characteristics. This study aims to unravel the petrological implications of petrographic and mineral chemical data to constrain the physicayd&#305;n&#231;ak&#305;rochemical conditions (temperature, pressure, oxygen fugacity) under which the Kaz&#305;kbeli magma crystallized and was emplaced. By integrating mineral chemical data, we seek to quantify emplacement pressure, crystallization temperature, and oxygen fugacity. A comprehensive understanding of the genetic relationships and physicochemical properties of the Kaz&#305;kbeli pluton rocks, as determined through geological, petrographic and mineral chemistry, is crucial for elucidating the geological evolution of the Eastern Pontides. The Kaz&#305;kbeli Pluton exhibits a predominant NE-SW orientation and encompasses an area of roughly 46 km&#178;. Modal mineralogical analysis reveals a compositional spectrum ranging from gabbroic diorite to monzogranite, with granodiorite and tonalite being the most prominent rock types. Textural variations encompass fine- to medium-grained, porphyritic, poikilitic, and occasionally graphic textures. The primary mineral assemblage of the pluton comprises plagioclase, orthoclase, quartz, amphibole, biotite, and Fe-Ti oxides. Accessory minerals include zircon, apatite, sphene, and allanite. Plagioclases are labradorite to oligoclase (An26 to An66) in composition. K-feldspar minerals exhibited an orthoclase composition (Or80 to Or97). All amphiboles belong to the calcic amphibole field and exhibit a magnesio-hornblende (Mg#=0.63-0.73) composition. Biotites crystallized as solidified melt products with compositions between annite and phlogopite endmembers, plotting close to the magnesium-rich (Mg#=0.52-0.58) end of the phlogopite solid solution series. Calculated crystallization temperatures derived from amphibole and biotite data range from 712&#176;C to 824&#176;C. Pressure estimations calculated using amphibole-plagioclase, amphibole and biotite suggest a range of 0.04 to 2.06 kbar. Oxygen fugacity (&#402;O2) values calculated using amphibole and biotite fall between -12.5 and -16.1. Amphibole-based water content estimations indicate a range of 3.7% to 5.7% for the pluton. Biotite compositions within the studied Kaz&#305;kbeli pluton rocks exhibit characteristics suggestive of a potential mantle origin. Geobarometric calculations based on mineral chemistry data with geological and petrographic features indicate the emplacement of the Kaz&#305;kbeli Pluton at relatively shallow depths within the crust (~1 to 8 km).</description>
      <author>Zikrullah Samet G&#252;lo&#287;lu, Abdullah Kaygusuz, Emre Ayd&#305;n&#231;ak&#305;r, Cem Y&#252;cel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.19111/bulletinofmre.1529525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concurrent Amorphization and Nanocatalyst Formation in Cu&#8208;Substituted Perovskite Oxide Surface: Effects on Oxygen Reduction Reaction at Elevated Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404103</link>
      <description>SungHyun Jeon, Wan&#8208;Gil Jung, Hohan Bae, Sejong Ahn, Bonjae Koo, Wei Yu, Seunghyun Kim, DongHwan Oh, Uisik Kim, Scott A. Barnett, Jongsu Seo, Bong&#8208;Joong Kim, WooChul Jung, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401459076

                Abstract The activity and durability of chemical/electrochemical catalysts are significantly influenced by their surface environments, highlighting the importance of thoroughly examining the catalyst surface. Here, Cu&#8208;substituted La 0.6 Sr 0.4 Co 0.2 Fe 0.8 O 3&#8208;&#948; is selected, a state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art material for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), to explore the real&#8208;time evolution of surface morphology and chemistry under a reducing atmosphere at elevated temperatures. Remarkably, in a pioneering observation, it is discovered that the perovskite surface starts to amorphize at an unusually low temperature of approximately 100 &#176;C and multicomponent metal nanocatalysts additionally form on the amorphous surface as the temperature raises to 400 &#176;C. Moreover, this investigation into the stability of the resulting amorphous layer under oxidizing conditions reveals that the amorphous structure can withstand a high&#8208;temperature oxidizing atmosphere (&#8805;650 &#176;C) only when it has undergone sufficient reduction for an extended period. Therefore, the coexistence of the active nanocatalysts and defective amorphous surface leads to a nearly 100% enhancement in the electrode resistance for the ORR over 200 h without significant degradation. These observations provide a new catalytic design strategy for using redox&#8208;dynamic perovskite oxide host materials.</description>
      <author>SungHyun Jeon, Wan&#8208;Gil Jung, Hohan Bae, Sejong Ahn, Bonjae Koo, Wei Yu, Seunghyun Kim, DongHwan Oh, Uisik Kim, Scott A. Barnett, Jongsu Seo, Bong&#8208;Joong Kim, WooChul Jung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise Synthesis of Ligand-Protected Metal Nanoclusters for Electrochemical/Photoelectrochemical Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/chemle/upae155</link>
      <description>Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Yuichi Negishi, Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401413124

                Abstract Ligand-protected metal nanoclusters (NCs) represent a significant advancement in the field of catalysis due to their unique size-specific electronic and geometric structures. These properties are highly dependent on the metal species, number of constituent atoms, and geometric structure of the metal NC. We discuss on the synthesis, stability, structural characterization, and electrocatalytic/photocatalytic applications of these fascinating materials, emphasizing their superior performance over conventional catalysts. In this study, we have obtained a deeper understanding of the interaction between the metal core and the organic ligands protecting the metal NCs, as well as the desorption behavior of the ligands under calcination, which is crucial for the application of metal NCs as heterogeneous catalysts. Based on this understanding, we have demonstrated that metal NCs-supported catalysts with appropriate pretreatment exhibit higher activity as photocatalysts compared to conventional catalysts. Moreover, by suppressing oxygen poisoning through the use of sulfur species in the ligands, Pt NCs showed high activity as cocatalysts for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution in water splitting. Additionally, atomically precised phosphine-protected Pt NCs exhibited high activity as cathode electrocatalysts for fuel cells. These findings are expected to significantly contribute to the development of more diverse catalysts based on metal NCs, including those with varying metal species, numbers of constituent atoms, and geometric structures.</description>
      <author>Tokuhisa Kawawaki, Yuichi Negishi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/chemle/upae155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wettability step electrode to generate millimeter-scale gas&#8211;liquid interface for drag reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0220158</link>
      <description>Mengzhuo Zhang, Haibao Hu, Liuzhen Ren, Jun Wen, Luo Xie, Physics of Fluids. 36(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337021

                Superhydrophobic surfaces can seal the gas&#8211;liquid interface (GLI) under water to produce the drag reduction effect. Enhancing the stability and slip length of the GLI is an important issue in this context. Herein, we fabricate wettability step electrodes (WSEs) by creating an array of millimeter-scale circular superhydrophobic regions on a hydrophilic graphite plate by using an economical and efficient mask spraying method. When the WSE was electrified as an anode, the oxygen produced by the electrolytic reaction was preferentially precipitated in the superhydrophobic regions and ultimately formed an array of millimeter-scale GLIs. The evolution process of this GLI can be divided into a spreading stage and a growth stage. The results of experiments revealed that the spreading duration of the GLI increased with the diameter of the superhydrophobic regions (D) and decreased with the spacing between adjacent superhydrophobic regions (L). During the growth stage, the height of the GLI decreased with the ratio D/(L + D) and increased over the duration of electrification according to a 1/3 power-law relationship. Finally, we measured the slip characteristic on a single millimeter-scale GLI by particle image velocimetry. The result showed that the effective slip length of the GLI with a streamwise length of 2 mm can exceed 100 &#956;m, thus confirming the potential of the millimeter-scale GLI for drag reduction.</description>
      <author>Mengzhuo Zhang, Haibao Hu, Liuzhen Ren, Jun Wen, Luo Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0220158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S&#8208;scheme MnO2/Co3O4 sugar&#8208;gourd nanohybrids with abundant oxygen vacancies for efficient visible&#8208;light&#8208;driven CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401057</link>
      <description>Linfeng Jin, Hao Yu, Chenhui Wang, Changfa Guo, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Yijun Zhong, Yong Hu, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401399360

                Converting CO2 to carbon&#8208;based fuels using solar energy via photocatalysis is a promising approach to boost carbon neutrality. However, the solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion efficiency is hampered by interconnected multiple factors including insufficient light absorption, low separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers as well as complex and sluggish surface reaction kinetics. Herein, we incorporate MnO2 nanowires and Co3O4 hollow polyhedrons with abundant oxygen vacancies (Vo) into MnO2/Co3O4 sugar&#8208;gourd nanohybrids for boosting CO2 photoreduction. The MnO2/Co3O4 nanohybrids not only display strong absorption in the visible&#8211;near infrared region, but also facilitate the separation of photogenerated carriers in terms of S&#8208;scheme transfer pathway, supplying abundant electrons for CO2 reduction reaction. Furthermore, the presence of VO enhances the separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers and promotes the chemical adsorption to CO2 molecules. In addition, the interfacial electronic interaction between MnO2 and Co3O4 also contributes to the chemical adsorption and activation to CO2. Owing to the synergy of S&#8208;scheme transfer pathway and VO, the MnO2/Co3O4 hybrids exhibit greatly enhanced photocatalytic activity towards CO2 reduction under the irradiation of visible light in comparison with bare MnO2 and Co3O4, delivering a CO evolution rate of 15.9 umol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 with a 100% selectivity.</description>
      <author>Linfeng Jin, Hao Yu, Chenhui Wang, Changfa Guo, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Yijun Zhong, Yong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PNEUMOMEDIASTINO ESPONT&#194;NEO EM REC&#201;M-NASCIDO: UM RELATO DE CASO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.69849/revistaft/ra10202408071556</link>
      <description>Ana Maria Esteves Cascabulho, Ana Paula Machado Frizzo, Carlos Henrique Carvalhal Gasparelli J&#250;nior, Caroline Andrade de S&#225;, Carone Lima Alves, Caetano Pereira, Guilherme Soares Veloso, Paula Martins Ribeiro Garcia, Rebeca dos Santos Veiga do Carmo, Wellington Luiz Rodrigues Magalh&#227;es, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401478136

                Pneumomediastinum, characterized by the presence of air in the mediastinum, is rare in newborns, especially in the spontaneous form, when it is not associated with assisted ventilation procedures or other pulmonary impairments. The diagnosis is not always obvious and immediate, which is why, in most cases, additional imaging tests are required for confirmation. Early identification of the lesion and appropriate treatment are essential, as the undue presence of air can compromise lung structures and, in the case of neonates, pneumomediastinum is associated with loculation. With the aim of elucidating the topic, the case of a full-term male newborn, born by Cesarean section at 37 weeks of gestation, was reported. Son of a healthy 26-year-old mother, the newborn's vital signs were normal and anthropometry was considered adequate. With one day of life, signs of respiratory distress were recorded, with a drop in oxygen saturation and moderate subcostal insufficiency. Chest x-rays and computed tomography were performed. Imaging examinations revealed slightly triangular hyper transparency resulting from the removal of the thymus gland by a collection of repressed air, which is known as &#8220;Spinnaker sign&#8221;, or &#8220;boat sail sign&#8221;, or even &#8220;angel wing sign&#8221;, being the main radiographic feature of pneumomediastinum. The pneumomediastinum of the patient in question proved to be too voluminous, therefore, it was decided to perform mediastinal drainage. No complications were recorded after the intervention, with the newborn's satisfactory and progressive clinical evolution.</description>
      <author>Ana Maria Esteves Cascabulho, Ana Paula Machado Frizzo, Carlos Henrique Carvalhal Gasparelli J&#250;nior, Caroline Andrade de S&#225;, Carone Lima Alves, Caetano Pereira, Guilherme Soares Veloso, Paula Martins Ribeiro Garcia, Rebeca dos Santos Veiga do Carmo, Wellington Luiz Rodrigues Magalh&#227;es</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.69849/revistaft/ra10202408071556</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excited&#8208;State Dynamics and Optical Properties of Silica Under Ultrafast Laser Irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/apxr.202400106</link>
      <description>Arshak A. Tsaturyan, Elena P. Silaeva, Razvan Stoian, Jean&#8208;Philippe Colombier, Advanced Physics Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354141

                Abstract Excited by intense infrared ultrafast light pulses, a wide bandgap material undergoes nonlinear ionization, generating a high density of free electrons in conduction states. As a result, the electronic band structure is critically modified and the bandgap shrinks. This induces rapid changes in optical properties, dramatically affecting the absorption spectrum during light coupling to the dielectric surface or during nonlinear propagation inside the bulk. This study analyzes the structural behavior and the modification of the optical properties of laser&#8208;excited silica glass at the molecular cluster level through first&#8208;principles simulations. Employing density functional theory and the GW approximations for band structure under nonequilibrium conditions, alongside the Bethe&#8211;Salpeter equation, the dynamics of the optical properties of fused silica are comprehensively explored. The behavior of excited fused silica in a wide photon energy range (from a few to 20 eV) is thus predicted. Laser&#8208;induced electron excitation triggers a redistribution of charges between oxygen and silicon atoms, accompanied by a significant increase in electronic pressure, local atomic structure rearrangement, and material expansion. Molecular dynamics simulations offer a temporal perspective on the excited state dynamics, unveiling the intricate interplay between electronic and atomic effects on bandgap evolution. The analysis sheds light on excitonic resonances, intraband and interband transitions in fused silica under ultrafast laser irradiation, providing valuable insights into its excited state behavior and optical properties.</description>
      <author>Arshak A. Tsaturyan, Elena P. Silaeva, Razvan Stoian, Jean&#8208;Philippe Colombier</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/apxr.202400106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Structure Reformulation from CuO to Cu/Cu(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Highly Efficient Nitrate Reduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202404194</link>
      <description>Jin Li, Qiuling Jiang, Xiujing Xing, Chunyan Sun, Ying Wang, Ying Wang, Wei Xiong, Hao Li, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401463627

                Abstract Electrochemical conversion of nitrate (NO 3 &#8722; ) to ammonia (NH 3 ) is a potential way to produce green NH 3 and remediate the nitrogen cycle. In this paper, an efficient catalyst of spherical CuO made by stacking small particles with oxygen&#8208;rich vacancies is reported. The NH 3 yield and Faraday efficiency are 15.53 mg h &#8722;1 mg cat &#8722;1 and 90.69%, respectively, in a neutral electrolyte at a voltage of &#8208;0.80 V (vs. reversible hydrogen electrode). The high activity of the electrodes results from changes in the phase and structure during electrochemical reduction. Structurally, there is a shift from a spherical structure with dense accumulation of small particles to a layered network structure with uniform distribution of small particles stacked on top of each other, thus exposing more active sites. Furthermore, in terms of phase, the electrode transitions from CuO to Cu/Cu(OH) 2 . Density functional theory calculations showed that Cu(OH) 2 formation enhances NO 3 &#8208; adsorption. Meanwhile, the Cu(OH) 2 can inhibit the competing hydrogen evolution reaction, while the formation of Cu (111) crystal surfaces facilitates the hydrogenation reaction. The synergistic effect between the two promotes the NO 3 &#8208; to NH 3 . Therefore, this study provides a new idea and direction for Cu&#8208;based oxides in electrocatalytic NH 3 production.</description>
      <author>Jin Li, Qiuling Jiang, Xiujing Xing, Chunyan Sun, Ying Wang, Ying Wang, Wei Xiong, Hao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202404194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Defect Engineering of Fe&#8208;MIL for Self&#8208;Enhanced Peroxidase&#8208;Like Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403354</link>
      <description>Yujia Cai, Yu Wu, Yinjun Tang, Weiqing Xu, Yifei Chen, Rina Su, Yuexi Fan, Wenxuan Jiang, Yating Wen, Wenling Gu, Hongcheng Sun, Chengzhou Zhu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333995

                Abstract Defect engineering is an effective strategy to enhance the enzyme&#8208;like activity of nanozymes. However, previous efforts have primarily focused on introducing defects via de novo synthesis and post&#8208;synthetic treatment, overlooking the dynamic evolution of defects during the catalytic process involving highly reactive oxygen species. Herein, a defect&#8208;engineered metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nanozyme with mixed linkers is reported. Over twofold peroxidase (POD)&#8208;like activity enhancement compared with unmodified nanozyme highlights the critical role of in situ defect formation in enhancing the catalytic performance of nanozyme. Experimental results reveal that highly active hydroxyl radical (&#8226;OH) generated in the catalytic process etches the 2,5&#8208;dihydroxyterephthalic acid ligands, contributing to electronic structure modulation of metal sites and enlarged pore sizes in the framework. The self&#8208;enhanced POD&#8208;like activity induced by in situ defect engineering promotes the generation of &#8226;OH, holding promise in colorimetric sensing for detecting dichlorvos. Utilizing smartphone photography for RGB value extraction, the resultant sensing platform achieves the detection for dichlorvos ranging from 5 to 300 ng mL &#8722;1 with a low detection limit of 2.06 ng mL &#8722;1 . This pioneering work in creating in situ defects in MOFs to improve catalytic activity offers a novel perspective on traditional defect engineering.</description>
      <author>Yujia Cai, Yu Wu, Yinjun Tang, Weiqing Xu, Yifei Chen, Rina Su, Yuexi Fan, Wenxuan Jiang, Yating Wen, Wenling Gu, Hongcheng Sun, Chengzhou Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Controlled Condition Ice Encasement of Creeping Bentgrass and Annual Bluegrass on Plant Recovery, Gas Evolution, and Metabolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21273/jashs05394-24</link>
      <description>Megan Gendjar, Devendra Prasad Chalise, Randolph M. Beaudry, Emily Merewitz, Journal of the American Society for Horticultural Science. 149(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333606

                Two cool-season putting green turfgrass species, annual bluegrass and creeping bentgrass, are differential in ice encasement tolerance. Physiological mechanisms associated with creeping bentgrass ice encasement tolerance and annual bluegrass susceptibility are not understood. The objectives were to evaluate oxygen, ethylene, and CO 2 content within the upper soil space of the plants while frozen and immediately after ice melt after 0, 5, 10, 20, and 28 days of ice encasement (2.54 cm of ice) in growth chamber conditions. Following ice melt, plant samples were separated into leaf, crown, and root tissues and used to evaluate carbohydrate and amino acid content. Annual bluegrass exhibited higher damage (slower recovery rates) on most sampling days compared with creeping bentgrass. The organs that were most damaged and exhibited a differential principal component analysis snapshot, were the leaf and crown tissues. Creeping bentgrass may preserve leaf and crown tissues for postwinter recovery whereas significant metabolic changes occur in annual bluegrass leaves and crowns. Creeping bentgrass retained total amino acids in leaves following ice encasement whereas total leaf amino acid levels declined in annual bluegrass. Specific carbohydrates and amino acids such as the ability to maintain high levels of fructose, asparagine, and proline may be important indicators of the tolerance to ice encasement stress. On the basis of more prominent carbohydrate and amino acid loss in leaves and crowns and higher levels of CO 2 evolution, annual bluegrass may exhibit a higher metabolism and/or tissue damage during ice encasement compared with creeping bentgrass, which could reduce spring recuperative potential.</description>
      <author>Megan Gendjar, Devendra Prasad Chalise, Randolph M. Beaudry, Emily Merewitz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21273/jashs05394-24</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tourmaline triggered biofilm transformation: Boosting ultrafiltration efficiency and fouling resistance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.122212</link>
      <description>Dan Song, Lu Wang, Wing&#8208;Fung Sun, Yingjie Zhang, Binghan Xie, Paul K. Chu, Wei Wang, Peizhi Wang, Panpan Wang, Wei Cheng, Water Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401345122

                Ultralow pressure filtration system, which integrates the dual functionalities of biofilm degradation and membrane filtration, has gained significant attention in water treatment due to its superior contaminant removal efficiency. However, it is a challenge to mitigate membrane biofouling while maintaining the high activity of biofilm. This study presents a novel ceramic-based ultrafiltration membrane functionalized with tourmaline nanoparticles to address this challenge. The incorporation of tourmaline nanoparticles enables the release of nutrient elements and the generation of an electric field, which enhances the biofilm activity on the membrane surface and simultaneously alleviates intrapore biofouling. The tourmaline-modified ceramic membrane (TCM) demonstrated a significant antifouling effect, with a substantial increase in water flux by 60%. Additionally, the TCM achieved high removal efficiencies for contaminants (48.78% in TOC, 22.28% in UV254, and 24.42% in TN) after 30 days of continuous operation. The fouling resistance by various constituents in natural water was individually analyzed using model compounds. The TCM with improved electronegativity and hydrophilicity exhibited superior resistance to irreversible fouling through increased electrostatic repulsion and reduced adhesion to foulants. Comprehensive characterizations and analyses, including interfacial interaction energies, redox reaction processes, and biofilm evolutions, demonstrated that the TCM can release nutrient elements to facilitate the development of functional microbial community within the biofilm, and generate reactive oxygen species (ROS) on the membrane surface to the degrade contaminants and mitigate membrane biofouling. The electric field generated by tourmaline nanoparticles can promote electron transfer in the Fe(III)/Fe(II) cycle, ensuring a stable and sustainable generation of ROS and bactericidal negative ions. These synergistic functions enhance contaminant removal and reduce irreversible fouling of the TCM. This study provides fundamental insights into the role of tourmaline-modified surfaces in enhancing membrane filtration performance and fouling resistance, inspiring the development of high-performance, anti-fouling membranes.</description>
      <author>Dan Song, Lu Wang, Wing&#8208;Fung Sun, Yingjie Zhang, Binghan Xie, Paul K. Chu, Wei Wang, Peizhi Wang, Panpan Wang, Wei Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.watres.2024.122212</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Damage evolution characteristics of siliceous slate with varying initial water content during freeze-thaw cycles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175200</link>
      <description>Zhiquan Yang, Qinghao Zhao, J. Gan, Shouxin Zhang, Chen Mao, Yingyan Zhu, The Science of The Total Environment. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401372012

                Comprehensive studies on the freeze-thaw (F-T) damage mechanism in siliceous slates are lacking. In this study, we investigated the evolutionary characteristics of F-T damage in siliceous slates. To this end, scanning electron microscopy, X-ray diffraction, X-ray fluorescence, and uniaxial compression tests were used to analyze the microstructure, phase composition, porosity, and macroscopic mechanical parameters of siliceous slate with varying initial water content during F-T cycles. The results revealed several insights. (1) The microstructure of siliceous slate undergoes significant change with respect to increasing water content and number of F-T cycles. The rock surface changed from smooth to rough, and the arrangement of the mineral particles changed from tight to loose. (2) More than 80 % of the contents of siliceous slate comprise oxygen, aluminum, silicon, potassium, and iron. In particular, siliceous slate comprises muscovite, quartz, clinochlore, and kaolinite. Both the clinochlore and kaolinite are unstable clay minerals. As clay minerals exhibit strong water absorption and expansion characteristics, kaolinite undergoes strong hydration reactions. Compared to rock samples without F-T cycles in the dry state, the clay mineral content of siliceous slate decreased by nearly 50 %, from 28.8 % to 15.5 %, after 30 F-T cycles in the saturated state. (3) The mechanical parameters of siliceous slates with varying water content decreased exponentially with the number of F-T cycles, while their porosity exhibited a positive correlation with the number of F-T cycles. The degree of deterioration in both increased with increasing water content. Both the number of F-T cycles and the initial water content were observed to wield a significant effect on the deterioration of siliceous slates. (4) The evolution curve of F-T load damage in siliceous slate exhibited characteristics of transitioning from gentle to concave and then to a convex stage of growth. Our results are expected to provide theoretical guidance for the evaluation and prevention of F-T disasters in cold regions.</description>
      <author>Zhiquan Yang, Qinghao Zhao, J. Gan, Shouxin Zhang, Chen Mao, Yingyan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2024.175200</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
