<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 01:20:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>High-performance Porous 3D Ni Skeleton Electrodes for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.10.113</link>
      <description>Somayyeh Abbasi, Bruno Guerreiro, Mohsen Fakourihassanabadi, Natalie Herkendaal, Victor Vanpeene, Manuel H. Martin, Julie Gaudet, Lionel Rou&#233;, Steven J. Thorpe, Daniel Guay, Journal of Materials Research and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403445542

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Somayyeh Abbasi, Bruno Guerreiro, Mohsen Fakourihassanabadi, Natalie Herkendaal, Victor Vanpeene, Manuel H. Martin, Julie Gaudet, Lionel Rou&#233;, Steven J. Thorpe, Daniel Guay</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmrt.2024.10.113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing advanced oxygen electrodes for reversible protonic ceramic electrochemical cells via controlled bismuth doping on diverse perovskite lattice positions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156758</link>
      <description>Yushi Feng, Peng Su, Xiangcun Li, Xu Sun, Bin Zhang, Qian Duan, Jingwei Li, Yu Shen, Fang Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403448381

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yushi Feng, Peng Su, Xiangcun Li, Xu Sun, Bin Zhang, Qian Duan, Jingwei Li, Yu Shen, Fang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design of Ceo2 Anchored in Cofe-Layered Double Hydroxide Hollow Polyhedra Via an Ion Exchange Strategy for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4989631</link>
      <description>Yibing Chen, Ningzhao Shang, Tingyu Zhang, Li Wang, Yufan Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403451555

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yibing Chen, Ningzhao Shang, Tingyu Zhang, Li Wang, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4989631</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Tuning of Heterovalent States and Oxygen-Vacancy Defect Engineering in Hydrophilic W-Doped Sb&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;OS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced Nitrogen Photoreduction to Ammonia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16630</link>
      <description>Binghong Wu, Baoqian Yang, Xinru Wu, Dong&#8208;Hau Kuo, Zhengjie Su, Longyan Chen, Pengkun Zhang, Mengistu Tadesse Mosisa, Dongfang Lu, Zhanhui Yuan, Jinguo Lin, Xiaoyun Chen, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403456843

                Nitrogen fixation reaction via photocatalysis offers a green and promising strategy for renewable NH</description>
      <author>Binghong Wu, Baoqian Yang, Xinru Wu, Dong&#8208;Hau Kuo, Zhengjie Su, Longyan Chen, Pengkun Zhang, Mengistu Tadesse Mosisa, Dongfang Lu, Zhanhui Yuan, Jinguo Lin, Xiaoyun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c16630</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur doping and oxygen vacancy in In2O3 nanotube co-regulate intermediates of CO2 electroreduction for efficient HCOOH production and rechargeable Zn-CO2 battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.09.057</link>
      <description>Yang Yang, Zhengrong Xu, Quanxin Guo, Qin Li, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457556

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yang Yang, Zhengrong Xu, Quanxin Guo, Qin Li, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.09.057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Regulation of a Multi&#8208;Component Co2P2O7&#8208;MoN/NC Electrocatalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403235</link>
      <description>Man Jin, Yan Zou, Bo&#8208;Cong Shi, Yujia Tang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Li Liu, Dongsheng Geng, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403463007

                Realizing efficient and durable non&#8208;precious metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) still remains a great challenge. Here, a multi&#8208;component composite of Co2P2O7&#8208;MoN/NC containing pyrophosphate, nitride, and nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon is successfully prepared via a facile two&#8208;step synthesis method. Combining the structural regulation between the active metal&#8208; and non&#8208;metal&#8208;based species, Co2P2O7&#8208;MoN/NC demonstrates superior activity and durability for OER, requiring an overpotential of 278 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a Tafel slope of 83.3 mV dec&#8722;1, and long&#8208;term stability over 100 h in an alkaline solution. Post&#8208;characterizations reveal that synergistic effect among stable Co2P2O7, partially dissolved MoN, N&#8208;doped carbon, and new&#8208;formed CoOOH nanosheets enable structural reconstruction, fast charge transfer, and formation of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates, promoting the OER performance significantly. This work provides a promising pathway to tune multi&#8208;components to fabricate efficient transition&#8208;metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts in energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Man Jin, Yan Zou, Bo&#8208;Cong Shi, Yujia Tang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Li Liu, Dongsheng Geng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited Manganese Dioxides and Their Composites as Electrocatalysts for Energy Conversion Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401907</link>
      <description>Masaharu Nakayama, Wataru Yoshida, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403463183

                Enhancing the efficiencies of electrochemical reactions for converting renewable energy into clean chemical fuels as well as generating clean energy is critical to achieving carbon neutrality. However, this enhancement can be achieved using materials that are not constrained by resource limitations and those that can be converted into devices in a scalable manner, preferably for industrial applications. This review explores the applications of electrochemically deposited manganese dioxides (MnO2) and their composites as electrochemical catalysts for oxygen evolution (OER) and hydrogen evolution reactions for converting renewable energy into chemical fuels. It also explores their applications as electrochemical catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and bifunctional OER/ORR for the efficient operation of fuel cells and metal&#8211;air batteries, respectively. Manganese is the second most abundant transition metal in the Earth&#8217;s crust, and electrodeposition represents a binder&#8208;free and scalable technique for fabricating devices (electrodes). To propose an improved catalyst design, the studies on the electrodeposition mechanism of MnO2 as well as the fabrication techniques for MnO2&#8208;based nanocomposites accumulated in the development of electrodes for supercapacitors are also included in this review.</description>
      <author>Masaharu Nakayama, Wataru Yoshida</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Plasma Triggered Co&#8208;O&#8208;Fe Motif in Prussian Blue Analogue for Efficient and Robust Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415423</link>
      <description>Hao Xu, Chen Zhu, Hao Lin, Ji Kai Liu, Yi Xiao Wu, Huai Qin Fu, Xinyu Zhang, Fangxin Mao, Hai Yang Yuan, Chenghua Sun, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403463314

                In the context of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the construction of high&#8208;valent transition metal sites to trigger the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism is considered crucial for overcoming the performance limitations of traditional adsorbate evolution mechanism. However, the dynamic evolution of lattice oxygen during the reaction poses significant challenges for the stability of high&#8208;valent metal sites, particularly in high&#8208;current&#8208;density water&#8208;splitting systems. Here, we have successfully constructed Co&#8208;O&#8208;Fe catalytic active motifs in cobalt&#8208;iron Prussian blue analogs (CoFe&#8208;PBA) through oxygen plasma bombardment, effectively activating lattice oxygen reactivity while sustaining robust stability. Our spectroscopic and theoretical studies reveal that the Co&#8208;O&#8208;Fe bridged motifs enable a unique double&#8208;exchange interaction between Co and Fe atoms, promoting the formation of high&#8208;valent Co species as OER active centers while maintaining Fe in a low&#8208;valent state, preventing its dissolution. The resultant catalyst (CoFe&#8208;PBA&#8208;30) requires an overpotential of only 276 mV to achieve 1000 mA cm&#8208;2. Furthermore, the assembled alkaline exchange membrane electrolyzer using CoFe&#8208;PBA&#8208;30 as anode material achieves a high current density of 1 A cm&#8208;2 at 1.76 V and continuously operates for 250 hours with negligible degradation. This work provides significant insights for activating lattice oxygen redox without compromising structure stability in practical water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Hao Xu, Chen Zhu, Hao Lin, Ji Kai Liu, Yi Xiao Wu, Huai Qin Fu, Xinyu Zhang, Fangxin Mao, Hai Yang Yuan, Chenghua Sun, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of FeNi alloy foams at high oxygen evolution reaction rates using a dry anode setup in alkaline environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-np6gc</link>
      <description>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403465506

                We investigated the composition-activity relationship of porous FeNi alloy foams for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We compared conventional transient behavior using cyclic voltammetry with the performance at high geometric current densities up to 3.0 A cm-2 achieved at quasi steady-state conditions employing pulsed electrolysis. The experiments were performed under setup parameters, we introduce as dry anode conditions for anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolyzers. In this context, a dry anode refers to an electrode setup in which the catalyst is not directly submerged in a liquid medium, unlike conventional electrodes fed with an alkaline electrolyte. Instead, the anode is purged with humidified gas. Eleven different compositions in the FeNi alloy space (93 &#8211; 2 at. % Fe) were synthesized using the hydrogen bubble template method, resulting in porous foams with similar structures. A rigorous statistical analysis of all measured data was conducted to ensure reproducibility. The influence of bubble formation on the solution resistance is elucidated and, consequently, the apparent performance is assessed. The most efficient alloy composition required an averaged mean potential of 1.82 VRHE for 3 A cm-2 under quasi steady-state conditions.</description>
      <author>Etienne Berner, Gustav K. H. Wiberg, Matthias Arenz</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-np6gc</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiO/ATO as an efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution and urea oxidation reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113315</link>
      <description>T.V.M. Sreekanth, B. Naresh, K. Prasad, J. Kim, K. Yoo, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403466327

                No abstract</description>
      <author>T.V.M. Sreekanth, B. Naresh, K. Prasad, J. Kim, K. Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe/Ce Co-Doped Ni2p Catalyst to Enhance Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4989288</link>
      <description>Luo Zhao, Li Wang, Ruijie Shi, Hao Xu, Zixuan Zeng, Xiaomin Lang, Yi Huang, Yuping Liu, Xiaoqin Liao, Mingxia Nie, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403466520

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luo Zhao, Li Wang, Ruijie Shi, Hao Xu, Zixuan Zeng, Xiaomin Lang, Yi Huang, Yuping Liu, Xiaoqin Liao, Mingxia Nie</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4989288</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synchronous Interlayer and surface engineering of NiFe layered double hydroxides by functional ligands for boosting oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145231</link>
      <description>Kuang Chang, Xue Bai, Jiangyong Liu, Jing Wang, Xiaodong Yan, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403467476

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kuang Chang, Xue Bai, Jiangyong Liu, Jing Wang, Xiaodong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxyanions Enhancing Crystallinity of Reconstructed Phase for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415132</link>
      <description>Wenbin Wang, Qunlei Wen, Danji Huang, Lin Yu, Nian-Dan Zhao, Lan Tang, Ming Li, Youwen Liu, Rongxing He, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403471004

                The catalysts were always undergoing continuous amorphization and dissolution of active structure in operating condition, hindering the compatibility between stability and activity for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we propose the selective adsorption of leached NO3&#8208; to strengthen the crystallinity and activity of surface reconstructed layer with amorphous and crystalline (a&#8208;c) heterojunction. Taking a&#8208;c Ni doped Fe2O(OH)3NO3&#183;H2O (Ni&#8208;FeNH) as a model precatalyst, we uncover that the leached NO3&#8208; are readily adsorbs on the crystalline phase in the formed a&#8208;c Fe(Ni)OOH during OER, lowering the disorder degree and further activating Ni and Fe ion of the crystalline Fe(Ni)OOH on a&#8208;c heterojunctions. Accordingly, Ni&#8208;FeNH deliver a low overpotential of 303 mV and high durability of 500 hours at 500 mA cm&#8208;2 for OER. Particularly, constructing industrial water electrolysis equipment exhibits high stability of 100 hours under a high operating current of 8000 mA.</description>
      <author>Wenbin Wang, Qunlei Wen, Danji Huang, Lin Yu, Nian-Dan Zhao, Lan Tang, Ming Li, Youwen Liu, Rongxing He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fleeting-Active-Site-Thrust Oxygen Evolution Reaction by Iron Cations from the Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09585</link>
      <description>Zeyu Wang, Hai Xiao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403471736

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is key to sustainable energy and environmental engineering, thus necessitating rational design of high-performing electrocatalysts that requires understanding the structure-performance relationship with a possible dynamic nature under working conditions. Herein, we uncover a novel type of OER mechanisms thrust by the fleeting active sites (FASs) dynamically formed on Ni-based layered double hydroxides (Ni-LDHs) by Fe cations from the electrolyte under OER potentials. We employ grand-canonical ensemble methods and microkinetic modeling to elucidate the potential-dependent structures of FASs on Ni-LDHs and demonstrate that the fleeting-active-site-thrust (FAST) mechanism delivers superior OER activity via the FAST intramolecular oxygen coupling pathway, which also suppresses the lattice oxygen mechanism, leading to improved operando stability of Ni-LDHs. We further reveal that introducing only trace-level loadings (10-100 ppm) of FASs on Ni-LDHs can significantly boost and govern the catalytic performance for OER. This underscores the crucial importance of considering the novel FAST mechanism in OER and also suggests the electrolyte as a key part of the structure-performance relationship as well as an effective design strategy via engineering the electrolyte.</description>
      <author>Zeyu Wang, Hai Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c09585</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Fluid Dynamics Modelling of Hydrogen Production via Water Splitting in Oxygen Membrane Reactors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/membranes14100219</link>
      <description>Kai Bittner, Nikolaos Margaritis, Falk Schulze&#8208;K&#252;ppers, J. Wolters, Ghaleb Natour, Membranes. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403478574

                The utilization of oxygen transport membranes enables the production of high-purity hydrogen by the thermal decomposition of water below 1000 &#176;C. This process is based on a chemical potential gradient across the membrane, which is usually achieved by introducing a reducing gas. Computational fluid dynamics (CFD) can be used to model reactors based on this concept. In this study, a modelling approach for water splitting is presented in which oxygen transport through the membrane acts as the rate-determining process for the overall reaction. This transport step is implemented in the CFD simulation. Both gas compartments are modelled in the simulations. Hydrogen and methane are used as reducing gases. The model is validated using experimental data from the literature and compared with a simplified perfect mixing modelling approach. Although the main focus of this work is to propose an approach to implement the water splitting in CFD simulations, a simulation study was conducted to exemplify how CFD modelling can be utilized in design optimization. Simplified 2-dimensional and rotational symmetric reactor geometries were compared. This study shows that a parallel overflow of the membrane in an elongated reactor is advantageous, as this reduces the back diffusion of the reaction products, which increases the mean driving force for oxygen transport through the membrane.</description>
      <author>Kai Bittner, Nikolaos Margaritis, Falk Schulze&#8208;K&#252;ppers, J. Wolters, Ghaleb Natour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/membranes14100219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hard X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy Probing Fe Segregation during the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11902</link>
      <description>Filippo Longo, P.J. Lloreda-Jurado, Jorge Gil&#8208;Rostra, Agust&#305;&#769;n R. Gonz&#225;lez-Elipe, F. Yubero, Sabrina L. J. Thom&#228;, A. Neels, Andreas Borgschulte, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403480328

                NiFe electrocatalysts are among the most active phases for water splitting with regard to the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The interplay between Ni and Fe, both at the surface and in the subsurface of the catalyst, is crucial to understanding such outstanding properties and remains a subject of debate. Various phenomena, ranging from the formation of oxides/(oxy)hydroxides to the associated segregation of certain species, occur during the electrochemical reactions and add another dimension of complexity that hinders the rational design of electrodes for water splitting. In this work, we have developed the procedure for the quantification of chemical depth profiling by XPS/HAXPES measurements and applied it to two NiFe electrodes with different porosities. The main outcome of this study is related to the surface reconstruction of the electrodes during the OER, followed at two different depths by means of X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. We find that Fe initially segregates at the surface when exposed to ambient conditions, resulting in the formation of an inactive FeO</description>
      <author>Filippo Longo, P.J. Lloreda-Jurado, Jorge Gil&#8208;Rostra, Agust&#305;&#769;n R. Gonz&#225;lez-Elipe, F. Yubero, Sabrina L. J. Thom&#228;, A. Neels, Andreas Borgschulte</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11902</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis of Oxygen Evolution Reaction Promoted by CoNiMn Films Synthesized by Electrodeposition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c05057</link>
      <description>Ana Lu&#237;sa Silva, Marcos V. Cola&#231;o, Liying Liu, Yutao Xing, Nak&#233;dia M. F. Carvalho, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403485549

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ana Lu&#237;sa Silva, Marcos V. Cola&#231;o, Liying Liu, Yutao Xing, Nak&#233;dia M. F. Carvalho</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c05057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/Se-CNTs as Advanced Metal-Free Catalysts for the Photoassisted Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11777</link>
      <description>Tingting Du, Ling Bai, Hao Cui, Yidan Gao, Shijie Jia, Xin Zhang, Fengchun Yang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403494164

                Photoassisted electrocatalysis is a frontier direction of electrocatalysis for promoting energy conversion. In this work, a metal-free C</description>
      <author>Tingting Du, Ling Bai, Hao Cui, Yidan Gao, Shijie Jia, Xin Zhang, Fengchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of preparation and oxygen evolution catalysis on CoNiFe oxide electrocatalysts revealed by STEM-EELS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412925036</link>
      <description>Nils Rockstroh, Trang Pham, Carsten Kreyenschulte, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke, BIO Web of Conferences. 129(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403496117

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nils Rockstroh, Trang Pham, Carsten Kreyenschulte, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/bioconf/202412925036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Ni Doping on the Catalytic Activity and Stability of Ruo2 Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4991349</link>
      <description>Hyunwoo Jang, Seungwon Shim, Youngho Kang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403504426

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hyunwoo Jang, Seungwon Shim, Youngho Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4991349</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward Finding the Role of Surface Iron Ions in Enhancing Oxygen-Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03779</link>
      <description>Mohammad Khateri, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403508760

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media is crucial for energy conversion technologies, and Fe-based catalysts have garnered significant attention for their efficacy. In this study, we provide an investigation of Fe-based catalysts under OER conditions using some techniques. Our findings reveal minimal structural alterations in the bulk FeH</description>
      <author>Mohammad Khateri, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly efficient bimetallic counter cations-based tungsten bronzes electrocatalysts developed for sustainable oxygen evolution in acidic solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.105</link>
      <description>Akash Pandit, Md. Mominul Islam, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 91(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403515322

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Akash Pandit, Md. Mominul Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double-Shell Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; with Rich Surface Octahedron Oxygen Vacancies for High-Selectivity Electrocatalytic Chlorine Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10031</link>
      <description>Ying Deng, Qian Zhang, Qiuyue Liang, Jingyu Gao, Wenna Wang, Zexing Wu, Yujing Zhu, Zhenyu Xiao, Lei Wang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403520756

                The development of non-noble-metal-based chlorine evolution reaction (CER) catalysts with excellent activity, kinetics, and selectivity is urgently needed but still remains a major challenge. In this study, a morphology self-evolving and surface octahedron oxygen-vacancy-generating strategy is applied at double-shell nanospheres to obtain the target hierarchical double-shell Co</description>
      <author>Ying Deng, Qian Zhang, Qiuyue Liang, Jingyu Gao, Wenna Wang, Zexing Wu, Yujing Zhu, Zhenyu Xiao, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe2O4 with the In&#8208;Situ Formed Oxygen Vacancies and Co Particles as an Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403229</link>
      <description>Ren Z, Sujie Jiang, Keke Su, Wenfeng Liu, Fuquan Niu, Zhenpu Shi, Zhansheng Lu, Yuantao Cui, Shuting Yang, Yanhong Yin, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403538257

                Rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries (RZABs) are considered as one of the most promising clean energy device due to their abundant resources, low cost and environmental friendliness. However, their energy efficiency and cycle life are far from satisfactory due to the poor activity and stability of bi&#8208;functional electrocatalyst in air cathode. In this work, an efficient bi&#8208;functional catalyst (rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4/Co) was derived from its precursor (rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4) through a simple annealing process. Electrochemical measurements prove that rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4/Co with the in&#8208;situ formed Co nano particles and rich oxygen vacancies appears excellent oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction catalytic activity compared to its counterpart. Its half&#8208;wave potential is 0.81 V (vs RHE) and the OER overpotential is only 310 mV (vs RHE). In addition, rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries assembled with rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4/Co show the highest peak power density (128.9 mW cm&#8208;2) and cycling stability compared to rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4 and commercial Pt/C&#8208;RuO2 catalysts. This work provides a simple strategy for the design of advanced bifunctional catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ren Z, Sujie Jiang, Keke Su, Wenfeng Liu, Fuquan Niu, Zhenpu Shi, Zhansheng Lu, Yuantao Cui, Shuting Yang, Yanhong Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential oxygen evolution and decoupled water splitting via electrochemical redox reaction of nickel hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53310-5</link>
      <description>Jie Wei, Yangfan Shao, Jingbo Xu, Fang Yin, Zejian Li, Haitao Qian, Yinping Wei, Liang Chang, Yu Han, Jia Li, Lin Gan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403540533

                Alkaline water electrolysis is a promising low-cost strategy for clean and sustainable hydrogen production but is largely limited by the sluggish anodic oxygen evolution reaction and the challenges in maintaining adequate separation between H2 and O2. Here, we reveal an anodic-cathodic sequential oxygen evolution process via electrochemical oxidation and subsequent reduction of Ni hydroxides, enabling much lower overpotentials than conventional anodic oxygen evolution. By using (isotope-labeled) differential electrochemical mass spectrometry and in situ Raman spectroscopy combined with density functional theory calculations, we evidence that the sequential oxygen evolution originates from the electrochemical oxidation of Ni hydroxides to NiOO&#8211; active species while undergoing a different, reductive step of NiOO&#8211; for the final release of O2 due to weakened Ni&#8211;O covalency. Based on this sequential process, we propose and demonstrate a hybrid water electrolysis and energy storage device, which enables time-decoupled hydrogen and oxygen evolution and electrochemical energy storage in the Ni hydroxides. The authors report a sequential oxygen evolution process via electrochemical oxidation and reduction of Ni hydroxides, allowing for decoupled oxygen evolution and hydrogen evolution during water splitting and energy storage in the Ni hydroxides.</description>
      <author>Jie Wei, Yangfan Shao, Jingbo Xu, Fang Yin, Zejian Li, Haitao Qian, Yinping Wei, Liang Chang, Yu Han, Jia Li, Lin Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53310-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Charge Transfer Modulation in Laser-Synthesized Catalysts for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06794k</link>
      <description>Dong Soo Lee, R. D. Kerkar, Deepak Arumugam, Theerthagiri Jayaraman, R. Shankar, Soorathep Kheawhom, Myong Yong Choi, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403542497

                Advancements in laser-based material development have enabled precise engineering of catalysts, thus promoting efficient and sustainable water-splitting reactions. This study presents a green approach for synthesizing a layered double hydroxide...</description>
      <author>Dong Soo Lee, R. D. Kerkar, Deepak Arumugam, Theerthagiri Jayaraman, R. Shankar, Soorathep Kheawhom, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06794k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational construction of N-containing carbon sheets atomically doped NiP-CoP nanohybrid electrocatalysts for enhanced green hydrogen and oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145236</link>
      <description>Adewale K. Ipadeola, Mostafa H. Sliem, Patrick V. Mwonga, Kenneth I. Ozoemena, Aboubakr M. Abdullah, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403548371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adewale K. Ipadeola, Mostafa H. Sliem, Patrick V. Mwonga, Kenneth I. Ozoemena, Aboubakr M. Abdullah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo&#8208;doped &#945;&#8208;MnO2 for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401553</link>
      <description>Ying Chen, Shujiao Yang, Ting Wang, Sisi Li, Xiaohan Liu, Jing Wang, Rui Cao, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403548549

                Manganese is a key metal involved in the catalysis of natural photosynthesis. Thus, the investigation of Mn&#8208;based electrocatalysts for water oxidation is of high importance. This work reports the doping of Mo into &#945;&#8208;MnO2 nanorods to improve the water oxidation performance. The doping of Mo can transform the microstructure of &#945;&#8208;MnO2 from nanorods into nanosphere superstructures. As a dopant, Mo expands the &#945;&#8208;MnO2 lattice to result in a decrease in the average oxidation state of Mn and the generation of oxygen vacancies, which are beneficial to water oxidation catalysis. Under optimized doping, the OER overpotential of Mo/&#945;&#8208;MnO2 is reduced by 80 mV (at 10 mA/cm2) compared with pure &#945;&#8208;MnO2.</description>
      <author>Ying Chen, Shujiao Yang, Ting Wang, Sisi Li, Xiaohan Liu, Jing Wang, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ synthesis of FeNi3/(Fe,Ni)9S8/Ni4S3/C nanorods and enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.193.1333</link>
      <description>Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, S. J. Zhong, J. H. Chen, Mengyang Li, Yele Sun, Digest Journal of Nanomaterials and Biostructures. 19(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403549377

                NiFe-based nanomaterials have emerged as highly promising catalysts to replace platinum, ruthenium and iridium for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), in &#8220;green hydrogen&#8221; production process through water splitting. Using iron (2+) sulfate and nickel acetate as the raw materials, with the molar ratio of Ni acetate to iron (2+) sulfate controlled at 8:5, the concentration of metal-ion was 0.6 mol/L, and precursor fibers rich in Ni2+, Fe2+, and SO4 2&#8722; were prepared using electrospinning technology, with polyvinyl alcohol acting as the colloid. Subsequently, composite nanorods rich in the elements of Ni, Fe, S, and C were successfully obtained at a heat treatment temperature of 1000&#176;C in an Ar gas atmosphere. The results demonstrate that the nanorod samples possessed a surface diameter of ~200 nm, and the main phases of the nanorods after heat treatment at 1000&#176;C included FeNi3 alloy, (Fe,Ni)9S8, Ni4S3, and amorphous C. Electrochemical performance tests conducted in a 1.0 mol/L KOH solution exhibited excellent oxygen evolution reaction properties of the catalysts prepared using FeNi3/(Fe,Ni)9S8/Ni4S3/C nanorods as the materials. The overpotential was about 258.6 mV of the catalyst material at 10 mA&#61589;cm&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, S. J. Zhong, J. H. Chen, Mengyang Li, Yele Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.193.1333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active learning accelerated exploration of single-atom local environments in multimetallic systems for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01432-1</link>
      <description>Hoje Chun, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jeung Ku Kang, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Byungchan Han, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403560061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hoje Chun, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jeung Ku Kang, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Byungchan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01432-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycling spent battery components into highly efficient hydrogen and oxygen evolution electro-nano-catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145268</link>
      <description>Basel A. Samy, Zaheer Khan, Shaeel A. Al&#8208;Thabaiti, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403574615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Basel A. Samy, Zaheer Khan, Shaeel A. Al&#8208;Thabaiti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145268</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Cocatalytic Sites Synergize NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402046</link>
      <description>Yue Shi, Lumin Song, Yan Liu, Tiantian Wang, Caixia Li, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403584566

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;iron layered double hydroxide (LDH) is a promising cost&#8208;efficient catalyst to replace noble metals for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER), yet its intrinsic activity under high current density conditions is not satisfactory, which greatly constrains the industrial application of NiFe LDH catalysts. Herein, a new class of integrated Co and W co&#8208;doped NiFe LDH catalysts is reported with dual cocatalytic sites for alkaline OER catalysis. The optimized Co 2.8 , W 3.8 &#8208;NiFe LDH integrated catalyst has superior alkaline OER activity (255 mV@1000 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and excellent catalytic stability (200 h@500 mA cm &#8722;2 ). The turnover frequency value of Co 2.8 , W 3.8 &#8208;NiFe LDH can reach 4.02 s &#8722;1 at 1.49 V versus RHE, which is 9.6 times higher than that of NiFe LDH and superior to the noble metal catalysts. Moreover, it can achieve 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.86 V and maintain 300&#8208;h stable operation in anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Theoretical and experimental studies indicate that W sites promote the *OH adsorption and Co sites favor protons desorption of OH*. These dual cocatalytic sites jointly promote *O coverage, effectively accelerating alkaline OER kinetic.</description>
      <author>Yue Shi, Lumin Song, Yan Liu, Tiantian Wang, Caixia Li, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural, magnetic and electrocatalytic properties of rock salt oxide nanofibers (Ni0.2Mg0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2-xCo0.2+x)O produced by air-heated solution blow spinning (A-HSBS) for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161593</link>
      <description>Ronaldo M. Oliveira Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Mederios, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403590066

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ronaldo M. Oliveira Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Mederios, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile fabrication of nickel selenide with manganese telluride (NiSe/MnTe) nanocomposite employed as strong electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00433-6</link>
      <description>Nirma Rasool, Haifa A. Alyousef, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Basel Al-Otaibi, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Khursheed Ahmad, Journal of the Korean Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403596747

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nirma Rasool, Haifa A. Alyousef, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Basel Al-Otaibi, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Khursheed Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00433-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-coordinated cobalt single atom Steered by Doped-O and CoO for efficient hydrogen evolution at industrial current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156990</link>
      <description>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Ruyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Peng Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Ruyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Peng Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D -Band Center Theory-Guided Mixed Metal Oxide-Based Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Ultra-Stable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994483</link>
      <description>Weipeng Zhao, Qicheng Zhang, P. W. Zhao, Bin Chen, Yang Li, Wenchao Peng, Xiaobin Fan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weipeng Zhao, Qicheng Zhang, P. W. Zhao, Bin Chen, Yang Li, Wenchao Peng, Xiaobin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomass-Derived-Carbon-Supported Spinel Cobalt Molybdate as High-Efficiency Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29204953</link>
      <description>Baoli Wang, Xiujiu Yang, Yan Chen, Jiahan Wang, Mingguo Lan, Kai Tang, Feng Yang, Molecules. 29(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403603383

                Ananas comosus leaves were converted to a porous graphitized carbon (GPLC) material via a high-temperature pyrolysis method by employing iron salt as a catalyst. A cobalt molybdate (CoMoO4)-and-GPLC composite (CoMoO4/GPLC) was then prepared by engineering CoMoO4 nanorods in situ, grown on GPLC. N2 adsorption&#8211;desorption isothermal curves and a pore size distribution curve verify that the proposed composite possesses a porous structure and a large specific surface area, which are favorable for charge and reactant transport and the rapid escape of O2 bubbles. Consequently, the as-synthesized CoMoO4/GPLC shows low overpotentials of 289 mV and 399 mV to afford the current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2 towards the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is superior to many CoMoO4-based catalysts in previous studies. In addition, the decrease in current density is particularly small, with a reduction rate of 3.2% after a continuous OER procedure for 30 h, indicating its good stability. The excellent performance of the CoMoO4/GPLC composite proves that the GPLC carrier can obviously impel the catalytic activity of CoMoO4 by improving electrical conductivity, enhancing mass transport and exposing more active sites of the composite. This work provides an effective strategy for the efficient conversion of waste ananas comosus leaves to a biomass-derived-carbon-supported Co-Mo-based OER electrocatalyst with good performance, which may represent a potential approach to the development of new catalysts for OER, as well as the treatment of waste biomass.</description>
      <author>Baoli Wang, Xiujiu Yang, Yan Chen, Jiahan Wang, Mingguo Lan, Kai Tang, Feng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29204953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasmall RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles with robust interfacial interactions for the enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00719k</link>
      <description>Ming Wei, Liuhua Mu, Zhi&#8208;Wei Liu, Feng Gao, Guangjian Song, Qiankang Si, Mao Zhang, Fangfang Dai, Min Zhang, Rui Ding, Li Yang, Zhonggui Gao, Sanzhao Song, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403606874

                Ultrasmall RuO 2 /CoFe 2 O 4 nanoparticles with strong interfacial interactions exhibit enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, driven by efficient charge transfer between RuO 2 and CoFe 2 O 4 .</description>
      <author>Ming Wei, Liuhua Mu, Zhi&#8208;Wei Liu, Feng Gao, Guangjian Song, Qiankang Si, Mao Zhang, Fangfang Dai, Min Zhang, Rui Ding, Li Yang, Zhonggui Gao, Sanzhao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00719k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Out-of-plane coordination of iridium single atoms with organic molecules and cobalt&#8211;iron hydroxides to boost oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-024-01807-x</link>
      <description>Jie Zhao, Yue Guo, Zhiqi Zhang, Xilin Zhang, Qianqian Ji, Han Zhang, Zhaoqi Song, Dongqing Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Erhuan Zhang, Yuhao Wang, Guangzhi Hu, Muhammad Asim Mushtaq, Waseem Raza, Xingke Cai, Francesco Ciucci, Nature Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403609594

                Abstract Advancements in single-atom-based catalysts are crucial for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance while reducing precious metal usage. A comprehensive understanding of underlying mechanisms will expedite this progress further. Here we report Ir single atoms coordinated out-of-plane with dimethylimidazole (MI) on CoFe hydroxide (Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI). This Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI catalyst, which was prepared using a simple immersion method, delivers ultralow overpotentials of 179 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and 257 mV at 600 mA cm &#8722;2 as well as an ultra-small Tafel slope of 24 mV dec &#8722;1 . Furthermore, Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI has a total mass activity exceeding that of commercial IrO 2 by a factor of 58.4. Ab initio simulations indicate that the coordination of MI leads to electron redistribution around the Ir sites. This causes a positive shift in the d -band centre at adjacent Ir and Co sites, facilitating an optimal energy pathway for OER.</description>
      <author>Jie Zhao, Yue Guo, Zhiqi Zhang, Xilin Zhang, Qianqian Ji, Han Zhang, Zhaoqi Song, Dongqing Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Erhuan Zhang, Yuhao Wang, Guangzhi Hu, Muhammad Asim Mushtaq, Waseem Raza, Xingke Cai, Francesco Ciucci</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-024-01807-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Developments in Membrane&#8208;Free Hybrid Water Electrolysis for Low&#8208;Cost Hydrogen Production Along with Value&#8208;Added Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407845</link>
      <description>Neshanth Vadivel, Arun Prasad Murthy, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403610580

                Abstract Water electrolysis using renewable energy is considered as a promising technique for sustainable and green hydrogen production. Conventional water electrolysis has two components &#8211; hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) occurring at the cathode and anode respectively. However, electrolysis of water suffers from high overpotential due to the slow kinetics of OER. To overcome this hybrid water electrolysis has been developed by replacing conventional anode oxidation producing oxygen with oxidation of cost&#8208;effective materials producing value&#8208;added chemicals. This review summarizes recent advances in organic oxidative reactions such as alcohols, urea, hydrazine, and biomass at the anode instead of OER. Furthermore, the review also highlights the use of membrane&#8208;free hybrid water electrolysis as a method to overcome the cost and complexity associated with conventional membrane&#8208;based electrolyzer thereby improving overall efficiency. This approach holds promise for scalable and cost&#8208;effective large&#8208;scale hydrogen production along with value&#8208;added products. Finally, current challenges and future perspectives are discussed for further development in membrane&#8208;free hybrid water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Neshanth Vadivel, Arun Prasad Murthy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuCo@C Hollow Nanoprisms Derived from ZIF&#8208;67 for Enhanced Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401862</link>
      <description>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Samah A. Mahyoub, Fahim A. Qaraah, Abdo Hezam, Q.A. Drmosh, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403612479

                Zeolitic imidazolate frameworks (ZIFs) are commonly used to create complex hollow structures for energy applications. This study presents a simple method to produce a novel hollow nanoprism Co@C hierarchical composite from ZIF&#8208;67 through high&#8208;temperature treatment at 800 &#176;C. This composite serves as a platform for Ru nanoparticle deposition, forming RuCo@C hollow nanoprism (RuCo@C HNP). As an electrocatalyst in 1 M KOH, RuCo@C HNP exhibits excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance, with a low overpotential of 32 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a Tafel slope of 39.67 mV dec&#8722;1, a high turnover frequency (TOF) of 3.83 s&#8722;1 at &#414;200, and stable performance over 50 h. It also achieves a low &#414;10 of 266 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with a Tafel slope of 45.22 mV dec&#8722;1. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that Ru doping in Ni/Co maintains a low water dissociation barrier, reduces the energy barrier for the OER rate&#8208;determining step, and creates active sites for H*, enhancing adsorption/desorption abilities. These results are attributed to the synergy between Co and Ru and the hollow prism structure's increased surface area. This method for synthesizing hollow structures using ZIF composites shows promise for applications in the energy sector.</description>
      <author>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Samah A. Mahyoub, Fahim A. Qaraah, Abdo Hezam, Q.A. Drmosh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Conversion of Metal Organic Frameworks into Porous Rugby Phosphides by Plasma for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03525</link>
      <description>Guochang Li, Mang Niu, Rongzheng An, Huayu Zhang, Bingxue Sun, Guoling Li, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403613070

                Electrolytic seawater is a green, sustainable, and promising approach for hydrogen production. Benefiting from the cost-effectiveness, crystal structures, and tailorable modification, transition metal phosphides become a highly attractive catalyst for the electrolysis of water. Considering the sufficient exposure and intrinsic catalytic activity of metal sites, here, carbon layer-coated NiFeP nanocrystals with a porous rugby structure are synthesized by Ar-H</description>
      <author>Guochang Li, Mang Niu, Rongzheng An, Huayu Zhang, Bingxue Sun, Guoling Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Match&#8208;Enabled Covalent Heterointerfaces with Built&#8208;in Electric Field for Efficient Hydrogen Peroxide Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412070</link>
      <description>Jundie Hu, Binrong Li, Xue Li, Tingyu Yang, Xiao&#8208;Gang Yang, Jiafu Qu, Yahui Cai, Hongbin Yang, Zhiqun Lin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615105

                Abstract Crafting semiconducting heterojunctions represents an effective route to enhance photocatalysis by improving interfacial charge separation and transport. However, lattice mismatch ( &#948; ) between different semiconductors can significantly hinder charge dynamics. Here, meticulous lattice tailoring is reported to create a covalent heterointerface with a built&#8208;in electric field (BIEF), imparting markedly improved hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) photosynthesis. Specifically, an In 2 S 3 /CdS heterojunction with a coherent heterointerface, characterized by covalent In&#9472;S&#9472;Cd bridge and exceptionally low lattice mismatch of 0.27%, and a BIEF from In 2 S 3 to CdS, is rationally designed. This heterojunction entails rapid charge separation and transfer, achieving an outstanding H 2 O 2 production rate of 2.09 mmol g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 without the need for scavengers and oxygen bubbling, and a high apparent quantum efficiency of 17.73% at 400 nm. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations further reveal that this Z&#8208;scheme heterojunction facilitates the adsorption of * O 2 and the generation of * OOH intermediates during the 2e &#8722; oxygen reduction reaction, associated with a low Gibbs free energy. This study underscores the significance of fine&#8208;tuning interfacial lattices and integrating BIEF to accelerate photocatalysis. The simple yet robust strategy can be conveniently leveraged to enhance device performance in optoelectronics, electrocatalysis, photoelectrocatalysis, and sensing.</description>
      <author>Jundie Hu, Binrong Li, Xue Li, Tingyu Yang, Xiao&#8208;Gang Yang, Jiafu Qu, Yahui Cai, Hongbin Yang, Zhiqun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially Immobilized PtPdFeCoNi as an Excellent Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202414537</link>
      <description>Mingkuan Xie, Yu Lu, Xinke Xiao, Duojie Wu, Bing Shao, Hao Nian, Chunsheng Wu, Wenjuan Wang, Jun Gu, Songbai Han, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615140

                Abstract Developing efficient oxygen electrocatalysts with low cost, high catalytic activity, and robust stability remains a formidable challenge for rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, highly dispersed ultrasmall PtPdFeCoNi high&#8208;entropy alloy nanoparticles with a size of &#8776; 2 nm and randomly distributed multimetallic single atoms spatially immobilized on the 3D hierarchically ordered porous nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon skeleton (denoted as PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC) are successfully synthesized via ultra&#8208;rapid Joule heating process. The spatial immobilization on 3D HOPNC skeleton is the key to the high dispersion of multi&#8208;active sites of oxygen electrocatalysts, and the formed hierarchical pore structure is conducive to the successful construction of the rapid mass transfer channel. As a result, the as&#8208;prepared PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC exhibits a positive half&#8208;wave potential of 0.866 V versus RHE for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), a low overpotential of 310 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and low Tafel slopes for both ORR and OER. Furthermore, ZAB using PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC as bifunctional oxygen catalysts exhibits excellent rate performances and superior cycling stability, surpassing that of a commercial Pt/C&#8208;RuO 2 mixture. The spatial immobilization strategy of HOPNC provides a new idea for the design and synthesis of efficient catalysts for various applications.</description>
      <author>Mingkuan Xie, Yu Lu, Xinke Xiao, Duojie Wu, Bing Shao, Hao Nian, Chunsheng Wu, Wenjuan Wang, Jun Gu, Songbai Han, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202414537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c</link>
      <description>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615829

                The design of efficient and active electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for renewable energy generation. Here, crystalline iron-doped nickel sulfide core, amorphous iron-doped nickel phosphate shell heterostructured...</description>
      <author>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution performance by single metal (tungsten, nickel and manganese) atom oxides anchored nanorods of CeO2-MnO2-rGO as electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105800</link>
      <description>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Yueshuai Wang, Tae Hwan Oh, Vanthana Jeyasingh, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, M. Swaminathan, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 165(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403623601

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Yueshuai Wang, Tae Hwan Oh, Vanthana Jeyasingh, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, M. Swaminathan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Site-Enabled O&#8211;O Coupling in Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</link>
      <description>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403624087

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629653

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629654

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629734

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629769

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403630496

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403630497

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxyanions Enhancing Crystallinity of Reconstructed Phase for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415132</link>
      <description>Wenbin Wang, Qunlei Wen, Danji Huang, Yu Lin, Nian-Dan Zhao, Lan Tang, Ming Li, Youwen Liu, Rongxing He, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403471129

                The catalysts were always undergoing continuous amorphization and dissolution of active structure in operating condition, hindering the compatibility between stability and activity for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we propose the selective adsorption of leached NO3&#8208; to strengthen the crystallinity and activity of surface reconstructed layer with amorphous and crystalline (a&#8208;c) heterojunction. Taking a&#8208;c Ni doped Fe2O(OH)3NO3&#183;H2O (Ni&#8208;FeNH) as a model precatalyst, we uncover that the leached NO3&#8208; are readily adsorbs on the crystalline phase in the formed a&#8208;c Fe(Ni)OOH during OER, lowering the disorder degree and further activating Ni and Fe ion of the crystalline Fe(Ni)OOH on a&#8208;c heterojunctions. Accordingly, Ni&#8208;FeNH deliver a low overpotential of 303 mV and high durability of 500 hours at 500 mA cm&#8208;2 for OER. Particularly, constructing industrial water electrolysis equipment exhibits high stability of 100 hours under a high operating current of 8000 mA.</description>
      <author>Wenbin Wang, Qunlei Wen, Danji Huang, Yu Lin, Nian-Dan Zhao, Lan Tang, Ming Li, Youwen Liu, Rongxing He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of agroindustry residues for their usage as oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114527</link>
      <description>Aida M. D&#237;ez, Mar&#237;a Bola&#241;os-V&#225;zquez, S. Chiussi, Marta Pazos, M.&#193;. Sanrom&#225;n, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403626228

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aida M. D&#237;ez, Mar&#237;a Bola&#241;os-V&#225;zquez, S. Chiussi, Marta Pazos, M.&#193;. Sanrom&#225;n</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ synthesis of FeNi3/(Fe,Ni)9S8/Ni4S3/C nanorods and enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.2024.193.1333</link>
      <description>Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, S. J. Zhong, J. H. Chen, Mengyang Li, Yele Sun, Digest Journal of Nanomaterials and Biostructures. 19(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403515726

                NiFe-based nanomaterials have emerged as highly promising catalysts to replace platinum, ruthenium and iridium for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), in &#8220;green hydrogen&#8221; production process through water splitting. Using iron (2+) sulfate and nickel acetate as the raw materials, with the molar ratio of Ni acetate to iron (2+) sulfate controlled at 8:5, the concentration of metal-ion was 0.6 mol/L, and precursor fibers rich in Ni2+, Fe2+, and SO4 2&#8722; were prepared using electrospinning technology, with polyvinyl alcohol acting as the colloid. Subsequently, composite nanorods rich in the elements of Ni, Fe, S, and C were successfully obtained at a heat treatment temperature of 1000&#176;C in an Ar gas atmosphere. The results demonstrate that the nanorod samples possessed a surface diameter of ~200 nm, and the main phases of the nanorods after heat treatment at 1000&#176;C included FeNi3 alloy, (Fe,Ni)9S8, Ni4S3, and amorphous C. Electrochemical performance tests conducted in a 1.0 mol/L KOH solution exhibited excellent oxygen evolution reaction properties of the catalysts prepared using FeNi3/(Fe,Ni)9S8/Ni4S3/C nanorods as the materials. The overpotential was about 258.6 mV of the catalyst material at 10 mA&#61589;cm&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, S. J. Zhong, J. H. Chen, Mengyang Li, Yele Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.2024.193.1333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Spin Channels in SrCoO3 through Triagonal&#8208;to&#8208;Cubic Structural Transformation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415797</link>
      <description>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403627497

                Oxygen evolution and reduction reactions (OER and ORR) play crucial roles in energy conversion processes such as water splitting and air batteries, where spin dynamics inherently influence their efficiency. However, the specific contribution of spin has yet to be fully understood. In this study, we intentionally introduce a spin channel through the transformation of trigonal antiferromagnetic SrCoO2.5 into cubic ferromagnetic SrCoO3, aiming to deepen our understanding of spin dynamics in catalytic reactions. Based on the results from spherical&#8208;aberration&#8208;corrected microscope, synchrotron absorption spectra, magnetic characterizations, and density functional theory calculations, it is revealed that surface electron transfer is predominantly governed by local geometric structures, while the presence of the spin channel significantly enhances the bulk transport of spin&#8208;polarized electrons, particularly under high current densities where surface electron transfer is no longer the limiting factor. The overpotential for OER is reduced by at least 70 mV at 150 mA cm&#8208;2 due to the enhanced conductivity from spin&#8208;polarized electrons facilitated by spin channels, with an expectation of even more significant reductions at higher current densities. This work provides a clearer picture of the role of spin in oxygen&#8208;involved electrocatalysis, providing critical insights for the design of more efficient catalytic systems in practical applications.</description>
      <author>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Spin Channels in SrCoO3 through Triagonal&#8208;to&#8208;Cubic Structural Transformation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415797</link>
      <description>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403627665

                Oxygen evolution and reduction reactions (OER and ORR) play crucial roles in energy conversion processes such as water splitting and air batteries, where spin dynamics inherently influence their efficiency. However, the specific contribution of spin has yet to be fully understood. In this study, we intentionally introduce a spin channel through the transformation of trigonal antiferromagnetic SrCoO2.5 into cubic ferromagnetic SrCoO3, aiming to deepen our understanding of spin dynamics in catalytic reactions. Based on the results from spherical&#8208;aberration&#8208;corrected microscope, synchrotron absorption spectra, magnetic characterizations, and density functional theory calculations, it is revealed that surface electron transfer is predominantly governed by local geometric structures, while the presence of the spin channel significantly enhances the bulk transport of spin&#8208;polarized electrons, particularly under high current densities where surface electron transfer is no longer the limiting factor. The overpotential for OER is reduced by at least 70 mV at 150 mA cm&#8208;2 due to the enhanced conductivity from spin&#8208;polarized electrons facilitated by spin channels, with an expectation of even more significant reductions at higher current densities. This work provides a clearer picture of the role of spin in oxygen&#8208;involved electrocatalysis, providing critical insights for the design of more efficient catalytic systems in practical applications.</description>
      <author>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Entropy Metallic-High Entropy Nonmetallic Community as High Performance Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc05326e</link>
      <description>Chunyan Zhang, Hang Li, Mengfei Su, Shengfa Li, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403607529

                The multi-element synergism in high-entropy materials (HEMs) provides great opportunities to promote the tandem reaction or meet the requirement of multi-functional catalysts. Herein, a high entropy precursor strategy is proposed...</description>
      <author>Chunyan Zhang, Hang Li, Mengfei Su, Shengfa Li, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc05326e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of High-Valence Metal Dissolution in Oxygen Evolution Kinetics of the Advanced FeNiO&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04454</link>
      <description>Jun Ke, Jiaxi Zhang, Longhai Zhang, Shunyi He, Chengzhi Zhong, Li Du, Jiajun Huang, Xiaoming Fang, Zhengguo Zhang, Zhiming Cui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403624235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Ke, Jiaxi Zhang, Longhai Zhang, Shunyi He, Chengzhi Zhong, Li Du, Jiajun Huang, Xiaoming Fang, Zhengguo Zhang, Zhiming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur Doping and Heterostructure on Nise@Co(Oh)2 with Facilitated Surface Reconstruction and Interfacial Electron Regulation to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994506</link>
      <description>Fei Nie, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Xiaodan Chong, Xiaoping Dai, Yikai Yang, Jinsheng Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600648

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Nie, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Xiaodan Chong, Xiaoping Dai, Yikai Yang, Jinsheng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab initio calculations of high-entropy clusters for oxygen reduction and evolution as well as CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161555</link>
      <description>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403561270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into (Mn/Fe/Co)M-N-C Dual-Atom Catalysts for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction: The Critical Role of Structural Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03924f</link>
      <description>Xiaoming Zhang, Suli Wang, Zhangxun Xia, Huanqiao Li, Shansheng Yu, Gongquan Sun, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403514402

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) based on metal-nitrogen-carbon (M-N-C) compounds have been identified as a potential substitute for Pt-based oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts due to their facile availability and low cost....</description>
      <author>Xiaoming Zhang, Suli Wang, Zhangxun Xia, Huanqiao Li, Shansheng Yu, Gongquan Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03924f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cauliflower-like Pd/MoC||Mo2C/C heterostructure as an efficient trifunctional catalyst for formic acid oxidation, hydrogen evolution, and oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176973</link>
      <description>Ting Wang, Yunzhu Feng, J. B. Su, Wei Qi, Xin Ruan, Jiannan Cai, Xiaofeng Zhang, Qiufeng Huang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403500890

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Wang, Yunzhu Feng, J. B. Su, Wei Qi, Xin Ruan, Jiannan Cai, Xiaofeng Zhang, Qiufeng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176973</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Catalytic Centres by RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Addition to CuFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Cathode Catalyst towards Rechargeable Lithium-Air Battery: Influence of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; on the Li-O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Battery Performances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01202j</link>
      <description>Pamangadan C. Sharafudeen, Perumal Elumalai, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403473383

                The oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER) kinetics of the inverse-spinel CuFe2O4 catalyst is enhanced by the addition of very little quantity of RuO2. It turned out that...</description>
      <author>Pamangadan C. Sharafudeen, Perumal Elumalai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01202j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial engineering of heterostructured CoP/FeP nanoflakes as bifunctional electrocatalyts toward alkaline water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.084</link>
      <description>Yu Zhang, Zhiyong Li, Siqi He, Yanxin Qiao, Aihua Yuan, Jianchun Wu, Hu Zhou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403524379

                Exploring highly-effective and nonprecious electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is urgent and challenging for developing the hydrogen economy. Interface engineering is a feasible approach for regulating the surface electronic distribution, thereby promoting the catalytic performance. Herein, the CoP/FeP heterostructure is fabricated via the oxidation and phosphating treatments of Fe-decorated Ni(OH)</description>
      <author>Yu Zhang, Zhiyong Li, Siqi He, Yanxin Qiao, Aihua Yuan, Jianchun Wu, Hu Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir Doping Modulates the Electronic Structure of Flower-Shaped Phosphides for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</link>
      <description>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633322

                Electrolysis of water to produce hydrogen is an efficient, clean, and environmentally friendly hydrogen production method with unlimited development prospects. However, its overall efficiency is hampered by the slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with complex electron transfer processes. Therefore, designing efficient and low-cost OER catalysts is the key to solving this problem. In this paper, Ir-doped Co</description>
      <author>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving High OER Performance by Tuning the Co/Mn Content in Prussian Blue Analogues</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13199</link>
      <description>Chang Wu, Jinsong Wang, Jiayang Li, Hang Zhang, Shailendra Kumar Sharma, Laura J. Titheridge, Campbell Tiffin, Yameng Fan, Lingfei Zhao, Weishen Yang, Zhengtao Li, Jian Peng, Jiazhao Wang, Aaron T. Marshall, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403509228

                The need for efficient, economical, and clean energy systems is increasing, and as a result, interest in water-splitting techniques to produce green hydrogen is also increasing. However, the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) hinders the practical application and widespread use of water-splitting technologies; therefore, to address this challenge, it is essential to develop cost-effective and efficient OER catalysts. In this work, we have synthesized an inexpensive and tunable FeCoMn Prussian blue analogue (PBAs) as an efficient OER catalyst via a straightforward process. The ratio of the Co and Mn to optimize the electrochemical performance, and as a result, the FeCo</description>
      <author>Chang Wu, Jinsong Wang, Jiayang Li, Hang Zhang, Shailendra Kumar Sharma, Laura J. Titheridge, Campbell Tiffin, Yameng Fan, Lingfei Zhao, Weishen Yang, Zhengtao Li, Jian Peng, Jiazhao Wang, Aaron T. Marshall</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis of Metal/Carbide Hybrid toward Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100730</link>
      <description>Jinpeng Mo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403601518

                The development of cost-effective and high-performance bifunctional catalysts for overall water splitting is crucial for achieving sustainable clean energy. In this study, a metal/carbide hybrid (NiFeMo/NiFeMoCx) was prepared through fast and facile cathodic plasma electrolytic deposition. Due to the synergistic effect between the metal and carbide, NiFeMo/NiFeMoCx exhibited high activity in both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), with overpotentials of 230 mV and 60 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. In addition, robust stability was demonstrated during the overall water splitting (1.52 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, with little degradation after 18 h of catalysis). This work provides a useful strategy for designing advanced water splitting catalysts for real application.</description>
      <author>Jinpeng Mo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Plasma Triggered Co&#8208;O&#8208;Fe Motif in Prussian Blue Analogue for Efficient and Robust Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415423</link>
      <description>Hao Xu, Chen Zhu, Hao Lin, Ji Kai Liu, Yi Xiao Wu, Huai Qin Fu, Xinyu Zhang, Fangxin Mao, Hai Yang Yuan, Chenghua Sun, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403463126

                In the context of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the construction of high&#8208;valent transition metal sites to trigger the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism is considered crucial for overcoming the performance limitations of traditional adsorbate evolution mechanism. However, the dynamic evolution of lattice oxygen during the reaction poses significant challenges for the stability of high&#8208;valent metal sites, particularly in high&#8208;current&#8208;density water&#8208;splitting systems. Here, we have successfully constructed Co&#8208;O&#8208;Fe catalytic active motifs in cobalt&#8208;iron Prussian blue analogs (CoFe&#8208;PBA) through oxygen plasma bombardment, effectively activating lattice oxygen reactivity while sustaining robust stability. Our spectroscopic and theoretical studies reveal that the Co&#8208;O&#8208;Fe bridged motifs enable a unique double&#8208;exchange interaction between Co and Fe atoms, promoting the formation of high&#8208;valent Co species as OER active centers while maintaining Fe in a low&#8208;valent state, preventing its dissolution. The resultant catalyst (CoFe&#8208;PBA&#8208;30) requires an overpotential of only 276 mV to achieve 1000 mA cm&#8208;2. Furthermore, the assembled alkaline exchange membrane electrolyzer using CoFe&#8208;PBA&#8208;30 as anode material achieves a high current density of 1 A cm&#8208;2 at 1.76 V and continuously operates for 250 hours with negligible degradation. This work provides significant insights for activating lattice oxygen redox without compromising structure stability in practical water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Hao Xu, Chen Zhu, Hao Lin, Ji Kai Liu, Yi Xiao Wu, Huai Qin Fu, Xinyu Zhang, Fangxin Mao, Hai Yang Yuan, Chenghua Sun, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Synergistic Effect of NiFe-LDH/3D GA Composites on Efficient Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14201661</link>
      <description>Jiangcheng Zhang, Qiuhan Cao, Xin Yu, Yao Hu, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Xiaohui Guo, Nanomaterials. 14(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403457301

                Currently, NiFe-LDH exhibits an excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to the interaction of the two metal elements on the layered double hydroxide (LDH) platform. However, such interaction is still insufficient to compensate for its poor electrical conductivity, limited number of active sites and sluggish dynamics. Herein, a feasible two-step hydrothermal strategy that involves coupling low-conductivity NiFe-LDH with 3D porous graphene aerogel (GA) is proposed. The optimized NiFe-LDH/GA (1:1) produced possesses a 257 mV (10 mA cm&#8722;2) overpotential and could operate stably for 56 h in an OER. Our investigation demonstrates that the NiFe-LDH/GA has a three-dimensional mesoporous structure, and that there is synergistic interaction between LDH and GA and interfacial reconstruction of NiOOH. Such an interface synergistic coupling effect promotes fast mass transfer and facilitates OER kinetics, and this work offers new insights into designing efficient and stable GA-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jiangcheng Zhang, Qiuhan Cao, Xin Yu, Yao Hu, Bao&#8208;Lian Su, Xiaohui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14201661</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Family of Twisted Chiral Engineered Inorganic Nanoarchitectures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03627</link>
      <description>Li&#8208;Li Tan, Zhihao Wen, Yiran Jin, Wenlong Fu, Qi Gao, Chengyu Xiao, Zhi Chen, Pengpeng Wang, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403521223

                Chiral inorganic materials possess unique asymmetric properties that could significantly impact various fields. However, their practical application has been hindered by challenges in creating structurally robust chiral materials. We report the synthesis of well-defined chiral-shaped hollow cobalt oxide nanostructures, extendable to a family of chalcogenides including sulfide, selenide, and telluride through topological transformations. Taking chiral cobalt oxide nanostructures as a representative material, we demonstrate precise control over their chiral architectures, enabling fine-tuning of parameters, such as twist degrees, handedness, and compositions. These chiral nanostructures exhibit high spin selectivity effects that influence the electron transfer processes in catalytic reactions. Leveraging this spin-selective behavior, the chiral cobalt oxide nanoarchitectures demonstrate enhanced electrocatalytic performance in the oxygen evolution reaction compared to their achiral counterparts. Our findings not only expand the library of chiral inorganic materials but also advance the application of chiral effects in fields such as catalysis, spintronics, and beyond.</description>
      <author>Li&#8208;Li Tan, Zhihao Wen, Yiran Jin, Wenlong Fu, Qi Gao, Chengyu Xiao, Zhi Chen, Pengpeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Of Cobalt Phosphates Co1-xmxpo4 Doped With Iron And Nickel Atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044457x24040071</link>
      <description>M. D. Pecherskaya, O. A. Galkina, Olim Ruzimuradov, Sh.I. Mamatkulov, &#1046;&#1091;&#1088;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083; &#1085;&#1077;&#1086;&#1088;&#1075;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1081; &#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1080;. 69(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403558513

                In this research, the electronic states, band structures, and bond properties of the framework compounds of CoPO4, Co1-xFexPO4, and Co1&#8211;xNixPO4 were investigated by the density functional theory calculations. The potential capabilities of these systems in the photocatalytic water splitting to produce hydrogen were analyzed. The spin-up electron densities of states for the CoPO4, Co1&#8211;xFexPO4, and Co1&#8211;xNixPO4 systems have band gaps of 2.7, 3.4, and 3.45 eV, respectively. The band of spin-down electron states has several energy gaps above the Fermi level. The density of states of electron with spin up near the Fermi level is obviously greater than that of electrons with spin down. In this case, localized states of electrons appear in the band gap of doped semiconductors due to impurity atoms. The calculated value of the energy at the lower edge of the conduction band for CoPO4 was &#8211;0.7 eV, which is more negative than the energy required for water splitting. Meanwhile, the calculated value of the energy at the upper edge of the valence band was 2.01 eV, which is more positive than the oxygen evolution energy of 1.23 eV.</description>
      <author>M. D. Pecherskaya, O. A. Galkina, Olim Ruzimuradov, Sh.I. Mamatkulov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044457x24040071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Nanoalloy&#8208;Cluster&#8208;Single Atom Sites Based Aerophilic Carbon Fiber Membranes as Binder&#8208;Free Cathodes for Ultra&#8208;Long&#8208;Life Zn&#8208;air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416422</link>
      <description>Jian Zhu, Zesheng Li, Jingze Shao, Yu Xia, Chuanlai Jiao, Shaoqing Chen, Guangshe Li, Yingcai Zhu, Shi Chen, Rouxi Chen, Zian Xu, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403550838

                Abstract High&#8208;efficient and durable electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER) are desirable to Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). However, most of catalysts in powder form with sole active sites remain challenging in achieving the satisfactory bifunctional catalysis and suffer from peeling off during the long&#8208;term operation. Herein, hybrid CoFe active sites are constructed containing nanoalloys (&#8776;10 nm), clusters (&lt; 2 nm), and single atoms on aerophilic carbon fiber membranes as binder&#8208;free air cathodes for ultra&#8208;long&#8208;life ZABs. In particular, the high air&#8208;permeability of membranes (0.2 s) can prevent the active sites from blocking by O 2 bubbles and promote the mass transfer. The theoretical and experimental results confirm that the hydrophilic CoFe 2 O 4 /CoFeOOH sites reconstructed on the surface of CoFe nanoalloys are mainly responsible for OER. While for single atoms and clusters on nitrogen (N)&#8208;doped carbon matrix, they play a synergetic role in optimizing the adsorption energy to enhance ORR activity. Thus, the as&#8208;prepared catalysts exhibit an ultra&#8208;low ORR/OER potential gap (0.64 V). When further assembled as freestanding air&#8208;electrodes, it exhibits an outstanding cycling lifespan of 1200 and 155 h in liquid&#8208; and quasi&#8208;solid&#8208;state ZABs respectively, which are fivefold and twofold higher than those of powder&#8208;based cathodes (240/67 h).</description>
      <author>Jian Zhu, Zesheng Li, Jingze Shao, Yu Xia, Chuanlai Jiao, Shaoqing Chen, Guangshe Li, Yingcai Zhu, Shi Chen, Rouxi Chen, Zian Xu, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Performance of Novel d-Ti3CN@CdSe Nanocomposite for Efficient Water Splitting: Achieving Low Overpotential and High Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad88ac</link>
      <description>Maryam Bibi, Muhammad Asad Asghar, Saba Ahmad, Sajjad Haider, Khurshid Alam, Shahid Ali Khan, Muhammad Adil Mansoor, Mudassir Iqbal, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403527934

                Abstract The escalating global demand for clean and sustainable energy has ignited significant interest in hydrogen production through water splitting. A major challenge in this pursuit is the development of efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, we present the synthesis of a novel two-dimensional d-Ti&#8323;CN @CdSe nanocomposite, designed as a high-performance electrocatalyst for overall water splitting. Synthesized via hydrothermal methods, the nanocomposite was characterized using advanced characterization techniques viz. Raman spectroscopy, XRD, XPS, and SEM/EDS. Electrochemical evaluations demonstrate that the d-Ti&#8323;CN @CdSe nanocomposite significantly enhances catalytic performance compared to its individual components, achieving a low overpotential of 232 mV for HER at 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; and reducing the OER overpotential from 498.3 mV for d-Ti&#8323;CN MXene to 382.2 mV in the nanocomposite at 30 mA cm&#8315;&#178;. Additionally, it exhibits excellent stability, retaining about 75.37% of its current density after 36 hours of continuous operation. This remarkable performance is attributed to the synergistic interactions between CdSe nanoparticles and Ti&#8323;CN MXene layers, which prevent restacking, increase the electrochemically active surface area, and enhance charge transfer efficiency. These features position the d-Ti&#8323;CN @CdSe nanocomposite as a promising candidate for scalable and sustainable water-splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Maryam Bibi, Muhammad Asad Asghar, Saba Ahmad, Sajjad Haider, Khurshid Alam, Shahid Ali Khan, Muhammad Adil Mansoor, Mudassir Iqbal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad88ac</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrosynthesis of Valuable para&#8208;Benzoquinone from Aqueous Phenol on NiRu Hybrid Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415438</link>
      <description>Shuangyin Wang, Fuqiang Liu, Wei Chen, Tong Wang, J. Zhang, Deyong Yang, Yinhao Dai, Guizi Liu, Jian Zhou, Xiaohong Guan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403565947

                Electrocatalytic oxidation of aqueous phenol to para&#8208;benzoquinone (p&#8208;BQ) offers a sustainable approach for both pollutant abatement and value&#8208;added chemicals production. However, achieving high phenol conversion and p&#8208;BQ yield under neutral conditions remains challenging. Herein, we report a Ni(OH)2&#8208;supported Ru nanoparticles (NiRu) hybrid electrocatalyst, which exhibits a superior phenol conversion of 96.5% and an excellent p&#8208;BQ yield of 83.4% at pH 7.0, significantly outperforming previously reported electrocatalysts. This exceptional performance benefits from the triple synergistic modulation of the NiRu catalyst, including enhanced phenol adsorption, increased p&#8208;BQ desorption, and suppressed oxygen evolution. By coupling a flow electrolyzer with an extraction&#8208;distillation separation unit, the simultaneous phenol removal and p&#8208;BQ recovery are realized. Additionally, the developed electrocatalytic system with the NiRu/C anode displays good stability, favorable energy consumption, and reduced greenhouse gas emissions for phenol&#8208;containing wastewater treatment, demonstrating its potential for practical applications. This work offers a promising strategy for achieving low&#8208;carbon emissions in phenol wastewater treatment.</description>
      <author>Shuangyin Wang, Fuqiang Liu, Wei Chen, Tong Wang, J. Zhang, Deyong Yang, Yinhao Dai, Guizi Liu, Jian Zhou, Xiaohong Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrosynthesis of Valuable para&#8208;Benzoquinone from Aqueous Phenol on NiRu Hybrid Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415438</link>
      <description>Shuangyin Wang, Fuqiang Liu, Wei Chen, Tong Wang, Juchao Zhang, Deyong Yang, Yinhao Dai, Guizi Liu, Jian Zhou, Xiaohong Guan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403565948

                Electrocatalytic oxidation of aqueous phenol to para&#8208;benzoquinone (p&#8208;BQ) offers a sustainable approach for both pollutant abatement and value&#8208;added chemicals production. However, achieving high phenol conversion and p&#8208;BQ yield under neutral conditions remains challenging. Herein, we report a Ni(OH)2&#8208;supported Ru nanoparticles (NiRu) hybrid electrocatalyst, which exhibits a superior phenol conversion of 96.5% and an excellent p&#8208;BQ yield of 83.4% at pH 7.0, significantly outperforming previously reported electrocatalysts. This exceptional performance benefits from the triple synergistic modulation of the NiRu catalyst, including enhanced phenol adsorption, increased p&#8208;BQ desorption, and suppressed oxygen evolution. By coupling a flow electrolyzer with an extraction&#8208;distillation separation unit, the simultaneous phenol removal and p&#8208;BQ recovery are realized. Additionally, the developed electrocatalytic system with the NiRu/C anode displays good stability, favorable energy consumption, and reduced greenhouse gas emissions for phenol&#8208;containing wastewater treatment, demonstrating its potential for practical applications. This work offers a promising strategy for achieving low&#8208;carbon emissions in phenol wastewater treatment.</description>
      <author>Shuangyin Wang, Fuqiang Liu, Wei Chen, Tong Wang, Juchao Zhang, Deyong Yang, Yinhao Dai, Guizi Liu, Jian Zhou, Xiaohong Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni&#8211;Cu Bimetallic Oxides with Tailored Morphology for High&#8208;Performance Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403451</link>
      <description>Anila Tabassum, Sadia Ata, Yulong Ding, Ijaz Ul Mohsin, Sajjad Ahmed Khan Leghari, Abdullah A. Al&#8208;Kahtani, Ayman Nafady, Manzar Sohail, ChemistrySelect. 9(39)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403529853

                Abstract Water oxidation, a crucial step in electrochemical water splitting, is often hindered by its complex kinetics. In our pursuit of designing efficient electrocatalysts, we have found that morphological modifications during synthesis are powerful tools. By manipulating various parameters, such as reaction time and temperature, we have tuned the morphology of the catalysts, leading to a significant enhancement in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) rate. Our thorough research involves using a simple hydrothermal method for synthesizing bimetallic Ni&#8211;Cu oxides, resulting in the emergence of different morphologies by varying reaction times from 4 to 24 h. The OER performance in an alkaline medium, using a 1 M KOH solution, has been meticulously investigated, and our results have unveiled the highest activity for Ni&#8211;Cu fabricated with a growth time of 24 h. Ni&#8211;Cu oxide 24 exhibits a remarkably low onset potential for OER at 222 mV with a Tafel slope of 373 mV/dec. The catalyst boasts the lowest R ct value of 2.788 ohm, ensuring faster charge transfer rates and stability up to 1000 cyclic voltammetry (CV) cycles, thereby supporting its electrochemical applications for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Anila Tabassum, Sadia Ata, Yulong Ding, Ijaz Ul Mohsin, Sajjad Ahmed Khan Leghari, Abdullah A. Al&#8208;Kahtani, Ayman Nafady, Manzar Sohail</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Transfer by Mechanical Alloying and Electrocatalytic Performance of the As&#8208;Sintered Self&#8208;Supported High&#8208;Entropy Alloy FeNiCoCuMo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202400807</link>
      <description>Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, P. M&#225;rt&#237;n, E. P&#237;o, Jorg&#233; Pavez, Claudio Aguilar, C. Suryanarayana, Maritza P&#225;ez, Advanced Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403609811

                Efficient, stable, and cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are essential for clean energy generation through water splitting. This study presents a FeNiCoCuMo high&#8208;entropy alloy (HEA) synthesized via mechanical alloying (MA) and sintering using hot&#8208;pressing. The energy transfer from the milling process influences phase transformations, with the High&#8208;Entropy Alloys Prediction Software (HEAPS) predicting the formation of an FCC phase. X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD) and scanning electron microscopy reveal an FCC phase after 150 h of milling, with no elemental segregation observed. The Burgio kinetic model estimates 448 kJ mol &#8722;1 is needed to achieve a 99% FCC phase. The crystallite size is 4 nm, with a lattice parameter of 0.371 nm. The as&#8208;milled phases were preserved during hot&#8208;pressing sintering. Electrodes (M1, M2, M3) fabricated from the HEA demonstrated high electrocatalytic efficiency, with an average overpotential of 380 mV and Tafel slope of 77 mV dec &#8722;1 . At a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , the electrodes maintained operation for up to 100 h. The synergy between constituent elements is key to the superior electrocatalytic performance of FeNiCoCuMo HEAs, demonstrating their potential as promising materials for OER electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, P. M&#225;rt&#237;n, E. P&#237;o, Jorg&#233; Pavez, Claudio Aguilar, C. Suryanarayana, Maritza P&#225;ez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202400807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Approach for the Synthesis of 2-Phenyl-2&lt;i&gt;H&lt;/i&gt;-indazoles and Quinazoline Derivatives Using Sustainable Heterogeneous Copper Oxide Nanoparticles Supported on Activated Carbon and OER Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03054</link>
      <description>R. Thrilokraj, Manesh Kumar, Vishwanath Ankalgi, Shoyebmohamad F. Shaikh, Abdullah M. Al&#8208;Enizi, J.G. Ma&#322;ecki, Umesh A. Kshirsagar, Chandra Sekhar Rout, Ramesh B. Dateer, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403471717

                This research work reports the synthesis of copper oxide (CuO) nanoparticles supported on activated carbon by a simple impregnation method using 2-propanol as a green solvent, followed by calcination. The synthesized CuO@C is used as an efficient heterogeneous nanocatalyst for the synthesis of 2H-indazoles and quinazolines utilizing commercially available 2-bromobenzaldehydes, primary amines, and sodium azide under ligand-free and base-free conditions. The present methodology demonstrates the formation of new N&#8211;N, C&#8211;N, and C&#9552;N bonds under one-pot reaction conditions using PEG-400 as a green solvent. The reaction pathways are supported by control experiments and mechanistic elucidation. Further, the synthesized catalyst was characterized by a range of microscopic and spectroscopic techniques such as powdered X-ray diffraction, fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, field emission scanning electron microscopy, energy-dispersive X-ray, UV&#8211;vis, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, high-resolution transmission electron microscopy, and BET-BJH analysis. Importantly, the study focused on the recyclability of the catalyst and successfully showed gram-scale production. Significantly, our active catalyst exhibited an outstanding performance in the oxygen evolution reaction, with an overpotential of 290 mV and a swallow Tafel slope of 91 mV dec&#8211;1.</description>
      <author>R. Thrilokraj, Manesh Kumar, Vishwanath Ankalgi, Shoyebmohamad F. Shaikh, Abdullah M. Al&#8208;Enizi, J.G. Ma&#322;ecki, Umesh A. Kshirsagar, Chandra Sekhar Rout, Ramesh B. Dateer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03054</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additive Manufacturing of Multiscale NiFeMn Multi-Principal Element Alloys with Tailored Composition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2752-5724/ad89e1</link>
      <description>Shahryar Mooraj, Jintao Fu, Shuai Feng, Alexander K. Ng, Eric B. Duoss, Sarah E. Baker, Cheng Zhu, Eric Detsi, Wen Chen, Materials Futures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403628641

                Abstract Nanostructured multi-principal element alloys (MPEAs) have been explored as next-generation engineering materials due to unique mechanical and functional properties which have significant advantages over traditional dilute alloys. However, the practical applications of nanostructured MPEAs are still limited due to the lack of scalable processing approaches to prepare a large quantity of nanostructured MPEAs, as well as lack of an efficient pathway for high-throughput discovery of better functional nanostructured MPEAs within their vast compositional space. Here we tackle these challenges by presenting an integrated approach by combining direct-ink-writing-based additive manufacturing, solid-state sintering, and chemical dealloying to manufacture hierarchically porous MPEAs. The hierarchical structure is comprised of macro- and micro-scale pores introduced via extrusion printing and polymer decomposition during sintering, as well as nanoscale pores formed via chemical dealloying. The macro- and micro-scale pores allow efficient dealloying of a large mass of material as the diffusion length that the corroding medium must penetrate remains at the scale of the ligaments formed after sintering (~10 &#956;m), despite the large volume of the 3D-printed samples. In addition, this integrated approach enables versatile control of the alloy composition via precisely tuning the ratio of elemental powders in the starting ink, thus offering a pathway for high-throughput discovery of novel functional MPEAs. As a case study, multiscale macro/micro/nanoporous NiFeMn MPEAs with three different compositions were investigated as catalysts to reduce the overpotential of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), where NiFeMn-based electrocatalysts display composition-dependent performance such that the overpotential measured at a current of 0.5 A/g for OER increases in the order of Ni58Fe29Mn13 &#8804; Ni64Fe26Mn10 &lt; Ni76Fe18Mn6. This introduced manufacturing process offers new opportunities for scalable fabrication and rapid screening of nanostructured multi-component complex alloys. &amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Shahryar Mooraj, Jintao Fu, Shuai Feng, Alexander K. Ng, Eric B. Duoss, Sarah E. Baker, Cheng Zhu, Eric Detsi, Wen Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2752-5724/ad89e1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Evaporating-Trapping Strategy to Synthesize Flexible and Robust Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Rechargeable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee03005b</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhang, Yu Meng, Lingzhe Fang, Fei Yang, Shangqian Zhu, Tao Li, Xiaohua Yu, Rong Ju, Weiwei Chen, Dong Su, Yi Mei, Peng&#8208;Xiang Hou, Chang Liu, Minhua Shao, Jincheng Li, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403567909

                Great efforts have been devoted to the development of bifunctional electrocatalysts to accelerate the sluggish kinetics of cathodic oxygen reduction/evolution reactions (ORR/OER) in zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Here we report a...</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhang, Yu Meng, Lingzhe Fang, Fei Yang, Shangqian Zhu, Tao Li, Xiaohua Yu, Rong Ju, Weiwei Chen, Dong Su, Yi Mei, Peng&#8208;Xiang Hou, Chang Liu, Minhua Shao, Jincheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee03005b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abiotic factors that prompt major ecological transitions: Are fish on land to escape an intolerable aquatic environment?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.14672</link>
      <description>Terry J. Ord, Elizabeth A. Surovic, Diego F. B. Vaz, Iker Irisarri, Functional Ecology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403551454

                Abstract Colonisation of novel habitats are important events in evolution, but the factors that initially prompt such ecological transitions are often unknown. The invasion of land by fish is an extreme habitat transition that offers an opportunity to empirically investigate the causes of major ecological transitions. The intertidal ecotone&#8212;and rock pools in particular&#8212;have been an important staging ground for transitions onto land. Classic hypotheses focus on the adverse abiotic conditions of rock pools at low tide as the instigator of fish voluntarily stranding themselves out of water, which can then lead to the evolution of an amphibious lifestyle. To test these hypotheses, we studied the abiotic conditions of 54 rock pools on the island of Guam where there are various species of aquatic, amphibious and terrestrial blenny fishes. We found little support for the expected deterioration of abiotic conditions in standing pools at low tide (salinity, pH and oxygen), and fish were not seen to be excluded from those pools that were found to exhibit poor abiotic conditions (temperature, salinity and pH). Hypoxia was the only factor that might account for the absence of blennies from certain rock pools. Next, we experimentally measured oxygen depletion by an aquatic, mildly amphibious and highly amphibious species of blenny found on Guam in a simulated rockpool to infer the proportion of rock pools at low tide outside the tolerable range of blennies. Rock pools were found to have oxygen levels within the requirements of most blennies and those of other marine fishes reported in the literature. We conclude that the abiotic environment of rock pools alone was unlikely to have instigated the evolution of amphibious behaviour in blennies, at least on Guam. Instead, the broad range of abiotic conditions experienced in rock pools suggests these conditions could have primed amphibious blennies to better endure the novel conditions on land. Any ecotone typified by fluctuations or gradients in abiotic conditions is likely a key transitional environment for the invasion of novel habitats and, as such, are an important location for adaptive evolution and species diversification. Read the free Plain Language Summary for this article on the Journal blog.</description>
      <author>Terry J. Ord, Elizabeth A. Surovic, Diego F. B. Vaz, Iker Irisarri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.14672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain evolution in BiFeO3 epitaxial nanoisland array via post-annealing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237974</link>
      <description>Guo Tian, Xing&#8208;Chen Zhang, Gui Wang, Jun Jin, Huaichun Zhou, Jiyan Dai, Jun&#8208;Ming Liu, Xingsen Gao, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403548419

                We describe the impact of post-annealing on ferroelectric-domain structures in arrays of BiFeO3 (BFO) epitaxial nanoislands, which exhibit a domain evolution from an initial 71&#176; stripe/vortex domains to center-convergent topological domains. These results suggest that the increase and redistribution of charged defects, e.g., oxygen vacancies, in BFO nanoislands play a crucial role in driving the formation of center-type domain structures. The observation of defect-driven domain evolution in BFO nanoislands provides a path for further exploring their formation mechanism, topological properties, novel functionalities, and potential applications.</description>
      <author>Guo Tian, Xing&#8208;Chen Zhang, Gui Wang, Jun Jin, Huaichun Zhou, Jiyan Dai, Jun&#8208;Ming Liu, Xingsen Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mitochondrial genomes of the reef-dwelling spiny lobsters Panulirus echinatus and Panulirus interruptus with insights into the phylogeny and adaptive evolution of protein-coding genes in the Achelata</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00338-024-02569-7</link>
      <description>Alyssa Baker, Natalie C. Stephens, F&#225;bio Mendon&#231;a Diniz, Francisco J. Garc&#237;a&#8208;D&#233; Le&#243;n, J. Antonio Baeza, Coral Reefs. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403607195

                Abstract Temperature and oxygen levels drive the evolution of morphological, behavioral, and physiological traits in marine invertebrates, including crustaceans. Environmental conditions are also expected to prompt the adaptive evolution of mitochondrial protein-coding genes (PCGs), which are vital for energy production via the oxidative phosphorylation pathway. We formally tested for adaptive evolution in mitochondrial protein-coding genes in representatives of the decapod infraorder Achelata, including two spiny lobsters, Panulirus echinatus and P. interruptus , for which we sequenced complete mitochondrial genomes (15,644 and 15,659 bp long, respectively). A phylomitogenomic analysis supported the monophyly of the genus Panulirus , the families Palinuridae and Scyllaridae, and the infraorder Achelata. Over the strong negative selection background observed for mitochondrial PCGs in the Achelata, signatures of positive selective pressure were detected within PCGs in equatorial Panulirus spp. and deepwater Scyllaridae. In Panulirus spp. inhabiting equatorial latitudes with consistently high temperatures, the Datamonkey analysis RELAX suggested intensified purifying selection strength in 9 of the 13 PCGs and relaxation in purifying selection strength in atp6 , while aBSREL, BUSTED, and MEME recovered signatures of positive selection on PCGs within Complex I, III, and IV PCGs. Likewise, in Scyllaridae species inhabiting depths with low-oxygen levels, RELAX indicated relaxed selection strength in 6 of the 13 PCGs, while aBSREL, BUSTED, and MEME recovered signatures of positive selection on PCGs within Complexes I, III, IV, and V. The newly assembled mitochondrial genomes of P. echinatus and P. interruptus represent new genomic resources to aid with the conservation and management of lobsters targeted by major fisheries and contribute to our understanding of how environmental conditions drive adaptive evolution in spiny and slipper lobster mitochondrial PCGs.</description>
      <author>Alyssa Baker, Natalie C. Stephens, F&#225;bio Mendon&#231;a Diniz, Francisco J. Garc&#237;a&#8208;D&#233; Le&#243;n, J. Antonio Baeza</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00338-024-02569-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diverse Transient Chiral Dynamics in Evolutionary distinct
  Photosynthetic Reaction Centers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.06996</link>
      <description>Yong Yang, Zihui Liu, Fulu Zheng, Panpan Zhang, Hongxing He, Ajay Jha, Hong-Guang Duan, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403621288

                The evolution of photosynthetic reaction centers (RCs) from anoxygenic bacteria to oxygenic cyanobacteria and plants reflects their structural and functional adaptation to environmental conditions. Chirality plays a significant role in influencing the arrangement and function of key molecules in these RCs. This study investigates chirality-related energy transfer in two distinct RCs: Thermochromatium tepidum (BRC) and Thermosynechococcus vulcanus (PSII RC) using two-dimensional electronic spectroscopy (2DES). Circularly polarized laser pulses reveal transient chiral dynamics, with 2DCD spectroscopy highlighting chiral contributions. BRC displays more complex chiral behavior, while PSII RC shows faster coherence decay, possibly as an adaptation to oxidative stress. Comparing the chiral dynamics of BRC and PSII RC provides insights into photosynthetic protein evolution and function.</description>
      <author>Yong Yang, Zihui Liu, Fulu Zheng, Panpan Zhang, Hongxing He, Ajay Jha, Hong-Guang Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.06996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Activity and Stability in AgCl&#8208;CuO Electrocatalysts: Insights from Different Morphologies for Enhanced ORR Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400989</link>
      <description>Anagha Yatheendran, K. N., Aaron George, N. Sandhyarani, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403465103

                Highly enduring and methanol&#8208;tolerant electrocatalysts are pertinent to revolutionizing direct methanol fuel cell (DMFC) technologies. Transition metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts are anticipated to rank among the remarkable electrocatalysts for boosting the sluggish Oxygen Reduction Reaction (ORR) kinetics. Herein, we report a facile approach to optimize the activity and stability of the AgCl&#8208;CuO systems. The tailored Nano Particle&#8208;Nano Rod (NP&#8208;NR) and Nano Leaf (NL) like morphologies deliver remarkable bifunctional catalytic performance for oxygen reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions, sustained activity, and comparatively better stability for ORR. A meager shift of only 0.014 V and 0.024 V in the half&#8208;wave potential is observed in the NP&#8208;NR and NL structures, respectively, for the ORR even after 2500 cycles. Furthermore, both the AgCl&#8208;CuO composite exhibits an excellent tolerance to methanol.</description>
      <author>Anagha Yatheendran, K. N., Aaron George, N. Sandhyarani</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3-Electrode Setup for the Operando Detection of Side Reactions in Li-Ion Batteries: The Quantification of Released Lattice Oxygen and Transition Metal Ions from NCA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad8038</link>
      <description>Lennart Reuter, Leonhard Reinschl&#252;ssel, Hubert A. Gasteiger, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. 171(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403503541

                Detecting parasitic side reactions is paramount for developing stable cathode active materials (CAMs) for Li-ion batteries. This study presents a method for the quantification of released lattice oxygen and transition metal ions (TM II+ ions). It is based on a 3-electrode cell design employing a Vulcan carbon-based sense electrode (SE) that is held at a controlled voltage against a partially delithiated lithium iron phosphate (LFP) counter electrode (CE). At this SE, reductive currents can be measured while polarizing a CAM working electrode (WE), here a LiNi 0.80 Co 0.15 Al 0.05 O 2 (NCA), against the same LFP CE. In voltammetric scans, we show how the SE potential can be selected to specifically detect a given side reaction during CAM charge/discharge, allowing, e.g., to discriminate between lattice oxygen and dissolved TMs. Furthermore, it is shown via online electrochemical mass spectrometry (OEMS) that O 2 reduction in the here-used LP47 electrolyte consumes &#8764;2.3 electrons/O 2 . Using this value, the lattice oxygen release deduced from the 3-electrode setup upon charging of the NCA WE is in good agreement with OEMS measurements up to NCA potentials &gt;4.65 V Li . At higher potentials, the contributions from the reduction of TM II+ ions can be quantified by comparing the integrated SE current with the O 2 evolution from OEMS.</description>
      <author>Lennart Reuter, Leonhard Reinschl&#252;ssel, Hubert A. Gasteiger</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad8038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haemoglobin Gene Repertoire in Teleost and Cichlid Fishes Shaped by Gene Duplications and Genome Rearrangements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.17559</link>
      <description>Dmytro Omelchenko, Arnold Roger Bitja Nyom, Michael Matschiner, Milan Malinsky, Adrian Indermaur, Walter Salzburger, Old&#345;ich Barto&#353;, Zuzana Musilov&#225;, Molecular Ecology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403619473

                ABSTRACT Haemoglobin is a key molecule for oxygen transport in vertebrates. It exhibits remarkable gene diversity in teleost fishes, reflecting adaptation to various aquatic environments. In this study, we present the dynamic evolution of haemoglobin subunit genes based on a comparison of high&#8208;quality genome assemblies of 24 vertebrate species, including 17 teleosts (of which six are cichlids). Our findings indicate that teleost genomes contain a range of haemoglobin genes, from as few as five in fugu to as many as 43 in salmon, with the latter being the largest repertoire found in vertebrates. We find evidence that the teleost ancestor had at least four Hb&#945; and three or four Hb&#946; subunit genes, and that the current gene diversity emerged during teleost radiation, driven primarily by (tandem) gene duplications, genome compaction, and rearrangement dynamics. We provide insights into the genomic organisation of haemoglobin clusters in different teleost species. We further show that the evolution of paralogous rhbdf1 genes flanking both teleost clusters (LA and MN) supports the hypothesis for the origin of the LA cluster by rearrangement within teleosts, rather than by the teleost specific whole&#8208;genome duplication. We specifically focus on cichlid fishes, where adaptation to low oxygen environment plays role in species diversification. Our analysis of six cichlid genomes, including Pungu maclareni from the Barombi Mbo crater lake, for which we sequenced a representative genome, reveals 18&#8211;32 copies of the Hb genes, and elevated rates of non&#8208;synonymous substitutions compared to other teleosts. Overall, this work facilitates a deeper understanding of how haemoglobin genes contribute to the adaptive potential of teleosts.</description>
      <author>Dmytro Omelchenko, Arnold Roger Bitja Nyom, Michael Matschiner, Milan Malinsky, Adrian Indermaur, Walter Salzburger, Old&#345;ich Barto&#353;, Zuzana Musilov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.17559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Management of vulnerable patients hospitalized for COVID-19 with remdesivir: a retrospective comparative effectiveness study of mortality in US hospitals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciae512</link>
      <description>Essy Mozaffari, Aastha Chandak, Mark Berry, Paul E. Sax, Paul Loubet, Yohei Doi, Alpesh Amin, Neera Ahuja, Veronika M&#252;ller, Roman Casciano, Martin Kolditz, Clinical Infectious Diseases. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403524147

                Abstract Background COVID-19 remains a major public health concern, with continued resurgences of cases and substantial risk of mortality for hospitalized patients. Remdesivir has become standard-of-care for hospitalized COVID-19 patients. Given the continued evolution of the disease, clinical management relies on evidence from the current endemic period. Methods Using the PINC AI Healthcare database, effectiveness of remdesivir was evaluated among adults hospitalized with a primary diagnosis of COVID-19 between December 2021 and February 2024. Three cohorts were analysed: adults, elderly (&#8805;65 years), and those with documented COVID-19 pneumonia. Analyses were stratified by oxygen requirements. Patients receiving remdesivir were matched to those not receiving remdesivir using propensity score matching. Cox proportional hazards models were used to examine in-hospital mortality. Results 169,965 adults hospitalized for COVID-19 were included, of which 94,129 (55.4%) initiated remdesivir in the first two days of hospitalization. Remdesivir was associated with a significantly lower mortality rate as compared to no remdesivir among patients with no supplemental oxygen charges (NSOc) (aHR [95% CI]: 14-day, 0.75 [0.69-0.82]; 28-day, 0.77 [0.72-0.83]) and among those with supplemental oxygen charges (SOc): 14-day, 0.76 [0.72-0.81]; 28-day, 0.79 [0.74-0.83]) (p&amp;lt;0.0001, for all). Similar findings were observed for elderly patients and those hospitalized with COVID-19 pneumonia. Conclusions This evidence builds on learnings from randomized controlled trials from the pandemic era to inform clinical practices. Remdesivir was associated with significant reduction in mortality for hospitalized patients including the elderly and those with COVID-19 pneumonia.</description>
      <author>Essy Mozaffari, Aastha Chandak, Mark Berry, Paul E. Sax, Paul Loubet, Yohei Doi, Alpesh Amin, Neera Ahuja, Veronika M&#252;ller, Roman Casciano, Martin Kolditz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/cid/ciae512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanobubble Formation and Coverage during High Current Density Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03657</link>
      <description>Joshua A. Hammons, ShinYoung Kang, Thomas Ferron, Fikret Aydin, Tiras Y. Lin, Kansas Seung, Paul Chow, Yuming Xiao, Jonathan T. Davis, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403459328

                Gas bubbles are a necessary byproduct of water electrolysis whereby hydrogen and oxygen are produced from water. These attached gases reduce the electrode's active area, which necessitates a deep understanding of the bubble life cycle starting from nanobubbles. Synchronized with the electrochemistry, the time evolution of the surface nanobubble size and coverage is resolved using grazing incidence small-angle X-ray scattering (GISAXS) and correlated with optical microscopy and theoretical calculations to show that a significant portion of the surface is covered in nanobubbles after larger micron-sized bubbles are observed. These nanobubbles increase in number and decrease in size, toward 2 nm diameter, with the charge passed. The trend in size and number is consistent with an increase in supersaturation, which reduces the nascent bubble size. Altogether, this study suggests a significant portion of the surface contains nanobubbles and that strategies to reduce the dissolved hydrogen would be effective at reducing the nanobubble surface coverage.</description>
      <author>Joshua A. Hammons, ShinYoung Kang, Thomas Ferron, Fikret Aydin, Tiras Y. Lin, Kansas Seung, Paul Chow, Yuming Xiao, Jonathan T. Davis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c03657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalysis for Urea Evolution and Oxidation Through Confining Atomic Ni Into In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheet Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202415859</link>
      <description>Haoyue Sun, Sangseob Lee, Rui Tang, Lizhuo Wang, Cheng&#8208;Jie Yang, Weibin Liang, Shenlong Zhao, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Aloysius Soon, Jun Huang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403464827

                Abstract Urea, a highly sought&#8208;after fertilizer, is conventionally manufactured through the energy&#8208;intensive Haber&#8211;Bosch process but is frequently encountered as a pollutant in wastewater. Thus, achieving sustainable urea production under ambient conditions and the potential to recycle urea from wastewater represent significant eco&#8208;economic advancements. In this study, a novel Ni&#8208;confined In 2 O 3 (Ni&#8208;In 2 O 3 ) electrocatalyst demonstrating outstanding capabilities in both the urea evolution reaction (UER) from nitrate and carbon dioxide and the highly efficient urea oxidation reaction (UOR) for waste urea utilization is introduced. Computational data and in situ X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) analysis demonstrate that the unique Ni&#8208;oxygen vacancy (Ni&#8208;Vo) local structure effectively modulates the electronic configuration of neighboring In and Ni atoms. This structural refinement results in a significantly reduced energy barrier for the potential&#8208;determining steps (PDS) in both UER (*COOHNH 2 &#8594; *CONH 2 ) and UOR (*CO(NH 2 ) 2 &#8594; *CONHNH 2 ). Consequently, the optimized catalysts achieve a urea evolution faradic efficiency of 19.6%, accompanied by remarkable UOR performance, attaining a 100 mA cm &#8722;2 anodic current density at a potential of 1.35 V. This work not only offers a sustainable route to urea production but also highlights the potential for efficient urea oxidation, contributing to a greener and more economically viable future for the nitrogen cycle.</description>
      <author>Haoyue Sun, Sangseob Lee, Rui Tang, Lizhuo Wang, Cheng&#8208;Jie Yang, Weibin Liang, Shenlong Zhao, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Aloysius Soon, Jun Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202415859</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Performance of Mn2O3 Electrodes for Hydrogen Evolution Using Natural Bischofite Salt from Atacama Desert: A Novel Application for Solar Saline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205129</link>
      <description>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Edward Fuentealba, Susana Leiva-Guajardo, Luis C&#225;ceres, Carlos Portillo, Felipe D. Sep&#250;lveda, Iv&#225;n Brito, J.A. Cobos-Murcia, Omar F. Rojas-Moreno, Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, Eduardo Schott, &#193;lvaro Soliz, Materials. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403602520

                Solar saline water splitting is a promising approach to sustainable hydrogen production, harnessing abundant solar energy and the availability of brine resources, especially in the Atacama Desert. Bischofite salt (MgCl2&#183;6H2O) has garnered significant attention due to its wide range of industrial applications. Efficient hydrogen production in arid or hyper arid locations using bischofite solutions is a novel and revolutionary idea. This work studied the electrochemical performance of Mn2O3 electrodes using a superposition model based on mixed potential theory and evaluated the superficial performance of this electrode in contact with a 0.5 M bischofite salt solution focusing on the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) that occur during saline water splitting. The application of the non-linear superposition model provides valuable electrochemical kinetic parameters that complement the understanding of Mn2O3, this being one of the novelties of this work.</description>
      <author>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Edward Fuentealba, Susana Leiva-Guajardo, Luis C&#225;ceres, Carlos Portillo, Felipe D. Sep&#250;lveda, Iv&#225;n Brito, J.A. Cobos-Murcia, Omar F. Rojas-Moreno, Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, Eduardo Schott, &#193;lvaro Soliz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abundances of iron-peak elements in 58 bulge spheroid stars from APOGEE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202452235</link>
      <description>B. Barbuy, A. C. S. Fria&#231;a, H. Ernandes, Patricia Siqueira Silva, S. O. Souza, Jos&#233; G. Fern&#225;ndez-Trincado, K&#225;tia Cunha, Verne V. Smith, T. Masseron, A. P&#233;rez-Villegas, C. Chiappini, A. B. A. Queiroz, B. X. Santiago, Timothy C. Beers, F. Anders, Ricardo P. Schiavon, M. Valentini, S. Hoyer, D. Geisler, Diogo Souto, V. M Placco, M. Zoccali, S. Feltzing, M. Schultheis, C. Nitschelm, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403509626

                Stars presently identified in the bulge spheroid are probably very old, and their abundances can be interpreted as due to the fast chemical enrichment of the early Galactic bulge. The abundances of the iron-peak elements are important tracers of nucleosynthesis processes, in particular oxygen burning, silicon burning, the weak $s$-process, and alpha -rich freeze-out. The aim of this work is to derive the abundances of V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu in 58 bulge spheroid stars and to compare them with the results of a previous analysis of data from the Apache Point Observatory Galactic Evolution Experiment (APOGEE). We selected the best lines for V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu located within the H -band of the spectrum, identifying the most suitable ones for abundance determination, and discarding severe blends. Using the stellar physical parameters available for our sample from the DR17 release of the APOGEE project, we derived the individual abundances through spectrum synthesis. We then complemented these measurements with similar results from different bulge field and globular cluster stars, in order to define the trends of the individual elements and compare with the results of chemical-evolution models. We verify that the H -band has useful lines for the derivation of the elements V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu in moderately metal-poor stars. The abundances, plotted together with others from high-resolution spectroscopy of bulge stars, indicate that: V, Cr, and Ni vary in lockstep with Fe; Co tends to vary in lockstep with Fe, but could be showing a slight decrease with decreasing metallicity; and Mn and Cu decrease with decreasing metallicity. These behaviours are well reproduced by chemical-evolution models that adopt literature yields, except for Cu, which appears to drop faster than the models predict for Fe/H $&lt;$$-$0.8. Finally, abundance indicators combined with kinematical and dynamical criteria appear to show that our 58 sample stars are likely to have originated in situ.</description>
      <author>B. Barbuy, A. C. S. Fria&#231;a, H. Ernandes, Patricia Siqueira Silva, S. O. Souza, Jos&#233; G. Fern&#225;ndez-Trincado, K&#225;tia Cunha, Verne V. Smith, T. Masseron, A. P&#233;rez-Villegas, C. Chiappini, A. B. A. Queiroz, B. X. Santiago, Timothy C. Beers, F. Anders, Ricardo P. Schiavon, M. Valentini, S. Hoyer, D. Geisler, Diogo Souto, V. M Placco, M. Zoccali, S. Feltzing, M. Schultheis, C. Nitschelm</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202452235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Roles of Mitochondria in Human Being&#8217;s Life and Aging</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biom14101317</link>
      <description>Hiroko P. Indo, Moragot Chatatikun, Ikuo Nakanishi, Ken&#8208;ichiro Matsumoto, Motoki Imai, Fumitaka Kawakami, Miyoko Kubo, Hiroshi Abe, Hiroshi Ichikawa, Yoshikazu Yonei, Hidehiko Beppu, Yukiko Minamiyama, Takuro Kanekura, Takafumi Ichikawa, Atthaphong Phongphithakchai, Lunla Udomwech, Suriyan Sukati, Nurdina Charong, Voravuth Somsak, Jitbanjong Tangpong, Sachiyo Nomura, Hideyuki J. Majima, Biomolecules. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403479440

                The universe began 13.8 billion years ago, and Earth was born 4.6 billion years ago. Early traces of life were found as soon as 4.1 billion years ago; then, ~200,000 years ago, the human being was born. The evolution of life on earth was to become individual rather than cellular life. The birth of mitochondria made this possible to be the individual life. Since then, individuals have had a limited time of life. It was 1.4 billion years ago that a bacterial cell began living inside an archaeal host cell, a form of endosymbiosis that is the development of eukaryotic cells, which contain a nucleus and other membrane-bound compartments. The bacterium started to provide its host cell with additional energy, and the interaction eventually resulted in a eukaryotic cell, with both archaeal (the host cell) and bacterial (mitochondrial) origins still having genomes. The cells survived high concentrations of oxygen producing more energy inside the cell. Further, the roles of mitochondria in human being&#8217;s life and aging will be discussed.</description>
      <author>Hiroko P. Indo, Moragot Chatatikun, Ikuo Nakanishi, Ken&#8208;ichiro Matsumoto, Motoki Imai, Fumitaka Kawakami, Miyoko Kubo, Hiroshi Abe, Hiroshi Ichikawa, Yoshikazu Yonei, Hidehiko Beppu, Yukiko Minamiyama, Takuro Kanekura, Takafumi Ichikawa, Atthaphong Phongphithakchai, Lunla Udomwech, Suriyan Sukati, Nurdina Charong, Voravuth Somsak, Jitbanjong Tangpong, Sachiyo Nomura, Hideyuki J. Majima</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biom14101317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abundances of iron-peak elements in 58 bulge spheroid stars from APOGEE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.13751</link>
      <description>B. Barbuy, A. C. S. Fria&#231;a, H. Ernandes, Patricia Siqueira Silva, S. O. Souza, J. G. Fern&#225;ndez-Trincado, K&#225;tia Cunha, V. V. Smith, T. Masseron, &#193;ngeles P&#233;rez-Villegas, C. Chiappini, A. B. A. Queiroz, B. X. Santiago, T. C. Beers, F. Anders, Ricardo P. Schiavon, M. Valentini, D. Minniti, D. Geisler, Diogo Souto, Vinicius M. Placco, M. Zoccali, S. Feltzing, M. Schultheis, C. Nitschelm, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403580076

                Stars presently identified in the bulge spheroid are probably very old, and their abundances can be interpreted as due to the fast chemical enrichment of the early Galactic bulge. The abundances of the iron-peak elements are important tracers of nucleosynthesis processes, in particular oxygen burning, silicon burning, the weak s-process, and alpha-rich freeze-out. Aims. The aim of this work is to derive the abundances of V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu in 58 bulge spheroid stars and to compare them with the results of a previous analysis of data from APOGEE. We selected the best lines for V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu located within the H-band of the spectrum, identifying the most suitable ones for abundance determination, and discarding severe blends. Using the stellar physical parameters available for our sample from the DR17 release of the APOGEE project, we derived the individual abundances through spectrum synthesis. We then complemented these measurements with similar results from different bulge field and globular cluster stars, in order to define the trends of the individual elements and compare with the results of chemical-evolution models. We verify that the H-band has useful lines for the derivation of the elements V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu in moderately metal-poor stars. The resulting abundances indicate that: V, Cr, and Ni vary in lockstep with Fe; Co tends to vary in lockstep with Fe, but could be showing a slight decrease with decreasing metallicity; and Mn and Cu decrease with decreasing metallicity. These behaviours are well reproduced by chemical-evolution models except for Cu, which appears to drop faster than the models predict for moderate metallicities. Finally, abundance indicators combined with kinematical and dynamical criteria appear to show that our 58 sample stars are likely to have originated in situ.</description>
      <author>B. Barbuy, A. C. S. Fria&#231;a, H. Ernandes, Patricia Siqueira Silva, S. O. Souza, J. G. Fern&#225;ndez-Trincado, K&#225;tia Cunha, V. V. Smith, T. Masseron, &#193;ngeles P&#233;rez-Villegas, C. Chiappini, A. B. A. Queiroz, B. X. Santiago, T. C. Beers, F. Anders, Ricardo P. Schiavon, M. Valentini, D. Minniti, D. Geisler, Diogo Souto, Vinicius M. Placco, M. Zoccali, S. Feltzing, M. Schultheis, C. Nitschelm</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.13751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Structural and Chemical Evolution of Layered Oxide Cathode for Na&#8208;Ion Batteries Induced by Water Vapor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410485</link>
      <description>Pengxiang Ji, Xincheng Lei, Li Wang, Zhen Han, Yuhan Wang, Yangfan Li, Mengshu Ge, Jianxiong Zhao, Sijie Guo, Xiao-zhi Liu, Xuefeng Wang, Lin Gu, An&#8208;Min Cao, Dong Su, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403464806

                Abstract Na&#8208;ion batteries (NIBs) have received considerable attention as promising alternatives to lithium&#8208;ion batteries, particularly for low&#8208;speed electric vehicles and large&#8208;scale energy storage applications. Currently, layered oxide compounds are considered the most important cathode materials for NIBs. However, they suffer from reduced capacity and a shortened lifespan when exposed to water vapor during storage or battery assembly. This article elaborates on the structural and chemical evolution of NaNi 1/3 Fe 1/3 Mn 1/3 O 2 (NFM) cathode at the atomic scale in a pure water vapor environment. The Na + /H + exchange induces the formation of a spinel&#8208;like phase via a multi&#8208;site nucleation mechanism. This transition preferentially occurs either at the cathode surface or along planar defects such as twin boundaries and grain boundaries. Additionally, numerous microcracks perpendicular to &lt;003&gt; direction appear inside NFM grains, further exacerbating the structural deterioration. Upon prolonged exposure to water vapor, NFM grains decompose into a mixture of Na 2 O and transition metal oxide nanoparticles (FeO, NiO, and MnO), accompanied by the generation of oxygen gas. This research provides a comprehensive atomic&#8208;scale insight into the water vapor instability mechanism of layered oxide cathodes, offering guidance for the design and manufacture of the next generation of water vapor&#8208;tolerant layered oxide cathodes in NIBs.</description>
      <author>Pengxiang Ji, Xincheng Lei, Li Wang, Zhen Han, Yuhan Wang, Yangfan Li, Mengshu Ge, Jianxiong Zhao, Sijie Guo, Xiao-zhi Liu, Xuefeng Wang, Lin Gu, An&#8208;Min Cao, Dong Su</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202410485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Reversible Zn Anode Design Through Oriented ZnO(002) Facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408908</link>
      <description>Chengwu Yang, Pattaraporn Woottapanit, Sining Geng, Kittima Lolupiman, Qian Zhang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Guanjie He, Jiaqian Qin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615344

                Abstract The practical implementation of aqueous Zn&#8208;ion batteries presents formidable hurdles, including uncontrolled dendrite growth, water&#8208;induced side reactions, suboptimal Zn metal utilization, and intricate Zn anode manufacturing. Here, large&#8208;scale construction of a highly oriented ZnO(002) lattice plane on Zn anode (ZnO(002)@Zn) with thermodynamic inertia and kinetic zincophilicity is designed to address such problems. Both theoretical calculations and experiment results elucidate that the ZnO(002)@Zn possesses high Zn chemical affinity, hydrogen evolution reaction suppression, and dendrite&#8208;free deposition ability due to the abundant lattice oxygen species in ZnO(002) and its low lattice mismatch with Zn(002). These features synergistically promote ion transport and enable homogeneous Zn deposition. Consequently, the ZnO(002)@Zn anode displays a stable and prolonged cycling lifespan exceeding 500 h even under a larger depth of discharge (85.6%) and realizes an impressive average Coulombic efficiency of 99.7%. Moreover, its efficacy is also evident in V 2 O 5 &#8208;cathode coin cells and pouch cells with not only high discharge capacity but also exceptional cycling stability. This integrated approach presents a promising avenue for addressing the challenges associated with Zn metal anodes, thereby advancing the prospects of aqueous Zn&#8208;ion battery technologies.</description>
      <author>Chengwu Yang, Pattaraporn Woottapanit, Sining Geng, Kittima Lolupiman, Qian Zhang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Guanjie He, Jiaqian Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the Mechanism of Oxidative Potential Increase in Atmospheric Particulate Matter during Photoaging: Important Role of Aromatic Nitrogenous Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03199</link>
      <description>Qingwen Wang, Qingcai Chen, Hao Lin, Jiale Ding, Tong Sha, Yuemei Han, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633329

                Particulate matter (PM) undergoing various aging processes in the atmosphere changes its toxicity. However, the mechanism of toxicity evolution is not fully clarified currently. This study demonstrates that photoaging promotes an increase in the oxidative potential (OP) of atmospheric PM by about 30%, and the increased OP is mainly attributed to the production of secondary organic compounds, while water-soluble metal ions contribute only 11%. The OP of nonextractable matters (NEMs) of atmospheric PM was mostly increased after photoaging, followed by water-soluble matters (WSMs). NEM can produce quinone-like functional groups and secondary persistent free radicals during photoaging, which are most likely to produce reactive oxygen species (ROS). For WSM, the conversion of low-oxidation humic-like substances (HULIS) to high-oxidation HULIS is the main reason for the increase in OP. Quinones, nitrophenols, and N-containing heterocycles are the OP contributors produced during the conversion process. Among them, quinones are the main secondary oxidizing active compounds, while nitro-phenolic compounds and N-containing heterocyclic compounds may play a catalyst-like role, facilitating the production of oxidizing active compounds and ROS in the newly converted high-oxidation HULIS. This study clarifies the secondary OP generation mechanism and provides new insights into the uncertainty of PM toxicity during atmospheric aging.</description>
      <author>Qingwen Wang, Qingcai Chen, Hao Lin, Jiale Ding, Tong Sha, Yuemei Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A growth-coupling strategy for improving the stability of terpenoid bioproduction in Escherichia coli</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12934-024-02548-1</link>
      <description>Joo Shun Tan, Qitiao Hu, Nigel S. Scrutton, Microbial Cell Factories. 23(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403470371

                Abstract Background Achieving cost-competitiveness remains challenging for industrial biomanufacturing. With whole-cell biocatalysis, inefficiency presents when individual cells vary in their production levels. The problem exacerbates when the basis for such production heterogeneity is heritable. Here, evolution selects for the low- and non-producers, as they have lowered/abolished the cost of bioproduction to fitness. With the scale of population expansion required for industrial bioproduction, the asymmetrical enrichment can be severe enough to compromise the performance, and hence commercial viability of the bioprocess. Clearly, addressing production heterogeneity is crucial, especially in improving the stability of bioproduction across the cell generations. In this respect, we designed a growth-coupling strategy for terpenoid bioproduction in Escherichia coli . By knocking out the native 1-deoxy-D-xylulose 5-phosphate reductoisomerase ( dxr ) gene and introducing the heterologous mevalonate pathway, we created a chassis that relies solely on the latter for synthesis of all terpenoids. We hypothesise that the need to sustain the biosynthesis of endogenous life-sustaining terpenoids will impose a minimum level of productivity, which concomitantly improves the bioproduction of our target terpenoid. Results Following the confirmation of lethality of a dxr knockout, we challenged the strains with a continuous plasmid-based bioproduction of linalool. The &#916; dxr strain achieved an improved productivity profile in the first three days post-inoculation when compared to the parental strain. Productivity of the &#916; dxr strain remained observable near the end of 12 days, and after a disruption in nutrient and oxygen supply in a separate run. Unlike the parental strain, the &#916; dxr strain did not evolve the same deleterious mutations in the mevalonate pathway, nor a viable subgroup that had lost its resistance to the antibiotic selection pressure (a plausible plasmid loss event). We believe that this divergence in the evolution trajectories is indicative of a successful growth-coupling. Conclusion We have demonstrated a proof of concept of a growth-coupling strategy that improves the performance, and stability of terpenoid bioproduction across cell generations. The strategy is relatively broad in scope, and easy to implement in the background as a &#8216;fail-safe&#8217; against a fall in productivity below the imposed minimum. We thus believe this work will find widespread utility in our collective effort towards industrial bioproduction.</description>
      <author>Joo Shun Tan, Qitiao Hu, Nigel S. Scrutton</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12934-024-02548-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct estimates of nitrogen abundance for Seyfert 2 nuclei</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2253</link>
      <description>O. L. Dors, M. V. Cardaci, G. F. H&#228;gele, Mabel Valerdi, Gabriele S Ilha, C B Oliveira, Rogemar A. Riffel, Sophia R. Flury, Karla Z. Arellano-C&#243;rdova, Tha&#237;sa Storchi-Bergmann, Rog&#233;rio Riffel, G. C. Almeida, I. N. Morais, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403445653

                Abstract We derive the nitrogen and oxygen abundances in the Narrow Line Regions (NLRs) of a sample of 38 local (z &amp;lt; 0.4) Seyfert 2 nuclei. For that, we consider narrow optical emission line intensities and direct estimates of the electron temperatures (Te-method). We obtain a new theoretical expression for the nitrogen Ionization Correction Factor [ICF($\rm N^{+}$)] for NLRs. Applying this new ICF, we unexpectedly find that NLRs and disk H ii regions exhibit similar ICF distributions. We find nitrogen abundances in the range $7.6 \: &amp;lt; \: \rm 12+log(N/H) \: &amp;lt; \: 8.6$ (mean value 8.06 &#177; 0.22) or $\rm 0.4 \: &amp;lt; \: (N/N_{\odot }) \: &amp;lt; 4.7$, in the metallicity regime $8.3 \: &amp;lt; \: \rm 12+log(O/H) \: &amp;lt; \: 9.0$. Our results indicate that the dispersion in N/H abundance for a fixed O/H value in AGNs of &#8764;0.2 dex agrees with that for disc H ii regions with similar metallicity. We show that Seyfert 2 nuclei follow a similar (N/O)-(O/H) relation to the one followed by star-forming objects. Finally, we find that active galaxies called as &#8221;nitrogen-loud&#8221; observed at very high redshift (z &amp;gt; 5) show N/O values in consonance with those derived for local NLRs. This result indicates that the main star-formation event is completed in the early evolution stages of active galaxies.</description>
      <author>O. L. Dors, M. V. Cardaci, G. F. H&#228;gele, Mabel Valerdi, Gabriele S Ilha, C B Oliveira, Rogemar A. Riffel, Sophia R. Flury, Karla Z. Arellano-C&#243;rdova, Tha&#237;sa Storchi-Bergmann, Rog&#233;rio Riffel, G. C. Almeida, I. N. Morais</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant Dynamical Paramagnetism in the driven pseudogap phase of $ \rm
  YBa_2Cu_3O_{6+x}$</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.12919</link>
      <description>Marios H. Michael, Duilio De Santis, Eugene Demler, Patrick A. Lee, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403578830

                In the past decade, photo-induced superconducting-like behaviors have been reported in a number of materials driven by intense pump fields. Of particular interest is the high-$T_c$ cuprate $\rm Y Ba_2 Cu_2 O_{6+x}$, where such effect has been reported up to the so-called pseudogap temperature $T^* \sim 300-400$ K. In a recent tour-de-force experiment, a transient magnetic field which is proportional to and in the same direction of an applied field has been observed outside the sample, suggestive of flux exclusion due to the Meissner effect. In this paper, we point out that the transient magnetic field could be explained by a model of bilayers of copper-oxygen planes with a local superconducting phase variable persisting up to the pseudo-gap temperature at equilibrium. Under pumping, the time evolution is described by a driven sine-Gordon equation. In the presence of an external magnetic field, this model exhibits a novel instability which amplifies the current at the edges of the bilayer formed by defects or grain boundaries, producing a giant paramagnetic magnetization in the same direction as the applied field. We present how this scenario can fit most of the available data and propose additional experimental tests which can distinguish our proposal from the Meissner flux exclusion scenario. To the extent that this model can account for the data, we conclude that the experiments have the important consequence of revealing the presence of local pairing in the pseudogap phase. More broadly, this work provides a new mechanism for amplifying external magnetic fields at ultra-fast time scales.</description>
      <author>Marios H. Michael, Duilio De Santis, Eugene Demler, Patrick A. Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.12919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restructuring the interfacial active sites to generalize the volcano curves for platinum-cobalt synergistic catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53474-0</link>
      <description>Wenyao Chen, Yao Shi, Changwei Liu, Zhouhong Ren, Zhigang Huang, Zhou Chen, Xiangxue Zhang, Shanshan Liang, Lei Xie, Cheng Lian, Gang Qian, Jing Zhang, Xi Liu, De Chen, Xinggui Zhou, Weikang Yuan, Xuezhi Duan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403546946

                Computationally derived volcano curve has become the gold standard in catalysis, whose practical application usually relies on empirical interpretations of composition or size effects by the identical active site assumption. Here, we present a proof-of-concept study on disclosing both the support- and adsorbate-induced restructuring of Pt-Co bimetallic catalysts, and the related interplays among different interfacial sites to propose the synergy-dependent volcano curves. Multiple characterizations, isotopic kinetic investigations, and multiscale simulations unravel that the progressive incorporation of Co into Pt catalysts, driven by strong Pt-C bonding (metal-support interfaces) and Co-O bonding (metal-adsorbate interfaces), initiates the formation of Pt-rich alloys accompanied by isolated Co species, then Co segregation to epitaxial CoOx overlayers and adjacent Co3O4 clusters, and ultimately structural collapse into amorphous alloys. Accordingly, three distinct synergies, involving lattice oxygen redox from Pt-Co alloy/Co3O4 clusters, dual-active sites engineering via Pt-rich alloy/CoOx overlayer, and electron coupling within exposed alloy, are identified and quantified for CO oxidation (gas-phase), ammonia borane hydrolysis (liquid-phase), and hydrogen evolution reaction (electrocatalysis), respectively. The resultant synergy-dependent volcano curves represent an advancement over traditional composition-/size-dependent ones, serving as a bridge between theoretical models and experimental observations in bimetallic catalysis. Volcano curves have become the gold standard in catalyst design. Here, the authors propose synergy-dependent volcano curves by disclosing both support- and adsorbate-induced catalyst restructuring, ideally bridging the gap between theoretical models and experimental observations.</description>
      <author>Wenyao Chen, Yao Shi, Changwei Liu, Zhouhong Ren, Zhigang Huang, Zhou Chen, Xiangxue Zhang, Shanshan Liang, Lei Xie, Cheng Lian, Gang Qian, Jing Zhang, Xi Liu, De Chen, Xinggui Zhou, Weikang Yuan, Xuezhi Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53474-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PPCon 1.0: Biogeochemical-Argo profile prediction with 1D convolutional networks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-17-7347-2024</link>
      <description>Gloria Pietropolli, Luca Manzoni, Gianpiero Cossarini, Geoscientific model development. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403473897

                Abstract. Effective observation of the ocean is vital for studying and assessing the state and evolution of the marine ecosystem and for evaluating the impact of human activities. However, obtaining comprehensive oceanic measurements across temporal and spatial scales and for different biogeochemical variables remains challenging. Autonomous oceanographic instruments, such as Biogeochemical (BGC)-Argo profiling floats, have helped expand our ability to obtain subsurface and deep-ocean measurements, but measuring biogeochemical variables, such as nutrient concentration, still remains more demanding and expensive than measuring physical variables. Therefore, developing methods to estimate marine biogeochemical variables from high-frequency measurements is very much needed. Current neural network (NN) models developed for this task are based on a multilayer perceptron (MLP) architecture, trained over point-wise pairs of input&#8211;output features. Although MLPs can produce smooth outputs if the inputs change smoothly, convolutional neural networks (CNNs) are inherently designed to handle profile data effectively. In this study, we present a novel one-dimensional (1D) CNN model to predict profiles leveraging the typical shape of vertical profiles of a variable as a prior constraint during training. In particular, the Predict Profiles Convolutional (PPCon) model predicts nitrate, chlorophyll, and backscattering (bbp700) starting from the date and geolocation and from temperature, salinity, and oxygen profiles. Its effectiveness is demonstrated using a robust BGC-Argo dataset collected in the Mediterranean Sea for training and validation. Results, which include quantitative metrics and visual representations, prove the capability of PPCon to produce smooth and accurate profile predictions improving upon previous MLP applications.</description>
      <author>Gloria Pietropolli, Luca Manzoni, Gianpiero Cossarini</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/gmd-17-7347-2024</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
