<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 01:24:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-defective ruthenium oxide as an efficient and durable electrocatalyst for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06592a</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Lejuan Cai, Zhipeng Yu, Hao Tan, Xinyi Xiang, Kaiyang Xu, Chao Yang, Sitaramanjaneya Mouli Thalluri, Fei Lin, Haoliang Huang, Chenyue Zhang, Yang Zhao, Wenlong Wang, Lifeng Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404233886

                Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) is considered a promising technology for green hydrogen production in combination with renewable energy. However, the high cost and particularly the scarcity of iridium...</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Lejuan Cai, Zhipeng Yu, Hao Tan, Xinyi Xiang, Kaiyang Xu, Chao Yang, Sitaramanjaneya Mouli Thalluri, Fei Lin, Haoliang Huang, Chenyue Zhang, Yang Zhao, Wenlong Wang, Lifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06592a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermal-Induced Cationic Vacancies in NiAl Hydroxide for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Activities through Optimization of e&lt;sub&gt;g&lt;/sub&gt;* Band Broadening</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14089</link>
      <description>Haoyan Meng, Junhua Li, Chao Wu, Qi Zhang, Li Wang, Ying Tang, Anqi Zou, Yiming Zhang, Rui Ma, Zhi Gen Yu, Feng Gao, Shibo Xi, Junmin Xue, Xiaopeng Wang, Jiagang Wu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404235787

                Nickel-based hydroxides [Ni(OH)</description>
      <author>Haoyan Meng, Junhua Li, Chao Wu, Qi Zhang, Li Wang, Ying Tang, Anqi Zou, Yiming Zhang, Rui Ma, Zhi Gen Yu, Feng Gao, Shibo Xi, Junmin Xue, Xiaopeng Wang, Jiagang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Doped Ni-Based Catalysts Surpass Ir-Baselines for Oxygen Evolution Due to Optimal Charge-Transfer Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</link>
      <description>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237251

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mai&#8208;Anh Ha, Shaun M Alia, Andrew G. Norman, Elisa M. Miller</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machine-Learning-Assisted Screening of Nanocluster Electrocatalysts: Mapping and Reshaping the Activity Volcano for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14076</link>
      <description>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Milan Kumar Jena, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404241066

                In computational heterogeneous catalysis, Sabatier's principle-based activity volcano plots provide an intuitive guide to catalyst design but impose a fundamental constraint on the maximum achievable catalytic performance. Recently, subnano clusters have emerged as an exciting platform, offering high noble metal utilization and superior performance for various reactions compared to extended surfaces, reflecting a complex structure-activity relationship in the non-scalable regime. However, understanding their non-monotonic catalytic activity, attributed to the large configurational space and their fluxional identity, poses a formidable challenge. Here, we present a machine learning (ML) framework that captures the non-monotonic trends in oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity at the subnanometer scale, attributed to their dynamic fluxional characteristics. We demonstrate a size-dependent shifting and reshaping of the ORR activity volcano, with Au replacing Pt at the peak. Leveraging only upon the non-</description>
      <author>Rahul Kumar Sharma, Milan Kumar Jena, Harpriya Minhas, Biswarup Pathak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14076</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Engineering of Ruo2/Coooh Heterojunction for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5016770</link>
      <description>Ji-Sen Li, Xianjun Niu, Yin-Lei Ma, Jun-Ya Gao, Shumei Sun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404242056

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ji-Sen Li, Xianjun Niu, Yin-Lei Ma, Jun-Ya Gao, Shumei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5016770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactivity and Stability of Reduced Ir-Weight TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported Oxygen Evolution Catalysts for Proton Exchange Membrane (PEM) Water Electrolyzer Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07002</link>
      <description>Hoang Phi Tran, Hong Nhan Nong, Matej Zlatar, Aram Yoon, Uta Hejral, Martina R&#252;scher, Janis Timoshenko, S&#246;ren Selve, Dirk Berger, Matthias Kroschel, Malte Klingenhof, Benjamin Paul, Sebastian M&#246;hle, Kerolus Nasser Nagi Nasralla, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Arno Bergmann, Serhiy Cherevko, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Peter Strasser, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404246558

                Reducing the iridium demand in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers (PEM WE) is a critical priority for the green hydrogen industry. This study reports the discovery of a TiO</description>
      <author>Hoang Phi Tran, Hong Nhan Nong, Matej Zlatar, Aram Yoon, Uta Hejral, Martina R&#252;scher, Janis Timoshenko, S&#246;ren Selve, Dirk Berger, Matthias Kroschel, Malte Klingenhof, Benjamin Paul, Sebastian M&#246;hle, Kerolus Nasser Nagi Nasralla, Daniel Escalera&#8208;L&#243;pez, Arno Bergmann, Serhiy Cherevko, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Peter Strasser</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c07002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-organic framework-based self-supported electrodes for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.26</link>
      <description>Shulin Li, Dai Tang, Xiaofei Jing, Chemical Synthesis. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404249552

                Oxygen evolution reactions (OER), commonly employed in applications such as metal-air batteries, water electrolysis, fuel cells, etc. , often suffer from slow kinetics, thus leading to ultra-high potentials that severely affect device energy efficiency. Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have garnered massive attention as electrodes for OER, benefiting from their highly ordered porous frameworks, abundant accessible active metal sites, and adjustable lattice structures. However, using powdered MOFs in OER poses a challenge, limiting the exposure of numerous active sites and resulting in suboptimal efficiency. To address this limitation, the trend towards designing MOF-based self-supported electrodes with enhanced contact between MOFs and the current collector has gained considerable attention for OER applications. This review highlights recent advancements and future prospects in developing MOF-based self-supported electrodes for OER. We delve into various aspects, including preparation methods, optimization strategies, catalytic efficiencies, and OER mechanisms with MOF-based electrocatalysts. Furthermore, we explore the existing challenges associated with MOF-based self-supported electrodes for OER. This comprehensive overview provides valuable insights into the evolving landscape of MOF-based materials in advancing OER.</description>
      <author>Shulin Li, Dai Tang, Xiaofei Jing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.26</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation Migration&#8208;Induced Lattice Oxygen Oxidation in Spinel Oxide for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416757</link>
      <description>Lydia Helena Wong, Mahmoud G. Ahmed, Ying Fan Tay, Xiao Chi, Ahmed S. Razeen, Yanan Fang, Mengyuan Zhang, Anqi Sng, Sing Yang Chiam, Andrivo Rusydi, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404251421

                Activating the lattice oxygen can significantly improve the kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), however, it often results in reduced stability due to the bulk structure degradation. Here, we develop a spinel Fe0.3Co0.9Cr1.8O4 with active lattice oxygen by high-throughput methods, achieving high OER activity and stability, superior to the benchmark IrO2. The oxide exhibits an ultralow overpotential (190 mV at 10 mA cm-2) with outstanding stability for over 170 h at 100 mA cm-2. Soft X-ray absorption- and Raman-spectroscopies, combined with 18O isotope-labelling experiments, reveal that lattice oxygen activation is driven by Cr oxidation, which induces a cation migration from CrO6 octahedrons to CrO4 tetrahedrons. The geometry conversion creates accessible non-bonding oxygen states, crucial for lattice oxygen oxidation. Upon oxidation, peroxo O-O bond is formed and further stabilized by Cr6+ (CrO4 tetrahedra) via dimerization. This work establishes a new approach for designing efficient catalysts that feature active and stable lattice oxygen without compromising structural integrity.</description>
      <author>Lydia Helena Wong, Mahmoud G. Ahmed, Ying Fan Tay, Xiao Chi, Ahmed S. Razeen, Yanan Fang, Mengyuan Zhang, Anqi Sng, Sing Yang Chiam, Andrivo Rusydi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation Migration&#8208;Induced Lattice Oxygen Oxidation in Spinel Oxide for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416757</link>
      <description>Lydia Helena Wong, Mahmoud G. Ahmed, Ying Fan Tay, Xiao Chi, Ahmed S. Razeen, Yanan Fang, Mengyuan Zhang, Anqi Sng, Sing Yang Chiam, Andrivo Rusydi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404251472

                Activating the lattice oxygen can significantly improve the kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), however, it often results in reduced stability due to the bulk structure degradation. Here, we develop a spinel Fe0.3Co0.9Cr1.8O4 with active lattice oxygen by high&#8208;throughput methods, achieving high OER activity and stability, superior to the benchmark IrO2. The oxide exhibits an ultralow overpotential (190 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2) with outstanding stability for over 170 h at 100 mA cm&#8211;2. Soft X&#8208;ray absorption&#8208; and Raman&#8208;spectroscopies, combined with 18O isotope&#8208;labelling experiments, reveal that lattice oxygen activation is driven by Cr oxidation, which induces a cation migration from CrO6 octahedrons to CrO4 tetrahedrons. The geometry conversion creates accessible non&#8208;bonding oxygen states, crucial for lattice oxygen oxidation. Upon oxidation, peroxo O&#8211;O bond is formed and further stabilized by Cr6+ (CrO4 tetrahedra) via dimerization. This work establishes a new approach for designing efficient catalysts that feature active and stable lattice oxygen without compromising structural integrity.</description>
      <author>Lydia Helena Wong, Mahmoud G. Ahmed, Ying Fan Tay, Xiao Chi, Ahmed S. Razeen, Yanan Fang, Mengyuan Zhang, Anqi Sng, Sing Yang Chiam, Andrivo Rusydi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416757</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cqds Modified Tio2/Sn-Fe2o3-X Heterojunction Photoanode with Abundant Oxygen Vacancies for Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5018120</link>
      <description>Na Dai, Yingjie Zhang, Zhiwei Peng, Ji&#8208;Kai Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404254074

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Na Dai, Yingjie Zhang, Zhiwei Peng, Ji&#8208;Kai Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5018120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activation of Hidden Catalytic Sites in 2D Basal Plane via p&#8211;n Heterojunction Interface Engineering Toward Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403722</link>
      <description>Eugene Kim, Sungsoon Kim, Yong&#8208;Chul Kim, Kiran Hamkins, Jihyun Baek, MinJoong Kim, Tae&#8208;Kyung Liu, Young Moon Choi, Jung Hwan Lee, Gyu Yong Jang, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Geunsik Lee, Xiaolin Zheng, Jong Hyeok Park, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404255224

                Abstract Nonprecious metal&#8208;based 2D materials have shown promising electrocatalytic activity toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the catalytically active sites of 2D materials are mainly presented at the edge, and most of their basal planes are still catalytically inactive, which turns into a significant drawback on the catalytic efficiency. Here, a novel p&#8211;n heterojunction strategy is suggested that generates active sites on the basal plane of 2D NiFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH). The n&#8208;type NiFe&#8208;LDH is first grown on a nickel foam (NF) substrate, and p&#8208;type Co 3 O 4 nanocubes are deposited through a simple dip&#8208;coating method to fabricate a Co 3 O 4 /NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF p&#8211;n heterojunction electrode. As a result, electron transfer is induced at the interface of p&#8208;type Co 3 O 4 and n&#8208;type NiFe&#8208;LDH, which consequently promotes oxidation of the inert Ni 2+ state to a more catalytically active Ni 3+ state on the inert basal plane of NiFe&#8208;LDH. As&#8208;prepared Co 3 O 4 /NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF electrodes obtained enhanced OER performance showing a high current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.48 V (vs RHE) which outperforms that of pristine NiFe&#8208;LDH@NF. The utilization of the p&#8211;n junction concept will disclose a new strategy for modifying the electronic structure of the catalytically inactive basal plane and stimulating its electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Eugene Kim, Sungsoon Kim, Yong&#8208;Chul Kim, Kiran Hamkins, Jihyun Baek, MinJoong Kim, Tae&#8208;Kyung Liu, Young Moon Choi, Jung Hwan Lee, Gyu Yong Jang, Kug&#8208;Seung Lee, Geunsik Lee, Xiaolin Zheng, Jong Hyeok Park</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced photocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution activity by two-dimensional van der Waals AlSb/ZnO heterostructure: A first-principles study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105397</link>
      <description>Aroni Ghosh, Ahmed Zubair, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404258858

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aroni Ghosh, Ahmed Zubair</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directing the Electrode-Electrolyte Interface Towards Active
  Nickel-Based Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.16715</link>
      <description>Ben Wang, Tomohiro Fukushima, Hiro Minamimoto, Andrey Lyalin, Kei Murakoshi, Tetsuya Taketsugu, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404261170

                A comprehensive understanding of the electrode-electrolyte interface in energy conversion systems remains challenging due to the complex and multifaceted nature of interfacial processes. This complexity hinders the development of more efficient electrocatalysts. In this work, we propose a hybrid approach to the theoretical description of the OER process on nickel-iron-based oxyhydroxides ($\gamma$-Ni$_{1-x}$Fe$_x$OOH) electrodes in alkaline media as a model system. Multiple reaction pathways represented by the single- and dual-site mechanisms were investigated by taking into account the realistic structure of the catalyst, the doping, and the solvation effects using a simple and computationally feasible strategy. Accounting for the variable solvation effects considerably affects the predicted overpotential in a roughly linear relationship between overpotential and dielectric constant. By incorporating quantum chemical simulations with kinetic modeling, we demonstrate that tuning the local solvation environment can significantly enhance the OER activity, opening new routine ways for elucidation of the emerging issues of OER processes on transition metal oxide surfaces and design of cost-effective, efficient electrocatalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Ben Wang, Tomohiro Fukushima, Hiro Minamimoto, Andrey Lyalin, Kei Murakoshi, Tetsuya Taketsugu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.16715</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Front Cover: Graphitic Carbon Nitride Structures on Carbon Cloth Containing Ultra&#8208; and Nano&#8208;Dispersed NiO for Photoactivated Oxygen Evolution (ChemSusChem 21/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202482101</link>
      <description>Enrico Scattolin, Mattia Benedet, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Oleg I. Lebedev, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato, ChemSusChem. 17(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404263367

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Enrico Scattolin, Mattia Benedet, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Oleg I. Lebedev, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202482101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Dihydroxyacetone Production via Photoelectrochemical Glycerol Oxidation using Oxygen Vacant BiVO4 Photoanode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04085f</link>
      <description>Yeji Lee, Yeseul Jo, Youn Jeong Jang, Journal of Materials Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404271363

                Photoelectrochemical conversion of glycerol into high-value dihydroxyacetone offers a sustainable approach via BiVO4 semiconductor materials, which manifest highly photoactive properties. However, dihydroxyacetone production poses a limitation due to poor charge...</description>
      <author>Yeji Lee, Yeseul Jo, Youn Jeong Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04085f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal Single Atom&#8208;Hydroxyl Incorporation in Poly(heptazine imide) to Create Active Sites for Photocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408436</link>
      <description>Wenxuan Hu, Aifeng Li, Haiping Li, Yu Wang, Zhenzhong Fan, Quanhua Deng, Guoan Wang, Yuguo Xia, Wanguo Hou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404273304

                Abstract Poly(heptazine imide) (PHI) salts are extensively researched crystalline carbon nitride photocatalysts, but their photocatalytic water oxidation (PWO) performance is scarcely researched because of the difficulty in creating efficient active sites. Interference of metal ion (e.g., Na + and K + ) loss from the PHI salts in their PWO research has hardly been considered. Herein, metal single atom&#9472;OH (e.g., Co&#9472;OH) groups are incorporated into PHI to create efficient PWO active sites, via simple ion metathesis, hydrolysis, and deprotonation. The Co&#9472;OH modified PHI exhibits 9.3&#8208;fold higher PWO (oxygen evolution) activity than PHI, with an external quantum yield reaching 0.44% even at 600 nm. Excluding interference of the metal ion loss, the function of the Co&#9472;OH incorporation is evidenced mainly to facilitate the oxygen evolution reaction, as well as to promote photogenerated charge separation and raise visible light absorption, with the role of the OH especially revealed. Moreover, it is discovered that Na + loss from sodium PHI will decrease its PWO activity, protonation of PHI has a detrimental effect on its PWO performance, and some other metal single atom&#9472;OH incorporation in PHI can also enhance its PWO activity. Overall, this work provides a general way to create PWO active sites in PHI.</description>
      <author>Wenxuan Hu, Aifeng Li, Haiping Li, Yu Wang, Zhenzhong Fan, Quanhua Deng, Guoan Wang, Yuguo Xia, Wanguo Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Active Oxygen Evolution Reaction of NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Sub&#8208;1 nm Nanowires Boosts Luminol Electrochemiluminescence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407321</link>
      <description>Hao Zang, Dong Mei Wang, Wen Dai, Lin Chen, Yi&#8208;Ting Wang, Qiang Wang, Li Wang, Gao Chen, Jia Li, Jia Xie, Hong Yan Zou, Cheng Huang, Yuan Fang Li, Shu Jun Zhen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404275027

                Abstract In recent years, there has been an increasing research focus on the luminol&#8211;H 2 O electrochemiluminescence (ECL) system due to its ability to address the instability and toxicity of H 2 O 2 , which are common issues associated with the conventional luminol&#8211;H 2 O 2 ECL system. To enhance the ECL efficiency of the luminol&#8211;H 2 O system, researchers have developed electrocatalytic materials with exceptional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) properties to facilitate water electrolysis into O 2 to produce reactive oxygen species (ROS) and act as co&#8208;reactant promoters. However, most of these materials are characterized by their nanoscale or microscale dimensions, resulting in relatively large sizes and low specific surface areas, which hinder the application of the luminol&#8211;H 2 O system. To address this challenge, nickel molybdate sub&#8208;1 nm nanowires (NiMoO 4 S1 NWs) with a large specific surface area is synthesized that can offer many active sites to enhance the performance of the OER to boost the ECL of luminol. This study demonstrates that the large amount of ROS generated by the OER of NiMoO 4 S1 NWs play a crucial role in enhancing the ECL intensity of luminol. Finally, a NiMoO 4 S1 NWs&#8208;based ECL biosensor for the highly sensitive detection of the nucleocapsid proteins of SARS&#8208;CoV&#8208;2 is successfully constructed.</description>
      <author>Hao Zang, Dong Mei Wang, Wen Dai, Lin Chen, Yi&#8208;Ting Wang, Qiang Wang, Li Wang, Gao Chen, Jia Li, Jia Xie, Hong Yan Zou, Cheng Huang, Yuan Fang Li, Shu Jun Zhen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407321</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Potential-Driven Coordinated Oxygen Migration in an Electrocatalyst for Sustainable H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11307</link>
      <description>Zhiping Deng, Song Jin, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Min Ho Seo, Xiaolei Wang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404276344

                Local coordination environment (LCE) manipulation has emerged as a significant approach for modulating the electrocatalytic behavior of low-dimensional nanomaterials. However, challenges persist in accurately identifying active sites and understanding dynamic changes during operation. Here, we underscore the influence of LCE on the electrochemical production of H</description>
      <author>Zhiping Deng, Song Jin, Mingxing Gong, Ning Chen, Weifeng Chen, Min Ho Seo, Xiaolei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c11307</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Scalable Synthesis of N&#8211;Doped Graphene&#8211;Oxide&#8211;Supported FeCo(OH)x Nanosheets for Efficient Co&#8211;Doped Fe3O4 Nanoparticle-Based Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06684g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404286406

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06684g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Scalable Synthesis of N&#8211;Doped Graphene&#8211;Oxide&#8211;Supported FeCo(OH)x Nanosheets for Efficient Co&#8211;Doped Fe3O4 Nanoparticle-Based Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06684g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404286856

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06684g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering MXene Surface via Oxygen Functionalization and Au Nanoparticle Deposition for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401569</link>
      <description>Mengrui Li, Xiaoxiao Dong, Qinzhu Li, Yaru Liu, Shuang Cao, Chun&#8208;Chao Hou, Tong Sun, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404287069

                Abstract MXene, a family of 2D transition metal carbides and nitrides, presents promising applications in electrocatalysis. Maximizing its large surface area is key to developing efficient non&#8208;noble&#8208;metal catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). In this study, oxygen&#8208;functionalized Ti 3 C 2 T x MXene (Ti 3 C 2 O x ) is synthesized and deposited gold nanoparticles (Au NPs) onto it, forming a novel composite material, Au&#8208;Ti 3 C 2 O x . By selectively removing other functional groups, mainly &#8208;O functional groups are retained on the surface, directing electron transfer from Au NPs to MXene due to electronic metal&#8208;support interaction (EMSI), thereby improving the catalytic activity of the MXene surface. Additionally, the interaction between Au NPs and &#8208;O functional groups further enhanced the overall catalytic activity, achieving an overpotential of 62 mV and a Tafel slope of 40.1 mV dec &#8722;1 at a current density of &#8722;10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 solution. Density functional theory calculations and scanning electrochemical microscopy with &#8804;150 nm resolution confirmed the enhanced catalytic efficiency due to the specific interaction between Au NPs and Ti 3 C 2 O x . This work provides a surface modification strategy to fully utilize the MXene surface and enhance the overall catalytic activity of MXene&#8208;based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mengrui Li, Xiaoxiao Dong, Qinzhu Li, Yaru Liu, Shuang Cao, Chun&#8208;Chao Hou, Tong Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401569</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen coverage effect promotes oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.123</link>
      <description>Hsin-Hung Lin, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Chemical Synthesis. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404290086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hsin-Hung Lin, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorine&#8208;Induced Lattice Oxygen Participation in 2D Layered Double Hydroxide/MXene Hybrids for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202410812</link>
      <description>Chengang Pei, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Unbeom Baeck, Won Tae Hong, Jong Hun Kim, Hyungu Han, Jaekyum Kim, Sung&#8208;Min Cho, Yu Xu, Jongwook Park, Ho Seok Park, Jung Kyu Kim, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404291185

                Abstract In oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the participation of lattice oxygen can break the limitation of adsorption evolution mechanism, but the activation of lattice oxygen remains a critical challenge. Herein, a surface fluorinated highly active 2D/2D FeNi layered double hydroxide/MXene (F&#8208;LDH/MX) is demonstrated, boosting OER with the enhanced lattice&#8208;oxygen&#8208;mediated path. The introduction of fluorine promotes the self&#8208;evolution of catalyst in an alkaline environment, even without an external current. It further accelerates the formation of active metal oxyhydroxides with abundant oxygen vacancies under the operating potential. The introduced oxygen vacancy activates the lattice oxygen, increasing the proportion of lattice oxygen mechanism in OER. Owing to the synergistic effects of the 2D/2D hierarchical structure and the modulated active surface, F&#8208;LDH/MX possesses excellent electrochemical performances, including a low overpotential of 251 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , a low Tafel slope of 40.28 mV dec &#8722;1 , and robust stability. The water electrolyzer system with F&#8208;LDH/MX as the anode offers the benchmark current density at a low cell voltage of 1.53 V, while the Zn&#8208;air battery with F&#8208;LDH/MX as the air electrode exhibits a higher power density of 75.43 mW cm &#8722;2 . This study presents a promising strategy to design highly active electrocatalysts for energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Chengang Pei, Min&#8208;Cheol Kim, Unbeom Baeck, Won Tae Hong, Jong Hun Kim, Hyungu Han, Jaekyum Kim, Sung&#8208;Min Cho, Yu Xu, Jongwook Park, Ho Seok Park, Jung Kyu Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202410812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancy-enriched CoPi/TiO2 nanotubes/WO3 electrode for enhanced photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-024-13808-6</link>
      <description>Shujun Yu, Ke Sun, Guangyu Fang, Jinsheng Feng, Qiaonan Yu, Junling Chen, Pengcheng Wu, Keliang Wu, Journal of Materials Science Materials in Electronics. 35(32)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404293457

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shujun Yu, Ke Sun, Guangyu Fang, Jinsheng Feng, Qiaonan Yu, Junling Chen, Pengcheng Wu, Keliang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10854-024-13808-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seaweed-like Co-MOF/Cu(OH)2/CF composite as an advanced pre-catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.087</link>
      <description>Liuyang Guo, Qiming Jiang, Shanjing Liu, Zhi Zeng, Xingmei Guo, Xiangjun Zheng, Yuanjun Liu, Qianqian Fan, Zhongyao Duan, Chunsheng Li, Junhao Zhang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 94(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404296204

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liuyang Guo, Qiming Jiang, Shanjing Liu, Zhi Zeng, Xingmei Guo, Xiangjun Zheng, Yuanjun Liu, Qianqian Fan, Zhongyao Duan, Chunsheng Li, Junhao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effect of particle size on structural and catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction of (CoFeNiMnCr)3O4 prepared by controlled synthesis with polyvinylpyrrolidone (PVP)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.068</link>
      <description>Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Bruno Alessandro Silva Guedes de Lima, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, Duncan P. Fagg, Daniel A. Macedo, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Marco A. Morales, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 680(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404297459

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Bruno Alessandro Silva Guedes de Lima, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, Duncan P. Fagg, Daniel A. Macedo, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Marco A. Morales</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt nanoclusters Deposit on Nitrogen-Doped graphene Sheets as bifunctional electrocatalysts for high performance lithium &#8211; Oxygen batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.066</link>
      <description>Raja Palani, Yi&#8208;Shiuan Wu, She&#8211;Huang Wu, Jeng&#8208;Kuei Chang, Rajan Jose, Chun&#8208;Chen Yang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404297677

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Raja Palani, Yi&#8208;Shiuan Wu, She&#8211;Huang Wu, Jeng&#8208;Kuei Chang, Rajan Jose, Chun&#8208;Chen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.066</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ Raman Monitoring of Surface Structures and Oxygen Species on Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Au/Nickel Foam During Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05471</link>
      <description>Xiaocong Ma, Zhou Yu, Yali Zhang, Jie Jin, Jianping Li, Xu-Liang Fan, Qiang Wan, Ju&#8208;Fang Zheng, Xiao&#8208;Shun Zhou, Yahao Wang, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404299144

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaocong Ma, Zhou Yu, Yali Zhang, Jie Jin, Jianping Li, Xu-Liang Fan, Qiang Wan, Ju&#8208;Fang Zheng, Xiao&#8208;Shun Zhou, Yahao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c05471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-Based Layered Perovskite Oxyfluoride Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution: Insights from Crystal Facets with Heteroanionic Coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05740</link>
      <description>Ryusuke Mizuochi, Yuuki Sugawara, Kengo Oka, Yoshiyuki Inaguma, Shunsuke Nozawa, Toshiyuki Yokoi, Takeo Yamaguchi, Kazuhiko Maeda, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404320100

                Mixed-anion compounds have recently attracted attention as solid-state materials that exhibit properties unattainable with those of their single-anion counterparts. However, the use of mixed-anion compounds to control the morphology and engineer the crystal facets of electrocatalysts has been limited because their synthesis method is still immature. This study explored the electrocatalytic properties of a Pb-Fe oxyfluoride, Pb</description>
      <author>Ryusuke Mizuochi, Yuuki Sugawara, Kengo Oka, Yoshiyuki Inaguma, Shunsuke Nozawa, Toshiyuki Yokoi, Takeo Yamaguchi, Kazuhiko Maeda</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Coordination Environment of Cobalt-Based Spinel Octahedral Metal Sites to Boost Metal&#8211;Oxygen Bond Covalency for Reversible Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06092</link>
      <description>Yu Pan, Anjun Hu, Ruizhe Xu, Jingze Chen, Borui Yang, Ting Li, Kun Li, Yuanjian Li, Zhi Wei Seh, Jianping Long, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404320226

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yu Pan, Anjun Hu, Ruizhe Xu, Jingze Chen, Borui Yang, Ting Li, Kun Li, Yuanjian Li, Zhi Wei Seh, Jianping Long</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06092</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual active site pathways in cobalt-based bimetallic catalysts enhance oxygen evolution reaction activity: Density functional theory studies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105428</link>
      <description>Zeliang Ju, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Chengfeng Yin, Qingxin Kang, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404321196

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeliang Ju, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Chengfeng Yin, Qingxin Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering bimetallic cluster architectures: harnessing unique &#8220;remote synergy effect&#8221; between Mn and Y for enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100332</link>
      <description>Yijian Song, Chao Han, Weijie Li, Xiufeng Yi, Qing Liao, Ji Zhou, Yaqin Zhou, Yitao Ouyang, Yingping Zhang, Qingqing Zheng, Anqiang Pan, eScience. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404322409

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yijian Song, Chao Han, Weijie Li, Xiufeng Yi, Qing Liao, Ji Zhou, Yaqin Zhou, Yitao Ouyang, Yingping Zhang, Qingqing Zheng, Anqiang Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.esci.2024.100332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Quest for Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts Based on Layered Double Hydroxides: An Electrochemical and Chemometric Combined Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400233</link>
      <description>Isacco Gualandi, Elisa Musella, Giulia Costa, Massimo Gazzano, Erika Scavetta, Sergio Zappoli, Domenica Tonelli, Advanced Energy and Sustainability Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404325990

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a crucial process in various energy conversion and storage technologies, such as water electrolysis. Developing efficient and cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts is essential to achieve the commercialization of devices for the transition toward sustainable energy solutions. Herein, ternary layer double hydroxides (LDHs) are synthesized and characterized as electrocatalysts for OER using a potentiodynamic electrochemical deposition method on Grafoil. A chemometric approach based on experimental design is employed to rationalize the effort in the investigation of the LDHs which are based on Ni, Co, and Fe. The deposited films are characterized using cyclic voltammetry and X&#8208;ray diffraction to determine peak currents and potentials, and crystal size. Furthermore, the electrocatalyst performances are assessed by linear sweep voltammetry in 1M KOH from which the Tafel slope and onset potential are calculated. The obtained data are used to derive models describing the material properties and electrocatalyst performance as a function of the electrolyte composition used during the LDHs electrodeposition. This study provides valuable insights into the relationship between the electrocatalyst composition and its OER activity, enabling the design of more efficient and sustainable electrochemical systems for energy applications.</description>
      <author>Isacco Gualandi, Elisa Musella, Giulia Costa, Massimo Gazzano, Erika Scavetta, Sergio Zappoli, Domenica Tonelli</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aesr.202400233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Producing Supersaturated Dissolved Oxygen Seawater by Photosynthesis of &lt;i&gt;Ulva&lt;/i&gt; sp. and Its Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9411516</link>
      <description>Shin Hirayama, Kazuya Urata, Miyuki Kusumoto, Yasuyuki Ikegami, Aquaculture Research. 2024(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404326349

                In order to create new value in biomass production using sterile Ulva with high production efficiency, we selected sterile Ulva with high culture stability from the coast of Imari City in Japan and investigated the conditions for generating high concentrations of dissolved oxygen through photosynthesis using the sterile Ulva . In the cultivation of sterile Ulva , we investigated the conditions for generating high concentrations of dissolved oxygen (DO) by controlling conditions such as aeration, NO 3 &#8208;N concentration, and population density. As a result, we found that under the cultivation control conditions we found, DO reached about 3.8 times the saturation concentration after 3 h. It was found that this high level of DO can be maintained if the supersaturated DO seawater obtained here is properly sealed. Seawater containing high levels of DO is essential for the cultivation of oysters and shellfish, which also prefer a growth temperature of 20&#176;C&#8722;25&#176;C. Therefore, from the perspective of creating new value in biomass production, we developed a new system for simultaneously cultivating sterile Ulva and cultivating oysters.</description>
      <author>Shin Hirayama, Kazuya Urata, Miyuki Kusumoto, Yasuyuki Ikegami</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9411516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Hierarchical Porous Fe/N Codoped Carbon Nanosheets as Oxygen Reduction Reaction Electrocatalysts for the Zinc-Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03145</link>
      <description>Yanjing Lin, Yaru Li, Jiahao Liu, Wei Zhang, Renren Sun, Yanfeng Pu, Yong Liu, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404329494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanjing Lin, Yaru Li, Jiahao Liu, Wei Zhang, Renren Sun, Yanfeng Pu, Yong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03145</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the electrocatalytic role of magnesium doped bismuth copper titanate (BCTO) in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118803</link>
      <description>Sarvatej Kumar Maurya, Amisha Soni, Manisha Malviya, Dhanesh Tiwary, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404338372

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sarvatej Kumar Maurya, Amisha Soni, Manisha Malviya, Dhanesh Tiwary</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile construction of hierarchically porous carbon nanofibers modified by FeCu/FeF3 heterojunction for oxygen electrocatalysis in liquid and flexible Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05503a</link>
      <description>Nanping Deng, Yilong Wang, Qiang Zeng, Yan Feng, Gang Wang, Hao Chi, Weimin Kang, Bowen Cheng, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404341619

                Highly efficiency, excellent stability and low-cost catalysts equipping with uniform distribution and enough active sites are rather important for zinc-air batteries (ZABs). In this study, inspired by hollow bubble structured...</description>
      <author>Nanping Deng, Yilong Wang, Qiang Zeng, Yan Feng, Gang Wang, Hao Chi, Weimin Kang, Bowen Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05503a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal oxide plating for maximizing the performance in ruthenium(IV) oxide-catalyzed electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03678f</link>
      <description>Shin&#8208;ichi Naya, Mio Nagamitsu, Hisashi Sugime, Tetsuro Soejima, Hiroaki Tada, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404355977

                Hydrogen production by proton exchange membrane water electrolysis requires the anode with low overpotential for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and robustness in acidic solution. While exploring new electrode materials to...</description>
      <author>Shin&#8208;ichi Naya, Mio Nagamitsu, Hisashi Sugime, Tetsuro Soejima, Hiroaki Tada</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03678f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AlOOH Nanosheets Modified Ti-Fe2O3 with Oxygen Vacancies for Highly Efficient Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177536</link>
      <description>Chunxiao Li, Xin Jia, Qifeng Zhao, Jingran Xiao, Sheng Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404356795

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chunxiao Li, Xin Jia, Qifeng Zhao, Jingran Xiao, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combining nanocrystalline NiCo with MOFs-Derived carbon fibers Skeleton: A dual confinement strategy to efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.137727</link>
      <description>Xiya Yang, Shuai Liang, Guanzhihui Wang, Bao Zhou, Zhuoqi Duan, Zhaoxiong Xie, Yongmao Hu, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404360990

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiya Yang, Shuai Liang, Guanzhihui Wang, Bao Zhou, Zhuoqi Duan, Zhaoxiong Xie, Yongmao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.137727</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of CeO2/Co(OH)2/FeS@NF nanosheet arrays for high-performance electrocatalytic oxygen evolution/urea oxidation, and overall water/urea splitting reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.141</link>
      <description>Fei Duan, Yunqin Hu, Junfeng Lin, Mingyue Li, Hao Chen, Zhiqing Cui, Caihong Fang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 94(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404366369

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Duan, Yunqin Hu, Junfeng Lin, Mingyue Li, Hao Chen, Zhiqing Cui, Caihong Fang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Raman Spectroscopic Observation of Electrolyte-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Reaction Intermediates in Nickel-Based Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06732</link>
      <description>Tomohiro Fukushima, Kenko Tsuchimoto, Nobuaki Oyamada, Daiki Sato, Hiro Minamimoto, Kei Murakoshi, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404375901

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tomohiro Fukushima, Kenko Tsuchimoto, Nobuaki Oyamada, Daiki Sato, Hiro Minamimoto, Kei Murakoshi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06732</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the Coordination Environment of Fe/Co Dual&#8208;atom Sites towards Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis for Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419595</link>
      <description>Hengqi Liu, Jinzhen Huang, Kun Feng, Rui Xiong, Shengyu Ma, Li Wang, Qiang Fu, Moniba Rafique, Zhiguo Liu, Jiecai Han, Daxing Hua, Jiajie Li, Jun Zhong, Xianjie Wang, Zhonglong Zhao, Tai Yao, Sida Jiang, Ping Xu, Zhihua Zhang, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404378321

                Dual&#8208;atom catalysts with nitrogen&#8208;coordinated metal sites embedded in carbon can drive the oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER) in rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs), and the further improvement is limited by the linear scaling relationship of intermediate binding energies in the absorbate evolution mechanism (AEM). Triggering the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) is promising to overcome this challenge, but has yet been verified since the lacking of bridge oxygen (O) in the rigid coordination environment of the metal centers. Here, we demonstrate that suitably tailored dual&#8208;atom catalysts of FeCo&#8211;N&#8211;C can undergo out&#8208;plane and in&#8208;plane reconstruction to form the both axial O and bridge O at the metal centers, and thus activate the LOM pathway. The tailored FeCo&#8211;N&#8211;C with shortened Fe&#8211;N bonds also favor the ORR process, therefore is a promising dual&#8208;atom oxygen catalyst. The assembled rechargeable ZABs demonstrate a peak power density of 332 mW cm&#8722;2, and exhibit no notable decline after ~ 720 h of continuous cycling.</description>
      <author>Hengqi Liu, Jinzhen Huang, Kun Feng, Rui Xiong, Shengyu Ma, Li Wang, Qiang Fu, Moniba Rafique, Zhiguo Liu, Jiecai Han, Daxing Hua, Jiajie Li, Jun Zhong, Xianjie Wang, Zhonglong Zhao, Tai Yao, Sida Jiang, Ping Xu, Zhihua Zhang, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influenece of Calcination Ramp on the Electrocatalytic and Photoelectrocatalytic Performance of Ni3teo6 for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5020837</link>
      <description>Manisha Sharma, Kamana K. Mishra, Sachin Singh, Jay N. Mishra, Sachin Kumar Singh, Prabhakar Singh, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404385993

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manisha Sharma, Kamana K. Mishra, Sachin Singh, Jay N. Mishra, Sachin Kumar Singh, Prabhakar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5020837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvement of Electrochemical Performance of Eutectic High-Entropy Alloy Bulk Electrode for Excellent Oxygen Evolution Reaction Through Surface Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5020772</link>
      <description>Si-Cheng Zhong, Jia Li, Zhe Cui, Guang-Run Tian, Fa-Chang Zhao, Zhong-Hong Zhou, Hongfei Jiao, Danyang Liu, Jie-Fu Xiong, Li&#8208;Chen Wang, Jun Xiang, Fufa Wu, Rong-Da Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404387737

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Si-Cheng Zhong, Jia Li, Zhe Cui, Guang-Run Tian, Fa-Chang Zhao, Zhong-Hong Zhou, Hongfei Jiao, Danyang Liu, Jie-Fu Xiong, Li&#8208;Chen Wang, Jun Xiang, Fufa Wu, Rong-Da Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5020772</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Potential of Rock-Salt Type High Entropy Oxides Synthesized by Green Microwave Irradiation Method for Excellent Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5020776</link>
      <description>Muhammad Asim, Akbar Hussain, Sadia Kanwal, Meryem Samanc&#305;, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan, Andrea Strakov&#225; Fedorkov&#225;, Naveed Kausar Janjua, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404387896

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Asim, Akbar Hussain, Sadia Kanwal, Meryem Samanc&#305;, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan, Andrea Strakov&#225; Fedorkov&#225;, Naveed Kausar Janjua</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5020776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Coordination&#8208;Driven Metal&#8208;Oxygen Interaction Triggers Oxygen Evolution in Polymorphic and High&#8208;Entropy Phosphate Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416834</link>
      <description>Sampath Gayathri, Paulraj Arunkumar, Dipankar Saha, Durga P. Acharya, J. Karthikeyan, Jong Hun Han, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404390058

                Abstract Engineering metal&#8208;oxygen (M&#8210;O) interactions for catalyzing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by tuning the coordination geometry of metal sites is crucial for improving catalytic performance, which remains unexplored, especially in structurally diverse phosphate&#8208;based catalysts. Herein, two NaCoPO 4 (NCP) polymorphs with distinct metal coordinations: orthorhombic&#8208; Pnma (CoO 6 ) and hexagonal&#8208;P 6 5 (CoO 4 ) denoted as O&#8208;NCP and H&#8208;NCP, respectively are synthesized through unique quenching&#8208;based synthesis, to investigate the impact of coordination geometry on M&#8210;O covalency and OER performance. The CoO 4 (H&#8208;NCP) polymorph delivered superior OER activity with low overpotential at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 (&#951; 10 = 303 mV) and long&#8208;term stability than CoO 6 &#8208;based O&#8208;NCP. Spectroscopic and computational studies linked the superior activity of CoO 4 to higher Co&#8210;O covalency, enhanced metal electronic states near the Fermi level, and improved electrochemical reconstruction. Further, M&#8210;O covalency regulated OER mechanism, where high&#8208;covalent CoO 4 follows conventional concerted proton&#8208;electron transfer pathway, while CoO 6 entails a non&#8208;concerted pathway, where the lattice oxygen participation remains unfavorable due to downshifted O 2p band center. Further, OER&#8208;active tetrahedral metal is demonstrated in a high&#8208;entropy catalyst requiring lower &#951; 10 of &#8776;284 mV. This study unlocks a unique strategy for designing next&#8208;generation OER catalysts with superior activity and durability, harnessing the interplay between metal coordination and metal&#8208;oxygen covalency.</description>
      <author>Sampath Gayathri, Paulraj Arunkumar, Dipankar Saha, Durga P. Acharya, J. Karthikeyan, Jong Hun Han</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalyst Design for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-73442-7_4</link>
      <description>Zafar Khan Ghouri, SpringerBriefs in energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404391140

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zafar Khan Ghouri</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-73442-7_4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-Doped Cobalt Carbonate Hydroxide Hydrate Nanosheets Induced by Anion Exchange to Trigger Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5021979</link>
      <description>Bo Feng, Yindan Wu, Yonghao Gan, Xueli Yin, Yihua Cao, Run Cai, Qi Wang, Xiaoping Dai, Xintong Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404393157

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bo Feng, Yindan Wu, Yonghao Gan, Xueli Yin, Yihua Cao, Run Cai, Qi Wang, Xiaoping Dai, Xintong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5021979</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Cation and Anion Vacancies in Ruthenium Oxide on the Activity and Stability of Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02779</link>
      <description>Jiao Yang, Keyu An, Zhichao Yu, Lulu Qiao, Youpeng Cao, Yujuan Zhuang, Chunfa Liu, Jun Li, Lishan Peng, Hui Pan, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404401878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiao Yang, Keyu An, Zhichao Yu, Lulu Qiao, Youpeng Cao, Yujuan Zhuang, Chunfa Liu, Jun Li, Lishan Peng, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c02779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of Inert ZnO by Incorporating Ni and Trace-Level Ir for Scalable and Industrial-Level Water-Splitting Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05913</link>
      <description>S. H. Yoon, Da Young Kwon, Yong Hwan Lee, Nochang Park, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404411120

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. H. Yoon, Da Young Kwon, Yong Hwan Lee, Nochang Park</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c05913</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Insights into Hydrogen Peroxide Generation on Carbon Electrodes: Influence of Defects, Oxygen Functional Groups, and Alkali Metals in the Electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04734</link>
      <description>Andr&#233; Olean&#8208;Oliveira, Najeeb Hasnain, Ricardo Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Hincapi&#233;, Ulrich Hagemann, Adarsh Jain, Doris Segets, Ioannis Spanos, Viktor &#268;oli&#263;, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404412919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Andr&#233; Olean&#8208;Oliveira, Najeeb Hasnain, Ricardo Mart&#237;nez&#8208;Hincapi&#233;, Ulrich Hagemann, Adarsh Jain, Doris Segets, Ioannis Spanos, Viktor &#268;oli&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-flower-shaped Ru-NiFeAl-LDHs@rGO for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177588</link>
      <description>Shunxiang Wang, Sen Hu, Cuili Xiang, Yongjin Zou, Fen Xu, Ningbo Qin, Lixian Sun, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404413499

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shunxiang Wang, Sen Hu, Cuili Xiang, Yongjin Zou, Fen Xu, Ningbo Qin, Lixian Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maximizing Oxygen Evolution Performance of NiFeOx Semitransparent Electrocatalysts Applicable to Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting Device</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400536</link>
      <description>Koichi Yoshiyama, Tomohiro Higashi, Tian Xiao, Kenji Yoshino, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404420516

                In photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting, semiconductor&#8208;based photoelectrodes can improve reaction rates and durability by incorporating cocatalysts that serve as active sites for the water splitting process. However, achieving both high light transmittance and efficient catalytic activity is essential for these cocatalysts. This study aimed to optimize the surface loading of semitransparent NiFeOx thin&#8208;film electrocatalysts to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) rates while maintaining high light transmittance. NiFeOx thin films were deposited on fluorine&#8208;doped SnO2 (FTO) transparent conductive substrates, and the relationship between the NiFeOx loading amount (&#915;) and the OER rate was examined using electrochemical techniques. The OER rate of NiFeOx on FTO (NiFeOx/FTO) was the highest at a &#915; value of 0.20 &#956;mol cm&#8208;2. To further explore the connection between this optimized &#915; and PEC activity, the impact of &#915; on the PEC OER performance of visible&#8208;light&#8208;absorbing &#945;&#8208;Fe2O3 semitransparent photoanodes was evaluated as a model system. Applying the optimized &#915; of NiFeOx to modify the &#945;&#8208;Fe2O3 surface also led to enhanced PEC OER performance. These findings highlight the critical role of surface design, specifically the optimization of cocatalyst loading and electrocatalytic activity, in improving PEC water splitting efficiency, providing valuable guidelines for future semitransparent photoelectrode development.</description>
      <author>Koichi Yoshiyama, Tomohiro Higashi, Tian Xiao, Kenji Yoshino</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Valence Co Stabilized by In&#8208;Situ Growth of ZIF&#8208;67 on NiCo&#8208;LDH for Enhanced Performance in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407443</link>
      <description>Yankai Huang, Tong Li, Han Feng, Luotian Lv, Tongxin Tang, Zhan Lin, Kai&#8208;Hang Ye, Yongqing Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404421563

                Abstract The application of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) in the electro&#8208;catalysis of heterogeneous structures is limited by the problems of low electrical conductivity and poor mechanical strength due to the complex synthesis process, although their high specific surface area and controllable structure. In this study, a method involving metal precipitation and ligand reaction is used during the electrochemical corrosion of hydroxides/oxy&#8208;hydroxides to obtain ZIF&#8208;67 in situ. The in situ growth technology not only effectively addresses the bonding strength and material conductivity challenges in the heterostructure between MOFs and the substrate but also enhances the catalyst's surface area and activity. Additionally, the exposure and protection of Co 4+ by ZIF&#8208;67 contribute to the electrocatalyst's performance, demonstrating a low overpotential (&#951; 100 ) of 293 mV, a Tafel slope of 25.8 mV dec &#8722;1 , and a charge transfer resistance of 3.9 &#937;, with long&#8208;term robustness proven in continuous stability test exceeding 75 000 s under the superhigh current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work on binder&#8208;free in situ growth of MOFs not only provides relevant theoretical insights and experimental experience for cost&#8208;effective and controllable production of MOF&#8208;based catalysts but also offers ideas for the development of future electrocatalysts by exploring the exposure and protection of active site using MOFs materials.</description>
      <author>Yankai Huang, Tong Li, Han Feng, Luotian Lv, Tongxin Tang, Zhan Lin, Kai&#8208;Hang Ye, Yongqing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambipolar Nature Accelerates Dual&#8208;Functionality on Ni/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N@NC for Simultaneous Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution in Electrochemical Water Splitting System (Adv. Sustainable Syst. 11/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202470038</link>
      <description>Gnanaprakasam Janani, Subramani Surendran, Dae Jun Moon, Poonchi Sivasankaran Ramesh, Joon Young Kim, Yoongu Lim, Krishnan Veeramani, Shivraj Mahadik, Sebastian Cyril Jesudass, Jinuk Choi, Il Goo Kim, Pildo Jung, Heechae Choi, Gibum Kwon, Kyoungsuk Jin, Jung Kyu Kim, Yong Il Park, Jaeyeong Heo, Kootak Hong, Young Soo Kang, Uk Sim, Advanced Sustainable Systems. 8(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404422512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gnanaprakasam Janani, Subramani Surendran, Dae Jun Moon, Poonchi Sivasankaran Ramesh, Joon Young Kim, Yoongu Lim, Krishnan Veeramani, Shivraj Mahadik, Sebastian Cyril Jesudass, Jinuk Choi, Il Goo Kim, Pildo Jung, Heechae Choi, Gibum Kwon, Kyoungsuk Jin, Jung Kyu Kim, Yong Il Park, Jaeyeong Heo, Kootak Hong, Young Soo Kang, Uk Sim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202470038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalysis via Introducing Lanthanides for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400747</link>
      <description>Qi Ding, Linfeng Xie, Zijie Lin, Zhuhuang Qin, Yunan Li, Qing Li, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404429159

                Abstract The low activity of ruthenium dioxide (RuO 2 ) and the rapid dissolution of the ruthenium (Ru) site during acid oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at high current density restricts its application in proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzers. In this work, a series of rare&#8208;earth (RE) elements doped RuO 2 nanorods is developed as high&#8208;performance OER electrocatalysts. X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy suggests that RE doping regulates the local coordination environment around Ru sites, lowers the valance of Ru, and shortens the Ru&#9472;O&#9472;Ru(M) bond length, which enhances structural stability. Among the RE&#8208;RuO 2 samples, Sm&#8208;RuO 2 exhibits remarkable performance with a low overpotential of 283 mV to reach 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and maintained stability for over 140 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Moreover, the PEM electrolyzer using Sm&#8208;RuO 2 as the anode can be stably operated at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 for 15 h. Electrochemical analysis, X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy, and in situ Raman spectroscopy show that Sm doping lowers the d &#8208;band center, reduces the adsorption energy of O intermediates to enhance the OER activity, and restrains excessive oxidation of Ru sites while stabilizing lattice oxygen during the OER process, thereby enhancing OER stability. This work offers valuable insights into improving the stability of metal oxide catalysts in acidic electrolytes.</description>
      <author>Qi Ding, Linfeng Xie, Zijie Lin, Zhuhuang Qin, Yunan Li, Qing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430348

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430597

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430726

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhou, Xuan Hao, Jiexin Guan, Yilin Deng, Zi Wei, Yashu Liu, Guoxing Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhou, Xuan Hao, Jiexin Guan, Yilin Deng, Zi Wei, Yashu Liu, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistic Fe,Ce doping of Ni&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;S&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02187h/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430801

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02187h/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430870

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Synergistic Fe,Ce doping of Ni&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;S&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02187h/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430878

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02187h/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistic Fe,Ce doping of Ni&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;S&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02187h/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404430926

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02187h/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Coordination tuning of Ni/Fe complex-based electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404431066

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01934b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low&#8208;Spin Fe&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; Evoked by Multiple Defects with Optimal Intermediate Adsorption Attaining Unparalleled Performance in Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412598</link>
      <description>Yihao Wang, Shanqing Li, Xu Hou, Ting-Ting Cui, Zechao Zhuang, Yunhe Zhao, Haozhi Wang, Wei Wei, Ming Xu, Qiang Fu, Chunxia Chen, Dingsheng Wang, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404431075

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting is long constrained by the sluggish kinetics of anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and rational spin&#8208;state manipulation holds great promise to break through this bottleneck. Low&#8208;spin Fe 3+ (LS, t 2g 5 e g 0 ) species are identified as highly active sites for OER in theory, whereas it is still a formidable challenge to construct experimentally. Herein, a new strategy is demonstrated for the effective construction of LS Fe 3+ in NiFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide (NiFe&#8208;LDH) by introducing multiple defects, which induce coordination unsaturation over Fe sites and thus enlarge their d orbital splitting energy. The as&#8208;obtained catalyst exhibits extraordinary OER performance with an ultra&#8208;low overpotential of 244 mV at the industrially required current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 , which is 110 mV lower than that of the conventional NiFe&#8208;LDH with high&#8208;spin Fe 3+ (HS, t 2g 3 e g 2 ) and superior to most previously reported NiFe&#8208;based catalysts. Comprehensive experimental and theoretical studies reveal that LS Fe 3+ configuration effectively reduces the adsorption strength of the O* intermediate compared with that of the HS case, thereby altering the rate&#8208;determining step from (O* &#8594; OOH*) to (OH* &#8594; O*) of OER and lowering its reaction energy barrier. This work paves a new avenue for developing efficient spin&#8208;dependent electrocatalysts for OER and beyond.</description>
      <author>Yihao Wang, Shanqing Li, Xu Hou, Ting-Ting Cui, Zechao Zhuang, Yunhe Zhao, Haozhi Wang, Wei Wei, Ming Xu, Qiang Fu, Chunxia Chen, Dingsheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202412598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Catalytic Sites in High&#8208;Entropy Metal Hydroxide Organic Framework for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408114</link>
      <description>Arkendu Roy, Sourabh Kumar, Ana Guilherme Buzanich, Carsten Prinz, Emilia G&#246;tz, Anika Retzmann, Tilmann Hickel, Biswajit Bhattacharya, Franziska Emmerling, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404431258

                Abstract The integration of multiple elements in a high&#8208;entropy state is crucial in the design of high&#8208;performance, durable electrocatalysts. High&#8208;entropy metal hydroxide organic frameworks (HE&#8208;MHOFs) are synthesized under mild solvothermal conditions. This novel crystalline metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) features a random, homogeneous distribution of cations within high&#8208;entropy hydroxide layers. HE&#8208;MHOF exhibits excellent electrocatalytic performance for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), reaching a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 at &#8776;1.64 V RHE , and demonstrates remarkable durability, maintaining a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for over 100 h. Notably, HE&#8208;MHOF outperforms precious metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts despite containing only &#8776;60% OER active metals. Ab initio calculations and operando X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) demonstrate that the high&#8208;entropy catalyst contains active sites that facilitate a multifaceted OER mechanism. This study highlights the benefits of high&#8208;entropy MOFs in developing noble metal&#8208;free electrocatalysts, reducing reliance on precious metals, lowering metal loading (especially for Ni, Co, and Mn), and ultimately reducing costs for sustainable water electrolysis technologies.</description>
      <author>Arkendu Roy, Sourabh Kumar, Ana Guilherme Buzanich, Carsten Prinz, Emilia G&#246;tz, Anika Retzmann, Tilmann Hickel, Biswajit Bhattacharya, Franziska Emmerling</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408114</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Self&#8208;Healing of the Reconstructed Phase in Perovskite Oxides for Efficient and Stable Electrocatalytic OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407851</link>
      <description>Yiyue Zhai, Xiangrong Ren, Shouxin Zhang, Tao Gan, Na Yang, Bolun Wang, Shengzhong Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404435434

                Abstract Neither electrocatalytic activity nor structural stability is inconsequential in water electrolysis. Unfortunately, they have to be compromised in practice, especially in the anodic redox chemistry of lattice oxygen. Herein, the discovery of a La 1&#8722; x Ce x FeO 3 perovskite is presented which shows both good stability and high catalytic activity. Using advanced operando characterizations, it is identified that the self&#8208;healing evolution of the La 1&#8722; x Ce x FeO 3 perovskite plays a key role during water oxidation in the lattice oxygen&#8208;mediated mechanism (LOM) pathway. Unlike irreversible reconstruction, the formation of reconstructed active&#8208;phase &#945; &#8208;FeOOH is reversed by re&#8208;crystallization of surface La 1&#8722; x Ce x FeO 3 upon return to noncatalytic conditions. The self&#8208;healing transformation of the &#945; &#8208;FeOOH termination layer on the stable La 1&#8722; x Ce x FeO 3 core imparts remarkable long&#8208;term stability as well as excellent electrocatalytic performance. As a result, a composition La 0.9 Ce 0.1 FeO 3 @FeOOH is designed that exhibits ultralow overpotentials of 257 and 312 mV to achieve 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. The findings provide insight into self&#8208;healing behavior toward engineering perovskite oxides for efficient and stable oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Yiyue Zhai, Xiangrong Ren, Shouxin Zhang, Tao Gan, Na Yang, Bolun Wang, Shengzhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of NiFe2O4/Fe2O3@Ni(OH)2 hollow core&#8211;shell nanotubes based on metal&#8211;organic frameworks for efficient oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-10426-9</link>
      <description>Peng Tian, Jian Shao, Zhou Yu, Shengnan Song, Qing Jiang, Yuwei Dong, Journal of Materials Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404440273

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Peng Tian, Jian Shao, Zhou Yu, Shengnan Song, Qing Jiang, Yuwei Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-10426-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-Operation of Oxygen and Nitrogen of Functionalized Nitrogen-Dopd Porous Carbon for Efficient H2o2 Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5023620</link>
      <description>Ying&#8208;Jie Zhu, Huang hengbo, Yong Yang, Shuling Shen, Zhihong Tang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404441171

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ying&#8208;Jie Zhu, Huang hengbo, Yong Yang, Shuling Shen, Zhihong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5023620</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microwave-Assisted synthesis of CuxFe100-x/Carbon aerogel (x = 0, 30, 50, 70) with enhanced Electrocatalytic activity towards oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118811</link>
      <description>Meryem Samanc&#305;, Muhammad Asim, Akbar Hussain, Naveed Kausar Janjua, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404442521

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Meryem Samanc&#305;, Muhammad Asim, Akbar Hussain, Naveed Kausar Janjua, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118811</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic electrochemical performance of NdFeO3/rGO composite for enhanced oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118807</link>
      <description>Khalid A. Alrashidi, Iram Manzoor, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Saikh Mohammad, Muhammad Bilal, Nadir Abbas, Farooq Ahmad, Jafar Hussain Shah, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404447092

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Khalid A. Alrashidi, Iram Manzoor, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Saikh Mohammad, Muhammad Bilal, Nadir Abbas, Farooq Ahmad, Jafar Hussain Shah</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctional benzoselenadiazole-capped organic molecule-based nanohybrid for efficient asymmetric supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114604</link>
      <description>Devraj Singh, Lalita Wagh, Apurba K. Das, Journal of Energy Storage. 104(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404447833

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Devraj Singh, Lalita Wagh, Apurba K. Das</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.114604</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru-embedded TiO2-x with rich Ru-Ti bonds and triggered oxygen vacancies for boosted and sustained hydrogen oxidation and evolution electrocatalysis in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157669</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Cong, Mengling Liu, Luyun Chen, Y. Q. Qi, Limin Zhang, Qiuping Zhao, Chunlei Li, Haibin Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. 501(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404454064

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Cong, Mengling Liu, Luyun Chen, Y. Q. Qi, Limin Zhang, Qiuping Zhao, Chunlei Li, Haibin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157669</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical behaviour of WO3 and Se-WO3 films modified with cobalt-based oxygen evolving catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2017.28.2.2</link>
      <description>Simona Ostachavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Agn&#279; &#352;ul&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Eugenijus Valatka, Chemija. 28(2)] 2017. https://openalex.org/W4404244929

                Thin &#64257;lms of bare and Se-containing tungsten trioxide (WO3) on AISI304 stainless steel were prepared by electrochemical deposition using peroxy-tungstate solutions. Cobalt-phosphate catalyst was photochemically deposited onto the surface of semiconductor particles in order to enhance their activity towards the oxygen evolution reaction. The photoelectrochemical properties of as-prepared electrodes were investigated in neutral 0.1 M phosphate buffer solutions. The voltammetric characteristics revealed that the presence of cobalt-based catalyst effectively changes the photoelectrocatalytic activity of WO3 and Se-WO3 particles.</description>
      <author>Simona Ostachavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Agn&#279; &#352;ul&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Eugenijus Valatka</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2017.28.2.2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity&#8211;Stability Relationships in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.4c00086</link>
      <description>Wonchul Park, Dong Young Chung, ACS Materials Au. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404410584

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wonchul Park, Dong Young Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialsau.4c00086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy enriched structurally modulated Nickel Ferrite for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400480</link>
      <description>Shraddhanjali Senapati, Rajaram Bal, M. Mohapatra, Bijayalaxmi Jena, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404361762

                Generation of clean hydrogen fuel from renewable source like water by electrocatalytic water splitting is an advanced energy conversion technology. The idea of water splitting attracts the researcher to focus on the synthesis of active and stable catalysts. We modulated nickel ferrite using different surfactants and developed an active two&#8208;dimensional (2D), economic and sturdy catalyst for the study of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in basic electrolytic solution. Nickel ferrite with CTAB named as NF(C), with ascorbic acid named as NF(A) and with oxalic acid named as NF(O) and Nickel ferrite without surfactant is named as NF. NF(O) having 2D structure shows better catalytic activity among all. The catalytic activity of NF(O) was further enhanced through reduction process. We reduced NF(O) using hydrazine hydrate along with ultrasonication power treatment to induce vacancy in the material namely Vo&#8208; NF(O). Vo&#8208; NF(O) exhibits low overpotential of 260 mV at 10 mA/cm2 with Tafel slope of 25 mV/dec and stability of 18 h. Creation of vacancy boosts the catalytic activity of electrocatalyst by increasing the surface area and number of reactive sites of the catalyst which improve electrical conductivity, thus facilitating the transfer of charge.</description>
      <author>Shraddhanjali Senapati, Rajaram Bal, M. Mohapatra, Bijayalaxmi Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400480</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single atom catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101606</link>
      <description>Jean Rouger, Sara Cavali&#232;re, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Current Opinion in Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404321131

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jean Rouger, Sara Cavali&#232;re, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.coelec.2024.101606</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ternary NiFeCo-Glycerolate Catalysts: Rational Design for Improved Oxygen Evolution Reaction Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06455k</link>
      <description>Irlan S. Lima, Josu&#233; M. Gon&#231;alves, L&#250;cio Angnes, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404334261

                Catalysts capable of overcoming the bottleneck of water splitting, known as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), are indispensable to the expansion of renewable energy systems. Thus, we report the synthesis...</description>
      <author>Irlan S. Lima, Josu&#233; M. Gon&#231;alves, L&#250;cio Angnes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06455k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the effect of codoping in strontium ferrite for oxygen evolution in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04145c</link>
      <description>Shuangshuang Zhu, Mingyuan Wang, Yuguang Mao, Jiayuan Wang, Jiabao Ding, Guiwu Liu, Weifeng Zhang, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404303214

                Co and Ni codoped strontium ferrite particles were prepared by a solid-state strategy and employed as catalysts for OER. It exhibits a Tafel slope of 55 mV dec -1 and requires...</description>
      <author>Shuangshuang Zhu, Mingyuan Wang, Yuguang Mao, Jiayuan Wang, Jiabao Ding, Guiwu Liu, Weifeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04145c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the superwetting FeOOH-modified NiMoO4 electrodes for efficient alkaline oxygen evolution reaction: An in-situ spectroscopy study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124814</link>
      <description>Hongru Hao, Jiahui Wang, Zhe Wang, Shuo Shen, Lingling Xu, Zhe Lv, Bo Wei, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. 363(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404281349

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongru Hao, Jiahui Wang, Zhe Wang, Shuo Shen, Lingling Xu, Zhe Lv, Bo Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical and experimental study on the effect of mechanical strain force activated polyhedron on oxygen evolution reaction performance and mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.148</link>
      <description>Hao Zhou, Le Chen, Guoyu Hou, Ping He, Xueyang Rui, Sorachon Yoriya, Zaiguo Fu, P Li, Kai Sheng, Kai Huang, Jiang Wu, Jia Horng Lin, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 94(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404366273

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Zhou, Le Chen, Guoyu Hou, Ping He, Xueyang Rui, Sorachon Yoriya, Zaiguo Fu, P Li, Kai Sheng, Kai Huang, Jiang Wu, Jia Horng Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.11.148</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing the intrinsic oxygen evolution reaction activity of perovskite oxides across conductivity ranges using thin film model systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-6mgpj</link>
      <description>Lisa Heymann, Iris C. G. van den Bosch, Daan Harm Wielens, Ole Kurbjeweit, Emma van der Minne, Ellen M. Kiens, Anton Kaus, Daniel Sch&#246;n, Stephan Menzel, Bernard A. Boukamp, Felix Gunkel, Christoph Baeumer, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404448537

                The development of efficient electrocatalysts in water electrolysis is essential to decrease the high overpotentials especially at the anode where the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) takes place. However, establishing catalyst design rules to find optimal electrocatalysts is a substantial challenge. Complex oxides, which are often considered as suitable OER catalysts, can exhibit vastly different conductivity values, making it challenging to separate intrinsic catalytic activities from internal transport limitations. Here, we systematically decouple the limitations arising from electrical bulk resistivity, contact resistances to the catalyst support, and intrinsic OER catalytic properties using a systematic epitaxial thin film model catalyst approach. We investigate the influence of the resistivity of the three perovskite oxides LaNiO3-&#948; (3.7x10-4 &#8486;cm), La0.67Sr0.33MnO3-&#948; (2.7x10-3 &#8486;cm) and La0.6Ca0.4FeO3-&#948;, (0.57 &#8486;cm) on the observed catalytic activity. We tune the electron pathway through the catalyst bulk by comparing insulating and conductive substrates. The conducting substrate reduces the electron pathway through the catalyst bulk from millimeter to nanometer length scale. As we show, for the large electron pathways, the observed catalytic activity scales with the resistivity because of a highly inhomogeneous lateral current density distribution. At the same time, even on the conducting substrate (Nb-doped SrTiO3), large contact resistances occur that limit the determination of intrinsic catalytic properties. By inserting interfacial dipole layers (in this case LaAlO3) we lifted these interface resistances, allowing us to reveal the intrinsic catalytic properties of all examined catalysts. We find that La0.6Ca0.4FeO3-&#948; and LaNiO3-&#948; exhibit a similar intrinsic overpotential of 0.36 V at 0.1 mA/cm2, while their resistivities differ by three orders of magnitude. This finding shows that optimizing the electron pathway of OER catalyst can lead the way to find new structure-activity relationships and to identify high-activity catalysts even if the electronic resistance is high.</description>
      <author>Lisa Heymann, Iris C. G. van den Bosch, Daan Harm Wielens, Ole Kurbjeweit, Emma van der Minne, Ellen M. Kiens, Anton Kaus, Daniel Sch&#246;n, Stephan Menzel, Bernard A. Boukamp, Felix Gunkel, Christoph Baeumer</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-6mgpj</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A general machine-learning framework for high-throughput screening for stable and efficient RuO2-based acidic oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5347326/v1</link>
      <description>Zhe Shang, Qian Dang, Sheng Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404257326

                Abstract Doping guest elements is an effective way to increase activity and stability of RuO2 catalysts in acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, due to the vastness of doping space, it is challenging for either high-cost experiments or density functional theory (DFT) calculations to screen out the doped structures with the optimized catalytic performance. Herein, we reported a machine-learning (ML) framework that aims to realize high-throughput screening for both stability and activity of doped-RuO2 acidic OER catalysts from mono-doping to triple-doping at a low level of computational cost. Compared to the d-band theory and some other previous models, our ML model was constructed based on more general input features and realized higher prediction accuracy with mean absolute errors (MAEs) of 0.074, 0.142 and 0.082 eV for *OH, *O and *OOH adsorption, respectively. Through the ML models, three doping structures, Ru41Zn7O96, Ru41Zn4Fe3O96, and Ru39Zn4Cu4Co1O96 were found to possess the extraordinarily high stability and comparable or higher activity than the previously reported OER catalysts. This work provided an efficient study paradigm in fields of material screening and a useful guide for experimental synthesis.</description>
      <author>Zhe Shang, Qian Dang, Sheng Wang, Xiaoming Sun, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5347326/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commercial Fe-Ni-Cr alloys as highly active and low-cost oxygen evolution reaction catalyst in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4404309933</link>
      <description>Lucile Magnier, Garance Cossard, &#201;ric Sibert, Val&#233;rie Parry, Marian Chatenet, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404309933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lucile Magnier, Garance Cossard, &#201;ric Sibert, Val&#233;rie Parry, Marian Chatenet</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4404309933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redox-Mediated Oxygen Evolution Mechanism in Atomically Dispersed Pt-Supported NiO: Defying the Hydroxyl-Mediated Mechanism of NiO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01920</link>
      <description>Jatin Nama, Sudhanshu Sharma, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404237909

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jatin Nama, Sudhanshu Sharma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01920</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Porphyrin-linked graphdiyne as a substrate for constructing single-atom catalysts with transition metals towards oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404427688

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Porphyrin-linked graphdiyne as a substrate for constructing single-atom catalysts with transition metals towards oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404428333

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Porphyrin-linked graphdiyne as a substrate for constructing single-atom catalysts with transition metals towards oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404428323

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keys to Unravel the Stability/Durability Issues of Platinum-Group-Metal Catalysts toward Oxygen Evolution Reaction for Acidic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c01363</link>
      <description>Yangdong Zhou, Weijia Guo, Lixin Xing, Zhun Dong, Yunsong Yang, Lei Du, Xiaohong Xie, Siyu Ye, ACS Central Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404301210

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yangdong Zhou, Weijia Guo, Lixin Xing, Zhun Dong, Yunsong Yang, Lei Du, Xiaohong Xie, Siyu Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscentsci.4c01363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Porphyrin-linked graphdiyne as a substrate for constructing single-atom catalysts with transition metals towards oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404427730

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Porphyrin-linked graphdiyne as a substrate for constructing single-atom catalysts with transition metals towards oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404427709

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Porphyrin-linked graphdiyne as a substrate for constructing single-atom catalysts with transition metals towards oxygen reduction reactions and oxygen evolution reactions"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Jiejie Ping, Mei Wu, Manyu Liu, Yan Jiang, Wenhui Shang, Menggai Jiao, Jiahao Ruan, Nan Wang, Zhiyu Jia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404428310

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiejie Ping, Mei Wu, Manyu Liu, Yan Jiang, Wenhui Shang, Menggai Jiao, Jiahao Ruan, Nan Wang, Zhiyu Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00555d/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Degree of Span Control to Determine the Impact of Different Mechanisms and Limiting Steps: Oxygen Evolution Reaction Over Co3o4(001) as a Case Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5023098</link>
      <description>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404443680

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kapil Dhaka, Kai S. Exner</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5023098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microenvironment Regulation of the electronic structure of bismuth oxychloride via rare-earth element Samarium doping for remarkable Visible-Light-Responsive oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161740</link>
      <description>Zheng Gao, Yuhong Luo, Yu Qi, Zhaochi Feng, Beibei Dong, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404402775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheng Gao, Yuhong Luo, Yu Qi, Zhaochi Feng, Beibei Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamma-rays induced strong coupling between Ru nanoparticle and cobalt-based metal organic framework nanolayer for methanol oxidation and hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04418e</link>
      <description>Mengyu Hu, Hanzhi Yu, Chong Chen, Yukun Zhang, Changjiang Hu, Jun Ma, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404390003

                The development of anodic reactions with accelerated kinetics to replace the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) reaction to promote the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with high value-added production is of crucial...</description>
      <author>Mengyu Hu, Hanzhi Yu, Chong Chen, Yukun Zhang, Changjiang Hu, Jun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04418e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile engineering of CoS/rGO heterostructures on carbon cloth for efficient all-pH hydrogen evolution reaction and alkaline water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06710j</link>
      <description>Yuxian Chen, Jiayi Rong, Qiaolin Fan, Meng Sun, Qing Deng, Zhonghua Ni, Xiaolu Li, Tao Hu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404420194

                Developing a cost-effective and commercially viable catalyst from non-noble metals that exhibits superior performance in both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) presents a significant challenge...</description>
      <author>Yuxian Chen, Jiayi Rong, Qiaolin Fan, Meng Sun, Qing Deng, Zhonghua Ni, Xiaolu Li, Tao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06710j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical ZnCoS@CoFe-layered double hydroxide on Ni foam to enhance the OER performance for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03986f</link>
      <description>Tianyun Li, Zhongxiao Chen, Chunping Dong, Dan Wang, Wenchang Wang, Xueling Shan, Zhidong Chen, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404282029

                For sustainable energy generation technologies, improving the slow kinetics of the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential. In this study, a three-step hydrothermal-sulfidation-electrodeposition method was developed to prepare a...</description>
      <author>Tianyun Li, Zhongxiao Chen, Chunping Dong, Dan Wang, Wenchang Wang, Xueling Shan, Zhidong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03986f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Oxide Pathway Mechanism for Sustainable Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12942</link>
      <description>Xuejie Cao, Hongye Qin, Jinyang Zhang, Xiaojie Chen, Lifang Jiao, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404283747

                The advancement of acid-stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is crucial for efficient hydrogen production through proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis. Unfortunately, the activity of electrocatalysts is constrained by a linear scaling relationship in the adsorbed evolution mechanism, while the lattice-oxygen-mediated mechanism undermines stability. Here, we propose a heterogeneous dual-site oxide pathway mechanism (OPM) that avoids these limitations through direct dioxygen radical coupling. A combination of Lewis acid (Cr) and Ru to form solid solution oxides (Cr</description>
      <author>Xuejie Cao, Hongye Qin, Jinyang Zhang, Xiaojie Chen, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12942</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XPS investigation of CuxO-functionalized amorphous carbon nitride</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0004078</link>
      <description>Giacomo Marchiori, Mattia Benedet, Angelica Fasan, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto, Surface Science Spectra. 31(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404243982

                In this work, we report the x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy characterization of a novel nanocomposite (photo)electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction, based on amorphous carbon nitride (aCN) functionalized with CuxO nanoparticles (NPs). The specimen has been fabricated employing two sequential plasma-assisted processes, involving the initial aCN deposition onto conductive glass via magnetron sputtering, followed by carbon nitride functionalization with CuxO (x = 1, 2) NPs by radio frequency-sputtering. The results reported herein include the survey spectrum and the high-resolution C 1s, N 1s, O 1s, Cu 2p, and Cu LMM signals. The most significant spectral features are analyzed and critically discussed.</description>
      <author>Giacomo Marchiori, Mattia Benedet, Angelica Fasan, Davide Barreca, Chiara Maccato, Gian Andrea Rizzi, Alberto Gasparotto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1116/6.0004078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting electrode performance and bubble management via Direct Laser
  Interference Patterning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.03373</link>
      <description>Hannes Rox, Fabian R&#228;nke, Jonathan M&#228;dler, Mateusz Marzec, Krystian Soko&#322;owski, Robert Baumann, Homa Hamedi, Xuegeng Yang, Gerd Mutschke, Leon Urbas, Andr&#233;s Fabi&#225;n Lasagni, Kerstin Eckert, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404354505

                Laser-structuring techniques like Direct Laser Interference Patterning show great potential for optimizing electrodes for water electrolysis. Therefore, a systematic experimental study based on statistical design of experiments is performed to analyze the influence of the spatial period and the aspect ratio between spatial period and structure depth on the electrode performance for pure Ni electrodes. The electrochemically active surface area could be increased by a factor of 12 compared to a non-structured electrode. For oxygen evolution reaction, a significantly lower onset potential and overpotential ($\approx$-164 mV at 100 mA/cm$^2$) is found. This is explained by a lower number of active nucleation sites and, simultaneously, larger detached bubbles, resulting in reduced electrode blocking and thus, lower ohmic resistance. It is found that the spatial distance between the laser-structures is the decisive processing parameter for the improvement of the electrode performance.</description>
      <author>Hannes Rox, Fabian R&#228;nke, Jonathan M&#228;dler, Mateusz Marzec, Krystian Soko&#322;owski, Robert Baumann, Homa Hamedi, Xuegeng Yang, Gerd Mutschke, Leon Urbas, Andr&#233;s Fabi&#225;n Lasagni, Kerstin Eckert</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.03373</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Rechargeable Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225313</link>
      <description>Hui Zhao, Molecules. 29(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404241269

                Rechargeable Zn-air batteries are considered to be an effective energy storage device due to their high energy density, environmental friendliness, and long operating life. Further progress on rechargeable Zn-air batteries with high energy density/power density is greatly needed to satisfy the increasing energy conversion and storage demands. This review summarizes the strategies proposed so far to pursue high-efficiency Zn-air batteries, including the aspects of the electrocatalysts (from noble metals to non-noble metals), the electrode chemistry (from the oxygen evolution reaction to the organic oxidation reaction), electrode engineering (from powdery to free-standing), aqueous electrolytes (from alkaline to non-alkaline) and the battery configuration (from liquid to flexible). An essential evaluation of electrochemistry is highlighted to solve the challenges in boosting the efficiency of rechargeable metal-air batteries. In the end, the perspective on current challenges and future research directions to promote the industrial application of rechargeable Zn-air batteries is provided.</description>
      <author>Hui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29225313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Analysis of the Conceptual and Functional Factors Affecting the Effectiveness of Proton-Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering8060116</link>
      <description>Gaydaa Al Zohbi, ChemEngineering. 8(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404322371

                Hydrogen has the potential to decarbonize the energy and industrial sectors in the future, mainly if it is generated by water electrolysis. The proton-exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) system is regarded as a propitious technology to produce green hydrogen from water using power supplied by renewable energy sources. It offers many benefits, such as high performance, high proton conductibility, quick response, compact size, and low working temperature. Many conceptual and functional parameters influence the effectiveness of PEM, including temperature, pressure of anode and cathode regions, water content and wideness of the layer, and cathode and anode exchange current density. In addition, the anodic half-reaction (known as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER)) and cathodic half-reaction (known as the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)) perform an important function in the development of PEMWE. The current study aims to present these parameters and discuss their impacts on the performance of PEM. Also, the PEM efficiency is presented. The different methods used to enhance the scattering of OER electrocatalysts and minimize catalyst loading to minimize the price of PEMWE are also highlighted. Moreover, the alternative noble metals that could be used as electrocatalysts in HER and OER to minimize the cost of PEM are reviewed and presented.</description>
      <author>Gaydaa Al Zohbi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/chemengineering8060116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe Hydroxide Nanopheres for Enhanced Alkaline Splitting and Seawater Oxidation:Anion Doping Effects of Fluorine and Carbonate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403628</link>
      <description>Tingting Zheng, Junyu Shi, Dandan Wang, Yulin Min, Qunjie Xu, Qiaoxia Li, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404458249

                Green hydrogen production can be achieved through electrolysis of fresh water or the use of renewable energy to electrolyze seawater. However, due to the low activity and poor stability of oxygen evolution reaction catalysts, direct electrolysis of alkaline seawater faces significant challenges. Herein, The catalyst F&#8208;CoFe(OH)&#8208;CO3/NF with three&#8208;dimensional nanosphere structure was prepared, The introduction of CO32&#8208; into the intermediate layer of CoFe Hydroxide improves the corrosion resistance of alkaline electrolyte and the doping of F&#8208; is to design three&#8208;dimensional layered nanostructures, increase the active site, and accelerate the diffusion of the electrolyte. By in situ Raman analysis, partial oxidation of CoFe hydroxide to CoFe (oxy)hydroxide as the active center can accelerating the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;related intermediates. In 1M KOH, it requires overpotentials of 210 mV and 251mV to drive current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8208;2, respectively. And it remained stable at the current density of 100 mA cm&#8208;2 for 120 h in 1M KOH. F&#8208;CoFe(OH)&#8208;CO3/NF can also catalyzes the decomposition of electrolytic seawater. Compared with hydroxide, anion&#8208;doped carbonate hydroxide is more efficient and stable in electrolyte solution, which is of great importance for the development of a new stable electrocatalyst for water decomposition.</description>
      <author>Tingting Zheng, Junyu Shi, Dandan Wang, Yulin Min, Qunjie Xu, Qiaoxia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403628</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfate Oxyanion Steered &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;Orbital Electronic State of Nickel&#8208;Iron Nanoalloy for Boosting Electrocatalytic Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408171</link>
      <description>Yachao Jin, Xinjian Qu, Zihao Zhou, Rong Liu, Mengxian Zhang, Li Song, Wenqiang Ma, Ming&#8208;Dao Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404390009

                Abstract Oxyanion groups recently offer an innovative avenue for improving the sluggish kinetics of electrochemical reactions benefitting from their particular polyanion configurations and large electronegativity. Nevertheless, the exact structure design and deep regulating mechanism of oxyanion species remain poorly understood. Herein, a fresh architecture of the sulfate oxyanion coordinated nickel&#8208;iron nanoalloy on nitrogen and sulfur co&#8208;doped carbon nanotube (SO 4 2&#8722; &#8208;NiFe/NSCT) is newly proposed to study the activity increment effect and mechanism. The SO 4 2&#8722; &#8208;NiFe/NSCT displays hierarchical nanostructure with robust&#8208;wrinkled surface and highly efficient active sites. Importantly, the SO 4 2&#8722; group, as a significant manipulation factor, is first evidenced to promote the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activity for NiFe nanoalloy under the reductive condition, showcasing outstanding bifunctional properties toward ORR and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), as well as the exceptional performance in non&#8208;aqueous Li&#8208;O 2 battery. Both experimental and theoretical results elucidate that, as an electron bridge, the introduction of SO 4 2&#8722; downshifts the d&#8208;band center of SO 4 2&#8722; &#8208;NiFe/NSCT and gives the electron transfer passageway between the H atom in OH* intermediate and the O atom in SO 4 2&#8722; group, greatly optimizing the metal&#8208;intermediate interaction with weaker bond energy. This work provides a deep insight into the activity enhancement mechanism by the sulfate oxyanion.</description>
      <author>Yachao Jin, Xinjian Qu, Zihao Zhou, Rong Liu, Mengxian Zhang, Li Song, Wenqiang Ma, Ming&#8208;Dao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408171</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Raman Study of Layered Double Hydroxide Catalysts for Water Oxidation to Hydrogen Evolution: Recent Progress and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17225712</link>
      <description>Jing Wen, Siyuan Tang, Xiang Ding, Yin Yin, Fuzhan Song, Xinchun Yang, Energies. 17(22)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404417724

                With the increasing global emphasis on green energy and sustainable development goals, the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is gradually becoming a crucial focus in research on water oxidation for hydrogen generation. However, its complicated reaction processes associated with its high energy barrier severely limit the efficiency of energy conversion. Recently, layered double hydroxide (LDH) has been considered as one of the most promising catalysts in alkaline media. Nonetheless, lacking a deep insight into the kinetic process of the electrocatalytic OER process is detrimental to the further optimization of LDH catalysts. Therefore, monitoring the catalytic reaction kinetic process via surface-sensitive in situ spectroscopy is especially important. In particular, the in situ Raman technique is capable of providing fingerprint information for surface species and intermediates in the operating environment. From the perspective of Raman spectroscopy, this paper provides an exhaustive overview of research progress in in situ Raman for the characterization of the catalytic mechanism of LDH catalysts, providing theoretical guidance for designing LDH materials. Finally, we present an incisive discussion on the challenges of the electrocatalytic in situ Raman technique and its future development trend.</description>
      <author>Jing Wen, Siyuan Tang, Xiang Ding, Yin Yin, Fuzhan Song, Xinchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17225712</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn&#8208;Doped CoFeP Nanosheets as Effective Electrocatalysts for Superior Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202401512</link>
      <description>Ning Li, Yue Dong, Wei Ma, Jiatong Zhang, Yanping Qiu, Yangqin Gao, Zhifeng Liu, Lei Ge, Energy Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404449340

                For green hydrogen, the exploitation of advanced electrocatalysts is crucial, and transition metal phosphides have great potential in water splitting due to their abundant reserves and optimized electronic structure. Herein, a synergistic approach involving Mn doping and phosphorization is applied to CoFe&#8208;layered double hydroxide nanoflowers to produce a series of bifunctional catalysts Mn&#8208;doped CoFeP (Mn&#8208;CoFeP). Electrochemical evaluations demonstrate that the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of Mn(10%)&#8208;CoFeP both have notable improvement in 1 M KOH, with the overpotentials of only 160 and 239 mV to achieve current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. Comparative electrocatalytic analysis indicates that moderate Mn doping mainly contributes to improve the OER performance, while the phosphorization significantly enhances the HER activity, resulting in effective bifunctional catalysis. For overall water decomposition, a total hydrolysis electrolysis cell equipped with the Mn(10%)&#8208;CoFeP bifunctional catalyst requires only 1.64 V to reach a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Furthermore, it performs stable operation for 10 h at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a current maintenance rate of 83.6%. This work offers new insights into preparing effective bifunctional electrocatalysts, advancing clean energy development.</description>
      <author>Ning Li, Yue Dong, Wei Ma, Jiatong Zhang, Yanping Qiu, Yangqin Gao, Zhifeng Liu, Lei Ge</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202401512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase transformation and water adsorption behavior of ALD deposited and
  annealed Ru and RuO2 films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.22666</link>
      <description>Swapnil Nalawade, R. S. Kim, Jonathan Mahl, Sheilah Cherono, Ikenna Chris-Okoro, V. Cr&#259;ciun, Jia Yan, Ethan J. Crumlin, D. Kumar, Shyam Aravamudhan, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404342523

                Ruthenium metal and its oxide stand out for their exceptional catalytic activity, stability in Oxygen Evolution Reactions (OER) and electrical conductivity, making them indispensable in electronics and electrocatalysis. In this study, atomic layer deposition (ALD) was used to synthesize ruthenium thin films, and the subsequent annealing of deposited ruthenium films at different elevated temperatures resulted in a progressive phase transformation from ruthenium metal to ruthenium dioxide (RuO2). The films were systematically characterized using atomic force microscopy (AFM), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), X-ray diffraction (XRD), and Raman spectroscopy. XPS was carried out with both soft X-rays from a lab-based instrument and tender X-rays from the synchrotron. The different probing depths of the techniques revealed the gradual transformation of Ru to RuO2 from the top surface as the annealing temperature was increased. The water adsorption behavior of the films was also assessed using ambient pressure XPS (APXPS) at different water vapor pressures. The influence of annealing conditions on the films affinity for water and tendency for water dissociation was analyzed to seek an initial understanding of the surface chemistry relevant to electrochemical water splitting.</description>
      <author>Swapnil Nalawade, R. S. Kim, Jonathan Mahl, Sheilah Cherono, Ikenna Chris-Okoro, V. Cr&#259;ciun, Jia Yan, Ethan J. Crumlin, D. Kumar, Shyam Aravamudhan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.22666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Scalable One&#8208;step Production of Catalysts for Low&#8208;Iridium Content Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401659</link>
      <description>Suriya Venkatesan, Jens Mitzel, Sambal Shashank Ambu, Tobias Morawietz, Indro Biswas, Oscar Recalde, Esmaeil Adabifiroozjaei, Leopoldo Molina&#8208;Luna, Deven P. Estes, Karsten Wegner, Pawel Gazdzicki, Aldo Saul Gago, K. Andreas Friedrich, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404443367

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) is a promising technology for green hydrogen production, although its widespread development with state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art loadings is threatened by the scarcity of iridium (Ir). Homogeneous dispersion of Ir in an immiscible electro&#8208;ceramic matrix can enhance catalytic mass activity and structural stability. The study presents Ir y Sn 0.9(1&#8722; y ) Sb 0.1(1&#8722; y ) O x solid solutions produced by highly scalable flame spray pyrolysis (FSP) process as efficient anode electrocatalysts for PEMWE, containing only 0.2 mg cm &#8722;2 of Ir in the catalyst layer (CL). Intense mixing of metal vapor and large thermal gradients in the precursor&#8208;derived high&#8208;temperature flame aids stabilizing sub&#8208;nanoscale entropic mixing within self&#8208;preserved 4&#8211;6 nm particles. Detailed investigations confirm that the one&#8208;step prepared solid solution electrocatalysts exhibit up to fourfold higher activity toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) compared to Ir black. The anode of a PEMWE utilizing this catalyst exhibits high performance and stability over 2000 h but with tenfold lower Ir loading than the state&#8208;of&#8208;art.</description>
      <author>Suriya Venkatesan, Jens Mitzel, Sambal Shashank Ambu, Tobias Morawietz, Indro Biswas, Oscar Recalde, Esmaeil Adabifiroozjaei, Leopoldo Molina&#8208;Luna, Deven P. Estes, Karsten Wegner, Pawel Gazdzicki, Aldo Saul Gago, K. Andreas Friedrich</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202401659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tribute to Kenneth Sauer (1931&#8211;2022): a mentor, a role-model, and an inspiration to all in the field of photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01119-0</link>
      <description>Junko Yano, Jan Kern, Robert E. Blankenship, Johannes Messinger, Vittal K. Yachandra, Photosynthesis Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404337762

                Abstract Kenneth (Ken) Sauer was a mainstay of research in photosynthesis at the University of California, Berkeley and the Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory (LBNL) for more than 50 years. Ken will be remembered by his colleagues, and other workers in the field of photosynthesis as well, for his pioneering work that introduced the physical techniques whose application have enriched our understanding of the basic reactions of oxygenic photosynthesis. His laboratory was a training ground for many students and postdocs who went on to success in the field of photosynthesis and many others. Trained as a physical chemist, he always brought that quantitative approach to research questions and used several spectroscopic methods in his research. His broad scientific interests concerned the role of manganese in oxygen evolution, electronic properties of chlorophylls, energy transport in antenna complexes, and electron transport reactions. He was also an enthusiastic teacher, an enormously successful mentor who leaves behind a legion of scientists as his abiding legacy, a lover of music and the outdoors with many interests beyond science, and a dedicated family man with a great sense of humility. In this tribute, we summarize some aspects of Ken Sauer&#8217;s life and career, illustrated with selected research achievements, and describe his approach to research and life as we perceived it, which is complemented by reminiscences of several current researchers in photosynthesis and other fields. The supporting material includes Ken Sauers&#8217;s CV and publication list, as well as a list of the graduate students and postdocs he trained and of researchers that spent a sabbatical in his lab.</description>
      <author>Junko Yano, Jan Kern, Robert E. Blankenship, Johannes Messinger, Vittal K. Yachandra</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01119-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Charge Separation and Transport: Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting in &#945;-Fe2O3/CZTS Nanorod Arrays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110812</link>
      <description>Wen Chen, Ao-Sheng She, Ming-Hao Ji, Hao-Yan Shi, Yang Yang, Yunlong Pu, Rui Chen, Weihua Yang, Yanxin Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu, Catalysts. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404254297

                This study explores the enhancement of &#945;-Fe2O3 (hematite) nanorod arrays for photoelec-trochemical applications by constructing a Cu2ZnSnS4 (CZTS) heterojunction. While &#945;-Fe2O3 offers good stability, a low cost, and environmental benefits, its efficiency is limited by slow oxygen evolution kinetics, high carrier recombination rates, and low conductivity. By introducing CZTS, a material with strong light absorption and charge transport properties, we enhance the separation of photogenerated charge carriers, reduce charge transfer resistance, and increase the carrier concentration, thereby boosting the overall photoelectrochemical performance. The experimental results show that a modified FC-15 photoanode achieves a photocurrent density of 3.40 mA/cm2 at 1.60 V vs. RHE, a substantial increase compared to 0.40 mA/cm2 for unmodified &#945;-Fe2O3. Band gap analysis reveals a reduced band gap in the FC-15 material, enhancing light absorption and boosting the photoelectrocatalytic performance. In photoelectrochemical water-splitting tests, the FC-15 photoanode achieves a hydrogen production rate of 41.6 &#956;mol/cm2/h, which is significantly improved over the unmodified sample at 5.64 &#956;mol/cm2/h. These findings indicate that the CZTS/&#945;-Fe2O3 heterojunction effectively promotes charge separation, enhances charge transport, and improves light absorption, substantially increasing photocatalytic efficiency. This heterojunction approach offers new insights and technical strategies for developing photocatalytic materials with potential applications in renewable energy.</description>
      <author>Wen Chen, Ao-Sheng She, Ming-Hao Ji, Hao-Yan Shi, Yang Yang, Yunlong Pu, Rui Chen, Weihua Yang, Yanxin Chen, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14110812</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Two&#8208;Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Electrochemical Glycerol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416178</link>
      <description>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404458317

                Electrochemical glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) is a promising candidate to couple with cathodic reaction, like hydrogen evolution reaction, to produce high&#8208;value product with less energy consumption. Two&#8208;dimensional conjugated metal&#8208;organic frameworks (2D c&#8208;MOFs), comprising square&#8208;planar metal&#8208;coordination motifs (e.g., MO4, M(NH)4, MS4), are notable for their programable active sites, intrinsic charge transport, and excellent stability, making them promising catalyst candidates for GOR. Here, we introduce a novel class of 2D c&#8208;MOFs electrocatalysts, M2[NiPcS8] (M=Co/Ni/Cu), which are synthesized via coordination of octathiolphthalocyaninato nickel (NiPc(SH)8) with various metal centers. Due to a fast kinetic and high activity of CoS4 sites for GOR, the electrocatalytic tests demonstrate that Co2[NiPcS8] supported on carbon paper displays a low GOR potential of 1.35 V vs. RHE at 10 mA cm&#8208;2, significantly reducing the overall water&#8208;electrolysis&#8208;voltage reduction by 0.27 V from oxygen evolution reaction to GOR, thereby outperforming Ni2[NiPcS8] and Cu2[NiPcS8]. Additionally, we have determined that the GOR activity of CoX4 linkage sites varies with different heteroatoms, following an experimentally and theoretically confirmed activity order of CoS4&gt;CoO4&gt;Co(NH)4. The GOR performance of Co2[NiPcS8] not only demonstrate superior performance among non&#8208;noble metal complex, but also provides critical insights on designing high&#8208;performance MOF electrocatalysts upon optimizing the electronic environment of active sites.</description>
      <author>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8208;Phthalocyanine&#8208;Based Two&#8208;Dimensional Conjugated Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Electrochemical Glycerol Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416178</link>
      <description>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404455598

                Electrochemical glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) is a promising candidate to couple with cathodic reaction, like hydrogen evolution reaction, to produce high&#8208;value product with less energy consumption. Two&#8208;dimensional conjugated metal&#8208;organic frameworks (2D c&#8208;MOFs), comprising square&#8208;planar metal&#8208;coordination motifs (e.g., MO4, M(NH)4, MS4), are notable for their programable active sites, intrinsic charge transport, and excellent stability, making them promising catalyst candidates for GOR. Here, we introduce a novel class of 2D c&#8208;MOFs electrocatalysts, M2[NiPcS8] (M=Co/Ni/Cu), which are synthesized via coordination of octathiolphthalocyaninato nickel (NiPc(SH)8) with various metal centers. Due to a fast kinetic and high activity of CoS4 sites for GOR, the electrocatalytic tests demonstrate that Co2[NiPcS8] supported on carbon paper displays a low GOR potential of 1.35 V vs. RHE at 10 mA cm&#8208;2, significantly reducing the overall water&#8208;electrolysis&#8208;voltage reduction by 0.27 V from oxygen evolution reaction to GOR, thereby outperforming Ni2[NiPcS8] and Cu2[NiPcS8]. Additionally, we have determined that the GOR activity of CoX4 linkage sites varies with different heteroatoms, following an experimentally and theoretically confirmed activity order of CoS4&gt;CoO4&gt;Co(NH)4. The GOR performance of Co2[NiPcS8] not only demonstrate superior performance among non&#8208;noble metal complex, but also provides critical insights on designing high&#8208;performance MOF electrocatalysts upon optimizing the electronic environment of active sites.</description>
      <author>Xing Huang, Mingchao Wang, Haixia Zhong, Xiaodong Li, Huaping Wang, Yang Lu, Geping Zhang, Yannan Liu, Shouxin Zhang, Ruqiang Zou, Xinliang Feng, Renhao Dong&#10731;</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416178</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomistic understanding of hydrogen coverage on RuO2(110) surface under
  electrochemical conditions from ab initio statistical thermodynamics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.18421</link>
      <description>Fuchun Zhang, Jan Kloppenburg, Chia&#8208;Yi Lin, Luka Mitrovic, Simon Gelin, Ismaila Dabo, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich, Geoffroy Hautier, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404306534

                Understanding the dehydrogenation of transition metal oxide surfaces under electrochemical potential is critical to the control of important chemical processes such as the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Using first principles computations, we model the thermodynamic dehydrogenation process on RuO$_2$(110) and compare the results to experimental cyclic voltammetry (CV) on single crystal. We use a cluster expansion model trained on *ab initio* energy data coupled with Monte Carlo (MC) sampling to derive the macroscopic electrochemical observables, i.e., experimental CV, from the energetics of different hydrogen coverage microstates on well-defined RuO$_2$(110). Our model reproduces the unique "two-peaks" cyclic voltammogram observed experimentally with current density peak positions and shapes in good qualitative agreement. We show that RuO$_2$(110) starts as a water-covered surface with hydrogen on bridge (BRG) and coordination-unsaturated sites (CUS) at low potential (less than 0.4 V vs. reversible hydrogen electrode, RHE). As the potential increases, the hydrogens on BRG desorb, becoming the main contributor to the first CV peak with smaller contributions from CUS. When all BRG hydrogens are desorbed (before 1.2 V vs. RHE), the remaining CUS hydrogens desorb abruptly in a very small potential window leading to the sharp second peak observed during CV. Our work shows that above 1.23 V, the OER proceeds on a fully dehydrogenated RuO$_2$(110) surface.</description>
      <author>Fuchun Zhang, Jan Kloppenburg, Chia&#8208;Yi Lin, Luka Mitrovic, Simon Gelin, Ismaila Dabo, Darrell G. Schlom, Jin Suntivich, Geoffroy Hautier</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.18421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Synthesis of 2D Nanostructured Bimetallic Oxide (NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;) on Self&#8208;Supported Nickel Foam for Boosted Electrocatalytic Seawater Oxidation Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400941</link>
      <description>G. Shanmugam, Harish Santhana Krishnan, Senthil Kumar Eswaran, M. Navaneethan, Energy Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404370196

                The design and development of effective electrocatalysts containing nonprecious materials for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in seawater splitting remains a significant challenge for large&#8208;scale industrial hydrogen production. Nonprecious bimetallic oxide&#8208;constructed catalysts are utmost promising candidates to obtain boosting electrochemical water oxidation performance. Herein, a transition bimetallic oxide nanostructure electrocatalyst as NiMoO 4 vertically standing nanosheet over the nickel foam substrate (NiMoO 4 /NF) for electrochemical water oxidation process in alkaline fresh/simulated seawater conditions is presented. NiMoO 4 nanostructure on NF substrate is successfully obtained using a straightforward hydrothermal reaction route and thermal annealing processes. The surface morphology with elemental characteristics of the resultant NiMoO 4 /NF sample exposes highly homogenous vertical standing nanosheets assembled on the NF surface. The electrochemical water oxidation performance of the as&#8208;prepared electrodes demonstrates the function of diverse hydrothermal reaction times (3, 6, and 9 h) in fresh and simulated seawater electrolyte conditions. In alkaline seawater electrolyte conditions, optimal hydrothermal reaction time&#8208;assisted NiMoO 4 /NF&#8208;6 h electrocatalyst possesses significant OER electrocatalytic actives compared to the other samples. Similarly, NiMoO 4 /NF&#8208;6 h catalyst exhibits a small overpotential of 429 mV to achieve a current density of 50 mA cm &#8722;2 with a Tafel slope value of 122 mV dec &#8722;1 for OER process. As a result, the resultant superior electrocatalytic performance of the optimal hydrothermal reaction time&#8208;aided electrocatalyst (NiMoO 4 /NF&#8208;6 h) is ascribed to highly accessible catalytic active centers and enhanced charge transfer kinetics at the interface for electrochemical reactions. Thus, proposed nanostructure&#8208;constructed electrocatalysts could prove to be prospective OER candidates for electrochemical water oxidation.</description>
      <author>G. Shanmugam, Harish Santhana Krishnan, Senthil Kumar Eswaran, M. Navaneethan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202400941</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Non-Oxygenic Origins of Thylakoids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.07081</link>
      <description>Luc Cornet, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404391957

                Recent studies have shed light on the emergence and evolution of oxygenic photosynthesis. It is likely that the ancestor of Terrabacteria already possessed two distinct reaction centers, and that the ability to split water via photosystem II arose early in their evolution. Consequently, it is equally probable that the emergence of thylakoid membranes played a crucial role in the accumulation of oxygen in the atmosphere. However, the study of thylakoid emergence remains less explored than the origin of photosystems. With a highly synchronized process involving numerous assembly factors, the biogenesis of thylakoid membranes suggests the existence of intermediate evolutionary states in the emergence of these compartments. Constrained by the sulfide-rich environment of the Archean, I propose a non-oxygenic origin of thylakoid membranes, which would have been initially devoted to alternative electron flows.</description>
      <author>Luc Cornet</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.07081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructing the Coordination Environment of Fe/Co Dual&#8208;atom Sites towards Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis for Zn&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419595</link>
      <description>Hengqi Liu, Jinzhen Huang, Kun Feng, Rui Xiong, Shengyu Ma, Ran Wang, Qiang Fu, Moniba Rafique, Zhiguo Liu, Jiecai Han, Daxing Hua, Jiajie Li, Jun Zhong, Xianjie Wang, Zhonglong Zhao, Tai Yao, Sida Jiang, Ping Xu, Zhihua Zhang, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404378712

                Dual&#8208;atom catalysts with nitrogen&#8208;coordinated metal sites embedded in carbon can drive the oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER) in rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs), and the further improvement is limited by the linear scaling relationship of intermediate binding energies in the absorbate evolution mechanism (AEM). Triggering the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) is promising to overcome this challenge, but has yet been verified since the lacking of bridge oxygen (O) in the rigid coordination environment of the metal centers. Here, we demonstrate that suitably tailored dual&#8208;atom catalysts of FeCo&#8211;N&#8211;C can undergo out&#8208;plane and in&#8208;plane reconstruction to form the both axial O and bridge O at the metal centers, and thus activate the LOM pathway. The tailored FeCo&#8211;N&#8211;C with shortened Fe&#8211;N bonds also favor the ORR process, therefore is a promising dual&#8208;atom oxygen catalyst. The assembled rechargeable ZABs demonstrate a peak power density of 332 mW cm&#8722;2, and exhibit no notable decline after ~ 720 h of continuous cycling.</description>
      <author>Hengqi Liu, Jinzhen Huang, Kun Feng, Rui Xiong, Shengyu Ma, Ran Wang, Qiang Fu, Moniba Rafique, Zhiguo Liu, Jiecai Han, Daxing Hua, Jiajie Li, Jun Zhong, Xianjie Wang, Zhonglong Zhao, Tai Yao, Sida Jiang, Ping Xu, Zhihua Zhang, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPD: Oxygen levels in the cornea with contact lens wear</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12968/opti.2023.268.6911.20</link>
      <description>Douglas Clarkson, Optician. 268(6911)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4404243079

                Dr Douglas Clarkson describes the way a cornea maintains oxygen supply during contact lens wear against the back-drop of contact lens evolution over the last decades (C106006, suitable for logging as one distance learning CPD point for optometrists, contact lens opticians and dispensing opticians)</description>
      <author>Douglas Clarkson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12968/opti.2023.268.6911.20</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CORROS&#195;O LOCALIZADA DO ALUM&#205;NIO EM MEIOS AERADOS E EM MEIOS COM BAIXO TEOR OXIG&#202;NIO: ESTUDO E COMPARA&#199;&#195;O POR MEIO DE CURVAS DE POLARIZA&#199;&#195;O</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21577/0100-4042.20250067</link>
      <description>Jo&#227;o Victor de Sousa Araujo, Aline D Gabbardo, S.M.C. Fernandes, Isolda Costa, Qu&#237;mica Nova. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404239881

                LOCALIZED CORROSION OF ALUMINUM IN AERATED ENVIRONMENTS AND IN ENVIRONMENTS WITH LOW OXYGEN CONTENT: STUDY AND COMPARISON THROUGH POLARIZATION CURVES. In this study, the influence of deaeration on the electrochemical behavior of aluminum was studied by polarization techniques. The advantages of deaeration for the evaluation of localized corrosion on aluminum are discussed. The influence of the corrosive environment with low oxygen contents on the electrochemical response of aluminum was evaluated by anodic and cathodic potentiodynamic polarization curves. The polarization tests were carried out in chloride solutions followed by optical and scanning electron microscopy characterization. It was observed that deaeration of the solution significantly influences the electrochemical behavior of aluminum, as predicted by corrosion kinetics theories. For the cathodic curves, a decrease in the limiting current density for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) was observed for low oxygen solutions, while the &#8220;apparent&#8221; initiation of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) was shifted to higher potentials. In the anodic curves, a common passive behavior was not observed in aerated conditions, however, at the corrosion potential, localized pitting was observed indicating that the material was already above the breakdown potential (Ebr). In the low oxygen content solution, however, a passive region with a breakdown potential, was observed on the anodic curves.</description>
      <author>Jo&#227;o Victor de Sousa Araujo, Aline D Gabbardo, S.M.C. Fernandes, Isolda Costa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21577/0100-4042.20250067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COMET: monitoring mitochondrial shock in anesthesiology and intensive care medicine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s44254-024-00079-x</link>
      <description>Yan Yang, Wei Zhang, Zhengliang Ma, Xiaoping Gu, Anesthesiology and Perioperative Science. 2(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404340123

                Abstract Mitochondria, as the cellular end-users of oxygen and responsible for approximately 98% of total body oxygen consumption, play a significant role in the development of organ dysfunction during shock. Therefore, integrating information on mitochondrial oxygen homeostasis with macroscopic observations of macrocirculation and microcirculation is crucial for monitoring critically ill patients or those undergoing high-risk surgery. However, current clinical practice still lack reliable surrogate parameters for assessing mitochondrial function. The Cellular Oxygen METabolism (COMET) monitor, utilizing the protoporphyrin IX triplet state lifetime technique (PpIX-TSLT), represents the first clinical device capable of non-invasive, in vivo measurement of mitochondrial oxygen pressure and oxidative phosphorylation. Recent research suggests that implementing this real-time bedside monitoring will provide additional insights into microcirculatory dynamics and enhance patient management. This review will comprehensively detail the rationale, methodologies, evolution, and clinical applications of the technique, aiming at improving the understanding of mitochondrial pathology in daily clinical practice and facilitating the development of targeted therapeutic strategies. Graphical Abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Yang, Wei Zhang, Zhengliang Ma, Xiaoping Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s44254-024-00079-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Micro-Environments to Macroscopic Effects: How the Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction Drives Cu Cathodic Corrosion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-d6hl7</link>
      <description>Hori Pada Sarker, Anshuman Goswami, Michael T. Tang, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404393449

                Cathodic corrosion of copper (Cu) has posed a significant challenge for over a century, impeding various technological progresses such as electrochemical conversion of CO2 (eCO2RR) into fuels and other value-added carbon products. In this study, employing a combined Density Functional Theory (DFT) and kinetic Monte Carlo (kMC) simulation approach, we delve into the atomistic level mechanism driving this phenomenon in Cu. Our hypothesis posits the pivotal role of alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in facilitating cathodic corrosion in Cu. We rigorously develop a pH-dependent hydroxide (OH) adsorption mechanism and calculate the equilibrium OH coverage (&#120579;OH) at varying pH levels, the thermodynamic stability of subsurface oxygen (Osub), as well as the Cu-vacancy mediated diffusion of subsurface oxygens (Osub). Through comprehensive analysis, we establish correlation among various microenvironments, including oxygen diffusion in subsurface layers, pH-dependent OH adsorption, and Cu dissolution into the electrolyte as (Cu- OH) complexes. Furthermore, our investigation explores the correlation between surface coordination environment of active sites and cathodic corrosion of Cu. Finally, by integrating DFT- derived thermodynamic data into a kMC model, we successfully predict the formation of experimentally observed corrosion pits on Cu-surfaces. This combined approach not only advances our fundamental understanding of Cu cathodic corrosion but also offers insights crucial for developing effective corrosion mitigation strategies.</description>
      <author>Hori Pada Sarker, Anshuman Goswami, Michael T. Tang, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-d6hl7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interspecies Organoids Reveal Human-Specific Molecular Features of Dopaminergic Neuron Development and Vulnerability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.14.623592</link>
      <description>Sara Nolbrant, Jenelle L. Wallace, Jingwen Ding, Tianjia Zhu, Jess L. Sevetson, Janko Kajtez, Isabella A. Baldacci, Emily K. Corrigan, Kaylynn Hoglin, Reed McMullen, Matthew T. Schmitz, Arnar Breevoort, Dani Swope, Fengxia Wu, Bryan J. Pavlovic, Sofie R. Salama, Agnete Kirkeby, Hao Huang, Nathan K. Schaefer, Alex A. Pollen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404410560

                The disproportionate expansion of telencephalic structures during human evolution involved tradeoffs that imposed greater connectivity and metabolic demands on midbrain dopaminergic neurons. Despite the central role of dopaminergic neurons in human-enriched disorders, molecular specializations associated with human-specific features and vulnerabilities of the dopaminergic system remain unexplored. Here, we establish a phylogeny-in-a-dish approach to examine gene regulatory evolution by differentiating pools of human, chimpanzee, orangutan, and macaque pluripotent stem cells into ventral midbrain organoids capable of forming long-range projections, spontaneous activity, and dopamine release. We identify human-specific gene expression changes related to axonal transport of mitochondria and reactive oxygen species buffering and candidate cis- and trans-regulatory mechanisms underlying gene expression divergence. Our findings are consistent with a model of evolved neuroprotection in response to tradeoffs related to brain expansion and could contribute to the discovery of therapeutic targets and strategies for treating disorders involving the dopaminergic system.</description>
      <author>Sara Nolbrant, Jenelle L. Wallace, Jingwen Ding, Tianjia Zhu, Jess L. Sevetson, Janko Kajtez, Isabella A. Baldacci, Emily K. Corrigan, Kaylynn Hoglin, Reed McMullen, Matthew T. Schmitz, Arnar Breevoort, Dani Swope, Fengxia Wu, Bryan J. Pavlovic, Sofie R. Salama, Agnete Kirkeby, Hao Huang, Nathan K. Schaefer, Alex A. Pollen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.14.623592</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of pore formation and carburizing mechanism of magnetite reduction by CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/02670836241298116</link>
      <description>Meijie Zhou, Liqun Ai, Lukuo Hong, Wenquan Cui, Caijiao Sun, Weijia An, Shuai Tong, Materials Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404423683

                To investigate the porosity and expansion mechanism of CO-reduced magnetite, the reduced microstructures of magnetite under conventional heating and microwave heating were compared. The microstructure characteristics of magnetite with various reduction degrees were examined in a 60%CO-Ar reduction atmosphere, and the formation and evolution mechanism of the structure were analyzed in conjunction with the reduction effect. The results indicate that the reduction product of CO reduced magnetite possesses a porous structure. Nevertheless, when the gas diffusion is restricted, the reduction process is sluggish and the porous structure is not readily formed. Microwave heating enhances the gas-phase diffusion capacity, thermodynamic carburizing capacity, and solid-phase carbon-oxygen diffusion capacity, resulting in a higher oxygen loss rate than that of conventional heating. Under the experimental conditions, the lattice shrinkage during the Fe 3 O 4 &#8594; Fe 0.88 O transformation and the rapid expansion of Fe 0.88 O &#8594; Fe 0.94 O are the causes of the crack. Microwaves facilitate the formation of pores and cracks in the product. This study offers a novel concept for the development of foam steel.</description>
      <author>Meijie Zhou, Liqun Ai, Lukuo Hong, Wenquan Cui, Caijiao Sun, Weijia An, Shuai Tong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/02670836241298116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A phenotype-structured mathematical model for the influence of hypoxia
  on oncolytic virotherapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.02413</link>
      <description>David Morselli, Giulia Chiari, Federico Frascoli, Marcello Delitala, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404355595

                The effectiveness of oncolytic virotherapy is significantly affected by several elements of the tumour microenvironment, which reduce the ability of the virus to infect cancer cells. In this work, we focus on the influence of hypoxia on this therapy and develop a novel continuous mathematical model that considers both the spatial and epigenetic heterogeneity of the tumour. We investigate how oxygen gradients within tumours affect the spatial distribution and replication of both the tumour and oncolytic viruses, focusing on regions of severe hypoxia versus normoxic areas. Additionally, we analyse the evolutionary dynamics of tumour cells under hypoxic conditions and their influence on susceptibility to viral infection. Our findings show that the reduced metabolic activity of hypoxic cells may significantly impact the virotherapy effectiveness; the knowledge of the tumour's oxygenation could, therefore, suggest the most suitable type of virus to optimise the outcome. The combination of numerical simulations and theoretical results for the model equilibrium values allows us to elucidate the complex interplay between viruses, tumour evolution and oxygen dynamics, ultimately contributing to developing more effective and personalised cancer treatments.</description>
      <author>David Morselli, Giulia Chiari, Federico Frascoli, Marcello Delitala</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.02413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research on aging mechanism and capacity attenuation of automotive lithium-ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/09544070241293593</link>
      <description>Guanqiang Ruan, Liu Shi-wen, Xing Hu, Xiaoyu Fu, Zhongxun An, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers Part D Journal of Automobile Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404325374

                In order to investigate the internal mechanism and the variation law of capacity attenuation of LIBs, a simplified electrochemical model of the LIBs was established using the nickel-cobalt-aluminum LIBs as the research object, and the aging model of solid electrolyte interface SEI growth and lithium evolution was added to simulate the electrochemical behavior of the batteries. The results showed that the porosity of the anode/diaphragm reduced continually at the start of the cycle, while the SEI film grew continuously. The loss of active materials accelerated as the number of cycles increased, while the side reaction of lithium development continued. Finally, the aging mechanism was confirmed by using microscopic morphology. The results show that the negative particles are obviously crushed and contain white deposited substances. The formation of these compounds increases the oxygen content, reduces the carbon content, reduces the porosity of the electrode, increases the overpotential of the electrolyte transport, and becomes the main reason for the attenuation of the battery life. Finally, the positive particles expand and break, which leads to the sudden reduction of the battery capacity. This study determined the evolution process of aging mechanism in the whole life cycle, and provided a theoretical basis for the establishment of mechanism aging model.</description>
      <author>Guanqiang Ruan, Liu Shi-wen, Xing Hu, Xiaoyu Fu, Zhongxun An</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/09544070241293593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pressure-Induced Superconductivity in Pr4Ni3O10 Single Crystals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.08677</link>
      <description>Cuiying Pei, Mingxin Zhang, Di Peng, Shangxiong Huangfu, Shihao Zhu, Qi Wang, Juefei Wu, Zhenfang Xing, Lili Zhang, Yulin Chen, Jinkui Zhao, Wenge Yang, Hongli Suo, Hanjie Guo, Qiaoshi Zeng, Yanpeng Qi, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404407911

                The recent discovery of superconductivity in pressurized Ruddlesden-Popper (RP) of nickelates has potential similarities with cuprate superconductors, which may provide unique perspectives on the mechanisms of high-temperature superconductivity. Up to now, most of high-pressure experiments concentrated on the lanthanum-related RP phase. Therefore, the discovery of new superconducting nickelate compounds is highly desired to explore the generality of pressure-induced superconductivity in RP nickelates. Here, we grow high-quality Pr4Ni3O10 single crystal with an optical floating zone furnace under high oxygen pressure and conduct high-pressure transport measurements with various pressure transmitting mediums. The density wave in Pr4Ni3O10 single crystal was suppressed by pressure, accompanying the arising of superconducting state beyond 10 GPa. The maximum and unsaturated Tc of 39 K is obtained within our research pressure. Although zero resistivity was not achieved in our experiments, the pressure and temperature-dependent diamagnetism along with the systematic evolution of resistivity with applied magnetic field, corroborate the superconductivity in Pr4Ni3O10 single crystals. Our findings provide a new platform for the investigation of the relationship among structural evolution, magnetism, correlation, and superconductivity in Ruddlesden-Popper nickelates.</description>
      <author>Cuiying Pei, Mingxin Zhang, Di Peng, Shangxiong Huangfu, Shihao Zhu, Qi Wang, Juefei Wu, Zhenfang Xing, Lili Zhang, Yulin Chen, Jinkui Zhao, Wenge Yang, Hongli Suo, Hanjie Guo, Qiaoshi Zeng, Yanpeng Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.08677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction of cytosine-5 DNA methylation sensitizes cells to oxidative damage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.103432</link>
      <description>Joanna Krwawicz, Caroline J. Sheeba, K Hains, Terry McMahon, Yimo Zhang, Skirmantas Kriau&#269;ionis, Peter Sarkies, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404414246

                DNA methylation at the 5 position of cytosine (5mC) is an ancient epigenetic mark in eukaryotes. The levels of total 5mC vary enormously between different species, and the DNA methyltransferases that introduce 5mC have been repeatedly lost in several independent lineages. DNA methyltransferases are a threat to genomic stability due to the increased mutagenicity of 5mC bases and the propensity of DNA methyltransferases themselves to introduce DNA alkylation damage as an off-target effect. However, whether alkylation damage explains why 5mC is frequently lost in evolution is unclear. Here we tested the fitness consequences of DNA methyltransferase-induced alkylation damage by introducing a eukaryotic-like 5mC system into E. coli . We showed that introducing 5mC genome-wide leads to increased sensitivity to alkylating agents, which is strongly enhanced by removal of the 3mC repair enzyme AlkB. Unexpectedly, we discovered that 5mC introduction led to increased sensitivity to oxidative stress. We showed that this is due to increased formation of reactive oxygen in the presence of 5mC. We determined that reactive oxygen species led to non-enzymatic oxidation of 5mC, producing modified cytosines such as 5fC that are recognised as DNA base damage in E. coli . Overall, our work identifies increased sensitivity to oxidative stress, as well as alkylating agents, as a negative consequence of genome-wide 5mC. Oxidative stress is frequently encountered by organisms in their environment, thus offering a plausible reason for total loss of 5mC in some species.</description>
      <author>Joanna Krwawicz, Caroline J. Sheeba, K Hains, Terry McMahon, Yimo Zhang, Skirmantas Kriau&#269;ionis, Peter Sarkies</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.103432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction of cytosine-5 DNA methylation sensitizes cells to oxidative damage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.103432.1</link>
      <description>Joanna Krwawicz, Caroline J. Sheeba, K Hains, Terry McMahon, Yimo Zhang, Skirmantas Kriau&#269;ionis, Peter Sarkies, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404414306

                DNA methylation at the 5 position of cytosine (5mC) is an ancient epigenetic mark in eukaryotes. The levels of total 5mC vary enormously between different species, and the DNA methyltransferases that introduce 5mC have been repeatedly lost in several independent lineages. DNA methyltransferases are a threat to genomic stability due to the increased mutagenicity of 5mC bases and the propensity of DNA methyltransferases themselves to introduce DNA alkylation damage as an off-target effect. However, whether alkylation damage explains why 5mC is frequently lost in evolution is unclear. Here we tested the fitness consequences of DNA methyltransferase-induced alkylation damage by introducing a eukaryotic-like 5mC system into E. coli . We showed that introducing 5mC genome-wide leads to increased sensitivity to alkylating agents, which is strongly enhanced by removal of the 3mC repair enzyme AlkB. Unexpectedly, we discovered that 5mC introduction led to increased sensitivity to oxidative stress. We showed that this is due to increased formation of reactive oxygen in the presence of 5mC. We determined that reactive oxygen species led to non-enzymatic oxidation of 5mC, producing modified cytosines such as 5fC that are recognised as DNA base damage in E. coli . Overall, our work identifies increased sensitivity to oxidative stress, as well as alkylating agents, as a negative consequence of genome-wide 5mC. Oxidative stress is frequently encountered by organisms in their environment, thus offering a plausible reason for total loss of 5mC in some species.</description>
      <author>Joanna Krwawicz, Caroline J. Sheeba, K Hains, Terry McMahon, Yimo Zhang, Skirmantas Kriau&#269;ionis, Peter Sarkies</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7554/elife.103432.1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of MoS2/CNT heterostructure with rich S-vacancy for enhanced HER performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237254</link>
      <description>Yuxin Sun, Jinhua Li, Zhiying Wang, Fengxue Tan, Kaixi Shi, Yingjiao Zhai, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 161(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404244572

                Molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) is a promising electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) due to excellent stability and low cost. However, the utilization in electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution is constrained by inherent shortcomings, including fewer edge active sites, poor dispersion, and electrical conductivity. In this work, MoS2 was compounded with carbon nanotubes (CNTs), which are known for their high specific surface area and excellent electrical conductivity. These CNTs, laden with oxygen-containing functional groups, provided nucleation sites that facilitated the rapid assembly of MoS2 nanoflowers under hydrothermal conditions within 3 h. Due to their diminutive size (&#8764;300 nm), these nanoflowers possess a large specific surface area and numerous active sites at their edges. Furthermore, MoS2 nanoflowers exhibited a high concentration of intrinsic S-vacancies. This heterojunction material exhibited superior HER properties. In addition, density functional theory simulation further confirmed that the MoS2 with S vacancy and CNT heterojunction electrocatalysts (VS-M/C) provided a fast charge transfer pathway for water electrolysis, and analysis showed that the conduction band minimum and valence band maximum were mainly contributed by the d orbits of Mo and the p orbits of C. This study proffered a novel approach for the engineering of high-performance MoS2-based HER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuxin Sun, Jinhua Li, Zhiying Wang, Fengxue Tan, Kaixi Shi, Yingjiao Zhai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237254</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 American Heart Association and American Red Cross Guidelines for First Aid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1161/cir.0000000000001281</link>
      <description>Elizabeth K. Hewett Brumberg, Matthew J. Douma, Kostas Alibertis, Nathan P. Charlton, Michael P. Goldman, Katrina Harper-Kirksey, Seth C. Hawkins, Amber V. Hoover, Amy Kule, Stefan W. Leichtle, Sarah Frances McClure, George Sam Wang, Mark Whelchel, Lynn J. White, Eric J. Lavonas, Circulation. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404358049

                Codeveloped by the American Heart Association and the American Red Cross, these guidelines represent the first comprehensive update of first aid treatment recommendations since 2010. Incorporating the results of structured evidence reviews from the International Liaison Committee on Resuscitation, these guidelines cover first aid treatment for critical and common medical, traumatic, environmental, and toxicological conditions. This update emphasizes the continuous evolution of evidence evaluation and the necessity of adapting educational strategies to local needs and diverse community demographics. Existing guidelines remain relevant unless specifically updated in this publication. Key topics that are new, are substantially revised, or have significant new literature include opioid overdose, bleeding control, open chest wounds, spinal motion restriction, hypothermia, frostbite, presyncope, anaphylaxis, snakebite, oxygen administration, and the use of pulse oximetry in first aid, with the inclusion of pediatric-specific guidance as warranted.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth K. Hewett Brumberg, Matthew J. Douma, Kostas Alibertis, Nathan P. Charlton, Michael P. Goldman, Katrina Harper-Kirksey, Seth C. Hawkins, Amber V. Hoover, Amy Kule, Stefan W. Leichtle, Sarah Frances McClure, George Sam Wang, Mark Whelchel, Lynn J. White, Eric J. Lavonas</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1161/cir.0000000000001281</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Evolution of R-process Elements in Stars (CERES) II. The impact
  of stellar evolution and rotation on light and heavy elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.04180</link>
      <description>Raphaela Fernandes de Melo, Linda Lombardo, Arthur Alencastro Puls, D. Romano, C. J. Hansen, Sophie Tsiatsiou, G. Meynet, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404396347

                Context. Carbon, nitrogen, and oxygen are the most abundant elements throughout the universe, after hydrogen and helium. Studying these elements in low-metallicity stars can provide crucial information on the chemical composition in the early Galaxy and possible internal mixing processes that can alter the surface composition of the stars. Aims. This work aims to investigate the chemical abundance patterns for CNO elements and Li in a homogeneously analyzed sample of 52 metal-poor halo giant stars. Methods. We used high-resolution spectra with a high signal-to-noise ratio (S/N) to carry out a spectral synthesis to derive detailed C, N, O, and Li abundances for a sample of stars with metallicities in the range of -3.58 &lt;= [Fe/H] &lt;= -1.79 dex. Our study was based on the assumption of one-dimensional (1D) local thermodynamic equilibrium (LTE) atmospheres. Results. Based on carbon and nitrogen abundances, we investigated the deep mixing taking place within stars along the red giant branch (RGB). The individual abundances of carbon decrease towards the upper RGB while nitrogen shows an increasing trend, indicating that carbon has been converted into nitrogen. No signatures of ON-cycle processed material were found for the stars in our sample. We computed a set of galactic chemical evolution (GCE) models, implementing different sets of massive star yields, both with and without including the effects of stellar rotation on nucleosynthesis. We confirm that stellar rotation is necessary to explain the highest [N/Fe] and [N/O] ratios observed in unmixed halo stars. The predicted level of N enhancement varies sensibly in dependence of the specific set of yields that are adopted. For stars with stellar parameters similar to those of our sample, heavy elements such as Sr, Y, and Zr appear to have unchanged abundances despite the stellar evolution mixing processes.</description>
      <author>Raphaela Fernandes de Melo, Linda Lombardo, Arthur Alencastro Puls, D. Romano, C. J. Hansen, Sophie Tsiatsiou, G. Meynet</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.04180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the Average Ultraviolet Emission Line Spectra of High-Redshift
  Galaxies: Hot and Cold, Carbon-poor, Nitrogen-modest, and Oozing Ionizing
  Photons</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.09262</link>
      <description>Matthew Hayes, Alberto Saldana-Lopez, Annalisa Citro, Bethan L. James, Matilde Mingozzi, Claudia Scarlata, Zorayda Martinez, Danielle A. Berg, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404450512

                We determine the spectroscopic properties of ~1000 ostensibly star-forming galaxies at redshifts (z=4-10) using prism spectroscopy from JWST/NIRSpec. With rest-wavelength coverage between Lya and [S II] in the optical, we stack spectra as a function of nebular conditions, and compare UV spectral properties with stellar age. This reveals UV lines of N III], N IV], C III], C IV, He II, and O III] in the average high-z galaxy. All UV lines are more intense in younger starbursts. We measure electron temperatures from the collisionally excited [O III] line ratios, finding Te=18000-22000 K for the O++ regions. We also detect a significant nebular Balmer Jump from which we estimate only Te=8000-13000 K. Accounting for typical temperature offsets between zones bearing doubly and singly ionized oxygen, these two temperatures remain discrepant by around 40%. We use the [O III] temperatures to estimate abundances of carbon, nitrogen, and oxygen. We find that log(C/O) is consistently ~-1, with no evolution of C/O with metallicity or stellar age. The average spectra are mildly enhanced in Nitrogen, with higher N/O than low-z starbursts, but are less enhanced than samples of high-z galaxies with visible UV N III] and N IV]. Whatever processes produce the N-enhancement in the individual galaxies must also be ongoing, at lower levels, in the median galaxy in the early Universe. The strongest starbursts are a source of significant ionizing emission: ionizing photon production efficiencies reach 10^25.7 Hz/erg, and show multiple signatures of high Lyman continuum escape, including Mg II escape fractions nearing 100%, significant deficits in [S II] emission, high degrees of ionization, and blue UV colors.</description>
      <author>Matthew Hayes, Alberto Saldana-Lopez, Annalisa Citro, Bethan L. James, Matilde Mingozzi, Claudia Scarlata, Zorayda Martinez, Danielle A. Berg</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.09262</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supersensitive seismic magnetometry on white dwarfs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.20557</link>
      <description>Nicholas Z. Rui, Jim Fuller, J. J. Hermes, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404314173

                The origin of magnetic fields in white dwarfs (WDs) remains mysterious. Magnetic WDs are traditionally associated with field strengths $\gtrsim1\,\mathrm{MG}$, set by the sensitivity of typical spectroscopic magnetic field measurements. Informed by recent developments in red giant magnetoasteroseismology, we revisit the use of WD pulsations as a seismic magnetometer. WD pulsations primarily probe near-surface magnetic fields, whose effect on oscillation mode frequencies is to asymmetrize rotational multiplets and, if strong enough, suppress gravity-mode propagation altogether. The sensitivity of seismology to magnetic fields increases strongly with mode period and decreases quickly with the depth of the partial ionization-driven surface convective zone. We place upper limits for magnetic fields in $24$ pulsating WDs: $20$ hydrogen-atmosphere (DAV) and three helium-atmosphere (DBV) carbon-oxygen WDs, and one extremely low-mass (helium-core) pulsator. These bounds are typically $\sim1$-$10\,\mathrm{kG}$, although they can reach down to $\sim10$-$100\,\mathrm{G}$ for DAVs and helium-core WDs in which lower-frequency modes are excited. Seismic magnetometry may enable new insights into the formation and evolution of WD magnetism.</description>
      <author>Nicholas Z. Rui, Jim Fuller, J. J. Hermes</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.20557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Personalized &lt;i&gt;in silico&lt;/i&gt; model for radiation-induced pulmonary fibrosis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2024.0525</link>
      <description>Eleftherios Ioannou, Myrianthi Hadjicharalambous, Anastasia Malai, Elisavet Papageorgiou, Antri Peraticou, Nicos Katodritis, Dimitrios Vomvas, Vasileios Vavourakis, Journal of The Royal Society Interface. 21(220)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404282542

                Radiation-induced pulmonary fibrosis (RIPF) is a severe late-stage complication of radiotherapy (RT) to the chest area, typically used in lung cancer treatment. This condition is characterized by the gradual and irreversible replacement of healthy lung tissue with fibrous scar tissue, leading to decreased lung function, reduced oxygen exchange and critical respiratory deficiencies. Currently, predicting and managing lung fibrosis post-RT remains challenging, with limited preventive and treatment options. Accurate prediction of fibrosis onset and progression is therefore clinically crucial. We present a personalized in silico model for pulmonary fibrosis that encompasses tumour regression, fibrosis development and lung tissue remodelling post-radiation. Our continuum-based model was developed using data from 12 RT-treated lung cancer patients and integrates computed tomography (CT) and dosimetry data to simulate the spatio-temporal evolution of fibrosis. We demonstrate the ability of the in silico model to capture the extent of fibrosis in the entire cohort with a less than 1% deviation from clinical observations, in addition to providing quantitative metrics of spatial similarity. These findings underscore the potential of the model to improve treatment planning and risk assessment, paving the way for more personalized and effective management of RIPF.</description>
      <author>Eleftherios Ioannou, Myrianthi Hadjicharalambous, Anastasia Malai, Elisavet Papageorgiou, Antri Peraticou, Nicos Katodritis, Dimitrios Vomvas, Vasileios Vavourakis</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1098/rsif.2024.0525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Throughput UV&#8208;Induced Synthesis and Screening of Alloy Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406848</link>
      <description>Xu Li, Jianyun Cao, Jiexin Chen, Jiyang Xie, Chengding Gu, Xiaohong Li, Nigel Brandon, Wanbiao Hu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404390051

                Abstract The combination of different elements in alloy catalysts can lead to improved activity as it provides opportunities to tune the electronic structures of surface atoms. However, the synthesis and performance screening of alloy catalysts through a vast chemical space are cost&#8208; and labor&#8208;intensive. Herein, a UV&#8208;induced, high&#8208;throughput method is reported for the synthesis and screening of alloy electrocatalysts in a fast and low&#8208;cost manner. A platform that integrates 37 mini&#8208;reaction&#8208;cells enables simultaneous UV&#8208;induced photodeposition of alloy nanoparticles with up to 37 compositions. These mini&#8208;reaction&#8208;cells further allow a transfer&#8208;free, high&#8208;throughput electrochemical performance screening. Binary (PtPd, PtIr, PdIr), ternary (PtPdIr, PtRuIr) and quaternary (PtPdRuIr) alloys have been synthesized with the activity of the binary alloys (57 compositions) for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) being screened. The predicted high performance of identified alloy compositions are subsequently validated by standard measurements using a rotating disk electrode configuration. It is found that the as&#8208;synthesized alloy nanoparticles are rich in twin boundaries and thus possess lattice strain. Density functional theory calculation implies that the high ORR activity of the screened Pt 0.75 Pd 0.25 alloy originates from the interplay between the differentiated adsorption sites because of alloying and the strain&#8208;induced modulation of the d&#8208;band center.</description>
      <author>Xu Li, Jianyun Cao, Jiexin Chen, Jiyang Xie, Chengding Gu, Xiaohong Li, Nigel Brandon, Wanbiao Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protracted magma evolution and transcrustal magmatic plumbing system architecture at Erta Ale volcano (Afar, Ethiopia)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/petrology/egae118</link>
      <description>Juliette Pin, Gilles Chazot, Lyd&#233;ric France, B&#233;n&#233;dicte Abily, Andrey Gurenko, Herv&#233; Bertrand, Alexandra Loppin, Journal of Petrology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404246729

                Abstract The Afar region is one of the only places on Earth where magmatic continental rifting and associated ongoing break-up processes are exposed onshore. The several active magmatic segments there are characterized by contrasted morphologies, crustal thicknesses, magma production rates, and magma-tectonic styles. In the Erta Ale Range rift segment, extension is magmatically accommodated, making the range the ideal place to study the magmatic behavior of a mature rift segment. Erta Ale Range comprises sub-segments with magma compositions ranging from basalts to rhyolites, but only the Erta Ale Volcano (EAV) sub-segment is active, where only basaltic compositions have been reported so far. Here, we show for the first time protracted differentiation at EAV that is not expressed volcanically at the surface, but is rather accessible via unique cognate gabbroic and microgabbroic blocks, and recorded by mixing with erupted basaltic magmas. These cognate samples record previously unknown mushy and evolved parts of the EAV plumbing system. To constrain their origin and evolution, we measured the major and trace element compositions of the bulk rocks, interstitial glasses, and melt inclusions. We also measured the oxygen isotopic compositions of olivine crystals, interstitial glasses, and melt inclusions. By combining these results with textural relationships and oxy-thermo-barometry calculations, we discuss magma differentiation and storage conditions, as well as magmatic interactions during transport through the crust. Comparison of our results with rhyolite-MELTS thermodynamic models highlights that protracted fractional crystallization is the main process of magma evolution, and when associated with reactive porous flow is capable of forming the evolved compositions observed (up to 75 wt.% SiO2). We also use the model outputs to quantify distinct steps of igneous differentiation in both shallow and deep crustal reservoirs, and we highlight significant interactions with hydrothermally altered wall rocks. We discuss this model within the geological contexts of the Erta Ale Range rift segment and the larger Afar region, and highlight contrasts with mature oceanic systems to argue that the region is not in the final stages of continental break-up.</description>
      <author>Juliette Pin, Gilles Chazot, Lyd&#233;ric France, B&#233;n&#233;dicte Abily, Andrey Gurenko, Herv&#233; Bertrand, Alexandra Loppin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/petrology/egae118</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focus on podocytes: diabetic kidney disease and renal fibrosis &#8212; a global bibliometric analysis (2000&#8211;2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2024.1454586</link>
      <description>Deok-Gyun An, Jun Tan, Yiping Lu, Zehuai Wen, Yini Bao, Zhou-Hui Yao, Ziyan Chen, Pingping Wang, Wei Zhou, Qiao Yang, Min Hao, Frontiers in Pharmacology. 15(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404393861

                Background Diabetic kidney disease (DKD) is a common pathway to End-stage renal disease (ESRD). Podocytes are crucial due to their dual barrier functions in kidney diseases. Their role in renal fibrosis and DKD regulatory mechanisms is increasingly studied. However, bibliometric research in this field has not been explored. Methods 1,250 publications from Jan. 1, 2000, to Feb. 16, 2024, were retrieved from the WoSCC database and analyzed by the Web of Science results analysis tool, VOSviewer, and CiteSpace. Results Our scrutiny reveals that authors Liu Youhua, Fogo Agnes B, and Zhao Yingyong have made substantial contributions to this domain. Notably, &#8220;Kidney International&#8221; has the highest volume of publications in this area. Furthermore, our analysis identifies ten co-citation clusters: DKD, IncRNA, reactive oxygen species, glomerulosclerosis, Poria cocos, glomerular diseases, fibroblasts, connective tissue growth factor, coagulation, and Wnt. Recent research accentuates keywords such as autophagy, TRPC6, ERS, epigenetics, and NLRP3 inflammasome as frequently occurring terms in this field. The prevailing research hotspot keywords include autophagy, biomarker, and exosomes. Conclusion Through the utilization of bibliometric tools and knowledge graph analysis, we have undertaken a comprehensive review of the intricate nexus between podocytes in DKD and renal fibrosis. This study imparts valuable insights to scholars regarding the dynamic evolution of this association and delineates prospective research avenues in this pivotal realm.</description>
      <author>Deok-Gyun An, Jun Tan, Yiping Lu, Zehuai Wen, Yini Bao, Zhou-Hui Yao, Ziyan Chen, Pingping Wang, Wei Zhou, Qiao Yang, Min Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fphar.2024.1454586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Versatile Organometallic Synthesis of 0D/2D Metal@Germanane Nanoarchitectonics for Electrochemical Energy Conversion Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400854</link>
      <description>Yiming Lei, Xavier Sala, Jordi Garc&#237;a&#8208;Ant&#243;n, Jos&#233; Mu&#241;oz, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404326221

                Abstract Hydrogen&#8208;terminated 2D&#8211;Germanane (2D&#8211;GeH), a germanium&#8208;based 2D material akin to graphene, is receiving enormous attention owing to its predicted optoelectronic characteristics. However, experimental research of 2D&#8211;GeH is still in an early stage, and therefore its real implementation for task&#8208;specific applications will depend on the correct development of suitable chemical functionalization methods. Herein, a general and straightforward organometallic (OM) approach is provided for the robust functionalization of 2D&#8211;GeH with different 0D noble metal nanoparticles (M&#8211;NPs), resulting in 0D/2D M@GeH nanoarchitectonics. As a proof&#8208;of&#8208;principle, 0D/2D Pt@GeH and Au@GeH nanoarchitectonics have been successfully synthesized, characterized, and explored as unconventional electrocatalysts for boosting energy conversion reactions. While the hydrogen evolution reaction activity was evaluated for Pt@GeH, the oxygen reduction reaction was interrogated for Au@GeH. Interestingly, the implanted catalytic features of M&#8211;NPs yielded to 0D/2D M@GeH nanoarchitectonics with enhanced energy conversion activity comparing to pristine 2D&#8211;GeH counterpart. This work proves the suitability of 2D&#8211;GeH as unconventional substrates to stabilize nobleM&#8722;NPs, and the versatility of the OM approach for the custom design of a new family of 0D/2D M@GeH nanoarchitectonics to expand the implementation of monoelemental 2D materials as promising electrocatalysts in energy conversion field and beyond.</description>
      <author>Yiming Lei, Xavier Sala, Jordi Garc&#237;a&#8208;Ant&#243;n, Jos&#233; Mu&#241;oz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400854</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Characterizing the marine iodine cycle and its relationship to ocean deoxygenation in an Earth system model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-4927-2024</link>
      <description>Keyi Cheng, Andy Ridgwell, Dalton Hardisty, Biogeosciences. 21(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404326688

                Abstract. Iodine (I) abundance in marine carbonates (measured as an elemental ratio with calcium, I / Ca) is of broad interest as a proxy for local/regional ocean redox. This connection arises because the speciation of iodine in seawater, the balance between iodate (IO3-) and iodide (I&#8722;), is sensitive to the prevalence of oxic vs. anoxic conditions. However, although I / Ca ratios are increasingly commonly being measured in ancient carbonate samples, a fully quantitative interpretation of this proxy requires the availability of a mechanistic interpretative framework for the marine iodine cycle that can account for the extent and intensity of ocean deoxygenation in the past. Here we present and evaluate a representation of marine iodine cycling embedded in an Earth system model (&#8220;cGENIE&#8221;) against both modern and paleo-observations. In this framework, we account for IO3- uptake and release of I&#8722; through the biological pump, the reduction in ambient IO3- to I&#8722; in the water column, and the re-oxidation of I&#8722; to IO3-. We develop and test a variety of different plausible mechanisms for iodine reduction and oxidation transformation and contrast model projections against an updated compilation of observed dissolved IO3- and I&#8722; concentrations in the present-day ocean. By optimizing the parameters controlling previously proposed mechanisms involved in marine iodine cycling, we find that we can obtain broad matches to observed iodine speciation gradients in zonal surface distribution, depth profiles, and oxygen-deficient zones (ODZs). However, we also identify alternative, equally well performing mechanisms which assume a more explicit mechanistic link between iodine transformation and environment &#8211; an ambiguity that highlights the need for more process-based studies on modern marine iodine cycling. Finally, to help distinguish between competing representations of the marine iodine cycle and because our ultimate motivation is to further our ability to reconstruct ocean oxygenation in the geological past, we conducted &#8220;plausibility tests&#8221; of different model schemes against available I / Ca measurements made on Cretaceous carbonates &#8211; a time of substantially depleted ocean oxygen availability compared to modern and hence a strong test of our model. Overall, the simultaneous broad match we can achieve between modeled iodine speciation and modern observations, and between forward proxy modeled I / Ca and geological elemental ratios, supports the application of our Earth system modeling in simulating the marine iodine cycle to help interpret and constrain the redox evolution of past oceans.</description>
      <author>Keyi Cheng, Andy Ridgwell, Dalton Hardisty</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/bg-21-4927-2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Magma Plumbing System and Regional Magmatic Processes via Chemical and Structural Zoning of Biotite in Rhyolite from Long Valley, CA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024jb029205</link>
      <description>Jiaxin Xi, Yiping Yang, Huifang Xu, Haiyang Xian, Fabin Pan, Shan Li, Shuo Xue, Yonghua Cao, Jianxi Zhu, Hongping He, Journal of Geophysical Research Solid Earth. 129(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404291502

                Abstract Minerals with compositional zoning in volcanic products are widely used to decipher the history of magmatic evolution. However, structural information, which reflects physical conditions and crystallization equilibrium, has often been overlooked. This study presents the first report on the structural zoning of deep&#8208;derived biotite phenocrysts through investigations of metaluminous rhyolite from Long Valley, CA. Biotite is enriched in Si, Mg, and K and depleted in Fe 3+ , Ti, and Al IV in core zones compared with rims. In situ structural analyses, including micro X&#8208;ray diffraction, Raman spectroscopy, and transmission electron microscopy, were conducted to identify cores with perfect 2 M 1 polytype and disordered rims of biotite. The results demonstrate the effectiveness of these methods in revealing various (micro)polytypes of a single species, which occur at different crystallization temperatures, pressures, supersaturation levels, and oxygen fugacities. The concept of structural zoning is introduced here to describe the different structural features distributed systematically in various parts of minerals. By combining structural and chemical zoning, we illustrate a two&#8208;step growth for samples: equilibrium crystallization of the highly ordered cores in a deep magma reservoir with high temperature and pressure, followed by rapid growth of disordered rims during magma mixing in a crystal mush. We further discuss the implications of these findings for reflecting the plumbing system structure and eruption history of rhyolitic magma over extended periods. Our study underscores the remarkable sensitivity of structural zoning in delineating the crystallization conditions of minerals and documenting the environmental changes within magma.</description>
      <author>Jiaxin Xi, Yiping Yang, Huifang Xu, Haiyang Xian, Fabin Pan, Shan Li, Shuo Xue, Yonghua Cao, Jianxi Zhu, Hongping He</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024jb029205</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ALMA Spectral Survey of An eruptive Young star, V883 Ori (ASSAY): II.
  Freshly Sublimated Complex Organic Molecules (COMs) in the Keplerian Disk</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.03826</link>
      <description>Jae-Hong Jeong, Jeong&#8208;Eun Lee, Seonjae Lee, Giseon Baek, Ji&#8211;Hyun Kang, Seokho Lee, Chul-Hwan Kim, Hyeong-Sik Yun, Yuri Aikawa, Gregory J. Herczeg, Doug Johnstone, Lucas Cieza, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404368497

                We present an investigation of Complex Organic Molecules (COMs) in the spatially resolved Keplerian disk around V883 Ori, an eruptive young star, based on a spectral survey carried out with ALMA in Band 6 (220.7$-$274.9 GHz). We identified about 3,700 molecular emission lines and discovered 23 COMs in the disk. We estimated the column densities of COMs detected through the iterative LTE line fitting method. According to our analyses, using only optically thin lines is critical to deriving the reliable column densities of COMs. Therefore, covering a large frequency range is important for the studies of COMs. The most distinct phenomenon found from the spectra of the V883 Ori disk is that nitrogen-bearing COMs other than CH$_{3}$CN are missing, whereas various oxygen-bearing COMs, except for the CH$_2$OH-bearing molecules, are detected. The missing CH$_2$OH-bearing COMs may indicate the warm water-ice dominant environment for forming COMs. We compared our results with various objects in different evolutionary stages, from Class 0 hot corinos to a Solar System comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, to examine the effect of evolution on the COM compositions. In general, the COMs abundances relative to methanol in V883 Ori are higher than in the hot corinos and hot cores, while they are comparable to the cometary values. This may indicate the planet-forming material chemically evolves in the disk midplane after being accreted from the envelope. In addition, as found in the comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko, nitrogen might also be trapped as ammonium salt within the dust grains in the V883 Ori disk.</description>
      <author>Jae-Hong Jeong, Jeong&#8208;Eun Lee, Seonjae Lee, Giseon Baek, Ji&#8211;Hyun Kang, Seokho Lee, Chul-Hwan Kim, Hyeong-Sik Yun, Yuri Aikawa, Gregory J. Herczeg, Doug Johnstone, Lucas Cieza</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.03826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Occurrence of Gravitational Collapse in the Accreting Neutron Stars of Binary-driven Hypernovae</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad82ea</link>
      <description>L. M. Becerra, Federico Cipolletta, Chris L. Fryer, D&#233;bora P. Menezes, Constan&#231;a Provid&#234;ncia, J. A. Rueda, R. Ruffini, The Astrophysical Journal. 976(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404362239

                Abstract The binary-driven hypernova (BdHN) model proposes long gamma-ray bursts (GRBs) originate in binaries composed of a carbon&#8211;oxygen (CO) star and a neutron star (NS) companion. The CO core collapse generates a newborn NS and a supernova that triggers the GRB by accreting onto the NSs, rapidly transferring mass and angular momentum to them. This article aims to determine the conditions under which a black hole (BH) forms from NS collapse induced by the accretion and the impact on the GRB&#8217;s observational properties and taxonomy. We perform three-dimensional, smoothed particle hydrodynamics simulations of BdHNe using up-to-date NS nuclear equations of state, with and without hyperons, and calculate the structure evolution in full general relativity. We assess the binary parameters leading either NS in the binary to the critical mass for gravitational collapse into a BH and its occurrence time, t col . We include a nonzero angular momentum of the NSs and find that t col ranges from a few tens of seconds to hours for decreasing NS initial angular momentum values. BdHNe I are the most compact (about 5 minute orbital period), promptly form a BH, and release &#8819;10 52 erg of energy. They form NS&#8211;BH binaries with tens of kiloyears merger timescales by gravitational-wave emission. BdHNe II and III do not form BHs, and release &#8764;10 50 &#8211;10 52 erg and &#8818;10 50 erg of energy, respectively. They form NS&#8211;NS binaries with a range of merger timescales larger than for NS&#8211;BH binaries. In some compact BdHNe II, either NS can become supramassive, i.e., above the critical mass of a nonrotating NS. Magnetic braking by a 10 13 G field can delay BH formation, leading to BH&#8211;BH or NS&#8211;BH with tens of kiloyears merger timescales.</description>
      <author>L. M. Becerra, Federico Cipolletta, Chris L. Fryer, D&#233;bora P. Menezes, Constan&#231;a Provid&#234;ncia, J. A. Rueda, R. Ruffini</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad82ea</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatio-chemical deconvolution of the LiNi0.6Co0.2Mn0.2O2/Li6PS5Cl interphase layer in all-solid-state batteries using combined X-ray spectroscopic methods</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-016md</link>
      <description>Barth&#233;l&#233;my Lelotte, C. A. F. Vaz, Linfeng Xu, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, P. Vincent, Christian Jordy, Lorenz Gubler, Mario El Kazzi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404393072

                The (electro-)chemical degradation at the interface between Li6PS5Cl (LPSC) and LiNi0.6Co0.2Mn0.2O2 (NCM622) is systematically investigated using non-destructive synchrotron X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and X-ray photoemission electron microscopy (XPEEM). These techniques provide surface chemical depth profiling (from 2 nm to several hundred nm) and high-resolution elemental imaging of both LPSC and NCM622 particles. This analysis was complemented by galvanostatic cycling, impedance spectroscopy, and operando cell pressure measurements. Several correlations between interphase evolution and cell electrochemical performance are clarified, while some inconsistencies are rationalized and discussed. Firstly, the intrinsic LPSC electrochemical oxidation mechanisms were studied using an LPSC:C65 working electrode. The results showed that increased cell resistance during the first charge stemmed from polysulfide by-products and particle contact loss due to LPSC volume shrinkage at the interface. Secondly, when using an NCM622:LPSC working electrode, species such as sulfites, sulfates and phosphates, were detected on both LPSC and NCM622 particles, while electrochemically inactive reduced transition metals (TMs) were observed only at NCM622 surfaces. These species, initially present at open circuit potential, increased after the first charge, due to the chemical reactions between LPSC and NCM622 surface lattice oxygen. The estimated interphase thickness on the LPSC and NCM622 surface over the cycling remains below &#8275;3 nm. Our findings highlight that the formation of an electrochemically inactive NCM622 surface is a primary cause of impedance rise during the first charge, along with the formation of LPSC by-products and contact loss. However, the continuous increase in cell resistance could not be attributed to further interphase growth after the first charge. We hypothesize that this may result from slow and progressive LPSC polymerization reactions (e.g., form Li2PS6 and P2S5) and structural changes at the NCM622 surface.</description>
      <author>Barth&#233;l&#233;my Lelotte, C. A. F. Vaz, Linfeng Xu, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, P. Vincent, Christian Jordy, Lorenz Gubler, Mario El Kazzi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-016md</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur-bearing molecules in a sample of early star-forming cores</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.00539</link>
      <description>N. C. Martinez, S. Par&#243;n, M. E. Ortega, A. Petriella, A. Guti&#233;rrez del &#193;lamo, Michael A. Brook, C. Carballo, T. Heberling, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404345238

                The sulfur content in dense molecular regions of the interstellar medium is highly depleted in comparison to diffuse clouds. The reason of this phenomenon is unclear, thus it is necessary to carry out observational studies of sulfur-bearing species towards dense regions, mainly at early evolutive stages to uncover the early sulfur chemistry. Using data from the Atacama Large Millimeter Array (ALMA) data archive, we investigated a sample of 37 dense cores embedded in the most massive infrared-quiet molecular clumps from the ATLASGAL survey. Lines of 34SO, SO2, NS, SO, SO+, and H2CS were analyzed and column densities of each molecular species were obtained. From the continuum emission, and two CH3OH lines, the 37 cores were characterized in density and temperature, and the corresponding H2 column densities were derived. The abundances of such sulfur-bearing species were derived and studied. We find that the abundances of the analyzed species increase with the growth of the gas temperature, suggesting that the chemistry involved in the formation of each of the analyzed molecule may have a similar dependence with Tk in the range 20 to 100 K. We find that the comparisons among abundances are, in general, highly correlated. Given that such correlation decreases in more evolved sources, we suggest that the sulfur-bearing species here analyzed should have a similar chemical origin. From the measured line widths we point out that molecules with oxygen content (34SO, SO2, SO, and SO+) may be associated with warmer and more turbulent gas than the other ones. H2CS and NS are associated with more quiescent gas, probably in the external envelopes of the cores. This work gives quantitative information about abundances that could be useful in chemical models pointing to explain the sulfur chemistry in the interstellar medium.</description>
      <author>N. C. Martinez, S. Par&#243;n, M. E. Ortega, A. Petriella, A. Guti&#233;rrez del &#193;lamo, Michael A. Brook, C. Carballo, T. Heberling</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2411.00539</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JWST/NIRSpec WIDE survey: a z=4.6 low-mass star-forming galaxy hosting a jet-driven shock with low ionisation and solar metallicity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2545</link>
      <description>Francesco D&#8217;Eugenio, R. Maiolino, V. H. Mahatma, Giovanni Mazzolari, Stefano Carniani, Anna de Graaff, Michael V. Maseda, Eleonora Parlanti, Andrew J. Bunker, Xihan Ji, Gareth C Jones, Jakob M. Helton, R. Morganti, Jan Scholtz, Sandro Tacchella, C. N. Tadhunter, Hannah &#220;bler, G. Venturi, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404334828

                Abstract We present NIRSpec/MSA observations from the JWST large-area survey WIDE, targeting the rest-frame UV&#8211;optical spectrum of Ulema, a radio-AGN host at redshift z = 4.6348. The low-resolution prism spectrum displays high equivalent width nebular emission, with remarkably high ratios of low-ionisation species of oxygen, nitrogen and sulphur, relative to hydrogen; auroral O+ emission is clearly detected, possibly also C+. From the high-resolution grating spectrum, we measure a gas velocity dispersion of &#963; &#8764; 400 km s&#8722;1, broad enough to rule out star-forming gas in equilibrium in the gravitational potential of the galaxy. Diagnostics based on emission-line ratios suggest that the nebular emission is due to a shock which ran out of pre-shock gas. To infer the physical properties of the system, we model simultaneously the galaxy spectral energy distribution (SED) and shock-driven line emission under a Bayesian framework. We find a relatively low-mass, star-forming system (M&#8902; = 1.4 &#215; 1010 M&#8857;, SFR = 70 M&#8857; yr&#8722;1), where shock-driven emission contributes 50 per cent to the total H&#946; luminosity. The nebular metallicity is near solar &#8211; three times higher than that predicted by the mass-metallicity relation at z = 4.6, possibly related to fast-paced chemical evolution near the galaxy nucleus. We find no evidence for a recent decline in the SFR of the galaxy, meaning that, already at this early epoch, fast radio-mode AGN feedback was poorly coupled with the bulk of the star-forming gas; therefore, most of the feedback energy must end up in the galaxy halo, setting the stage for future quenching.</description>
      <author>Francesco D&#8217;Eugenio, R. Maiolino, V. H. Mahatma, Giovanni Mazzolari, Stefano Carniani, Anna de Graaff, Michael V. Maseda, Eleonora Parlanti, Andrew J. Bunker, Xihan Ji, Gareth C Jones, Jakob M. Helton, R. Morganti, Jan Scholtz, Sandro Tacchella, C. N. Tadhunter, Hannah &#220;bler, G. Venturi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2545</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tell-tale tracer for externally irradiated protoplanetary disks: Comparing the [C I] 8727 line and ALMA observations in proplyds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451737</link>
      <description>Mari-Liis Aru, Karina Mauc&#243;, C. F. Manara, Thomas J. Haworth, Nick Ballering, Ryan D. Boyden, J. Campbell-White, Stefano Facchini, Giovanni Rosotti, Andrew J Winter, A. Miotello, Anna F. McLeod, Massimo Robberto, M. G. Petr-Gotzens, Giulia Ballabio, S. Vicente, Megan Ansdell, L. Ilsedore Cleeves, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404293489

                The evolution of protoplanetary disks in regions with massive OB stars is influenced by externally driven winds that deplete the outer parts of these disks. The winds have previously been studied via forbidden oxygen emission lines, which also arise in isolated disks in low-mass star-forming regions (SFRs) with weak external UV fields in photoevaporative or magnetic (internal) disk winds. It is crucial to determine how to disentangle external winds from internal ones. Here, we report a proxy for unambiguously identifying externally driven winds with a forbidden line of neutral atomic carbon We compare for the first time the spatial location of the emission in the and lines traced by VLT/MUSE-NFM with the ALMA Band 7 continuum disk emission in a sample of 12 proplyds in the Orion Nebula Cluster (ONC). We confirm that the emission is co-spatial with the disk emission, whereas that of is emitted both on the disk surface and on the ionization front of the proplyds. We show for the first time that the line is also co-spatial with the disk surface in proplyds, as seen in the MUSE and ALMA data comparison. The peak emission is compatible with the stellar location in all cases, apart from one target with high relative inclination with respect to the ionizing radiation, where the peak emission is located at the disk edge in the direction of the ionizing radiation. To verify whether the line is detected in regions where external photoevaporation is not expected, we examined VLT/X-Shooter spectra for young stars in low-mass SFRs. Although the and 6300 lines are well detected in all these targets, the total detection rate is $ in the case of the line. This number increases substantially to a $ detection rate in sigma -Orionis, a region with higher UV radiation than in low-mass SFRs, but lower than in the ONC. The spatial location of the line emission and the lack of its detection in isolated disks in low-mass SFRs strongly suggest that this line is a tell-tale tracer of externally driven photoevaporative winds, which agrees with recent excitation models.</description>
      <author>Mari-Liis Aru, Karina Mauc&#243;, C. F. Manara, Thomas J. Haworth, Nick Ballering, Ryan D. Boyden, J. Campbell-White, Stefano Facchini, Giovanni Rosotti, Andrew J Winter, A. Miotello, Anna F. McLeod, Massimo Robberto, M. G. Petr-Gotzens, Giulia Ballabio, S. Vicente, Megan Ansdell, L. Ilsedore Cleeves</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202451737</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A tell-tale tracer for externally irradiated protoplanetary disks:
  comparing the [CI] 8727 A line and ALMA observations in proplyds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.21018</link>
      <description>Mari-Liis Aru, Karina Mauc&#243;, C. F. Manara, Thomas J. Haworth, Nick Ballering, Ryan D. Boyden, J. Campbell-White, Stefano Facchini, Giovanni Rosotti, Andrew J Winter, A. Miotello, Anna F. McLeod, Massimo Robberto, M. G. Petr-Gotzens, Giulia Ballabio, S. Vicente, Megan Ansdell, L. Ilsedore Cleeves, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404399474

                The evolution of protoplanetary disks in regions with massive OB stars is influenced by externally driven winds that deplete the outer parts of disks. These winds have previously been studied via forbidden oxygen emission lines, which also arise in isolated disks in low-mass star forming-regions (SFRs) with weak external UV fields in photoevaporative or magnetic (internal) disk winds. It is crucial to determine how to disentangle external winds from internal ones. Here, we report a proxy for unambiguously identifying externally driven winds with a forbidden line of neutral atomic carbon, [C i] 8727 A. We compare for the first time the spatial location of the emission in the [O i] 5577 A, [O i] 6300 A, and [C i] 8727 A lines traced by VLT/MUSE-NFM, with the ALMA Band 7 continuum disk emission in a sample of 12 proplyds in the Orion Nebula Cluster (ONC). We confirm that the [O i] 5577 A emission is co-spatial with the disk emission, whereas the [O i] 6300 A is emitted both on the disk surface and on the ionization front of the proplyds. We show for the first time that the [C i] 8727 A line is also co-spatial with the disk surface in proplyds, as seen in the MUSE and ALMA data comparison. To verify whether the [C i] 8727 A line is detected in regions where external photoevaporation is not expected, we examine VLT/X-Shooter spectra for young stars in low-mass SFRs. Although the [O i] lines are well detected in all these targets, there is &lt;&lt;10% detection rate in the case of the [C i] 8727 A line. This number increases substantially to a ~40% detection rate in sigma-Orionis, a region with intermediate UV radiation. The spatial location of the [C i] 8727 A line emission and the lack of its detection in isolated disks in low-mass SFRs strongly suggest that this line is a tell-tale tracer of externally driven photoevaporative winds, which agrees with recent excitation models.</description>
      <author>Mari-Liis Aru, Karina Mauc&#243;, C. F. Manara, Thomas J. Haworth, Nick Ballering, Ryan D. Boyden, J. Campbell-White, Stefano Facchini, Giovanni Rosotti, Andrew J Winter, A. Miotello, Anna F. McLeod, Massimo Robberto, M. G. Petr-Gotzens, Giulia Ballabio, S. Vicente, Megan Ansdell, L. Ilsedore Cleeves</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.21018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UV-Induced DNA Repair Mechanisms and Their Effects on Mutagenesis and Culturability in Escherichia coli</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.14.623584</link>
      <description>Sreyashi Ghosh, Mehmet A. Orman, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404366645

                Mutagenic processes drive evolutionary progress, with ultraviolet (UV) radiation significantly affecting evolution. Despite extensive research on SOS response-mediated mutagenesis, UV-induced repair mechanisms remain complex, and their effects on cell survival and mutagenesis are not fully understood. We previously observed a near-perfect correlation between RecA-mediated SOS response and mutation levels in Escherichia coli following UV treatment. However, prolonged UV exposure caused transient non-culturability and impaired SOS-mediated mutagenesis. Using fluorescent reporters, flow cytometry, promoter-reporter assays, single-gene deletions, knockouts, and clonogenic assays, we found that excessive UV exposure disrupts cellular translation, reducing SOS gene expression, albeit with minimal impact on membrane permeability or reactive oxygen species levels. While our findings underline the abundance of repair mechanisms in E. coli cells, enabling them to compensate when specific genes are disrupted, they also highlighted the differential impacts of gene deletions on mutagenesis versus culturability, leading to three major outcomes: (i) Disruption of proteins involved in DNA polymerase for trans-lesion synthesis (UmuC and UmuD) or Holliday junction resolution (RuvC) results in significantly decreased mutagenesis levels while maintaining a transient non-culturability pattern after UV exposure. (ii) Disruption of proteins involved in homologous recombination (RecA and RecB) and nucleotide excision repair (UvrA) leads to both significantly reduced mutagenesis and a more severe transient non-culturability pattern after UV exposure, making these cells more sensitive to UV. (iii) Disruption of DNA Helicase II (UvrD), which functions in mismatch repair, does not affect mutagenesis levels from UV radiation but results in a very pronounced transient non-culturability pattern following UV exposure. Overall, our results further advance our understanding of bacterial adaptation mechanisms and the role of DNA repair pathways in shaping mutagenesis.</description>
      <author>Sreyashi Ghosh, Mehmet A. Orman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.11.14.623584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abstract 4143506: Inflammation but not Coronary Atherosclerotic Burden Is Related to Oxygen Uptake On-Kinetics in the 6-Minute Walk Test</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.150.suppl_1.4143506</link>
      <description>Isadora S. Rocco, Walter J. Gomes, Caroline Bublitz, Isis Begot Krainer, Nelson Am&#233;rico Hossne, Ross Arena, Solange Guizilini, Circulation. 150(Suppl_1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404359658

                Background: Anatomic burden of coronary artery disease (CAD) has been considered a consistent prognostic marker. Inflammation also increases the cardiovascular risk and plays a significant role in the evolution of atherosclerosis. The progression of CAD impacts the responses to exercise, reducing functional capacity. Despite this knowledge, the specific interplay between inflammation and atherosclerotic burden in influencing submaximal exercise capacity, particularly oxygen uptake (VO 2 ) kinetics, remains underexplored in CAD. This study aims to investigate how these factors correlate with VO 2 on-kinetics in the Six-minute Walk Test (6MWT) in patients with CAD. METHODS: Patients with obstructive CAD, confirmed by coronary angiography, underwent a 6MWT using a mobile telemetric cardiopulmonary monitoring to assess functional capacity and the VO 2 on-kinetics through the mean response time corrected by work (wMRT). Inflammatory markers were analyzed by dosage of high-sensitivity C-reactive protein, interferon-gama, tumor necrosis factor alpha and interleukins (IL), IL-6, IL-8 and IL-10. Coronary atherosclerotic burden was evaluated by the Grading Scale for Anatomic Burden of Disease from COURAGE Trial. Correlation analyses were performed according to the symmetric distribution of data, using Pearson&#8217;s (r) or Spearman&#8217;s rank correlation coefficients(r s ). RESULTS: A total of thirty-four patients aged between 60.3&#177;8.0 years were enrolled, presenting body mass index of 26.0&#177;3.7kg/cm 2 , left ventricular ejection fraction of 0.50&#177;0.14, walking distance of 443&#177;66m, VO 2 at steady-state (VO 2SS ) of 896&#177;240ml/min and wMRT of 1.64x10 -3 &#177; 1.00x10 -3 min 2 /ml. Although correlated with distance and VO 2SS (r=-0.472;p=0.002 and r=-0.434;p=0.015, respectively), atherosclerotic burden was not associated with wMRT (p=0.17). High-sensitivity C-reactive protein and IL-8 were negatively associated with both distance and VO 2SS (r s =-0.428;p=0.001/ r s =-0.543;p=0.001 and r s =-0.438;p=0.014/ r s =-0.407;p=0.019) and positively correlated with wMRT (r s =0.412;p=0.022/ r s =0.505;p=0.003). CONCLUSION: In contrast to anatomic burden, inflammatory markers were associated with both walking intensity and VO 2 kinetics. Therefore, inflammation may be more crucial to exercise response mechanisms than coronary stenosis, suggesting a paradigm shift in our understanding of clinical repercussions of obstructive CAD. Actions able to attenuate the inflammatory profile may improve exercise capacity and prognosis.</description>
      <author>Isadora S. Rocco, Walter J. Gomes, Caroline Bublitz, Isis Begot Krainer, Nelson Am&#233;rico Hossne, Ross Arena, Solange Guizilini</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1161/circ.150.suppl_1.4143506</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
