<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 01:24:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the Electronic Properties of an Fe Single Atom Catalyst via Secondary Coordination Sphere Engineering to Provide Enhanced Oxygen Electrocatalytic Activity in Zinc-Air Batteries.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202410121</link>
      <description>Siqi Ji, Yimin Mou, Hongxue Liu, Xue Lu, Qian Zhang, Chunmin Guo, Kai Sun, Dong Liu, J. Hugh Horton, Li Wang, Yu Wang, Zhijun Li, PubMed. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402555445

                Oxygen reduction and evolution reactions are two key processes in electrochemical energy conversion technologies. Synthesis of nonprecious metal, carbon-based electrocatalysts with high oxygen bifunctional activity and stability is a crucial, yet challenging step to achieving electrochemical energy conversion. Here, an approach to address this issue: synthesis of an atomically dispersed Fe electrocatalyst (Fe</description>
      <author>Siqi Ji, Yimin Mou, Hongxue Liu, Xue Lu, Qian Zhang, Chunmin Guo, Kai Sun, Dong Liu, J. Hugh Horton, Li Wang, Yu Wang, Zhijun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202410121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Photosynthetic Cell with Molecular Biomimetic Thylakoid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416289</link>
      <description>Enbo Zhou, Shi&#8208;Chen Yan, Xiang Zhang, Baloch Ur Rehman Ateeq, Yangdan Hui, F.S. Wang, Lei Jiao, Jiafang Xie, Daqiang Yuan, Li Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402556634

                The construction of solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion system by mimicking the photosynthetic network of the chloroplast holds great promise on efficient solar energy utilization. We developed an artificial photosynthetic cell (APC) based on molecular biomimetic thylakoid (CoTPP&#8208;FePy) to split water into hydrogen and oxygen (H2 and O2) at low driving voltage (1.1 V) and neutral condition (pH&#8776;7). The CoTPP&#8208;FePy can emulate the light reaction in thylakoids to produce O2 by coupling light harvesting, photocatalysis, and electron/energy storage (FeIII/FeII&#8208;Py). Subsequently, a membrane electrode assembly (MEA) were employed to simulate the dark reaction, wherein the proton, electron and energy generated by the light reaction can drive the H2 producing process. By a temporally and spatially coupling of the light and dark reactions, the resulting APC achieved a solar conversion efficiency of 3.1%, exceeding that of natural photosynthetic systems and demonstrating the potential of artificial photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Enbo Zhou, Shi&#8208;Chen Yan, Xiang Zhang, Baloch Ur Rehman Ateeq, Yangdan Hui, F.S. Wang, Lei Jiao, Jiafang Xie, Daqiang Yuan, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co3O4 nanoparticles synthesized with rotten-grape extract for use in supercapacitors and oxygen evolution devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102922</link>
      <description>Asma Hayat, Aneela Tahira, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Irum Naz, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Elmuez A. Dawi, Matteo Tonezzer, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, Results in Engineering. 24(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402560066

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asma Hayat, Aneela Tahira, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Irum Naz, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Elmuez A. Dawi, Matteo Tonezzer, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma-engineering of Pt-decorated NiCo2O4 nanowires with rich oxygen vacancies for enhanced oxygen electrocatalysis and zinc-air battery performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124607</link>
      <description>He Li, Luka Hansen, Ainura Aliyeva, Jihao Wang, Haoyi Qiu, Martin M&#252;ller, Shilong Chen, Cenk Aktas, Lorenz Kienle, Bernd Hartke, Jan Benedikt, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402565710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>He Li, Luka Hansen, Ainura Aliyeva, Jihao Wang, Haoyi Qiu, Martin M&#252;ller, Shilong Chen, Cenk Aktas, Lorenz Kienle, Bernd Hartke, Jan Benedikt</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Hydrogen Production by Low&#8208;Temperature Membrane&#8208;Engineered Water Electrolyzers, and Regenerative Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400574</link>
      <description>Alexandre Bodard, Zhangsen Chen, Oumayma ELJarray, Gaixia Zhang, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402567352

                Abstract Green hydrogen (H 2 ) is an essential component of global plans to reduce carbon emissions from hard&#8208;to&#8208;abate industries and heavy transport. However, challenges remain in the highly efficient H 2 production from water electrolysis powered by renewable energies. The sluggish oxygen evolution restrains the H 2 production from water splitting. Rational electrocatalyst designs for highly efficient H 2 production and oxygen evolution are pivotal for water electrolysis. With the development of high&#8208;performance electrolyzers, the scale&#8208;up of H 2 production to an industrial&#8208;level related activity can be achieved. This review summarizes recent advances in water electrolysis such as the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) and anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE). The critical challenges for PEMWE and AEMWE are the high cost of noble&#8208;metal catalysts and their durability, respectively. This review highlights the anode and cathode designs for improving the catalytic performance of electrocatalysts, the electrolyte and membrane engineering for membrane electrode assembly (MEA) optimizations, and stack systems for the most promising electrolyzers in water electrolysis. Besides, the advantages of integrating water electrolyzers, fuel cells (FC), and regenerative fuel cells (RFC) into the hydrogen ecosystem are introduced. Finally, the perspective of electrolyzer designs with superior performance is presented.</description>
      <author>Alexandre Bodard, Zhangsen Chen, Oumayma ELJarray, Gaixia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorine&#8208;lodged high&#8208;valent high&#8208;entropy layered double hydroxide for efficient, long&#8208;lasting zinc&#8208;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410978</link>
      <description>Zonglong Zhu, Jing Zhong, Li Wang, Jialun Gu, Fucong Lyu, Shengmei Chen, Haikun Wu, Lanxi Li, Chunyi Zhi, Jian L&#252;, Yang Yang Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568141

                Efficient and stable bifunctional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts are urgently needed to unlock the full potential of zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). High&#8208;valence oxides (HVOs) and high entropy oxides (HEOs) are suitable candidates for their optimal electronic structures and stability but suffer from demanding synthesis. Here, a low&#8208;cost fluorine&#8208;lodged high&#8208;valent high&#8208;entropy layered double hydroxide (HV&#8208;HE&#8208;LDH) (FeCoNi2F4(OH)4) is conveniently prepared through multi&#8208;ions co&#8208;precipitation, where F&#8208; are firmly embedded into the individual hydroxide layers. Spectroscopic detections and theoretical simulations reveal high valent metal cations are obtained in FeCoNi2F4(OH)4, which enlarge the energy band overlap between metal 3d and O 2p, enhancing the electronic conductivity and charge transfer, thus affording high intrinsic OER catalytic activity. More importantly, the strengthened metal&#8208;oxygen (M&#8208;O) bonds and stable octahedral geometry (M&#8208;O(F)6) in FeCoNi2F4(OH)4 prevent structural reorganization, rendering long&#8208;term catalytic stability. Furthermore, an efficient three&#8208;phase reaction interface with fast oxygen transportation was constructed, significantly improving the ORR activity. ZABs assembled with FeCoNi2F4(OH)4@HCC (hydrophobic carbon cloth) cathodes deliver a top performance with high round&#8208;trip energy efficiency (60.6% at 10 mA cm&#8208;2) and long&#8208;term stability (efficiency remains at 58.8% after 1050 charge&#8208;discharge cycles).</description>
      <author>Zonglong Zhu, Jing Zhong, Li Wang, Jialun Gu, Fucong Lyu, Shengmei Chen, Haikun Wu, Lanxi Li, Chunyi Zhi, Jian L&#252;, Yang Yang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trifunctional Graphene&#8208;Sandwiched Heterojunction&#8208;Embedded Layered Lattice Electrocatalyst for High Performance in Zn&#8208;Air Battery&#8208;Driven Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408869</link>
      <description>Dong&#8208;Won Kim, Jihoon Kim, Jong Hui Choi, Do Hwan Jung, Jeung Ku Kang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568155

                Abstract Zn&#8208;air battery (ZAB)&#8208;driven water splitting holds great promise as a next&#8208;generation energy conversion technology, but its large overpotential, low activity, and poor stability for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) remain obstacles. Here, a trifunctional graphene&#8208;sandwiched, heterojunction&#8208;embedded layered lattice (G&#8208;SHELL) electrocatalyst offering a solution to these challenges are reported. Its hollow core&#8208;layered shell morphology promotes ion transport to Co 3 S 4 for OER and graphene&#8208;sandwiched MoS 2 for ORR/HER, while its heterojunction&#8208;induced internal electric fields facilitate electron migration. The structural characteristics of G&#8208;SHELL are thoroughly investigated using X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy. Additionally, atomic&#8208;resolution transmission electron microscopy (TEM) images align well with the DFT&#8208;relaxed structures and simulated TEM images, further confirming its structure. It exhibits an approximately threefold smaller ORR charge transfer resistance than Pt/C, a lower OER overpotential and Tafel slope than RuO&#8322;, and excellent HER overpotential and Tafel slope, while outlasting noble metals in terms of durability. Ex situ X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy analysis under varying potentials by examining the peak shifts and ratios (Co 2+ /Co 3+ and Mo 4+ /Mo 6+ ) elucidates electrocatalytic reaction mechanisms. Furthermore, the ZAB with G&#8208;SHELL outperforms Pt/C+RuO 2 in terms of energy density (797 Wh kg &#8722;1 ) and peak power density (275.8 mW cm &#8722;2 ), realizing the ZAB&#8208;driven water splitting.</description>
      <author>Dong&#8208;Won Kim, Jihoon Kim, Jong Hui Choi, Do Hwan Jung, Jeung Ku Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Multiple Strategies Using Biotechnology to Design High&#8208;Performance Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413072</link>
      <description>Lin Ge, Chang Liu, Tingting Xue, Yiyang Kang, Yining Sun, Yuxi Chen, Jiajie Wu, Kai Wen Teng, Lei Li, Qing Qu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568366

                Abstract Combining multiple design strategies often enhances catalyst performance but usually comes with high costs and low reproducibility. A technique that enhances catalyst performance in multiple strategies is urgently needed. Herein, a novel bioregulation technique is introduced, allowing simultaneous control over morphology, particle size, doping, interface engineering, and electronic properties. Bioregulation technique utilizes the soluble extracellular polymer from Aspergillus niger as a templating agent to construct high&#8208;performance catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction (HER and OER). This technique controls catalyst morphology, introduces biological N and S doping, and regulates the electronic structure of the catalyst surface. Biomolecule modification enhances surface hydrophilicity, and the nanostructure increases surface roughness and gas&#8208;release efficiency. Theoretical calculations show that the bioregulation technique shortens the d/p&#8208;band center, optimizing reaction intermediate adsorption and desorption. The Bio&#8208;Pt/Co 3 O 4 catalyst with trace Pt on the surface, designed with these strategies, achieves HER ( &#951; 10 of 42 mV), OER ( &#951; 10 of 221 mV), and overall water&#8208;splitting performance (1.51 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), maintaining stability for over 50 h, outperforming most Pt&#8208;based catalysts. Notably, using spent lithium&#8208;ion battery cathodes leachate, rich in Co 2 &#8314;, successfully replicates the experiment. This approach holds promise as a mainstream method for synthesizing high&#8208;performance materials in the future.</description>
      <author>Lin Ge, Chang Liu, Tingting Xue, Yiyang Kang, Yining Sun, Yuxi Chen, Jiajie Wu, Kai Wen Teng, Lei Li, Qing Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of catalytic activity of BSCF towards electrochemical oxygen reactions using different synthetic approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.138</link>
      <description>Sachin Bhagat, Nandita Singh, Monika Singh, Ashish Kumar Singh, Suryabhan Singh, Uday Pratap Azad, Akhilesh Kumar Singh, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 88(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sachin Bhagat, Nandita Singh, Monika Singh, Ashish Kumar Singh, Suryabhan Singh, Uday Pratap Azad, Akhilesh Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-modulated NiFe&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Co Layered Double Hydroxide on Ni Foam for Efficient Oxygen Precipitation Reaction in Alkaline Water Electrolysis for Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23919/ccc63176.2024.10661943</link>
      <description>Jialin Dong, Shihong Yue, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402570146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jialin Dong, Shihong Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23919/ccc63176.2024.10661943</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Correlation between Spin Effect and Catalytic Activity of Two Dimensional Metal Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402538460

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Correlation between Spin Effect and Catalytic Activity of Two Dimensional Metal Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402538465

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Correlation between Spin Effect and Catalytic Activity of Two Dimensional Metal Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Feifan Wang, Yukui Zhang, Jing Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402538479

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Feifan Wang, Yukui Zhang, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Correlation between Spin Effect and Catalytic Activity of Two Dimensional Metal Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402538494

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Correlation between Spin Effect and Catalytic Activity of Two Dimensional Metal Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402538504

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Correlation between Spin Effect and Catalytic Activity of Two Dimensional Metal Organic Frameworks for Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402538882

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05700g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Rechargeable Urea&#8208;Assisted Zn&#8208;Air Battery with High Energy Efficiency and Fast&#8208;Charging Enabled by Engineering High&#8208;Energy Interfacial Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410845</link>
      <description>Mingjie Wu, Yinghui Xu, Jian Luo, Siyi Yang, Gaixia Zhang, Lei Du, Huixia Luo, Xun Cui, Yingkui Yang, Shuhui Sun, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402542550

                Electrochemical urea oxidation reaction (UOR) offers a promising alternative to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in clean energy conversion and storage systems. Nickel&#8208;based catalysts are highly regarded as promising electrocatalysts for the UOR. However, their effectiveness is significantly hindered by the unavoidable self&#8208;oxidation reaction of nickel species during UOR. To address this challenge, we proposed an interface chemistry modulation strategy to boost UOR kinetics by creating a high&#8208;energy interfacial heterostructure. This heterostructure features the incorporation of Ag at the CoOOH@NiOOH heterojunction interface. Strong interactions significantly promote the electron exchanges in the heterointerface between the &#8208;OH and &#8208;O. Consequently, the improved electron delocalization led to the formation of stronger bonds between Co sites and urea CO(NH2)2, promoting a preference for urea to occupy Co active sites over OH*. The resulting catalyst, Ag&#8208;CoOOH@NiOOH, affords an ultrahigh UOR activity with a low potential of 1.33 V at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. The fabricated catalyst exhibits a mass activity exceeding that of initial cobalt oxyhydroxide by over 11.9 times. The rechargeable urea&#8208;assisted zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) achieves a record&#8208;breaking energy efficiency of 74.56% at 1 mA cm&#8208;2, remarkable durability (1000 hours at even a current density of 50 mA cm&#8208;2), and quick charge performances.</description>
      <author>Mingjie Wu, Yinghui Xu, Jian Luo, Siyi Yang, Gaixia Zhang, Lei Du, Huixia Luo, Xun Cui, Yingkui Yang, Shuhui Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis of Carbon-Coated Nips3 Nanoparticle Electrocatalyst for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4956197</link>
      <description>Dongjun Lee, Doyeon Lee, Wook Kim, Seong&#8208;Hyeon Hong, Hee Jo Song, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402545967

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dongjun Lee, Doyeon Lee, Wook Kim, Seong&#8208;Hyeon Hong, Hee Jo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4956197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of Enhanced Oxygen Evolution in Restructured Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413916</link>
      <description>Ying Li, Jing Wang, Xiaolei Hao, Xiaopei Xu, Lingling Xu, Bo Wei, Zhongwei Chen, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402546461

                Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks (MOFs), praised for structural flexibility and tunability, are prominent catalyst prototypes for exploring oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Yet, their intricate transformations under OER, especially in industrial high&#8208;current environments, pose significant challenges in accurately elucidating their structure&#8208;activity correlation. Here, we harnessed an electrooxidation process for controllable MOF reconstruction, discovering that Fe doping expedites Ni(Fe)&#8208;MOF structural evolution, accompanied by the elongation of Ni&#8208;O bonds, monitored by in&#8208;situ Raman and UV&#8208;visible spectroscopy. Theoretical modeling further reveals that Fe doping and defect&#8208;induced tensile strain in the NiO6 octahedra augments the metal ds&#8208;Op hybridization, optimizing their adsorption behavior and augmenting OER activity. The reconstructed Ni(Fe)&#8208;MOF, serving as the anode in anion exchange membrane water electrolysis, achieves a noteworthy current density of 3.3 A cm&#8208;2 at 2.2 V while maintaining equally stable operation for 160 h spanning from 0.5 A cm&#8208;2 to 1 A cm&#8208;2. This undertaking elevates our comprehension of OER catalyst reconstruction, furnishing promising avenues for designing highly efficacious catalysts across electrochemical platforms.</description>
      <author>Ying Li, Jing Wang, Xiaolei Hao, Xiaopei Xu, Lingling Xu, Bo Wei, Zhongwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of Enhanced Oxygen Evolution in Restructured Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413916</link>
      <description>Ying Li, Yang Liu, Xiaolei Hao, Xiaopei Xu, Lingling Xu, Bo Wei, Zhongwei Chen, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402546561

                Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks (MOFs), praised for structural flexibility and tunability, are prominent catalyst prototypes for exploring oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Yet, their intricate transformations under OER, especially in industrial high&#8208;current environments, pose significant challenges in accurately elucidating their structure&#8208;activity correlation. Here, we harnessed an electrooxidation process for controllable MOF reconstruction, discovering that Fe doping expedites Ni(Fe)&#8208;MOF structural evolution, accompanied by the elongation of Ni&#8208;O bonds, monitored by in&#8208;situ Raman and UV&#8208;visible spectroscopy. Theoretical modeling further reveals that Fe doping and defect&#8208;induced tensile strain in the NiO6 octahedra augments the metal ds&#8208;Op hybridization, optimizing their adsorption behavior and augmenting OER activity. The reconstructed Ni(Fe)&#8208;MOF, serving as the anode in anion exchange membrane water electrolysis, achieves a noteworthy current density of 3.3 A cm&#8208;2 at 2.2 V while maintaining equally stable operation for 160 h spanning from 0.5 A cm&#8208;2 to 1 A cm&#8208;2. This undertaking elevates our comprehension of OER catalyst reconstruction, furnishing promising avenues for designing highly efficacious catalysts across electrochemical platforms.</description>
      <author>Ying Li, Yang Liu, Xiaolei Hao, Xiaopei Xu, Lingling Xu, Bo Wei, Zhongwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413916</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrospun Mn1-xCoxFe2O4 (x=0-0.7) Nanofibers for Supercapacitors and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129948</link>
      <description>Zahra Ansari Jokandan, J. Mazloom, Morteza Safari, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402549944

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahra Ansari Jokandan, J. Mazloom, Morteza Safari</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe, Cu bimetallic precursor-driven quaternary active sites boost oxygen reduction / evolution reaction bifunctional catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235423</link>
      <description>Yurong Yuan, Mengwei Pan, Mengjie Zhang, Yuchen Zhou, Qin Fei-long, Yaoyu Yang, Rui Hao, Weifang Liu, Kaiyu Liu, Journal of Power Sources. 623(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402550124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yurong Yuan, Mengwei Pan, Mengjie Zhang, Yuchen Zhou, Qin Fei-long, Yaoyu Yang, Rui Hao, Weifang Liu, Kaiyu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommended practice for measurement and evaluation of oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12486</link>
      <description>Hongyu An, Wanki Park, Heejong Shin, Dong Young Chung, EcoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402567939

                Abstract The Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a pivotal technology driving next&#8208;generation sustainable energy conversion and storage devices. Establishing a robust analytical methodology is paramount to fostering innovation in this field. This review offers a comprehensive discussion on measurement and interpretation, advocating for standardized protocols and best practices to mitigate the myriad factors that complicate analysis. The initial focus is directed toward substrate electrodes and gas bubbles, both significant contributors to reduced reliability and reproducibility. Subsequently, the review focuses on intrinsic activity assessment, identification of electrochemical active sites, and the disentanglement of competing process contributions. These careful methodologies ensure the systematic delivery of insights crucial for assessing OER performance. In conclusion, the review highlights the critical role played by precise measurement techniques and unbiased activity comparison methodologies in propelling advancements in OER catalyst development. image</description>
      <author>Hongyu An, Wanki Park, Heejong Shin, Dong Young Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-tuning of coordination compound for improved oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjche.2024.07.023</link>
      <description>Kai Yang, Yuanjun Liu, Yuyu Liu, Xingmei Guo, Xiangjun Zheng, Junhao Zhang, Guoxing Zhu, Chinese Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402565094

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Yang, Yuanjun Liu, Yuyu Liu, Xingmei Guo, Xiangjun Zheng, Junhao Zhang, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjche.2024.07.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the evolution of molybdenum-nitrogen doped carbon with long-term durability for efficient oxygen reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155778</link>
      <description>Xingyu Luo, Bingbao Mei, Ru Feng, Xiaofeng Xu, Zhongyan Zhang, Mingyu Ou, Fanfei Sun, Huajun Zheng, Meiqin Shi, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402546983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingyu Luo, Bingbao Mei, Ru Feng, Xiaofeng Xu, Zhongyan Zhang, Mingyu Ou, Fanfei Sun, Huajun Zheng, Meiqin Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155778</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo-Induced Surface Reconstruction in Ni/Co-OOH Prickly Flower Clusters for Improving the Hydrogen Production in Alkaline Seawater Splitting.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404858</link>
      <description>Wen Zhang, Jianyang Gao, Qixing Gong, Fusheng Liu, Yang Zhang, Guangrui Xu, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, PubMed. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402554797

                Seawater electrolysis is the most promising technology for hydrogen production, in which surface reconstruction on the interface of electrode/electrolyte plays a crucial role in activating the catalytic reactions with a low activation energy barrier. Herein, an efficient Mo modifying NiCoMo prickly flower clusters electrocatalyst supported on nickel foam (Mo-doped Ni/Co-OOH prickly flower clusters) is obtained, which serves as an eminently active and durable catalyst for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to the surface reconstruction during the alkaline seawater electrolysis with ultralow overpotentials. It just requires a cell voltage of 1.52 V to achieve the current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Wen Zhang, Jianyang Gao, Qixing Gong, Fusheng Liu, Yang Zhang, Guangrui Xu, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Nanostructure NiO&#8211;GeSe Core&#8211;Shell/MAPbBr&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Solar Cell in Solar Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting: Superior Efficiency Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9454136</link>
      <description>Maryam Shahrostami, Mehdi Eskandari, Davood Fathi, International Journal of Energy Research. 2024(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402574927

                Solar&#8208;driven photoelectrochemical (PEC) water&#8208;splitting cells coupled with a photovoltaic (PV) cell as a photoanode have become an intriguing topic in solar energy conversion. In this study, for the purpose of developing a system with high efficiency, several photoanode materials were investigated to adjust the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) energy bands. Among all, MAPbBr 3 with a wide bandgap (2.3 eV) was selected. However, the power conversion efficiency of the PV cell was not desirable due to the low light absorption. Therefore, the NiO&#8211;GeSe core&#8211;shell was placed inside the perovskite layer to enhance light absorption and carrier generation. In order to achieve a cell with the maximum performance, the core&#8211;shell height, and the shell radius were optimized, where the optimum structure was recognized with a core&#8211;shell height of 300 nm and a radius of 25&#8211;60 nm. The system&#8217;s total efficiency, which is represented by the solar to hydrogen efficiency, was then increased from 5.49% to 19.74% for the planar and nanostructure photoanode, respectively. The proposed PEC cell with the optimized photoanode is considered as the most efficient half&#8208;tandem and perovskite&#8208;based reported coupled system, operating without the need for an external voltage. In this study, three optical, electrical, and electrochemical models were solved using the finite element method to analyze the coupled system.</description>
      <author>Maryam Shahrostami, Mehdi Eskandari, Davood Fathi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9454136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Rechargeable Urea&#8208;Assisted Zn&#8208;Air Battery with High Energy Efficiency and Fast&#8208;Charging Enabled by Engineering High&#8208;Energy Interfacial Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410845</link>
      <description>Mingjie Wu, Yinghui Xu, Jian Luo, Siyi Yang, Gaixia Zhang, Lei Du, Huixia Luo, Xun Cui, Yingkui Yang, Shuhui Sun, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402542551

                Electrochemical urea oxidation reaction (UOR) offers a promising alternative to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in clean energy conversion and storage systems. Nickel&#8208;based catalysts are highly regarded as promising electrocatalysts for the UOR. However, their effectiveness is significantly hindered by the unavoidable self&#8208;oxidation reaction of nickel species during UOR. To address this challenge, we proposed an interface chemistry modulation strategy to boost UOR kinetics by creating a high&#8208;energy interfacial heterostructure. This heterostructure features the incorporation of Ag at the CoOOH@NiOOH heterojunction interface. Strong interactions significantly promote the electron exchanges in the heterointerface between the &#8208;OH and &#8208;O. Consequently, the improved electron delocalization led to the formation of stronger bonds between Co sites and urea CO(NH2)2, promoting a preference for urea to occupy Co active sites over OH*. The resulting catalyst, Ag&#8208;CoOOH@NiOOH, affords an ultrahigh UOR activity with a low potential of 1.33 V at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. The fabricated catalyst exhibits a mass activity exceeding that of initial cobalt oxyhydroxide by over 11.9 times. The rechargeable urea&#8208;assisted zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) achieves a record&#8208;breaking energy efficiency of 74.56% at 1 mA cm&#8208;2, remarkable durability (1000 hours at even a current density of 50 mA cm&#8208;2), and quick charge performances.</description>
      <author>Mingjie Wu, Yinghui Xu, Jian Luo, Siyi Yang, Gaixia Zhang, Lei Du, Huixia Luo, Xun Cui, Yingkui Yang, Shuhui Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A perspective to efficient synthesis of zirconium carbide via novel pyro-vacuum method: lower temperatures and enhanced purity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53063/synsint.2024.43233</link>
      <description>Faramarz Kazemi, Behzad Nayebi, Synthesis and Sintering. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402559567

                The use of ultra-high temperature ceramics (UHTCs) as a novel additive in the refractory industry is becoming increasingly popular. However, the synthesis of such materials is associated with some commercial obstacles, mainly high-temperature synthesis methods. In the present study, the pyro-vacuum method is presented as a new method to decrease the final product's synthesis temperature and oxygen content. Some thermodynamic aspects and phase evolution of the materials during the synthesis procedure are described for the synthesis of non-oxide material. Conclusively, it seems that by applying vacuum conditions, the final UHTC phases can be synthesized at significantly lower temperatures (&gt;400 &#176;C lower, for ZrC), if adequate powder mixtures are considered. Also due to phase analysis, it was found that the oxygen content of the final phase is lower than the conventional routes and other references. The process provides promising prospects for the economic synthesis of UHTCs.</description>
      <author>Faramarz Kazemi, Behzad Nayebi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53063/synsint.2024.43233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D TiNBr as photocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vxdq4</link>
      <description>Yatong Wang, Geert Brocks, Ceren Tayran, S&#252;leyman Er, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402583716

                Two-dimensional (2D) Janus materials gain increasing attention as water splitting photocatalysts for hydrogen production. We use first-principles calculations to predict a stable 2D Janus $T$-TiNBr structure, with strong near-ultraviolet sunlight absorption and band edges that align favorably with the water redox potentials for oxygen and hydrogen evolution. We show that the optical and electronic properties of $T$-TiNBr can be modulated to a certain extend by applying external uniaxial strain. Explicit calculations of the redox reactions reveal that solar-driven water splitting is viable at the N-side of $T$-TiNBr, while the Br-side requires modifications such as vacancy creation, the application of an external potential, or adjustment of the pH conditions.</description>
      <author>Yatong Wang, Geert Brocks, Ceren Tayran, S&#252;leyman Er</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vxdq4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Depth-resolved characterization of Meissner screening breakdown in surface treated niobium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-71724-5</link>
      <description>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. A. MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402541511

                We report direct measurements of the magnetic field screening at the limits of the Meissner phase for two superconducting niobium (Nb) samples. The samples are processed with two different surface treatments that have been developed for superconducting radio-frequency (SRF) cavity applications-a "baseline" treatment and an oxygen-doping ("O-doping") treatment. The measurements show: (1) that the screening length is significantly longer in the "O-doping" sample compared to the "baseline" sample; (2) that the screening length near the limits of the Meissner phase increases with applied field; (3) the evolution of the screening profile as the material transitions from the Meissner phase to the mixed phase; and (4) a demonstration of the absence of any screening profile for the highest applied field, indicative of the full flux entering the sample. Measurements are performed utilizing the</description>
      <author>Edward Thoeng, Md Asaduzzaman, Philipp Kolb, Ryan M. L. McFadden, G. D. Morris, John O. Ticknor, S. R. Dunsiger, Victoria L. Karner, Derek Fujimoto, Tobias Junginger, R. F. Kiefl, W. A. MacFarlane, Ruohong Li, Suresh Saminathan, Robert Laxdal</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-71724-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treatment of domestic wastewater and extracellular polymeric substance accumulation in siphon&#8208;type composite vertical subsurface flow constructed wetland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wer.11132</link>
      <description>Hao Chen, Lin Qiu, Hong Wu, Fahui Nie, Yong Liu, Wenping Cao, Water Environment Research. 96(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402570326

                Abstract In this study, the siphon&#8208;type composite vertical flow constructed wetland (Sc&#8208;VSsFCW) was constructed with anthracite and shale ceramsite chosen as the substrate bed materials. During the 90&#8208;day experiment, typical pollutant removal effects of wastewater and extracellular polymeric substance (EPS) accumulation were investigated. Meanwhile, X&#8208;ray diffraction and scanning electron microscopy were used to examine the phase composition and surface morphology to analyze adsorptive property. Additionally, we evaluated the impact of siphon effluent on clogging and depolymerization by measuring the EPS components' evolution within the system. The findings reveal that both the anthracite and shale ceramsite systems exhibit impressive removal efficiencies for total phosphorus (TP), total dissolved phosphorus (TDP), soluble reactive phosphorus (SRP), chemical oxygen demand (COD), ammonium nitrogen (NH 4 + &#8208;N), and nitrate nitrogen (NO 3 &#8722; &#8208;N). However, as the experiment progressed, TP removal rates in both systems gradually declined because of the saturation of adsorption sites on the substrate surfaces. Although the dissolved oxygen (DO) levels remained relatively stable throughout the experiment, pH exhibited distinct patterns, suggesting that the anthracite system relies primarily on chemical adsorption, whereas the shale ceramsite system predominantly utilizes physical adsorption. After an initial period of fluctuation, the permeability coefficient and porosity of the system gradually stabilized, and the protein and polysaccharide contents in both systems exhibited a downward trend. The study underscores that anthracite and shale ceramsite have good effectiveness in pollutant removal as substrate materials. Overall, the hydraulic conditions of the double repeated oxygen coupling siphon in the Sc&#8208;VSsFCW system contribute to enhanced re&#8208;oxygenation capacity and permeability coefficient during operation. The changes in EPS content indicate that the siphon effluent exerts a certain depolymerization effect on the EPS within the system, thereby mitigating the risk of biological clogging to a certain extent. Practitioner Points The system can still maintain good pollutant treatment effect in long&#8208;term operation. The re&#8208;oxygenation method of the system can achieve efficient and long&#8208;term re&#8208;oxygenation effect. The siphon effluent has a certain improvement effect on the permeability coefficient and porosity, but it cannot effectively inhibit the occurrence of clogging. The EPS content did not change significantly during the operation of the system, and there was a risk of biological clogging.</description>
      <author>Hao Chen, Lin Qiu, Hong Wu, Fahui Nie, Yong Liu, Wenping Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wer.11132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Built&#8208;In Electric Field via Defect&#8208;Mediated Interfacial Chemical Bond Construction in Chalcogenide Heterojunction for Alcohol Photooxidation Coupled with H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411991</link>
      <description>Yi&#8208;Wen Han, Ying&#8208;Hao Chu, Lei Ye, Tian&#8208;Jun Gong, Xuebin L&#252;, Yao Fu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402541839

                Abstract Rationally designing nanostructures based on an adequate understanding of structure&#8208;performance relationships is key for directional charge transfer regulation in heterojunction photocatalysts. A general strategy is developed for synthesizing bifunctional Sv&#8208;chalcogenide/Ti 3 C 2 Schottky junctions (Sv = sulfur vacancies, chalcogenides containing CdS, CdIn 2 S 4 , ZnIn 2 S 4 , ZnS, CuInS 2 ) featuring a giant built&#8208;in electric field (BIEF) via defect&#8208;mediated heterocomponent anchorage, which consists of sulfur vacancy modulation of chalcogenides and Ti 3 C 2 nanoparticle anchoring at defects via interfacial Metal&#9472;Oxygen (M&#9472;O) bonds. These heterojunctions have the distinctive interface structure of semicoherent phase boundaries and a directionally aligned BIEF pointing from chalcogenides to Ti 3 C 2 . The enhanced BIEF creates an asymmetrical charge distribution, which not only governs the charge migration behavior by enabling charge carrier localization and delocalized electron transport continuity but also regulates the molecular catalytic behavior by optimizing pivotal intermediate adsorption/activation ( * Ar&#8208;CH(R 2 )&#8208;OH in dehydrogenation and H * in H 2 evolution) in selective alcohol photooxidation coupled with H 2 generation. Encouragingly, Sv&#8208;chalcogenide/Ti 3 C 2 exhibits unprecedented performance (up to 13.34&#8208;fold higher efficiency than unmodulated chalcogenides) and good substrate compatibility for various alcohols. This work demonstrates the synergistic effects of surface electron density control and interfacial interaction modulation in regulating BIEFs, elucidating the substantial impact of reinforced BIEF on carrier transport properties and molecular catalytic behavior.</description>
      <author>Yi&#8208;Wen Han, Ying&#8208;Hao Chu, Lei Ye, Tian&#8208;Jun Gong, Xuebin L&#252;, Yao Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202411991</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
