<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 01:35:01 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>An Electrochemical Reduction Cell Model of Photosynthesis for Carbon Dioxide Capture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5083012</link>
      <description>Tamunosaki Graham Douglas, Okpara Obinna Michael, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406063550

                Since carbon dioxide levels in the atmosphere have increased at unprecedented rate over the last ten years, global warming has become an increasingly pressing concern for humanity. This work suggests a sustainable solution to this issue by employing a unique mechanism that uses sunlight and electricity to transform CO2 into useful fuel. To construct the device, a Simulink model of the electrochemical reduction cell was created. The model essentially transforms photovoltaic power, CO2 and water into other chemical products. Using the reversible, activation and ohmic equations, the voltage needed to run the CO2 reduction cell was determined. As the anode, cathode, and voltage source blocks are the three main models that make up the CO2 electrolyser cell, the production flow rates of formic acid and oxygen were also evaluated based on molar and charge balances, as well as continuity equations at operating conditions of 1 atm and 298 K. The simulation predicts about 176 kg of CO2 consumption in 10 seconds of the electrochemical conversion. Therefore, the implication of this study is to justify photosynthesis as electrochemical reduction process to efficiently mitigate the accumulation of CO2 in the atmosphere.</description>
      <author>Tamunosaki Graham Douglas, Okpara Obinna Michael</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5083012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Properties of Gold and Cobalt Oxyhydroxide in Plasmon-Mediated Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06632</link>
      <description>Janet Zhen, Timothy Lin, Tucker Forbes, Mark Engelhard, Jingjing Qiu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084303

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Janet Zhen, Timothy Lin, Tucker Forbes, Mark Engelhard, Jingjing Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c06632</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Modulation Doping in Van der Waals Layered Iridium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422740</link>
      <description>Ke Jia, Wenxiang Zhu, Yujin Ji, Jinxin Chen, Chenchen Li, Yue Wang, Qun Wang, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Zhiwei Hu, Youyong Li, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084440

                Anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) exhibits a sluggish four&#8208;electron transfer process, necessitating catalysts with exceptional catalytic activity to enhance its kinetic rate. Van der Waals layered oxides are ideal materials for catalyst design, yet its stability for acidic OER remains large obstacle. Doping provides a crucial way to improve the activity and stability simultaneously. However, doping in Van der Waals layered oxides remains a great challenge since it easily leads to lattice distortion or even the crystal structure damage. In this work, we successfully doping acid&#8208;resistant niobium (Nb) into Van der Waals layered edge&#8208;shared 1T phase iridium oxide (1T&#8208;IrO2) via alkali&#8208;assisted thermal method. 1T&#8208;IrO2 with a 5% Nb doping (Nb0.05Ir0.95O2) only required an overpotential of 191 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4, 56 mV lower than that of 1T&#8208;IrO2. When applied in a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer, Nb0.05Ir0.95O2 achieved a current density of 1.2 A cm&#8208;2 at a cell voltage of 1.7 V for 50 days. Density functional theory calculation reveals that doping Nb changes the potential&#8208;determining step from the *OOH deprotonation process in 1T&#8208;IrO2 to the *O&#8208;OH coupling process in Nb0.05Ir0.95O2.</description>
      <author>Ke Jia, Wenxiang Zhu, Yujin Ji, Jinxin Chen, Chenchen Li, Yue Wang, Qun Wang, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Zhiwei Hu, Youyong Li, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202422740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Modulation Doping in Van der Waals Layered Iridium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422740</link>
      <description>Ke Jia, Wenxiang Zhu, Yujin Ji, Jinxin Chen, Chenchen Li, Yue Wang, Qun Wang, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Zhiwei Hu, Youyong Li, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084475

                Anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) exhibits a sluggish four&#8208;electron transfer process, necessitating catalysts with exceptional catalytic activity to enhance its kinetic rate. Van der Waals layered oxides are ideal materials for catalyst design, yet its stability for acidic OER remains large obstacle. Doping provides a crucial way to improve the activity and stability simultaneously. However, doping in Van der Waals layered oxides remains a great challenge since it easily leads to lattice distortion or even the crystal structure damage. In this work, we successfully doping acid&#8208;resistant niobium (Nb) into Van der Waals layered edge&#8208;shared 1T phase iridium oxide (1T&#8208;IrO2) via alkali&#8208;assisted thermal method. 1T&#8208;IrO2 with a 5% Nb doping (Nb0.05Ir0.95O2) only required an overpotential of 191 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4, 56 mV lower than that of 1T&#8208;IrO2. When applied in a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer, Nb0.05Ir0.95O2 achieved a current density of 1.2 A cm&#8208;2 at a cell voltage of 1.7 V for 50 days. Density functional theory calculation reveals that doping Nb changes the potential&#8208;determining step from the *OOH deprotonation process in 1T&#8208;IrO2 to the *O&#8208;OH coupling process in Nb0.05Ir0.95O2.</description>
      <author>Ke Jia, Wenxiang Zhu, Yujin Ji, Jinxin Chen, Chenchen Li, Yue Wang, Qun Wang, Wei-Hsiang Huang, Zhiwei Hu, Youyong Li, Qi Shao, Jianmei Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202422740</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electron Accumulation of Ir-Co3o4 Toward Efficient Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084021</link>
      <description>Aiying Song, Chao Cai, Ming Jiang, Pengcheng Li, Ping Liao, Yue Huang, L. Chen, Xuming He, Yuanmin Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406085792

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aiying Song, Chao Cai, Ming Jiang, Pengcheng Li, Ping Liao, Yue Huang, L. Chen, Xuming He, Yuanmin Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Oxygen Vacancies Properties in B-Tio2 Photocatalyst Induced by Rare-Earth Decorating (Re: Nd, Sm, EU, Er, Tm)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084087</link>
      <description>Yanzi Wang, Jianan Dai, Jing Ma, Tengyue Zhang, Zili Liang, Liangsheng Qiang, Rui Liu, Shu&#8208;Hao Chang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406086218

                Enhancing the properties of titanium dioxide (TiO&#8322;) through modification with rare earth metals has become a significant area of research. This study focuses on synthesizing hollow core-shell nanostructured RE-B-TiO&#8322; (RE: Nd, Sm, Eu, Er, Tm) catalysts using solvothermal technology and evaluating their visible-light catalytic efficiency in degrading tetracycline hydrochloride (TCH) and generating H&#8322;. Findings indicate that rare earth element doping enhances oxygen vacancies, minimizes electron-hole recombination, improves electron transfer rates in hollow TiO&#8322; structures, and broadens light absorption from ultraviolet to visible ranges. Under visible light, the Er-B-TiO&#8322; catalyst achieved a 93.2% TCH degradation rate after 120 min. Upon further examination of the effects of catalyst dosage, initial pH, various anions, TCH concentration, and different antibiotics, it was found that pH levels and specific anions significantly impacted the photocatalytic degradation of TCH. An strong absorption band of visible light is achieved in RE-B-TiO&#8322; by intentionally introducing oxygen vacancies, leading to active photochemical oxidation under visible light. Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations and HPLC-MS analyses helped outline the photodegradation pathway and mechanism, while Toxicity predictions indicated a progressive reduction in toxicity during TCH degradation. The enhanced photocatalytic performance is attributed to a slight band gap reduction resulting from the RE 4f-level introduction, offering a promising strategy for designing high-performance photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yanzi Wang, Jianan Dai, Jing Ma, Tengyue Zhang, Zili Liang, Liangsheng Qiang, Rui Liu, Shu&#8208;Hao Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced reconstruction of RuCoNiCuMn high entropy MOF for excellent alkaline oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.510</link>
      <description>Jingting Hou, Ningning Chen, Da Bi, Zhi Long Liu, Yanyu Liang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406086882

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingting Hou, Ningning Chen, Da Bi, Zhi Long Liu, Yanyu Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced reactive oxygen species generation: Synergic process of three-electron oxygen reduction and electrochemical ozone production by bimetallic La-Nb oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.039</link>
      <description>Xiaoge Peng, Xu Liu, Xiaosa Wang, Yuanan Li, Suiqin Li, Yuhang Wang, Zhikang Bao, Hao-Qiang Cao, Yue Cao, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406092443

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoge Peng, Xu Liu, Xiaosa Wang, Yuanan Li, Suiqin Li, Yuhang Wang, Zhikang Bao, Hao-Qiang Cao, Yue Cao, Xing Zhong, Jianguo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.12.039</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood&#8208;Inspired Electrode for Sustainable Electrocatalytic Energy Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smm2.1326</link>
      <description>Weijia Guo, Yawen Wang, Shunyu Shen, Han Wang, Kai Shao, Zhenjie Wang, Yao Shi, Caicai Li, Qingfeng Sun, Huiqiao Li, SmartMat. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406101616

                ABSTRACT Electrocatalysis plays a central role in electrochemical energy storage and conversion systems, providing a number of sustainable processes for future technologies. As a green, renewable, and abundant natural polymer material, the unique structure and physicochemical properties of wood and its derivatives provide a unique application advantage in the field of electrocatalysis, which has aroused intense attention from researchers. At present, researchers have developed many wood&#8208;based catalytic electrodes by taking advantage of the anisotropic hierarchical porous structure of wood and abundant active functional groups on the cell wall surface of wood. Here, a comprehensive review of recent progress in the design and synthesis of wood&#8208;inspired electrodes for electrocatalytic reactions is summarized. Starting from the role and importance of the electrocatalytic process in the whole energy conversion system, this review highlights the composition and structure of wood, analyzes the mechanisms of electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), urea oxidation reaction (UOR), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and discusses the structure&#8208;activity relationship between the structural properties and electrochemical activity of wood&#8208;inspired electrodes. Finally, the opportunities, challenges, and future directions in the application of wood and its derivatives in the field of electrocatalysis are prospected.</description>
      <author>Weijia Guo, Yawen Wang, Shunyu Shen, Han Wang, Kai Shao, Zhenjie Wang, Yao Shi, Caicai Li, Qingfeng Sun, Huiqiao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smm2.1326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal atoms embedded in monolayer C&lt;sub&gt;13&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; as OER/ORR bifunctional electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01160k</link>
      <description>Xiaoxue Yu, Junkai Xu, Yunhao Wang, Jianjun Fang, Xian-Fang Yue, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, Jing Li, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406107125

                Developing bifunctional electrocatalysts for efficiently catalyzing the oxygen evolution/reduction reaction (OER/ORR) is essential for water electrolysis and other processes. Herein, we have investigated the OER and ORR performance of monolayered...</description>
      <author>Xiaoxue Yu, Junkai Xu, Yunhao Wang, Jianjun Fang, Xian-Fang Yue, Breno R. L. Galv&#227;o, Jing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01160k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligands Defect Engineered NH2-MIL-88B(Fe) for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in alkaline seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00968a</link>
      <description>Dongling Xie, Jianan Wang, Bo Huang, Yiyi Yang, Dunmin Lin, Chenggang Xu, Fengyu Xie, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406110150

                Rational design of viable routes to develop affordable and efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is essential for advancing electrochemical water splitting, yet significant challenges remain, particularly in seawater. Here,...</description>
      <author>Dongling Xie, Jianan Wang, Bo Huang, Yiyi Yang, Dunmin Lin, Chenggang Xu, Fengyu Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00968a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Modified Titanium Using Cobalt as Dimensionally Stable Electrodes for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085439</link>
      <description>Raguvaran Ponnurasu, P. Ganesan, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406115684

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Raguvaran Ponnurasu, P. Ganesan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Bimetal Nanoparticles Anchored Hierarchical Carbon Nanospheres with Abundant Active Sites for High-Performance Liquid/Flexible Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085813</link>
      <description>Dingsheng Yuan, Li-Juan Peng, Dan Zhu, Ruchun Li, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406117188

                The development of highly active bifunctional electrocatalysts is crucial to the sluggish oxygen reduction reaction/oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER) for efficient wearable Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZAB). The Fe-Nx-C moieties anchored on carbon supports emerge as a desirable alternative as ORR catalysts but its OER activity suffers from low catalytic performance and stability. Herein, a N-doped carbon-encapsulated Fe3C and MnO nanoparticles composite (FeMn-NC) was developed using a simple one-step pyrolysis of the self-sacrificial template. The obtained FeMn-NC possess a hierarchical porous structure with a large specific surface area and rich pyridinic N, which are favorable for the exposure of the active sites. The introduction of the Fe3C/MnO interface can regulate the charge redistribution to promote ORR/OER kinetics, which is confirmed by theoretical calculations. The obtained FeMn-NC exhibits an excellent bifunctional ORR/OER activity in alkaline electrolytes.The assembled liquid ZAB with the FeMn-NC as the cathode can achieve ultrahigh specific capacity of 831.7 mAh g-1 and charge-discharged stability up to 800 h at 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; (2400 cycles). Furthermore, the corresponding flexible solid-state ZAB provides a stable open-circuit voltage of 1.50 V and a specific capacity of 676.1 mAh g&#8722;1 at 1.0 mA cm-2 with good cycling stability. This work offers a simple strategy to synthesize hierarchical porous materials with highly active bifunctional properties, which can be applied in other electrochemical energy devices.</description>
      <author>Dingsheng Yuan, Li-Juan Peng, Dan Zhu, Ruchun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;Zn&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;(PO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt;&#183;&lt;scp&gt;4H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;/scp&gt;/&lt;scp&gt;TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; Structure for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Energy Storage Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/est2.70112</link>
      <description>Mohammad Wahiduzzaman Khan, Ritu Raj, Mange Ram, Anju Rani, Krishna Kanta Haldar, Energy Storage. 7(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406118645

                ABSTRACT In this study, we present the synthesis and characterization of a high&#8208;performance Zn 3 (PO 4 ) 2 &#183;4H&#8322;O/TiO 2 nanocomposite, designed as a versatile electrocatalyst for advanced energy storage and conversion applications. The synthesis of the Zn 3 (PO 4 ) 2 &#183;4H&#8322;O/TiO 2 nanocomposite was confirmed using various sophisticated analytical techniques such as powder x&#8208;ray diffraction, FTIR, UV spectroscopy, FESEM imaging, EDX, and XPS etc. Notably, the nanocomposite demonstrates exceptional performance in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), with a low overpotential of 250 mV at a current density of 50 mV/cm 2 and a Tafel slope of 129 mV/dec, indicating superior kinetics. Furthermore, it demonstrates a specific capacitance of 112 F/g at a scan rate of 20 mV/s and remarkable cyclic stability, retaining 91% capacitance over 1000 cycles in supercapacitor applications. Additionally, in a practical application, the nanocomposite successfully powered a red light&#8208;emitting diode (LED) for 11 min. The combined effect of Zn 3 (PO 4 ) 2 &#183;4H&#8322;O 2 and TiO 2 contributes to its outstanding electrochemical properties. This makes it a promising candidate for sustainable energy solutions, with the potential to enhance the efficiency and durability of energy storage and conversion systems.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Wahiduzzaman Khan, Ritu Raj, Mange Ram, Anju Rani, Krishna Kanta Haldar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/est2.70112</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h</link>
      <description>Weiguang Hu, Qinghua Xia, Lian Ying Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Qinggang He, Weiyong Yuan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406122704

                Amorphous MOFs (a-MOFs) could be highly promising cocatalysts of 3-D &#945;-Fe 2 O 3 to greatly improve its photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution performance, but their effective synthesis and assembly on 3-D &#945;-Fe 2 O 3 presents formidable...</description>
      <author>Weiguang Hu, Qinghua Xia, Lian Ying Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Qinggang He, Weiyong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of In Situ and Postsynthetic Formation of MOF-Carbon Composites as Electrocatalysts for the Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020208</link>
      <description>Linda Sondermann, Laura Maria Voggenauer, Annette Vollrath, Till Strothmann, Christoph Janiak, Molecules. 30(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126560

                Mixed-metal nickel-iron, NixFe materials draw attention as affordable earth-abundant electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, nickel and mixed-metal nickel-iron metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) composites with the carbon materials ketjenblack (KB) or carbon nanotubes (CNT) were synthesized in situ in a one-pot solvothermal reaction. As a direct comparison to these in situ synthesized composites, the neat MOFs were postsynthetically mixed by grinding with KB or CNT, to generate physical mixture composites. The in situ and postsynthetic MOF/carbon samples were comparatively tested as (pre-)catalysts for the OER, and most of them outperformed the RuO2 benchmark. Depending on the carbon material and metal ratio, the in situ or postsynthetic composites performed better, showing that the method to generate the composite can influence the OER activity. The best material Ni5Fe-CNT was synthesized in situ and achieved an overpotential (&#951;) of 301 mV (RuO2 &#951; = 354 mV), a Tafel slope (b) of 58 mV/dec (RuO2 b = 91 mV/dec), a charge transfer resistance (Rct) of 7 &#8486; (RuO2 Rct = 39 &#8486;), and a faradaic efficiency (FE) of 95% (RuO2 FE = 91%). Structural changes in the materials could be seen through a stability test in the alkaline electrolyte, and chronopotentiometry over 12 h showed that the derived electrocatalysts and RuO2 have good stability.</description>
      <author>Linda Sondermann, Laura Maria Voggenauer, Annette Vollrath, Till Strothmann, Christoph Janiak</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30020208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymetallic Sulfides Based on Co-Bdc/Nf for High Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085458</link>
      <description>Nana Gao, Zhengyuan Liu, Yaqiong Gong, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126664

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nana Gao, Zhengyuan Liu, Yaqiong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nabh4 Modified Cobalt Gallium Bimetallic Hydroxide Nanosheets: A High-Performance Amorphous Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085451</link>
      <description>Fangping Wang, Yuee Zhao, Guizhen Xian, Shiyan Zhao, Haidong Yang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126816

                The development of highly efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a significant goal but faces substantial challenges for large-scale water-splitting applications. Recent studies suggest synergistic effect in multi-metal catalysts or crystalline-amorphous composite materials may effectively enhance OER performance. In this work, we synthesized highly amorphous cobalt gallium bimetallic hydroxide (CoGa-BH-x) by introducing various concentrations of sodium borohydride solution through a simple coprecipitation method, yielding a highly active and stable OER electrocatalyst. The optimized CoGa-BH-0.125 catalyst exhibited remarkable catalytic activity for OER, achieving a low overpotential of 322 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm-2. This performance is attributed to its amorphous nanosheet structure, which provides numerous exposed active sites and facilitates effective contact between the active sites and reactants, enhancing OER efficiency. Furthermore, the successful synthesis of CoGa-BH-0.125 presents a promising approach for the development of amorphous OER electrocatalyst and transition metal catalysts for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Fangping Wang, Yuee Zhao, Guizhen Xian, Shiyan Zhao, Haidong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Differentiated Modulating the Electronic Structure of NiFe@Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOx via Phase Transformation Engineering to Synergy Promote Bifunctional Water Splitting Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410752</link>
      <description>Min Feng, Yu Tang, Zhimin Li, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Jianhong Yi, Jiangzhao Chen, Jinsong Wang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406127033

                Abstract Modulating electronic structure to balance the requirement of both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for developing bifunctional catalysts. Herein, phase transformation engineering is utilized to separately regulate catalyst structure, and the designed NiFe@Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOOH schottky heterojunction exhibits remarkable bifunctional electrocatalytic activity with low overpotentials of 19 and 230 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for HER and OER in 1M KOH, respectively. Meanwhile, an anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolyzer employing NiFe@Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOOH as electrodes shows low voltages of 1.487/1.953 V at 10/1000 mA cm &#8722;2 , and operating over 200 h at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 . Combining theoretical calculations and experiments reveal that phase transformation engineering can differentially regulate the active phases of HER/OER. In the HER, Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOOH and metallic NiFe act as the *OH and *H acceptors respectively to accelerates the water dissociation and subsequent Heyrovsky/Tafel step. While in the OER, the significant Jahn&#8208;Teller effect of Mn 3+ induces the surface reconstruction from Ni/Fe&#8208;MnOOH to Ni/Fe&#8208;MnO 2 . The formative high value Mn 4+ can modify the M&#8208;O hybridization and activate the lattice oxygen mechanism, which is pivotal for breaking the restriction of volcanic relationship and reducing OER overpotential. These findings provide valuable design guidelines for high&#8208;performance multi&#8208;functional electrocatalysts via phase transformation engineering.</description>
      <author>Min Feng, Yu Tang, Zhimin Li, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Jianhong Yi, Jiangzhao Chen, Jinsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410752</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction Three-Dimensional Fe-Based Electrodes for Oxygen Evolution at Large Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085359</link>
      <description>Shuai Niu, Feng Wu, Jing Zhang, Tao Luo, Ying Yuan, Jing Guo, Hao Luo, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406128382

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuai Niu, Feng Wu, Jing Zhang, Tao Luo, Ying Yuan, Jing Guo, Hao Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085359</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt/cobalt phosphide/nitrogen-doped carbon derived from zeolitic imidazolate framework-11@zeolitic imidazolate framework-12 core-shell structure as efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.014</link>
      <description>Chen-Han Lin, Yin-Chen Lin, Chia&#8208;Lin Yeh, L. Lin, Kuo&#8208;Chuan Ho, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406133976

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chen-Han Lin, Yin-Chen Lin, Chia&#8208;Lin Yeh, L. Lin, Kuo&#8208;Chuan Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances and Perspectives on Coupled Water Electrolysis for Energy&#8208;Saving Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411964</link>
      <description>Jiachen Li, Yuqiang Ma, Xiaogang Mu, Xuanjun Wang, Yang Li, Haixia Ma, Zhengxiao Guo, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406146049

                Abstract Overall water splitting (OWS) to produce hydrogen has attracted large attention in recent years due to its ecological&#8208;friendliness and sustainability. However, the efficiency of OWS has been forced by the sluggish kinetics of the four&#8208;electron oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The replacement of OER by alternative electrooxidation of small molecules with more thermodynamically favorable potentials may fundamentally break the limitation and achieve hydrogen production with low energy consumption, which may also be accompanied by the production of more value&#8208;added chemicals than oxygen or by electrochemical degradation of pollutants. This review critically assesses the latest discoveries in the coupled electrooxidation of various small molecules with OWS, including alcohols, aldehydes, amides, urea, hydrazine, etc. Emphasis is placed on the corresponding electrocatalyst design and related reaction mechanisms (e.g., dual hydrogenation and N&#8211;N bond breaking of hydrazine and C&#9552;N bond regulation in urea splitting to inhibit hazardous NCO &#8722; and NO &#8722; productions, etc.), along with emerging alternative electrooxidation reactions (electrooxidation of tetrazoles, furazans, iodide, quinolines, ascorbic acid, sterol, trimethylamine, etc.). Some new decoupled electrolysis and self&#8208;powered systems are also discussed in detail. Finally, the potential challenges and prospects of coupled water electrolysis systems are highlighted to aid future research directions.</description>
      <author>Jiachen Li, Yuqiang Ma, Xiaogang Mu, Xuanjun Wang, Yang Li, Haixia Ma, Zhengxiao Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202411964</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient bifunctional V&#8208;doped NiCoP/Ni2P electrocatalysts for overall water splitting achieved through a simple heterointerfaces construction strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202402006</link>
      <description>Zhong-Hang Xing, Wenfang Cai, Yun&#8208;Hai Wang, Qing&#8208;Yun Chen, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406146246

                Developing efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst with oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is imperative for water electrolysis. Herein, the construction of heterointerfaces was achieved through the simple phosphating treatment, and a unique chrysanthemum&#8208;like V&#8208;doped NiCoP/Ni2P/NF was synthesized for the efficient water splitting. The prepared V&#8208;doped NiCoP/Ni2P/NF demonstrated favorable bifunctional catalytic performance, requiring low overpotentials of 82 mV and 245 mV to achieve current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for the HER and OER, respectively. At a current density of 50 mA cm&#8208;2, the cell voltage for overall water splitting (OWS) is only 1.66 V, with no significant degradation after 60 hours of operation. The characterization and DFT calculations revealed that the heterointerfaces between NiCoP and Ni2P significantly enhanced the catalytic performance by facilitating electron transfer and optimizing charge distribution. Vanadium doping further changed the electronic properties at the interfaces and optimized the adsorption of intermediates. Due to the synergistic effect of heterointerfaces and vanadium doping, V&#8208;doped NiCoP/Ni2P/NF exhibited excellent bifunctional properties, with more reaction sites, high conductivity, and stability. This strategy could open up new possibilities for designing high&#8208;performance catalysts for renewable energy production and sustainable hydrogen generation.</description>
      <author>Zhong-Hang Xing, Wenfang Cai, Yun&#8208;Hai Wang, Qing&#8208;Yun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202402006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversible Hydrogen Spillover Enhances Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on Electrodeposited Moni 4 /Ni 17 W 3 with Amorphous/Crystalline Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085748</link>
      <description>Zhongqing Liu, Xiaoxiao Yin, Yujia Wang, Xiao Fu, Xu Liu, Lixin Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406147671

                Hydrogen spillover phenomena have recently created a new opportunity for ehancing the surface adsorption/desorption kinetics of reactants and intermediates, thereby effectively improving electrocatalytic activity. In this work, Mo elements are introduced into an electrolyte containing Ni, W, and Co, inducing the in-situ formation of an amorphous MoNi4 phase during electrodeposition. Consequently, a coral-like porous MoNi4/Ni17W3 heterostructure is constructed on a stainless steel mesh substrate. The MoNi4/Ni17W3 heterogeneous structure features abundant defect sites and oxygen vacancies, which promote enhanced interfacial charge transfer. This configuration optimizes the H* adsorption, transfer, and desorption processes by facilitating a reversible hydrogen spillover effect between MoNi4 and Ni17W3, as suggested by both experimental results and DFT calculations. These advancements notably improve the kinetics of the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), highlighting its promising potential for efficient hydrogen production. In a 1 M KOH solution, the MoNi4/Ni17W3 electrode affords the overpotentials of only 26 mV and 98 mV at current densities of 10 mA cm-2 and 100 mA cm-2, respectively. Moreover, the electrode maintain almost unchanged HER performance during a 48-hour stability test at a current density of 100 mA cm-2. This work provides a new approach for designing and constructing high-performance non-noble-metal-based heterostructured electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhongqing Liu, Xiaoxiao Yin, Yujia Wang, Xiao Fu, Xu Liu, Lixin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5085748</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Radial Ligand Effect of Biomimetic Amino Acid toward Stable Alkaline Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04889</link>
      <description>Jianye Wang, Zengxuan Chen, Xiaojing Lin, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaodong Chen, Xingheng Zhang, Jiao Li, Jinpeng Liu, Siyuan Liu, Shuxian Wei, Daofeng Sun, Xiaoqing L&#252;, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151000

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jianye Wang, Zengxuan Chen, Xiaojing Lin, Zhaojie Wang, Xiaodong Chen, Xingheng Zhang, Jiao Li, Jinpeng Liu, Siyuan Liu, Shuxian Wei, Daofeng Sun, Xiaoqing L&#252;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c04889</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering pH Mismatching at the Electrified Electrode&#8211;Electrolyte Interface towards Understanding Intrinsic Water Molecule Oxidation Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419823</link>
      <description>Miao Wang, Ken Sakaushi, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151168

                Abstract Unveiling the key influencing factors towards electrode/electrolyte interface control is a long&#8208;standing challenge for a better understanding of microscopic electrode kinetics, which is indispensable to building up guiding principles for designer electrocatalysts with desirable functionality. Herein, we exemplify the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) via water molecule oxidation with the iridium dioxide electrocatalyst and uncovered the significant mismatching effect of pH between local electrode surface and bulk electrolyte: the intrinsic OER activity under acidic or near&#8208;neutral condition was deciphered to be identical by adjusting this pH mismatching. This result indicates that the local pH effect at the electrified solid&#8211;liquid interface plays the main role in the &#8220;fake&#8221; OER performance. This local pH effect on the OER electrode process is further verified by integrating a wide spectrum of analytical approaches. This study will accelerate the understanding of the local proton&#8208;induced effect on electrode interface processes and the development of advanced electrochemical activity.</description>
      <author>Miao Wang, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202419823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering pH Mismatching at the Electrified Electrode&#8211;Electrolyte Interface towards Understanding Intrinsic Water Molecule Oxidation Kinetics</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419823</link>
      <description>Miao Wang, Ken Sakaushi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151788

                Abstract Unveiling the key influencing factors towards electrode/electrolyte interface control is a long&#8208;standing challenge for a better understanding of microscopic electrode kinetics, which is indispensable to building up guiding principles for designer electrocatalysts with desirable functionality. Herein, we exemplify the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) via water molecule oxidation with the iridium dioxide electrocatalyst and uncovered the significant mismatching effect of pH between local electrode surface and bulk electrolyte: the intrinsic OER activity under acidic or near&#8208;neutral condition was deciphered to be identical by adjusting this pH mismatching. This result indicates that the local pH effect at the electrified solid&#8211;liquid interface plays the main role in the &#8220;fake&#8221; OER performance. This local pH effect on the OER electrode process is further verified by integrating a wide spectrum of analytical approaches. This study will accelerate the understanding of the local proton&#8208;induced effect on electrode interface processes and the development of advanced electrochemical activity.</description>
      <author>Miao Wang, Ken Sakaushi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202419823</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eco-Friendly Synthesis of Rod-Like Hydroxyapatite on Spherical Carbon: A Dual-Function Composite for Selective Cobalt Removal and Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.137164</link>
      <description>Ali Mohammadi, Santosh Kumar Tamang, Muruganantham Rethinasabapathy, Kugalur Shanmugam Ranjith, Moein Safarkhani, Cheol Hwan Kwak, Changhyun Roh, Yun Suk Huh, Youngkyu Han, Journal of Hazardous Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406160939

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ali Mohammadi, Santosh Kumar Tamang, Muruganantham Rethinasabapathy, Kugalur Shanmugam Ranjith, Moein Safarkhani, Cheol Hwan Kwak, Changhyun Roh, Yun Suk Huh, Youngkyu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2025.137164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Dispersed Ni-Fe Active Sites on Fullerene based Electron Buffer to boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06990k</link>
      <description>Qin Tang, Lingyue Wang, Shenglong Zhang, Pengfei Xue, Yuye Zhang, Hongbo Li, Dongdong Zhu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406162345

                It is critical to develop highly efficient electrocatalysts for water splitting to achieve energy-saving hydrogen production. Recently, fullerene-based electrocatalysts have been widely reported for cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), while...</description>
      <author>Qin Tang, Lingyue Wang, Shenglong Zhang, Pengfei Xue, Yuye Zhang, Hongbo Li, Dongdong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06990k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution with Prussain Blue Coated ZnO Origami Core&#8208;Shell Nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400817</link>
      <description>Ruby Phul, Guobin Jia, Emir Utku Skercileroglu, Ratnadip De, Yves Carstensen, Andrea Dellith, Jan Dellith, Jonathan Plentz, Ferdi Karadas, Benjamin Dietzek&#8208;Ivan&#353;i&#263;, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406164313

                The design and development of particulate photocatalysts has been an attractive strategy to incorporate earth&#8208;abundant metal ions to water splitting devices. Herein, we synthesized CoFe&#8208;Prussian blue (PB) coated ZnO origami core&#8208;shell nanostructures (PB@ZnO) with different mass ratio of PB components and investigated their photocatalytic water oxidation activities in the presence of an electron scavenger. Photocatalytic experiments reveal that the integration of PB on ZnO boosts the oxygen evolution rate by a factor of ~2.4 compared to bare ZnO origami. We ascribe this increased photocatalytic rate to an improved charge carrier separation and transfer due to the formation of heterojunction at the interface between PB and ZnO. Long&#8208;term photocatalytic experiments indicate that the activity and stability of the catalyst was preserved up to 9 h. Our results indicate that the core&#8208;shell PB@ZnO particles possess a proper band energy alignment for the photocatalytic water oxidation process.</description>
      <author>Ruby Phul, Guobin Jia, Emir Utku Skercileroglu, Ratnadip De, Yves Carstensen, Andrea Dellith, Jan Dellith, Jonathan Plentz, Ferdi Karadas, Benjamin Dietzek&#8208;Ivan&#353;i&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400817</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Atomic Environment Optimization of Nickel&#8211;Iron Dual Sites by Co Doping and Cr Vacancy for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14675</link>
      <description>Hua&#8208;Jie Niu, Nian Ran, Wei Zhou, Wei An, Chuanxue Huang, Wenxing Chen, Min Zhou, Wen-Feng Lin, Jianjun Liu, Lin Guo, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406164462

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hua&#8208;Jie Niu, Nian Ran, Wei Zhou, Wei An, Chuanxue Huang, Wenxing Chen, Min Zhou, Wen-Feng Lin, Jianjun Liu, Lin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c14675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deliberate design of MOF-based pre-catalyst rationalizing the structural reconstruction toward efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2453-2</link>
      <description>Yunhui Chen, Meng Tian, Zhongqi Zhang, Guangzhao Wang, Yan Guo, Wu Jing, Dawei Qi, Zhenhua Yan, Xiangyu Liu, Xi Liu, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406166108

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yunhui Chen, Meng Tian, Zhongqi Zhang, Guangzhao Wang, Yan Guo, Wu Jing, Dawei Qi, Zhenhua Yan, Xiangyu Liu, Xi Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2453-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Ni3S2@Mo-doped CoFe-LDH electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118931</link>
      <description>Wenchi Zhang, Chaoen Li, Lei Sun, Wen Qian, Sorachon Yoriya, Ping He, Rui Zhu, Jiang Wu, Yan Lu, Xin Zeng, Jiajun Wei, Weixiang Liu, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406168179

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenchi Zhang, Chaoen Li, Lei Sun, Wen Qian, Sorachon Yoriya, Ping He, Rui Zhu, Jiang Wu, Yan Lu, Xin Zeng, Jiajun Wei, Weixiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118931</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mos2/Nixsy/Nf Heterojunction Catalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5088225</link>
      <description>Ting Xie, Zhong He Han, Dandan Wu, Jicheng Wu, Guojian Jiang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406171257

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ting Xie, Zhong He Han, Dandan Wu, Jicheng Wu, Guojian Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5088225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Pb&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxygen Evolution Interlayers for Enhancing the Electrochemical Stability of Dimensionally Stable Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03678</link>
      <description>Xu Chen, Jingjing Jin, Junzhe Fan, Juan Luo, Qian Wang, Lida Wang, Wen Sun, Meng Wang, Guichang Liu, Zhengqing Yang, Industrial &amp; Engineering Chemistry Research. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406182921

                Deactivation of the dimensionally stable anode (DSA) restricts their long-term service in the harsh electrolysis industries. In this work, Ti/IrxPb1&#8211;xO2/RuIrSnO2 electrodes with enhanced electrochemical stability were prepared by the thermal decomposition method. Compared with Ti/RuIrSnO2 electrode (95 h), the accelerated service lifetime of Ti/Ir0.7Pb0.3O2/RuIrSnO2 electrode (245 h) was increased by 2.5 times. The increase of the Ir:Pb ratio in IrxPb1&#8211;xO2 interlayer enhanced the oxygen evolution reaction activity and stability of the interlayer to some extent. The electrochemical stability of the RuIrSnO2 layer was closely associated with an electrochemical property of introduced IrxPb1&#8211;xO2 interlayers. This was because once the cracks in the electrode extended to the interlayer, the local defects with high oxygen evolution reaction activity tended to preferentially convert active oxygen species into O2. It impeded the permeation of active oxygen species through oxide matrix to passivate the substrate. This work provided an effective strategy to prolong the service lifetime of DSA.</description>
      <author>Xu Chen, Jingjing Jin, Junzhe Fan, Juan Luo, Qian Wang, Lida Wang, Wen Sun, Meng Wang, Guichang Liu, Zhengqing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.iecr.4c03678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the role of Cobalt Nanoparticles and Mn-phosphate in Etched ZIF-67/Phthalimide-NC and Phthalimene Oxide for Supercapacitor and Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00979g</link>
      <description>Tapan Dey, Nitish Kumar, Rahul Patil, Prakash Kumar Pathak, Sudip Bhattacharjee, Praveen Kumar Yadav, Asim Bhaumik, Rahul R. Salunkhe, Saikat Dutta, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406183979

                The electrochemical supercapacitors and electrochemical oxidation of biomass-derived oxygenate have great significance for long-term high-performance devices. However, appropriate sites with redox features remain a bottleneck for electrochemical oxidation and capacitance...</description>
      <author>Tapan Dey, Nitish Kumar, Rahul Patil, Prakash Kumar Pathak, Sudip Bhattacharjee, Praveen Kumar Yadav, Asim Bhaumik, Rahul R. Salunkhe, Saikat Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00979g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of CNTs composites with mono and bimetallic oxides for the oxygen evolution reactions in water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.111961</link>
      <description>Muhammad Khurram, Nadiah Yousef Aldaleeli, Muhammad Yasir, Abid Ali, Sheza Muqaddas, Muhammad Naveed Arshad, Rizwan Shoukat, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406185824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Khurram, Nadiah Yousef Aldaleeli, Muhammad Yasir, Abid Ali, Sheza Muqaddas, Muhammad Naveed Arshad, Rizwan Shoukat</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.111961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a</link>
      <description>Yuwei Dong, Mingyu Wu, Yu Ren, Zhou Yu, Zhao Zhen, Journal of Materials Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406188293

                Schiff base metal complexes exhibit huge potential as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the high overpotential and complex synthesis process largely restrict their practical application. Herein, we...</description>
      <author>Yuwei Dong, Mingyu Wu, Yu Ren, Zhou Yu, Zhao Zhen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Oxygen Vacancy Engineering in CoMo&#8208;Based Catalysts for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202425503</link>
      <description>Na Luo, Ao Cai, Junhui Pei, Xiongfeng Zeng, Xing Wang, Na Yao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406193832

                Abstract Oxygen vacancy (V O ) engineering is widely regarded as a key strategy for enhancing CoMo&#8208;based catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) while understanding their formation mechanisms and role in boosting OER activity remains a significant challenge. Herein, a CoMoO x system doped is developed with different 3 d &#8208;orbital atoms M (V, Ni, Zn, and Mn) to investigate the construction and stabilization of V O and its crucial role in OER performance. In situ and ex situ measurements along with theoretical calculations demonstrate that V doping adjusts the bandgap between the CoMo&#8208; d and O &#8208;p orbitals, leading to the transfer of electrons from the O&#8208; p orbitals to the M&#8208; d orbitals, thereby promoting the formation of V O . The formation of V O leads to an upshifted d &#8208;band center, optimizing the desorption of oxygen intermediates on V O &#8208;CoMoVO x and lowering the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS), thereby enhancing the catalyst's activity. Additionally, V doping promotes electron transfer from Co to V atoms, stabilizing the V O and ultimately improving the catalyst's stability. The resulting V O &#8208;CoMoVO x catalyst delivered attractive activity (overpotential of 248 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and durability over 600 h. This study offers a rational method for designing efficient OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Na Luo, Ao Cai, Junhui Pei, Xiongfeng Zeng, Xing Wang, Na Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202425503</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Proof&#8208;of&#8208;Principle Demonstration: Exploring the Effect of Anode Layer Microstructure on the Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202421352</link>
      <description>Adarsh Jain, Christian Marcks, Lars Grebener, Jacob Johny, Ahammed Suhail Odungat, Mohit Chatwani, Mena&#8208;Alexander Kr&#228;enbring, Ashin Shaji, Marc F. Tesch, Anna K. Mechler, Vineetha Vinayakumar, Doris Segets, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406194266

                Abstract This study explores the effect of nickel cobalt oxide (Ni&#8208;Co&#8208;O) anode layer microstructure on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Four anodes with similar Ni&#8208;Co&#8208;O loadings and chemical characteristics but distinct morphologies are fabricated by ultrasonic spraying catalyst inks of varying solvent composition (pure water versus a water&#8208;ethanol mixture) and drying temperatures (50 and 150 &#176;C) on nickel (Ni) plates. Upon varying solvent composition, particles in the water&#8208;based ink exhibited lower stability than particles in the water&#8208;ethanol&#8208;based ink, boosting the particle connectivity in the layers. This particle connectivity correlated with the mechanical strength of the layers, resulting in reduced contact resistance and enhanced activity. The second observation is that at 50 &#176;C, the surface morphology exhibited hill&#8208;like islands with higher roughness, while at 150 &#176;C, concave hemispherical shapes with lower roughness are observed. From 2D&#8208;distribution data, it is found that surface roughness correlated with the wettability with electrolyte. Roughness increased the lyophobicity and enhanced the activity through more accessible active sites and efficient bubble transport. This work highlights how microstructure affects macroscopic layer properties, and how these in turn can enhance or diminish the performance of the OER compared to bare Ni, offering insights into the knowledge&#8208;based design of anode layers.</description>
      <author>Adarsh Jain, Christian Marcks, Lars Grebener, Jacob Johny, Ahammed Suhail Odungat, Mohit Chatwani, Mena&#8208;Alexander Kr&#228;enbring, Ashin Shaji, Marc F. Tesch, Anna K. Mechler, Vineetha Vinayakumar, Doris Segets</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202421352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406206683

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An In&#8208;depth Study of the Fe&#8208;Se System at the Nanoscale Reveals Remarkable Results on the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400743</link>
      <description>Dinesh Singh, Monika Ghalawat, Pankaj Poddar, European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406209376

                A catalyst for an electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key component of the large&#8208;scale storage of renewable energy through the conversion of water into oxygen and hydrogen. Iron&#8208;based selenide materials are currently being considered as potential options for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) because of their, widespread availability, inexpensive cost, and outstanding performance. In this study, we employed a thermal decomposition method to synthesize all stable phases of the Fe&#8208;Se system, including Fe7Se8, Fe3Se4, FeSe2, and FeSe. Additionally, we slurry&#8208;coated these phases onto a 3D nickel foam substrate. The prepared three&#8208;dimensional electrodes of Fe7Se8, Fe3Se4, FeSe2, and FeSe exhibit remarkably low overpotentials of 270, 276, 299, and 289 mV at a current density of 50 mA/cm2 for OER. In addition, the catalytic activity for OER is also tested on glassy carbon electrodes to compare its performance with the Ni&#8208;foam 3D substrate. The Fe7Se8 phase in the Fe&#8208;Se system exhibits the highest catalytic activity towards OER on both substrates due to variations in the Fe2+/Fe3+ ratio and the presence of Fe vacancies (cation vacancies) within the crystal lattice. Moreover, a faradaic efficiency of 98% was exhibited by Fe7Se8 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Dinesh Singh, Monika Ghalawat, Pankaj Poddar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vs2-Incorporated Nis/Nis2/Zn-Doped Nimoo4 Nanosheet Arrays on Nickel Foam with Multiphase Heterointerface as Highly Efficient Alkaline Electrocatalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5091049</link>
      <description>Lina Jia, Gaohui Du, Qingmei Su, Huayv Li, Shixian Chen, Bingshe Xu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210180

                Exploring and developing highly active and low-cost transition metal-based electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and overall water splitting in alkaline media is greatly significant for achieving large-scale applications of sustainable clean energy. Herein, we reported the preparation of VS2/NiSx-Zn-NiMoO4 porous nanosheet arrays grown on nickel foam (NF) with rich multiphase interfacial structures via transition metal doping and sulfurization, and its electrocatalytic properties of HER, OER and overall water splitting were studied. The doping of the NiMoO4 host material with transition metal cations (Zn2+) optimizes its electronic structure and generates abundant active sites, thus accelerating the OER reaction kinetics. The formation of transition metal nickel-based sulfides (NiS and NiS2) is beneficial for improving the conductivity of the material. Meanwhile, the introduction of VS2 also promotes the adsorption and transport efficiency of intermediate hydrogen atoms, thereby enhancing HER activity. The multiphase interfaces in VS2/NiSx-Zn-NiMoO4 nanosheets synergistically modulated NiMoO4, which fully utilized the advantages of each material to accelerate electron transfer and induce synergistic catalytic effects to achieve excellent electrocatalytic performance. When VS2/NiSx-Zn-NiMoO4/NF was used as catalyst for HER and OER in an alkaline solution, it required only 162 and 118 mV overpotential at 100 mA cm-2, respectively. Furthermore, the water electrolyser system constructed by using it as the cathode and anode showed excellent performance, requiring only 1.60 V cell voltage to reach 100 mA cm-2 and showing excellent stability. This work provides a new perspective for the application of transition metal molybdates in highly efficient electrocatalysts for alkaline water splitting through reasonable structural optimization.</description>
      <author>Lina Jia, Gaohui Du, Qingmei Su, Huayv Li, Shixian Chen, Bingshe Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5091049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Performance of Er-Mof/Femoo4/Nf</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5090999</link>
      <description>Luo Zhao, Wang Li, Hao Xu, Zikang Wang, Daxiang Yang, Yuping Liu, Xiaoqin Liao, Ming Nie, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210274

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luo Zhao, Wang Li, Hao Xu, Zikang Wang, Daxiang Yang, Yuping Liu, Xiaoqin Liao, Ming Nie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5090999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyphenol-metal coordination derived high-entropy alloy as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03065-1</link>
      <description>Mengdi Hao, Qin Li, Jong-Won Sun, Liu Deng, Hualong Yu, Rui Liu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406214563

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengdi Hao, Qin Li, Jong-Won Sun, Liu Deng, Hualong Yu, Rui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03065-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Redox Dynamics in Zeolite&#8208;Encapsulated CsPbBr&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Perovskite OER Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202412679</link>
      <description>Xiangrong Ren, Yiyue Zhai, Na Yang, Bolun Wang, Shengzhong Liu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406222609

                Abstract Understanding the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) mechanism is pivotal for improving the overall efficiency of water electrolysis. Despite methylammonium lead halide perovskites (MAPbX 3 ) have shown promising OER performance due to their soft&#8208;lattice nature that allows lattice&#8208;oxygen oxidation of active &#945;&#8208;PbO 2 layer surface, the role of A&#8208;site MA or X&#8208;site elements in the electrochemical reconstruction and OER mechanisms has yet to be explored. Here, it is demonstrated that the OER mechanism of perovskite@zeolite composites is intrinsically dominated by the A&#8208;site group of lead&#8208;halide perovskites, while the type of X&#8208;site halogen is crucial for the reconstruction kinetics of the composites. Using CsPbBr x I 3&#8208; x @AlPO&#8208;5 ( x = 0, 1, 2, 3) as a model OER catalyst, it is found that the CsPbBr 3 @AlPO&#8208;5 behaves oxygen&#8208;intercalation pseudocapacitance during surface restructuring due to absence of halogen&#8208;ion migration and phase separation in the CsPbBr 3 , achieving a larger diffusion rate of OH &#8722; within the core&#8208;shell structure. Moreover, distinct from the single&#8208;metal&#8208;site mechanism of MAPbBr 3 @AlPO&#8208;5, experimental and theoretical investigations reveal that the soft lattice nature of CsPbBr 3 triggers the oxygen&#8208;vacancy&#8208;site mechanism via the CsPbBr 3 /&#945;&#8208;PbO 2 interface, resulting in excellent OER performance. Owing to the variety and easy tailoring of lead&#8208;halide perovskite compositions, these findings pave a way for the development of novel perovskite@zeolite type catalysts for efficient oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Xiangrong Ren, Yiyue Zhai, Na Yang, Bolun Wang, Shengzhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202412679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous-flow electrooxidation for scalable biomass upgrading over copper-supported CoFe Prussian blue analogues</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.37</link>
      <description>Bowen Zhang, Tian&#8208;Tian Xiao, Cejun Hu, Ziwei Liu, Peng Chen, Zhengyu Zhao, Dingxiang Lai, Jinming Huang, Hongwei Zhang, Xiaojun Bao, Pei Pei Yuan, Chemical Synthesis. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406227756

                Electrochemical biomass upgrading is a promising substitute for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to generate valuable chemicals in conjunction with hydrogen generation. Pursuing highly efficient and durable electrocatalysts for significant concentration levels (&#8805; 50 mM) of biomass electrooxidation remains an enduring challenge. Herein, we introduce a robust Cu-supported CoFe Prussian blue analogue (CoFe PBA/CF) electrocatalyst, adept at facilitating high-concentration (50 mM) 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation into 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA), achieving an exceptional HMF conversion (100%) with a notable FDCA yield of 98.4%. The influence of copper substrate and adsorption energy are therefore discussed. Impressively, the CoFe PBA/CF electrode sustains considerable durability in a continuous-flow electrochemical reactor designed for consecutive FDCA production, showcasing FDCA yields of 100/94% at flow rates of 0.4/0.8 mL&#183;min-1 over 60 h&#8217; uninterrupted electrolysis. This work provides a promising strategy to develop highly efficient and robust electrocatalysts for the consecutive production of high-value products coupled with green H2 production.</description>
      <author>Bowen Zhang, Tian&#8208;Tian Xiao, Cejun Hu, Ziwei Liu, Peng Chen, Zhengyu Zhao, Dingxiang Lai, Jinming Huang, Hongwei Zhang, Xiaojun Bao, Pei Pei Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.37</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing electronic synergy of atomically dispersed dual-metal sites for high-efficiency Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05706f</link>
      <description>Yue Wang, Caihong Feng, Ziang Shang, Xintong Li, Chao Ma, Guanzhen Chen, Ying Zhao, Shaoheng Wu, Yunhu Han, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406227995

                We reported an exogenous nitrogen-doped method to synthesize a bifunctional electrocatalyst with oxygen reduction and evolution reaction activity. This electrocatalyst display excellent ORR (E1/2 = 0.9 V vs. RHE) and...</description>
      <author>Yue Wang, Caihong Feng, Ziang Shang, Xintong Li, Chao Ma, Guanzhen Chen, Ying Zhao, Shaoheng Wu, Yunhu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05706f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280192

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280211

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280214

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280225

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe ion doping as an effective strategy to enhance oxygen evolution reaction activity in NiCo2O4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.236159</link>
      <description>Xiaoxue Fu, Juan Yu, Han Li, Yongxing Zhang, Shencheng Pan, Yongsheng Fu, Bing Li, Journal of Power Sources. 630(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406062474

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoxue Fu, Juan Yu, Han Li, Yongxing Zhang, Shencheng Pan, Yongsheng Fu, Bing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.236159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface/interface regulation of Ni0.85Se via tungsten-doping for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178478</link>
      <description>Xiao Fu, Xu Liu, Yi Wang, Yujia Wang, Xiaoxiao Yin, Zhongqing Liu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406064051

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao Fu, Xu Liu, Yi Wang, Yujia Wang, Xiaoxiao Yin, Zhongqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2025.178478</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doping La into NiFe LDH/NiS heterostructure achieving high-current-density oxygen evolution for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157526</link>
      <description>Qi Song, Kangnan Li, Zhenhua Cao, Mi Yang, Qian Kong, Gang He, Hongyu Liu, Qian Qiao, Liangzhong Yao, Yufan Wang, Xiaoping Dai, Xin Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qi Song, Kangnan Li, Zhenhua Cao, Mi Yang, Qian Kong, Gang He, Hongyu Liu, Qian Qiao, Liangzhong Yao, Yufan Wang, Xiaoping Dai, Xin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157526</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Benchmark for Pure Nickel-Based Oxygen-Evolution Electrocatalyst: Tailored Large NiMoO4&#183;xH2O Monocrystals for Complete Reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125024</link>
      <description>Xin Cui, Tang Tang, Feiyang Zhang, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Cui, Tang Tang, Feiyang Zhang, Licheng Sun, Biaobiao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2025.125024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406064935

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065107

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065133

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Hongrui Zhu, Guixiang Ding, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, V. Yu. Fominski, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065138

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Hongrui Zhu, Guixiang Ding, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, V. Yu. Fominski</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065175

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065181

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065198

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Linqing Liao, Wangyan Gou, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065405

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Linqing Liao, Wangyan Gou, Mingkai Zhang, Xiaohe Tan, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065411

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065420

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065439

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065442

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Metastable State Structure Promotes Surface Reconstruction of Spinel NiFe2O4 for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065466

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07846b/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406065471

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280114

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280167

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280292

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280306

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280428

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280429

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High content Fe(III) electrocatalyst for the oxygen reduction and evolution reactions. Spectroscopic, electrochemical, and theoretical insights</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.385</link>
      <description>C&#233;sar Z&#250;&#241;iga Loyola, Andrea Zitolo, Nicol&#225;s Troncoso, Jesus Carrasco, Sergio Choque, Gabriel Abarca, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Walter Orellana, Federico Tasca, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 101(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406074461

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C&#233;sar Z&#250;&#241;iga Loyola, Andrea Zitolo, Nicol&#225;s Troncoso, Jesus Carrasco, Sergio Choque, Gabriel Abarca, Jos&#233; H. Zagal, Walter Orellana, Federico Tasca</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.12.385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the photosynthesis process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.59783/aire.2023.18</link>
      <description>Blanka Balyi, Nela Marinovi&#263;, Nata&#353;a Nikoli&#263;-Lukovska, AIDASCO Reviews. 1(1)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4406142614

                In this Review, some fascinating and essential concepts of photosynthesis were described. There is much information about photosynthesis, which is widely known, considering the importance of this process. However, there is also a range of information about photosynthesis that is unknown and not often mentioned. Photosynthesis is the name given to the set of biochemical reactions that change carbon dioxide and water into sugar, glucose, and oxygen. Sunlight is often harnessed by chlorophyll, which is green because it reflects green light. This Review will give a deeper insight into some parts of the photosynthesis process.</description>
      <author>Blanka Balyi, Nela Marinovi&#263;, Nata&#353;a Nikoli&#263;-Lukovska</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.59783/aire.2023.18</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoelectrochemical behavior of WO3 and TiO2 films modified with cobalt-based oxygen evolution catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2014.25.3.4</link>
      <description>Simona Ostachavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Rasa Mardosait&#279;, Eugenijus Valatka, Chemija. 25(3)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4406095564

                Continuous tungsten trioxide (WO3) and porous titanium dioxide (TiO2) films on AISI304 type steel were prepared by electrochemical methods. The morphology and structure of the obtained films were studied by X-ray diffraction analysis and scanning electron microscopy. Oxygen evolution catalyst containing cobalt&#8211;phosphate compound was deposited photochemically onto the surface of semiconductor particles. The photoelectrochemical properties of the prepared electrodes were investigated in neutral 0.1 M phosphate buffer solutions. The voltammetric characteristics revealed that the presence of cobalt-based catalyst effectively changes the photoelectrocatalytic activity of WO3 and TiO2 particles. The influence of some synthesis parameters (type of cobalt(II) salt, photodeposition time) on the electrochemical properties of the prepared electrodes was evaluated experimentally.</description>
      <author>Simona Ostachavi&#269;i&#363;t&#279;, Rasa Mardosait&#279;, Eugenijus Valatka</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.6001/chemija.2014.25.3.4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polarization switching-controlled oxygen evolution and reduction reactions for ferroelectric single-atom catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159247</link>
      <description>Wenqing Li, Hongyu Zhang, Ruoyan Xu, Xingxing Jiang, Haiyu Meng, Xiong&#8208;Xiong Xue, Shengli Zhang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406069716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenqing Li, Hongyu Zhang, Ruoyan Xu, Xingxing Jiang, Haiyu Meng, Xiong&#8208;Xiong Xue, Shengli Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2025.159247</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of NiSe /Mo3O8 heterogeneous structure with obvious polarity difference for promoted oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134282</link>
      <description>Xiao Fu, Lang Qin, Yujia Wang, Xiaoxiao Yin, Xu Liu, Zhongqing Liu, Fuel. 386(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406119533

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiao Fu, Lang Qin, Yujia Wang, Xiaoxiao Yin, Xu Liu, Zhongqing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2025.134282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Spillover of active oxygen intermediates of binary RuO2/Nb2O5 nanowires for highly active and robust acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406065416

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nh00437j/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406207155

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406206988

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406206708

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Yuwei Dong, Mingyu Wu, Yu Ren, Zhou Yu, Zhao Zhen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406207003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuwei Dong, Mingyu Wu, Yu Ren, Zhou Yu, Zhao Zhen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406206666

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406206678

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidation of the Electrocatalytic Function of Composite Metal Carbides Co&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;W&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;C and Co&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;Mo&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;C with Oxygen Reduction and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5796/electrochemistry.24-00123</link>
      <description>Ikki Yanagimoto, Masashi Wada, Satoko Takase, Toshiyuki Takizawa, Youichi Shimizu, Electrochemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406159303

                Metal-air secondary batteries have attracted attention as a next-generation energy storage system due to their high energy density and environmentally friendly characteristics.However, it is important to develop a catalyst that can rapidly promote both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).We have found that Co3W3C and Co3Mo3C composite metal carbides prepared by a wet method have high bifunctional electrode performance, but the mechanism of action has not been elucidated.In this study, we comprehensively evaluated the adsorption behavior of oxygen molecules and surface hydroxyl groups, the charge density difference, and the effects of surface structure and chemical composition on catalytic activity by combining DFT (density functional theory) calculations and instrumental analysis.In particular, we found that Co3Mo3C optimizes the adsorption of oxygen molecules by metal compositing, contributing to the improvement of electrode catalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Ikki Yanagimoto, Masashi Wada, Satoko Takase, Toshiyuki Takizawa, Youichi Shimizu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5796/electrochemistry.24-00123</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406170150

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406170086

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406170151

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406169724

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Weiguang Hu, Qinghua Xia, Lian Ying Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Qinggang He, Weiyong Yuan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406169531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiguang Hu, Qinghua Xia, Lian Ying Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Qinggang He, Weiyong Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406170174

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "&amp;lt;i&amp;gt;In situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; controllably self-assembled amorphous Co-TDPAT MOFs as superior cocatalysts of &#945;-Fe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; nanosheet arrays for highly efficient and ultrastable photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406158323

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07843h/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/Crystalline ZrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with Oxygen Vacancies Anchored Nano&#8208;Ru Enhance Reverse Hydrogen Spillover in Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410436</link>
      <description>Jingyang Niu, Huimei Duan, Ting Sun, Zelun Zhi, Daohao Li, Xiaokun Fan, Lijie Zhang, Dongjiang Yang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406085038

                Abstract Hydrogen spillover&#8208;based binary (HSBB) system has attracted significant attention in alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Accelerating hydrogen spillover in the HSBB system is crucial for the HER activity. Herein, a highly efficient HSBB system is developed by anchoring nano&#8208;Ru on oxygen vacancy (Vo) rich amorphous/crystal ZrO 2 . Theoretical and experimental results reveal that the water molecules dissociate on the Vo of ZrO 2 into protons, which then couple with electrons to form H * , and the produced H * are spilled over to the nano&#8208;Ru to evolve H 2 . The amorphous regions enhance the adsorption and desorption rates of hydrogen while exposing a greater number of active sites; meanwhile, the Vo significantly reduce the work function of ZrO 2 , facilitates electron transfer from ZrO 2 to Ru, and thereby accelerates hydrogen spillover. As a result, the Ru/ac&#8208;ZrO 2 delivers a low overpotential of 14 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a high mass activity of 46.47 A mg metal &#8722;2 at 300 mV for alkaline HER, bypass those of commercial Pt/C (19 mV and 0.09 A mg metal &#8722;2 , respectively).</description>
      <author>Jingyang Niu, Huimei Duan, Ting Sun, Zelun Zhi, Daohao Li, Xiaokun Fan, Lijie Zhang, Dongjiang Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410436</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280283

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trace Cobalt Inserted Platinum Lattice Gap to Enable Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07260j</link>
      <description>Jie Yang, Shilong Song, Bo Zhang, Zhanwei Chen, Yuyu Guo, Ying Guo, Hepeng Zhang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406107149

                Platinum-based materials are generally considered as efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysts but worse for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), limiting their applications in zinc-air batteries (ZABs). Therefore, it is of...</description>
      <author>Jie Yang, Shilong Song, Bo Zhang, Zhanwei Chen, Yuyu Guo, Ying Guo, Hepeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07260j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Au-Ni synergy for enhanced electrochemical oxidation of ethanol over Au/Ni foam electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01490a</link>
      <description>Xing Tan, Ruixing Du, Qitong Zhong, Longfei Liao, Huanhao Chen, Zhenchen Tang, Dafeng Yan, Shiming Chen, Feng Zeng, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406093305

                Replacing the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction with ethanol oxidation can reduce the overpotential while generating value-added products. In this study, a highly active and stable catalyst was synthesized via electrochemical...</description>
      <author>Xing Tan, Ruixing Du, Qitong Zhong, Longfei Liao, Huanhao Chen, Zhenchen Tang, Dafeng Yan, Shiming Chen, Feng Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy01490a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic aldehyde oxidation: An emerging anodic reaction for efficient electrolytic systems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01515k</link>
      <description>Fen Hu, Peng&#8208;Yuan Wang, Z. L&#252;, Kai Chen, Yichun Ding, Wang Li, Zhenhai Wen, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406108597

                Conventional electrolytic systems (e.g., water electrolysis), which rely on the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), are hindered by sluggish anodic kinetics and high energy demands. Electrocatalytic aldehyde oxidation, which has...</description>
      <author>Fen Hu, Peng&#8208;Yuan Wang, Z. L&#252;, Kai Chen, Yichun Ding, Wang Li, Zhenhai Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se01515k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A self-supported nickel pseudo-intermetallic alloy electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102369</link>
      <description>Naznin Shaikh, Supriya Sau, Sagar Mitra, Indrajit Mukhopadhyay, Abhijit Ray, Cell Reports Physical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406143605

                Highlights&#8226;Self-supported, binder-free Ni surface alloy bifunctional electrocatalyst for hydrogen&#8226;Electrodes with industrial current density at low applied electrical bias&#8226;No significant loss of current after 30 h of testingSummaryDeveloping non-noble electrocatalysts for efficient water splitting remains a significant challenge. This study reports a selenized intermetallic-like surface alloy, Ni0.91Mo0.09, directly grown on Ni foam (NF), as a highly active electrode. A hierarchical stack of Ni3Se4/Ni0.91Mo0.09 interfaces is fabricated on porous NF (NiMoSe/NF) through Se diffusion into an electrodeposited (Ni-Mo) alloy via rapid thermal annealing. Experimental studies, supported by theoretical calculations, reveal that these interfaces provide abundant active sites, optimize hydrogen and oxygen absorption free energy, and facilitate efficient electron transfer for hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. The porous structure enhances mass transport, further boosting performance. The Ni3Se4/Ni0.91Mo0.09@NF heterostructure achieves 50 and 100 mA cm&#8315;2 at overpotentials of 62 and 116 mV for hydrogen evolution and 208 and 348 mV for oxygen evolution, respectively, in 0.5 M H&#8322;SO&#8324;, with stability over 60 h of continuous H&#8322; evolution.Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Naznin Shaikh, Supriya Sau, Sagar Mitra, Indrajit Mukhopadhyay, Abhijit Ray</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.xcrp.2024.102369</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Secondary Coordination Effects of Adjacent Metal Center in Metal-Nitrogen-Carbon Improve Scaling Relation of Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3mjc9-v2</link>
      <description>Ke Ye, Yulan Han, Min Hu, P. Hu, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084263

                Heterogenous single-atom catalysts (SACs) are reminescent of homogenous catalysts because of similarity of structural motif of active sites, showing the potential of using the advantage of homogenous catalysts to tackle challenges in hetereogenous catalysis. In heterogeneous oxygen electrocatalysis, the homogeneity of adsorption patterns of reaction intermediates leads to scaling relationships that limit their activities. In contrast, homogeneous catalysts can circumvent such limits by selectively altering the adsorption of intermediates through secondary coordination effects (SCE). This inspired us to explored potential SCE in metal-nitrogen-carbon (M-N-C), a promising type of oxygen evolution electrocatalysts. We introduced SCE with a neighboring metal site, which can modulate the adsorption strengths of oxygen-containing intermediates. First-principles calculations show that the second site in heteronuclear duo four-nitrogen-coordinated metal-center can induce SCE that selectively stabilize the OOH intermediate, but with minor effects on the OH intermediate, and thereby, disrupt scaling relation between oxygen-species, and eventually increase the catalytic activity in oxygen evolution reactions. Additionally, the activity of oxygen reduction reaction of selected M-N-C is also enhanced by such SCE. Our computational work underscored the critical role SCE can have in shaping activities of SACs, particularly in altering scaling relationships favorably, and demonstrated its potential of addressing catalytic challenges in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Ke Ye, Yulan Han, Min Hu, P. Hu, M&#229;rten S. G. Ahlquist, Guozhen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3mjc9-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Approaching Theoretical Limit of &lt;scp&gt;T&lt;/scp&gt;a&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;scp&gt;N&lt;/scp&gt;&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanode via Photothermal&#8208;Accelerating Kinetics with Full&#8208;Spectrum Utilization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12868</link>
      <description>Yi Liu, Yanwei Zhang, Yicheng Wang, Xiaopeng Zhan, Peng&#8208;Fei Sui, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Chenyu Xu, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406133714

                Tantalum nitride is widely considered as a promising photoanode material for its suitable band structure as well as the high theoretical conversion efficiency in solar water splitting. However, it is limited to inefficient photoinduced electron&#8211;hole pair separation and interfacial dynamics in the photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution reaction. Herein, multiple layers including Ti x Si y and NiFeCoO x were fabricated based on band engineering to regulate tandem electric states for efficient transfer of energy carriers. Besides, photothermal local surface plasmon resonance was introduced to accelerate the kinetics of photoelectrochemical reactions at the interface when the special Ag nanoparticles were loaded to extend the absorbance to near infrared light. Consequently, a recordable photocurrent density of 12.73 mA cm &#8722;2 has been achieved at 1.23 V versus RHE, approaching a theoretical limit of the tantalum nitride photoanode with full&#8208;spectrum solar utilization. Meanwhile, compared to the applied bias photon&#8208;to&#8208;current efficiency of 1.36% without photothermal factor, a high applied bias photon&#8208;to&#8208;current efficiency of 2.27% could be raised by applying local surface plasmon resonance to photoelectrochemical oxygen evolution reaction. The efficient design could maximize the use of solar light via the classification of spectrum and, therefore, may spark more innovative ideas for the future design and development of the next&#8208;generation photoelectrode.</description>
      <author>Yi Liu, Yanwei Zhang, Yicheng Wang, Xiaopeng Zhan, Peng&#8208;Fei Sui, Jing&#8208;Li Luo, Chenyu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12868</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Fe, Co, Ni-based single atom catalysts and the progress of their application in electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.65</link>
      <description>Yuquan Yang, Meifang Huang, Bin-Bin Gao, Chenjing Wang, Hongjing Wu, Yanru Yuan, Jinlong Zheng, Microstructures. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406190925

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) have garnered considerable attention owing to their profound potential in promoting the efficient utilization of metal resources and attaining atomic-level economy. Fe, Co, Ni SACs have demonstrated broad application prospects in electrocatalysis due to their tunable composition and structure, as well as their unique electronic properties. Firstly, the various preparation methods for Fe, Co, Ni SACs are outlined in this review, including high-temperature pyrolysis, impregnation, chemical vapor deposition, and atomic layer deposition. These methods not only enhance the utilization efficiency of metal atoms but also ensure the stability of the catalysts. Subsequently, this review summarizes the recent progress in the applications of Fe, Co, Ni SACs for electrocatalysis, with a particular focus on their efficacy in hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, oxygen reduction reaction, carbon dioxide reduction reaction, and nitrogen reduction reaction. Despite remarkable advancements, Fe, Co, Ni SACs still face challenges related to large-scale production, stability enhancement, comprehensive characterization, and mechanistic exploration. Finally, this review discusses these challenges and proposes strategies to address them in order to fully realize the potential of Fe, Co, Ni SACs as high-performance catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuquan Yang, Meifang Huang, Bin-Bin Gao, Chenjing Wang, Hongjing Wu, Yanru Yuan, Jinlong Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2024.65</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phytic Acid Acts as an "Electronic Diaphragm" to Enhance the Uor Activity and Stability of Nise2 at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084015</link>
      <description>Qiuyan Chen, Jinwei Chen, Xing-Shu Dong, Changxue Dong, Yunzhe Zhou, Jie Zhang, Gang Wang, Ruilin Wang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406085580

                The development of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR) catalysts with high activity and stability at large current density is the key to realizing efficient and energy-saving electrolytic hydrogen production and wastewater degradation. Herein, an interfacial coordination assembly scheme is established to complement phytic acid coordination complex (NiSe2@PA) on NiSe2 nanorods arrays to achieve enhanced and sustained UOR electrocatalytic activity and stability at high current densities. The experimental density functional theory (DFT) are proved that the modification of PA on the surface of NiSe2 can manipulate the electronic states of Ni sites, and the in-situ evolution of charge redistribution surface can promote urea adsorption. It is impressive that PA functionalization can imbue a negatively charged catalyst surface, not only improving hydrophobic/gaseous properties, but also weakening *COO adsorption and facilitating CO2 removal, reducing catalyst poisoning and enhancing durability. Therefore, NiSe2@PA exhibits excellent UOR performance, with an ultra-low potential of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at 1.295 V (vs. RHE), a small Tafel slope (34.97 mV dec&#8722;1), and strong durability (500 mA cm&#8722;2 @ 60 h). It is comparable to the best nickel-based electrocatalysts recorded to date.</description>
      <author>Qiuyan Chen, Jinwei Chen, Xing-Shu Dong, Changxue Dong, Yunzhe Zhou, Jie Zhang, Gang Wang, Ruilin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5084015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Synthesis of Ternary Ni-Fe-Mo Nanosheet Arrays for OER in Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30010177</link>
      <description>Zhi L&#252;, Yifan Guo, Shilin Li, Jiaqi Ding, Yingzi Ren, Kun Tang, Jiefeng Wang, Chang&#8208;Jiu Li, Zhan Shi, Ziqi Sun, Hongbo Meng, Guangxin Wang, Molecules. 30(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406084377

                Water electrolysis is a promising path to the industrialization development of hydrogen energy. The exploitation of high-efficiency and inexpensive catalysts become important to the mass use of water decomposition. Ni-based nanomaterials have exhibited great potential for the catalysis of water splitting, which have attracted the attention of researchers around the world. Here, we prepared a novel Mo-doped NiFe-based layered double hydroxide (LDH) with a nanoarray microstructure on Ni foam. The doping amount of Mo can significantly change the microstructure of the electrocatalysis, which will further affect the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of water splitting. This novel nanomaterial required only an overpotential of 227 mV for 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 54.8 mV/dec in 1 M KOH. Meanwhile, there was no Mo, and the NiFe-LDH needed 233 mV to attain to 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Compared to the NiFe-LDH without Mo, the NiFeMo-LDH nanosheet arrays exhibited enhanced activities with 17.1 mV/dec less Tafel in OER. The good performance of the electrocatalyst is ascribed to the special nanosheet arrays and the heterostructure of the Ni-Fe-Mo system. These features help to increase the active surface, enhancing the efficient charge transfer and the reactive activity in OER.</description>
      <author>Zhi L&#252;, Yifan Guo, Shilin Li, Jiaqi Ding, Yingzi Ren, Kun Tang, Jiefeng Wang, Chang&#8208;Jiu Li, Zhan Shi, Ziqi Sun, Hongbo Meng, Guangxin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules30010177</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controlled Structural Activation of Iridium Single Atom Catalyst for High-Performance Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11442</link>
      <description>Wonjae Ko, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Hyunsoo Ahn, Hyeonseok Kwon, Kangjae Lee, Yoon Seok Jung, Wytse Hooch Antink, Chan Woo Lee, Sungeun Heo, Seongbeom Lee, Junghwan Jang, Jiheon Kim, Hyeon Seok Lee, Sung-Pyo Cho, Byoung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Minho Kim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Taeghwan Hyeon, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406170449

                Iridium single atom catalysts are promising oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE), as they can reduce the reliance on costly Ir in the OER catalysts. However, their practical application is hindered by their limited stability during PEMWE operation. Herein, we report on the activation of Ir-doped CoMn2O4 in acidic electrolyte that leads to enhanced activity and stability in acidic OER for long-term PEMWE operation. In-depth material characterization combined with electrochemical analysis and theoretical calculations reveal that activating Ir-doped CoMn2O4 induces controlled restructuring of Ir single atoms to IrOx nanoclusters, resulting in an optimized Ir configuration with outstanding mass activity of 3562 A gIr&#8211;1 at 1.53 V (vs RHE) and enhanced OER stability. The PEMWE using activated Ir-doped CoMn2O4 exhibited a stable operation for &gt;1000 h at 250 mA cm&#8211;2 with a low degradation rate of 0.013 mV h&#8211;1, demonstrating its practical applicability. Furthermore, it remained stable for more than 400 h at a high current density of 1000 mA cm&#8211;2, demonstrating long-term durability under practical operation conditions.</description>
      <author>Wonjae Ko, Jae-Hyuk Shim, Hyunsoo Ahn, Hyeonseok Kwon, Kangjae Lee, Yoon Seok Jung, Wytse Hooch Antink, Chan Woo Lee, Sungeun Heo, Seongbeom Lee, Junghwan Jang, Jiheon Kim, Hyeon Seok Lee, Sung-Pyo Cho, Byoung&#8208;Hoon Lee, Minho Kim, Yung&#8208;Eun Sung, Taeghwan Hyeon</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c11442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D Co&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;Mo&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt;C&#8208;Based Heterojunctional Nanowires from Pyrolytically &#8220;Squeezing&#8221; PMo&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;/ZIF&#8208;67 Cubes for Efficient Overall Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409703</link>
      <description>Xinhui Zhang, Aiping Wu, Dongxu Wang, Ying Xie, Alexander I. Gubanov, Gennadiy &#1040;. &#1050;&#1086;stin, Chungui Tian, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406115361

                Abstract The bi&#8208;transition&#8208;metal interstitial compounds (BTMICs) are promising for water electrolysis. The previous BTMICs are usually composed of irregular particles. Here, this work shows the synthesis of novel 1D Co 6 Mo 6 C&#8208;based heterojunction nanowires (1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C) with diameters about 50 nm and a length&#8208;to&#8208;diameter ratio about 20 for efficient water electrolysis. An interesting growth process based on pyrolytically &#8220;squeezing&#8221; PMo 12 (Phosphomolybdic acid)/ZIF&#8208;67 (Zeolitic Imidazolate Framework&#8208;67) cube precursor is demonstrated. The &#8220;squeezing&#8221; growth is related to the role of Mo species for isolating Co species. A series of tests and theoretical calculation show the mutual regulation of Co and Mo to optimize the electronic structure, accelerating H 2 O dissociation and the reduction kinetics of H + . Additionally, the nanowires provide pathways for electron transfer and the transmission of reactants. Consequently, the 1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C exhibits high activity for hydrogen evolution reaction ( &#951; 10 of 31 mV) and oxygen evolution reaction ( &#951; 10 of 210 mV) in 1 m KOH. The electrolytic cell based on 1D Co/Co 6 Mo 6 C requires a low voltage of 1.43 V to drive 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . The catalyst also exhibits good HER performance in 1 m phosphate&#8208;buffered saline solution, exceeding Pt/C at a current density &gt;42 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Xinhui Zhang, Aiping Wu, Dongxu Wang, Ying Xie, Alexander I. Gubanov, Gennadiy &#1040;. &#1050;&#1086;stin, Chungui Tian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tiara Nickel Cluster Story from Theory to Catalytic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00087</link>
      <description>Piracha Sanwal, Xinrui Gu, Yifei Zhang, Gao Li, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406207307

                As a transition material between bulk materials and individual atoms, nickel clusters have interesting electrical and structural characteristics that could make them useful as catalysts. To examine the catalytic efficiency of nickel clusters in different applications, this Review combines experimental techniques with density functional theory (DFT). Researchers have shown that nickel clusters can activate and alter tiny molecules like CO, NO, and H2 through DFT studies that delve deeply into their electronic structures, adsorption mechanisms, and stability. These findings lay the groundwork for the development of effective catalysts for various processes. Nickel clusters considerably improve the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), indicating their promise for renewable energy conversion. Furthermore, electrocatalysis for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) showcases the electrochemical performance of nickel clusters, demonstrating their stability and efficiency. The adaptability of nickel clusters is further demonstrated by their use in nitrogen reduction to ammonia. Experimental data confirm that these clusters are good catalysts for this crucial industrial activity. Hydrocarbon reforming and pollutant degradation are two areas in which research has shown that nickel clusters can be useful in thermal reactions. X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and environmental transmission electron microscopy (ETEM) are examples of in situ characterization techniques that support theoretical predictions by providing real-time insights into the structural alterations and active sites of nickel clusters during these processes. Preparing the way for future research and practical applications in energy and environmental technologies, this thorough study highlights the great potential of nickel clusters in constructing sustainable and efficient catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Piracha Sanwal, Xinrui Gu, Yifei Zhang, Gao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Performance of Alkaline Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer with Vanadium&#8208;Doped NiFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410006</link>
      <description>Minsol Kwon, Jun Seok Ha, Dong Hyeon Lee, Taehyun Kwon, Minseo Kim, Young&#8208;Hun Jeong, Han Seul Kim, Alexander S. Ditter, David A. Shapiro, Young&#8208;Sang Yu, Yoo Sei Park, Dongju Lee, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406187235

                Abstract Developing efficient, economical, and stable catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction is pivotal for producing large&#8208;scale green hydrogen in the future. Herein, a vanadium&#8208;doped nickel&#8208;iron oxide supported on nickel foam (V&#8208;NiFe 2 O 4 /NF) is introduced, and synthesized via a facile hydrothermal method as a highly efficient electrocatalyst for water electrolysis. X&#8208;ray photoelectron and absorption spectroscopies reveal a synergistic interaction between the vanadium dopant and nickel/iron in the host material, which tunes the electronic structure of NiFe 2 O 4 to increase the number of electrochemically active sites. The V&#8208;NiFe 2 O 4 /NF electrode exhibited superior electrochemical performance, with a low overpotential of 186 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , a Tafel slope value of 54.45 mV dec &#8722;1 , and minimal charge transfer resistance. Employing the V&#8208;NiFe 2 O 4 /NF electrode as an anode in an alkaline anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer single&#8208;cell, a cell voltage of 1.711 V is required to achieve a high current density of 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 . Remarkably, the cell delivered an energy conversion efficiency of 73.30% with enduring stability, making it a promising candidate for industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Minsol Kwon, Jun Seok Ha, Dong Hyeon Lee, Taehyun Kwon, Minseo Kim, Young&#8208;Hun Jeong, Han Seul Kim, Alexander S. Ditter, David A. Shapiro, Young&#8208;Sang Yu, Yoo Sei Park, Dongju Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Spin&#8208;Polarized Nanosheet Array for Boosting Ampere&#8208;Level Water Oxidation Under Magnetic Field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420810</link>
      <description>Haifan Li, Quan Quan, Hongliang Dong, Yuxuan Zhang, Pengshan Xie, Dong Chen, Di Yin, Chun&#8208;Yuen Wong, Johnny C. Ho, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406126967

                Abstract The spin&#8208;polarization strategy by manipulating magnetic electrocatalysts can promote the spin&#8208;sensitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER) while developing efficient spin&#8208;polarized materials toward ampere&#8208;level OER is still challenging. Herein, a hierarchical inter&#8208;doped (Ru&#8208;Ni)O x nanosheet array in situ grown on nickel foam is designed, which exhibits a distinguished overpotential of 286 mV at 1 A cm &#8722;2 under 0.4 T magnetic field and a steady lifespan of 200 h at the ampere current density (i.e., 1 A cm &#8722;2 ), outperforming most reported state&#8208;of&#8208;art spin&#8208;selective OER catalysts in alkaline electrolytes Integrating intrinsic and interfacial spin&#8208;polarization on the inter&#8208;doped (Ru&#8208;Ni)O x nanosheet array can significantly boost the catalytic activity for ampere&#8208;level OER under a magnetic field. Specifically, the spin&#8208;aligned Ru sites optimize the rate&#8208;determined O&#9472;O coupling step to reduce the thermodynamic barrier of OER. Meanwhile, the charge transfer kinetics is promoted due to the accelerating spin&#8208;selective electron transfer via spin pinning at the ferromagnetic&#8208;antiferromagnetic interface. The design of a hierarchical spin&#8208;polarized structure that integrates intrinsic and interfacial spin&#8208;polarization strategies provides an additional route to developing a spin&#8208;polarized OER catalyst capable of serving ampere current densities.</description>
      <author>Haifan Li, Quan Quan, Hongliang Dong, Yuxuan Zhang, Pengshan Xie, Dong Chen, Di Yin, Chun&#8208;Yuen Wong, Johnny C. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202420810</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental and Modeling Study for the Solar-Driven CO2 Electrochemical Reduction to CO</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/app15020549</link>
      <description>Matteo Agliuzza, Roberto Speranza, Andrea Lamberti, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Adriano Sacco, Applied Sciences. 15(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406171439

                With the rising levels of atmospheric CO2, electrochemistry shows great promise in decarbonizing industrial processes by converting CO2 into valuable products through scalable and sustainable technologies. In this framework, the present study investigates the solar-driven CO2 reduction toward carbon monoxide, achieved by the integration between the electrochemical reactor and dye-sensitized solar cells (DSSCs), both in experimental and modeling perspectives. COMSOL&#174; Multiphysics 6.3 was used to develop a detailed finite element method model of the electrochemical cell integrated with a photovoltaic module, validated with the experimental results that demonstrated a strong correlation. A 2D model was designed, incorporating cathode and anode regions divided by an ion-exchange membrane. The model includes platinum foil and silver nanoparticles as catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction and CO2 reduction reaction, respectively. Integration with the fundamental equations of the DSSCs was simulated to analyze the solar-driven CO2 reduction behavior under solar irradiance variations, offering a valuable tool for optimizing operating conditions and predicting the device performance under different environmental conditions. The integrated device successfully produces CO with a faradaic efficiency of 73.85% at a current density of J = 3.35 mA/cm2 under 1 sun illumination, with the result validated and reproduced by the mathematical model. Under reduced illumination conditions of 0.8 and 0.6 suns, faradaic efficiencies of 68.5% and 64.1% were achieved, respectively.</description>
      <author>Matteo Agliuzza, Roberto Speranza, Andrea Lamberti, Candido Fabrizio Pirri, Adriano Sacco</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/app15020549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linkage Regulation of &#946;-Ketoamine Covalent Organic Frameworks for Boosting Photocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20472</link>
      <description>Yiwen Yang, Hong&#8208;Da Ren, Hanyu Zhang, Yingnan Zhao, Huaqiao Tan, Zhongling Lang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406134747

                Two dimensional &#946;-ketoamine covalent organic frameworks (2D TP-COFs) are one category of promising metal-free catalysts for photocatalytic overall water splitting (OWS) because of their unusual stability and versatile electronic/optical properties. However, none of the currently reported TP-COFs can accomplish the hydrogen evolution (HER) and oxygen evolution reactions (OER) simultaneously without adding any sacrificial agents and cocatalysts. To address this challenging issue, we rationally designed 23 2D TP-COFs by regulating the linkage groups and comprehensively evaluated their OWS activity by using the first-principles method. First, the electronic band structure calculations at the HSE06 level reveal that the band gap can be reasonably adjusted with values ranging from 1.67&#8211;3.16 eV. Among these 23 systems, 10 TP-COFs are realized to match well with both the chemical potentials of H2/H+ and O2/H2O, which are capable of visible-light-driven OWS from an electronic perspective. Further thermal activity results on OWS demonstrate that only Hep-BDA (heptazine-aniline) and Bpy-4 (bipyrimidinamine) based COFs can satisfy the completely spontaneous of HER and OER under light irradiation and neutral conditions. Importantly, the calculated small exciton binding energies and high carrier mobility for Hep-BDA and Bpy-4 TP-COFs propose they are potentially applied in photocatalytic OWS. We also achieved the theoretical energy conversion efficiency of Hep-BDA can reach as high as 13.01%. Because there are very few successful applications of TP-COFs on OWS, this theoretical work not only offers valuable insights and innovative ideas for the exploration of novel metal-free photocatalysts for OWS but also supplies a direction for the development of new TP-COF derivatives.</description>
      <author>Yiwen Yang, Hong&#8208;Da Ren, Hanyu Zhang, Yingnan Zhao, Huaqiao Tan, Zhongling Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling Nitrate&#8208;to&#8208;Ammonia Conversion and Sulfion Oxidation Reaction Over Hierarchical Porous Spinel MFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; (M&#9552;Ni, Co, Fe, Mn) in Wastewater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411317</link>
      <description>Junyang Ding, Lang Zhang, Zihao Wei, Zhifeng Wang, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Jun Luo, Xijun Liu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406127030

                Abstract The construction of coupled electrolysis systems utilizing renewable energy sources for electrocatalytic nitrate reduction and sulfion oxidation reactions (NO 3 RR and SOR), is considered a promising approach for environmental remediation, ammonia production, and sulfur recovery. Here, a simple chemical dealloying method is reported to fabricate a hierarchical porous multi&#8208;metallic spinel MFe 2 O 4 (M&#9552;Ni, Co, Fe, Mn) dual&#8208;functional electrocatalysts consisting of Mn&#8208;doped porous NiFe 2 O 4 /CoFe 2 O 4 heterostructure networks and Ni/Co/Mn co&#8208;doped Fe 3 O 4 nanosheet networks. The excellent NO 3 RR with high NH 3 Faradaic efficiency of 95.2% at &#8208;0.80 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs RHE) and NH 3 yield rate of 608.9 &#181;mol h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 at &#8722;1.60 V vs RHE, and impressive SOR performance (100 mA cm &#8722;2@0.98 V vs RHE) is achieved for MFe 2 O 4 . Key intermediates such as * NO, * NH 2 , and NH 3 are identified in the NO 3 RR process by in situ Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (in situ FTIR). The MFe 2 O 4 &#8208;assembled two&#8208;electrode coupling system (NO 3 RR||SOR) shows an ultra&#8208;low cell voltage of 1.14 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , much lower than the NO 3 RR||OER (oxygen evolution reaction, 10 mA cm &#8722;2@2.62 V), simultaneously achieving two expected targets of value&#8208;added ammonia generation and sulfur recovery, and also demonstrating high durability of 18 h. This work also demonstrates the great potential of spinel ferrite&#8208;based catalysts for environmental remediation.</description>
      <author>Junyang Ding, Lang Zhang, Zihao Wei, Zhifeng Wang, Qian Liu, Guangzhi Hu, Jun Luo, Xijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411317</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work-biased path-sampling calculations of chemical potentials: Principles and applications to uranium oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229575</link>
      <description>Orane Barbour, Jean-Paul Crocombette, Theo Beigbedder, Julien Tranchida, Manuel Ath&#232;nes, The Journal of Chemical Physics. 162(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406153043

                We present the work-biased path-sampling scheme to calculate chemical potentials in atomic scale simulations. This scheme is based on a series of chained insertion and deletion paths from N to N + 1 to N atom systems, the sampling being performed on the paths themselves rather than on the final configurations. Equations for parallel path generations as well as geometrically biased insertions or deletions are presented. We then present two applications of our approach for the uranium dioxide crystal. The first is a test case validation of our approach for the insertion of a Xe atom in UO2. The second explores the relationship between cluster structure stability and oxygen chemical potential in overstoichiometric UO2+x oxide as a function of temperature from 800 to 2000 K and composition, from UO2 to UO2.16, using two different empirical potentials. We find that the evolution of the oxygen chemical potential is irregular, with dips for specific numbers of added oxygen atoms. Five oxygen clusters are stable at 800 K and are associated with strong dips in the chemical potential values. At intermediate temperatures, clusters of four and five oxygen atoms compete in stability. They become unstable at the highest temperatures, and the evolution of the chemical potential is then monotonous with composition.</description>
      <author>Orane Barbour, Jean-Paul Crocombette, Theo Beigbedder, Julien Tranchida, Manuel Ath&#232;nes</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0229575</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cocktail Effect of 4&lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;/5&lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt; Band Twisted High&#8208;Entropy Alloys on Carbon Nanotube for Hydrazine Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410304</link>
      <description>Chae Eun Park, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, V. Maheskumar, Anuj Kumar, Gyoung Hwa Jeong, Myong Yong Choi, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406112406

                Herein, multi-walled carbon nanotubes (CNT) embedded with RuPdIrPtAu-high entropy alloys (HEA) via pulsed laser irradiation in liquids are successfully fabricated. The resultant composite synergistically enhances hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR)-boosted water electrolysis. Notably, HEA with &#8776;2-5 nm size, are uniformly distributed across the surface of the CNTs. An optimized HEA/CNT-10 demonstrates exceptional performance in oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions (OER and HER), depicted by ultralow overpotentials of 30.7 and 330 mV at 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Chae Eun Park, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, V. Maheskumar, Anuj Kumar, Gyoung Hwa Jeong, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410304</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the iodine cycle and the late stabilization of the Earth&#8217;s ozone layer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2412898121</link>
      <description>Jingjun Liu, Dalton Hardisty, James F. Kasting, Mojtaba Fakhraee, Noah J. Planavsky, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406110855

                The origin of complex life and the evolution of terrestrial ecosystems are fundamental aspects of the natural history on Earth. Here, we present evidence for a protracted stabilization of the Earth&#8217;s ozone layer. The destruction of atmospheric ozone today is inherently linked to the cycling of marine and atmospheric iodine. Supported by multiple independent lines of geological evidence and examined through an iodine mass balance model, we find that elevated marine iodide content prevailed through most of Earth&#8217;s history. Since the rise of oxygen ~2.4 billion years ago, high marine iodide concentrations would have led to significant inorganic iodine emissions to the atmosphere, facilitating catalytic ozone destruction and resulting in atmospheric ozone instability with periodic or persistently lower ozone levels. At a global scale, unstable and low ozone levels likely persisted for about two billion years until the early Phanerozoic, roughly 0.5 billion years ago. The delayed stabilization of the Earth&#8217;s ozone layer holds significant implications for the tempo and direction of the evolution of life, in particular life on land.</description>
      <author>Jingjun Liu, Dalton Hardisty, James F. Kasting, Mojtaba Fakhraee, Noah J. Planavsky</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2412898121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The value of returning a sample of the Martian atmosphere</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2404258121</link>
      <description>T. D. Swindle, Andreas Pack, S. P. Schwenzer, Edward Young, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences. 122(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406110845

                The elemental and isotopic abundances of major species in the Martian atmosphere have been determined, but analyses often lack sufficient precision, and those of minor and trace species are frequently not well known. Many important questions about the evolution and current state of Mars require the kind of knowledge that can be gained from analysis of a returned sample of the Martian atmosphere. Key target species include the noble gases, nitrogen, and various species containing carbon, hydrogen, and oxygen, such as methane. More detailed analyses will no doubt provide measurements of other species that will allow insights of their own. These volatiles can constrain the origin of the Martian atmosphere, exchange of volatiles between the surface and interior, polar processes, and (in the case of methane) the possibility of extant biology on Mars.</description>
      <author>T. D. Swindle, Andreas Pack, S. P. Schwenzer, Edward Young</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2404258121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of cancer cell volatile organic compounds: their metabolism and evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmolb.2024.1499104</link>
      <description>Takeshi Furuhashi, Kanako Toda, Wolfram Weckwerth, Frontiers in Molecular Biosciences. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406129860

                Cancer is ranked as the top cause of premature mortality. Volatile organic compounds (VOCs) are produced from catalytic peroxidation by reactive oxygen species (ROS) and have become a highly attractive non-invasive cancer screening approach. For future clinical applications, however, the correlation between cancer hallmarks and cancer-specific VOCs requires further study. This review discusses and compares cellular metabolism, signal transduction as well as mitochondrial metabolite translocation in view of cancer evolution and the basic biology of VOCs production. Certain cancerous characteristics as well as the origin of the ROS removal system date back to procaryotes and early eukaryotes and share commonalities with non-cancerous proliferative cells. This calls for future studies on metabolic cross talks and regulation of the VOCs production pathway.</description>
      <author>Takeshi Furuhashi, Kanako Toda, Wolfram Weckwerth</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmolb.2024.1499104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post&#8208;Degradation Recovery of CsPbI&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Quantum Dot Solar Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409709</link>
      <description>Julius Brunner, Angelika Wrzesi&#324;ska&#8208;Lashkova, Lucas Scalon, Robson Ferrari Muniz, Anatol Prudnikau, Darius Pohl, Markus L&#246;ffler, Fabian Paulus, Yana Vaynzof, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406226647

                Abstract The stability of perovskite quantum dot solar cells is one of the key challenges of this technology. This study reveals the unique degradation behavior of cesium lead triiodide (CsPbI 3 ) quantum dot solar cells. For the first time, it is shown that the oxygen&#8208;induced degradation and performance loss of CsPbI 3 quantum dot photovoltaic devices can be reversed by exposing the degraded samples to humidity, allowing the performance to recover and even surpass the initial performance. By careful characterization and analysis throughout the degradation and recovery process, the underlying physical and chemical mechanisms that govern the evolution of the device performance could be identified. It is shown that the ligand shell of the quantum dots, rather than the instability of the semiconducting material itself, is the driving factor in these mechanisms. This highlights the important role of surface chemistry and ligand design in enhancing perovskite quantum dot photovoltaics.</description>
      <author>Julius Brunner, Angelika Wrzesi&#324;ska&#8208;Lashkova, Lucas Scalon, Robson Ferrari Muniz, Anatol Prudnikau, Darius Pohl, Markus L&#246;ffler, Fabian Paulus, Yana Vaynzof</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Effect of Shape Anisotropy of Plasmonic Tungsten Oxide Nanostructures for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02233</link>
      <description>G. A. Davis, Brian C. Wyatt, Barry B. Muhoberac, Rajesh Sardar, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406094095

                Platinum is the most efficient electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER); however, the lack of earth abundance and high cost restrict its widespread use. Herein, we report electrocatalytic HER efficacy of oxygen-deficient, localized surface plasmon resonance (LSPR)-active tungsten-oxide (WO3&#8211;x) nanocrystals (NCs) as a function of free conduction electron density and metal oxidation states. These plasmonic, anisotropic WO3&#8211;x NCs display &#8764;160 mV overpotential at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and a Tafel slope of 54 mV/dec. Ultraviolet photoelectron spectroscopic measurements support the HER electrocatalytic properties attributed to the Fermi energy pinning as a function of the NC shape (i.e., nanowires, nanorods, and nanoplatelets) and chemical composition of the inorganic WO3&#8211;x lattice. Furthermore, our experimental data show that increasing the number of coordinatively unsaturated tungsten sites, which are generated from the ionization of surface oxygen atoms in WO3&#8211;x NCs, improves the surface reactivity and thus, enhances the catalytic performance. Together, structure&#8211;property relationship delineating the NC morphology and the resulting optoelectronic properties studied here provide the opportunity to unravel the correlation between the NC shape, free conduction electron density and the HER kinetics of this unique class of NC and to potentially initiate the designer principle of noble metal-free, highly active, but not limited to HER catalysts to produce an energy-dense fuel.</description>
      <author>G. A. Davis, Brian C. Wyatt, Barry B. Muhoberac, Rajesh Sardar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.4c02233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water or dry land &#8722; that is not a question for amphibious plant species</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/limn/2024025</link>
      <description>Mateja Germ, Alenka Gaber&#353;&#269;ik, International Journal of Limnology. 61(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406195203

                Amphibious plants attract much attention due to their unique ability to live in aquatic and terrestrial environments and sustain abrupt changes of water regime in the habitat. They may colonise habitats with pronounced water level fluctuations and water /dry land interface areas. Water and air differ in many aspects, like density, buoyancy, light and thermal conditions, as well as humidity and diffusion of gases, including oxygen and carbon dioxide, that all affect plant growth and development. The evolution of amphibious plant species resulted in high phenotypic plasticity that is manifested as a variety of ecophenes performing optimally in contrasting conditions. The most important adaptations are heterophylly and/or different life forms that differ at morphological, anatomical, biochemical, and physiological levels. These adaptations comprise the wide span of traits that are found in submerged and terrestrial plant species. The plasticity of amphibious plant species offers a potential to colonise water bodies where hydrology is affected by climate changes and present a unique model system where different scientific aspects of plants may be studied in genetically identical specimens.</description>
      <author>Mateja Germ, Alenka Gaber&#353;&#269;ik</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/limn/2024025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>C/O ratios in self-gravitating protoplanetary discs with dust evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1017/pasa.2024.126</link>
      <description>Tamara Molyarova, E. I. Vorobyov, Vitaly Akimkin, Publications of the Astronomical Society of Australia. 42(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406187615

                Abstract Elemental abundances, particularly the C/O ratio, are seen as a way to connect the composition of planetary atmospheres with planet formation scenario and the disc chemical environment. We model the chemical composition of gas and ices in a self-gravitating disc on timescales of 0.5 Myr since its formation to study the evolution of C/O ratio due to dust dynamics and growth and phase transitions of the volatile species. We use the thin-disc hydrodynamic code FEOSAD, which includes disc self-gravity, thermal balance, dust evolution, and turbulent diffusion, and treats dust as a dynamically different and evolving component interacting with the gas. It also describes freeze-out, sublimation, and advection of four most abundant volatile species: H $_2$ O, CO $_2$ , CH $_4$ , and CO. We demonstrate the effect of gas and dust substructures such as spirals and rings on the distribution of volatiles and C/O ratios, including the formation of multiple snowlines of one species, and point out the anticorrelation between dust-to-gas ratio and total C/O ratio emerging due to the contribution of oxygen-rich ice mantles. We identify time and spatial locations where two distinct trigger mechanisms for planet formation are operating and differentiate them by C/O ratio range: wide range of the C/O ratios of $0-1.4$ for streaming instability, and a much narrower range $0.3-0.6$ for gravitational instability (with the initial value of 0.34). This conclusion is corroborated by observations, showing that transiting exoplanets, which possibly experienced migration through a variety of disc conditions, have significantly larger spread of C/O in comparison with directly imaged exoplanets likely formed in gravitationally unstable outer disk regions. We show that the ice-phase $\textrm{C/O}\approx$ 0.2&#8211;0.3 between the CO, CO $_2$ , and CH $_4$ snowlines corresponds to the composition of the Solar system comets, that represent primordial planetesimals.</description>
      <author>Tamara Molyarova, E. I. Vorobyov, Vitaly Akimkin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1017/pasa.2024.126</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response Analysis of Microbial Community Structures and Functions Under Water and Sediment Changes in the Middle and Lower Yellow River</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/d17010041</link>
      <description>Ji Wu, Quan Hong, Jin Zhang, Chen Xie, Yang Liu, Dandan Li, Hao Liu, Ziwu Fan, Diversity. 17(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406119047

                Safety and ecological health are restricted by the high amount of suspended sediment in the Yellow River. To solve the problems of the high sediment content and siltation in the Yellow River, the Xiaolangdi Reservoir (XLDR) has been carrying out water&#8211;sediment regulation (WSR) since 2002. To clarify the effects of the water and sediment changes caused by WSR on microbial communities, we analysed the composition of the microbial communities and functional groups in surface water and sediments before and after WSR using high-throughput sequencing and microbial functional annotation. Proteobacteria, Actinobacteria, Bacteroidetes, and Firmicutes were detected as the main microbial communities in the Yellow River&#8217;s middle and lower reaches. The water temperature (WT), dissolved oxygen (DO), total nitrogen (TN), total phosphorus (TP), and evolution of the microbial communities were all correlated (p &lt; 0.05). The biodiversity indices of the surface water and sediment microbes, respectively, greatly declined. The WSR programme broke down nutrients that had been adsorbed on the sediments, which diminished microbial metabolic activity and impaired the water bodies&#8217; capacity to purify themselves. In summary, this study provides the biological information needed for the ecological conservation of the Yellow River basin, as well as insights into the changes in and response characteristics of microorganisms following severe disturbances in rivers with high sediment concentrations.</description>
      <author>Ji Wu, Quan Hong, Jin Zhang, Chen Xie, Yang Liu, Dandan Li, Hao Liu, Ziwu Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/d17010041</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for Accurate and Precise Stable Isotope Analysis of Calcite, Dolomite, and Magnesite Using a Carbonate Device for Continuous Flow&#8208;Isotope Ratio Mass Spectrometry (CF&#8208;IRMS)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/rcm.9958</link>
      <description>Soujung Kim, Sang&#8208;Tae Kim, Martin Knyf, Rapid Communications in Mass Spectrometry. 39(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406216816

                ABSTRACT Rationale Carbonate minerals are one of the most popular samples for an automated sample preparation system for CF&#8208;IRMS, such as GasBench II and iso FLOW, but no standardized analytical protocols exist. This study gives guidelines on optimal analytic conditions for carbon and oxygen isotope analysis of Ca&#8211;Mg carbonates when using the carbonate&#8211;phosphoric acid reaction method. Methods Calcite (CaCO 3 &#8211;McMaster Carrara), dolomite (CaMg(CO 3 ) 2 &#8211;MRSI Dolomite), and magnesite (MgCO 3 &#8211;ROM Brazil Magnesite) with two grain size fractions (&lt; 74 and 149&#8211;250 &#956;m) were reacted with 103% (specific gravity of 1.92) phosphoric acid under He atmosphere in 12&#8208;mL borosilicate glass vials to examine the full &#948; 13 C and &#948; 18 O evolution of acid&#8208;liberated CO 2 for an extended reaction time of up to 12&#8211;30 days at 25&#176;C and up to 3&#8211;7 days at 72&#176;C. Results At 25&#176;C, the optimal reaction time of calcite is 1 day for both grain size fractions while the optimal reaction time of 2&#8211;10 day is suggested for dolomite with a grain size of &lt; 74 &#956;m. At 72&#176;C, 30&#8208;min to 12&#8208;h or 45&#8208;min to 12&#8208;h reaction is optimal for calcite with &lt; 74&#8208;&#956;m or 149&#8208; to 250&#8208;&#956;m grain size fraction, respectively, whereas dolomite requires 12&#8208;h to 1&#8208;day reaction for both grain size fractions. The only optimal condition for magnesite is 6&#8211;7 days of reaction with &lt; 74&#8208;&#956;m grain size at 72&#176;C. Conclusions To determine precise and accurate &#948; 13 C and &#948; 18 O values of a carbonate mineral using the carbonate&#8211;phosphoric acid reaction method, an optimal reaction time must be assessed for a given analytical condition to avoid nonequilibrium isotope effects and unnecessary oxygen isotope exchange of acid&#8208;liberated CO 2 in the carbonate reaction vessel. Our experimental result provides a guideline for the accurate and precise stable isotope analysis of Ca&#8211;Mg carbonate minerals.</description>
      <author>Soujung Kim, Sang&#8208;Tae Kim, Martin Knyf</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/rcm.9958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving the mass transfer in the symbiotic recurrent nova T Coronae
  Borealis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.02984</link>
      <description>L. Planquart, A. Jorissen, H. Van Winckel, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406123341

                T Coronae Borealis (T CrB) is a symbiotic recurrent nova with an 80-year recurrence interval whose next eruption is imminent. We aim to resolve the accretion mechanism of the binary system governing the mass transfer during its super-active phase. Using phase-resolved high-resolution spectroscopy, we analyze the zoo of spectral-line profiles arising from the symbiotic activity. We perform Doppler tomography of selected emission lines to resolve the system's gaseous components and their different velocity regimes. We find evidence of enhanced accretion through Roche lobe overflow during the super-active phase, as traced by the oxygen, helium, and hydrogen lines. The accretion disc is found to be fully viscously evolved and extends up to its maximal radius. By mapping the kinematics of lines probing different excitation energies, we can identify distinct interaction sites. These include the bright spot at the stream impact on the accretion disc outer radius, the irradiation at the red-giant facing side, the stream-disc overflow, the accretion disk wind, and an expanding bipolar nebula. The bipolar jet emerged at the rise of the super-active phase and underwent an acceleration phase of about five years. The temporal evolution of the lines supports the scenario where the departure from quiescence started in the disc, likely triggered by a disc instability similar to what occurs in dwarf novae outburst, leading to an increased mass accretion and causing important irradiation of the giant that has further enhanced the mass-transfer rate during the super-active phase. Conclusions. Symbiotic recurrent novae, such as T CrB, are governed by similar mass-transfer mechanisms as found in cataclysmic variables despite their different orbital properties (longer orbital periods imposing larger accretion discs) and evolutionary pathways.</description>
      <author>L. Planquart, A. Jorissen, H. Van Winckel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2501.02984</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ambipolar doping of a charge-transfer insulator in the Emery model</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.045117</link>
      <description>G. Sordi, G. L. Reaney, Nicolas Kowalski, P. S&#233;mon, A.&#8211;M. S. Tremblay, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 111(4)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406142806

                Understanding the similarities and differences between adding or removing electrons from a charge-transfer insulator may provide insights about the origin of the electron-hole asymmetry found in cuprates. Here we study with cellular dynamical mean-field theory the Emery model set in the charge-transfer insulator regime, and dope it with either electrons or holes. We consider the normal state only and focus on the doping evolution of the orbital character of the dopants and on the nature of the doping-driven transition. Regarding the orbital character of the dopants, we found an electron-hole asymmetry: doped electrons mostly enter the copper orbitals, whereas doped holes mostly enter the oxygen orbitals. Regarding the nature of the doping-driven transition, we found no qualitative electron-hole asymmetry: On either electron or hole doping, there is a two-stage transition from a charge-transfer insulator to a strongly correlated pseudogap and then to a metal. This shows that a strongly correlated pseudogap is an emergent feature of doped correlated insulators in two dimensions, in qualitative agreement with recent experiments on ambipolar Sr1&#8722;xLaxCuO2+y cuprate films. Our results indicate that merely doping with holes or electrons a charge-transfer insulator is not sufficient for explaining the electron-hole asymmetry observed in the normal state phase diagram of cuprates. Our work reinforces the view that actual hole-doped cuprates are more correlated than their electron-doped counterparts. Published by the American Physical Society 2025</description>
      <author>G. Sordi, G. L. Reaney, Nicolas Kowalski, P. S&#233;mon, A.&#8211;M. S. Tremblay</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.111.045117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dangerous Area Evolution and Coal Spontaneous Combustion Prevention Method Induced by Air Leakage in Goaf of Ultra-Long Working Face</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00102202.2024.2448245</link>
      <description>Ma Li, Wenjun Zhang, Qingshan Zhao, Gaoming Wei, Ying Guo, Fang Lou, Shikui Jin, Longlong Tuo, Combustion Science and Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406070613

                Coal spontaneous combustion in goaf seriously affects the safety of mine production, and air leakage is one of the prerequisites for coal spontaneous combustion. Taking the ultra-long working face with a length of 410 m as an example, due to the insufficient compaction degree of the goaf, the high development of large-scale cracks, and the large air flow pressure difference between the intake and return air, the air leakage law in the goaf is not clear, and the risk of spontaneous combustion of broken residual coal increases. Based on the physical and mechanical parameters of coal rock, this paper studies the plastic failure and fracture development in the goaf under various stress disturbances in ultra-long working faces. The laws of gas migration and air leakage in goaf of ultra-long working face was studied by means of field test and numerical simulation. Based on the theory of coal-oxygen composite in goaf, the dangerous areas of coal spontaneous combustion in goaf with different mining sequence evolution of ultra-long working face were determined. Based on the distribution of air leakage flow field and coal spontaneous combustion danger zone in goaf, the comprehensive fire prevention and extinguishing technology of nitrogen injection inerting, plugging and leakage reduction was applied in field demonstration, and the application effect was verified. The research results show that the plastic failure range of overlying strata in goaf presents "saddle shape." The permeability and porosity increase gradually from the middle to the surrounding direction, showing "O-ring" distribution. The main air leakage channels are concentrated at the intake air tunnel corner of the goaf and 160&#8211;200 m of the working face. The air leakage sinks are located at a distance of 20&#8211;80 m along the dip direction of the working face and at the return corner of the working face, respectively. The average air leakage is 268 m3/min and 153 m3/min, and the maximum width of the coal spontaneous combustion danger zone in the goaf during the dynamic advancement of the ultra-long working face is 107 m. Through comprehensive fire prevention and extinguishing techniques such as nitrogen injection for inerting and filling with high-molecular-weight gel for sealing and leakage reduction, the prevention and control of coal spontaneous combustion in ultra-long working faces at different mining sequences under corresponding engineering backgrounds are effectively ensured.</description>
      <author>Ma Li, Wenjun Zhang, Qingshan Zhao, Gaoming Wei, Ying Guo, Fang Lou, Shikui Jin, Longlong Tuo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00102202.2024.2448245</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adaptation of global primary production model to the Greenland Sea conditions: parameterization and monitoring for 1998-2022</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1491180</link>
      <description>Alexandra Cherkasheva, Rustam Manurov, Piotr Kowalczuk, Alexandra Loginova, Monika Zab&#322;ocka, Astrid Bracher, Frontiers in Marine Science. 11(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406151632

                Phytoplankton are responsible for releasing half of the world&#8217;s oxygen and for removing large amounts of carbon dioxide from surface waters. Despite many studies on the topic conducted in the past decades, we are still far from a good understanding of ongoing rapid changes in the Arctic Ocean and how they will affect phytoplankton and the whole ecosystem. An example is the difference in net primary production modelling estimates, which differ twice globally and fifty times when only the Arctic region is considered. Here, we aim to improve the quality of Greenland Sea primary production estimates, by testing different versions of primary production model against in situ data and then calculating regional estimates and trends for 1998-2022 for those performing best. As a baseline, we chose the commonly used global primary production model and tested it with different combinations of empirical relationships and input data. Local empirical relationships were taken from measurements by the literature and derived from the unpublished data of Institute of Oceanology of Polish Academy of Sciences across the Fram Strait. For validation, we took historical net primary production 14 C data from literature and added to it our own gross primary production O 2 measurements. Field data showed good agreement between primary production measured with 14 C and O 2 evolution methods. From all the model setups, those including local chlorophyll a profile and local absorption spectrum best reproduced in situ data. Our modelled regional annual primary production estimates are equal to 346 TgC/year for the Nordic Seas region and 342 TgC/year for the Greenland Sea sector of the Arctic defined as 45&#176;W-15&#176;E, 66&#176;33&#8242;N-90&#176;N. These values are higher than those previously reported. Monthly values show a seasonal cycle with less monthly variability than previously reported. No significant increase or decrease in primary production was observed when studying regionally averaged trends. The accuracy of the selected here model setups to reproduce the field data in terms of Root Mean Square Difference is better than in the related Arctic studies. The improved primary production estimates strengthen researchers&#8217; ability to assess carbon flux and understand biogeochemical processes in the Greenland Sea.</description>
      <author>Alexandra Cherkasheva, Rustam Manurov, Piotr Kowalczuk, Alexandra Loginova, Monika Zab&#322;ocka, Astrid Bracher</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1491180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilization of Wearable Devices as means for Remote Digital Biometric Data Collection in a community&#8208;based, rural randomized controlled trial among Alzheimer&#8217;s disease dyads</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.090883</link>
      <description>Elizabeth K. Rhodus, Md. Saif Hassan Onim, Celeste Roberts, Sanjeev Kumar, Amer M. Burhan, Himanshu Thapliyal, Alzheimer s &amp; Dementia. 20(S2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406210955

                Abstract Background Use of remote measurement of physiological parameters using digital biometrics (i.e., Electro Dermal Activities, heart rate, oxygen saturation, blood volume pulse, etc.) has a multitude of opportunities in rural contexts that have not yet fully been explored in Alzheimer&#8217;s disease (AD) clinical research. This study assessed feasibility and acceptability of advanced digital biometric data collection among rural, community&#8208;dwelling adults living with Alzheimer&#8217;s disease with support from primary caregivers (dyad). Methods Initial feasibility and acceptability of a wrist&#8208;worn wearable device (Empatica E4) as means for digital biometric data collection were assessed among participants of a larger randomized controlled trial which was aimed to assess a non&#8208;pharmacological care intervention improving behavioral symptoms of AD. Following consent, dyads were mailed an E4 device and behavior tracking journal to companion digital recordings for one week of data collection. Caregivers assisted the person with AD in wear and care of the E4 device and completed time&#8208;stamped behavior tracking. Feasibility was assessed based on completeness of digital biometric data recordings and acceptability was determined based on wear schedules for the device in participants with AD (worn &gt;50% of allotted time). Results Digital biometric data collection via remote, wearable devices is feasible and acceptable among participants with AD in rural settings among 16 dyads (person with AD age x&#772;=77&#177;2.4 years, 10 female; caregiver age years x&#772;=57&#177;2.9 years, 8 female). The E4 correctly captured biometric signals (Electro Dermal Activities, blood volume pulse, Skin Temperature, etc.). The device was acceptable as 14 of the 16 participants with AD wore the device &gt;50% of allotted time with proper completion of the caregiver&#8208;reported behavior tracking. Further, we observed that unsupervised machine learning models were able to create digital biometrics that mirrored caregivers&#8217; notes. Conclusion Advances in technology, evolution of health status surveillance, and vast needs in rural areas create an ideal scenario to advance research in digital biometrics. With goals to use digital biometrics as primary outcome measures in AD clinical trials, the findings presented here illustrate feasibility and acceptability among geographically remote communities. Additional research is needed to assess context&#8208;aware machine learning applicability in intervention&#8208;based clinical research.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth K. Rhodus, Md. Saif Hassan Onim, Celeste Roberts, Sanjeev Kumar, Amer M. Burhan, Himanshu Thapliyal</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.090883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The ancestral architecture of the immune system in simplest animals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2024.1529836</link>
      <description>Daria Y. Romanova, Leonid L. Moroz, Frontiers in Immunology. 15(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406128604

                ~520 million years ago, the long biogeochemical history of our planet Earth resulted in a biodiversity burst. The rapid diversification of animals known as the Cambrian explosion (Mangano et al., 2014;Ahang et al., 2022;) transformed planetary ecosystems with novel habitats and food chains (Vannier et al., 2005(Vannier et al., ,2007)). However, this emergence of Paleozoic biodiversity (Harper et al., 2020) is still mysterious due to limited information about basal metazoans and their immune systems.The representatives of the phylum Placozoa with the simplest known body plan attract the attention of ecological physiologists seeking to understand integrative responses to environmental stress, often associated with climate changes, temperature, and oxygen levels, including complex symbiotic relationships over eons (Rognov, 2009;Sperling and Vinther, 2010;Spelling et al., 2013;Pruss and Gill, 2024). The simplicity of the cellular architecture in placozoans might correlate with a relatively small genome of 106 Mb (Srivastava et al., 2008). Placozoa do not have nervous and muscle systems or organs (Schulze, 1883;Rassat and Ruthmann, 1979;Malakhov, 1990;Smith et al., 2014). Still, these animals have an alternative integrating system of effector cells and a number of secretory cells that, by acting on the ciliated epithelium, control locomotion (Armon et al., 2018). In this architecture, the tetraploid fiber cell type, with a significantly high DNA context, is of utmost interest since these cells potentially perform three integrative functions (Behrendt and Ruthmann, 1986): (i) making a distributed functional network of the middle and epithelial layers (analogous to neurons), (ii) immune protection and growth control of endosymbiotic bacteria (immunity), and (iii) dynamic contractile functions (analogous to muscles) in responses to chemical environment and pH.The combination of all three functions within one cell type is relatively rare, even in other basal metazoan lineages such as comb jellies, sponges, and cnidarians. Here, we summarize the role of systemic and cellular functions as a unique window to illuminate the origins of immune architecture in early animals using a top-down approach, from organisms to cells to molecules, including novel insights into the critical master regulators of systemic immune responses.There is evidence for four distinct systemic immunity responses in Placozoa: (1) population aging, often associated with (2) infection; (3) resistance to radiation (next section); and (4) feeding, including interactions with pathogens and endosymbiosis. Below, we summarize the features of each of these responses.Population aging under long-term cultivation conditions is associated with various disease-like stages (Romanova et al., 2022). It includes the development of abnormal morphological changes (e.g., highly elongated body shapes) and the characteristic appearance of spherical formations on the upper epithelium with occasional rupture of the upper and middle layers. All of these can be reversed by fresh seawater and a dense substrate of microalgae as juvenilization (Romanova et al., 2022). The 'spheres' are analogs of the encapsulation of larger foreign objects for non-specific protection. If unfavored conditions are not changed, placozoan populations are transformed into the deterioration stage of irreversible spherical formations and death without a chance of recovery.Animals from the 'sick', with abundant spheres, population decrease locomotion and exploratory behaviors, as well as stop asexual reproduction. The 'spheres' with cavities consist of dorsal epithelium, fiber cells with multiple intracellular bacteria, and, probably, adjacent to the dorsal layer with 'shiny' cells containing large lipophilic inclusions with autofluorescent granules of unclear etiology but without bacteria (Romanova et al., 2022, Fig.7h-k). Animals can shed 'infected cells' encapsulated by the upper epithelium. Besides, there are morphological differences between the fiber cells of animals with endosymbionts (control) and ampicillin-treated animals (Romanova et al., 2022) without bacteria. This may indicate the ability to control the reproduction of bacterial endosymbionts by the complementary activation of phagocytosis and digest bacteria as a systemic innate immunity mechanism. Combined, this dynamic organismal-level architecture provided a landscape for exploring cellular and molecular innovations in the Placozoa lineage, potentially with cross-kingdom signaling between bacterial and their hosts.The process of shaping spherical formations involves the shiny cells of the upper epithelium (potentially releasing toxins (Jakson and Buss, 2009)) and the middle layer cells, represented by the fiber cells (Fig. 1A). The fiber cells represent the unique cell type associated with both integrative immune and feeding functions (Mayorova et al., 2021). The Gruber-Vodicka group (Berndt et al., 2024) showed multiple new organelles with lysozymes in Trichoplax -lysozymes as widespread components of metazoan immune and digestive enzymes (Mukherjee and Moroz, 2024). These enzymes provide antibacterial protection by hydrolyzing the peptide glycans of bacterial cell walls and participating in the digestion process. Interestingly, it was in the fiber cells that endosymbiotic Rickettsiales bacteria were originally found in H1 and H2 haplotypes (Driscoll et al., 2013;Kamm et al., 2019).Cellular immunity caused by phagocytosis (discovered by Metchnikov, 1892; Thiemann and Ruthmann, 1990) is the most ancient and common mechanism across eukaryotes; it includes chemotaxis, attachment of a foreign agent to the phagocyte membrane, and intracellular lysis. Chemoattractants can be signaling molecules from bacterial microorganisms, a change in the gradient of nitric oxide (NO) and related redox species (Moroz et al., 2020a), or a change in the amino acid composition (Moroz et al., 2020b). As a result of multifunctionality, fiber cell type is characterized by the presence of a massive mitochondrial cluster (Grell et al., 1991;Smith et al., 2014;Romanova et al., 2021), which may indicate high-energy costs for metabolic processes.In addition, fiber cells have exceptional intercellular contacts, found only in this cell type (Grell and Ruthman, 1991), which join all fiber cells into a network within the middle layer (Moroz and Romanova, 2022), and with multiple vesicles in the extracellular space (Moroz,Romanova,Kohn,2021). Thus, these are also neural-like cells that establish physiological connectivity from the middle to the dorsal layers (Moroz et al., 2021;Romanova et al., 2021;Moroz and Romanova, 2022). This 'network' can enable systemic immunity responses by immobilizing and consuming bacteria. Consequently, fiber cells are not fixed in their position and can be mobile as a result of chemoattraction, and be contractable.The Trichoplax ventral layer is formed by cell types with adherent junctions, which tightly hold cells facing biofilm substrates. The opposite is true for the dorsal layer, where the cells are elastic (Armon et al., 2018). Such epithelia are evolutionary innovative structures to protect early metazoans against bacterial infection as inherent parts of innate immunity system architectures.Opsonization, with the formation of distinct compartments, had been observed inside fiber cells (Romanova et al., 2021;Moroz et al., 2021;Romanova et al., 2022;Moroz and Romanova, 2022), and we detected bacteria in lysosomes. In some cases, bacterial cells were located in the perinuclear space (Romanova et al., 2021, Fig.5a), in close proximity to the cell nucleus. However, these are isolated cases with only 3-5% of the total number of fiber cells with bacteria. But the question remains openwhy do bacteria need such close proximity to the nucleus? Is this a metabolic symbiosis?MOLECULAR LEVEL OF IMMUNITY Distinctive insights into placozoan immunity were obtained by Fortunato et al. (2021), who exposed Trichoplax to a range of X-ray doses from 143.6 to 332.5 Gy. Surprisingly, placozoans can survive and restore their populations even after 218.6 Gy exposure with immune-related adaptive morphology -the appearance of spherical formations (Fortunato et al., 2021, Fig.3), which is similar to those shown in the description 'diseased' in animals (Romanova et al., 2022).Transcriptome analyses after 2 hrs of exposure of animals to a dose of 218.6 Gy revealed a cascade of inducible genes coupled with genome-wide immunity responses, including genes responsible for protection against double-strand breaks, such as RAD52, LIG4, DCLRE1C, RECQL5, XRCC6. Other radiation-induced genes (such as POLB, POLL and LIG3) also control various DNA repair mechanisms (Fortunato et al., 2021).Presumed immune regulatory gene networks of Toll-like receptors and scavenger receptors have been identified (Kamm et al., 2019). However, these authors did not find a homolog for the nuclear factor kappa B gene. In contrast, Porifera and Cnidaria have a complete homolog of the NF-&#954;B gene (Gauthier and Degnan, 2008;Song et al., 2012). It raises the question of whether placozoans have a highly modified/truncated NF-&#954;B (Kamm et al., 2019) or represent an ancestral stage before the acquisition of this transcription factor in immunity mechanisms.We performed a genome screening and found partial similarity of the human NF-&#954;B gene with the TriadITZ_000500 gene of the H1 haplotype with a large divergence between their sequences. AlphaFold2 reliably reconstructs the three-dimensional architecture of these protein orthologs across phyla. Intriguingly, both proteins from Placozoa and Chordata are mirror images of each other with preservation in Trichoplax all functional domains necessary for the activity of the NF-&#954;B (Fig. 1B). This finding illuminates the remarkable parallelism, modularity, and perhaps convergent evolution of immunity master regulators.What might be ancestral immunity architecture? Why does the simplest, a three-layer animal of one millimeter in size, employs the astonishing diversity of immune-related genes? Trichoplax genome encodes 5 genes of interleukins, 4 interferons, a number of immunoglobulins, two classes of the main histocompatibility complex, secretins, tetraspannins, and other genes necessary for intercellular information transmission from cell to cell, as in the canonical chordate immune system. According to single-cell transcriptomics (Sebe-Pedros et al., 2018), their expression is not cluster-specific, suggesting a broad distribution of innate immunity functions across cell populations in Placozoa.More likely, this situation reflects a great ancestral diversity of immune molecular toolkits as a result of a long history of holozoan-bacterial interactions. The early origins of multifunctional cell types with subsequent division of labor in large tetraploid fiber cells with elongated processes are morphologically and functionally similar to neurons and dendritic cells of the vertebrate immune system as well as muscle cells. These cells developed a powerful mitochondrial cluster and the largest nucleus among all Trichoplax cell types. Combined, these traits are associated with the omnipresence of bacteria both as food sources and pathogens with a dual role of bioenergetically demanding phagocytosis. Bacteria encapsulation might also be an ancestral immune strategy by making 'shells' of the 'friend-or-foe' recognition system with the recruitment of opsonin-like genes (Bang, 1975;Lackie, 1980;Bayne, 1990;Musser et al., 2021).Finally, fiber cells might be viewed as functional analogs of interneurons, with distributed connectivity and their localization uniting all cell layers.They forma highly distributed 'network' created by long processes of fiber cells for more efficient and rapid intercellular communications, integrating neural, hormonal, and contractive integrative systems. It would not be surprising if fiber cells were excitable with low-frequency oscillations (e.g., 100-150 ms) capable of secretion and chemical connectivity (Moroz et al., 2021).In sum, the multifunctionality of fiber cells can be the main operational module of the immune system for Placozoa and likely an example of exaptation for other emerging properties as dynamic links between immune and neural functions, which are responsible for organism-level integration. We would not be surprised if fiber cells could have epigenetic machinery for immune 'cellular memory' as the predecessor of acquired immunity.</description>
      <author>Daria Y. Romanova, Leonid L. Moroz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fimmu.2024.1529836</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
