<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:43:20 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Distance effect of single atoms on stability of cobalt oxide catalysts for acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46176-0</link>
      <description>Z. D. Zhang, Chuanyi Jia, Peiyu Ma, Feng Chen, Yang Jin, Jian Huang, Jian&#8208;Guo Zheng, Ming J. Zuo, Mingkai Liu, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392153698

                Abstract Developing efficient and economical electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE). Cobalt oxides are considered promising non-precious OER catalysts due to their high activities. However, the severe dissolution of Co atoms in acid media leads to the collapse of crystal structure, which impedes their application in PEMWE. Here, we report that introducing acid-resistant Ir single atoms into the lattice of spinel cobalt oxides can significantly suppress the Co dissolution and keep them highly stable during the acidic OER process. Combining theoretical and experimental studies, we reveal that the stabilizing effect induced by Ir heteroatoms exhibits a strong dependence on the distance of adjacent Ir single atoms, where the OER stability of cobalt oxides continuously improves with decreasing the distance. When the distance reduces to about 0.6 nm, the spinel cobalt oxides present no obvious degradation over a 60-h stability test for acidic OER, suggesting potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Z. D. Zhang, Chuanyi Jia, Peiyu Ma, Feng Chen, Yang Jin, Jian Huang, Jian&#8208;Guo Zheng, Ming J. Zuo, Mingkai Liu, Shiming Zhou, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-46176-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exfoliation of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks to Give 2D MOF Nanosheets for the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202402969</link>
      <description>Peng Wu, Shuang Geng, Xinyu Wang, Xinglong Zhang, Hongfeng Li, Lulu Zhang, Yu Shen, Baoli Zha, Suoying Zhang, Fengwei Huo, Weina Zhang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392156438

                The structure and properties of materials are determined by a diverse range of chemical bond formation and breaking mechanisms, which greatly motivates the development of selectively controlling the chemical bonds in order to achieve materials with specific characteristics. Here, an orientational intervening bond&#8208;breaking strategy is demonstrated for synthesizing ultrathin metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nanosheets through balancing the process of thermal decomposition and liquid nitrogen exfoliation. In such approach, proper thermal treatment can weaken the interlayer bond while maintaining the stability of the intralayer bond in the layered MOFs. And the following liquid nitrogen treatment results in significant deformation and stress in the layered MOFs&#8217; structure due to the instant temperature drop and drastic expansion of liquid N2, leading to the curling, detachment, and separation of the MOF layers. The produced MOF nanosheets with five cycles of treatment are primarily composed of nanosheets that are less than 10 nm in thickness. The MOF nanosheets exhibit enhanced catalytic performance in oxygen evolution reactions owing to the ultrathin thickness without capping agents which provide improved charge transfer efficiency and dense exposed active sites. This strategy underscores the significance of orientational intervention in chemical bonds to engineer innovative materials.</description>
      <author>Peng Wu, Shuang Geng, Xinyu Wang, Xinglong Zhang, Hongfeng Li, Lulu Zhang, Yu Shen, Baoli Zha, Suoying Zhang, Fengwei Huo, Weina Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202402969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exfoliation of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks to Give 2D MOF Nanosheets for the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202402969</link>
      <description>Peng Wu, Shuang Geng, Xinyu Wang, Xinglong Zhang, Hongfeng Li, Lulu Zhang, Yu Shen, Baoli Zha, Suoying Zhang, Fengwei Huo, Suoying Zhang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392166415

                The structure and properties of materials are determined by a diverse range of chemical bond formation and breaking mechanisms, which greatly motivates the development of selectively controlling the chemical bonds in order to achieve materials with specific characteristics. Here, an orientational intervening bond&#8208;breaking strategy is demonstrated for synthesizing ultrathin metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nanosheets through balancing the process of thermal decomposition and liquid nitrogen exfoliation. In such approach, proper thermal treatment can weaken the interlayer bond while maintaining the stability of the intralayer bond in the layered MOFs. And the following liquid nitrogen treatment results in significant deformation and stress in the layered MOFs&#8217; structure due to the instant temperature drop and drastic expansion of liquid N2, leading to the curling, detachment, and separation of the MOF layers. The produced MOF nanosheets with five cycles of treatment are primarily composed of nanosheets that are less than 10 nm in thickness. The MOF nanosheets exhibit enhanced catalytic performance in oxygen evolution reactions owing to the ultrathin thickness without capping agents which provide improved charge transfer efficiency and dense exposed active sites. This strategy underscores the significance of orientational intervention in chemical bonds to engineer innovative materials.</description>
      <author>Peng Wu, Shuang Geng, Xinyu Wang, Xinglong Zhang, Hongfeng Li, Lulu Zhang, Yu Shen, Baoli Zha, Suoying Zhang, Fengwei Huo, Suoying Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202402969</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural reconstruction of cobalt and ferrocene-based metal-organic framework during electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vlqz5</link>
      <description>Thomas Doughty, Andrea Zingl, Maximilian W&#252;nschek, Christian M. Pichler, Matthew Watkins, Souvik Roy, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392168646

                Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) are increasingly being investigated as electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their unique modular structures that present a hybrid between molecular and heterogeneous catalysts, featuring well-defined active sites. However, many fundamental questions remain open regarding the electrochemical stability of MOFs, structural reconstruction of coordination sites, and the role of in situ-formed species. Here we report structural transformation of a surface-grown MOF containing cobalt nodes and 1,1&#8217;-ferrocenedicarboxylic acid linkers (denoted as CoFc-MOF) during OER in alkaline electrolyte. Ex situ and in situ investigations of CoFc-MOF film suggests that the MOF acts as a pre-catalyst and undergoes a two-step restructuring process under operating conditions to generate a metal oxyhydroxide phase. The MOF-derived metal oxyhydroxide catalyst, supported on nickel foam electrodes, displays high activity towards OER with an overpotential of 190 mV at the current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2. While this study demonstrates the necessity of investigating structural evolution of MOFs in electrocatalysis, it also shows potential of using MOFs as precursors in catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Thomas Doughty, Andrea Zingl, Maximilian W&#252;nschek, Christian M. Pichler, Matthew Watkins, Souvik Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vlqz5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electroactive heterojunctions of iron-based compounds in oxygen evolution reaction &#8211; insight into synergy and mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144005</link>
      <description>Anna Dymerska, Ewa Mijowska, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Rustem Zairov, Ewa Mijowska, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392170706

                This research addresses the inherent challenges of low catalytic activity and stability often associated with Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) catalysts. We designed composites with outstanding electrocatalytic performance. The methodology is characterized by low-temperature operation and environmentally friendly substrates. We have successfully fostered a synergistic interplay between Fe and oxygen, carbon and nickel, respectively. Fabricated material composed of three different heterojunctions triggered the stability of the catalyst and facilitated efficient charge transfer in OER. Our optimized catalyst (Fe/Ni_3.0h), emerges as a promising candidate for practical applications, exhibiting an overpotential of 310 mV, a Tafel slope of 37 mV/dec, and a potential retention of 98.8% which is a 50% lower drop in respect to commercial RuO2. Therefore, our approach underlines the substantial influence of conductive Fe-based materials: FeNi3, Fe3C, and Fe3O4 on OER performance with revealed comprehensive mechanism via ex-situ XRD and M&#246;ssbauer spectroscopy analyses.</description>
      <author>Anna Dymerska, Ewa Mijowska, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Rustem Zairov, Ewa Mijowska</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface addition of Ag on PbO2 to enable efficient oxygen evolution reaction in pH-neutral media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150043</link>
      <description>Siming Li, Meng Shi, Chen Wu, Kaiqi Nie, Zheng Wang, Xiaoxu Jiang, Xinbing Liu, Huili Chen, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu, Siming Li, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392184832

                Electrocatalysts, particularly earth-abundant metal oxide ones, exhibit poor performance in catalyzing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under neutral conditions due to low ionic concentrations. This study introduces a novel strategy for fabricating a PbO2 + Ag composite electrode with significantly improved OER activity and stability in a pH-neutral environment. Our results suggest that incorporating Ag as a surface additive improves the efficiency of utilizing adsorbed oxygenated species via the bridge-site-top-site pathway. Moreover, the surface decoration of Ag resulted in enhanced electrocatalytic stability by diverting the attack of oxygenated species to Pb thereby effectively preventing Pb dissolution. The results not only establish a method for utilizing PbO2 in pH-neutral OER applications, but also propose a potential strategy for employing less noble catalysts in cost-effective electrochemical energy conversions.</description>
      <author>Siming Li, Meng Shi, Chen Wu, Kaiqi Nie, Zheng Wang, Xiaoxu Jiang, Xinbing Liu, Huili Chen, Xinlong Tian, Daoxiong Wu, Siming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Nanotube Composites with Bimetallic Transition Metal Selenides as Efficient Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/su16051953</link>
      <description>Saira Riaz, Muhammad Shafiq Anjum, Abid Ali, Yasir Mehmood, Muhammad Ahmad, Norah Alwadai, Munawar Iqbal, Salih Aky&#252;rekli, Noor Hassan, Rizwan Shoukat, Sustainability. 16(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392189844

                Hydrogen fuel is a clean and versatile energy carrier that can be used for various applications, including transportation, power generation, and industrial processes. Electrocatalytic water splitting could be the most beneficial and facile approach for producing hydrogen. In this work, transition metal selenide composites with carbon nanotubes (CNTs) have been investigated for electrocatalytic water splitting. The synthesis process involved the facile one-step hydrothermal growth of transition metal nanoparticles over the CNTs and acted as an efficient electrode toward electrochemical water splitting. Scanning electron microscopy and XRD patterns reveal that nanoparticles were firmly anchored on the CNTs, resulting in the formation of composites. The electrochemical measurements reveal that CNT composite with nickel&#8211;cobalt selenides (NiCo-Se/CNTs@NF) display remarkable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity in basic media, which is an important part of hydrogen production. It demonstrates the lowest overpotential (&#951;10mAcm&#8722;2) of 0.560 V vs. RHE, a reduced Tafel slope of 163 mV/dec, and lower charge transfer impedance for the OER process. The multi-metallic selenide composite with CNTs demonstrating unique nanostructure and synergistic effects offers a promising platform for enhancing electrocatalytic OER performance and opens up new avenues for efficient energy conversion and storage applications.</description>
      <author>Saira Riaz, Muhammad Shafiq Anjum, Abid Ali, Yasir Mehmood, Muhammad Ahmad, Norah Alwadai, Munawar Iqbal, Salih Aky&#252;rekli, Noor Hassan, Rizwan Shoukat</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/su16051953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasmall Ruthenium Nanoclusters Anchored on Thiol-Functionalized Metal&#8211;Organic Framework as a Catalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c06102</link>
      <description>Biswajit Mishra, Swayamprakash Biswal, Bijay P. Tripathi, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392191736

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Biswajit Mishra, Swayamprakash Biswal, Bijay P. Tripathi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c06102</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stability challenges and opportunities of NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.110</link>
      <description>Yujun Han, Jingyi Wang, Yuhang Liu, Tianqi Li, Tongzhou Wang, Xinyue Li, X. J. Ye, Guodong Li, Jihong Li, Wenbin Hu, Yida Deng, Carbon Neutralization. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392196226

                Abstract Water splitting is a critical process for the production of green hydrogen, contributing to the advancement of a circular economy. However, the application of water splitting devices on a large scale is primarily impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode. Thus, developing and designing efficient OER catalysts is a significant target. NiFe&#8208;based catalysts are extensively researched as excellent OER electrocatalysts due to their affordability, abundant reserves, and intrinsic activities. However, they still suffer from long&#8208;term stability challenges. To date, few systematic strategies for improving OER durability have been reported. In this review, various advanced NiFe&#8208;based catalysts are introduced. Moreover, the OER stability challenges of NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts in alkaline media, including iron segregation, structural degradation, and peeling from the substrate are summarized. More importantly, strategies to enhance OER stability are highlighted and opportunities are discussed to facilitate future stability studies for alkaline water electrolysis. This review presents a design strategy for NiFe&#8208;based electrocatalysts and anion exchange membrane (AEM) electrolyzers to overcome stability challenges in OER, which also emphasizes the importance of long&#8208;term stability in alkaline media and its significance for achieving large&#8208;scale commercialization.</description>
      <author>Yujun Han, Jingyi Wang, Yuhang Liu, Tianqi Li, Tongzhou Wang, Xinyue Li, X. J. Ye, Guodong Li, Jihong Li, Wenbin Hu, Yida Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnl2.110</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyridine caused structural reconfiguration forming ultrathin 2D metal-organic frameworks for oxygen evolution reaction.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta08079j</link>
      <description>Liusi Yang, Shuwei Deng, Shenyuan Fu, Xiaoteng Wang, Gang Liu, Haidong Yang, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392205602

                Two-dimensional metal-organic frameworks (2D MOFs) as an ideal prototype material for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) can expose more metal active sites due to their ultrathin 2D structure. Herein, a...</description>
      <author>Liusi Yang, Shuwei Deng, Shenyuan Fu, Xiaoteng Wang, Gang Liu, Haidong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta08079j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction on iridium-molybdenum mixed oxide electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4392181502</link>
      <description>C&#233;dric Tard, Marine Elmaalouf, Silvia Dur&#225;n, Mateusz Odziomek, Marco Faustini, C&#233;dric Boissi&#232;re, Marion Giraud, Jennifer P&#233;ron, No host. None(None)] 2019. https://openalex.org/W4392181502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>C&#233;dric Tard, Marine Elmaalouf, Silvia Dur&#225;n, Mateusz Odziomek, Marco Faustini, C&#233;dric Boissi&#232;re, Marion Giraud, Jennifer P&#233;ron</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4392181502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The behaviors of electrochemical oxygen intercalation of some oxygen-deficient ferrites and physical properties of perovskite Sr2LaFe3O8.95 prepared by electrochemical oxidation</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4392225188</link>
      <description>Fang Zhou, No host. None(None)] 1997. https://openalex.org/W4392225188

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 1997 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4392225188</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocomposites of Carbon for Metal-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-99-9931-6_7</link>
      <description>Kriti Shrivastava, Ankur Jain, Engineering materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392207371

                Extensive studies are being made on clean and sustainable energy conversion technologies to harness their potential in terms of great efficiency, large-scale uses, and negligible greenhouse gas emissions including fuel cells, metal-air batteries, and water-splitting techniques. Among them all, metal-air batteries are the most promising systems for portable electronic devices, electrical vehicles, and stationary microgrid applications due to their high energy density. However, the major limitation is the fundamental issues with their mechanism. The efficiency of energy conversion and storage is controlled by the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which are generally very slow and require noble metal catalysts for fast operation. The high cost and limited availability of noble metals caused a growing interest in developing metal-free carbons as a novel class of bifunctional electrocatalysts. These materials display exceptional strength, stability, conductivity, large surface area, and high stability in both acidic and alkaline environments and therefore can play a significant role in the field of clean energy storage/conversion technologies. In this chapter, the recent advances regarding the rational design of carbon-based electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction are summarized, with a special focus on their applications in Zn&#8211;air and Li&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Kriti Shrivastava, Ankur Jain</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-99-9931-6_7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A new Co-doped PbO2 anode for copper electrowinning: Electrochemical and morphological characterization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.111053</link>
      <description>Rasoul Rezaei, K. Jafarzadeh, S.M. Mirali, hadiseh mazhari abbasi, Journal of Energy Storage. 85(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392180202

                Anodic electrodeposition was used to create a high catalytic activity Co-doped PbO2 composite coating on Ti substrate, in order to reduce the overpotential and raising the electrocatalytic activity for oxygen evolution during the copper electrowinning process. The temperature, composition, and current density of the electrolyte were investigated in order to produce a composite anode with the best electrocatalytic behavior, stability, and efficiency in the electrowinning process. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) was utilized to investigate the morphology of the coating, and electrowinning, cyclic voltammetry (CV), and the accelerated life time test (ALT) were employed to evaluate the electrodes' electrochemical behavior. The ideal conditions in this investigation involved 65 g.L&#8722;1 cobalt nitrate with a 5 mA.cm&#8722;2 current density at 65 &#176;C for the electrodeposition of Co-doped PbO2 coating. Furthermore, the potential for oxygen evolution of the PbO2-CoOx anode was found to be approximately 180 and 220 mV lower than that of the PbO2 and Pb-Ca-Sn anodes, respectively, based on the results of the electrochemical test. The ALT test results showed that the PbO2-CoOx anode had a significantly lower initial cell voltage than the Pb-Ca-Sn and PbO2 anodes; however, this value increased after 165 h due to the anode's mechanical breakdown. The results showed that Cu electrowinning efficiency for Pb-Ca-Sn, PbO2, and PbO2-CoOx was 91.9 %, 98.4 %, and 100 % respectively.</description>
      <author>Rasoul Rezaei, K. Jafarzadeh, S.M. Mirali, hadiseh mazhari abbasi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.111053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual-site segmentally synergistic catalysis mechanism: boosting CoFeSx nanocluster for sustainable water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45700-6</link>
      <description>Siran Xu, Sihua Feng, Yue Yu, Dongping Xue, Mengli Liu, Chao Wang, Kaiyue Zhao, Bingjun Xu, Jianan Zhang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392165142

                Abstract Efficient oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts are essential for sustainable clean energy conversion. However, catalytic materials followed the conventional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) with the inherent scaling relationship between key oxygen intermediates *OOH and *OH, or the lattice-oxygen-mediated mechanism (LOM) with the possible lattice oxygen migration and structural reconstruction, which are not favorable to the balance between high activity and stability. Herein, we propose an unconventional Co-Fe dual-site segmentally synergistic mechanism (DSSM) for single-domain ferromagnetic catalyst CoFeS x nanoclusters on carbon nanotubes (CNT) (CFS-ACs/CNT), which can effectively break the scaling relationship without sacrificing stability. Co 3+ (L.S, t 2g 6 e g 0 ) supplies the strongest OH* adsorption energy, while Fe 3+ (M.S, t 2g 4 e g 1 ) exposes strong O* adsorption. These dual-sites synergistically produce of Co-O-O-Fe intermediates, thereby accelerating the release of triplet-state oxygen ( &#8593; O = O &#8593; ). As predicted, the prepared CFS-ACs/CNT catalyst exhibits less overpotential than that of commercial IrO 2 , as well as approximately 633 h of stability without significant potential loss.</description>
      <author>Siran Xu, Sihua Feng, Yue Yu, Dongping Xue, Mengli Liu, Chao Wang, Kaiyue Zhao, Bingjun Xu, Jianan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45700-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe, N&#8208;Inducing Interfacial Electron Redistribution in NiCo Spinel on Biomass&#8208;Derived Carbon for Bi&#8208;functional Oxygen Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202319983</link>
      <description>Yanyan Liu, Limin Zhou, Shilin Liu, Shu-Qi Li, Jingjing Zhou, Xin Li, Xiangmeng Chen, Kang Sun, Baojun Li, Jianchun Jiang, Huan Pang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392164726

                Herein, an interfacial electron redistribution is proposed to boost the activity of carbon&#8208;supported spinel NiCo2O4 catalyst toward oxygen conversion via Fe, N&#8208;doping strategy. Fe&#8208;doping into octahedron induces a redistribution of electrons between Co and Ni atoms on NiCo1.8Fe0.2O4@N&#8208;carbon. The increased electron density of Co promotes the coordination of water to Co sites and further dissociation. The generation of proton from water improves the overall activity for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The increased electron density of Ni facilitates the generation of oxygen vacancies. The Ni&#8208;VO&#8208;Fe structure accelerates the deprotonation of *OOH to improve the activity toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER). N&#8208;doping modulates the electron density of carbon to form active sites for the adsorption and protonation of oxygen species. Fir wood&#8208;derived carbon endows catalyst with an integral structure to enable outstanding electrocatalytic performance. The NiCo1.8Fe0.2O4@N&#8208;carbon express high half&#8208;wave potential up to 0.86 V in ORR and low overpotential of 270 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in OER. The zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) assembled with the as&#8208;prepared catalyst achieve long&#8208;term cycle stability (over 2000 cycles) with peak power density (180 mW cm&#8208;2). Fe, N&#8208;doping strategy drives the catalysis of biomass&#8208;derived carbon&#8208;based catalysts to the highest level for the oxygen conversion in ZABs.</description>
      <author>Yanyan Liu, Limin Zhou, Shilin Liu, Shu-Qi Li, Jingjing Zhou, Xin Li, Xiangmeng Chen, Kang Sun, Baojun Li, Jianchun Jiang, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202319983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe, N&#8208;Inducing Interfacial Electron Redistribution in NiCo Spinel on Biomass&#8208;Derived Carbon for Bi&#8208;functional Oxygen Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202319983</link>
      <description>Yanyan Liu, Limin Zhou, Shilin Liu, Shu-Qi Li, Jingjing Zhou, Xin Li, Xiangmeng Chen, Kang Sun, Baojun Li, Jianchun Jiang, Huan Pang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392160710

                Herein, an interfacial electron redistribution is proposed to boost the activity of carbon&#8208;supported spinel NiCo2O4 catalyst toward oxygen conversion via Fe, N&#8208;doping strategy. Fe&#8208;doping into octahedron induces a redistribution of electrons between Co and Ni atoms on NiCo1.8Fe0.2O4@N&#8208;carbon. The increased electron density of Co promotes the coordination of water to Co sites and further dissociation. The generation of proton from water improves the overall activity for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). The increased electron density of Ni facilitates the generation of oxygen vacancies. The Ni&#8208;VO&#8208;Fe structure accelerates the deprotonation of *OOH to improve the activity toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER). N&#8208;doping modulates the electron density of carbon to form active sites for the adsorption and protonation of oxygen species. Fir wood&#8208;derived carbon endows catalyst with an integral structure to enable outstanding electrocatalytic performance. The NiCo1.8Fe0.2O4@N&#8208;carbon express high half&#8208;wave potential up to 0.86 V in ORR and low overpotential of 270 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 in OER. The zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) assembled with the as&#8208;prepared catalyst achieve long&#8208;term cycle stability (over 2000 cycles) with peak power density (180 mW cm&#8208;2). Fe, N&#8208;doping strategy drives the catalysis of biomass&#8208;derived carbon&#8208;based catalysts to the highest level for the oxygen conversion in ZABs.</description>
      <author>Yanyan Liu, Limin Zhou, Shilin Liu, Shu-Qi Li, Jingjing Zhou, Xin Li, Xiangmeng Chen, Kang Sun, Baojun Li, Jianchun Jiang, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202319983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An NiFeSn Oxyhydroxide Electrocatalyst Wet Gel for Highly Efficient Water Electrolysis in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109428</link>
      <description>Taehee Kim, Hwapyung Jung, Hee Young Choi, Donghyeon Kang, Wonjun Lee, Vinayak G. Parale, Umakant M. Patil, Younghun Kim, J. S. Kim, Sang-Hyun Kim, Sang Woo Kim, Kazuyoshi Kanamori, Hyung Ho Park, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392184869

                Since the kinetic barrier posed by the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a significant obstacle in water-splitting systems, the creation of effective and inexpensive OER electrocatalysts has received considerable research interest. We report the facile synthesis of an amorphized NiFeSn oxyhydroxide wet gel on Ni foam via a gelation-induced embedding method. Its intrinsic pore structure provided a sufficiently large surface area without the need for a binder. The NiFeSn oxyhydroxide wet-gel electrocatalyst only needed overpotentials of 253, 301, and 346 mV to produce 100, 200, and 300 mA&#183;cm-2, respectively, for the OER and an overpotential value of 198 mV at 50 mA&#183;cm-2 for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Moreover, an exceptionally low voltage of 1.55 V was required for overall water splitting under alkaline conditions. Enhancement of the catalytic properties of the oxyhydroxide by adding Sn was confirmed by using density functional theory calculations. The nanoporous multi-metallic wet gel can be used to create effective low-cost stable self-supporting electrocatalysts with a high current density for enhanced water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Taehee Kim, Hwapyung Jung, Hee Young Choi, Donghyeon Kang, Wonjun Lee, Vinayak G. Parale, Umakant M. Patil, Younghun Kim, J. S. Kim, Sang-Hyun Kim, Sang Woo Kim, Kazuyoshi Kanamori, Hyung Ho Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109428</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting overall saline water splitting by constructing a strain&#8208;engineered high&#8208;entropy electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.519</link>
      <description>Ateer Bao, Yaohang Gu, Yuxuan Zhang, Bowen Zhang, Juncheng Wu, Bo Niu, Xiaoyan Zhang, Haijun Pan, Xiwei Qi, Carbon energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392199493

                Abstract High&#8208;entropy materials (HEMs), which are newly manufactured compounds that contain five or more metal cations, can be a platform with desired properties, including improved electrocatalytic performance owing to the inherent complexity. Here, a strain engineering methodology is proposed to design transition&#8208;metal&#8208;based HEM by Li manipulation (LiTM) with tunable lattice strain, thus tailoring the electronic structure and boosting electrocatalytic performance. As confirmed by the experiments and calculation results, tensile strain in the LiTM after Li manipulation can optimize the d &#8208;band center and increase the electrical conductivity. Accordingly, the as&#8208;prepared LiTM&#8208;25 demonstrates optimized oxygen evolution reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction activity in alkaline saline water, requiring ultralow overpotentials of 265 and 42 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. More strikingly, LiTM&#8208;25 retains 94.6% activity after 80 h of a durability test when assembled as an anion&#8208;exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Finally, in order to show the general efficacy of strain engineering, we incorporate Li into electrocatalysts with higher entropies as well.</description>
      <author>Ateer Bao, Yaohang Gu, Yuxuan Zhang, Bowen Zhang, Juncheng Wu, Bo Niu, Xiaoyan Zhang, Haijun Pan, Xiwei Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.519</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-Engineered Vanadium Doped NiS Catalyst for Efficient Electrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-99-9009-2_21</link>
      <description>Chandra Prakash, Priyambada Sahoo, Vijay Kumar Singh, Ambesh Dixit, Advances in sustainability science and technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392173137

                In this work, we demonstrate a single step hydrothermally grown nanorod shaped pristine and Vanadium (V) doped NiS on highly porous nickel foam substrate, i.e., NiS@NF and V-NiS@NF. A detailed electrochemical analysis, in terms of hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and Tafel slope, suggests that V doping enhances the electrocatalytic activity of NiS@NF for water splitting. V-NiS@NF delivered 172 mV HER and 310 mV OER overpotentials at current densities of 10 mA/cm2 and 50 mA/cm2, respectively. The Tafel slope values for HER and OER of V-NiS@NF are 45 mV/dec and 25 mV/dec, respectively. The better electrocatalytic performance of V-NiS@NF as compared to the NiS@NF was attributed to the matching of the atomic radius and deformation of the electronic structure of the pristine NiS@NF resulting in higher active sites. Due to the bifunctional nature with moderate HER/OER overpotentials and ease of synthesis, the present electrocatalyst V-NiS@NF can be used to develop an efficient electrolyzer for green hydrogen generation through water splitting.</description>
      <author>Chandra Prakash, Priyambada Sahoo, Vijay Kumar Singh, Ambesh Dixit</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-99-9009-2_21</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ construction of cation vacancies in amphoteric-metallic element-doped NiFe-LDH as ultrastable and efficient alkaline hydrogen evolution electrocatalysts at 1000 mA cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.184</link>
      <description>Q J Liu, Kaisheng Chen, Min Wang, Haibo Fan, Zihao Yan, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Yongjun Chen, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392203793

                Developing efficient and stable electrocatalysts at affordable costs is very important for large-scale production of green hydrogen. In this study, unique amphoteric metallic element-doped NiFe-LDH nanosheet arrays (NiFeCd-LDH, NiFeZn-LDH and NiFeAl-LDH) using as high-performance bifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) were reported, by tuning electronic structure and vacancy engineering. It was found that NiFeCd-LDH possesses the lowest overpotentials of 85 mV and 240 mV (at 10 mA cm-2) for HER and OER, respectively. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal the synergistic effect of Cd vacancies and Cd doping on improving alkaline HER performance, which promote the achievement of excellent catalytic activity and ultrastable hydrogen production at a large current density of 1000 mA cm-2 within 270 hours. Besides, the overall water splitting performance of the as-prepared NiFeCd-LDH requires only 1.580 V to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm-2 in alkaline seawater media, underscoring the importance of modifying the electronic properties of LDH for efficient overall water splitting in both alkaline water/seawater environments.</description>
      <author>Q J Liu, Kaisheng Chen, Min Wang, Haibo Fan, Zihao Yan, Xi&#8208;Wen Du, Yongjun Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.02.184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Water Oxidation Kinetics by Modulating Spin Alignment through Non-metal Vacancy Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03125</link>
      <description>Jianyong Lou, Junhui Liang, Xin Yao, Ma Hong, Yiqing Zhang, Huayu Chen, Laishun Qin, Yuexiang Huang, Ying Zhao, Da Chen, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392185671

                The efficiency of water splitting is primarily hampered by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Recently, increasing attention has been drawn to leverage spin polarization under an external magnetic field. However, the application of a magnetic field requires additional energy consumption and poses design challenges. Herein, we propose a simple defect engineering strategy aimed at aligning spins in paramagnetic materials to achieve an enhanced intrinsic OER activity. The hydrogenated NiFeP with P vacancies demonstrates elevated saturation magnetization (MS) and reduced overpotential (MS = 5.8 emu/mg, &#951;10 = 303 mV) compared to the untreated NiFeP sample (MS = 1.2 emu/mg, &#951;10 = 341 mV). We elucidate the underlying mechanism of the spin magnetic effect on the OER performance and provide insights into the intricate relationship among vacancies, saturation magnetization, spin state alignment, and oxygenated intermediates. These insights contribute to a better understanding and design of catalysts at the spintronic level, paving the way for more efficient water splitting processes.</description>
      <author>Jianyong Lou, Junhui Liang, Xin Yao, Ma Hong, Yiqing Zhang, Huayu Chen, Laishun Qin, Yuexiang Huang, Ying Zhao, Da Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03125</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A universal and scalable transformation of bulk metals into single-atom catalysts in ionic liquids</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2319136121</link>
      <description>Shujuan Wang, Ming&#8208;Hui Lu, Xuewen Xia, Fei Wang, Xiaolu Xiong, Kai Ding, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Qian Xu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Hujun Shen, Ji Li, Yufeng Zhao, Jing Wang, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392157760

                Single-atom catalysts (SACs) with maximized metal atom utilization and intriguing properties are of utmost importance for energy conversion and catalysis science. However, the lack of a straightforward and scalable synthesis strategy of SACs on diverse support materials remains the bottleneck for their large-scale industrial applications. Herein, we report a general approach to directly transform bulk metals into single atoms through the precise control of the electrodissolution&#8211;electrodeposition kinetics in ionic liquids and demonstrate the successful applicability of up to twenty different monometallic SACs and one multimetallic SAC with five distinct elements. As a case study, the atomically dispersed Pt was electrodeposited onto Ni 3 N/Ni-Co-graphene oxide heterostructures in varied scales (up to 5 cm &#215; 5 cm) as bifunctional catalysts with the electronic metal&#8211;support interaction, which exhibits low overpotentials at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER, 30 mV) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER, 263 mV) with a relatively low Pt loading (0.98 wt%). This work provides a simple and practical route for large-scale synthesis of various SACs with favorable catalytic properties on diversified supports using alternative ionic liquids and inspires the methodology on precise synthesis of multimetallic single-atom materials with tunable compositions.</description>
      <author>Shujuan Wang, Ming&#8208;Hui Lu, Xuewen Xia, Fei Wang, Xiaolu Xiong, Kai Ding, Zhongya Pang, Guangshi Li, Qian Xu, Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Hujun Shen, Ji Li, Yufeng Zhao, Jing Wang, Xingli Zou, Xionggang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2319136121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel mixed heterovalent (Mo/Co)Ox-zerovalent Cu system as bi-functional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-54934-9</link>
      <description>Ahmed R. Tartour, Moustafa M.S. Sanad, Ibrahim S. El-Hallag, Y. I. Moharram, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392159375

                Abstract A novel hybrid ternary metallic electrocatalyst of amorphous Mo/Co oxides and crystallized Cu metal was deposited over Ni foam using a one-pot, simple, and scalable solvothermal technique. The chemical structure of the prepared ternary electrocatalyst was systematically characterized and confirmed via XRD, FTIR, EDS, and XPS analysis techniques. FESEM images of (Mo/Co)O x &#8211;Cu@NF display the formation of 3D hierarchical structure with a particle size range of 3&#8211;5 &#181;m. The developed (Mo/Co)O x &#8211;Cu@NF ternary electrocatalyst exhibits the maximum activity with 188 mV and 410 mV overpotentials at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), respectively. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) results for the (Mo/Co)O x &#8211;Cu@NF sample demonstrate the minimum charge transfer resistance (R ct ) and maximum constant phase element (CPE) values. A two-electrode cell based on the ternary electrocatalyst just needs a voltage of about 1.86 V at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 for overall water splitting (OWS). The electrocatalyst shows satisfactory durability during the OWS for 24 h at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with an increase of only 33 mV in the cell potential.</description>
      <author>Ahmed R. Tartour, Moustafa M.S. Sanad, Ibrahim S. El-Hallag, Y. I. Moharram</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-54934-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel molybdenum selenide on carbon cloth as an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst for alkaline seawater splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131251</link>
      <description>Mohammad Saquib, Pratham Arora, Amit C. Bhosale, Fuel. 365(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392180320

                Exploring cost-effective and highly efficient electrocatalysts is desirable for the overall water-splitting challenge. In this work, a promising bifunctional electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution and hydrogen evolution reactions (OER/HER) in an alkaline medium (1 M KOH) and simulated alkaline seawater (1 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl) was rationally developed by a simple, one-step, inexpensive, and eco-friendly method. Mo-doped nickel selenide supported on activated carbon cloth (NiMoSe@CC) was successfully synthesized via a hydrothermal method. NiMoSe nanoparticles were observed to be densely grown with better uniformity on the carbon fibers, as confirmed by different characterization techniques. The NiMoSe@CC showed an enhanced OER activity with a low overpotential of 320 mV (alkaline medium) and 360 mV (alkaline seawater) at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. The HER performance of the NiMoSe@CC was also the highest amongst NiMoSe, NiSe@CC, and MoSe@CC in both the alkaline and seawater environments. In addition, NiMoSe@CC bears a high electrochemically active surface area, low charge transfer resistance of 1.77 &#937;, and high stability for both OER and HER. The NiMoSe@CC//NiMoSe@CC system was stable for 5000 LSV cycles with &#951;10 values of 1.63 V (1st LSV cycle) and 1.71 V (5000th LSV cycle).</description>
      <author>Mohammad Saquib, Pratham Arora, Amit C. Bhosale</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of the oxyl&#8217;s potential energy surface by the spectral kinetics of a vibrational mode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-dx2nv</link>
      <description>Tanja Cuk, James J. P. Stewart, Paul Zayka, Christen Courter, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392167066

                One of the most reactive intermediates for oxidative reactions is the oxyl radical, an electron-deficient oxygen atom. The discovery of a new vibration upon photoexcitation of the oxygen evolution catalysis detected the oxyl radical at the SrTiO3 surface. The vibration was assigned to a motion of the sub-surface oxygen underneath the titanium oxyl (Ti-O&#183;-), created upon hole transfer to (or electron extraction from) a hydroxylated surface site. Evidence for such an interfacial mode derived from its spectral shape which exhibited a Fano resonance&#8212;a coupling of a sharp normal mode to continu-um excitations. Here, this Fano resonance is utilized to derive precise formation kinetics of the oxyl radical and its associ-ated potential energy surface (PES). From the Fano lineshape, the formation kinetics are obtained from the anti-resonance (the kinetics of the coupling factor), the resonance (the kinetics of the coupled continuum excitations), and the frequency integrated spectrum (the kinetics of the normal mode&#8217;s cross-section). All three perspectives yield a logistic function growth with a half-rise of 2.3 &#177; 0.3 ps and rate of 0.48 &#177; 0.09 ps. A non-equilibrium transient associated with photoexcitation is separated from the rise of the equilibrated PES. The logistic function characterizes the oxyl coverage at the very initial stages (t~0) to have an exponential growth rate that quickly decreases towards zero as a limiting coverage is reached. Such time-dependent reaction kinetics identify a dynamic activation barrier associated with the formation of a PES and quantify it for an oxyl radical coverage.</description>
      <author>Tanja Cuk, James J. P. Stewart, Paul Zayka, Christen Courter</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-dx2nv</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
