<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 01:20:10 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the Electronic Properties of an Fe Single Atom Catalyst via Secondary Coordination Sphere Engineering to Provide Enhanced Oxygen Electrocatalytic Activity in Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202410121</link>
      <description>Siqi Ji, Yimin Mou, Hongxue Liu, Xue Lu, Qian Zhang, Chunmin Guo, Kai Sun, Dong Liu, J. Hugh Horton, Li Wang, Yu Wang, Zhijun Li, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402555445

                Oxygen reduction and evolution reactions are two key processes in electrochemical energy conversion technologies. Synthesis of nonprecious metal, carbon-based electrocatalysts with high oxygen bifunctional activity and stability is a crucial, yet challenging step to achieving electrochemical energy conversion. Here, an approach to address this issue: synthesis of an atomically dispersed Fe electrocatalyst (Fe</description>
      <author>Siqi Ji, Yimin Mou, Hongxue Liu, Xue Lu, Qian Zhang, Chunmin Guo, Kai Sun, Dong Liu, J. Hugh Horton, Li Wang, Yu Wang, Zhijun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202410121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Photosynthetic Cell with Molecular Biomimetic Thylakoid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416289</link>
      <description>Enbo Zhou, Shi&#8208;Chen Yan, Xiang Zhang, Baloch Ur Rehman Ateeq, Yangdan Hui, F.S. Wang, Lei Jiao, Jiafang Xie, Daqiang Yuan, Li Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402556634

                The construction of solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion system by mimicking the photosynthetic network of the chloroplast holds great promise on efficient solar energy utilization. We developed an artificial photosynthetic cell (APC) based on molecular biomimetic thylakoid (CoTPP&#8208;FePy) to split water into hydrogen and oxygen (H2 and O2) at low driving voltage (1.1 V) and neutral condition (pH&#8776;7). The CoTPP&#8208;FePy can emulate the light reaction in thylakoids to produce O2 by coupling light harvesting, photocatalysis, and electron/energy storage (FeIII/FeII&#8208;Py). Subsequently, a membrane electrode assembly (MEA) were employed to simulate the dark reaction, wherein the proton, electron and energy generated by the light reaction can drive the H2 producing process. By a temporally and spatially coupling of the light and dark reactions, the resulting APC achieved a solar conversion efficiency of 3.1%, exceeding that of natural photosynthetic systems and demonstrating the potential of artificial photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Enbo Zhou, Shi&#8208;Chen Yan, Xiang Zhang, Baloch Ur Rehman Ateeq, Yangdan Hui, F.S. Wang, Lei Jiao, Jiafang Xie, Daqiang Yuan, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co3O4 nanoparticles synthesized with rotten-grape extract for use in supercapacitors and oxygen evolution devices</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102922</link>
      <description>Asma Hayat, Aneela Tahira, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Irum Naz, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Elmuez A. Dawi, Matteo Tonezzer, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, Results in Engineering. 24(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402560066

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asma Hayat, Aneela Tahira, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Irum Naz, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Elmuez A. Dawi, Matteo Tonezzer, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rineng.2024.102922</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma-engineering of Pt-decorated NiCo2O4 nanowires with rich oxygen vacancies for enhanced oxygen electrocatalysis and zinc-air battery performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124607</link>
      <description>He Li, Luka Hansen, Ainura Aliyeva, Jihao Wang, Haoyi Qiu, Martin M&#252;ller, Shilong Chen, Cenk Aktas, Lorenz Kienle, Bernd Hartke, Jan Benedikt, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402565710

                No abstract</description>
      <author>He Li, Luka Hansen, Ainura Aliyeva, Jihao Wang, Haoyi Qiu, Martin M&#252;ller, Shilong Chen, Cenk Aktas, Lorenz Kienle, Bernd Hartke, Jan Benedikt</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124607</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Hydrogen Production by Low&#8208;Temperature Membrane&#8208;Engineered Water Electrolyzers, and Regenerative Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400574</link>
      <description>Alexandre Bodard, Zhangsen Chen, Oumayma ELJarray, Gaixia Zhang, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402567352

                Abstract Green hydrogen (H 2 ) is an essential component of global plans to reduce carbon emissions from hard&#8208;to&#8208;abate industries and heavy transport. However, challenges remain in the highly efficient H 2 production from water electrolysis powered by renewable energies. The sluggish oxygen evolution restrains the H 2 production from water splitting. Rational electrocatalyst designs for highly efficient H 2 production and oxygen evolution are pivotal for water electrolysis. With the development of high&#8208;performance electrolyzers, the scale&#8208;up of H 2 production to an industrial&#8208;level related activity can be achieved. This review summarizes recent advances in water electrolysis such as the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) and anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE). The critical challenges for PEMWE and AEMWE are the high cost of noble&#8208;metal catalysts and their durability, respectively. This review highlights the anode and cathode designs for improving the catalytic performance of electrocatalysts, the electrolyte and membrane engineering for membrane electrode assembly (MEA) optimizations, and stack systems for the most promising electrolyzers in water electrolysis. Besides, the advantages of integrating water electrolyzers, fuel cells (FC), and regenerative fuel cells (RFC) into the hydrogen ecosystem are introduced. Finally, the perspective of electrolyzer designs with superior performance is presented.</description>
      <author>Alexandre Bodard, Zhangsen Chen, Oumayma ELJarray, Gaixia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400574</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recommended practice for measurement and evaluation of oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12486</link>
      <description>Hongyu An, Wanki Park, Heejong Shin, Dong Young Chung, EcoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402567939

                Abstract The Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a pivotal technology driving next&#8208;generation sustainable energy conversion and storage devices. Establishing a robust analytical methodology is paramount to fostering innovation in this field. This review offers a comprehensive discussion on measurement and interpretation, advocating for standardized protocols and best practices to mitigate the myriad factors that complicate analysis. The initial focus is directed toward substrate electrodes and gas bubbles, both significant contributors to reduced reliability and reproducibility. Subsequently, the review focuses on intrinsic activity assessment, identification of electrochemical active sites, and the disentanglement of competing process contributions. These careful methodologies ensure the systematic delivery of insights crucial for assessing OER performance. In conclusion, the review highlights the critical role played by precise measurement techniques and unbiased activity comparison methodologies in propelling advancements in OER catalyst development. image</description>
      <author>Hongyu An, Wanki Park, Heejong Shin, Dong Young Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eom2.12486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fluorine&#8208;lodged high&#8208;valent high&#8208;entropy layered double hydroxide for efficient, long&#8208;lasting zinc&#8208;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410978</link>
      <description>Zonglong Zhu, Jing Zhong, Li Wang, Jialun Gu, Fucong Lyu, Shengmei Chen, Haikun Wu, Lanxi Li, Chunyi Zhi, Jian L&#252;, Yang Yang Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568141

                Efficient and stable bifunctional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) catalysts are urgently needed to unlock the full potential of zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). High&#8208;valence oxides (HVOs) and high entropy oxides (HEOs) are suitable candidates for their optimal electronic structures and stability but suffer from demanding synthesis. Here, a low&#8208;cost fluorine&#8208;lodged high&#8208;valent high&#8208;entropy layered double hydroxide (HV&#8208;HE&#8208;LDH) (FeCoNi2F4(OH)4) is conveniently prepared through multi&#8208;ions co&#8208;precipitation, where F&#8208; are firmly embedded into the individual hydroxide layers. Spectroscopic detections and theoretical simulations reveal high valent metal cations are obtained in FeCoNi2F4(OH)4, which enlarge the energy band overlap between metal 3d and O 2p, enhancing the electronic conductivity and charge transfer, thus affording high intrinsic OER catalytic activity. More importantly, the strengthened metal&#8208;oxygen (M&#8208;O) bonds and stable octahedral geometry (M&#8208;O(F)6) in FeCoNi2F4(OH)4 prevent structural reorganization, rendering long&#8208;term catalytic stability. Furthermore, an efficient three&#8208;phase reaction interface with fast oxygen transportation was constructed, significantly improving the ORR activity. ZABs assembled with FeCoNi2F4(OH)4@HCC (hydrophobic carbon cloth) cathodes deliver a top performance with high round&#8208;trip energy efficiency (60.6% at 10 mA cm&#8208;2) and long&#8208;term stability (efficiency remains at 58.8% after 1050 charge&#8208;discharge cycles).</description>
      <author>Zonglong Zhu, Jing Zhong, Li Wang, Jialun Gu, Fucong Lyu, Shengmei Chen, Haikun Wu, Lanxi Li, Chunyi Zhi, Jian L&#252;, Yang Yang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trifunctional Graphene&#8208;Sandwiched Heterojunction&#8208;Embedded Layered Lattice Electrocatalyst for High Performance in Zn&#8208;Air Battery&#8208;Driven Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408869</link>
      <description>Dong&#8208;Won Kim, Jihoon Kim, Jong Hui Choi, Do Hwan Jung, Jeung Ku Kang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568155

                Abstract Zn&#8208;air battery (ZAB)&#8208;driven water splitting holds great promise as a next&#8208;generation energy conversion technology, but its large overpotential, low activity, and poor stability for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) remain obstacles. Here, a trifunctional graphene&#8208;sandwiched, heterojunction&#8208;embedded layered lattice (G&#8208;SHELL) electrocatalyst offering a solution to these challenges are reported. Its hollow core&#8208;layered shell morphology promotes ion transport to Co 3 S 4 for OER and graphene&#8208;sandwiched MoS 2 for ORR/HER, while its heterojunction&#8208;induced internal electric fields facilitate electron migration. The structural characteristics of G&#8208;SHELL are thoroughly investigated using X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy. Additionally, atomic&#8208;resolution transmission electron microscopy (TEM) images align well with the DFT&#8208;relaxed structures and simulated TEM images, further confirming its structure. It exhibits an approximately threefold smaller ORR charge transfer resistance than Pt/C, a lower OER overpotential and Tafel slope than RuO&#8322;, and excellent HER overpotential and Tafel slope, while outlasting noble metals in terms of durability. Ex situ X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy analysis under varying potentials by examining the peak shifts and ratios (Co 2+ /Co 3+ and Mo 4+ /Mo 6+ ) elucidates electrocatalytic reaction mechanisms. Furthermore, the ZAB with G&#8208;SHELL outperforms Pt/C+RuO 2 in terms of energy density (797 Wh kg &#8722;1 ) and peak power density (275.8 mW cm &#8722;2 ), realizing the ZAB&#8208;driven water splitting.</description>
      <author>Dong&#8208;Won Kim, Jihoon Kim, Jong Hui Choi, Do Hwan Jung, Jeung Ku Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202408869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Multiple Strategies Using Biotechnology to Design High&#8208;Performance Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413072</link>
      <description>Lin Ge, Chang Liu, Tingting Xue, Yiyang Kang, Yining Sun, Yuxi Chen, Jiajie Wu, Kai Wen Teng, Lei Li, Qing Qu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568366

                Abstract Combining multiple design strategies often enhances catalyst performance but usually comes with high costs and low reproducibility. A technique that enhances catalyst performance in multiple strategies is urgently needed. Herein, a novel bioregulation technique is introduced, allowing simultaneous control over morphology, particle size, doping, interface engineering, and electronic properties. Bioregulation technique utilizes the soluble extracellular polymer from Aspergillus niger as a templating agent to construct high&#8208;performance catalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction (HER and OER). This technique controls catalyst morphology, introduces biological N and S doping, and regulates the electronic structure of the catalyst surface. Biomolecule modification enhances surface hydrophilicity, and the nanostructure increases surface roughness and gas&#8208;release efficiency. Theoretical calculations show that the bioregulation technique shortens the d/p&#8208;band center, optimizing reaction intermediate adsorption and desorption. The Bio&#8208;Pt/Co 3 O 4 catalyst with trace Pt on the surface, designed with these strategies, achieves HER ( &#951; 10 of 42 mV), OER ( &#951; 10 of 221 mV), and overall water&#8208;splitting performance (1.51 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 ), maintaining stability for over 50 h, outperforming most Pt&#8208;based catalysts. Notably, using spent lithium&#8208;ion battery cathodes leachate, rich in Co 2 &#8314;, successfully replicates the experiment. This approach holds promise as a mainstream method for synthesizing high&#8208;performance materials in the future.</description>
      <author>Lin Ge, Chang Liu, Tingting Xue, Yiyang Kang, Yining Sun, Yuxi Chen, Jiajie Wu, Kai Wen Teng, Lei Li, Qing Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation of catalytic activity of BSCF towards electrochemical oxygen reactions using different synthetic approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.138</link>
      <description>Sachin Bhagat, Nandita Singh, Monika Singh, Ashish Kumar Singh, Suryabhan Singh, Uday Pratap Azad, Akhilesh Kumar Singh, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 88(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402568572

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sachin Bhagat, Nandita Singh, Monika Singh, Ashish Kumar Singh, Suryabhan Singh, Uday Pratap Azad, Akhilesh Kumar Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.138</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-modulated NiFe&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Co Layered Double Hydroxide on Ni Foam for Efficient Oxygen Precipitation Reaction in Alkaline Water Electrolysis for Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.23919/ccc63176.2024.10661943</link>
      <description>Jialin Dong, Shihong Yue, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402570146

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jialin Dong, Shihong Yue</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.23919/ccc63176.2024.10661943</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of abundant oxygen vacancies in MOF-derived (Fe,Co)3O4 for oxygen evolution reaction and as an air cathode for zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161264</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Xinpeng Chen, Hua-Bin Yuan, Lili Xing, Desheng Sha, Aijing Li, Guoqiang Chen, Tieling Xing, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402570641

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Xinpeng Chen, Hua-Bin Yuan, Lili Xing, Desheng Sha, Aijing Li, Guoqiang Chen, Tieling Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conjugated polycarboxylate ligand-coordinated NiFe LDH for enhanced oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04498c</link>
      <description>Zi-Ye Liu, Qianyu Wang, Teng Xu, Ji&#8208;Ming Hu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402578884

                Nickel&#8211;iron layered double hydroxide (NiFe LDH) shows great performance in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to the interaction between Ni and Fe.</description>
      <author>Zi-Ye Liu, Qianyu Wang, Teng Xu, Ji&#8208;Ming Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04498c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrospun Iridium-Based Nanofiber Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Influence of Calcination on Activity&#8211;Stability Relation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07831</link>
      <description>Mikl&#243;s M&#225;rton Kov&#225;cs, Birk Fritsch, Leopold Lahn, Julien Bachmann, Olga Kasian, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Andreas Hutzler, Dominik Dworschak, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402588976

                The enhanced utilization of noble metal catalysts through highly porous nanostructures is crucial to advancing the commercialization prospects of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). In this study, hierarchically structured IrO</description>
      <author>Mikl&#243;s M&#225;rton Kov&#225;cs, Birk Fritsch, Leopold Lahn, Julien Bachmann, Olga Kasian, Karl J. J. Mayrhofer, Andreas Hutzler, Dominik Dworschak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c07831</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge Transfer in n-FeO and p-&#945;-Fe2O3 Nanoparticles for Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14181515</link>
      <description>Amir Humayun, Nandapriya Manivelan, Prabakar Kandasamy, Nanomaterials. 14(18)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402599911

                This study aims to explore the n-FeO and p-&#945;-Fe2O3 semiconductor nanoparticles in hydrogen (HER) and oxygen (OER) evolution reactions and a combined full cell electrocatalyst system to electrolyze the water. We have observed a distinct electrocatalytic performance for both HER and OER by tuning the interplay between iron oxidation states Fe2+ and Fe3+ and utilizing phase-transformed iron oxide nanoparticles (NPs). The Fe2+ rich n-FeO NPs exhibited superior HER performance compared to p-&#945;-Fe2O3 and Fe(OH)x NPs, which is attributed to the enhancement in n-type semiconducting nature under HER potential, facilitating the electron transfer for the reduction in H+ ions. In contrast, p-&#945;-Fe2O3 NPs demonstrated excellent OER activity. An H-cell constructed using n-FeO||p-&#945;-Fe2O3 NPs as cathode and anode achieved a cell voltage of 1.87 V at a current density of 50 mA/cm2. The cell exhibited remarkable stability after 30 h of activation and maintained the high current density of 100 mA/cm2 for 80 h with a negligible increase in cell voltage. This work highlights the semiconducting properties of n-FeO and p-&#945;-Fe2O3 for the electrochemical water splitting system using the band bending phenomenon under the applied potential.</description>
      <author>Amir Humayun, Nandapriya Manivelan, Prabakar Kandasamy</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14181515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402669476

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402669520

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402669528

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402669536

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v3/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402680871

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v3/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681002

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681075

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681089

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681112

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681139

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681141

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Rapid microwave synthesis of medium and high entropy oxides for outstanding oxygen evolution reaction performance"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681196

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ma00667d/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Cost-effective synthesis of rGO/CeNiO&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;3&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt; perovskite nanocomposites for enhanced and stable supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402681201

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03159h/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand-tuning of coordination compound for improved oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjche.2024.07.023</link>
      <description>Kai Yang, Yuanjun Liu, Yuyu Liu, Xingmei Guo, Xiangjun Zheng, Junhao Zhang, Guoxing Zhu, Chinese Journal of Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402565094

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Yang, Yuanjun Liu, Yuyu Liu, Xingmei Guo, Xiangjun Zheng, Junhao Zhang, Guoxing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cjche.2024.07.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phytic acid-modified NiFe-PBA stacked by &#960;-&#960; force for reinforcement electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01520g</link>
      <description>Yu Zheng, Chun Hua Han, Yuan Yuan, Gong Chen, Ye Fu, Yunhe Zhao, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402577708

                Prussian blue analogues (PBAs) with unique three-dimensional (3D) open metal framework structure and easily adjustable composition have been widely used in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) under alkaline conditions. Herein, disintegrative...</description>
      <author>Yu Zheng, Chun Hua Han, Yuan Yuan, Gong Chen, Ye Fu, Yunhe Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01520g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo-Induced Surface Reconstruction in Ni/Co-OOH Prickly Flower Clusters for Improving the Hydrogen Production in Alkaline Seawater Splitting.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404858</link>
      <description>Wen Zhang, Jianyang Gao, Qixing Gong, Fusheng Liu, Yang Zhang, Guangrui Xu, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang, PubMed. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402554797

                Seawater electrolysis is the most promising technology for hydrogen production, in which surface reconstruction on the interface of electrode/electrolyte plays a crucial role in activating the catalytic reactions with a low activation energy barrier. Herein, an efficient Mo modifying NiCoMo prickly flower clusters electrocatalyst supported on nickel foam (Mo-doped Ni/Co-OOH prickly flower clusters) is obtained, which serves as an eminently active and durable catalyst for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to the surface reconstruction during the alkaline seawater electrolysis with ultralow overpotentials. It just requires a cell voltage of 1.52 V to achieve the current density of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Wen Zhang, Jianyang Gao, Qixing Gong, Fusheng Liu, Yang Zhang, Guangrui Xu, Zexing Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From One-Pot to Powerhouse: Al&#8211;Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Thin Films Coupled with Hexagonal ZnFe LDH for Water Oxidation in Alkaline Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12180</link>
      <description>Ardra S. Darsan, P. Devi, P. Murugan, Alagarsamy Pandikumar, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402586343

                As COVID-19 profoundly affected nations worldwide, there was a significant reduction in gas and electricity consumption, contrasting with the surplus production of oil and gas by companies. This situation has ignited a growing interest in researching alternative green fuels. Electrochemical water-splitting has emerged as a promising avenue for advancing the green hydrogen economy. However, the high costs associated with traditional catalysts have hindered the feasibility of this remarkable method on an industrial scale. Here, this study mainly objects to fabricating an efficient, low cost and stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst and our focus has been on refining the morphology to enhance activity levels. The optimized one-pot synthesized 15% Al-doped Fe</description>
      <author>Ardra S. Darsan, P. Devi, P. Murugan, Alagarsamy Pandikumar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c12180</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Lithium&#8208;Oxygen Battery Exploiting Carbon Nanotubes, Graphene and Gold Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400381</link>
      <description>Stanislav Levchenko, Giacomo Valente, Jusef Hassoun, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402583165

                Abstract Lithium&#8208;oxygen (Li&#8208;O 2 ) battery is considered a high&#8208;energy alternative to Li&#8208;ion one due its characteristic electrochemical conversion process, with the additional advantage of lower cost and environmental impact. However, this emerging battery still requires an enhancement of stability and lifespan to allow its use as a practical energy storage system. In this work we investigate an electrode material benefitting of multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs), few layer graphene (FLG), and gold nano&#8208;powder catalyst to improve the Li&#8208;O 2 battery performances in terms of energy efficiency, cycle life and stability. Morphological, structural, and electrochemical tests indicate that the composite electrode can actually boost the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and enhance the Li&#8208;O 2 process reversibility, with a capacity of 1000 mAh g &#8722;1 over 70 cycles. On the other hand, the tests reveal the role of the gold in decreasing the polarization and increasing the cell life. Therefore, the results suggest the combination of carbons with various morphologies as a suitable architecture for hosting the Li&#8208;O 2 reaction products and allowing their reversible reaction. On the other hand, the results highlight the necessity for a better tuning the noble metal characteristics to further enhance the cell performances.</description>
      <author>Stanislav Levchenko, Giacomo Valente, Jusef Hassoun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Nanostructure NiO&#8211;GeSe Core&#8211;Shell/MAPbBr&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Solar Cell in Solar Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting: Superior Efficiency Enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9454136</link>
      <description>Maryam Shahrostami, Mehdi Eskandari, Davood Fathi, International Journal of Energy Research. 2024(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402574927

                Solar&#8208;driven photoelectrochemical (PEC) water&#8208;splitting cells coupled with a photovoltaic (PV) cell as a photoanode have become an intriguing topic in solar energy conversion. In this study, for the purpose of developing a system with high efficiency, several photoanode materials were investigated to adjust the oxygen evolution reaction and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) energy bands. Among all, MAPbBr 3 with a wide bandgap (2.3 eV) was selected. However, the power conversion efficiency of the PV cell was not desirable due to the low light absorption. Therefore, the NiO&#8211;GeSe core&#8211;shell was placed inside the perovskite layer to enhance light absorption and carrier generation. In order to achieve a cell with the maximum performance, the core&#8211;shell height, and the shell radius were optimized, where the optimum structure was recognized with a core&#8211;shell height of 300 nm and a radius of 25&#8211;60 nm. The system&#8217;s total efficiency, which is represented by the solar to hydrogen efficiency, was then increased from 5.49% to 19.74% for the planar and nanostructure photoanode, respectively. The proposed PEC cell with the optimized photoanode is considered as the most efficient half&#8208;tandem and perovskite&#8208;based reported coupled system, operating without the need for an external voltage. In this study, three optical, electrical, and electrochemical models were solved using the finite element method to analyze the coupled system.</description>
      <author>Maryam Shahrostami, Mehdi Eskandari, Davood Fathi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1155/2024/9454136</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A perspective to efficient synthesis of zirconium carbide via novel pyro-vacuum method: lower temperatures and enhanced purity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53063/synsint.2024.43233</link>
      <description>Faramarz Kazemi, Behzad Nayebi, Synthesis and Sintering. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402559567

                The use of ultra-high temperature ceramics (UHTCs) as a novel additive in the refractory industry is becoming increasingly popular. However, the synthesis of such materials is associated with some commercial obstacles, mainly high-temperature synthesis methods. In the present study, the pyro-vacuum method is presented as a new method to decrease the final product's synthesis temperature and oxygen content. Some thermodynamic aspects and phase evolution of the materials during the synthesis procedure are described for the synthesis of non-oxide material. Conclusively, it seems that by applying vacuum conditions, the final UHTC phases can be synthesized at significantly lower temperatures (&gt;400 &#176;C lower, for ZrC), if adequate powder mixtures are considered. Also due to phase analysis, it was found that the oxygen content of the final phase is lower than the conventional routes and other references. The process provides promising prospects for the economic synthesis of UHTCs.</description>
      <author>Faramarz Kazemi, Behzad Nayebi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53063/synsint.2024.43233</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D TiNBr as photocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vxdq4</link>
      <description>Yatong Wang, Geert Brocks, Ceren Tayran, S&#252;leyman Er, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402583716

                Two-dimensional (2D) Janus materials gain increasing attention as water splitting photocatalysts for hydrogen production. We use first-principles calculations to predict a stable 2D Janus $T$-TiNBr structure, with strong near-ultraviolet sunlight absorption and band edges that align favorably with the water redox potentials for oxygen and hydrogen evolution. We show that the optical and electronic properties of $T$-TiNBr can be modulated to a certain extend by applying external uniaxial strain. Explicit calculations of the redox reactions reveal that solar-driven water splitting is viable at the N-side of $T$-TiNBr, while the Br-side requires modifications such as vacancy creation, the application of an external potential, or adjustment of the pH conditions.</description>
      <author>Yatong Wang, Geert Brocks, Ceren Tayran, S&#252;leyman Er</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-vxdq4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treatment of domestic wastewater and extracellular polymeric substance accumulation in siphon&#8208;type composite vertical subsurface flow constructed wetland</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wer.11132</link>
      <description>Hao Chen, Lin Qiu, Hong Wu, Fahui Nie, Yong Liu, Wenping Cao, Water Environment Research. 96(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402570326

                Abstract In this study, the siphon&#8208;type composite vertical flow constructed wetland (Sc&#8208;VSsFCW) was constructed with anthracite and shale ceramsite chosen as the substrate bed materials. During the 90&#8208;day experiment, typical pollutant removal effects of wastewater and extracellular polymeric substance (EPS) accumulation were investigated. Meanwhile, X&#8208;ray diffraction and scanning electron microscopy were used to examine the phase composition and surface morphology to analyze adsorptive property. Additionally, we evaluated the impact of siphon effluent on clogging and depolymerization by measuring the EPS components' evolution within the system. The findings reveal that both the anthracite and shale ceramsite systems exhibit impressive removal efficiencies for total phosphorus (TP), total dissolved phosphorus (TDP), soluble reactive phosphorus (SRP), chemical oxygen demand (COD), ammonium nitrogen (NH 4 + &#8208;N), and nitrate nitrogen (NO 3 &#8722; &#8208;N). However, as the experiment progressed, TP removal rates in both systems gradually declined because of the saturation of adsorption sites on the substrate surfaces. Although the dissolved oxygen (DO) levels remained relatively stable throughout the experiment, pH exhibited distinct patterns, suggesting that the anthracite system relies primarily on chemical adsorption, whereas the shale ceramsite system predominantly utilizes physical adsorption. After an initial period of fluctuation, the permeability coefficient and porosity of the system gradually stabilized, and the protein and polysaccharide contents in both systems exhibited a downward trend. The study underscores that anthracite and shale ceramsite have good effectiveness in pollutant removal as substrate materials. Overall, the hydraulic conditions of the double repeated oxygen coupling siphon in the Sc&#8208;VSsFCW system contribute to enhanced re&#8208;oxygenation capacity and permeability coefficient during operation. The changes in EPS content indicate that the siphon effluent exerts a certain depolymerization effect on the EPS within the system, thereby mitigating the risk of biological clogging to a certain extent. Practitioner Points The system can still maintain good pollutant treatment effect in long&#8208;term operation. The re&#8208;oxygenation method of the system can achieve efficient and long&#8208;term re&#8208;oxygenation effect. The siphon effluent has a certain improvement effect on the permeability coefficient and porosity, but it cannot effectively inhibit the occurrence of clogging. The EPS content did not change significantly during the operation of the system, and there was a risk of biological clogging.</description>
      <author>Hao Chen, Lin Qiu, Hong Wu, Fahui Nie, Yong Liu, Wenping Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wer.11132</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The fate of nitrogen in deep magma oceans</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31223/x5db0k</link>
      <description>Ekanshu Mallick, Kelsey B. Prissel, K. Righter, Colin J. Jackson, EarthArXiv (California Digital Library). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402591600

                Nitrogen is important in planetary evolution because it is essential to life and the most abundant element in Earth&#8217;s atmosphere. Here, we investigate how core formation affects the distribution of N within accreting terrestrial planets. We conducted laser-heated diamond anvil cell experiments (LH-DAC) over a wide range of high pressure-temperature-compositional (PTX) conditions (38-103 GPa, 2728-5609 K, -1.95 to -1.03 &#8710;IW, 0.5-3.7 NBO/T) to study nitrogen partitioning in metal-silicate systems. Combining our data with existing low and high PT results, we developed a nitrogen partitioning model applicable from early accretion to extreme PT stages associated with giant impacts. We test the robustness of our model by accurately predicting nitrogen partitioning in a multi-anvil experiment conducted independently at 15 GPa, 2573 K with oxygen fugacity of -2.5 &#8710;IW. Our model shows that increasing pressure, oxygen fugacity, and N concentration in the alloy make nitrogen more siderophile, while increasing temperature, oxygen and silicon contents in the alloy, and the SiO2 content of the silicate melt make nitrogen less siderophile. Application of our model to core formation conditions under oxidized and reduced scenarios suggest that nitrogen can be siderophile or lithophile under low PT conditions but exhibits a neutral partitioning at high PT conditions (&amp;gt; 100 GPa, 5000 K) over a wide range of bulk planet compositions. Using our model, along with partitioning models for S and C, we examine how core formation scenarios can fractionate C/N and S/N ratios in the BSE. Our model suggests that backreaction of volatile rich cores from reduced, smaller impactors (sub-Mars-sized) within deep magma oceans can impart a wide range of C/N and S/N ratios on the magma ocean. We find that the amount of silicate entrainment has a strong control on elemental fractionations imparted to the magma oceans. Elevated C/N and S/N ratios are associated with larger degrees of silicate entrainment, and vice versa. Thus, Earth&#8217;s apparent depletion of N may relate to its volatiles being reprocessed within deep magma oceans, possibly during the end stages of accretion.</description>
      <author>Ekanshu Mallick, Kelsey B. Prissel, K. Righter, Colin J. Jackson</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31223/x5db0k</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
