<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:42:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Medium-Entropy Co&#8211;Fe&#8211;Cr&#8211;Mo Spinel Nanoflowers as Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05568</link>
      <description>Yuhang Sun, Tianmi Tang, Liyuan Xiao, Jingyi Han, Xue Bai, Mingyuan Shi, Siyu Chen, Jingru Sun, Yuanyuan Ma, Jingqi Guan, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391464648

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays an important role in many electrocatalysis-related fields. However, the slow kinetics of the OER seriously hinders energy efficiency. Here, we synthesize flower-like Co&#8211;Fe&#8211;Cr&#8211;Mo medium-entropy spinel (MES) nanosheets on nickel foam (NF) using one-step solvothermal method for the OER. Due to high stability and compositional diversity, the CoFeCrMoOx/NF catalyst exhibits excellent electrocatalytic OER performance with an overpotential of only 196 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 1.0 M KOH solution, much lower than CoFeCrMnOx/NF, CoFeCrCeOx/NF, CoFeCrSnOx/NF, CoFeCrAlOx/NF, and commercial IrO2 catalysts, reflecting that the formation of flower-like MES has a positive effect on the improvement of OER performance. The introduction of Mo increases active sites, promotes electron transfer, accelerates the adsorption and desorption of the OER intermediates, reduces the energy barrier, and thus improves the performance of the OER. In situ Raman spectra indicate that the surface CoOOH and FeOOH species are important active components for the OER.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Sun, Tianmi Tang, Liyuan Xiao, Jingyi Han, Xue Bai, Mingyuan Shi, Siyu Chen, Jingru Sun, Yuanyuan Ma, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and Stable Dual-Active-Site of Core-Shell NiFe-Layered Double Hydroxide Anchored on FeMnON-N-Doped Carbon Nanotubes as Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad258f</link>
      <description>Parisa Akbarian, Mehdi Kheirmand, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391465634

                Abstract The bifunctional air electrodes with numerous dual-active sites and low cost are desirable to modify the performance of Zn-air batteries (ZABs). Metal&#8211;oxygen-nitrogen&#8211;carbon substrate (M = Mn, Fe, Ni, etc.) and NiFe-layered double hydroxide (NiFe-LDH) nanosheets are excellent catalysts in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process, respectively. Here, we investigated a bifunctional electrocatalytic substrate with 3D core-shell hierarchical architecture by anchoring high OER-active NiFe-LDH on ORR-active FeMnZIF-8@gC3N4-derived FeMnON-N doped carbon nanotubes with bamboo like (NiFe-LDH@FeMnON-NC). This nano composite has unique features such as robust synergistic effects, high conductivity, balance, and optimization of surface chemical valences of Fe, Mn, and Ni atoms to boost the bifunctional ORR and OER properties and stability in ZABs. The NiFe-LDH@FeMnON-NC nanocomposite not only exhibited superior OER electroactivity with a low onset overpotential of 235 mV (10 mA cm&#8722;2), but also have excellent ORR activity with current density of -5.48 mAcm-2 and onset potential of 1.04 V, which is better than or comparable to those of commercial Pt/C and RuO2. Rechargeable ZABs constructed by bifunctional NiFe-LDH@FeMnON-NC have a peak power density (235.41 mW cm&#8722;2), open-circuit potential (OCV) (1.53 V), small discharge/charge band gap of 0.74 V and excellent discharge stability.</description>
      <author>Parisa Akbarian, Mehdi Kheirmand</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad258f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of the electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction by light and external magnetic fields, using hybrid electrodes made by Langmuir-Blodgett</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143910</link>
      <description>Viviana Beatriz Daboin, Sara Natalia Moya Betancourt, Eliana D. Farias, Julieta Soledad Riva, Paula G. Bercoff, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391467484

                The implementation of water electrolysis technology is hampered by the slow kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction. In an attempt to solve this issue, anodes which are able to respond to external stimuli such as magnetic field and light were successfully prepared by the Langmuir-Blodgett technique, using Fe3O4 magnetic nanoparticles (FTO/Fe3O4) and Fe3O4 nanoparticles together with tetrathiafulvalene as photosensitizer (FTO/Fe3O4/TTF). This technique allowed obtaining highly stable and homogeneous anodes in a simple and reproducible way. The electrodes produced a catalytic effect on the water oxidation reaction, without the use of a noble-metal, and proved to be sensitive to a 365 nm LED light as well as to an external magnetic field. Water oxidation reaction was evaluated by linear sweep voltammetry, by the Tafel slopes and also by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy. This work presents new perspectives for the water oxidation reaction, using electrodes fabricated by the Langmuir-Blodgett technique and catalyzed through the use of external stimuli such as light and magnetic fields.</description>
      <author>Viviana Beatriz Daboin, Sara Natalia Moya Betancourt, Eliana D. Farias, Julieta Soledad Riva, Paula G. Bercoff</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.143910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Excess Electrons in Reducible Metal Oxides for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity: A Mini&#8208;Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400081</link>
      <description>Xiang Huang, Hu Xu, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391480506

                Identifying a universal activity descriptor for metal oxides, akin to the d&#8208;band center for transition metals, remains a significant challenge in catalyst design, largely due to the intricate electronic structures of metal oxides. This review highlights a major advancement in formulating the number of excess electrons (NEE) as an activity descriptor for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on reducible metal oxide surfaces. We elaborate on the quantitative relationship between NEE and the adsorption properties of OER intermediates, and unveil the decisive role of the octet rule on the OER performance of these oxides. This insight provides a robust theoretical basis for designing effective OER catalysts. Moreover, we discuss critical experimental evidence supporting this theory and summarize recent advances in employing NEE as a guiding principle for developing highly efficient OER catalysts experimentally.</description>
      <author>Xiang Huang, Hu Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400081</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZIF-67-derived Se-doped CoSe2 grown on carbon nanofibers as oxygen electrocatalysis for rechargeable Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nj05569h</link>
      <description>Wenjing Cui, Shan Xu, Jie Bai, Chunping Li, Xueliang Sun, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391481457

                Exploring bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) combining the features of effective electrocatalytic activity, high electrical conductivity, and superior stability remains a significant challenge...</description>
      <author>Wenjing Cui, Shan Xu, Jie Bai, Chunping Li, Xueliang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nj05569h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir loaded Co(OH)2 nanosheets with vacancy defects for boosting oxygen evolution reaction and stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115352</link>
      <description>Junfang Zhang, Xiang Li, Zehao Zang, Chuanyan Fan, Yubo Luo, Lanlan Li, Xiaofei Yu, Xiaojing Yang, Zunming Lu, Xinghua Zhang, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391482605

                Transition metal hydroxides have great potential as oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, while its low reaction kinetics and unsatisfactory stability limits the further application. Herein, Co(OH)2 nanosheets with oxygen vacancies defects and anchored Ir atoms and clusters (Ir/D-Co(OH)2) were prepared by electrochemical deposition and in-situ etching. The Introduction of Ir species is beneficial to regulate the valence electron configuration on Co 3d orbit and enhance the conductivity, which contributes to improving kinetics of Co(OH)2. In addition, the introduced defects not only regulate the adsorption energy barrier of reaction intermediates, but also serve as anchor centers for stabilizing Ir atoms and clusters, thus enhancing the active surface area and catalytic stability. The Ir/D-Co(OH)2/NF catalyst owns ultralow OER potential of 270.5 mV at 100 mA cm-2, and it has superior long-term stability under high current density of 100 mA cm-2 for 100 hours. This work provides a simple method to design noble atoms loaded transition metal hydroxides with specific defects for enhancing OER performance and high stability.</description>
      <author>Junfang Zhang, Xiang Li, Zehao Zang, Chuanyan Fan, Yubo Luo, Lanlan Li, Xiaofei Yu, Xiaojing Yang, Zunming Lu, Xinghua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115352</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced catalytic activity through a unique cage structure of amorphous NiFe oxide via tri-doping P, B, N and introducing tungsten for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173726</link>
      <description>Eun-Su Jang, Pei-Chen Su, Jooheon Kim, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391482704

                Unique designs and doping strategies were adopted to control the variability of intrinsic active sites and to enhance the catalytic performance of bimetal catalysts in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This study introduces the fabrication of unique cage-structured NiFe-W-PBN oxide catalysts (u-NFWPBNO) through a facile stepwise reduction process. The two-step metal reduction, employing H4N2&#183;H2O followed by NaBH4, yields a cage structure (120 nm) featuring an uneven shell surface composed of small nanospheres (25 nm). Outstanding OER performance is achieved, which can be attributed to the P, B, N tri-doping strategy including both geometric and electronic structural changes. Furthermore, the introduction of tungsten (W) results in electron withdrawal at the metal centers. P, B and P, N dual-doped catalysts with different morphologies (NFWPBO, NFWPNO) and W-free (NFPBNO) comparison groups were prepared to compare these features. Consequently, u-NFWPBNO exhibits overpotentials of 256 mV for j10 and a Tafel slope of 32 mV/dec, demonstrating high performance. This study serves as a valuable guide for preparing uniquely designed, high-activity amorphous electrocatalysts and provides insights for developing Zn-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Eun-Su Jang, Pei-Chen Su, Jooheon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173726</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution and methanol oxidation reactions prepared by a facile and scale-up method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173745</link>
      <description>Fuyue Liu, Jiaxin Dang, Chuanyan Zhao, Bo Yuan, Haoqi Qiu, Qin Wang, Chunfei Zhang, Xiao Liu, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391482725

                Developing the facile, universal and scale-up method to prepare electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) is crucial for the high-efficient hydrogen production through water splitting. Herein, we load the CeO2 nanoparticles on the various metal foams by a very simple and scalable impregnation method. Taking iron-nickel foam (INF) as an example, we can obtain a high-efficient OER and MOR electrocatalyst of CeO2@INF-0.6. CeO2@INF-0.6 shows the superior electrocatalytic activities toward both OER and MOR with the oxidation potentials of 1.52 V and 1.47 V at 100 mA cm-2, respectively. This can be ascribed to the CeO2@INF-0.6 with strong adsorption and fast conversion ability of OH- in the alkaline electrolyte. CeO2@INF-0.6 also has good stability and selectivity in MOR-assisted alkaline water splitting, and the Faraday efficiency of formate is up to 99.2% at 1.42 V (vs. RHE). In addition, the Na+ and Cl- ions with high concentrations almost have the negligible effects on the OER and MOR activities of our CeO2@INF-0.6 in the alkaline solution. This indicates that using CeO2@INF-0.6 as anode for seawater electrolysis not only can greatly reduce the energy consumption, but produce the value-added anode product of formate.</description>
      <author>Fuyue Liu, Jiaxin Dang, Chuanyan Zhao, Bo Yuan, Haoqi Qiu, Qin Wang, Chunfei Zhang, Xiao Liu, He Miao, Jinliang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metastabilizing the Ruthenium Clusters by Interfacial Oxygen Vacancies for Boosted Water Splitting Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400059</link>
      <description>Ya Chen, Yaoda Liu, Wenfang Zhai, Huan Liu, S. Thangavel, Shengwu Guo, Zhengfei Dai, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391483783

                Abstract Metal&#8211;support interaction (MSI) is witnessed as an essential manner to stabilize active metals and tune catalytic activity for heterogonous water splitting. Kinetically driving the water electrolysis (WE) appeals for a rational MSI system with the coupled electron&#8208;donating/accepting (e&#8208;D/A) characters for hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER). However, the metal stabilization effect by MSI will in turn restrict the deblocking of e&#8208;D/A properties and challenge the full electrocatalytic optimization. This study profiles a heterostructure featuring metastable Ru clusters on defective NiFe hydroxide (Ru/d&#8208;NiFe LDH) support as a low&#8208;precious (&#8776;2 wt%) catalytic platform for efficient WE. It is indicated that the interfacial oxygen vacancies can deviate the stable Ru 4d 5 orbit to a metastable Ru 2+&#948; state, and regulate the metal d&#8208;band center levels toward the facilitated HER/OER processes. Resultantly, the Ru/d&#8208;NiFe LDH heterostructure attains the ultralow overpotentials at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for Pt&#8208;beyond alkaline HER (18 mV) and OER (220 mV) with fast kinetics and durability. The symmetrical water electrolyzer delivers a promising voltage of 1.49 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH and efficient seawater splitting performance. This work carries interesting opportunities in rationalizing sophisticated metal&#8208;support electrocatalysts through metal&#8208;site metastabilization engineering.</description>
      <author>Ya Chen, Yaoda Liu, Wenfang Zhai, Huan Liu, S. Thangavel, Shengwu Guo, Zhengfei Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved OH adsorption and effective oxygen evolution reaction on carbon-capsulated Co0.1Ni0.9O@C/CP electrode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159549</link>
      <description>Taesung Kim, Sujeong Kim, Harim Jeong, Younghwan Im, Nokeun Park, Misook Kang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391485013

                Hydroxide ion (OH&#8722;) adsorption is an important step in promoting the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media. This study aims to design a rational catalyst to obtain several OH&#8722; adsorption sites to achieve excellent OER performance: NiO was selected as the main catalyst, and a Co0.1Ni0.9O catalyst was prepared with 10 % lattice substitution of Co2+ ions. The Co0.1Ni0.9O surface was capsulated with amorphous carbon to prevent corrosion by strong alkaline media. XPS analysis revealed that Ni2+ ion defects occurred in the Co0.1Ni0.9O crystal, and highly oxidized Ni3+ ions were mixed to attain the desired stoichiometric ratio. Electrophilic Ni2O3 in a highly oxidized state promotes attack from OH&#8722; ions, which is a nucleophile, and easily transforms into a NiOOH intermediate, which ultimately leads to the rapid progress of OER. That is, the strong covalent nature between Ni3+&#8722;O2&#8722; in the Co0.1Ni0.9O/CP electrode promotes charge transfer between the cationic metal surface and the OH&#8722; adsorbate, thereby accelerating OER. Moreover, C-capsulation in the Co0.1Ni0.9O particles reduces the band gap owing to the filling of the electrons from C between the Ni 3d and O 2p orbitals. Consequently, this improved the conductivity of the electrode, effectively reducing the ohmic potential drop and energy loss between the catalyst and the current collector. Therefore, the overpotential reached by this electrode at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 was greatly reduced to 332 mV, the Tafel slope was low at 91.98 mV dec&#8722;1, and during OER with a Faraday efficiency of 94.7 %. Moreover, this excellent performance remained stable even after 10 d.</description>
      <author>Taesung Kim, Sujeong Kim, Harim Jeong, Younghwan Im, Nokeun Park, Misook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159549</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Metal-Ion-Doped Carbon Nitrides for Photocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05961</link>
      <description>Shanping Liu, Valentin Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Dong Fan, Peixiang Lu, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Guillaume Maurin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391486029

                Poly(heptazine imides) (PHIs) have emerged as prominent layered carbon nitride-based materials with potential oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalytic activity owing to their strong VIS light absorption, long excited-state lifetimes, high surface-to-volume ratios, and the possibility of tuning their properties via hosting different metal ions in their pores. A series of metal-ion-doped PHI-M (M = K+, Rb+, Mg2+, Zn2+, Mn2+, and Co2+) were first systematically explored using density functional theory calculations. These simulations led an in-depth understanding of the microscopic OER mechanism in these systems and identified PHI-Co2+ as the best OER catalyst of this family of PHIs, whereas PHI-Mn2+ can be an alternative promising OER catalyst. This level of performance was attributed to a thermodynamically favorable formation of the reaction intermediates as well as its red-shifted absorption in the VIS region involving the population of long-lived states, as revealed by time-dependent density functional theory calculations. We further demonstrated that the electronic properties of the *OH intermediates (Bader population, crystal orbital Hamilton population analysis, and adsorption energies) are reliable descriptors to anticipate the OER activity of this family of PHIs. This rational analysis paved the way toward the prediction of the OER performance of another PHI-M derivative, i.e., PHI-Fe2+. The computationally explored PHI-Fe2+, PHI-Mn2+, and PHI-Co2+ systems were then synthesized alongside PHI-K+, and their photocatalytic OER activities were assessed. These experimental findings confirmed the best photocatalytic OER performance for PHI-Co2+ with an oxygen production of 31.2 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1 that is 60 times higher than the pristine g-C3N4 (0.5 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1), whereas PHI-Fe2+ and PHI-Mn2+ are seen as alternative OER catalysts with attractive oxygen production of 11.20 and 4.69 &#956;mol&#183;h&#8211;1, respectively. Decisively, this joint experimental&#8211;computational study reveals PHI-Co2+ to be among the best of the OER catalysts so far reported in the literature including some perovskites.</description>
      <author>Shanping Liu, Valentin Diez&#8208;Cabanes, Dong Fan, Peixiang Lu, Yuanxing Fang, Markus Antonietti, Guillaume Maurin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Competition between the oxygen evolution reaction and the electrooxidation of alcohols on heteroatom-functionalized multi-walled carbon nanotubes-supported Ni oxide catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104026</link>
      <description>E. Morales, &#1052;ariya A. Kazakova, Alexander G. Selyutin, Georgiy V. Golubtsov, Dulce M. Morales, Arturo Manzo Robledo, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391487283

                Hybrid water electrolysis is a prominent route for hydrogen production that circumvents issues related to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the anode process in conventional water electrolysis, by integrating an alternative anode reaction. Herein, samples of nickel oxide nanoparticles supported on oxygen and nitrogen-functionalized multi-walled carbon nanotubes were evaluated as electrocatalysts for the OER and the electrooxidation of methanol (MOR), ethanol (EOR) and glycerol (GOR). The trend of overpotentials measured at a current of 0.1 mA was OER&gt;MOR&gt;EOR&gt;GOR, with slightly lower overpotentials observed for the nitrogen-doped sample, which is attributed to differences in nanoparticle size and distribution, support defectiveness, and nitrogen-induced electronic effects. The production of oxygen was monitored by Differential Electrochemical Mass Spectrometry (DEMS), indicating that the competition between OER and alcohol electrooxidation can be modulated by the support properties as well as by the nature and concentration of the alcohol.</description>
      <author>E. Morales, &#1052;ariya A. Kazakova, Alexander G. Selyutin, Georgiy V. Golubtsov, Dulce M. Morales, Arturo Manzo Robledo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom catalysts for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00012-4</link>
      <description>Ajit Singh, B. N. Singh, Arindam Indra, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391488890

                In recent years, a series of noble metals and transition metal-based single-atom catalysts (SACs) have been explored for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The unique structural and electronic features of the SACs facilitate the OER with maximum atomic utilization. As a result, a high turnover frequency is achieved with SACs. In this chapter, we have summarized the fundamentals of the SACs and their design strategies for electrochemical OER. The detailed characterization of the SACs and its utilization in OER has been discussed with suitable examples. The principles and reaction mechanism of electrochemical OER with SACs have been discussed looking at the structure of the active catalyst and reaction intermediates.</description>
      <author>Ajit Singh, B. N. Singh, Arindam Indra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-95237-8.00012-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Regulation of the Fe-Based Single-Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109268</link>
      <description>Xiaochen Wang, Zhiwen Kang, Dan Wang, Yafei Zhao, Xu Xiang, Huishan Shang, Bing Zhang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391490718

                The excessive consumption of fossil energy causes serious environmental problems, which has driven the exploration of clean and sustainable energy. Oxygen electrocatalysis as the core reaction of emerging energy conversion has attracted significant attention. Fe-based single-atom catalysts (SACs) are efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen electrocatalysis on account of high intrinsic reaction activity, maximized metal atom utilization, well-defined active sites, customizable coordination environment, and regulable electronic structure. Although considerable performance improvements for Fe-based SACs in the oxygen electrocatalysis process have been made, the principle of modifying the electronic structure to promote the catalytic performance of Fe-based SACs is still ambiguous. In this review, the authors systematically summarize the regulation tactics for optimizing the catalytic activity and durability of Fe-based SACs toward oxygen electrocatalysis through different electronic structure adjustment methods, including the modulation of coordination atoms, metallic regulation, and the substrate effect. Ultimately, the challenges and future perspectives in the further development of Fe-based SACs are proposed.</description>
      <author>Xiaochen Wang, Zhiwen Kang, Dan Wang, Yafei Zhao, Xu Xiang, Huishan Shang, Bing Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109268</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photoinduced Mitigation of Solid Oxide Electrolysis Cell Degradation: Light Healing Effect on Oxygen Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02754</link>
      <description>Guangyu Deng, Jia-Wei Mei, Xiuxiu Yin, J. L. Han, Menglin Wang, Chenyu Xu, Yanwei Zhang, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391491047

                Hydrogen energy, central to modern energy storage, is promising for use in solid oxide electrolysis cells (SOECs) due to its efficiency and production rate. However, the degradation of SOECs, possibly due to altered oxygen distribution, remains a significant challenge. This study introduces light as a method to stabilize the oxygen distribution and enhance oxygen vacancies, thus countering cell degradation. Using an LSM/GDC/YSZ/Ni-YSZ SOEC, we illuminated the LSM anode and identified a unique &#8220;light healing effect&#8221; (LHE). This effect, distinct from the photothermal influence, showcased a photoinduced hydrogen yield improvement of 270.1 mmol/m2/h, an 11.7% increase over that in the dark, at 800 &#176;C and 0.8 V. In the stability test, the cell exhibited no degradation and remained stable for 50 h with the LHE, compared to a 10.95% decrease in the dark. We consistently observed the LHE across diverse tests, including tests with traditional anodes (LSM, LSC, and LSCF) and orthogonal experiments ranging from 600 to 800 &#176;C and from 0.8 to 2 V. Our findings suggest that the LHE mechanism may be tied to the creation and buildup of photoinduced oxygen vacancies, which indicates an innovative way to avoid deactivation and even improve the performance of SOEC systems.</description>
      <author>Guangyu Deng, Jia-Wei Mei, Xiuxiu Yin, J. L. Han, Menglin Wang, Chenyu Xu, Yanwei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c02754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous hydrogel electrodes with flexible framework exhibiting enhanced mass transport for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc04632j</link>
      <description>Ritsuki Nakajima, Hiroki Wago, Tatsuya Taniguchi, Yuta Sasaki, Yoshinori Nishiki, Zaenal Awaludin, Takaaki Nakai, Akihisa Kato, Mitsushima Mitsushima, Yoshiyuki Kuroda, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391509597

                Mesoporous hydrogel electrodes with unique flexible mesopores surrounded by CoOOH nanosheets were prepared via the electrochemical deposition of hybrid cobalt hydroxide nanosheets, exhibiting high oxygen evolution reaction activity at a...</description>
      <author>Ritsuki Nakajima, Hiroki Wago, Tatsuya Taniguchi, Yuta Sasaki, Yoshinori Nishiki, Zaenal Awaludin, Takaaki Nakai, Akihisa Kato, Mitsushima Mitsushima, Yoshiyuki Kuroda</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc04632j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice oxygen activation and local electric field enhancement by co-doping Fe and F in CoO nanoneedle arrays for industrial electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45320-0</link>
      <description>Pengcheng Ye, Keming Fang, Haiyan Wang, Yahao Wang, Hao Huang, Chin-Chieh Mo, Jiqiang Ning, Yong Hu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391512123

                Abstract Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical to renewable energy conversion technologies, but the structure-activity relationships and underlying catalytic mechanisms in catalysts are not fully understood. We herein demonstrate a strategy to promote OER with simultaneously achieved lattice oxygen activation and enhanced local electric field by dual doping of cations and anions. Rough arrays of Fe and F co-doped CoO nanoneedles are constructed, and a low overpotential of 277 mV at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 is achieved. The dually doped Fe and F could cooperatively tailor the electronic properties of CoO, leading to improved metal-oxygen covalency and stimulated lattice oxygen activation. Particularly, Fe doping induces a synergetic effect of tip enhancement and proximity effect, which effectively concentrates OH &#8722; ions, optimizes reaction energy barrier and promotes O 2 desorption. This work demonstrates a conceptual strategy to couple lattice oxygen and local electric field for effective electrocatalytic water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Pengcheng Ye, Keming Fang, Haiyan Wang, Yahao Wang, Hao Huang, Chin-Chieh Mo, Jiqiang Ning, Yong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-45320-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable 1T&#8208;MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; by Facile Phase Transition Synthesis for Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202301251</link>
      <description>Ranjith Kumar Dharman, Hyeonae Im, Mrinal Kanti Kabiraz, Jeong&#8208;Hyeon Kim, Kiran P. Shejale, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Jeong Woo Han, Sung Yeol Kim, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391512635

                Abstract The 1T phase of MoS 2 exhibits much higher electrocatalytic activity and better stability than the 2H phase. However, the harsh conditions of 1T phase synthesis remain a significant challenge for various extensions and applications of MoS 2 . In this work, a simple hydrothermal&#8208;based synthesis method for the phase transition of MoS 2 is being developed. For this, the NH 2 &#8208;MIL&#8208;125(Ti) (Ti MOF) is successfully utilized to induce the phase transition of MoS 2 from 2H to 1T, achieving a high conversion ratio of &#8776;78.3%. The optimum phase&#8208;induced MoS 2 /Ti MOF heterostructure demonstrates enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, showing an overpotential of 290 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . The density functional theory (DFT) calculations are demonstrating the benefits of this phase transition, determining the electronic properties and OER performance of MoS 2 .</description>
      <author>Ranjith Kumar Dharman, Hyeonae Im, Mrinal Kanti Kabiraz, Jeong&#8208;Hyeon Kim, Kiran P. Shejale, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Jeong Woo Han, Sung Yeol Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202301251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impacts of Graphene Nanoribbon Production Methods on Oxygen&#8208;Reduction Electrocatalysis in Different Environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400083</link>
      <description>Eduardo S. F. Cardoso, Guilherme V. Fortunato, Clauber D. Rodrigues, Fausto E. B J&#250;nior, Marc Ledendecker, Marcos R.V. Lanza, Gilberto Maia, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391513539

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eduardo S. F. Cardoso, Guilherme V. Fortunato, Clauber D. Rodrigues, Fausto E. B J&#250;nior, Marc Ledendecker, Marcos R.V. Lanza, Gilberto Maia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400083</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous-crystalline interface coupling induced highly active ultrathin NiFe oxy-hydroxide design towards accelerated alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115354</link>
      <description>Hongyu Wang, Haijie Sun, Shuyi Cao, Yanji Wang, Xiaohang Du, Jingde Li, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391513950

                Amorphous NiFe-based oxyhydroxides can provide abundant active sites for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline water splitting, but their disordered atomic arrangement leads to severe charge accumulation and electrochemical polarization at high current density. To address this issue, a crystalline Fe2O3 supported ultrathin amorphous NiFe oxy-hydroxide amorphous-crystalline interface coupling design is proposed. In this design, the interfacial Fe3+ in Fe2O3 as a strong Lewis acid is conducive for trapping the electrons in amorphous NiFe(OH)x, reducing the surface charge accumulation, electrochemical polarization, and improves its OER performance. Meanwhile, in-situ Raman, in-situ IR and XPS analysis reveal that, the electrons transfer is accompanied with Ni2+ oxidation into the highly OER active Ni3+ species. Benefited from this design, the OER overpotentials of the resulting NiFe(OH)x/Fe2O3NAs catalyst are measured to be 111 and 233 mV at 10 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively, superior than many reported OER electrocatalysts. The anion exchange membrane electrolyzer using NiFe(OH)x/Fe2O3NAs delivers a current density of 600 mA cm&#8722;2 at a small cell voltage of 1.75 V, and exhibits excellent stability performance in high-current&#8211;density condition. This work provides a promising alternative strategy for the development of high-performance amorphous OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongyu Wang, Haijie Sun, Shuyi Cao, Yanji Wang, Xiaohang Du, Jingde Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous RE&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Ce&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Fluorite Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c14977</link>
      <description>Sreya Paladugu, Ibrahim Munkaila Abdullahi, Harcharan Singh, Sam Spinuzzi, Manashi Nath, Katharine Page, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391514994

                Developing highly active and stable electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is key to improving the efficiency and practical application of various sustainable energy technologies including water electrolysis, CO2 reduction, and metal air batteries. Here, we use evaporation-induced self-assembly (EISA) to synthesize highly porous fluorite nanocatalysts with a high surface area. In this study, we demonstrate that a 50% rare-earth cation substitution for Ce in the CeO2 fluorite lattice improves the OER activity and stability by introducing oxygen vacancies into the host lattice, which results in a decrease in the adsorption energy of the OH* intermediate in the OER. Among the binary fluorite compositions investigated, Nd2Ce2O7 is shown to display the lowest OER overpotential of 243 mV, achieved at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2, and excellent cycling stability in an alkaline medium. Importantly, we demonstrate that rare-earth oxide OER electrocatalysts with high activity and stability can be achieved using the EISA synthesis route without the incorporation of transition and noble metals.</description>
      <author>Sreya Paladugu, Ibrahim Munkaila Abdullahi, Harcharan Singh, Sam Spinuzzi, Manashi Nath, Katharine Page</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c14977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial coordinated iron-nitrogen-carbon as efficient electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution and oxygen redox reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109588</link>
      <description>Yanan Zhou, Li Sheng, Lanlan Chen, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391515429

                Designing highly active electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution and reduction reactions (OER and ORR) is pivotal to renewable energy technology. Herein, based on density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we systematically investigate the catalytic activity of iron-nitrogen-carbon based covalent organic frameworks (COF) monolayers with axially coordinated ligands (denotes as FeN4-X@COF, X refers to axial ligand, X= -SCN, -I, -H, -SH, -NO2, -Br, -ClO, -Cl, -HCO3, -NO, -ClO2, -OH, -CN and -F). The calculated results demonstrate that all the catalysts possess good thermodynamic and electrochemical stabilities. The different ligands axially ligated to the Fe active center could induce changes in the charge of the Fe center, which further regulates the interaction strength between intermediates and catalysts that governs the catalytic activity. Importantly, FeN4-SH@COF and FeN4-OH@COF are efficient bifunctional catalysts for HER and OER, FeN4-OH@COF and FeN4-I@COF are promising bifunctional catalysts for OER and ORR. These findings not only reveal promising bifunctional HER/OER and OER/ORR catalysts but also provide theoretical guidance for designing optimum iron-nitrogen-carbon based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yanan Zhou, Li Sheng, Lanlan Chen, Wenhua Zhang, Jinlong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Desiging Asymmetrical Tmn4 Sites Via Phosphorous or Sulfur Dual Coordination as High-Performanceelectrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4716365</link>
      <description>Xia Zhe, Jinzhong Tian, Rui Tan, Hua Hou, Xinyu Zhang, Yuhong Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391523080

                The development of highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts based on more cost-effective and earth-abundant elements is of great significance and still faces a huge challenge. In this work, a series of transition metal (TM) embedding a new-defined monolayer carbon nitride phase is theoretically profiled and constructed as a catalytic platform for OER studies. Typically, a four-step screening strategy was proposed to rapidly identified high performance candidates and the coordination structure and catalytic performance relationship was thoroughly analyzed. Moreover, the eliminating criterion was established to condenses valid range based on the Gibbs free energy of OH*. Our results reveal that the as-constructed 2FeCN/P exhibits superior activity toward OER with an ultralow overpotential of 0.25 V, at the same time, the established 3FeCN/S configuration performed well as a bifunctional OER/ORR electrocatalysis with extremely lower overpotential &#951;OER/&#951;ORR of 0.26/0.48 V. Overall, this work provides an effective framework for screening advanced OER catalysts, which can also be extended to the complex multistep catalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Xia Zhe, Jinzhong Tian, Rui Tan, Hua Hou, Xinyu Zhang, Yuhong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4716365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Mesoporous Carbon Nanostructures as a Bifunctional Electrode for All Quasi&#8208;Solid&#8208;State Supercapacitor and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admt.202301797</link>
      <description>Muzahir Iqbal, Nilesh G. Saykar, Abhijeet Singh, Imtiaz Ahmed, Anil Arya, Krishna Kanta Haldar, S. K. Mahapatra, Advanced Materials Technologies. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391537477

                Abstract 2D transition&#8208;metal sulfides have developed as favorable electroactive materials for electrochemical energy storage and conversion applications. In this work, WS 2 /mesoporous carbon (MC) is developed by a one&#8208;step hydrothermal technique for supercapacitor and oxygen evaluation reaction (OER) application. However, the metal sulfides have poor rate and cyclic performance due to the aggregations between two layers of structures restricting their performance. The interaction between WS 2 nanosheets and MC produces a synergistic effect, resulting in a decent electrochemical energy storage and conversion application. The synthesized materials used to prepare quasi&#8208;solid&#8208;state symmetric (QSSS) and asymmetric (QSSA) supercapacitor configuration enable the highest specific capacitance ( C SP ) of 305.45 F g &#8722;1 and 204.21 F g &#8722;1 @ 10 mV s &#8722;1 , respectively. Moreover, the specific energy and power density of QSSS and QSSA devices are 31.1 Wh kg &#8722;1 @824.95 W kg &#8722;1 and 24.74 Wh kg &#8722;1 @549.84 W kg &#8722;1 , respectively. Additionally, the multifunctionality of the synthesized binary nanocomposite is also tested for OER. The composite shows a desirable over potential of 307 mV in 6 m KOH electrolyte, with a 69 mV dec &#8722;1 Tafel slope. The dual role of WS 2 /MC for energy storage and oxygen evaluation reaction conversion reveals the potential of metal sulfides.</description>
      <author>Muzahir Iqbal, Nilesh G. Saykar, Abhijeet Singh, Imtiaz Ahmed, Anil Arya, Krishna Kanta Haldar, S. K. Mahapatra</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admt.202301797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Photoelectrochemically Enhanced Oxygen Evolution reaction via Thin Films of novel (1:2:1) SnO-Mn2O3-TiO2 hybrid nanotubes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104034</link>
      <description>Rabia Naeem, Sehar Shakir, Shahzad Sharif, Saba Afzal, Shahid Bashir, Muhammad Adil Mansoor, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391538514

                The oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions play a significant role in overall water splitting. The photoelectrochemical water splitting offers a high potential for conversion efficiency at low voltage and temperature. Therefore, in the present work comparative studies of novel (1:2:1)) SnO-Mn2O3-TiO2 (SMT) ternary and SnO-Mn2O3 (SM), SnO-TiO2 (ST) and Mn2O3-TiO2 (MT) binary mixed-metal oxides thin films for hydrogen generation are performed. method. The Aerosol Assisted Chemical Vapor Deposition (AACVD) fabricated thin films were analyzed through X-ray diffraction (XRD), Raman spectroscopy, scanning electron microscopy (SEM) coupled with energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), X-ray photoelectron microscopy (XPS) and UV-visible spectroscopy to determine the crystallinity, surface morphology, binding energy, and band gaps. The Photoelectrochemical studies demonstrate that the SnO-Mn2O3-TiO2 (SMT) thin film yields 1.96, 2.37, and 2.7 times maximum current density than the binary SnO-Mn2O3 (SM), SnO-TiO2 (ST) and Mn2O3-TiO2 (MT) metal oxides, respectively. These results illustrate that due to unique topography, uniform distribution, and good optoelectronic properties of ternary SnO-Mn2O3-TiO2 (SMT) nanotubular layers show better light-harvesting performance as compared to the binary (SM, ST, and MT) metal oxides. Therefore, it is believed that SMT is a promising candidate for energy harvesting applications.</description>
      <author>Rabia Naeem, Sehar Shakir, Shahzad Sharif, Saba Afzal, Shahid Bashir, Muhammad Adil Mansoor</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Effective Oxygen Evolution Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1595/003214085x2912626</link>
      <description>Tao Dou, Platinum Metals Review. 29(1)] 1985. https://openalex.org/W4391606168

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tao Dou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 1985 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1595/003214085x2912626</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Oxygen Vacancies on Oxygen Evolution: The Case of BiVO_4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02472281mtgabs</link>
      <description>Nicklas &#214;sterbacka, Hassan Ouhbi, Julia Wiktor, Francesco Ambrosio, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(47)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391639104

                Bismuth vanadate, BiVO 4 , is one of the most promising photoanode materials for the challenging oxygen evolution half-reaction in solar-driven water splitting. The material tends to be rich in oxygen vacancies, which strongly affects its photoelectrochemical properties. Experimental evidence suggests that oxygen deficiency is beneficial for the oxygen evolution reaction in the material, but the mechanism behind this enhancement is still controversial. The defects could be involved directly in the reaction if present at the surface, and the occupancy of the defect states could also play an important role. The latter is seldom considered in mechanistic studies, however. Using density functional theory, we show that the surface oxygen vacancy in bismuth vanadate is stablest when fully ionized. We investigate how this affects the oxygen evolution mechanism by mapping out the stablest reaction intermediates and compare the resulting pathway with those on the unionized oxygen-deficient surface as well as the defect-free material. The overpotentials required to drive the reaction in each case are computed to quantify whether or not vacancy formation, and subsequent ionization, improves the thermodynamics of oxygen evolution.</description>
      <author>Nicklas &#214;sterbacka, Hassan Ouhbi, Julia Wiktor, Francesco Ambrosio</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02472281mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposited Ni-Based Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02201255mtgabs</link>
      <description>Yashwardhan Deo, Niklas Thissen, Anna K. Mechler, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(20)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391663002

                Alkaline water electrolysis is one of the most mature technologies for producing green hydrogen. However, there still are possibilities to enhance this process by using better electrocatalysts for the kinetically limited oxygen evolution reaction (OER). While there are several existing methods for catalyst synthesis, such as spray coating, coprecipitation and hydrothermal synthesis, they face challenges of either versatility or scalability. [1,2] In this regard, electrodeposition is a promising catalyst synthesis method, due to its excellent process control and ease of scalability. In this work, electrodeposition is used to prepare nickel-based catalysts as a benchmark system. These catalysts are deposited on expanded Ni-mesh supports. Initially, the deposition parameters are optimized to obtain uniform Ni deposits, which provide reproducible activity measurements. Herein, we observe that the deposited Ni catalysts exhibit better OER activities than the Ni mesh support, most likely due to the evolution of a pyramidal morphology with an increased surface area (Fig. 1). The optimized deposition parameters are further used to deposit different Ni-based alloys such as Ni-Fe and Ni-Co, by adding the respective ionized metal species to the Ni electrolyte. The microstructure and composition of these catalysts is analyzed using material characterization techniques like scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX). Finally, the OER activity and long-term stability of the deposited catalysts is evaluated in an in-house developed electrochemical beaker cell at elevated concentration, temperature, and current densities (30 wt.% KOH, 80 &#176;C, up to 1 A/cm 2 ). The results obtained for the different catalysts are compared to understand the correlation of the catalyst structure and composition with their electrochemical OER performance under industrial conditions. Bibliography [1] Lu Xunyu et al.; Nature Communications; DOI: 10.1038/ncomms7616 [2] Zuraya Angeles-Olvera et al.; Energies ; DOI: 10.3390/en15051609 Figure 1</description>
      <author>Yashwardhan Deo, Niklas Thissen, Anna K. Mechler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02201255mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Activities of High-Entropy Oxides for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02542604mtgabs</link>
      <description>Yun-Hyuk Choi, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(54)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391638064

                Electrocatalytic water-splitting hydrogen generation consists of the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), where the four-electron-relevant OER is the rate-determining step. So far, there have been many efforts to substitute for the highly expensive noble-metal electrocatalysts (platinum, ruthenium or rhodium oxides, etc.). Transition-metal oxides based on Co, Ni, Mn, and V have been suggested as such alternatives, due to their low cost, high efficiency, and high stability. Recently, since the compositional diversity can provide a new breakthrough in that area, a high-entropy oxide (HEO) with five transition-metal cations has been suggested as a promising electrocatalyst toward the OER. In our studies, two kinds of HEOs were prepared and their OER activities were investigated. To begin with, for the (Mg 0.2 Fe 0.2 Co 0.2 Ni 0.2 Cu 0.2 )O, the effect of constituent cations on the OER activity was unveiled. Furthermore, a core cation driving the high OER activity was found. For it, the medium-entropy oxides (MEOs) with four cations are prepared by subtracting each cation (Mg, Fe, Co, Ni, or Cu) from the HEO, exhibiting homogeneous morphology, equiatomic composition, and single-phase rocksalt structure. As a result, it is found that the highest concentration of Co 3+ in the MEO (w/o Cu) leads to the best OER activity, and thus Co 3+ is the core ion driving the high OER activity. Furthermore, it is regarded that Cu 2+ ions prevent the conversion of Co or Fe cations from 2 + to 3 + in the HEO and MEOs. Accordingly, maximizing the concentration of Co 3+ within electrocatalysts is suggested as an effective design strategy for the high-efficiency electrocatalysts based on high or medium entropy materials. Secondly, the relationship between structure and OER activity was elucidated for the (Mg 0.2 Fe 0.2 Co 0.2 Zn 0.2 Cu 0.2 )O with a temperature-dependent rocksalt-to-spinel transition.</description>
      <author>Yun-Hyuk Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02542604mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Evolution Reaction with ZrCo and ZrNi Electrode Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422147mtgabs</link>
      <description>Sylvain Le Tonquesse, S. G. Altendorf, Yuri Grin, Iryna Antonyshyn, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(42)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391638760

                Investigation of the intermetallic compounds as anode materials for water electrolysis helps to solve a lot of issues, which electrocatalysis and solid state chemistry communities face nowadays. Intermetallic compounds possess unique properties in terms of their crystal structure, electronic properties and chemical bonding, allowing the knowledge-based route for electrocatalyst development. Furthermore, usage of the single-phase anode material is a way to exclude the influence of interface as well as nature and stability issues of the support. At the same time, studies of the intermetallic compounds under the reaction conditions shed light onto the chemical properties of the intermetallic compounds, which are scarcely described in literature and of particular importance for solid state chemistry field. In this study, binary intermetallic compounds ZrCo and ZrNi were studied as anode materials for alkaline water electrolysis. The successful synthesis of single-phase samples of both compounds was followed by manufacturing of the cylindrically-shaped electrodes using spark plasma sintering technique. The assessment of the electrocatalytic performance was carried out in three-electrode cell, applying different measurement protocols, giving the information about OER activity of studied materials, its stability over time as well as other electrochemical features, giving the information about the processes occurring on the electrode surfaces. To monitor the material changes under conditions of OER, the electrodes were comprehensively characterized before and after the electrochemical experiments using bulk- and surface-sensitive techniques. Combined data was discussed and compared with state-of-the-art OER electrocatalysts for alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Sylvain Le Tonquesse, S. G. Altendorf, Yuri Grin, Iryna Antonyshyn</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422147mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gas Diffusion Electrode for Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst Testing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02371726mtgabs</link>
      <description>Vinod Kumar Puthiyapura, Christopher Mark Zalitis, James Stevens, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(37)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391638856

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the major contributors of efficiency loss in water electrolysis and consequently, development of OER catalysts to improve the electrolyser efficiency is a major reasearch theme in the field. Though the current commercial PEMWE may operate at anode potential &lt;1.60 V, futue PEMWE may operate at potential higher than this as the drive to operate PEMWE at high current density is inceasing. Inorder to achieve this, an active and stable catalyst is required that can operate at this regime. Also, the potential experienced by the anode during the startup/shutdown of an electrolyser are different to the steady state value. Conventional OER testing involves catalysts coated on a conductive substrate submerged in an electrolyte solution, in a three electrode cell. However, such techniques are generally limited to low current densities due to oxygen bubble formation and site blocking at high current density limiting the system to study the OER kinetics below realistic operating current density. Although Rotating Disk Electrode(RDE) is widely employed to mitigate this, the RDE system is still not effective enough to remove the bubbles 1 . A floating electrode system developed by Kucernak et al 2 shows that combining direct access with a lower catalyst loading improves the O 2 gas mass transport and a higher current density could be achieved for the ORR. This technique also used for OER by Arenz et al. 3 , for easier bubble removal. Combining these two above mentioned systems, we have developed a new GDE cell system which allows screening of OER catalyst at industrially relevant current densities. This cell allows to study the OER kinetics at very realistic voltage/current regime and the information obtained helps to develop more active/stable catalyst. The OER catalyst diagnostics test from our GDE cell was comparable to the standard three electrode cell with an additional advantage of extended potential window upto 1.80 V vs.RHE. Preliminary results obtained from our study shows a promising opportunity to study the OER at high current densities. Reference FathiTovini, A.Hartig-Wei&#223;, H.A.Gasteigerand, H.A.El Sayed, Journal of The ElectrochemicalSociety, 2021, 168, 014512. M.Zalitis,D.KramerandA.R.Kucernak,Phys.Chem.Chem.Phys.,2013,15,4329-4340 Schr&#246;der,V.A.Mints,A.Bornet,E.Berner,M.FathiTovini,J.Quinson,etal., JACS Au 2021,1(3),247-25</description>
      <author>Vinod Kumar Puthiyapura, Christopher Mark Zalitis, James Stevens</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02371726mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin States and Spin Order in Perovskite Oxide Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02472304mtgabs</link>
      <description>Emma van der Minne, Achim F&#252;ngerlings, Marcus Wohlgemuth, Gertjan Koster, Felix Gunkel, Rossitza Pentcheva, Christoph Baeumer, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(47)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391638550

                The &#8216;power-to-hydrogen&#8217; strategy aims at splitting water into O 2 and H 2 via the oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions. The complex four-step oxygen evolution reaction (OER) limits the overall efficiency of hydrogen production. An important reason of the low efficiency is that the production of ground-state (triplet) O 2 is a spin-forbidden reaction: in fact, the reactants, OH - or H 2 O, are diamagnetic, but the final product, O 2 , is a paramagnetic molecule. Recently, this was well-recognized theoretically 1 and the use of spin selective catalysts was described as a possible way to promote the OER. 2 . However, it remains complex to understand and exploit intrinsic and extrinsic magnetic features to enhance catalytic performance. Here, we investigate the role of magnetic moments in individual active sites in the catalyst surface layer and the role of spin order in ferromagnetic vs. paramagnetic catalysts, focussing on perovskite oxides. First, we investigated the role of Ni magnetic moment in the the (001), (110) and (111) facet of LaNiO 3 electrocatalysts, which we studied using electrochemical measurements, X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS), and density functional theory (DFT+ U ) calculations. 3 The results show a facet-dependent activity, where the (111) overpotential is ~60 mV lower as compared to the other facets. Closer investigation of the (001) and (111) facets reveals a surface transformation to a oxyhydroxide-like NiOO with edge-sharing octahedra, 4 and we observed that the transformed surface is thicker for (111) than for (001). 3 The detailed DFT+ U analysis reveals important distinctions that give rise to the increased activity: the transformed LaNiO 3 (111) surface exhibits a better match to the underlying perovskite layer. Moreover, protonation induces reduced Ni 3+ with a finite magnetic moment. A moderate Jahn-Teller distortion enables a favorable binding of reaction intermediates. In contrast, the structural mismatch to the underlying LaNiO 3 (001)-substrate leads to a strong distortion of the transformed layer for this orientation and a weak binding of *O and ultimately to a different potential determining step (PDS), *OH&#8594;*O, compared to *O&#8594;*OOH for the transformed LaNiO 3 (111) surface. Second, we experimentally demonstrate the effect of intrinsic magnetic order on the OER on catalytic performance. Thin films of La 0.67 Sr 0.33 MnO 3 grown by pulsed laser deposition with appropriate magnetic and electronic properties were chosen as well-defined model systems. Using the ferromagnetic to paramagnetic transition at the Curie temperature in these ferromagnetic perovskite oxides, the magnetic order of the catalysts were switched in situ during the OER by changing the temperature. For ferromagnetic films, the decrease in current density with decreasing temperature, induced by the reduction of thermal energy, was suppressed for temperatures below the Curie temperature, indicating that the presence of ferromagnetic ordering below Curie temperature enhances OER activity. This claim is further supported by an enhancement of OER activity for the same ferromagnetic film upon alignment of magnetic domains with an external magnetic field. All in all, our results reveal that the spin state, intrinsic spin order, and extrinsic magnetic fields are decisive for the OER activity. Biz, C., Fianchini, M. &amp; Gracia, J. Strongly Correlated Electrons in Catalysis: Focus on Quantum Exchange. ACS Catal 11 , 14249&#8211;14261 (2021). Sun, Y. et al. Spin&#8208;Related Electron Transfer and Orbital Interactions in Oxygen Electrocatalysis. Advanced Materials 32 , 2003297 (2020). F&#252;ngerlings, A. et al. Crystal-facet-dependent surface transformation dictates the oxygen evolution reaction activity in lanthanum nickelate. in preparation (2023). Baeumer, C. et al. Tuning electrochemically driven surface transformation in atomically flat LaNiO 3 thin films for enhanced water electrolysis. Nat Mater 20 , 674&#8211;682 (2021).</description>
      <author>Emma van der Minne, Achim F&#252;ngerlings, Marcus Wohlgemuth, Gertjan Koster, Felix Gunkel, Rossitza Pentcheva, Christoph Baeumer</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02472304mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Role of Cracks in Active Oxygen Species Formation during Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02653164mtgabs</link>
      <description>Sihong Wang, Fang Song, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(65)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391663336

                Understanding the formation and location of catalytic intermediates is crucial for unraveling the mechanism of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), a key process in electrochemical water splitting. Despite the availability of various in-situ and ex-situ characterization methods, the formation and location of intermediates remain elusive, hindering the development of more efficient electrocatalysts. In this work, we discovered a stable static active oxygen species formed during the chemical oxidation of cobalt hydroxide flakes, providing a unique opportunity to probe the intermediates involved in OER. We are able to monitor the equilibrium conversion between stable peroxo structure and superoxo radical via EPR and Raman test, shedding light on the nature of the active oxygen species. In addition, CoOOH flakes with cracks were synthesized via controlled chemical oxidation, enabling the investigation of the role of crack/edge structures in the electrocatalytic activity. Statistical regression analysis combining morphological features, electrochemical performance, and Raman spectroscopy confirmed a strong correlation between morphology evolution, OER activity, and active oxygen species, highlighting the importance of controlling the morphology of electrocatalysts for enhancing their performance. Therefore, we propose that the source of active oxygen intermediates can be attributed to the presence of crack/edge structures. The crack-rich CoOOH exhibit significantly higher current density at a lower overpotential, providing a new direction for the design of efficient water oxidation electrocatalysts. Overall, this work offers important insights into the mechanism of OER and provides a basis for the development of more efficient and sustainable electrocatalysts for energy conversion and storage.</description>
      <author>Sihong Wang, Fang Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02653164mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten Oxide-Based Materials as Catalyst Support for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422096mtgabs</link>
      <description>Yung&#8208;Tin Pan, Lu Yu Chueh, Yu-Wei Hsu, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(42)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391663247

                The high cost of iridium (Ir) is a major concern for the large scale deployment of polymer electrolyte membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). To mitigate its impact, the usage of Ir on the anode must be significantly reduced. Down-sizing the catalyst particle is a straight forward strategy but requires the use of appropriate support materials to disperse and anchor fine Ir nanoparticles. We have investigated the use of tungsten oxide-based materials as support for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) Ir and ruthenium (Ru) catalyst. The synthesis of nanostructured substoichiometric tungsten oxide and the subsequent loading of ultrafine Ir/Ru-based nanoparticles is thoroughly studied. Due to the successful loading, the mass activity of the tungsten oxide-supported Ir/Ru-based catalyst shows significant improvements under rotating disk electrode (RDE) conditions compared with commercially available Ir/Ru-blacks. Furthermore, non-destructive depth profiling by synchrotron-based X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) has revealed the strong catalyst-support interaction which suppressed the oxidation of the supported Ir/Ru-based catalysts, leading to much enhanced durability under accelerated durability testing conditions. To verify its performance under practical PEM electrolysis conditions, the tungsten oxide-supported OER catalyst is directly coated onto a polymer electrolyte membrane, i.e., forming a catalyst coated membrane (CCM), and tested under single cell testing conditions without pressure differential. The voltage dependent chemical state of the supported catalyst is also probed in-situ by synchrotron-based XPS where a potential dependent electron transfer between the catalyst and tungsten-oxide support is discovered. Our discovery is anticipated to aid the development of cost effective PEM electrolysis anodes.</description>
      <author>Yung&#8208;Tin Pan, Lu Yu Chueh, Yu-Wei Hsu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422096mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ionomer-Dependent Oxygen Evolution Reaction in a Half-Cell and a Liquid Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02391892mtgabs</link>
      <description>Joy Marie Mora, Guangfu Li, Po&#8208;Ya Abel Chuang, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(39)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391638465

                Electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is an important area of research due to its significance in water electrolysis, which contributes to the clean-energy storage and conversion techniques. OER exhibits irreversible and sluggish kinetics, which necessitates a high overpotential to achieve the desired reaction rate. In an alkaline medium, non-precious metals (such as Ni, Fe, Co) or metal-free materials (such as 3d-transition metal oxides and heteroatom-doped carbons) can replace expensive iridium and ruthenium oxides, which is otherwise required in an acidic medium to facilitate the reaction. However, developing new catalysts for alkaline OER is limited by the scaling relations among adsorption energetics of key intermediates (i.e., OOH*, OH*, and O*). The electrochemical reaction kinetics depends critically on the nature of the interface between catalyst and the electrolyte where an electrical double layer (EDL) forms during OER. The current understanding of the EDL structure involves the interfacial interactions between adsorbates and catalyst layer (CL) which can be modified to improve the reaction efficiency. Ionomers are essential components of the CL and are vital in uniformly dispersing catalyst particles in ink solution. The ionomers also act as binder for the catalyst particles in the CL, helping to improve the electrode&#8217;s durability and stability over time. In addition, despite the fact that ionomers affect the properties of EDL, the impact of ionomer on the reaction pathway is often overlooked in electrocatalytic research. In this study, we investigate the role of ionomer in the catalyst layer by comparing different polymer dispersions, including PTFE, Nafion, and commercial As-4. The results indicate that the Nafion-contained CL performs better than other polymer CLs in TF-RDE/RRDE, as it facilitates direct O*-O* coupling. In contrast, anionic ionomer demonstrates superior long-term stability in alkaline liquid electrolyzers, despite oxidization degradation.</description>
      <author>Joy Marie Mora, Guangfu Li, Po&#8208;Ya Abel Chuang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02391892mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into the Structure Sensitivity of Fe-Based Materials for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02542547mtgabs</link>
      <description>Ricardo Alberto Hincapi&#233; Isaza, Viktor &#268;oli&#263;, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(54)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391663581

                The conversion of renewable energy into storable fuels is fundamental to the meeting of the net-zero CO 2 emissions objective by 2050. However, the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the poor stability of electrocatalysts at industrial-level currents remain a problem for electrolyzers 1 . Using platinum group metal-free electrocatalysts in anion exchange membrane electrolyzers is an appealing strategy to overcome some of the problems associated with PEM electrolyzers. Fe-based materials offer the possibility for the development of active, stable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts for the OER in alkaline media. In this work, we explore the influence of structure, composition, or crystalline phase on different Fe-based electrodes for the OER. Different fabrication procedures such as additive manufacturing 2 , flame spray synthesis, or pulse laser ablation 3 allow us to have a wide range of Fe-based materials with a well-defined structure/composition/phase. The materials have been extensively characterized by physicochemical methods (XPS, Raman, XRD, ICP) and their electrocatalytic activity evaluates following careful procedures in order to obtain reliable results. The results show that the activity of Fe-rich electrodes is poor. However, if Fe is alloyed with other materials or its surface structure or crystallinity degree is modified, it results in a more active material. This information could guide the synthesis of more active and stable water-splitting materials. References S. Cherevko, S. Geiger, O. Kasian, N. Kulyk, J.-P. Grote, A. Savan, B. R. Shrestha, S. Merzlikin, B. Breitbach, A. Ludwig, and K. J. J. Mayrhofer, Catalysis Today, 262 170-180 (2016). J. Wegner, R. Mart&#237;nez-Hincapi&#233;, V. &#268;oli&#263;, and S. Kleszczynski, Advanced Materials Interfaces, n/a (n/a), 2202499 (2023). J. Johny, Y. Li, M. Kamp, O. Prymak, S.-X. Liang, T. Krekeler, M. Ritter, L. Kienle, C. Rehbock, S. Barcikowski, and S. Reichenberger, Nano Research, 15 (6), 4807-4819 (2022).</description>
      <author>Ricardo Alberto Hincapi&#233; Isaza, Viktor &#268;oli&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02542547mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium Single Atom Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422087mtgabs</link>
      <description>Jean Rouger, Sara Cavaliere, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Deborah J. Jones, Fabien Dufour, Maureen Georges, Julien Thuilliez, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(42)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391638495

                In order to reduce CO 2 emissions and produce clean hydrogen one solution is to use sustainable energies (wind, solar or hydraulic) coupled with water electrolyser to produce H 2 and store it before use it in fuel cell. The electrolyzer based on proton exchange membranes (PEM) is a promising technology because it can reach high current density (2 A.cm -2 ) [1] and can be easily coupled with intermittent energy sources [2]. However, the acidic conditions and working temperatures (80 &#176;C) require the use of noble metals. On the anode side the oxidative condition prevents the use of carbon supported catalyst and the best catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) so far is IrO x . The use of Ir single atom catalyst (SAC) supported on conducting oxide is a promising way to reduce the quantity of the scarce and expensive noble metal, increasing the electroactive surface and durability. SACs present an excellent dispersion and activity [3] and some conducting oxides are very promising regarding electrical conductivity and stability under oxidative conditions [4]. There are different approaches to prepare Ir SAC (wet impregnation, co-precipitation, photoelectrochemical reduction...) [3], whose success mainly depends on the nature of the Ir precursor, its interaction with the support and the thermal treatment temperature/duration. Some research groups have prepared and characterized Ir SAC on indium-tin oxide [5] but the activity and stability still need to be improved. The objective of this communication is to present the synthesis and the characterization of Ir SAC on different conducting oxide supports. Ir precursor was synthesized and deposed on various supports. The physical characterization entails XRD, TEM, MEB, EDX to assess the morphology and composition of the catalyst. Spectroscopic analysis like XPS and XAS brings information on the chemical environment of Ir sites, while electrochemical measurements give information on the OER activity and stability of the catalyst. References [1] C.D. Ferreira da Silva et al. , ACS Catal. , 2021 , 11, 4107-4116 [2] O. Schmidt et al. , Int. J. Hydrog. Energy , 2017 , 42, 30471-30492 [3] J. Liu, ACS Catal. , 2017 , 7, 34-59 [4] Moriau et al. , ChemCatChem , 2022 , 14, e202200586 [5] D. Lebedev et al., ACS Cent. Sci. 2020 , 6, 1189-1198 [6] Q. Wang et al. , ACS Catal., 2020 , 142, 7425-7433</description>
      <author>Jean Rouger, Sara Cavaliere, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Jaouen, Deborah J. Jones, Fabien Dufour, Maureen Georges, Julien Thuilliez</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422087mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Study on Inhibition of Oxygen Evolution in Layered Cathode Materials during Charging</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-025828mtgabs</link>
      <description>Kuan-Yu Lin, Shaohui Xu, Santhanamoorthi Nachimuthu, Jyh&#8208;Chiang Jiang, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(5)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391662769

                In recent years, Ni, Mn-based layered cathode materials (Li 1.2 Ni 0.2 Mn 0.6 O 2 , LiNi 1-x-y Co x Mn y O 2 ) have shown great promise for high energy density LIBs. Research has shown that nickel-rich materials are ideal candidates for high-capacity batteries. The valence state from Ni 2+ to Ni 4+ allows more Li + to transfer between the cathode and anode, providing excellent electrochemical performance. However, the oxidation of oxygen atoms triggers irreversible structural rearrangements on the surface, while Ni 3+ introduces Jahn-Teller distortion. At high voltages, the stability of layered cathode materials is severely hampered. We present theoretical work on Li 1.2 Ni 0.2 Mn 0.6 O 2 and LiNi 1-x-y Co x Mn y O 2 using density functional theory, considering cation- and anion-doped surface treatments. We found that doped layered cathode materials successfully suppressed O 2 formation at highly delithiated levels. Through DFT calculations, we understand the mechanism of oxygen evolution from layered cathode materials during the charging process and discover how to suppress oxygen evolution strategies.</description>
      <author>Kuan-Yu Lin, Shaohui Xu, Santhanamoorthi Nachimuthu, Jyh&#8208;Chiang Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-025828mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Interplay of Anodic Passivation and Oxygen Evolution of Medium Entropy Alloys in Artificial Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02111073mtgabs</link>
      <description>Annica Wetzel, &#214;zlem &#214;zcan, Julia Witt, Daniel Morell, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(11)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391639471

                Medium entropy alloys (MEA) have gained increased interest in both academic and industrial sectors due to their favorable mechanical and anti-corrosion properties, rendering them ideal candidates for engineering and potentially catalytic applications. Although previous studies have shown high current densities at high anodic potentials for MEAs, a lack of understanding on the underlying transpassive dissolution and local corrosion behavior remains. This project aimed to investigate and compare the passivation behavior of MEAs CrCoNi and FeCrNi (equimolar) under high anodic potentials, focusing on the mechanisms of transpassive dissolution and the oxygen evolution reaction in artificial seawater. The study utilized various techniques such as scanning electrochemical microscopy (SECM) to instantaneously detect evolving metal species and oxygen, and inductively coupled plasma mass spectrocmetry (ICP-MS) to quantify the dissolved metal species. For these investigations, the alloys were subjected to precisely controlled corrosion loads employing potentiodynamic, potentiostatic, and chronoamperometric methods during the SECM experiments and subsequent ICP-MS analysis. Macroscopic corrosion and passive film properties were studied via potentiodynamic polarization, electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), and X-Ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS). Finally, in-situ atomic force microscopy (AFM) and scanning Kelvin probe force microscopy (SKPFM) were used to analyze the corrosion morphology and surface potentials before, during, and after passivity breakdown. Overall, this study aimed to provide a comprehensive understanding of the interplay between passivation, anodic dissolution and oxygen evolution of the MEAs in artificial seawater.</description>
      <author>Annica Wetzel, &#214;zlem &#214;zcan, Julia Witt, Daniel Morell</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02111073mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Measurement of Enthalpy and Entropy of a Model Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301578</link>
      <description>Joaqu&#237;n Morales-Santelices, Marcel Risch, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391605478

                Experimentally determined thermodynamic parameters are rarely reported for electrocatalytic reactions including the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Yet, they contain unique and valuable mechanistic insight and present a missing link to theoretical investigations. Herein, a protocol for determining thermodynamic properties of the rate determining state and intermediate (RDSI) of the OER is presented. Cobalt oxide is investigated at pH 7 as a case study. Two different approaches are employed: steady state polarization (SSP) that uses chronopotentiometry at different temperatures and current values, and potentiostatic electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (PEIS) at different DC voltages and temperatures. The data is used to fit a 3D plane from which entropy and enthalpy of the RDSI are obtained. The data analysis requires an appropriate filtering of the data. Hence, we discuss suitable figures of merit for establishing appropriate filtering criteria. The values obtained are 0.72 and &#8208;0.39 eV (at 298 K) for enthalpic and entropic contributions, respectively. The obtained values are reproducible for both approaches and consistent with literature.</description>
      <author>Joaqu&#237;n Morales-Santelices, Marcel Risch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supported-Ir Catalysts: The Impact of the Supports' Chemical Composition on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422097mtgabs</link>
      <description>Lucinda Blanco Redondo, Yevheniia Lobko, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Thu Ngan Dinhov&#225;, Tom&#225;&#353; Hrbek, Serhiy Cherevko, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(42)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391663482

                In water electrolyzer cells, the anode electrode is one of the most important components, where the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) takes place. In this process, the water molecules split into oxygen ions, protons, and electrons, and the oxygen gas is produced on the anode surface [1]. The most suitable materials that catalyze OER are ruthenium, iridium, and their oxides, but their cost and scarcity require reduction and enhancement of their utilization [2]. One morphological strategy consists of the dispersion of the active nanoparticles in supportive nanoparticles made of less expensive materials to increase their mass activity. In addition, due to the high potential reached during operating conditions for water splitting, supportive materials have to possess a high corrosion resistance. Titanium oxides are good candidates because of their high thermal and chemical stability, low cost, and commercial availability [3]. But their poor electric conductivity (&#8764;10 &#8722;6 S cm &#8722;1 ) makes the design of an active and stable catalyst a complex task. In this work, Ir nanoparticles have been synthesized on the surface of several Ti-based nanoparticles and a complete analysis of their physicochemical properties have been carried out ( Fig. 1a-b ). In addition, electrochemical behaviour has been tested ex-situ in a half cell by the rotating disk electrode technique and after, the catalysts have been deposited in a polymer membrane for testing in-situ in a single cell proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer. The results show a successful performance of the supported Ir/TiO 2 nanoparticles comparable to the pure Ir black nanoparticles but with an active metal loading five times lower. Differently, even though TiC showed excellent electrical conductivity during the ex-situ characterization, Ir/TiC nanoparticles had a poor activity after just one day of performance in the WE due to the complete oxidation of the TiC into TiO 2 ( Fig. 1c-d ). Finally, Ir/TiB 2 showed a balanced result in terms of activity and stability, showing promising properties as a catalyst for PEM-WE. Sadhasivam T., Ho-Young J. Chapter 3 - Nanostructured bifunctional electrocatalyst support materials for unitized regenerative fuel cells// Nanostructured, Functional, and Flexible Materials for Energy Conversion and Storage Systems- 2020. - 69-103. Antolini E. Iridium as Catalyst and Cocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution /Reduction in Acidic Polymer Electrolyte Membrane Electrolyzers and Fuel Cells // ACS Catal. - 2014.- 4, N 5.- P. 1426-1440. Van Pham C., B&#252;hler M. IrO2 coated TiO2 core-shell microparticles advance performance of low loading proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers// Applied Catalysis B: Environmental-2020.- P 269.- P. 118762. Figure 1. TEM image of Ir/TIO 2 (a), EDX mapping of Ir/TiO 2 (b), linear sweep voltammetry of catalysts (c), the current density at given potential 1.80 V (d). Figure 1</description>
      <author>Lucinda Blanco Redondo, Yevheniia Lobko, Miquel Gam&#243;n Rodr&#237;guez, Thu Ngan Dinhov&#225;, Tom&#225;&#353; Hrbek, Serhiy Cherevko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422097mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Terminated Surface Reconstruction of Lanthanum Nickelates Promotes Alkaline Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02542536mtgabs</link>
      <description>Yi&#8208;Hsuan Wu, Marcel Jan&#225;k, Paula M. Abdala, Denis A. Kuznetsov, Christoph R. M&#252;ller, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(54)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391663278

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) itself is expected to have a strong impact on the state of the surface of the electrocatalyst, yet the actual structure of the surface under operating conditions is rarely considered while formulating structure-activity correlations in electrocatalysis. In this study, changes in the surface structure of Ruddlesden-Popper-type lanthanum nickelate, La 2 NiO 4+&#948; , and the perovskite LaNiO 3 are probed and contrasted using a series of complementary surface sensitive techniques, including XPS, HRTEM and O K-edge XAS. We found noticeable surface changes to occur on La 2 NiO 4+&#948; after exposure its exposure to the alkaline electrolyte that is accompanied by the emergence of a strong Ni n+/n+1 redox feature and the coincides with a 45-fold enhancement of the OER activity (at &#951; = 370 mV) in 0.1 M KOH, as compared to the pristine La 2 NiO 4+&#948; phase. We observe that the in situ formation of an amorphous nickel (oxy)hydroxide layer on the surface increases the electrochemically-active surface area of La 2 NiO 4+&#948; and imparts a high stability of the catalyst under OER conditions (the formation of the amorphous layer self-terminates at ca. 3 nm). In addition, the transition from octahedral Ni sites (O h ) to square-planar Ni sites (D 4h ) in the reconstructed surface was observed using O K-edge X-ray absorption spectroscopy. Further, we found no evidence for any surface transformations in the perovskite-based catalyst LaNiO 3 that also did not demonstrate any improvement in its activity over cycling. This work highlights the importance of a detailed surface analysis of the catalysts under operation to build robust structure-activity correlations for the metal oxides under electrochemical reaction conditions. Figure 1</description>
      <author>Yi&#8208;Hsuan Wu, Marcel Jan&#225;k, Paula M. Abdala, Denis A. Kuznetsov, Christoph R. M&#252;ller</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02542536mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Li+ Cations Activate NiFeOOH for Oxygen Evolution in Sodium and Potassium Hydroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202318692</link>
      <description>Onno van der Heijden, Jordy J.J. Eggebeen, Hanna Trzesniowski, Nipon Deka, Ronny Golnak, Jie Xiao, Maartje van Rijn, Rik V. Mom, Marc T. M. Koper, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391614562

                The efficiency of green hydrogen production is reduced due to the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In addition to the optimal catalyst properties, electrocatalytic activity also depends on the interaction of the electrocatalyst with the electrolyte. Here, we show that the addition of small amounts of Li+ to Fe&#8208;free NaOH or KOH electrolytes activates NiFeOOH for the OER compared to single&#8208;cation electrolytes. Moreover, the activation was maintained when the solution was returned to pure NaOH. Importantly, we show that the origin of activation by Li+ cations is primarily non&#8208;kinetic in nature, as the OER onset for the mixed electrolyte does not change and the Tafel slope at low current density is ~30 mV/dec in both electrolytes. However, the increase of the apparent Tafel slope remains lower at increasing current densities in the presence of Li+. Based on electrochemical quartz crystal microbalance and in situ X&#8208;Ray Absorption Spectroscopy measurements, we show that this reduction of non&#8208;kinetic effects is due to enhanced intercalation of sodium, water and hydroxide in the Li+ activated catalyst. This enhanced electrolyte penetration facilitates the OER, especially at higher current densities and for increased catalyst loading, which is important for industrial electrolyzer systems.</description>
      <author>Onno van der Heijden, Jordy J.J. Eggebeen, Hanna Trzesniowski, Nipon Deka, Ronny Golnak, Jie Xiao, Maartje van Rijn, Rik V. Mom, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202318692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Li+ Cations Activate NiFeOOH for Oxygen Evolution in Sodium and Potassium Hydroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202318692</link>
      <description>Onno van der Heijden, Jordy J.J. Eggebeen, Hanna Trzesniowski, Nipon Deka, Ronny Golnak, Jie Xiao, Maartje van Rijn, Rik V. Mom, Marc T. M. Koper, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4391617266

                The efficiency of green hydrogen production is reduced due to the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In addition to the optimal catalyst properties, electrocatalytic activity also depends on the interaction of the electrocatalyst with the electrolyte. Here, we show that the addition of small amounts of Li+ to Fe&#8208;free NaOH or KOH electrolytes activates NiFeOOH for the OER compared to single&#8208;cation electrolytes. Moreover, the activation was maintained when the solution was returned to pure NaOH. Importantly, we show that the origin of activation by Li+ cations is primarily non&#8208;kinetic in nature, as the OER onset for the mixed electrolyte does not change and the Tafel slope at low current density is ~30 mV/dec in both electrolytes. However, the increase of the apparent Tafel slope remains lower at increasing current densities in the presence of Li+. Based on electrochemical quartz crystal microbalance and in situ X&#8208;Ray Absorption Spectroscopy measurements, we show that this reduction of non&#8208;kinetic effects is due to enhanced intercalation of sodium, water and hydroxide in the Li+ activated catalyst. This enhanced electrolyte penetration facilitates the OER, especially at higher current densities and for increased catalyst loading, which is important for industrial electrolyzer systems.</description>
      <author>Onno van der Heijden, Jordy J.J. Eggebeen, Hanna Trzesniowski, Nipon Deka, Ronny Golnak, Jie Xiao, Maartje van Rijn, Rik V. Mom, Marc T. M. Koper</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202318692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured Fe-Doped Nickel Sulfide on Ni Foam As Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02542621mtgabs</link>
      <description>Jianguo Zhu, Paolo P. Pescarmona, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(54)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391638605

                In recent years, with the increasing demand for clean and renewable energy, growing research efforts have been dedicated to the generation of hydrogen through water electrolysis [1,2] . To industrialize hydrogen production, it is important to find low-cost and high-activity electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and, especially, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) [3] . OER is more challenging because it involves a four-electron transfer process, while HER is a two-electron transfer process. In this study, Ni 3 S 2 nanorods were synthesized on Ni foam (NiS/Ni foam, Fig. 1a) by a new one-step solvothermal reaction, with S powder as the sulfur source and Ni foam as the nickel source. Experimental results indicated that the NiS/Ni foam electrocatalyst had an overpotential of 276 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 for OER in 1 M KOH electrolyte. To boost the electrocatalytic activity of Ni 3 S 2 , we developed an effective method of doping with Fe via hydrothermal reaction. The obtained nanostructured Fe-doped Ni 3 S 2 on Ni foam (Fe-NiS/Ni foam, see Fig. 1b) achieved OER at an extremely low overpotential of 218 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 . Remarkably, Fe-NiS/Ni foam exhibited high stability at an industrially-relevant high current density (500 mA/cm 2 for 24h). Currently, we are studying its phase transfer process with in situ XPS. REFERENCES Jiao, S., et al., Energy &amp; Environmental Science, 2021. 14(4): p. 1722-1770. Boppella, R., et al., Coordination Chemistry Reviews, 2021. 427. Du, J., F. Li, and L. Sun, Chem Soc Rev, 2021. 50(4): p. 2663-2695. Figure 1</description>
      <author>Jianguo Zhu, Paolo P. Pescarmona</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02542621mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Exchange in Transition Metal Oxyhydroxides and Metal Hydroxide Organic Frameworks Elucidated for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422146mtgabs</link>
      <description>Mikaela Gorlin, Nicole A. Sagu&#236;, Daniel J. Zheng, Kaylee Lynn McCormack, Z. Khosravizadeh, Junghwa Kim, Hongbin Xu, Jiayu Peng, Per Malmberg, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Mario Valvo, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Tomas Edvinsson, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(42)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391663343

                To achieve the goal of climate neutrality by 2050, it is essential to increase the use of renewable fuels and carbon-neutral energy. 1 The anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key reaction not only in electrocatalytic production of many renewable fuels, 2 but also for next generation of charge storage devices such as metal-air batteries. 3 However, the slow kinetics of the OER process result in high energy losses and costs. 4 Therefore, the development of more efficient electrocatalysts is critical for making renewable energy via electrocatalysis a viable option in emerging energy systems. Transition metal (TM) oxides are a promising alternative to expensive noble metals due to their high catalytic OER activity under alkaline conditions and wider earth-abundance. Despite extensive research, establishing structure-activity correlations and understanding mechanistic processes is challenging, given the intricate interplay between external and intrinsic parameters. In this study, we investigate the role of lattice oxygens in electrodeposited Ni-Fe, Co-Fe, and Mn-Fe oxyhydroxide (M(OH) x O y , M = TM) electrocatalysts using surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) in conjunction with secondary ion mass spectroscopy (SIMS). By taking advantage of the Raman shift that results from 16 O/ 18 O isotope exchange, 5&#8211;7 we can track the participation of lattice oxygens in the electrocatalytic cycle. Our investigation reveals that, during OER, all the electrocatalysts display minimal exchange of lattice oxygens with the electrolyte (less than 5%). However, many of these electrocatalysts show partial or complete exchange when exposed to non-catalytic potential when in their more reduced states (see Figure 1). Apart from fully inorganic catalysts, we also present results from Ni-derived metal-hydroxide-organic frameworks (MHOFs), which are analogous to M(OH) x O y catalysts but with organic linkers separating the layers. 8 Our findings indicate that MHOFs with linkers that have a high &#960;-&#960; stacking energy (and a high structural stability) 8 undergo near complete 16 O/ 18 O exchange during OER, while MHOFs employing linkers with a low &#960;-&#960; stacking energy (and thus a low stability) show minor or no lattice exchange during OER. Our study suggests that participation oflattice oxygens is closely linked to the oxidation state of the transition metals rather than to the catalytic process. The work provides a detailed picture of the exchange mechanism and elucidates alternative processes involved in lattice oxygen participation and discusses their relation to the mechanisms of the OER process. References IEA (2023), Energy Technology Perspectives 2023, IEA, Paris https://www.iea.org/reports/energy-technology-perspectives-2023, License: CC BY 4.0 . Wei, S. Z. et al. Combining theory and experiment in electrocatalysis: Insights into materials design. Science (80-. ). 355 , eaad4998 (2017). Li, Y. &amp; Lu, J. Metal&#8211;Air Batteries: Will They Be the Future Electrochemical Energy Storage Device of Choice? ACS Energy Lett. 2 , 1370&#8211;1377 (2017). Song, F. et al. Transition Metal Oxides as Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Solutions: An Application-Inspired Renaissance. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 140 , 7748&#8211;7759 (2018). Lee, S., Banjac, K., Lingenfelder, M. &amp; Hu, X. Oxygen Isotope Labeling Experiments Reveal Different Reaction Sites for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Nickel and Nickel Iron Oxides. Angew. Chemie Int. Ed. 58 , 10295&#8211;10299 (2019). Moysiadou, A., Lee, S., Hsu, C.-S., Chen, H. M. &amp; Hu, X. Mechanism of Oxygen Evolution Catalyzed by Cobalt Oxyhydroxide: Cobalt Superoxide Species as a Key Intermediate and Dioxygen Release as a Rate-Determining Step. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 142 , 11901&#8211;11914 (2020). Diaz-Morales, O., Ferrus-Suspedra, D. &amp; Koper, M. T. M. The importance of nickel oxyhydroxide deprotonation on its activity towards electrochemical water oxidation. Chem. Sci. 7 , 2639&#8211;2645 (2016). Yuan, S. et al. Tunable metal hydroxide&#8211;organic frameworks for catalysing oxygen evolution. Nat. Mater. 21 , 673&#8211;680 (2022). Figure 1</description>
      <author>Mikaela Gorlin, Nicole A. Sagu&#236;, Daniel J. Zheng, Kaylee Lynn McCormack, Z. Khosravizadeh, Junghwa Kim, Hongbin Xu, Jiayu Peng, Per Malmberg, Yuriy Rom&#225;n&#8208;Leshkov, Mario Valvo, Yang Shao&#8208;Horn, Tomas Edvinsson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02422146mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Supports for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02582810mtgabs</link>
      <description>Laurie A. King, Debora Belami, Umesh Sai Jonnalagadda, Wenhao Fan, James J. Kwan, Yagya N. Regmi, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(58)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391663439

                The usage of scarce and expensive iridium as a catalyst for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) represents a significant barrier to up-scaling the deployment of proton exchange membrane water electrolysers (PEM-WEs). Accordingly, strategies such as nanostructuring catalysts to increase the electrochemical surface area (e.g. nanoparticles, single-atom catalysts, nanoclusters) as well as investigating mixed metal alloys and oxides (e.g. perovskites, pyrochlores) have been developed with promising half-cell performances. One further approach that has recently gained attention is the deployment of catalyst-supports whereby a high surface area support is used to scaffold the dispersed iridium catalyst. 1 Analogous to the selection of a catalyst, the catalyst support must withstand the highly corrosive and oxidising conditions of a PEM-WE anode. Thus, metal oxides such as titanium dioxide are commonly deployed as catalyst-supports for acidic OER. The catalyst-support moiety must also be sufficiently conductive when integrated into the PEM-WE catalyst layers. Otherwise, the cell voltages required to generate sufficient activity will render the device impractical. Accordingly, strategies such as doping, or the addition of conductive layers between the catalyst and support have been investigated. 2 In this study we investigate a unique support morphology that affords promising OER activity and stability in acidic electrolyte with high iridium mass activities. Specifically, we deploy a hollow TiO 2 catalyst support, 3 coated with a Au/Pd interlayer to provide electrical conductivity. The OER activity and stability is initially screened in a rotating disk electrode (RDE) configuration as a function of thermal treatments (reducing vs oxidising) as well as with at various Au/Pd (1 &#8211; 5 wt%) and Ir loadings (35 &#8211; 50 wt%). Our highest performing catalyst have a mass activity of around 480 A/g Ir at 1.60 V vs RHE. The catalysts are subsequently investigated in a membrane electrode assembly (MEA) and subject to 10k accelerated stress test stability measurements. To understand the role of the support morphology, Au/Pd interlayer and iridium loadings on electrochemical performance, we also characterise the synthesised catalysts by (scanning) transmission electron microscopy (STEM/TEM), X-ray diffraction (XRD), X-ray photoelectron microscopy (XPS) and electrical conductivity measurements. Collectively, we report the critical role of the Au/Pd interlayer to enable such high electrochemical performance. We also show that the hollow structure of the TiO 2 support may be enhancing mass transport in the catalyst layers. References 1 A. S. Pushkarev, I. V Pushkareva and D. G. Bessarabov, Energy &amp; Fuels , 2022, 36 , 6631&#8211;6625. 2 Y. N. Regmi, E. Tzanetopoulos, G. Zeng, X. Peng, D. I. Kushner, T. A. Kistler, L. A. King and N. Danilovic, ACS Catal. , 2020, 10 , 13125&#8211;13135. 3 U. S. Jonnalagadda, X. Su and J. J. Kwan, Ultrason. Sonochem. , 2021, 73 , 105530.</description>
      <author>Laurie A. King, Debora Belami, Umesh Sai Jonnalagadda, Wenhao Fan, James J. Kwan, Yagya N. Regmi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02582810mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Active Interface of Iron-Decorated Cobalt (Oxy)Hydroxide for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02653141mtgabs</link>
      <description>Qiyang Jiang, Fang Song, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(65)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391637763

                Iron can significantly enhance the activity of Co (oxy)hydroxide. However, the nature of active sites is currently under debate for Fe-Co (oxy)hydroxide. Here, we use well-define crystalline cobalt hydroxide nanosheets and nanorods as model catalysts to investigate the role of Fe on different crystal planes. The electrochemical reactivity and morphology-dependent analysis suggest that the lateral facets of Co(OH) 2 are active sites and the enhancement effect of iron incorporation only occurs on lateral facets rather than basal facets. Furthermore, by introducing tetramethylammonium cation (TMA+) as a chemical probe in KOH solution, we demonstrate the Fe species can interact strongly with the &#8220;active species&#8221; on the lateral facets and promote the improvement of OER activity. This work identifies the active site of cobalt hydroxides in the presence and absence of iron and elucidates the interaction of Fe species with &#8220;active oxygen&#8221; species on the lateral facets of cobalt hydroxide, which has a fundamental implication on the design of efficient OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qiyang Jiang, Fang Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02653141mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Composition Control of Cobalt Nickel Oxides by ALD for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02291504mtgabs</link>
      <description>Renee T. M. van Limpt, Marek Lavorenti, Mengmeng Lao, Marcel A. Verheijen, Mihalis N. Tsampas, M. Creatore, ECS Meeting Abstracts. MA2023-02(29)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4391662767

                Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis is a potentially low-cost and sustainable technology for renewable-energy driven hydrogen production. Realisation of its full potential relies on the development of cost-effective, earth-abundant OER electrocatalysts alternatives to the state-of-the art noble metal oxides 1 . Ternary transition metal oxides, such as cobalt nickel oxides, are promising candidates due to their excellent alkali resistance in combination with remarkable catalytic activities. The latter relate to their tuneable oxidation states and variation in coordination of their metal centres. These correlations can be properly investigated when precise control over the layer chemical composition is attained. Atomic layer deposition (ALD) is widely acknowledged to deliver control over film uniformity, thickness and conformality, as well as film chemical composition due to the self-limiting nature of its surface reactions. In this study, an ALD supercycle process based on cobalt cyclopentadienyl (CoCp 2 ) and nickel methylcyclopentadienyl (Ni( Me Cp) 2 ) precursors and an oxygen plasma co-reactant has been developed 2 to investigate the influence of chemical composition and crystallographic properties of cobalt nickel oxide thin films on their electrocatalytic OER performance. Deposition of ~20 nm binary nickel oxide and cobalt oxide results in the growth of polycrystalline films of the rock-salt and spinel phase, respectively. Ternary cobalt nickel oxide films with various ratios can be deposited uniformly, as indicated by energy dispersive x-ray spectroscopy mapping. The mixed oxides display a transition from the +2 oxidation state-based pure rock-salt phase (&lt;25 at.% Co) to the spinel phase consisting of mixed +2/+3 oxidation states (&gt;75% at.% Co) upon increasing Co at.% as verified by electron diffraction (figure a) and x-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS). XPS furthermore reveals a linear increase in the Ni 3+ -to-Ni 2+ ratio with increasing Co at.%, which indicates that an inverse spinel structure is formed. The formation of a Ni 3+ -rich inverse spinel cobalt nickel oxide between 55 and 75 at.% Co facilitates the formation of a semi-metallic state (10 2 S/cm) as opposed to the poorly conductive binary oxides (10 -3 S/cm and 10 -2 S/cm for NiO and Co 3 O 4 , respectively). Cyclic voltammetry (CV) measurements in 1M KOH, reveal chemical composition dependent activation behaviour (figure b). Continuous activation behaviour is observed for rock-salt phase films, whilst increment of the Co at.% results in reduced film activation until virtually no activation of the spinel phase films is observed. The activation of the nickel-rich film is accompanied by irreversible redox changes from the +2 to +3 oxidation state as indicated by the integrated non-catalytic wave. Post CV XPS analysis confirms the transition from Co 2+ and Ni 2+ oxidation states to Co 3+ and Ni 3+ . The formation of an (oxy)hydroxide state is observed for the rock-salt dominated films, whilst oxidation states characteristic of a spinel- like oxide structure are observed for the cobalt-rich films. No changes in the transition metal ratios are observed after activation. Scanning electron microscopy images furthermore reveal that the transformation of the Ni-rich films is accompanied by surface restructuring. These results indicate that initial composition can significantly influence the electrocatalytic performance of ternary oxides and therefore highlight the importance of techniques such as atomic layer deposition to study their complex behaviour. 1 Xu et al., Energy Chem., 4 (2022) 100087 2 van Limpt et al., J. Vac. Sci. Technol. A, 41 (2023) 032407 This work has been carried out within the SCALE project (NWA.1237.18.001) funded jointly by the Netherlands Organization for Scientific Research. Authors would like to thank the co-founders of the project ISPT, Syngaschem, VecoPrecision and Vsparticle and international partners Toyota Motor Europe and FORTH institute. Figure: (a) ALD deposited cobalt nickel oxide film show a transition from the +2 oxidation state-based rock-salt phase (NiO) to the spinel structure consisting of mixed +2/+3 oxidation states (Co 3 O 4 ) upon tuning the chemical composition as identified by electron diffraction. (b) This significantly affects the OER-electrocatalytic performance and activation of the films as represented by the current density at 1.8V vs RHE over 500 CV cycles in 1M KOH. Data labels indicate cobalt concentration as at.% Co/(at.% Co+ at.% Ni) . Figure 1</description>
      <author>Renee T. M. van Limpt, Marek Lavorenti, Mengmeng Lao, Marcel A. Verheijen, Mihalis N. Tsampas, M. Creatore</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/ma2023-02291504mtgabs</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
