<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 01:18:22 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Surface S-Doped Nanostructured RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Its Anion Passivating Effect for Efficient Overall Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14851</link>
      <description>Yu Liu, Wu Lu, Yong Wang, Le&#8208;Wei Shen, Ge Tian, Lianmeng Cui, Ling Qin, Liang Zhou, Yuexing Zhang, Federico Rosei, Xiaoyu Yang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406204831

                Electrolysis of seawater for hydrogen (H2) production to harvest clean energy is an appealing approach. In this context, there is an urgent need for catalysts with high activity and durability. RuO2 electrocatalysts have shown efficient activity in the hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER), but they still suffer from poor stability. Herein, surface S-doped nanostructured RuO2 (S-RuO2) is rationally fabricated for efficient overall seawater splitting. Doping with S enhances the activity (overpotentials of 25 mV for the HER and 243 mV for the OER), long-term durability (1000 h at 100 mA cm&#8211;2), and achieves nearly 100% Faraday efficiency (FE). Moreover, the S-RuO2-based anion exchange membrane seawater electrolyzer requires 2.01 V to reach 1.0 A cm&#8211;2 under demanding industrial conditions. Experimental analysis and theoretical calculations indicate that surface S introduction could lower the valence state of Ru, thereby conferring enhanced activity and stability. Furthermore, the nanostructured S-RuO2 electrocatalyst is highly protected by the S-doped surface, which repels Cl&#8211; in alkaline seawater. This investigation presents a feasible strategy for designing RuO2-based seawater splitting catalysts with both high performance and good resistance to anodic corrosion.</description>
      <author>Yu Liu, Wu Lu, Yong Wang, Le&#8208;Wei Shen, Ge Tian, Lianmeng Cui, Ling Qin, Liang Zhou, Yuexing Zhang, Federico Rosei, Xiaoyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c14851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406206683

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An In&#8208;depth Study of the Fe&#8208;Se System at the Nanoscale Reveals Remarkable Results on the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400743</link>
      <description>Dinesh Singh, Monika Ghalawat, Pankaj Poddar, European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406209376

                A catalyst for an electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key component of the large&#8208;scale storage of renewable energy through the conversion of water into oxygen and hydrogen. Iron&#8208;based selenide materials are currently being considered as potential options for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) because of their, widespread availability, inexpensive cost, and outstanding performance. In this study, we employed a thermal decomposition method to synthesize all stable phases of the Fe&#8208;Se system, including Fe7Se8, Fe3Se4, FeSe2, and FeSe. Additionally, we slurry&#8208;coated these phases onto a 3D nickel foam substrate. The prepared three&#8208;dimensional electrodes of Fe7Se8, Fe3Se4, FeSe2, and FeSe exhibit remarkably low overpotentials of 270, 276, 299, and 289 mV at a current density of 50 mA/cm2 for OER. In addition, the catalytic activity for OER is also tested on glassy carbon electrodes to compare its performance with the Ni&#8208;foam 3D substrate. The Fe7Se8 phase in the Fe&#8208;Se system exhibits the highest catalytic activity towards OER on both substrates due to variations in the Fe2+/Fe3+ ratio and the presence of Fe vacancies (cation vacancies) within the crystal lattice. Moreover, a faradaic efficiency of 98% was exhibited by Fe7Se8 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Dinesh Singh, Monika Ghalawat, Pankaj Poddar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ejic.202400743</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vs2-Incorporated Nis/Nis2/Zn-Doped Nimoo4 Nanosheet Arrays on Nickel Foam with Multiphase Heterointerface as Highly Efficient Alkaline Electrocatalysts for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5091049</link>
      <description>Lina Jia, Gaohui Du, Qingmei Su, Huayv Li, Shixian Chen, Bingshe Xu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210180

                Exploring and developing highly active and low-cost transition metal-based electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and overall water splitting in alkaline media is greatly significant for achieving large-scale applications of sustainable clean energy. Herein, we reported the preparation of VS2/NiSx-Zn-NiMoO4 porous nanosheet arrays grown on nickel foam (NF) with rich multiphase interfacial structures via transition metal doping and sulfurization, and its electrocatalytic properties of HER, OER and overall water splitting were studied. The doping of the NiMoO4 host material with transition metal cations (Zn2+) optimizes its electronic structure and generates abundant active sites, thus accelerating the OER reaction kinetics. The formation of transition metal nickel-based sulfides (NiS and NiS2) is beneficial for improving the conductivity of the material. Meanwhile, the introduction of VS2 also promotes the adsorption and transport efficiency of intermediate hydrogen atoms, thereby enhancing HER activity. The multiphase interfaces in VS2/NiSx-Zn-NiMoO4 nanosheets synergistically modulated NiMoO4, which fully utilized the advantages of each material to accelerate electron transfer and induce synergistic catalytic effects to achieve excellent electrocatalytic performance. When VS2/NiSx-Zn-NiMoO4/NF was used as catalyst for HER and OER in an alkaline solution, it required only 162 and 118 mV overpotential at 100 mA cm-2, respectively. Furthermore, the water electrolyser system constructed by using it as the cathode and anode showed excellent performance, requiring only 1.60 V cell voltage to reach 100 mA cm-2 and showing excellent stability. This work provides a new perspective for the application of transition metal molybdates in highly efficient electrocatalysts for alkaline water splitting through reasonable structural optimization.</description>
      <author>Lina Jia, Gaohui Du, Qingmei Su, Huayv Li, Shixian Chen, Bingshe Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5091049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Performance of Er-Mof/Femoo4/Nf</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5090999</link>
      <description>Luo Zhao, Wang Li, Hao Xu, Zikang Wang, Daxiang Yang, Yuping Liu, Xiaoqin Liao, Ming Nie, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406210274

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luo Zhao, Wang Li, Hao Xu, Zikang Wang, Daxiang Yang, Yuping Liu, Xiaoqin Liao, Ming Nie</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5090999</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyphenol-metal coordination derived high-entropy alloy as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03065-1</link>
      <description>Mengdi Hao, Qin Li, Jong-Won Sun, Liu Deng, Hualong Yu, Rui Liu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406214563

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengdi Hao, Qin Li, Jong-Won Sun, Liu Deng, Hualong Yu, Rui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-03065-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Oxygen Redox Dynamics in Zeolite&#8208;Encapsulated CsPbBr&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Perovskite OER Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202412679</link>
      <description>Xiangrong Ren, Yiyue Zhai, Na Yang, Bolun Wang, Shengzhong Liu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406222609

                Abstract Understanding the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) mechanism is pivotal for improving the overall efficiency of water electrolysis. Despite methylammonium lead halide perovskites (MAPbX 3 ) have shown promising OER performance due to their soft&#8208;lattice nature that allows lattice&#8208;oxygen oxidation of active &#945;&#8208;PbO 2 layer surface, the role of A&#8208;site MA or X&#8208;site elements in the electrochemical reconstruction and OER mechanisms has yet to be explored. Here, it is demonstrated that the OER mechanism of perovskite@zeolite composites is intrinsically dominated by the A&#8208;site group of lead&#8208;halide perovskites, while the type of X&#8208;site halogen is crucial for the reconstruction kinetics of the composites. Using CsPbBr x I 3&#8208; x @AlPO&#8208;5 ( x = 0, 1, 2, 3) as a model OER catalyst, it is found that the CsPbBr 3 @AlPO&#8208;5 behaves oxygen&#8208;intercalation pseudocapacitance during surface restructuring due to absence of halogen&#8208;ion migration and phase separation in the CsPbBr 3 , achieving a larger diffusion rate of OH &#8722; within the core&#8208;shell structure. Moreover, distinct from the single&#8208;metal&#8208;site mechanism of MAPbBr 3 @AlPO&#8208;5, experimental and theoretical investigations reveal that the soft lattice nature of CsPbBr 3 triggers the oxygen&#8208;vacancy&#8208;site mechanism via the CsPbBr 3 /&#945;&#8208;PbO 2 interface, resulting in excellent OER performance. Owing to the variety and easy tailoring of lead&#8208;halide perovskite compositions, these findings pave a way for the development of novel perovskite@zeolite type catalysts for efficient oxygen electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Xiangrong Ren, Yiyue Zhai, Na Yang, Bolun Wang, Shengzhong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202412679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Sulfur in VNi-Layered Double Hydroxide Enables Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxidation of Benzylamine with High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20149</link>
      <description>Baghendra Singh, Rakesh Kumar, Neetu Verma, Apparao Draksharapu, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406225746

                The replacement of the thermodynamically unfavorable anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with a more favorable organic oxidation reaction, such as the anodic oxidation of benzylamine, has garnered significant interest in hybrid water electrolyzer cells. This approach promises the production of value-added chemicals alongside hydrogen fuel generation, improving overall energy efficiency. However, achieving high current density for benzylamine oxidation without interference from OER remains a challenge, limiting the practical efficiency of the electrolyzer cell. In this study, we investigated a room temperature method for sulfur introduction in VNi-layered double hydroxide (LDH) catalyst and its application for electrocatalytic benzylamine oxidation. The S-introduction in VNi-LDH was found to modulate the electronic states of nickel and vanadium, increasing the number of active sites, electrochemical surface area, and charge transfer properties. The resulting S-VNi-LDH catalyst achieved a high current density of 400 mA cm&#8211;2 at only 1.39 V vs RHE potential for benzylamine oxidation, avoiding interference from oxygen evolution. The catalyst demonstrated 100% selectivity (Faradaic Efficiency = 98.6%) for the conversion of benzylamine into benzonitrile within 2.5 h of the reaction. In a two-electrode electrolysis system, S-VNi-LDH achieved a current density of 400 mA cm&#8211;2 at a cell voltage of 1.50 V when OER was substituted with benzylamine oxidation. The S-VNi-LDH showed energy consumption of 4.67 kWh/m3 H2 for OER and 1.31 kWh/m3 H2 during benzylamine oxidation, indicating a high energy efficiency with exceptional stability over five cycles, maintaining 98.6 &#177; 0.4% FE and consistent voltage. The S-VNi-LDH also oxidized various amines, including substituted benzylamines and secondary amines, achieving high conversion (95&#8211;97%) and faradaic efficiency (85.8&#8211;98%). This study presents an eco-friendly, room-temperature method for S-doping in VNi-LDH, which out performed the reported catalysts in the literature.</description>
      <author>Baghendra Singh, Rakesh Kumar, Neetu Verma, Apparao Draksharapu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c20149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous-flow electrooxidation for scalable biomass upgrading over copper-supported CoFe Prussian blue analogues</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.37</link>
      <description>Bowen Zhang, Tian&#8208;Tian Xiao, Cejun Hu, Ziwei Liu, Peng Chen, Zhengyu Zhao, Dingxiang Lai, Jinming Huang, Hongwei Zhang, Xiaojun Bao, Pei Pei Yuan, Chemical Synthesis. 5(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406227756

                Electrochemical biomass upgrading is a promising substitute for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to generate valuable chemicals in conjunction with hydrogen generation. Pursuing highly efficient and durable electrocatalysts for significant concentration levels (&#8805; 50 mM) of biomass electrooxidation remains an enduring challenge. Herein, we introduce a robust Cu-supported CoFe Prussian blue analogue (CoFe PBA/CF) electrocatalyst, adept at facilitating high-concentration (50 mM) 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation into 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA), achieving an exceptional HMF conversion (100%) with a notable FDCA yield of 98.4%. The influence of copper substrate and adsorption energy are therefore discussed. Impressively, the CoFe PBA/CF electrode sustains considerable durability in a continuous-flow electrochemical reactor designed for consecutive FDCA production, showcasing FDCA yields of 100/94% at flow rates of 0.4/0.8 mL&#183;min-1 over 60 h&#8217; uninterrupted electrolysis. This work provides a promising strategy to develop highly efficient and robust electrocatalysts for the consecutive production of high-value products coupled with green H2 production.</description>
      <author>Bowen Zhang, Tian&#8208;Tian Xiao, Cejun Hu, Ziwei Liu, Peng Chen, Zhengyu Zhao, Dingxiang Lai, Jinming Huang, Hongwei Zhang, Xiaojun Bao, Pei Pei Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2024.37</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing electronic synergy of atomically dispersed dual-metal sites for high-efficiency Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05706f</link>
      <description>Yue Wang, Caihong Feng, Ziang Shang, Xintong Li, Chao Ma, Guanzhen Chen, Ying Zhao, Shaoheng Wu, Yunhu Han, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406227995

                We reported an exogenous nitrogen-doped method to synthesize a bifunctional electrocatalyst with oxygen reduction and evolution reaction activity. This electrocatalyst display excellent ORR (E1/2 = 0.9 V vs. RHE) and...</description>
      <author>Yue Wang, Caihong Feng, Ziang Shang, Xintong Li, Chao Ma, Guanzhen Chen, Ying Zhao, Shaoheng Wu, Yunhu Han</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc05706f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic Selenide NiCo&#8208;Se/CFP as Effective Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalyst for Electrocatalytic Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405201</link>
      <description>Yajie Guo, Mengwei Wang, Cong Zhang, Kelun Jia, F. Niu, Ke Wang, ChemistrySelect. 10(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406243837

                Abstract The industrial application of green hydrogen production from water electrolysis strongly depends on the invention of low&#8208;cost, highly&#8208;active, and stable nonprecious electrocatalysts for an oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this work, a two&#8208;step process is developed to prepare a NiCo&#8208;Se/CFP bimetallic electrocatalyst by a low&#8208;temperature selenization of NiCo&#8208;PBA precursors electro&#8208;deposited on carbon fibre paper. The NiCo&#8208;Se/CFP bimetallic electrocatalyst exhibits good catalytic activity for the OER, with an overpotential of 307 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a Tafel slope of only 39.94 mV dec &#8722;1 in 1 M KOH. The steady current density and well&#8208;preserved microscopic morphology during the 20 h electrolysis proves its outstanding stability. The high inherent activity of the electrocatalyst is attributed to the 3D porous structure, the synergistic effects of Ni, and Co active components doping, and low&#8208;temperature selenization. The results provide an insightful reference for further improving composition and structure design while investigating nonprecious metal electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yajie Guo, Mengwei Wang, Cong Zhang, Kelun Jia, F. Niu, Ke Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistically self-assembled &lt;i&gt;in situ&lt;/i&gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k</link>
      <description>Saleem Raza, Ata Ur Rehman, Cheng Chen, Tianyu Zhao, Asif Hayat, Tariq Bashir, Liguo Shen, Yasin Orooji, Hongjun Lin, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406247174

                The need to minimize carbon emissions and improve sustainable energy systems has stimulated significant research into multifunctional materials.</description>
      <author>Saleem Raza, Ata Ur Rehman, Cheng Chen, Tianyu Zhao, Asif Hayat, Tariq Bashir, Liguo Shen, Yasin Orooji, Hongjun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visual Location of Oxygen Vacancies on Bismuth Titanate Nanosheets with Periodic Quantum Well and Promoting H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410883</link>
      <description>Yuqing Gao, Zhen Zhan, Liping Guo, Zhenzi Li, Songhua Cai, Xuepeng Wang, Mingxia Li, Ying Xie, Wei Zhou, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406248916

                Abstract Oxygen vacancy (OV) defect engineering plays a crucial role in enhancing photocatalytic efficiency. However, the direct visual characterization of oxygen vacancies still remains technically limited. Herein, a bismuth titanate (Bi 4 Ti 3 O 12 , BTO&#8208;OV) model photocatalyst containing oxygen vacancies is constructed through density functional theory (DFT) calculations to reveal the influence mechanism of distinctive periodic quantum well and oxygen vacancies on the charge transfer behavior in BTO. Notably, the distribution of oxygen vacancies is directly observed using the low&#8208;dose integrated differential phase contrast&#8208;scanning transmission electron microscopy (iDPC&#8208;STEM), providing visual evidence for the location of these oxygen vacancies in BTO&#8208;OV. Furthermore, the theoretical calculation results are verified by characterizing the photoelectric properties and conducting performance tests on the hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) photosynthesis. Specifically, the oxygen vacancies and distinctive periodic quantum well in BTO&#8208;OV accelerate charge separation, leading to a H 2 O 2 photosynthesis efficiency reaching 5278 &#181; m g &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 , which is 5 times that of the original BTO. This work offers theoretical and experimental references for the visual characterization of oxygen vacancies and the improvement of the charge transfer mechanism.</description>
      <author>Yuqing Gao, Zhen Zhan, Liping Guo, Zhenzi Li, Songhua Cai, Xuepeng Wang, Mingxia Li, Ying Xie, Wei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ionic&#8208;Liquid Synthesis of Atomic Molybdenum Nitride Clusters as Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction and Evolution Reactions Electrocatalysts for Alkaline Zn&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403706</link>
      <description>Nannan Wang, Jing Li, Jinpei Hei, Xiaodong Chen, Xiaojie Yin, Yanjun Yin, Yaqiong Kong, Lifeng Cui, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406249300

                Transition&#8208;metal nitrides (TMNs) have garnered considerable attention for energy conversion applications owing to their exceptional electronic structures and high catalytic activities. However, the scarcity of active sites in TMNs impedes their large&#8208;scale application. This study describes the use of wetness impregnation and ionic&#8208;liquid methods to enhance the electrocatalytic efficiency of molybdenum nitride (MoN) atomic clusters finely dispersed on nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon (MoN@NC) substrates. The as&#8208;synthesized electrocatalysts feature atomically dispersed MoN clusters, achieving an impressive onset potential of 0.93 V vs. RHE for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and maintaining an overpotential of just 295 mV at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The MoN@NC&#8208;based zinc&#8211;air battery demonstrated a high&#8208;power density of 151 mW/cm2, a robust specific discharge capacity of 759 mAh/gZn at 20 mA/cm2, and superior charge&#8211;discharge cycling stability exceeding 190 cycles. The detailed experimental characterization revealed that the uniformly dispersed MoN clusters served as the primary active sites driving the observed catalytic performance. Additionally, the present findings suggested significant correlations between the phase of the material, crystallization, atomic cluster distribution, support porosity, and nitridation temperature. These insights are expected to refine strategies for achieving atomically dispersed nitrides with optimized ORR performance.</description>
      <author>Nannan Wang, Jing Li, Jinpei Hei, Xiaodong Chen, Xiaojie Yin, Yanjun Yin, Yaqiong Kong, Lifeng Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k</link>
      <description>Liangdong Chen, Jie Ding, Xinhua Zhu, RSC Applied Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406249873

                In the past decade, the rapidly increasing global demand for energy and extensive concerns about the greenhouse effect and environmental problem from fossil fuels, have stimulated intensive research interest in...</description>
      <author>Liangdong Chen, Jie Ding, Xinhua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An efficient electrocatalytic in-situ hydrogen peroxide generation for ballast water treatment with oxygen groups</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2025.178444</link>
      <description>Zhiquan Yao, Wei Xiong, Yong Shi, Xinyong Li, Michael K.H. Leung, The Science of The Total Environment. 962(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406254907

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhiquan Yao, Wei Xiong, Yong Shi, Xinyong Li, Michael K.H. Leung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2025.178444</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing the Link Between Oxygen Vacancy and Activity Enhancement in Acidic Water Oxidation of Trigonal Iridium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423353</link>
      <description>Wenxiang Zhu, Mengjie Ma, Dongdong Gao, Jinxin Chen, Hui Huang, Kun Feng, Qun Wang, Jie Wu, Penghao Li, Jian Guo, Zhenglong Fan, Jun Zhong, Qi Shao, Fan Liao, Yan Liu, Mingwang Shao, Zhenhui Kang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406255148

                Developing durable IrO2&#8208;based electrocatalysts with high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity under acidic condition is crucial for proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. While oxygen defects are considered potentially important in OER, their direct relationship with catalytic activity has yet to be established. In this study, we introduced abundant oxygen vacancies through Re doping in 2D IrO2 (Re0.03Ir0.97O2), demonstrating their decisive role in enhancing OER performance. The Re0.03Ir0.97O2 catalyst exhibited excellent OER performance with an overpotential of 193 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and sustained activity for over 650 hours, significantly surpassing the undoped catalyst. Moreover, it maintained operation at a cell voltage of 1.70 V (~1200 mA cm&#8208;2) for over 140 hours without significant performance degradation. Theoretical calculations coupled with cyclic voltammetry, transient potential scanning and in&#8208;situ characterizations confirmed the adsorbate evolving mechanism on Re0.03Ir0.97O2, as well as the critical role of Re&#8208;induced oxygen vacancies in enhancing OER performance. These findings highlight that oxygen defects directly influence OER activity, providing guidance for the application of oxygen vacancy engineering in electrocatalyst design.</description>
      <author>Wenxiang Zhu, Mengjie Ma, Dongdong Gao, Jinxin Chen, Hui Huang, Kun Feng, Qun Wang, Jie Wu, Penghao Li, Jian Guo, Zhenglong Fan, Jun Zhong, Qi Shao, Fan Liao, Yan Liu, Mingwang Shao, Zhenhui Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloride Residues in RuO2 Catalysts Enhance Its Stability and Efficiency for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420860</link>
      <description>Huile Jin, Jiadong Chen, Menghui Qi, Yun Yang, Xiaofen Xiao, Ying Li, Yong Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406255437

                Ruthenium dioxide (RuO2) is a benchmark electrocatalyst for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE), but its stability during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is often compromised by lattice oxygen involvement and metal dissolution. Despite that the typical synthesis of RuO2 produces chloride residues, the underlying function of chloride have not well investigated. In this study, we synthesized chlorine&#8208;containing RuO2 (RuO2&#8208;Cl) and pure RuO2 catalysts with similar morphology and crystallinity. RuO2&#8208;Cl demonstrated superior stability, three times greater than that of pure RuO2, and a lower overpotential of 176 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2. Furthermore, the RuO2&#8208;Cl catalysts that were in situ synthesized on a platinum&#8208;coated titanium felt could maintain high performance for up to 1200 hours at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. Computational and experimental analyses show that chloride stabilizes RuO2 by substituting the bridging oxygen atoms, which subsequently inhibits lattice oxygen evolution and Ru demetallation. Notably, this substitution also lowers the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step by strengthening the binding of *OOH intermediates. These findings offer new insights into the previously unknown role of chloride residues and how to improve RuO2 stability.</description>
      <author>Huile Jin, Jiadong Chen, Menghui Qi, Yun Yang, Xiaofen Xiao, Ying Li, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando monitoring of the functional role of tetrahedral cobalt centers for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55857-3</link>
      <description>Yonggui Zhao, Nanchen Dongfang, Chong Qing Huang, Rolf Erni, Jingguo Li, Han Zhao, Long Pan, Marcella Iannuzzi, Greta R. Patzke, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406268330

                The complexity of the intrinsic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) mechanism, particularly the precise relationships between the local coordination geometry of active metal centers and the resulting OER kinetics, remains to be fully understood. Herein, we construct a series of 3 d transition metal-incorporated cobalt hydroxide-based nanobox architectures for the OER which contain tetrahedrally coordinated Co(II) centers. Combination of bulk- and surface-sensitive operando spectroelectrochemical approaches reveals that tetrahedral Co(II) centers undergo a dynamic transformation into highly active Co(IV) intermediates acting as the true OER active species which activate lattice oxygen during the OER. Such a dynamic change in the local coordination geometry of Co centers can be further facilitated by partial Fe incorporation. In comparison, the formation of such active Co(IV) species is found to be hindered in CoOOH and Co-FeOOH, which are predominantly containing [CoIIIO6] and [CoII/FeIIIO6] octahedra, respectively, but no mono-&#956;-oxo-bridged [CoIIO4] moieties. This study offers a comprehensive view of the dynamic role of local coordination geometry of active metal centers in the OER kinetics. The oxygen evolution reaction and its relationship with metal center coordination remain unclear. Here, the authors report that optimization of the local coordination geometry of Co centers plays a crucial role in facilitating the O-O bond formation atop high-valent Co (IV) sites.</description>
      <author>Yonggui Zhao, Nanchen Dongfang, Chong Qing Huang, Rolf Erni, Jingguo Li, Han Zhao, Long Pan, Marcella Iannuzzi, Greta R. Patzke</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55857-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimising CNF-supported cobalt catalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction activity through plasma modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118936</link>
      <description>Dominik Maj, Termeh Darvishzad, David Sebasti&#225;n, Gabriela Grzybek, M.J. L&#225;zaro, Andrzej Kotarba, Pawe&#322; Stelmachowski, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406268631

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dominik Maj, Termeh Darvishzad, David Sebasti&#225;n, Gabriela Grzybek, M.J. L&#225;zaro, Andrzej Kotarba, Pawe&#322; Stelmachowski</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial&#8208;induced Synthesis of nano NiFe LDH for High&#8208;efficiency Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202404086</link>
      <description>Weiwei Li, Haifang Wu, Qi Chang Li, Xuefei Wang, Feng Duan, Hao Xie, Jian Zhang, Qiang Shen, Xiaoyu Yang, Guoqiang Luo, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406269876

                NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH) currently are the most efficient catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline environments. However, the development of high&#8208;performance low cost OER electrocatalysts using straightforward strategies remains a significant challenge. In this study, we describe an innovative microbial mineralization&#8208;based method for in situ&#8208;induced preparation of NiFe LDH nanosheets loaded on nickel foam and demonstrate that this material serves as an efficient oxygen evolution electrocatalyst. In the microbial mineralization process, bacteria adhere to electrode materials and promote the surface nucleation of nanomaterials when metal ions are present. Specifically, our findings indicate that biomineralization accelerates the formation and regulation of NiFe LDH. The new electrocatalyst displays excellent OER performance, with a small overpotential of 220 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope down to 38.6 mV dec&#8722;1 in alkaline solution. The remarkable OER performance of the microbial mineralization&#8208;derived electrocatalyst is attributed to the synergistic effect of NiFe LDH and a bacterial&#8208;specific surface area that contains multiple active sites. This study has uncovered a new approach for the assembly of NiFe LDH that relies on biomineralization to bring about morphological and structural modification of LDH nanosheets.</description>
      <author>Weiwei Li, Haifang Wu, Qi Chang Li, Xuefei Wang, Feng Duan, Hao Xie, Jian Zhang, Qiang Shen, Xiaoyu Yang, Guoqiang Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202404086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-modified multicomponent-doped Cr2O3 oxide: An efficient and ultra stable electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction and water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118937</link>
      <description>Zeyu Jin, Yuelin Wang, Linshan Zhu, Jingzi Zhang, Xi Lin, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406270045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyu Jin, Yuelin Wang, Linshan Zhu, Jingzi Zhang, Xi Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2025.118937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic-level Ru-Ir mixing in rutile-type (RuIr)O2 for efficient and durable oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55910-1</link>
      <description>Yeji Park, Ho Yeon Jang, Tae Kyung Lee, Taekyung Kim, Doyeop Kim, Dong-Jin Kim, Hionsuck Baik, Jinwon Choi, Taehyun Kwon, Sung Jong Yoo, Seoin Back, Kwangyeol Lee, Nature Communications. 16(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406270753

                Abstract The success of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) depends on active and robust electrocatalysts to facilitate oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Heteroatom-doped-RuO x has emerged as a promising electrocatalysts because heteroatoms suppress lattice oxygen participation in the OER, thereby preventing the destabilization of surface Ru and catalyst degradation. However, identifying suitable heteroatoms and achieving their atomic-scale coupling with Ru atoms are nontrivial tasks. Herein, to steer the reaction pathway away from the involvement of lattice oxygen, we integrate OER-active Ir atoms into the RuO 2 matrix, which maximizes the synergy between stable Ru and active Ir centers, by leveraging the changeable growth behavior of Ru/Ir atoms on lattice parameter-modulated templates. In PEMWE, the resulting (RuIr)O 2 /C electrocatalysts demonstrate notable current density of 4.96 A cm &#8722;2 and mass activity of 19.84 A mg Ru+Ir &#8722;1 at 2.0 V. In situ spectroscopic analysis and computational calculations highlight the importance of the synergistic coexistence of Ru/Ir-dual-OER-active sites for mitigating Ru dissolution via the optimization of the binding energy with oxygen intermediates and stabilization of Ru sites.</description>
      <author>Yeji Park, Ho Yeon Jang, Tae Kyung Lee, Taekyung Kim, Doyeop Kim, Dong-Jin Kim, Hionsuck Baik, Jinwon Choi, Taehyun Kwon, Sung Jong Yoo, Seoin Back, Kwangyeol Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-025-55910-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biphase Alloy Nanoheterojunction Encapsulated within N&#8208;Doped Carbon Nanotubes as Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for High&#8208;Performance Zn&#8208;Air and Mg&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423767</link>
      <description>Min Wang, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Jing Wang, Xinxin Yin, Yali Cao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406272012

                Abstract N&#8208;doped carbon confined alloy catalysts possess considerable potential in facilitating oxygen electrocatalytic reaction and consequent applications in metal air batteries, but the sluggish catalytic kinetics and high reaction barrier of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) remain the bottleneck restricting its further development. Here, a novel CoFe&#8208;NiFe biphase alloy nanoheterojunction encapsulated within N&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes (CoFe&#8208;NiFe@NCNT) is fabricated via the hydrothermal carbothermic reduction approach. Owing to the plentiful active sites and high electrical conductance, the potential difference between OER and ORR amounts to merely 0.68 V. Simultaneously, the performance of the Zn&#8208;air and Mg&#8208;air batteries assembled by CoFe&#8208;NiFe@NCNT serving as the air&#8208;cathode are superior to that of commercial Pt/C + RuO 2 . The DFT outcomes reveal that the transformation between *OOH and *O is the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS) of ORR/OER. Also, the synergy between the biphase alloy heterojunction and N&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes is conducive to reduce the reaction energy barrier. This study offers a profound understanding toward the structural design of biphase alloy nanoheterojunction electrocatalysts and the utilization in metal&#8208;air batteries for portable wearable electronic apparatuses.</description>
      <author>Min Wang, Jing Xie, Zhenjiang Lu, Jing Wang, Xinxin Yin, Yali Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202423767</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrophilicity and electronic structure modulation of Pb-doped RuO2 for pH-universal oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236194</link>
      <description>Xiaojing Dong, Jintao Wang, Yue Hao, Yiqiang Sun, Xu Zhang, Bo Xu, Cuncheng Li, Journal of Power Sources. 631(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406279332

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojing Dong, Jintao Wang, Yue Hao, Yiqiang Sun, Xu Zhang, Bo Xu, Cuncheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2025.236194</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research progress on NiCo-LDH electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.035</link>
      <description>Yubo Zhang, Zhe Zhang, Xiaoxuan Zhang, Jinsheng Li, Rui Guo, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406279417

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yubo Zhang, Zhe Zhang, Xiaoxuan Zhang, Jinsheng Li, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280192

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Liangdong Chen, Jie Ding, Xinhua Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280210

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liangdong Chen, Jie Ding, Xinhua Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280211

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280214

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406280225

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon nanotube directed synthesis of blue TiO2 with oxygen vacancy for sonocatalytic H2 production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122379</link>
      <description>Huaqiang Zhuang, Xiangge Wang, Miaoling Huang, Xiao&#8208;Bing Lian, Xiaobin Liu, Xiaoyang Pan, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406291240

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Huaqiang Zhuang, Xiangge Wang, Miaoling Huang, Xiao&#8208;Bing Lian, Xiaobin Liu, Xiaoyang Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2025.122379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Manipulation of Surface Spin Configurations for Enhanced Performance in Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c05609</link>
      <description>Chao Zhong, Wenda Zhou, Xingfang Luo, Tingfeng Li, Fujin Huang, Jie Hu, Zhenzhen Jiang, Ce Hu, Wen Lei, Cailei Yuan, Nano Letters. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406309081

                In situ studies of the relationship between surface spin configurations and spin-related electrocatalytic reactions are crucial for understanding how magnetic catalysts enhance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance under magnetic fields. In this work, 2D Fe7Se8 nanosheets with rich surface spin configurations are synthesized via chemical vapor deposition. In situ magnetic force microscopy and Raman spectroscopy reveal that a 200 mT magnetic field eliminates spin-disordered domain walls, forming a spin-ordered single-domain structure, which lowers the OER energy barrier, as confirmed by theoretical calculations. Electrochemical tests show that under a 200 mT magnetic field, the OER overpotential of multidomain Fe7Se8 nanosheets at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 decreases from 346 mV to 259 mV, while the magnetic field has minimal effect on single-domain nanosheets. These findings highlight the critical role of spin configurations in enhancing electrocatalytic performance, offering new insights into the design of magnetic catalysts for industrial applications.</description>
      <author>Chao Zhong, Wenda Zhou, Xingfang Luo, Tingfeng Li, Fujin Huang, Jie Hu, Zhenzhen Jiang, Ce Hu, Wen Lei, Cailei Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c05609</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the catalytic performance of spinel sulphides by incorporating g-C3N4 for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.111980</link>
      <description>Munaza sadiq, Abhinav Kumar, Subhash Chandra, Jayanti Makasana, Suhas Ballal, Soumaya Gouadria, Prateek Pathak, Suman Saini, Rahul Chaudhary, Vijayalaxmi Mishra, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406309474

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Munaza sadiq, Abhinav Kumar, Subhash Chandra, Jayanti Makasana, Suhas Ballal, Soumaya Gouadria, Prateek Pathak, Suman Saini, Rahul Chaudhary, Vijayalaxmi Mishra</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2025.111980</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing RuO2 with Fe-doped Co2RuO4 for boosting alkaline electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.103</link>
      <description>Mengyue Qi, Huamei Tong, Gaojie Li, Xinyu Zheng, Y&#252; Liu, Ye Cheng, Zaoxue Yan, Deli Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406315508

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyue Qi, Huamei Tong, Gaojie Li, Xinyu Zheng, Y&#252; Liu, Ye Cheng, Zaoxue Yan, Deli Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of Cr-Cofe-Layered Double Hydroxide Via the Synergistic Roles of Fe Etching, Cr Doping, and Anion Intercalation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095918</link>
      <description>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Anaclet Nsabimana, Shigang Shen, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406321086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Anaclet Nsabimana, Shigang Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solid-State Reaction Synthesis of CoSb2O6-Based Electrodes Towards Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Electrolytes: Effects of Calcination Time and Temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010068</link>
      <description>Francesco Vanzetti, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez, Catalysts. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406325851

                Mitigating global warming necessitates transitioning from fossil fuels to alternative energy carriers like hydrogen. Efficient hydrogen production via electrocatalysis requires high-performance, stable anode materials for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to support the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode. Developing noble metal-free electrocatalysts is therefore crucial, particularly for acidic electrolytes, to avoid reliance on scarce and expensive metals such as Ir and Ru. This study investigates a low-cost, solvent-free solid-state synthesis of CoSb2O6, focusing on the influence of calcination time and temperature. Six samples were prepared and characterized using powder X-ray diffraction (PXRD), energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), Brunauer&#8211;Emmett&#8211;Teller (BET) analysis, field-emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM), and electrochemical techniques. A non-pure CoSb2O6 phase was observed across all samples. Electrochemical testing revealed good short-term stability; however, all samples exhibited Tafel slopes exceeding 200 mV dec&#8722;1 and overpotentials greater than 1 V. The sample calcined at 600 &#176;C for 6 h showed the best performance, with the lowest Tafel slope and overpotential, attributed to its high CoSb2O6 content and maximized {110} facet exposure. This work highlights the role of calcination protocols in developing Co-based OER catalysts and offers insights for enhancing their electrocatalytic properties.</description>
      <author>Francesco Vanzetti, Hilmar Guzm&#225;n, Simelys Hern&#225;ndez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal15010068</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Role of CE in Fes2/Ni3s2 Nanoarray for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Promoting Oh- Absorption and *O Desorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095410</link>
      <description>Jicheng Wu, Dandan Wu, Wei Yuan, Yixing Luo, Zhong He Han, Xiaowei Xu, Shufang Chang, Ming Wen, Changbao Huang, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406328942

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jicheng Wu, Dandan Wu, Wei Yuan, Yixing Luo, Zhong He Han, Xiaowei Xu, Shufang Chang, Ming Wen, Changbao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095410</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper doping in perovskite oxide: a novel route to high-performance oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04898a</link>
      <description>Rida Zahra, Abhinav Kumar, Soumaya Gouadria, Subhash Chandra, R. Roopashree, Rajendra K. Sharma, Prateek Pathak, Rahul Chaudhary, Vijayalaxmi Mishra, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406337276

                The growing demand for electrocatalysts with excellent electrochemical properties and environment friendly characteristics is driving research on water-splitting to generate sustainable hydrogen energy resources.</description>
      <author>Rida Zahra, Abhinav Kumar, Soumaya Gouadria, Subhash Chandra, R. Roopashree, Rajendra K. Sharma, Prateek Pathak, Rahul Chaudhary, Vijayalaxmi Mishra</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04898a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid and in-depth reconstruction of fluorine-doped bimetallic oxide in electrocatalytic oxygen evolution processes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.057</link>
      <description>Yutong Wang, Hui Feng, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Wenzhi Zhang, Mei&#8208;li Qi, Yue Li, Guohua Dong, Yibo Wang, Dongxuan Guo, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406338350

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yutong Wang, Hui Feng, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Wenzhi Zhang, Mei&#8208;li Qi, Yue Li, Guohua Dong, Yibo Wang, Dongxuan Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2025.01.057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decoding Dual&#8208;Functionality in N&#8208;doped Defective Carbon: Unveiling Active Sites for Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411035</link>
      <description>Sakshi Bhardwaj, A. J. Pathak, Sabuj Kanti Das, Prasenjit Das, Ranjit Thapa, Ramendra Sundar Dey, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406340062

                Abstract Oxygen electrocatalysis plays a pivotal role in energy conversion and storage technologies. The precise identification of active sites for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for developing an efficient bifunctional electrocatalyst. However, this remains a challenging endeavor. Here, it is demonstrated that metal&#8208;free N&#8208;doped defective carbon material derived from triazene derivative exhibits excellent bifunctional activity, achieving a notable &#916;E value of 0.72 V. Through comprehensive X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy and Raman spectroscopic analyses, the active sites responsible for oxygen electrocatalysis are elucidated, resolving a long&#8208;standing issue. Specifically, pyridinic&#8208;N sites are crucial for ORR, while graphitic&#8208;N are good for OER. A predictive model utilizing &#960;&#8208;electron descriptors further aids in identifying these sites, with theoretical insights aligning with experimental results. Additionally, in situ ATR&#8208;FTIR spectroscopy provides clarity on reaction intermediates for both reactions. This research paves the way for developing metal&#8208;free, site&#8208;specific electrocatalysts for practical applications in energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Bhardwaj, A. J. Pathak, Sabuj Kanti Das, Prasenjit Das, Ranjit Thapa, Ramendra Sundar Dey</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411035</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zeolitic Imidazolate Framework-Derived Bifunctional CoO-Mn3O4 Heterostructure Cathode Enhancing Oxygen Reduction/Evolution via Dynamic O-Vacancy Formation and Healing for High-Performance Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104040</link>
      <description>Jong Hui Choi, Hoje Chun, Dong&#8208;Won Kim, Mrinal Kanti Kabiraz, Jeonghyeon Kim, Jihoon Kim, Keon&#8208;Han Kim, Benzhi Wang, Hyung Mo Jeong, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Byungchan Han, Jeung Ku Kang, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406362412

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jong Hui Choi, Hoje Chun, Dong&#8208;Won Kim, Mrinal Kanti Kabiraz, Jeonghyeon Kim, Jihoon Kim, Keon&#8208;Han Kim, Benzhi Wang, Hyung Mo Jeong, Sang&#8208;Il Choi, Byungchan Han, Jeung Ku Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2025.104040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Grown NiFe-Based MOF for Efficient Oxygen Evolution in Alkaline Seawater at High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj05248j</link>
      <description>Yawen Hu, Xin Zhao, Yulin Min, Qunjie Xu, Qiaoxia Li, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406363226

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) characterized by four-electron transfer mechanism is inherently limited by significant overpotential requirements and sluggish kinetics. A water-stable NH2-MIL-88B (Fe2Ni) Metal-Organic Framework (MOF) was in-situ synthesized...</description>
      <author>Yawen Hu, Xin Zhao, Yulin Min, Qunjie Xu, Qiaoxia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj05248j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Phase Composition of the Hybrid Electrocatalysts Based on Nickel Phosphides and N,P-Doped Carbon on the Activities in the Processes of Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolutions From Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11237-025-09819-x</link>
      <description>D. O. Mazur, Olena O. Pariiska, Ya. I. Kurys, V. G. Koshechko, V. D. Pokhodenko, Theoretical and Experimental Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406368138

                No abstract</description>
      <author>D. O. Mazur, Olena O. Pariiska, Ya. I. Kurys, V. G. Koshechko, V. D. Pokhodenko</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11237-025-09819-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Iron in the Electrolyte to Improve Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance: Fundamentals, Strategies, and Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423071</link>
      <description>Hai-Yan Li, Yuwei Zhang, Yubo Chen, Yang Li, Zhongjian Li, Bin Yang, Qinghua Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Lecheng Lei, Zhichuan J. Xu, Yang Hou, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406370828

                Electrochemical water splitting is a pivotal technology for storing intermittent electricity from renewable sources into hydrogen fuel. However, its overall energy efficiency is impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode. In the quest to design high-performance anode catalysts for driving the OER under non-acidic conditions, iron (Fe) has emerged as a crucial element. Although the profound impact of adventitious electrolyte Fen+ species on OER catalysis had been reported forty years ago, recent interest in tailoring the electrode-electrolyte interface has spurred studies on the controlled introduction of Fe ions into the electrolyte to improve OER performance. During the catalytic process, scenarios where the rate of Fen+ deposition on a specific host material outruns that of dissolution pave the way for establishing highly efficient and dynamically stable electrochemical interfaces for long-term steady operation. This review systematically summarizes recent endeavors devoted to elucidating the behaviors of in situ Fe(aq.) incorporation, the role of incorporated Fe sites in the OER, and critical factors influencing the interplay between the electrode surface and Fe ions in the electrolyte environment. Finally, unexplored issues related to comprehensively understanding and leveraging the dynamic exchange of Fen+ at the interface for improved OER catalysis are summarized.</description>
      <author>Hai-Yan Li, Yuwei Zhang, Yubo Chen, Yang Li, Zhongjian Li, Bin Yang, Qinghua Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Lecheng Lei, Zhichuan J. Xu, Yang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202423071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Iron in the Electrolyte to Improve Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance: Fundamentals, Strategies, and Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423071</link>
      <description>Haiyan Li, Yuwei Zhang, Yubo Chen, Yang Li, Zhongjian Li, Bin Yang, Qinghua Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Lecheng Lei, Zhichuan J. Xu, Yang Hou, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406370843

                Electrochemical water splitting is a pivotal technology for storing intermittent electricity from renewable sources into hydrogen fuel. However, its overall energy efficiency is impeded by the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode. In the quest to design high&#8208;performance anode catalysts for driving the OER under non&#8208;acidic conditions, iron (Fe) has emerged as a crucial element. Although the profound impact of adventitious electrolyte Fen+ species on OER catalysis had been reported forty years ago, recent interest in tailoring the electrode&#8208;electrolyte interface has spurred studies on the controlled introduction of Fe ions into the electrolyte to improve OER performance. During the catalytic process, scenarios where the rate of Fen+ deposition on a specific host material outruns that of dissolution pave the way for establishing highly efficient and dynamically stable electrochemical interfaces for long&#8208;term steady operation. This review systematically summarizes recent endeavors devoted to elucidating the behaviors of in situ Fe(aq.) incorporation, the role of incorporated Fe sites in the OER, and critical factors influencing the interplay between the electrode surface and Fe ions in the electrolyte environment. Finally, unexplored issues related to comprehensively understanding and leveraging the dynamic exchange of Fen+ at the interface for improved OER catalysis are summarized.</description>
      <author>Haiyan Li, Yuwei Zhang, Yubo Chen, Yang Li, Zhongjian Li, Bin Yang, Qinghua Zhang, Jianguo L&#252;, Lecheng Lei, Zhichuan J. Xu, Yang Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3d&#8211;5d Orbital Hybridization in Nanoflower&#8208;Like High&#8208;Entropy Alloy for Highly Efficient Overall Water Splitting at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411394</link>
      <description>Xiaolong Ma, Yaojiang Zhou, Shuang Zhang, Wenli Lei, Yuanmeng Zhao, Changsheng Shan, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406371287

                Abstract Exploring highlyefficient electrocatalysts for overall water splitting is a challenging butnecessary task for development of green and renewable energy. Herein, PtIrFeCoNi high&#8208;entropy alloy nanoflowers (HEA NFs) withstrong 3d&#8208;5d orbital hybridization were fabricated to achieve highly efficientoverall water splitting at high current density. The Pt 26 Ir 7 Fe 13 Co 22 Ni 32 HEA NFs achieved a 57.52&#8208;fold higher than commercial IrO 2 in turnoverfrequency (TOF) for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Besides, its TOF value forhydrogen evolution reaction (HER) was 2.11&#8208;fold higher than that of commercialPt/C. The cell voltages based on Pt 26 Ir 7 Fe 13 Co 22 Ni 32 HEA NFs for overall water splitting were only 1.594 V and 1.861 V at currentdensities of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and 500 mA cm &#8722;2 , which weresignificantly lower than those of Pt/C</description>
      <author>Xiaolong Ma, Yaojiang Zhou, Shuang Zhang, Wenli Lei, Yuanmeng Zhao, Changsheng Shan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstitial Doping in Ultrafine Nanocrystals for Efficient and Durable Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202424195</link>
      <description>Minming Jiang, Jiang Xu, Yujie Chen, Luqi Wang, Qi Zhou, Paul Munroe, Linlin Li, Zonghan Xie, Shengjie Peng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406377559

                Transition metal&#8208;based catalysts with high efficiency and stability for overall water splitting (OWS) offer significant potential for reducing green hydrogen production costs. Utilizing sputtering deposition technology, we propose a deposition&#8208;diffusion strategy to fabricate heterojunction coatings composed of ultrafine FeCoNi&#8208;C&#8208;N transition metal interstitial solid solution (TMISS) nanocrystals and amorphous nitrided carbon (NC) on the pre&#8208;deposited NC micro column arrays. The diffusion of C and N atoms results in the formation of uniformly distributed TMISS nanocrystals, with an average diameter of ~1.9 nm, thus maximizing atomic utilization. The unique crystalline&#8208;amorphous heterojunction interface enhances electrocatalytic stability. Furthermore, the electronic regulation of metal sites by interstitial C and N atoms not only optimizes the adsorption&#8208;dissociation process in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), but also accelerates the surface reconstruction of hydroxyl oxides to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. As a result, the as&#8208;prepared coating achieved overpotentials of only 62 and 237 mV for the HER and OER at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline electrolytes, and exhibited excellent OWS performance and long&#8208;term stability at high current densities. This work presents a new perspective for synthesizing TMISS nanocrystals and promotes their application in bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Minming Jiang, Jiang Xu, Yujie Chen, Luqi Wang, Qi Zhou, Paul Munroe, Linlin Li, Zonghan Xie, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202424195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interstitial Doping in Ultrafine Nanocrystals for Efficient and Durable Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202424195</link>
      <description>Minming Jiang, Jiang Xu, Yujie Chen, Luqi Wang, Qi Zhou, Paul Munroe, Linlin Li, Zonghan Xie, Shengjie Peng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406377689

                Transition metal&#8208;based catalysts with high efficiency and stability for overall water splitting (OWS) offer significant potential for reducing green hydrogen production costs. Utilizing sputtering deposition technology, we propose a deposition&#8208;diffusion strategy to fabricate heterojunction coatings composed of ultrafine FeCoNi&#8208;C&#8208;N transition metal interstitial solid solution (TMISS) nanocrystals and amorphous nitrided carbon (NC) on the pre&#8208;deposited NC micro column arrays. The diffusion of C and N atoms results in the formation of uniformly distributed TMISS nanocrystals, with an average diameter of ~1.9 nm, thus maximizing atomic utilization. The unique crystalline&#8208;amorphous heterojunction interface enhances electrocatalytic stability. Furthermore, the electronic regulation of metal sites by interstitial C and N atoms not only optimizes the adsorption&#8208;dissociation process in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), but also accelerates the surface reconstruction of hydroxyl oxides to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. As a result, the as&#8208;prepared coating achieved overpotentials of only 62 and 237 mV for the HER and OER at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 in alkaline electrolytes, and exhibited excellent OWS performance and long&#8208;term stability at high current densities. This work presents a new perspective for synthesizing TMISS nanocrystals and promotes their application in bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Minming Jiang, Jiang Xu, Yujie Chen, Luqi Wang, Qi Zhou, Paul Munroe, Linlin Li, Zonghan Xie, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202424195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Electrocatalytic Activity and Corrosion Resistance of CoCrFeNi and MnCrFeNi Thin Films by Anodization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400797</link>
      <description>Clara Linder, Mikhail Vagin, Robert Boyd, Grzegorz Greczy&#324;ski, Daniel Lundin, Karin T&#246;rne, Per Eklund, Emma M. Bj&#246;rk, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406378989

                Abstract Transition metal oxides like Co, Ni, and Mn are promising alternatives to noble metals such as Pt for oxygen electrocatalysis in green energy. Alloying these metals forms multicomponent catalysts with compelling properties. In this study, CoCrFeNi and MnCrFeNi thin films are synthesized using High&#8208;Power Impulse Magnetron Sputtering (HiPIMS) and their catalytic activity for the Oxygen Reduction Reaction (ORR), the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), and corrosion resistance in 1 molar (1 M) potassium hydroxide (KOH) are evaluated. MnCrFeNi films exhibit a fine&#8208;grained single face&#8208;centered cubic (FCC) phase, while CoCrFeNi films have larger grains and multiple phases. ORR on CoCrFeNi follows a 2+1 electron transfer pathway, producing hydroxide radicals, while MnCrFeNi exhibits a 2&#8208;electron pathway, yielding hydrogen peroxide. Anodization reduces the CoCrFeNi overpotential from 0.9 to 0.5 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), comparable to platinum and iridium catalysts (Pt/C, Ir/C). Anodization also shifts CoCrFeNi ORR to a 2&#8208;electron pathway. In situ Raman spectroscopy detects no ORR intermediates, but nickel oxyhydroxide (NiOOH) appears during OER. Substituting Mn for Co increases corrosion resistance by raising the corrosion potential. All films show passive behavior during polarization, demonstrating their potential for corrosion protection and electrocatalysis in green energy applications.</description>
      <author>Clara Linder, Mikhail Vagin, Robert Boyd, Grzegorz Greczy&#324;ski, Daniel Lundin, Karin T&#246;rne, Per Eklund, Emma M. Bj&#246;rk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D CaWO4 nanosheets derived from scheelite minerals for enhanced electrocatalysis in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2389-9</link>
      <description>Qing Sun, Yongxiang Sun, Dong Yan, Hong Zhong, Hongbo Zeng, Science China Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406380504

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Sun, Yongxiang Sun, Dong Yan, Hong Zhong, Hongbo Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11426-024-2389-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1000-Hour Durable Rechargeable Aqueous Zn-Air Battery with Porous High Entropy Spinel Oxide Oxygen Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5096363</link>
      <description>Cagla Ozgur, Tuncay Erdil, Uygar Geyikci, Ersu L&#246;k&#231;&#252;, &#199;i&#287;dem Toparl&#305;, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406380642

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cagla Ozgur, Tuncay Erdil, Uygar Geyikci, Ersu L&#246;k&#231;&#252;, &#199;i&#287;dem Toparl&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5096363</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280114

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "A review on research progress of double perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts and supercapacitors"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280167

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4lf00395k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280292

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280306

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280428

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280429

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser induced oxidation Raman spectroscopy as analysis tool for iridium-based oxygen evolution catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03592e</link>
      <description>Stefan Speer, Sven Jovanovic, Alexandre Merlen, Francesco B&#224;rtoli, Kiran Kiran, N. Nijs-De Wolf, Andr&#233; Karl, Eva Jodat, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406346003

                The study of degradation behavior of electrocatalysts in an industrial context calls for rapid and efficient analysis methods. Optical methods like Raman spectroscopy fulfil these requirements and are thus predestined for this purpose. However, the iridium utilized in proton exchange membrane electrolysis (PEMEL) is Raman inactive in its metallic state. This work demonstrates the high oxidation sensitivity of iridium and its utilization in analysis of catalyst materials. Laser induced oxidation Raman spectroscopy (LIORS) is established as a novel method for qualitative, chemical and structural analysis of iridium catalysts. Differences in particle sizes of iridium powders drastically change oxidation sensitivity. Oxidation of the iridium powders to IrO2 occurred at a laser power density of 0.47 &#177; 0.06 mW &#956;m-2 for the 850 &#956;m powder and at 0.12 &#177; 0.06 mW &#956;m-2 and 0.019 &#177; 0.015 mW &#956;m-2 for the 50 &#956;m and 0.7-0.9 &#956;m powders respectively. LIORS was utilized to assess possible deterioration of an iridium electrocatalyst due to operation under electrolysis. The operating electrocatalyst exhibited higher oxidation sensitivity, suggesting smaller iridium particle size due to catalyst dissolution. Peak shifts of the IrO2 signal were utilized to assess differences in transformation temperatures. The operated electrocatalyst transformed to IrO2 at lower temperature (8 cm-1 redshift) relative to the pristine catalyst (10 cm-1 redshift), demonstrating that pre-oxidation of the iridium to amorphous IrOx during electrolysis diminishes the energy barrier needed for IrO2 formation. Thus, LIORS can be utilized as a straightforward screening method for the analysis of iridium electrocatalysts in the industrial application of PEMEL.</description>
      <author>Stefan Speer, Sven Jovanovic, Alexandre Merlen, Francesco B&#224;rtoli, Kiran Kiran, N. Nijs-De Wolf, Andr&#233; Karl, Eva Jodat, R&#252;diger&#8208;A. Eichel</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp03592e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Ni-exsolved Perovskite Catalysts for Oxygen-evolution Reactions in Alkaline Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7316/jhne.2024.35.6.661</link>
      <description>J.-F. Lee, Journal of Hydrogen and New Energy. 35(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406380292

                No abstract</description>
      <author>J.-F. Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7316/jhne.2024.35.6.661</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloride Residues in RuO2 Catalysts Enhance Its Stability and Efficiency for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420860</link>
      <description>Huile Jin, Jiadong Chen, Menghui Qi, Yun Yang, Xiaofen Xiao, Ying Li, Yong Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406255095

                Ruthenium dioxide (RuO2) is a benchmark electrocatalyst for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWE), but its stability during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is often compromised by lattice oxygen involvement and metal dissolution. Despite that the typical synthesis of RuO2 produces chloride residues, the underlying function of chloride have not well investigated. In this study, we synthesized chlorine&#8208;containing RuO2 (RuO2&#8208;Cl) and pure RuO2 catalysts with similar morphology and crystallinity. RuO2&#8208;Cl demonstrated superior stability, three times greater than that of pure RuO2, and a lower overpotential of 176 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2. Furthermore, the RuO2&#8208;Cl catalysts that were in situ synthesized on a platinum&#8208;coated titanium felt could maintain high performance for up to 1200 hours at 100 mA cm&#8208;2. Computational and experimental analyses show that chloride stabilizes RuO2 by substituting the bridging oxygen atoms, which subsequently inhibits lattice oxygen evolution and Ru demetallation. Notably, this substitution also lowers the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step by strengthening the binding of *OOH intermediates. These findings offer new insights into the previously unknown role of chloride residues and how to improve RuO2 stability.</description>
      <author>Huile Jin, Jiadong Chen, Menghui Qi, Yun Yang, Xiaofen Xiao, Ying Li, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo2C&#8211;CoNi heterostructure-knotted CNFs for efficient hydrogen and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.078</link>
      <description>Yingjie Ding, Chaoyang Zhu, Zezhong Xu, Weishen Yang, Hongdian Lu, Kunhong Hu, Ping Chen, Jinsong Xie, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406279917

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingjie Ding, Chaoyang Zhu, Zezhong Xu, Weishen Yang, Hongdian Lu, Kunhong Hu, Ping Chen, Jinsong Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Urchin-Like Nife2o4 Superparticles with Bi-Dimensional Carbon Structures for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095915</link>
      <description>Junjie Qiu, Xiangyun Xi, Shuoran Zheng, Tongtao Li, Yajun Wang, Xiaomeng Ren, Angang Dong, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406321124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junjie Qiu, Xiangyun Xi, Shuoran Zheng, Tongtao Li, Yajun Wang, Xiaomeng Ren, Angang Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5095915</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlation Between Conductivity and Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity in Perovskite Oxides CaMnO3-&#948;, Ca0.5Sr0.5MnO3-&#948; and SrMnO3-&#948;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/suschem6010003</link>
      <description>Amara Martinson, Mandy Guinn, Peter Mortensen, Ram Krishna Hona, Sustainable Chemistry. 6(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406324549

                The perovskite oxides CaMnO3-&#948;, Ca0.5Sr0.5MnO3-&#948;, and SrMnO3-&#948; were synthesized in air using a solid-state method, and their structural, electrical, and electrocatalytic properties were studied in relation to their oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Iodometric titration showed &#948; values of 0.05, 0.05, and 0.0, respectively, indicating that Mn is predominantly in the 4+ oxidation state across all materials, consistent with prior reports. Detailed characterization was performed using X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), iodometric titration, and variable-temperature conductivity measurements. Four-point probe DC measurements revealed that CaMnO3-&#948; (&#948; = 0.05) has a semiconductive behavior over a temperature range from 25 &#176;C to 300 &#176;C, with its highest conductivity attributed to polaron activity. Cyclic voltammetry (CV) in 0.1 M KOH was employed to assess OER catalytic performance, which correlated with room-temperature conductivity. CaMnO3-&#948; exhibited superior catalytic activity, followed by Ca0.5Sr0.5MnO3-&#948; and SrMnO3-&#948;, demonstrating that increased conductivity enhances OER performance. The conductivity trend, CaMnO3-&#948; &gt; Ca0.5Sr0.5MnO3-&#948; &gt; SrMnO3-&#948;, aligns with OER activity, underscoring a direct link between electronic transport properties and catalytic efficiency within this series.</description>
      <author>Amara Martinson, Mandy Guinn, Peter Mortensen, Ram Krishna Hona</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/suschem6010003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni etching bimetallic ZIF in-situ construction of NiCo layer double hydroxides to promote oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162383</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Ting He, Can Zhang, Hang Ma, Junli Wang, Ruidong Xu, Linjing Yang, Nan Wang, Hong Guo, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406338042

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Ting He, Can Zhang, Hang Ma, Junli Wang, Ruidong Xu, Linjing Yang, Nan Wang, Hong Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2025.162383</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the acidic oxygen evolution reaction efficiency of sol&#8211;gel synthesized SrCo0.5Ir0.5O3 catalysts through optimized ball milling and acid leaching</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242496</link>
      <description>D.Z. Yang, Nicolai Sage Andreas, Ankit K. Yadav, Kyriakos C. Stylianou, Zhenxing Feng, APL Energy. 3(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406329854

                High-efficiency and low-cost catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic electrolytes are critical for electrochemical water splitting in proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzers to produce green hydrogen, a clean fuel for sustainable energy conversion and storage. Among OER catalysts, solid-state synthesized SrCo1&#8722;xIrxO3 has demonstrated superior activity compared to commercial standards, such as IrO2 and RuO2. However, the solid-state synthesis process is economically inefficient for industrial use due to the potential for impurities and low yield of the final product. In addition, the requirement for electrochemical cycling to activate the catalyst introduces contaminations and uncertainties for industrial applications. In this study, a modified solution-based sol&#8211;gel method was employed to produce SrCo0.5Ir0.5O3 (SCIO) with high purity and yield. Subsequent ball milling and acid leaching treatments were applied, resulting in a catalyst with higher efficiency than those activated solely by electrochemical cycling. The electrochemical analysis and physical characterizations of our SCIO catalyst after ex-situ post-synthesis treatments show a similar active phase in composition and structure to those obtained through in situ electrochemical cycling and activation. Our approach simplifies the preparation process, making the catalyst ready for direct use in PEM electrolyzers without further treatment, offering a promising solution for producing high-performance, industrial-scale OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>D.Z. Yang, Nicolai Sage Andreas, Ankit K. Yadav, Kyriakos C. Stylianou, Zhenxing Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0242496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406206988

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406207155

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering surface sulfur vacancies of cobalt-doped nickel sulfide arrays induced by Ar plasma treatment to promote oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.059</link>
      <description>Kai Peng, Peng Cui, Fang Miao, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 102(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406341246

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kai Peng, Peng Cui, Fang Miao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2025.01.059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406206708

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Yuwei Dong, Mingyu Wu, Yu Ren, Zhou Yu, Zhao Zhen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406207003

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuwei Dong, Mingyu Wu, Yu Ren, Zhou Yu, Zhao Zhen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406206666

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Big pyridyl Schiff base &#960;-conjugated skeleton based cobalt/iron metal complexes: a bimetallic electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406206678

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc04325a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A general concept toward the in situ encapsulation of metal sites in a microporous Si-C-O-N-based matrix to stimulate superior oxygen evolution reaction activity (invited conference)</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4406339925</link>
      <description>Marwan Ben Miled, Marina Fradin, Olivier Masson, Aur&#233;lien Habrioux, Samuel Bernard, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406339925

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Marwan Ben Miled, Marina Fradin, Olivier Masson, Aur&#233;lien Habrioux, Samuel Bernard</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4406339925</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bi-directional Evolution of Graphenic Vacancy Structure in Oxygen Plasma Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2025.110529</link>
      <description>Yinong Chen, Shuyu Fan, Shu Xiao, Hu Zhang, Yi Wu, Jing Wu, Guoliang Tang, Fenghua Su, Paul K. Chu, Tribology International. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406326183

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yinong Chen, Shuyu Fan, Shu Xiao, Hu Zhang, Yi Wu, Jing Wu, Guoliang Tang, Fenghua Su, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.triboint.2025.110529</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Annealing effects on the microstructural and mechanical evolution of high-velocity oxygen-fuel (HVOF) sprayed Al0.3CrFeNiTi0.3 medium-entropy alloy coatings</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2025.131805</link>
      <description>Rasim Eri&#351;, Ashok Meghwal, Surinder Singh, Christopher C. Berndt, Andrew Siao Ming Ang, Paul Munroe, Surface and Coatings Technology. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406378455

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rasim Eri&#351;, Ashok Meghwal, Surinder Singh, Christopher C. Berndt, Andrew Siao Ming Ang, Paul Munroe</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2025.131805</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Saleem Raza, Ata Ur Rehman, Cheng Chen, Tianyu Zhao, Asif Hayat, Tariq Bashir, Liguo Shen, Yasin Orooji, Hongjun Lin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280299

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Saleem Raza, Ata Ur Rehman, Cheng Chen, Tianyu Zhao, Asif Hayat, Tariq Bashir, Liguo Shen, Yasin Orooji, Hongjun Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Synergistically self-assembled &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;in situ&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; growth of MXene@MOF derived sodium alginate hydrogel 3D frameworks as next-generation electrocatalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406280283

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta08240k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-doped graphene supported single-atom catalysts for efficient electrocatalytic oxidation of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural to to 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp04568h</link>
      <description>Mingrong Li, Yungan Huang, Qiong Luo, Yongfei Ji, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406358359

                Electrocatalytic oxidation of 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) to 2,5-furandicarboxylic acid (FDCA) is a promising alternative for oxygen evolution reactions. The search for efficient catalysts has been attracting increasing scientific attention. This work...</description>
      <author>Mingrong Li, Yungan Huang, Qiong Luo, Yongfei Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp04568h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activity and stability origin of core-shell catalysts: Unignorable atomic diffusion behavior</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc08019j</link>
      <description>Yuanyuan Xue, Letian Chen, Lijuan Zhang, Gengfeng Zheng, Xu Zhang, Zhen Ping Zhou, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333715

                The exceptional oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performances of core-shell catalysts are well-documented, yet their activity and durability origins have been interpreted only based on the...</description>
      <author>Yuanyuan Xue, Letian Chen, Lijuan Zhang, Gengfeng Zheng, Xu Zhang, Zhen Ping Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc08019j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ Raman study on the impact of configurational entropy on catalytic activity for industrial water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07090a</link>
      <description>Chenyang Duan, Hao Zhang, Zhiwei Hu, Zhenya Li, Wen&#8208;Jie Bian, Chao Jing, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Linjuan Zhang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406320124

                Modulating the configurational entropy of materials is an effective strategy to develop efficient and robust electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in clean energy technologies. However, the impact of...</description>
      <author>Chenyang Duan, Hao Zhang, Zhiwei Hu, Zhenya Li, Wen&#8208;Jie Bian, Chao Jing, Jian&#8208;Qiang Wang, Linjuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07090a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unravelling the pH-depended mechanism of ferroelectric polarization on different dynamic pathways of photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc08291e</link>
      <description>Xing Ji, Zhouhao Zhu, Ming Zhou, Ying Zhang, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Yunhuai Zhang, Peng Xiao, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406378842

                Ferroelectric polarization is considered to be an effective strategy capable of improving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) of photoelectrocatalysis. The frontier challenge is to clarify how the polarization field control...</description>
      <author>Xing Ji, Zhouhao Zhu, Ming Zhou, Ying Zhang, Li&#8208;Yong Gan, Yunhuai Zhang, Peng Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc08291e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the role of the Cr dopant in RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; in highly efficient acid water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt03131h</link>
      <description>Hui Liu, Maolin Li, Zhizhao Zhang, Ying Li, Qiuyan Hao, Limin Liang, Zhang Wen, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406328725

                The design of acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts with high activity and durability is the key to achieving efficient hydrogen production. Herein, we report a Cr-doped RuO</description>
      <author>Hui Liu, Maolin Li, Zhizhao Zhang, Ying Li, Qiuyan Hao, Limin Liang, Zhang Wen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt03131h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Establishing the Link Between Oxygen Vacancy and Activity Enhancement in Acidic Water Oxidation of Trigonal Iridium Oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423353</link>
      <description>Wenxiang Zhu, Mengjie Ma, Dongdong Gao, Jinxin Chen, Hui Huang, Kun Feng, Qun Wang, Jie Wu, Penghao Li, Jian Guo, Zhenglong Fan, Jun Zhong, Qi Shao, Fan Liao, Yan Liu, Mingwang Shao, Zhenhui Kang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406255149

                Developing durable IrO2&#8208;based electrocatalysts with high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity under acidic condition is crucial for proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. While oxygen defects are considered potentially important in OER, their direct relationship with catalytic activity has yet to be established. In this study, we introduced abundant oxygen vacancies through Re doping in 2D IrO2 (Re0.03Ir0.97O2), demonstrating their decisive role in enhancing OER performance. The Re0.03Ir0.97O2 catalyst exhibited excellent OER performance with an overpotential of 193 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and sustained activity for over 650 hours, significantly surpassing the undoped catalyst. Moreover, it maintained operation at a cell voltage of 1.70 V (~1200 mA cm&#8208;2) for over 140 hours without significant performance degradation. Theoretical calculations coupled with cyclic voltammetry, transient potential scanning and in&#8208;situ characterizations confirmed the adsorbate evolving mechanism on Re0.03Ir0.97O2, as well as the critical role of Re&#8208;induced oxygen vacancies in enhancing OER performance. These findings highlight that oxygen defects directly influence OER activity, providing guidance for the application of oxygen vacancy engineering in electrocatalyst design.</description>
      <author>Wenxiang Zhu, Mengjie Ma, Dongdong Gao, Jinxin Chen, Hui Huang, Kun Feng, Qun Wang, Jie Wu, Penghao Li, Jian Guo, Zhenglong Fan, Jun Zhong, Qi Shao, Fan Liao, Yan Liu, Mingwang Shao, Zhenhui Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202423353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution Performance of Manganese Carbonate in an Acidic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405336</link>
      <description>B. S. Krishnaveni, S. Devaraj, ChemistrySelect. 10(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406273025

                Abstract Hydrogen, a sustainable alternative to fossil fuels, can be efficiently produced by electrochemical water splitting, which involves hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode. Both HER and OER require electrocatalysts. The large scale implementation of this technology depends heavily on the development of highly active, stable, and cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts. In view of this, several electrocatalysts have been explored. Herein, the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution performance of MnCO 3 synthesized by hydrothermal method is reported. While MnCO 3 is chosen as the electrocatalyst owing to cost&#8208;effect and abundant precursors, environmental friendliness, and good electrochemical activity, the hydrothermal method is chosen for its simplicity, efficiency, and scalability. The micron size MnCO 3 synthesized hydrothermally exhibits &#951; 10 of 143 mV, a Tafel slope of 72 mV dec &#8722;1 and retains its performance over 3000 cycles and 14 h of continuous operation in 0.5 M H 2 SO 4 , demonstrating its utility in sustainable hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>B. S. Krishnaveni, S. Devaraj</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202405336</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induction of Nanoscale Magnetic Ordering in Non&#8208;Ferrous Layered Double Hydroxides: Stabilizing Spintronic Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412021</link>
      <description>Sakshi Kansal, Rahul Ravindran, Alok Kumar Srivastava, Amreesh Chandra, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406381670

                Abstract Inducing magnetic ordering in a non&#8208;ferrous layered double hydroxides (LDHs) instigates higher spin polarization, which leads to enhanced efficiency during oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In nano&#8208;sized magnetic materials, the concept of elongated grains drives domain alignment under the application of an external magnetic field. Hence, near the solid electrode interface, modified magnetohydrodynamics (MHD) positively impacts the electrocatalytic ability of non&#8208;ferrous nanocatalysts. Consequently, significant improvement in the water&#8208;splitting kinetics can be obtained by using even low magnetic fields. At 100 Gauss, 20% and 10% decrement in the overpotential is reported for OER and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), respectively. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations are also presented to explain the thermodynamics of the HER/OER processes. It is established that the Gibbs energy of the process can reduce the exchange energy barrier by using dopant like cobalt. The additional cobalt metal active site have the highest probability for adsorption of reactive intermediates during HER and OER, which results in higher efficiencies.</description>
      <author>Sakshi Kansal, Rahul Ravindran, Alok Kumar Srivastava, Amreesh Chandra</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202412021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-Doped activated carbon derived from water hyacinth for ultra-stable metal-free bifunctional electrode for zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4314/bcse.v39i3.14</link>
      <description>Assegid Ergete, Yongfa Huang, Jiawei Zhou, Teklewold Getachew, Asmamaw Taye, Ruidong Xia, Emmanuel I. Iwuoha, Xinwen Peng, Shimelis Admassie, Bulletin of the Chemical Society of Ethiopia. 39(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406243109

                Activated N-doped carbon derived from water hyacinth leaves (WHL) was prepared and investigated as metal-free bi-functional catalyst for oxygen reduction and evolution (ORR/OER) in zinc-air batteries (ZABs). Scanning electron microscopy (SEM), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and Brunauer&#8211;Emmett&#8211;Teller (BET) methods were used to examine the morphology, elemental composition and the specific surface area of the samples, respectively. Linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) at rotating disk electrodes (RDEs) and rotating ring-disk electrodes (RRDEs) were employed to characterize the electrocatalytic activities. The electrochemical studies reveal that N-doped porous carbon from N-WHLs exhibited remarkable electrocatalytic activity for ORR, with an onset potential of 0.95 V and half-wave potential of 0.88 V comparable to commercial Pt/C catalyst. It also displays promising activity towards OER, with an overall potential of 1.86 V versus RHE to reach a current density of 10 mAcm&#61485;&#61490;, resulting in an oxygen electrode activity (OEA) value of 0.98 V. The percentage of hydrogen peroxide produced was significantly low, with average electron transfer number value of 3.94 at 0.8 V for N-WHL. Furthermore, the ZAB using N-WHL catalysts as an air cathode displayed a power density of 84 mW cm&#8722;2 and superior stability over 450 hours. KEY WORDS: Bifunctional catalyst, Oxygen reduction reaction, Oxygen evolution reaction, Water hyacinth, Zinc-air battery. Bull. Chem. Soc. Ethiop. 2025, 39(3), 571-584. DOI: https://dx.doi.org/10.4314/bcse.v39i3.14</description>
      <author>Assegid Ergete, Yongfa Huang, Jiawei Zhou, Teklewold Getachew, Asmamaw Taye, Ruidong Xia, Emmanuel I. Iwuoha, Xinwen Peng, Shimelis Admassie</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4314/bcse.v39i3.14</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Catalysis for Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries by Multiwalled Carbon Nanotubes&#8208;Crosslinked Carbon Dodecahedra Embedded with Co&#8211;Fe Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409129</link>
      <description>Haiyang Shi, Lei Zhang, Xinhua Huang, Qingquan Kong, Abdukader Abdukayum, Yingtang Zhou, Guoyou Cheng, Sanshuang Gao, Guangzhi Hu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406288041

                Abstract The design and fabrication of nanocatalysts with high accessibility and sintering resistance remain significant challenges in heterogeneous electrocatalysis. Herein, a novel catalyst is introduced that combines electronic pumping with alloy crystal facet engineering. At the nanoscale, the electronic pump leverages the chemical potential difference to drive electron migration from one region to another, separating and transferring electron&#8208;hole pairs. This mechanism accelerates the reaction kinetics and improves the reaction rate. The interface electronic structure optimization enables the CoFe/carbon nanotube (CNT) catalyst to exhibit outstanding oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Specifically, this catalyst achieves an ORR half&#8208;wave potential (E&#8321;/&#8322;) of 0.895 V, outperforming standard Pt/C and RuO&#8322; electrocatalysts in terms of both specific activity and stability. It also demonstrates excellent electrochemical performance for OER, with an overpotential of only 287 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 . Theoretical calculations reveal that the carefully designed crystal facets reduce the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining steps for both ORR and OER, optimizing O&#8322; adsorption and promoting the oxygen capture process. This study highlights the potential of developing cost&#8208;effective bifunctional ORR&#8211;OER electrocatalysts, offering a promising strategy for advancing Zn&#8211;air battery technology.</description>
      <author>Haiyang Shi, Lei Zhang, Xinhua Huang, Qingquan Kong, Abdukader Abdukayum, Yingtang Zhou, Guoyou Cheng, Sanshuang Gao, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Potential of Metal Diborides for Electrocatalytic Water Splitting: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12873</link>
      <description>Ebrahim Sadeghi, Sanaz Chamani, Naeimeh Sadat Peighambardoust, Umut Aydemir, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406288078

                Electrocatalytic water splitting (EWS) driven by renewable energy is vital for clean hydrogen (H 2 ) production and reducing reliance on fossil fuels. While IrO 2 and RuO 2 are the leading electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and Pt for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acidic environments, the need for efficient, stable, and affordable materials persists. Recently, transition&#8208;metal borides (TMBs), particularly metal diborides (MDbs), have gained attention due to their unique layered crystal structures with multicentered boron bonds, offering remarkable physicochemical properties. Their nearly 2D structures boost electrochemical performance by offering high conductivity and a large active surface area, making them well&#8208;suited for advanced energy storage and conversion technologies. This review provides a comprehensive overview of the critical factors for water splitting, the crystal and electronic structures of MDbs, and their synthetic strategies. Furthermore, it examines the relationship between catalytic performance and intermediate adsorption as elucidated by first&#8208;principle calculations. The review also highlights the latest experimental advancements in MDb&#8208;based electrocatalysts and addresses the current challenges and future directions for their development.</description>
      <author>Ebrahim Sadeghi, Sanaz Chamani, Naeimeh Sadat Peighambardoust, Umut Aydemir</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12873</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Dual Active Sites of Ni/Co(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Ru Heterointerface for Robust Electrocatalytic Alkaline Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410086</link>
      <description>Xinhui Yu, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Xianyu Chu, Bo Liu, Shi Zhou, Chunbo Liu, Guangbo Che, Guojie Liu, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406381831

                Abstract Constructing bifunctional electrocatalysts through the synergistic effect of diverse metal sites is crucial for achieving high&#8208;efficiency and steady overall water splitting. Herein, a &#8220;dual&#8208;HER/OER&#8208;sites&#8208;in&#8208;one&#8221; strategy is proposed to regulate dominant active sites, wherein Ni/Co(OH) 2 &#8208;Ru heterogeneous catalysts formed on nickel foam (NF) demonstrate remarkable catalytic activity for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) as well as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Meanwhile, the potentials@10 mA cm &#8722;2 of Ni/Co(OH) 2 &#8208;Ru@NF for overall alkaline water and seawater splitting are only 1.36 and 1.41 V, respectively, surpassing those of commercial RuO 2 @NF and Pt/C@NF. The Ru site is identified as the primary active site for HER by density functional theory (DFT) calculations, while the Co(OH) 2 site displays the minimal rate&#8208;determining step energy barrier (RDS) and functions as the main active site for OER. This study offers novel perspectives on the rational utilization of diverse metal species&#8217; catalytic capabilities for developing dual active sites multifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Xinhui Yu, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Xianyu Chu, Bo Liu, Shi Zhou, Chunbo Liu, Guangbo Che, Guojie Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Functional NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@CoMo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction Couple as Electrode for Hydrogen Production via Energy&#8208;Saving Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410848</link>
      <description>Njemuwa Nwaji, Boka Fikadu, Magdalena Osial, Magdalena Warczak, Zahra Moazzami Goudarzi, Marianna Gniadek, Sohrab Asgaran, Jaebeom Lee, Michael Giersig, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406371194

                The urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is characterized by a lower overpotential compared to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) during electrolysis, which facilitates the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode. Charge distribution, which can be modulated by the introduction of a heterostructure, plays a key role in enhancing the adsorption and cleavage of chemical groups within urea molecules. Herein, a facile all-room temperature synthesis of functional heterojunction NiCo2S4/CoMo2S4 grown on carbon cloth (CC) is presented, and the as-prepared electrode served as a catalyst for simultaneous hydrogen evolution and urea oxidation reaction. The Density Functional Theory (DFT) study reveals spontaneous transfer of charge at the heterointerface of NiCo2S4/CoMo2S4, which triggers the formation of localized electrophilic/nucleophilic regions and facilitates the adsorption of electron donating/electron withdrawing group in urea molecules during the UOR. The NiCo2S4/CoMo2S4// NiCo2S4/CoMo2S4 electrode pair required only a cell voltage of 1.17 and 1.18 V to deliver a current density of 10 and 100 mA cm-2 respectively in urea electrolysis cell and display very good stability. Tests performed in real urine samples show similar catalytic performance to urea electrolytes, making the work one of the best transition metal-based catalysts for UOR applications, promising both efficient hydrogen production and urea decomposition.</description>
      <author>Njemuwa Nwaji, Boka Fikadu, Magdalena Osial, Magdalena Warczak, Zahra Moazzami Goudarzi, Marianna Gniadek, Sohrab Asgaran, Jaebeom Lee, Michael Giersig</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202410848</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Precise Modulation of Moni4/Moo2 Nanowires Via a Ternary Nicofe Complex for Enhanced Electrochemical Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5093560</link>
      <description>Peng Zuo, Fanfan Liu, Fuyan Zhao, Xiaofei Zhang, Yun Li, Kaiqin Xu, Fang Xiaowei, Zhiwei Zhang, Yun Shen, Jinyun Liu, Yefeng Liu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406275085

                Developing clean and renewable energy technologies requires the design of efficient bifunctional catalysts that do not rely on inert metals for electrochemical water splitting. This study introduced a novel three-step strategy to fabricate NiCoFe-modified MoNi4/MoO2 nanowires supported on nickel foam substrates (denoted as NiCoFe-MoNi4/MoO2/NF), which demonstrate excellent catalytic performance with an impressively low overpotential of just 13 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 current density for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 230 mV at 50 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Notably, its performance greatly exceeded that of many noble-metal catalysts, requiring only 1.51 V for overall water splitting at 50 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 current density. The exceptional catalytic efficiency is ascribed to the unique one-dimensional (1D) nanostructure and the synergistic interactions between the NiCoFe complex and the MoNi4/MoO2 framework, which improve mass transfer, increase active site exposure, and enhance intrinsic catalytic activity. The incorporation of cobalt (Co) and iron (Fe) into the ternary complex significantly enhanced the efficiencies of both HER and OER, offering a promising route for developing high-performance, low-cost bifunctional electrocatalysts and advancing sustainable energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Peng Zuo, Fanfan Liu, Fuyan Zhao, Xiaofei Zhang, Yun Li, Kaiqin Xu, Fang Xiaowei, Zhiwei Zhang, Yun Shen, Jinyun Liu, Yefeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5093560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the Coordination Energy of Co&#8208;N&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Sites by Co Nanoparticles Integrated with Fe&#8208;NCNTs for Boosting PEMFC and Zn&#8208;Air Battery Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411894</link>
      <description>Jie Zheng, C.W. Lai, Wenxuan Chen, Chao Liu, Tenghui Yuan, Jun Lv, Bote Zhao, Dai Dang, Guifa Long, Tiejun Wang, Xiaopeng Han, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406336466

                Abstract Enhancing the catalytic performance and durability of M&#8208;N&#9472;C catalyst is crucial for the efficient operation of proton exchange membrane fuel cells (PEMFCs) and Zn&#8208;Air batteries (ZABs). Herein, an approach is developed for the in situ fabrication of a MOFs&#8208;derived porous carbon material, co&#8208;loaded with Co nanoparticles (NPs) and Co&#8208;N x sites and integrated onto Fe&#8208;doped carbon nanotubes (CNTs), named Co NP/SA &#8208;NC/Fe&#8208;NCNTs. Incorporating polymer&#8208;wrapped CNTs improves MOFs dispersion annealing at high temperature, which amplifies the three&#8208;phase boundary (TPB) by generating much more mesopores and exposing additional active sites within the catalysts layer. Furthermore, density functional theory (DFT) calculations indicate that the presence of Co NPs promotes the conversion of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates for Co&#8208;N x sites. The optimized catalysts display a half&#8208;wave potential of 0.9 V (vs RHE) for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and a low overpotential of 327 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, which significantly outperforms the counterpart single structure, as well as noble&#8208;metal&#8208;based catalysts. Specifically, the PEMFCs and ZABs derived from Co NP/SA &#8208;NC/Fe&#8208;NCNTs catalyst exhibit power densities of 702 and 192 mW cm &#8722;2 , respectively. This work offers novel insights into the synthesis of the composited bifunctional carbon materials for ZABs and PEMFCs application.</description>
      <author>Jie Zheng, C.W. Lai, Wenxuan Chen, Chao Liu, Tenghui Yuan, Jun Lv, Bote Zhao, Dai Dang, Guifa Long, Tiejun Wang, Xiaopeng Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202411894</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Methanol-Enhanced Low-Cell-Voltage Hydrogen Generation at Industrial-Grade Current Density by Triadic Active Sites of Pt&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;Pd&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;n&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&#8211;(Ni,Co)(OH)&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12665</link>
      <description>An Pei, Ruikuan Xie, Lihua Zhu, Fengshun Wu, Zinan Huang, Yongyu Pang, Yu&#8208;Chung Chang, Guoliang Chai, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Qingsheng Gao, Congxiao Shang, Guang Li, Jinyu Ye, Huaze Zhu, Zhiqing Yang, Zhengxiao Guo, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406323640

                Methanol (ME) is a liquid hydrogen carrier, ideal for on-site-on-demand H2 generation, avoiding its costly and risky distribution issues, but this "ME-to-H2" electric conversion suffers from high voltage (energy consumption) and competitive oxygen evolution reaction. Herein, we demonstrate that a synergistic cofunctional Pt1Pdn/(Ni,Co)(OH)x catalyst with Pt single atoms (Pt1) and Pd nanoclusters (Pdn) anchored on OH-vacancy(VOH)-rich (Ni,Co)(OH)x nanoparticles create synergistic triadic active sites, allowing for methanol-enhanced low-voltage H2 generation. For MOR, OH* is preferentially adsorbed on Pdn and then interacts with the intermediates (such as *CHO or *CHOOH) adsorbed favorably on neighboring Pt1 with the assistance of hydrogen bonding from the surface hydrogen of (Ni,Co)(OH)x. The enhanced selectivity of the *CHOOH pathway, instead of *CO, sustains the MOR activity to a practically high current density. For HER, triadic Pt1, Pdn, and OH-vacancy sites on (Ni,Co)(OH)x create an "acid-base" microenvironment to facilitate water adsorption and splitting, forming H* species on Pt1 and Pdn, and *OH at the vacancy, to promote efficient H2 evolution from the asymmetric Pt1 and Pdn sites via the Tafel mechanism. The triadic-site synergy opens new avenues for the design and synthesis of highly efficient and stable cofunctional catalysts for "on-site-on-demand" H2 production, here facilitated by liquid methanol.</description>
      <author>An Pei, Ruikuan Xie, Lihua Zhu, Fengshun Wu, Zinan Huang, Yongyu Pang, Yu&#8208;Chung Chang, Guoliang Chai, Chih&#8208;Wen Pao, Qingsheng Gao, Congxiao Shang, Guang Li, Jinyu Ye, Huaze Zhu, Zhiqing Yang, Zhengxiao Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c12665</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Practical Inverse Design Approach for High-Entropy Catalysts with Generative AI</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5712388/v1</link>
      <description>Jun Jiang, Donglai Zhou, Ruyu Yang, Z. Jiao, Yuyang Cai, Luyuan Zhao, Lulu Guo, Guilin Ye, Song Wang, Linjiang Chen, Daobin Liu, Pieter E. S. Smith, Yan Huang, Qing Zhu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406380606

                Abstract The vast compositional space of high-entropy materials offers unprecedented opportunities for the development of powerful catalysts. However, their inverse design remains unfeasible due to the lack of robust theoretical frameworks and high-throughput experimental tools. This study demonstrates a practical inverse design approach that integrates spectroscopic descriptors, generative machine learning, and a robotic experimental platform to synthesize and optimize catalyst composition for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The automated system significantly accelerated catalysts design and experimental validation, reducing the time required for synthesis, characterization and performance testing from approximately 20 hours to only 78 minutes per sample. Following a rapid screen for efficient senary high-entropy catalysts, the spectroscopic generative model further optimized the top-performing candidate, lowering its overpotential at 10 mA/cm2 by an additional 32 mV. Our findings are a testament to the potential of an inverse design approach that incorporates spectroscopic descriptors into generative machine learning to accelerate catalyst discovery. Moreover, this approach is also expected to drive the intelligent design of high-performance complex materials.</description>
      <author>Jun Jiang, Donglai Zhou, Ruyu Yang, Z. Jiao, Yuyang Cai, Luyuan Zhao, Lulu Guo, Guilin Ye, Song Wang, Linjiang Chen, Daobin Liu, Pieter E. S. Smith, Yan Huang, Qing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5712388/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Reconstructed Spinel with Enhanced SO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt; Adsorption and Highly Exposed Co&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; From Heterostructure Boosts Activity and Stability at High Current Density for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419978</link>
      <description>Hongye Yang, F. Y. Chen, Xusheng Wang, Jinjie Qian, Jiajun Wang, Jiahao Li, Chang Lv, Lan Li, Sateesh Bandaru, Junkuo Gao, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406271936

                Abstract Developing overall water splitting non&#8208;noble metal electrocatalysts achieving long&#8208;term stability with high activity at industrial&#8208;grade current density remains challenging. Herein, a self&#8208;reconstruction strategy of Co 9 S 8 &#8208;Ni 3 S 2 /NCF is employed to fabricate Ni x Co 3&#8208;x O 4 &#8208;Ov&#8208; in which partial Co is replaced by Ni in the structure. The reconstructed Ni x Co 3&#8208;x O 4 &#8208;Ov can enhance the adsorbing ability of leached from the initial phase compared with Co spinel, achieving exceeding 1000&#8208;h oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and 600&#8208;h overall water splitting stability at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 with excellent activity. In situ Raman and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) results indicate that partial substitution of Ni for Co atoms enhances the adsorption capacity on the reconstructed Ni x Co 3&#8208;x O 4 &#8208;Ov, facilitating the formation of high&#8208;density Co 3+ active sites on (400) that expedited interfacial electron transfer at high current densities. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the adsorption of leached stabilizes surface oxygen vacancies and optimizes the adsorption energy of intermediates, thereby improving both stability and catalytic performance. The findings provide new insights into overcoming the activity&#8208;stability trade&#8208;off and contribute to the strategy for the design of electrocatalysts for long&#8208;term water splitting at industrial&#8208;grade current densities.</description>
      <author>Hongye Yang, F. Y. Chen, Xusheng Wang, Jinjie Qian, Jiajun Wang, Jiahao Li, Chang Lv, Lan Li, Sateesh Bandaru, Junkuo Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202419978</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Tiara Nickel Cluster Story from Theory to Catalytic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00087</link>
      <description>Piracha Sanwal, Xinrui Gu, Yifei Zhang, Gao Li, Precision Chemistry. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406207307

                As a transition material between bulk materials and individual atoms, nickel clusters have interesting electrical and structural characteristics that could make them useful as catalysts. To examine the catalytic efficiency of nickel clusters in different applications, this Review combines experimental techniques with density functional theory (DFT). Researchers have shown that nickel clusters can activate and alter tiny molecules like CO, NO, and H2 through DFT studies that delve deeply into their electronic structures, adsorption mechanisms, and stability. These findings lay the groundwork for the development of effective catalysts for various processes. Nickel clusters considerably improve the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), indicating their promise for renewable energy conversion. Furthermore, electrocatalysis for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) showcases the electrochemical performance of nickel clusters, demonstrating their stability and efficiency. The adaptability of nickel clusters is further demonstrated by their use in nitrogen reduction to ammonia. Experimental data confirm that these clusters are good catalysts for this crucial industrial activity. Hydrocarbon reforming and pollutant degradation are two areas in which research has shown that nickel clusters can be useful in thermal reactions. X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and environmental transmission electron microscopy (ETEM) are examples of in situ characterization techniques that support theoretical predictions by providing real-time insights into the structural alterations and active sites of nickel clusters during these processes. Preparing the way for future research and practical applications in energy and environmental technologies, this thorough study highlights the great potential of nickel clusters in constructing sustainable and efficient catalytic systems.</description>
      <author>Piracha Sanwal, Xinrui Gu, Yifei Zhang, Gao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/prechem.4c00087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroelectric Polarization&#8208;Induced Performance Enhancements in BiFeO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanodes for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417651</link>
      <description>Michael Gunawan, Owen Bowdler, Yingtang Zhou, Xueqing Fang, Qi Zhang, Yasuhiro Sakamoto, Kaiwen Sun, Denny Gunawan, Shery L. Y. Chang, Rose Amal, V. Nagarajan, Jason Scott, Judy N. Hart, Cui Ying Toe, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406371334

                Abstract Photoelectrochemical (PEC) processes will play a crucial role in future clean energy systems, however severe charge recombination and sluggish charge transfer kinetics have hindered their practical adoption. Exploiting ferroelectric polarization&#8208;controlled charge dynamics promises an additional lever that can potentially enable the performance limits of traditional static photoelectrodes to be surpassed. Here one of the most notable ferroelectric polarization&#8208;induced photocurrent enhancements is reported, using a heterostructure of the multiferroic bismuth ferrite (BFO) and the photoactive bismuth vanadate (BVO) in a neutral pH electrolyte. In contrast to previous works, enhancements for both poling directions are reported, of 136% for down&#8208;poled BFO/BVO and 70% for up&#8208;poled BFO/BVO at 1.23 V RHE in comparison to the unpoled sample, delivering a Faradaic efficiency of &gt;95% for prolonged oxygen evolution reaction. Extensive PEC and surface analyses complemented by density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal the improvements are attributed to the modulation of gradients in the BFO band energies, as well as changes in band&#8208;bending and offsets at the interfaces. Given the scalability of the employed sol&#8211;gel synthesis method and the use of environmentally benign materials and PEC conditions, these findings pave the way for multifunctional materials as new&#8208;generation agile and dynamic catalysts and photoelectrode systems.</description>
      <author>Michael Gunawan, Owen Bowdler, Yingtang Zhou, Xueqing Fang, Qi Zhang, Yasuhiro Sakamoto, Kaiwen Sun, Denny Gunawan, Shery L. Y. Chang, Rose Amal, V. Nagarajan, Jason Scott, Judy N. Hart, Cui Ying Toe</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Engineering Triggered Phase Formation of Bimetallic Thiospinels with Excellent HzOR and OER Activity for Energy&#8208;Efficient Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401773</link>
      <description>Diya Raveendran, Viplove Mishra, Athma E. Praveen, Avishek Roy, Aditi Chandrasekar, Venkataramanan Mahalingam, Ananda Basak, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406270417

                Introducing foreign elements into a crystal lattice could trigger phase transformation, serving as an excellent means to fabricate highly electrocatalytic phases. NiCo2S4 is a notably electrocatalytic thiospinel phase, normally synthesized via two&#8208;step route and rarely explored for electrocatalytic hydrazine oxidation reaction (HzOR). This work reports one&#8208;step hydrothermal syntheses of NiCo2S4 and CuCo2S4 and their performance for HzOR and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Time&#8208;dependent syntheses suggest formation of (M, Co)9S8; M=Ni/Cu phase, followed by conversion to the respective thiospinel phase. Computational study validates that the incorporation of Ni into Co9S8 disrupts its stability and induces the formation of a stable bi&#8208;metallic thiospinel phase. Even without the assistance of metal foam substrate, NiCo2S4 displayed remarkable activity for HzOR requiring potentials of 153 and 350 mV to afford current densities of 10 and 500 mA/cm2, respectively. Furthermore, NiCo2S4 showed good activity for OER, providing 10 mA/cm2 at 290 mV. For hydrazine&#8208;assisted H2 production, the two&#8208;electrode setup, NiCo2S4||Pt/C attained a current density of 10 mA/cm2 at 140 mV, which is 1.39 V less than that required for conventional water electrolyzer (1.53 V). Long&#8208;term durability of NiCo2S4 for both HzOR and OER at high current densities highlights the suitability of the catalyst for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Diya Raveendran, Viplove Mishra, Athma E. Praveen, Avishek Roy, Aditi Chandrasekar, Venkataramanan Mahalingam, Ananda Basak</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice Strain&#8208;Modulated Trifunctional CoMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Polymorph&#8208;Based Electrodes for Asymmetric Supercapacitors and Self&#8208;Powered Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409418</link>
      <description>Muhammad Mushtaq, Zhixiao Zhu, Hao Yang, Zeba Khanam, Yuwen Hu, Selvam Mathi, Zhongmin Wang, Muhammad&#8208;Sadeeq Balogun, Yongchao Huang, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406378838

                Abstract Developing efficient, multifunctional electrodes for energy storage and conversion devices is crucial. Herein, lattice strains are reported in the &#946;&#8208;phase polymorph of CoMoO 4 within CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 heterostructure via phosphorus doping (P&#8208;CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 ) and used as a high&#8208;performance trifunctional electrode for supercapacitors (SCs), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline electrolytes. A tensile strain of +2.42% on the &#946;&#8208;phase of CoMoO 4 in P&#8208;CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 results in superior electrochemical performance compared to CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 . The optimized P&#8208;CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 achieves a high energy density of 118 Wh kg &#8722;1 in an asymmetric supercapacitor and low overpotentials of 189 mV for the HER and 365 mV for the OER at a current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . This results in a low overall water splitting voltage of 1.71 V at the same current density making it an effective bifunctional electrode in a 1 m KOH freshwater electrolyte. Theoretical analysis shows that the excellent performance of P&#8208;CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 can be attributed to interfacial interactions between CoMoO 4 and Co 3 O 4 , and the &#946;&#8208;phase of CoMoO 4 , which lead to strong OH &#8722; adsorption and low energy barriers for reaction intermediates. Practical application is demonstrated by using P&#8208;CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 &#8208;based ASCs to self&#8208;generate hydrogen (H 2 ) in a P&#8208;CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 ||P&#8208;CoMoO 4 @Co 3 O 4 alkaline seawater electrolyzer, showcasing its potential for future energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Mushtaq, Zhixiao Zhu, Hao Yang, Zeba Khanam, Yuwen Hu, Selvam Mathi, Zhongmin Wang, Muhammad&#8208;Sadeeq Balogun, Yongchao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409418</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasonically Deposited Boron&#8208;Doped Silicon Decorated with Laser&#8208;Generated Iridium Nanoparticles as Manufacturing Approach for OER Electrodes in PEM Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400765</link>
      <description>Norbert Kazamer, Meike Tack, M. Spree, Martin Underberg, Ulrich Rost, Sven Reichenberger, Maximilian Cieluch, Hyder A. Salih, Florian J. Wirkert, Leonard B&#246;hm, Jeffrey Roth, Varatharaja Nallathambi, Baptiste Gault, Christoph Baer, Kerstin Orend, Stephan Barcikowski, Tim H&#252;lser, Michael Brodmann, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406378954

                Abstract The study introduces flexible and scalable manufacturing approach for electrodes utilizing boron&#8208;doped silicon as conductive support for iridium nanoparticles, addressing the challenges of cost and scarcity associated wit noble catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Colloidal Ir nanoparticles are synthesized via pulsed&#8208;laser ablation (&#8776;4&#8211;7 nm) and decorated on B&#8208;doped Si (&#8776;100 nm) through electrostatic adsorption. Titanium substrates are ultrasonically sprayed with Si:B &#8211; Ir and Ir nanoparticles with very low iridium loading of 12 wt.%. Crystalline Ir phases (Ir(111), Ir(200)) are observed and known to enhance the OER mechanism. Additionally, atom probe tomography confirms that the Si support particles contained 0.03&#8208;0.5 at% of boron throughout the entire particle, while electrical permittivity and through&#8208;plane measurements reveal a positive impact of B&#8208;doped Si on the electrical conductivity of the nanocatalysts and of the ultralow&#8208;loaded catalyst coated Ti substrates (0.12 mg Ir cm &#8722;2 ), respectively. Rotating disk electrode results show pronounced oxidation peaks for decorated Ir nanoparticles. The Si:B&#8208;Ir 4 nm catalyst exhibits the highest turonover frequency (2.62 s&#8315;&#185;) and a competitive electrochemical surface area (25 m 2 g Ir &#8722;1 ) compared to Si:B&#8208;Ir 7 nm (0.96 s&#8315;&#185;; 37.5 m 2 g Ir &#8722;1 ) and Ir black (0.24 s&#8315;&#185;; 5 m 2 g Ir &#8722;1 ). The overall analysis of the parameters highlights a performant catalytic efficiency, through balancing activity and reaction kinetics effectively.</description>
      <author>Norbert Kazamer, Meike Tack, M. Spree, Martin Underberg, Ulrich Rost, Sven Reichenberger, Maximilian Cieluch, Hyder A. Salih, Florian J. Wirkert, Leonard B&#246;hm, Jeffrey Roth, Varatharaja Nallathambi, Baptiste Gault, Christoph Baer, Kerstin Orend, Stephan Barcikowski, Tim H&#252;lser, Michael Brodmann</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400765</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positive Feedback Mechanism of Stability Degradation of the IrO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst Induced by Inferior Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05299</link>
      <description>Zeping Zhang, Minghui Yao, Renxing Huang, Chengcheng Sang, Zongqiang Mao, Y. P. Wang, Yanan Yin, Cheng Wang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406300745

                Iridium (Ir)-based catalysts embracing both catalytic activity and stability are of great significance for scaling up the application of proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). Herein, supported IrO2 on TiO2 (IrO2/TiO2) with high specific surface area and electrolytic activity was prepared by adopting a chlorine (Cl)-free synthesis based on the Adams fusion method. The crucial influential factors of annealing temperature were systematically explored on the catalytic activity and stability of IrO2/TiO2. Although increasing annealing temperature is believed to be of benefit to the increase of crystallinity and nanoparticle size in the catalyst, thus improving the stability of the catalyst, the as-prepared catalyst annealed at high temperature exhibited inferior stability at a constant-current density working state. This result is mainly attributed to the adverse impact of the annealing process at high temperatures on the catalytic activity, in terms of decreasing the active surface area due to the aggregation effect and decreasing the intrinsic activity due to the formation of a highly crystalline structure. The inferior catalytic activity caused by the adverse impact can induce a large working voltage, which can accelerate the catalyst degradation via a positive feedback mechanism (PFM) beneath the electrocatalytic system consisting of 'catalytic activity&#8211;electrocatalytic performance (working voltage)&#8211;aging'. Besides, the influences of Cl residue on the catalytic activity and stability of the as-prepared IrO2/TiO2 were also investigated by substituting a Cl-free precursor using IrCl3 (IrO2/TiO2&#8211;Cl). It presented slightly inferior initial oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalytic performance to that using a Cl-free precursor, perhaps due to the strong adsorption of Cl residue on IrO2 nanoparticles. However, the stability of the as-prepared IrO2/TiO2&#8211;Cl deteriorates significantly in chronopotentiometric measurement probably due to the PFM. Consequently, catalytic activity and stability are of equal significance; both the annealing temperature and Cl residue need to be fine-tuned to achieve an optimal combination of catalytic activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Zeping Zhang, Minghui Yao, Renxing Huang, Chengcheng Sang, Zongqiang Mao, Y. P. Wang, Yanan Yin, Cheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c05299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-THINGS: The Milky Way twin candidate NGC 3521</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202452605</link>
      <description>L. S. Pilyugin, M. A. Lara-L&#243;pez, G. Tautvai&#353;ien&#279;, I. A. Zinchenko, Luis E. Gardu&#241;o, M. E. De Rossi, J. Zaragoza-Cardiel, Sami Dib, Gilbert Vale, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406355031

                ii regions closest to the centre of the MW (at a radii of 4-5 kpc) are close to the binned oxygen abundances in NGC 3521 at the same galactocentric distances; an accurate value of the central oxygen abundance in the MW cannot be established because of the lack of the measurements near the centre. The oxygen abundances in the outer part of the MW are lower than those in the outer part of NGC 3521. The gas mass fraction in the outer part of the MW is higher than in NGC 3521. The obtained values of the effective oxygen yield, Y_eff, in NGC 3521 are close to the empirical estimation of the oxygen yield, Y_O. This suggests that mass exchange with the surroundings plays little to no role in the current chemical evolution of NGC3521. The values of the Y_eff in the MW were determined using two variants of the radial distribution of the gas mass surface density. The values of the Y_eff in the MW obtained with the first distribution are also close to Y_O, as in NGC 3521. The Y_eff in the MW obtained with the second distribution are below Y_O at radii between &#8764;6 and &#8764;10.4 kpc. This suggests that the mass exchange with the surroundings can play a significant role in the chemical evolution of this part of the MW, in contrast to that in NGC 3521. To draw a solid conclusion about the role of mass exchange with the surroundings in the chemical evolution of the MW it is essential to determine which of these distributions provides a more adequate description of the gas distribution in the MW.</description>
      <author>L. S. Pilyugin, M. A. Lara-L&#243;pez, G. Tautvai&#353;ien&#279;, I. A. Zinchenko, Luis E. Gardu&#241;o, M. E. De Rossi, J. Zaragoza-Cardiel, Sami Dib, Gilbert Vale</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202452605</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution Path of Nitrogen-Water Cluster Cation: A Theoretical Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3nnbx-v2</link>
      <description>Sihan Zhang, Z. Zhu, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406333469

                We applied a highly accurate Density Functional Theory (DFT) method to obtain thermodynamic data for various water-nitrogen clusters. In combination with ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations and wavefunction analysis, we proposed a theoretical pathway for the evolution of nitrogen-water cation clusters, offering insights into the formation of oxidative environments. Our calculations reveal that nitrogen molecules can form weak bonds with certain hydrogen-oxygen cations, stabilizing key intermediates during hydroxyl radical transfer. Such interaction alters the cluster&#8217;s evolution. Our findings show a clear map of how nitrogen-water cluster cations evolve and give oxidative reactants.</description>
      <author>Sihan Zhang, Z. Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3nnbx-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of the Hydrothermal Fluids Inferred from the Occurrence and Isotope Characteristics of the Carbonate Minerals at the Pogo Gold Deposit, Alaska, USA</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/min15010067</link>
      <description>Y. Morishita, Jamie R. Rogers, Minerals. 15(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406328344

                Pogo is identified as a deep-seated, intrusion-related gold deposit. Carbonate minerals have a close spatial relationship to hydrothermal gold mineralization in all of its principal ore zones. The carbon and oxygen isotopic ratios of carbonate minerals (siderite, ankerite, and calcite) present within the deposit illustrate the isotopic evolution of the ore-forming fluid. The initial hydrothermal fluid phase is interpreted to be magmatic in origin. The fluid evolution was characterized by a gradual decrease in &#948;18O and a slight increase in &#948;13C with decreasing temperature. The dominant carbon-bearing species was CO2, with methane introduced sporadically. Siderite is associated with early-stage mineralization and occurs with ankerite in main-stage ore assemblages. Calcite is recognized in the later stages of mineralization. Gold in the Pogo deposit occurs as native gold, Au-Bi-Te minerals, inclusions in sulfide minerals, or as &#8220;invisible gold&#8221;. The latter is found in pyrite, chalcopyrite, arsenopyrite, and quartz, based on ion microprobe analysis. The presence of invisible gold in these minerals has significant metallurgical implications for gold processing at the Pogo mine.</description>
      <author>Y. Morishita, Jamie R. Rogers</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/min15010067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of Time Series Analysis on Kinetic Monte Carlo Simulations of Hyperthermal Oxidation of Graphite</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07175</link>
      <description>Sharon Edward, Moon&#8208;ki Choi, Harley T. Johnson, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406245536

                The oxidation of carbon fiber ablators for thermal protection systems has been extensively studied for atmospheric reentry missions. We investigate this oxidation process at the atomic scale using atomistic kinetic Monte Carlo (A-KMC) simulations, focusing on the influence of two pathways of oxygen adsorption on carbon oxidation: adsorption of oxygen on the basal plane as epoxy groups and adsorption of oxygen directly on the edges of defects. We find that the majority of CO formation results from oxygen adsorbed on the basal plane, which subsequently diffuses toward defect edges. This is due to the greater availability of basal sites relative to defect edges throughout most of the simulation, and the rapid diffusion of epoxy groups toward defect edges at the studied temperatures (1700&#8211;2200 K). In this study, we exploit the temporal data from these A-KMC simulations to investigate the dynamics between the adsorption and CO formation reactions as they evolve with time. From KMC, we obtain time series that represent the time evolution of the frequency of occurrence of these reactions in the model. Pearson's correlation coefficient is used as a metric to identify correlated relationships between time series. By comparing adsorption and CO formation time series using this metric, we find that the contribution of each adsorption reaction toward CO formation varies with time due to the evolving oxidized graphite structure. Specifically, as the ratio of basal plane sites (nbasal) to defect edge sites (nedge) decreases during the simulation, the contribution of basal plane adsorption relative to direct edge adsorption toward CO formation also decreases. We also address several challenges associated with conducting time series analysis in KMC due to the stochastic nature of the method.</description>
      <author>Sharon Edward, Moon&#8208;ki Choi, Harley T. Johnson</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c07175</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Passivated Sulfur Vacancies in Monolayer MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for Enhanced Piezoelectricity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c13037</link>
      <description>Ajay Kumar Verma, Md. Ataur Rahman, Pargam Vashishtha, Xiangyang Guo, Manoj Sehrawat, Rahul Mitra, Sindhu Priya Giridhar, Moaz Waqar, Ankit Bhoriya, Billy J. Murdoch, Chenglong Xu, Ali Zavabeti, Wei Song, Yongxiang Li, Sanjay R. Dhakate, Bhasker Gahtori, Taimur Ahmed, Irfan Haider Abidi, Sumeet Walia, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406349189

                Modern-day applications demand onboard electricity generation that can be achieved using piezoelectric phenomena. Reducing the dimensionality of materials is a pathway to enhancing the piezoelectric properties. Transition-metal dichalcogenides have been shown to exhibit high piezoelectricity. Monolayer MoS2 possesses strong piezoelectricity that is otherwise negligible in its bulk form. The presence of sulfur vacancy defects in two-dimensional MoS2 can starkly reduce piezoelectric output due to enhanced charge screening. Oxygen passivation offers thermodynamically favorable and superior vacancy passivation. Here, we demonstrate an in situ oxygen passivation of sulfur vacancies achieved by performing chemical vapor deposition in atmospheric pressure conditions, resulting in a dramatically enhanced piezoelectric output. We achieved an out-of-plane effective piezoelectric coefficient d33eff 0.54 pm/V for the MoS2 monolayer with sulfur vacancies (SV-MoS2) and 0.94 pm/V where sulfur vacancies are passivated by oxygen (OP-MoS2). The piezoelectric device (PED) based on OP-MoS2 exhibits 26% higher output voltage than SV-MoS2 with the maximum peak-to-peak value of 0.95 V. Additionally, we show that the OP-MoS2-based PED can charge a 330 nF capacitor 30% faster than the SV-MoS2 PED for up to 50 mV in 0.5 s by repetitive finger tapping. The evolution of piezoelectricity in MoS2 with sulfur vacancy defect manipulation promises an avenue for scalable defect engineering for next-generation applications in miniaturized self-powered electronics and sensors across computing, healthcare, and size-, weight-, and power-constrained environments.</description>
      <author>Ajay Kumar Verma, Md. Ataur Rahman, Pargam Vashishtha, Xiangyang Guo, Manoj Sehrawat, Rahul Mitra, Sindhu Priya Giridhar, Moaz Waqar, Ankit Bhoriya, Billy J. Murdoch, Chenglong Xu, Ali Zavabeti, Wei Song, Yongxiang Li, Sanjay R. Dhakate, Bhasker Gahtori, Taimur Ahmed, Irfan Haider Abidi, Sumeet Walia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c13037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groundwater Recharge Evaluation Using Stable Isotopes and the NETPATH Model in Al-Madinah Al-Munawarah Province, Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/w17020211</link>
      <description>Milad Masoud, Maged El Osta, Nassir S. Al-Amri, Burhan Niyazi, Abdulaziz Alqarawy, Riyadh F. Halawani, Mohamed Rashed, Water. 17(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406362374

                In this study, hydrogeochemistry and environmentally stable isotopes were employed to examine the processes involved in recharging aquifer systems and the changes in the groundwater chemistry caused by the interaction between the water and the aquifer matrix. Based on data derived from 113 groundwater wells, various tools and techniques, including stable environmental isotopes Oxygen-18 and Deuterium (&#948;18O and &#948;D) for 33 samples and geochemical modeling with NETPATH, were used to evaluate the recharge mechanism and the evolution of the groundwater, combining GIS with hydrological and hydrochemical methods. The results revealed that groundwater from the Quaternary was the main source for irrigation; the water quality was categorized as relatively fresh to saline, with the total dissolved solids (TDSs) ranging from 261.3 to 8628.56 mg/L, exhibiting an average value of 2311.68 mg/L. The results of the environmental isotope analysis showed that the range of oxygen &#948;18O isotopes in the groundwater was from &#8722;5.65&#8240; to +0.39&#8240;, while the range of hydrogen &#948;D isotopes was from &#8722;32.60&#8240; to 4.73&#8240;. Moreover, the &#948;18O&#8211;&#948;D relationship indicated that the groundwater samples fell around the global meteoric precipitation line, showing a strong relationship, with a coefficient (R2) of approximately 0.82. The NETPATH model revealed that the dissolved chemical species within the groundwater system primarily originated from processes such as mineral weathering and dissolution, ion exchange, and evaporation.</description>
      <author>Milad Masoud, Maged El Osta, Nassir S. Al-Amri, Burhan Niyazi, Abdulaziz Alqarawy, Riyadh F. Halawani, Mohamed Rashed</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/w17020211</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post&#8208;Degradation Recovery of CsPbI&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Quantum Dot Solar Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409709</link>
      <description>Julius Brunner, Angelika Wrzesi&#324;ska&#8208;Lashkova, Lucas Scalon, Robson Ferrari Muniz, Anatol Prudnikau, Darius Pohl, Markus L&#246;ffler, Fabian Paulus, Yana Vaynzof, Small. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406226647

                Abstract The stability of perovskite quantum dot solar cells is one of the key challenges of this technology. This study reveals the unique degradation behavior of cesium lead triiodide (CsPbI 3 ) quantum dot solar cells. For the first time, it is shown that the oxygen&#8208;induced degradation and performance loss of CsPbI 3 quantum dot photovoltaic devices can be reversed by exposing the degraded samples to humidity, allowing the performance to recover and even surpass the initial performance. By careful characterization and analysis throughout the degradation and recovery process, the underlying physical and chemical mechanisms that govern the evolution of the device performance could be identified. It is shown that the ligand shell of the quantum dots, rather than the instability of the semiconducting material itself, is the driving factor in these mechanisms. This highlights the important role of surface chemistry and ligand design in enhancing perovskite quantum dot photovoltaics.</description>
      <author>Julius Brunner, Angelika Wrzesi&#324;ska&#8208;Lashkova, Lucas Scalon, Robson Ferrari Muniz, Anatol Prudnikau, Darius Pohl, Markus L&#246;ffler, Fabian Paulus, Yana Vaynzof</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409709</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polythiophene-Based Nonmetal Electrocatalyst with Biocompatibility to Boost Efficient CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/cbe.4c00156</link>
      <description>Xiaojun Bian, Ye Yang, Sulin Ni, Bin Yang, Yang Hou, Lecheng Lei, Min Yao, Zhongjian Li, Chem &amp; Bio Engineering. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406323927

                In a hybrid microbial&#8211;inorganic catalysis system, H2 evolution reaction (HER) electrocatalysts are coupled with microorganisms to achieve the highly efficient conversion of CO2 to value-added chemicals using H2 as an electron mediator. However, currently developed HER electrocatalysts suffer from poor biocompatibility, hindering the performance of the system. This study presents a N- and Si-doped polythiophene nanocomposite (PTh-NSi) as a nonmetal HER electrocatalyst with biocompatibility for use in a hybrid microbial&#8211;inorganic catalysis system. By coupling PTh-NSi with Ralstonia eutropha H16, conversion of CO2 to poly-&#946;-hydroxybutyrate with a maximum yield of 662.99 &#177; 27.46 mg/L was achieved. The PTh-NSi electrocatalyst demonstrated HER performance in bacterial media, minimal reactive oxygen species production, and no heavy metal ion leaching, ensuring biocompatibility with R. eutropha H16. The interactions between PTh-NSi and R. eutropha H16 were revealed. This work highlights an approach to designing biocompatible catalysts for hybrid microbial&#8211;inorganic catalysis systems, offering the potential for sustainable CO2 conversion.</description>
      <author>Xiaojun Bian, Ye Yang, Sulin Ni, Bin Yang, Yang Hou, Lecheng Lei, Min Yao, Zhongjian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/cbe.4c00156</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dressed Up to the Nines: The Interplay of Phytohormones Signaling and Redox Metabolism During Plant Response to Drought</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/plants14020208</link>
      <description>Douglas Jardim&#8208;Messeder, Ygor de Souza-Vieira, Gilberto Sachetto&#8208;Martins, Plants. 14(2)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406307964

                Plants must effectively respond to various environmental stimuli to achieve optimal growth. This is especially relevant in the context of climate change, where drought emerges as a major factor globally impacting crops and limiting overall yield potential. Throughout evolution, plants have developed adaptative strategies for environmental stimuli, with plant hormones and reactive oxygen species (ROS) playing essential roles in their development. Hormonal signaling and the maintenance of ROS homeostasis are interconnected, playing indispensable roles in growth, development, and stress responses and orchestrating diverse molecular responses during environmental adversities. Nine principal classes of phytohormones have been categorized: auxins, brassinosteroids, cytokinins, and gibberellins primarily oversee developmental growth regulation, while abscisic acid, ethylene, jasmonic acid, salicylic acid, and strigolactones are the main orchestrators of environmental stress responses. Coordination between phytohormones and transcriptional regulation is crucial for effective plant responses, especially in drought stress. Understanding the interplay of ROS and phytohormones is pivotal for elucidating the molecular mechanisms involved in plant stress responses. This review provides an overview of the intricate relationship between ROS, redox metabolism, and the nine different phytohormones signaling in plants, shedding light on potential strategies for enhancing drought tolerance for sustainable crop production.</description>
      <author>Douglas Jardim&#8208;Messeder, Ygor de Souza-Vieira, Gilberto Sachetto&#8208;Martins</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/plants14020208</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guidelines for Accurate and Precise Stable Isotope Analysis of Calcite, Dolomite, and Magnesite Using a Carbonate Device for Continuous Flow&#8208;Isotope Ratio Mass Spectrometry (CF&#8208;IRMS)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/rcm.9958</link>
      <description>Soujung Kim, Sang&#8208;Tae Kim, Martin Knyf, Rapid Communications in Mass Spectrometry. 39(5)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406216816

                ABSTRACT Rationale Carbonate minerals are one of the most popular samples for an automated sample preparation system for CF&#8208;IRMS, such as GasBench II and iso FLOW, but no standardized analytical protocols exist. This study gives guidelines on optimal analytic conditions for carbon and oxygen isotope analysis of Ca&#8211;Mg carbonates when using the carbonate&#8211;phosphoric acid reaction method. Methods Calcite (CaCO 3 &#8211;McMaster Carrara), dolomite (CaMg(CO 3 ) 2 &#8211;MRSI Dolomite), and magnesite (MgCO 3 &#8211;ROM Brazil Magnesite) with two grain size fractions (&lt; 74 and 149&#8211;250 &#956;m) were reacted with 103% (specific gravity of 1.92) phosphoric acid under He atmosphere in 12&#8208;mL borosilicate glass vials to examine the full &#948; 13 C and &#948; 18 O evolution of acid&#8208;liberated CO 2 for an extended reaction time of up to 12&#8211;30 days at 25&#176;C and up to 3&#8211;7 days at 72&#176;C. Results At 25&#176;C, the optimal reaction time of calcite is 1 day for both grain size fractions while the optimal reaction time of 2&#8211;10 day is suggested for dolomite with a grain size of &lt; 74 &#956;m. At 72&#176;C, 30&#8208;min to 12&#8208;h or 45&#8208;min to 12&#8208;h reaction is optimal for calcite with &lt; 74&#8208;&#956;m or 149&#8208; to 250&#8208;&#956;m grain size fraction, respectively, whereas dolomite requires 12&#8208;h to 1&#8208;day reaction for both grain size fractions. The only optimal condition for magnesite is 6&#8211;7 days of reaction with &lt; 74&#8208;&#956;m grain size at 72&#176;C. Conclusions To determine precise and accurate &#948; 13 C and &#948; 18 O values of a carbonate mineral using the carbonate&#8211;phosphoric acid reaction method, an optimal reaction time must be assessed for a given analytical condition to avoid nonequilibrium isotope effects and unnecessary oxygen isotope exchange of acid&#8208;liberated CO 2 in the carbonate reaction vessel. Our experimental result provides a guideline for the accurate and precise stable isotope analysis of Ca&#8211;Mg carbonate minerals.</description>
      <author>Soujung Kim, Sang&#8208;Tae Kim, Martin Knyf</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/rcm.9958</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The systemic evolutionary theory of the origin of cancer (SETOC): an update</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-025-01069-w</link>
      <description>Antonio Mazzocca, Giovanni Ferraro, Giovanni Misciagna, Molecular Medicine. 31(1)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406346950

                Abstract The Systemic Evolutionary Theory of the Origin of Cancer (SETOC) is a recently proposed theory founded on two primary principles: the cooperative and endosymbiotic process of cell evolution as described by Lynn Margulis, and the integration of complex systems operating in eukaryotic cells, which is a core concept in systems biology. The SETOC proposes that malignant transformation occurs when cells undergo a continuous adaptation process in response to long-term injuries, leading to tissue remodeling, chronic inflammation, fibrosis, and ultimately cancer. This process involves a maladaptive response, wherein the 'endosymbiotic contract&#8217; between the nuclear-cytoplasmic system (derived from the primordial archaeal cell) and the mitochondrial system (derived from the primordial &#945;-proteobacterium) gradually breaks down. This ultimately leads to uncoordinated behaviors and functions in transformed cells. The decoupling of the two cellular subsystems causes transformed cells to acquire phenotypic characteristics analogous to those of unicellular organisms, as well as certain biological features of embryonic development that are normally suppressed. These adaptive changes enable cancer cells to survive in the harsh tumor microenvironment characterized by low oxygen concentrations, inadequate nutrients, increased catabolic waste, and increased acidity. De-endosymbiosis reprograms the sequential metabolic functions of glycolysis, the TCA cycle, and oxidative phosphorylation (OxPhos). This leads to increased lactate fermentation (Warburg effect), respiratory chain dysfunction, and TCA cycle reversal. Here, we present an updated version of the SETOC that incorporates the fundamental principles outlined by this theory and integrates the epistemological approach used to develop it.</description>
      <author>Antonio Mazzocca, Giovanni Ferraro, Giovanni Misciagna</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-025-01069-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Utilization of Wearable Devices as means for Remote Digital Biometric Data Collection in a community&#8208;based, rural randomized controlled trial among Alzheimer&#8217;s disease dyads</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.090883</link>
      <description>Elizabeth K. Rhodus, Md. Saif Hassan Onim, Celeste Roberts, Sanjeev Kumar, Amer M. Burhan, Himanshu Thapliyal, Alzheimer s &amp; Dementia. 20(S2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4406210955

                Abstract Background Use of remote measurement of physiological parameters using digital biometrics (i.e., Electro Dermal Activities, heart rate, oxygen saturation, blood volume pulse, etc.) has a multitude of opportunities in rural contexts that have not yet fully been explored in Alzheimer&#8217;s disease (AD) clinical research. This study assessed feasibility and acceptability of advanced digital biometric data collection among rural, community&#8208;dwelling adults living with Alzheimer&#8217;s disease with support from primary caregivers (dyad). Methods Initial feasibility and acceptability of a wrist&#8208;worn wearable device (Empatica E4) as means for digital biometric data collection were assessed among participants of a larger randomized controlled trial which was aimed to assess a non&#8208;pharmacological care intervention improving behavioral symptoms of AD. Following consent, dyads were mailed an E4 device and behavior tracking journal to companion digital recordings for one week of data collection. Caregivers assisted the person with AD in wear and care of the E4 device and completed time&#8208;stamped behavior tracking. Feasibility was assessed based on completeness of digital biometric data recordings and acceptability was determined based on wear schedules for the device in participants with AD (worn &gt;50% of allotted time). Results Digital biometric data collection via remote, wearable devices is feasible and acceptable among participants with AD in rural settings among 16 dyads (person with AD age x&#772;=77&#177;2.4 years, 10 female; caregiver age years x&#772;=57&#177;2.9 years, 8 female). The E4 correctly captured biometric signals (Electro Dermal Activities, blood volume pulse, Skin Temperature, etc.). The device was acceptable as 14 of the 16 participants with AD wore the device &gt;50% of allotted time with proper completion of the caregiver&#8208;reported behavior tracking. Further, we observed that unsupervised machine learning models were able to create digital biometrics that mirrored caregivers&#8217; notes. Conclusion Advances in technology, evolution of health status surveillance, and vast needs in rural areas create an ideal scenario to advance research in digital biometrics. With goals to use digital biometrics as primary outcome measures in AD clinical trials, the findings presented here illustrate feasibility and acceptability among geographically remote communities. Additional research is needed to assess context&#8208;aware machine learning applicability in intervention&#8208;based clinical research.</description>
      <author>Elizabeth K. Rhodus, Md. Saif Hassan Onim, Celeste Roberts, Sanjeev Kumar, Amer M. Burhan, Himanshu Thapliyal</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/alz.090883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Editorial: Micro and nanoparticles for regenerative medicine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fbioe.2024.1548963</link>
      <description>Aurore Van de Walle, Yang Zhang, Alessandro Polini, Riccardo Di Corato, Frontiers in Bioengineering and Biotechnology. 12(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406346650

                The synthesis of micro-and nano-particles must be precisely controlled to achieve the desired shape and composition, as these characteristics profoundly influence their applicative efficacy. A large body of literature aims at constantly improving structure/function of these materials by refining synthesis procedures. Within it, a growing field of chemistry focuses on green synthesis methods to provide more sustainable alternatives while maintaining the bioactive efficiency of the particles. For instance, this Research Topic features a study on magnesium oxide (MgO) nanoparticles synthesized using Azadirachta indica (neem) extract (Al-Harbi et al., 2024). The produced MgO nanoparticles exhibit remarkable stability under heat and in biological media, alongside notable antioxidant, anti-inflammatory, and antibacterial properties. Aligned with this search for greener processes and materials, another featured study reviews the development of silk fibroin-based scaffolds for tissue engineering (Ma et al., 2024). Silk, biosynthesized by over 200,000 arthropod species -including the Bombyx mori moth, whose silk is the most characterized -offers a rich source of fibroin, a natural biopolymer. Silk fibroin stands out for its mechanical strength, biocompatibility, biodegradability, and structural tunability. It can be used alone or combined with other materials to enhance cell adhesion, proliferation, and differentiation.A focus in regenerative medicine consists in creating tissue alternatives to repair aging or diseased tissues and organs. It generally relies on the use of a scaffold for cell support. These scaffolds must meet precise guidelines to provide appropriate biomechanical and biochemical cues to facilitate cell adhesion and regulate phenotypic expression. Their conception thus requires control over shape, mechanical properties, and surface characteristics. The previously mentioned review on silk fibroin details the numerous possible processing techniques of this biomaterial (i.e. electrospinning, freeze-drying, solvent casting, gas foaming, particulate leaching, 3D printing) making it versatile and relevant for the repair of various tissues, including skin, bone, cartilage, blood vessel, and nerves (Ma et al., 2024). Nano-and micro-structuration of scaffolds is another approach to enhance scaffold features as explored in this research topic in a study that showcases the incorporation of graphene oxide to the pure hardystonite (used for bone repair) leading to the obtention of a porous nano-and microstructured hardystonite/reduced graphene oxide composite (Bagherpour et al., 2023). The produced biomaterial demonstrates enhanced osteogenic differentiation and mechanical strength. An additional study focuses on the nanoscale properties of biphasic calcium phosphate (BCP), also employed in bone repair (Su et al., 2023). Granular-shaped BCP nanoparticles were synthesized, and the nanoscale texturing of these materials enhanced biocompatibility and osteogenic features. Importantly, they demonstrated immunomodulatory effects by reducing the expression of proinflammatory cytokines in macrophages, even under lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced inflammatory conditions. The ability of BCP nanoparticles to restore osteogenesis impaired by inflammation underscores their dual role in promoting bone regeneration and modulating the immune response.Nanometer-scaled materials can provide stronger antibacterial features. The silver-copper bimetallic nanoparticles featured in this issue exemplify this strategy (Hao et al., 2024). Silver and copper nanoparticles have superior antibacterial effects compared to their bulk or micron-size counterparts. Furthermore, combining these nanomaterials rather than using them individually amplifies their antibacterial efficacy while minimizing cytotoxicity. These nanoparticles have dynamic interactions in biological environments through metal ions release and reactive oxygen species (ROS) generation, which collectively boost localized antibacterial activity, minimizing systemic side effects (Hao et al., 2024).Bioinspired MgO NPs also exhibited targeted effects. They show selective cytotoxicity against liver hepatic cancer cells in comparison to human umbilical vein endothelial ones, encouraging their potential in anticancer therapies (Al-Harbi et al., 2024). Additionally, they demonstrate significant antidiabetic activity through the inhibition of key enzymes like &#945;glucosidase and &#945;-amylase, along with robust anti-inflammatory effects via protein stabilization and cytokine regulation. Antioxidant activity is another critical aspect of bioactive particles. By scavenging free radicals, MgO NPs protect tissues from oxidative stress, a major contributor to inflammation and chronic diseases.Similarly, BCP nanomaterials have shown remarkable bioactivity. They mitigate inflammation in macrophages and enhance osteogenic processes by increasing alkaline phosphatase activity and upregulating osteogenesis-related genes, such as Runx2 and OPN (Su et al., 2023). Notably, BCP nanoparticles can reverse the detrimental effects of lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced inflammatory conditions on osteoblast activity. This dual functionality makes BCP nanoparticles promising candidates for applications in environments where inflammation impedes bone regeneration.The integration of micro-and nano-particles into regenerative medicine can not only support tissue regeneration but also actively engage in therapeutic processes. While these versatile biomaterials hold large promises, challenges still remain for their widespread adoption in the clinic. Among them, the assessment of long-term biocompatibility requires monitoring biomaterial evolution over years. It is a complex task, yet necessary, as these materials are designed to interact with biological systems over extended periods. Another challenge concerns their integration with advanced manufacturing, such as 3D printing, as well as the scalability and reproducibility of their manufacturing. This is necessary to ensure consistent production of high-quality particles for large-scale applications. In parallel to these technical hurdles come regulatory and translational barriers. However, as this field progresses and with sustained efforts to overcome these obstacles, we are optimistic that micro-and nanoparticles can pave the way for more effective medical solutions.</description>
      <author>Aurore Van de Walle, Yang Zhang, Alessandro Polini, Riccardo Di Corato</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fbioe.2024.1548963</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Targeting ferroptosis resistance resensitizes metastatic HR&lt;sup&gt;+&lt;/sup&gt;HER2&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;&lt;/sup&gt; breast cancer cells to palbociclib&#8208;hormone therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cac2.12646</link>
      <description>Charles Pottier, Laetitia Montero&#8208;Ruiz, Robin Jehay, Coline W&#233;ry, Dominique Baiwir, Gabriel Mazzucchelli, Sophie Bekisz, Romain Thissen, Claire Josse, Andr&#233;e Rorive, St&#233;phanie Gofflot, Ahmed Dahmani, Ludivine Morisset, Jo&#235;lle Collignon, Philippe Delvenne, Elisabetta Marangoni, Agn&#232;s No&#235;l, Guy J&#233;rusalem, Nor Eddine Sounni, Cancer Communications. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4406336154

                Metastatic hormone receptor-positive (HR+), human epidermal growth factor receptor 2-negative (HER2&#8722;) breast cancer often develops resistance to first-line treatment, typically combining cyclin-dependent kinase 4 and 6 inhibitors (CDK4/6i) with hormone therapy (HT) [1, 2]. After an initial response, most patients become resistant, and compensatory mechanisms are not fully uncovered [3]. To address this, we analyzed HR+ resistant CAMA1 and 747D cells using whole-exome and RNA sequencing, supplemented by proteomics and target validation with human samples. Additionally, we conducted combination therapy trials using xenografts and patient-derived xenografts (PDXs). Detailed study designs and methods are provided in the Supplementary file. In a cohort of 27 patients with metastatic breast cancer, we observed reduced progression-free survival in second- and third-line therapies following progression post palbociclib-HT treatment (Supplementary Figure S1A and Supplementary Table S1). Resistant tumors showed reduced estrogen receptor alpha (ER&#945;) and progesterone receptor (PR) and increased proliferation rates (Supplementary Figure S1B-D). CAMA1 and T47D cells, treated with palbociclib and fulvestrant (PF) for 2 years, developed resistance (CAMA1-PFR and T47D-PFR) confirmed by proliferation assays and elevated half-maximal inhibitory concentrations. Resistant cells exhibited reduced levels of ER&#945; and retinoblastoma protein (Supplementary Figure S2). Exome analysis revealed no drug resistance-related mutations (Supplementary Tables S2-S3), suggesting non-genetic factors. RNA sequencing of T47D cells treated with DMSO or PF for 20 days and T47D-PFR cells revealed 1,172 upregulated genes and 824 downregulated genes in the resistant cells (Supplementary Figure S3A). Gene set enrichment analysis indicated increased fatty acid localization (Supplementary Figure S3B), with a heatmap showing elevated fatty acid uptake and metabolism-related genes, such as fatty acid binding protein-6 (FABP6), FABP7, cluster of differentiation-36 (CD36), and proteasome proliferator-activated receptor-gamma (PPAR&#947;) in T47D-PFR cells (Figure 1A). Lipid droplets accumulated in PF-treated parental and PF-resistant T47D and CAMA1 cells (Figure 1B and Supplementary Figure S3C). FABP6 levels were elevated in PF-treated parental and PF-resistant cells, with CD36 overexpression unique to T47D-PFR cells at both protein and mRNA levels (Figure 1C and Supplementary Figure S3D-E), suggesting that lipid uptake might be an adaptive response to oxidative stress [4, 5]. This was supported by elevated reactive oxygen species (ROS) levels in PF-treated parental cells (Figure 1D). Furthermore, proteomic analysis in human biopsies revealed a functional network of 11 oxidative stress-triggered proteasomes (Supplementary Figure S4A and Supplementary Tables S4-S5) as indicators of oxidative stress [6]. Immunohistochemistry validated increased proteasome subunit alpha type-7 (PSMA7) in resistant biopsies (Supplementary Figure S4B). Ferroptosis inducers overcome resistance of HR+HER2&#8722; breast cancer cells to palbociclib-hormone therapy. (A) Heatmap of upregulated genes (red) or downregulated genes (blue) during the treatment of T47D cells with PF combination for 20 days, and in PF-resistant cells (T47D-PFR) after continuous PF treatment for 2 years, compared to parental T47D cells treated with vehicle (DMSO). All represented genes had a P value &lt; 0.05. (B) Lipid droplet detection by BODIPY 493/503 staining in parental CAMA1 and T47D cells after treatment with the PF combination for 20 days, and in CAMA1-PFR and T47D-PFR cells after continuous PF treatment for 2 years. DAPI staining was used to visualize the nuclei. (C) Western blot analysis of FABP6 and CD36 in parental CAMA1 and T47D cells after treatment with the PF combination for 20 days, and in CAMA1-PFR and T47D-PFR cells after continuous PF treatment for 2 years. (D) Measurement of ROS levels by DCFDA ROS assay in parental CAMA1 and T47D cells and in CAMA1-PFR and T47D-PFR cells treated for 5 days with DMSO or PF. Continuous PF treatment for resistant cells was discontinued 3 days prior to the assay. (E) Western blot analysis of GPX4 in parental CAMA1, T47D and ZR75.1 cells after treatment with PF combination for 20 days and in CAMA1-PFR, T47D-PFR and ZR75.1-PFR cells after continuous PF treatment for 2 years. (F) Immunohistochemistry analysis (images) and quantification (bar chart) of GPX4-positive cells in biopsies of patients taken before treatment with palbociclib-HT or after resistance (*P &lt; 0.05). (G) Assessment of cell proliferation according to the fold change in confluence in parental and PF-resistant CAMA1 and T47D cells treated with DMSO, the ferroptosis inducer RSL3 (1 &#181;mol/L), the ferroptosis inhibitor Trolox (10 &#181;mol/L), or a combination of both for 7 days. Continuous PF treatment for resistant cells was discontinued 3 days prior to the assay. (H) Assessment of cell proliferation according to the fold change in confluence in parental and PF-resistant CAMA1 and T47D cells treated with different combinations of DMSO, palbociclib (P) (0.3 &#181;mol/L), fulvestrant (F) (30 nmol/L), or eprenetapopt (Ep) (25 &#181;mol/L) for 7 days. Continuous PF treatment for resistant cells was discontinued 3 days prior to the assay. (I, J) Tumor growth curves of parental CAMA1 (6 mice per group) (I) and CAMA1-PFR (8 mice per group) (J) xenografts treated with different combinations of palbociclib (P) 75 mg/kg daily, fulvestrant (F) 50 mg/kg once a week, and eprenetapopt (Ep) 150 mg/kg, 2 times/day or RSL3 100 mg/kg by intratumoral injection every two days for two weeks (***P &lt; 0.001). (K) Growth curves of palbociclib-HT-na&#239;ve HBCx-124 PDXs (5 mice per group) treated with different combinations of palbociclib (P) 75 mg/kg daily, fulvestrant (F) 50 mg/kg once a week, and eprenetapopt (Ep) 150 mg/kg, 2 times/day (***P &lt; 0.001). (L) Growth curves of palbociclib-HT-resistant HBCx-180 PDXs (8 mice per group) treated with different combinations of palbociclib (P) 75 mg/kg daily, fulvestrant (F) 50 mg/kg once a week, and eprenetapopt (Ep) 150 mg/kg, 2 times/day. The difference between the measured tumor volumes was significant between the "vehicle" group and the eprenetapopt + fulvestrant + palbociclib (FPE) group from Day 25 until the end of the experiment (P &lt; 0.05). Tumor evolution formula is (Vf &#8722; V0 / V0) &#215; 100%, where V0 is the initial volume and Vf is the final volume measured at each time point. Abbreviations: CD36, cluster of differentiation 36; DAPI, 4&#8242;,6-diamidino-2-phenylindole; DCFDA, 2&#8242;,7&#8242;-Dichlorofluorescin Diacetate; DMSO, dimethyl sulfoxide; Ep, eprenetapopt; FABP6, fatty acid binding protein 6; GPX4, Glutathione peroxidase 4; HR+HER2&#8722;, hormone receptor positive and human epidermal growth factor receptor-2 negative; HT, hormone therapy; PDX, patient-derived xenograft; PF, palbociclib-fulvestrant; PF RSL3, palbociclib-fulvestrant-RSL3; PFE, palbociclib-fulvestrant-eprenetapopt; ROS, reactive oxygen species, RSL3, ras-selective lethal small molecule 3; Trolox, 6-hydroxy-2,5,7,8-tetramethylchroman-2-carboxylic acid. We investigated whether cell survival is affected by ferroptosis&#8212;a type of non-apoptotic cell death linked to lipid peroxidation. GPX4 protein, the main protector against ferroptosis, was overexpressed in parental cells after PF treatment and in PF-resistant cells, even after drug wash-out, with no changes in mRNA levels (Figure 1E and Supplementary Figure S5A-C). Silencing GPX4 expression reduced cell proliferation in parental and PF-resistant cells (Supplementary Figure S5D-F), indicating their reliance on GPX4. GPX4 overexpression was also observed in resistant human tumors (Figure 1F). Cells were treated with the GPX4 inhibitor RAS-selective lethal 3 (RSL3) and the antioxidant Trolox for 6 days. CAMA1 and T47D cells were insensitive to RSL3, whereas CAMA1-PFR and T47D-PFR cells showed high sensitivity to RSL3 (Figure 1G). Trolox reversed RSL3's effect in both cell lines (Figure 1G), highlighting the role of GPX4 in PF-resistant cell proliferation. Due to unverified safety of RLS3, we used eprenetapopt (Ep), a p53 activator and GSH depletory [7] proven safe in hematological cancer patients [8]. In vitro, CAMA1 and CAMA1-PFR cells were sensitive to Ep, while T47D cells were insensitive; T47D-PFR showed higher sensitivity (Figure 1H). To investigate the effect of pharmacologically induced ferroptosis on the palbociclib-fulvestrant response in vivo, we used nude mice implanted with estrogen pellets. Due to its low pharmacokinetics in mouse plasma [9], RSL3 was administered via intratumoral injection. Mice were treated with vehicle, PF, Ep, RSL3, a combination of palbociclib-fulvestrant and eprenetapopt (PFEp), or a combination of palbociclib-fulvestrant and RSL3 (PF-RSL3). PF effectively inhibited the growth of the CAMA1 xenografts, while CAMA1-PFR tumors were insensitive (Figure 1I and J). RSL3 alone did not affect CAMA1-PFR tumor growth, whereas PF-RSL3 demonstrated a strong antitumor effect (Figure 1J), suggesting that RSL3 sensitizes CAMA1-PFR cells to PF, or vice versa. Similarly, Ep alone did not inhibit CAMA1-PFR tumor growth, but its combination with PF completely abolished tumor growth (Figure 1J). To evaluate treatment effects on proliferation and cell death, we assessed Ki67, caspase-3 and hydroxynonenal (HNE) in tumors by immunohistochemistry. Parental CAMA1 tumors treated with PF showed a significant decrease in Ki67, with no effect on caspase-3, while CAMA1-PFR tumors exhibited no significant changes in either marker after treatment with PF, PFEp, or PF-RSL3 (Supplementary Figure S6A-D). HNE labeling revealed no difference between PF- and vehicle-treated CAMA1 tumors (Supplementary Figure S6E), but HNE increased moderately in CAMA1-PFR tumors treated with RSL3 and significantly with PFEp or PF-RSL3 (Supplementary Figure S6F), indicating potential cell death by ferroptosis. No treatments affected CD36 expression in either tumor type, although CAMA1-PFR xenografts showed significantly increased basal expression compared to human biopsies (Supplementary Figure S6G-J). To strengthen the translational impact of our findings, we used patient-derived xenografts (PDXs) from HR+HER2&#8722; breast cancer patients without p53 mutations (Supplementary Figure S7A) [10]. Consistent with human samples, GPX4 protein was upregulated in the palbociclib-HT-resistant PDX model (HBCx-180) compared to the palbociclib-HT-na&#239;ve PDX model (HBCx-124) (Supplementary Figure S7B). While GPX4 mRNA levels were unaffected in resistant cells, its expression was significantly higher in HBCx-180 (Supplementary Figure S7C), suggesting specific transcriptional/translational regulation differing between in vitro and in vivo contexts. In the HBCx-124 model, all the tumors (n = 5) responded well to PF, with no added benefit from Ep (PFEp), although a partial response to Ep monotherapy was observed (Figure 1K). Conversely, the HBCx-180 model showed no significant response to PF or Ep, with significant differences in tumor volumes between PFEp and vehicle and Ep groups from Day 25 onward (P &lt; 0.05) (Figure 1L). These results confirm that adding Ep to PF in PF-resistant tumors produces a strong antitumor effect. Ki67 labeling decreased with PF in the HBCx-124 PDX but not in the HBCx-180 PDX (Supplementary Figure S8A-B). Aside from reduction in caspase-3 labeling in the HBCx-124 treated with PF, no significant changes were observed with Ep or PFEp, and none of the treatment conditions affected HBCx-180 (Supplementary Figure S8C-D), indicating that proliferation and apoptosis are not affected in HBCx-180. HNE labeling suggested that PF promoted ferroptosis in HBCx-124, while only tumors treated with PFEp in HBCx-180 exhibited significant HNE increase compared to vehicle (Supplementary Figure S8E-F). PF slightly increased HNE in HBCx-124 without significance but the only vulnerability of HBCx-180 is attributed to ferroptosis induced with PFEp. The p53-dependent antitumor effect of eprenetapopt was excluded, as p53 expression was similar in parental and PF-resistant cells and in PDXs, while slightly elevated in resistant human tumors (Supplementary Figure S9). Finally, the addition of Ep or RSL3 to PF did not induce significant renal, hepatic, or hematological toxicity in mice (Supplementary Figure S10). In conclusion, HR+HER2&#8722; tumors resistant to palbociclib-HT are vulnerable to ferroptosis inducers, highlighting the potential of collateral drug sensitivity and the promise of developing pro-ferroptosis agents for treating drug-resistant metastatic breast cancer (Supplementary Figure S11). Conception and design: CP and NES. Development of methodology: CP, LMR, NES. Acquisition of data: CP, LMR, RT, CW, RJ, AR, JC, CJ, SG, SB, AD, PD, LM and EM. Analysis and interpretation of data (e.g., statistical analysis, biostatistics): CP, LMR, DB, GM, RT, CJ and NES. Writing, review, and/or revision of the manuscript: CP, GJ, AN and NES. Study supervision: GJ and NES. The authors thank the Cell Imaging Core Facility of the GIGA institute for Incucyte and fluorescence microscopy experiments; Isabelle Dasoul, Emilie Feyereisen, Erika Konradowski and Nathalie Lefin for their technical support; Maud Piron for enrolling the cohort of patients; and H&#233;l&#232;ne Schroeder for correcting the file sent to the human ethics committee and the Biobank of Li&#232;ge University for providing human samples. The authors also thank Latifa Karim and Manon Deckers from the GIGA Sequencing Platform (ULi&#232;ge, Belgium) for their help and advice; Erik Maquoi for image acquisition with Nanolive and Louis Baudin (Animascience, Li&#232;ge, Belgium) for the graphical abstract. The authors declare no competing interest except for Dr. Guy Jerusalem, who declares receiving grant support, paid to his institution, advisory board fees, lecture fees, travel support, and writing assistance from Novartis, Roche, and Pfizer. Disclosure is provided with the full text of this article. No other potential conflicts of interest relevant to this article were reported. This work was supported by grants from the National Fund for Scientific Research (NFSR-FNRS) Belgium (NES: PDR T.023020; CDR J.0178.22); the credit sectorial of the University of Liege (NES: FSR-S-SS-22/61; FSR-S-SS-22/64); and the Foundation Contre le Cancer, Belgium (NES and AN: FCC-2022-181). RNA sequencing data were deposited in the GEO-NCBI depository with the accession number: GSE270021 Exome sequencing data were registered in the BioProject database with the identification number: PRJNA1027140 Proteomic data were deposited in PRIDE with accession number: PXD053296. The data that support the findings of this study are available from the corresponding author upon reasonable request. A protocol was approved by the institutional Ethics Committee of the University Hospital of Liege (Liege, Belgium; file#2018/312) for the use of human samples in this study, and the ethical guidelines of the Declaration of Helsinki were followed. The ethical committee has authorized on May 15, 2019, to retrospectively use biopsies stored in the biobank of the University of Li&#232;ge and anonymized clinical data associated with these biopsies. The committee noted that this non-interventional use has no impact on patients and is not within the scope of the law of May 7, 2004, on experiments on human beings and thus did not require informed consents. For the animal study, all procedures were performed according to the Federation of European Laboratory Animal Sciences Associations (FELASA) within the accredited GIGA animal facility (University of Liege, Liege, Belgium) (project authorization no. 2078). PDX experiments were performed at the Institute of Curie, in accordance with institutional guidelines and the rules of the French Ethics Committee (project authorization no. 02163.02). Please note: The publisher is not responsible for the content or functionality of any supporting information supplied by the authors. Any queries (other than missing content) should be directed to the corresponding author for the article.</description>
      <author>Charles Pottier, Laetitia Montero&#8208;Ruiz, Robin Jehay, Coline W&#233;ry, Dominique Baiwir, Gabriel Mazzucchelli, Sophie Bekisz, Romain Thissen, Claire Josse, Andr&#233;e Rorive, St&#233;phanie Gofflot, Ahmed Dahmani, Ludivine Morisset, Jo&#235;lle Collignon, Philippe Delvenne, Elisabetta Marangoni, Agn&#232;s No&#235;l, Guy J&#233;rusalem, Nor Eddine Sounni</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cac2.12646</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
