<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 23:35:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancies modulated bifunctional S-NiMoO4 electrocatalyst for efficient alkaline overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc05444f</link>
      <description>Jiarong Mu, Peng Bai, Peng Wang, Zhi Xie, Yihua Zhao, Jianfang Jing, Yiguo Su, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390535943

                S-doped nickel molybdate nanorods grown on nickel foam (S-NiMoO4/NF) was fabricated by two-step hydrothermal method. The resultant S-NiMoO4/NF exhibited remarkable bifunctional electrocatalytic activity, with overpotentials of 235 mV for hydrogen...</description>
      <author>Jiarong Mu, Peng Bai, Peng Wang, Zhi Xie, Yihua Zhao, Jianfang Jing, Yiguo Su</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc05444f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A highly efficient MoO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;/Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; photoanode with rich vacancies for photoelectrochemical O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; evolution from water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nj04536f</link>
      <description>Yiyao Zhu, Lijing Zhang, Rui Ding, Qiuyan Fu, Lei Bi, Xuyan Zhou, Wenning Yan, Weixing Xia, Zuojie Luo, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390537696

                Highly efficient MoO x /Fe 2 O 3 photoanodes are constructed with rich vacancies for photoelectrochemical O 2 evolution from water splitting. The photocurrent density of MoO x /Fe 2 O 3 -3 reaches 3.3 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V vs. RHE.</description>
      <author>Yiyao Zhu, Lijing Zhang, Rui Ding, Qiuyan Fu, Lei Bi, Xuyan Zhou, Wenning Yan, Weixing Xia, Zuojie Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nj04536f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of NiFe-layered double hydroxides using triethanolamine-complexed precursors as oxygen evolution reaction catalysts: effects of Fe valence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt03373b</link>
      <description>Guoqiang Luo, Haoran Feng, Ruizhi Zhang, Y Zheng, Rong Tu, Qiang Shen, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390538157

                The OER performance of NiFe-LDH-based electrocatalysts prepared using triethanolamine-complexed precursors exhibits significant dependence on the iron valence state in iron sources.</description>
      <author>Guoqiang Luo, Haoran Feng, Ruizhi Zhang, Y Zheng, Rong Tu, Qiang Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3dt03373b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Electronic Redistribution via Anionic Modulator for Superb and Highly Stable Water/Seawater Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07364</link>
      <description>Jiawen Cui, Junzhi Li, Xu Zhao, Guichen Gao, Ming Ya, Haitong Tang, Mingrui Wang, Dongdong Li, Guangshe Li, Guangshe Li, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390543671

                Rational construction of efficient and stable transition-metal (TM)-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is extraordinarily favored and crucial to water/seawater splitting. Interface and heteroatom engineering are powerful strategies for improving the performance of the OER. Herein, we report a unique hydroxide/oxide heterostructure catalyst with P doping (Ni(OH)2/NiFe2O4&#8211;P) by an in situ growth strategy, following low-temperature phosphorylation for boosting water oxidation. The Ni(OH)2/NiFe2O4&#8211;P electrode, featuring an abundance of nanosheets, provides a greater number of functional active boundaries and enhances contact with the electrolyte for accelerated charge transfer. The incorporation of a P anionic modulator induces electron redistribution at heterogeneous interfaces, thereby tailoring the strong metal&#8211;anion interactions. Detailed electrochemical analysis further demonstrates that the Ni(OH)2/NiFe2O4&#8211;P heterostructure is an outstanding OER electrocatalyst, presenting low overpotentials of 224, 253, and 274 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 in alkaline solution, alkaline simulated seawater, and alkaline natural seawater, respectively. The cell voltage of the assembled two-electrode electrolyzer (Pt/C &#8741; Ni(OH)2/NiFe2O4&#8211;P) to deliver 10 mA cm&#8211;2 is only 1.62 V and can operate reliably for 150 h in an alkaline electrolyte.</description>
      <author>Jiawen Cui, Junzhi Li, Xu Zhao, Guichen Gao, Ming Ya, Haitong Tang, Mingrui Wang, Dongdong Li, Guangshe Li, Guangshe Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.3c07364</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A motif for B/O-site modulation in LaFeO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; towards boosted oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr05259a</link>
      <description>Wenli Kang, Zhishan Li, Jinsong Wang, Shaopeng Wu, Yanqin Gai, Guanghao Wang, Zhouhang Li, Xing Zhu, Zhu Tong, Hua Wang, Kongzhai Li, Chundong Wang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390544116

                Here, a series of transition metal (Ni) doped iron-based perovskite oxides LaFe 1&#8722; x Ni x O 3&#8722; &#948; ( x = 0, 0.25, 0.5, 0.75, 1) were prepared, and then the perovskite oxide with the optimized nickel&#8211;iron ratio was doped with non-metallic elements (N).</description>
      <author>Wenli Kang, Zhishan Li, Jinsong Wang, Shaopeng Wu, Yanqin Gai, Guanghao Wang, Zhouhang Li, Xing Zhu, Zhu Tong, Hua Wang, Kongzhai Li, Chundong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3nr05259a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstructed RuMnOx with enhanced performance in acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.159251</link>
      <description>Lu An, Xiyang Cai, Fan Yang, Jia-Bin You, Shu Yuan, Lutian Zhao, Congfan Zhao, Junliang Zhang, Xiaohui Yan, Shuiyun Shen, Junliang Zhang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390563080

                Transition metals-doped noble electrocatalysts are commonly applied for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Notwithstanding, most transition metal oxides are unstable under the conditions of acidic OER, questioning the real active sites on the surface of the electrocatalyst. Herein, RuMnOx is explored more than 30 % activity increased (at 1.7 V) after chronoamperometric activation measurement. The activities are improved when the chronoamperometric measurement potentials below 1.1 V. Coupling electrochemical measurements with Mn dissolution and Ru redeposition studies, we verify that the reconstruction of catalysts is responsible for the activated electrochemical activities. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the activity is enhanced by more hydroxyl adsorption on the surface, and the activated RuMnOx shows robust durability with a 0.027 mV/h potential increase rate for 2,600 h at current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Lu An, Xiyang Cai, Fan Yang, Jia-Bin You, Shu Yuan, Lutian Zhao, Congfan Zhao, Junliang Zhang, Xiaohui Yan, Shuiyun Shen, Junliang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2023.159251</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research and strategies for efficient electrocatalysts towards anodic oxygen evolution reaction in seawater electrolysis system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2023.11.020</link>
      <description>Han-Ming Zhang, Liang Zuo, Jiakang Li, Shaofei Zhang, Guo Jun, Xiaopu Li, Gang Lei, Peng Wang, J. Sun, Journal of Materials Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390585721

                Seawater electrolysis is one most promising development directions for future hydrogen energy. However, big challenges of active site poisoning, chloride oxidation (ClOR), and chloride corrosion on anode electrocatalysts, seriously impede seawater electrolysis development. Therefore, developing efficient anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is an urgent task for seawater electrolysis. The advanced strategies of improving OER kinetics, lowering ClOR kinetics, strengthening corrosion resistance, and recombining multifunction are summarized and analyzed to help researchers quickly grasp the recent progress on seawater oxidation. The outlooks for future research are put forward. The future research directions are proposed as internal and external cultivation, giving full play to the physicochemical properties of electrocatalysts, making sense of structure evolution and OER mechanism, and elucidating the electrical double layer of electrocatalysts. A lot of room for scalable application of seawater electrolysis calls for persistent effort and devotion of related researchers to boost seawater electrolysis development and universal hydrogen energy application.</description>
      <author>Han-Ming Zhang, Liang Zuo, Jiakang Li, Shaofei Zhang, Guo Jun, Xiaopu Li, Gang Lei, Peng Wang, J. Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2023.11.020</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-vacancy-rich NiFe-S nanosheets based on a fully electrochemical strategy for large-scale and quasi-industrial OER catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2023.123686</link>
      <description>Lixiang He, Ni Wang, Ming Xiang, Li Zhong, Sridhar Komarneni, Wencheng Hu, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390586697

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is regarded as a critical component in the water splitting system. Creating vacancies, increasing active surface area, and optimizing electronic structure would improve electrocatalytic performance. Herein, a facile electrochemical reduction method is used to generate sulfur vacancies in nickel iron sulfide (NiFe-S) with a large geometry area of 15&#215;16 cm2, which is synthesized using electrodeposition process assisted with the ion exchange (IOE) method. The X-ray absorption spectroscopies (XAS) are applied for atomic-level structural analysis, verifying that electrochemical desulfurization generates abundant S vacancies. The NiFe-S with abundant sulfur vacancies (NiFe-S-Vs) exhibits a low overpotential (252 mV at 100 mA cm-2), and long stability for 260 h at 500 mA cm-2. More importantly, the NiFe-S-Vs catalyst also delivers a small overpotential (235 mV at 1000 mA cm-2) and high alkaline tolerance (140 h at 500 mA cm-2) in 6 M KOH at 60 &#176;C), implying a potentially significant industrial application prospect. Finally, theory calculation further illustrates the high performance of as-prepared vacancies-rich catalyst.</description>
      <author>Lixiang He, Ni Wang, Ming Xiang, Li Zhong, Sridhar Komarneni, Wencheng Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2023.123686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface oxygen vacancy engineering of Cr-doped FeNi3/NiFe2O4 Mott-Schottky heterojunction as efficient electrocatalyst for high current density water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2023.173393</link>
      <description>S. Khatun, Santanu Kumar Pal, Poulomi Roy, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390590087

                The defect engineering at the surface by filling of oxygen vacancies during OER causing surface reconstruction is considered to be a unique way to boost up intrinsic electrocatalytic activity, especially towards oxygen evolution reaction (OER) mechanism. The present study aimed creation of large number of oxygen vacancies by Cr-doping into FeNi3/NiFe2O4 Mott-Schottky heterojunction electrocatalyst causing much desirable surface engineering and electronic modulation in favour of OER activity. The optimized heterojunction nanoparticles exhibited an excellent catalytic activity with low overpotential of 246 mV at the current density of 20 mA cm-2 with low Tafel slope value of 55 mV dec-1 for OER. Such oxygen vacancy-aided surface reconstruction during OER demonstrated an outstanding durability over 200 h even at high current density of 1000 mA cm-2 in 1 M KOH electrolyte. The surface oxygen vacancy engineering with the help of ex-situ Raman spectroscopy at different anodic potentials reveals the filling of vacancies and generation of MOOH as surface reconstruction of electrocatalyst during OER, also supported by XPS, TEM and EELS analyses.</description>
      <author>S. Khatun, Santanu Kumar Pal, Poulomi Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2023.173393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal-organic-framework-derived Fe, Co, N-tri-dopped porous carbon as oxygen electrocatalysts for Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2023.110345</link>
      <description>Ruili Song, Ling Guan, Lei Fan, Xianhua Miao, Hui Zhang, Jianchun Cheng, Tong Zhou, Cong Ni, Jian Fan, Journal of Energy Storage. 80(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390598699

                To commercialize the rechargeable zinc-air (Zn-air) battery, it is desirable but challenging to design highly active, low-cost, stable, and earth-rich bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to replace rare, expensive, and unstable noble-metal electrocatalysts. Herein, two MOFs are combined under electrostatic interaction and pressure by the way of Ball milling. Then, after post-processing including calcination, acid pickling, and N doping, the bimetal (Fe and Co) and N triple-doped porous carbon electrocatalyst (MIL/ZIF-4-700 &#176;C-NH3) is prepared. Noteworthily, the MIL/ZIF-4-700 &#176;C-NH3 has bimetallic active sites, high contents of pyridine N and graphite N, large surface area, mesoporous structure, and conductive carbon skeletons, which decide the excellent ORR performance. For ORR, the half-wave potential (E1/2 = 0.902 V vs. RHE) of MIL/ZIF-4-700 &#176;C-NH3 is 27 mV higher than that of 20 wt% Pt/C (E1/2 = 0.875 vs. RHE). And the catalyst has also excellent methanol tolerance and stability. The Zn-air battery with MIL/ZIF-4-700 &#176;C-NH3 as cathode catalyst has higher peak power density (176.5 mW cm&#8722;2) than that with 20 wt% Pt/C (141.8 mW cm&#8722;2) and 20 wt% Pt/C + RuO2 (94.4 mW cm&#8722;2) as cathode catalyst. Meanwhile, the Zn-air battery with MIL/ZIF-4-700 &#176;C-NH3 as cathode catalyst exhibits perfect charge-discharge stability (longer than 540 h).</description>
      <author>Ruili Song, Ling Guan, Lei Fan, Xianhua Miao, Hui Zhang, Jianchun Cheng, Tong Zhou, Cong Ni, Jian Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2023.110345</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PdOs bimetallene for energy-saving hydrogen production coupled with ethanol electro-oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101493</link>
      <description>Ziqiang Wang, Min Li, Shan Xu, Heng-Qing Ye, Kai Deng, You Xu, Hongjing Wang, Liang Wang, Materials Today Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390630246

                The replacement of sluggish oxygen evolution reaction by more thermodynamically favorable ethanol oxidation reaction (EOR) is a promising strategy for co-production of hydrogen and valuable chemicals in energy-saving mode. Here, we propose the synthesis of highly curved PdOs bimetallene, which possesses high active sites atomic utilization and conductivity. Furthermore, alloy effect can regulate electronic structure and optimize adsorption energy of reactants. Therefore, PdOs bimetallene exhibits superior performance for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and EOR under basic solutions, with overpotential of 36 mV at 10 mA cm-2 and mass activity of 1.51 mA &#956;g-1Pd, respectively. In the EOR-HER co-electrolysis system, PdOs bimetallene requires low voltage of 0.801 V for concurrent production of hydrogen and acetate at 50 mA cm&#8722;2, which greatly reduces energy consumption compared to conventional water electrolysis (1.976 V). This method provides a promising strategy for designing bimetallic electrocatalysts towards simultaneous energy-saving generation of hydrogen and high-value chemicals by replacing sluggish OER with more favorable ethanol oxidation reaction.</description>
      <author>Ziqiang Wang, Min Li, Shan Xu, Heng-Qing Ye, Kai Deng, You Xu, Hongjing Wang, Liang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtener.2024.101493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reinforced electrochemical energy storage through controlled construction of hierarchical hollow &#946;-Ni(OH)2 microspheres enriched with oxygen vacancies induced by functionalized MWCNTs</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159331</link>
      <description>Zhi-Jia Sun, J. Chen, Xiao&#8208;Man Cao, Hao Ge, Daliang Liu, Qiong Wu, Xi&#8211;Ming Song, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390636146

                As promising electrode materials, hollow-structured metallic oxides/hydroxides have attracted extensive attention for their significantly enhanced catalyst and electrochemical performances. In practice, however, it is still challenging to construct well-dispersed hollow structures using facile and versatile template-free methods. And, as a result of the weak conductivity of most metallic oxides/hydroxides, it is a particularly effective means to integrate metallic oxides/hydroxides with carbon-based conductive substrates or introduce oxygen vacancies for further promoting reaction kinetics and achieving boosted electrochemical performance. Herein, a novel composite material consisting of oxygen-rich vacancy &#946;-Ni(OH)2 coupled with oxidized multi-wall carbon nanotubes (Ov-N&#946;/Cm) was synthesized using a one-step hydrothermal technique without the need for templates. The hierarchical hollow microsphere structure was achieved by utilizing oxidized multi-wall carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) as an alternative to conventional surfactants or templates. The uniform distribution of multistage pores in the newly designed Ov-N&#946;/Cm composite facilitates the transportation of electrolyte ions, thereby endowing it with outstanding electrochemical performance. A straightforward technique for producing high-quality Ni(OH)2-based electrode materials is presented in this investigation, along with fresh perspectives on the formation mechanism of hollow-structured composites. Developing MWCNT-based hollow nanostructured composites with oxygen vacancies-enriched will offer an essential novel avenue to exploit excellent electrode materials for supercapacitors and other energy storage systems.</description>
      <author>Zhi-Jia Sun, J. Chen, Xiao&#8208;Man Cao, Hao Ge, Daliang Liu, Qiong Wu, Xi&#8211;Ming Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159331</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spray Pyrolysis Regulated FeCo Alloy Anchoring on Nitrogen&#8211;Doped Carbon Hollow Spheres Boost the Performance of Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310318</link>
      <description>Hong-Rui Huang, Qianqian Liang, Huajun Guo, Zhixing Wang, Guochun Yan, Feixiang Wu, Jiexi Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390637300

                Abstract Low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;efficiency non&#8208;precious metal&#8208;based oxygen reduction reaction (ORR)/oxygen evolution reaction (OER) bifunctional catalysts are the key to promoting the commercial application of metal&#8211;air batteries. Herein, a highly efficient catalyst of Fe 0.18 Co 0.82 alloy anchoring on the nitrogen&#8208;doped porous carbon hollow sphere (Fe x Co 1&#8208;x /N&#8208;C) is intelligently designed by spray pyrolysis (SP). The zinc in the SP&#8208;derived metal oxides and metal&#8208;organic framework volatilize at high temperature to construct a hierarchical porous structure with abundant defects and fully exposes the FeCo nanoparticles which uniformly anchor on the carbon substrate. In this structure, the coexistence of Fe 0.18 Co 0.82 alloy and binary metal active sites (Fe&#8208;N x /Co&#8208;N x ) guarantees the Fe 0.2 Co 0.8 /N&#8208;C catalyst exhibiting an excellent half&#8208;wave potential ( E 1/2 &#9552; 0.84 V) superior to 20% Pt/C for ORR and a suppressed overpotential (280 mV) than RuO 2 for OER. Assembled rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery (RZAB) demonstrates a promising specific capacity of 807.02 mAh g &#8722;1 , peak power density of 159.08 mW cm &#8722;2 and durability without electrolyte circulation (550 h). This work proposes the design concept of utilizing an oxide core to in situ consume the porous carbon shell for anchoring metal active sites and construct defects, which benefits from spray pyrolysis in achieving precise control of the alloy structure and mass preparation.</description>
      <author>Hong-Rui Huang, Qianqian Liang, Huajun Guo, Zhixing Wang, Guochun Yan, Feixiang Wu, Jiexi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical properties and kinetic studies of sulphur-induced oxygen vacancies in hydrothermally synthesized manganese molybdenum oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.135892</link>
      <description>Arumugam Sudalai, K. Vinoth Kumar, A. Aseema Banu, Sujin P. Jose, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390650057

                Manganese molybdenum oxide (MnMoO4) has recently garnered significant attention as a promising electrode material for advanced energy storage systems. It is found that the incorporation of oxygen vacancies due to the sulphur doping in MnMoO4 led to a larger interlayer spacing, facilitated charge storage kinetics, and maintained structural durability throughout the electrochemical processes. Hence, this work is focused on the hydrothermal synthesis of MnMoO4 with the sulphur-induced oxygen vacancies (S-MnMoO4) by secondary thermal heating processes. Structural and morphological characterizations confirmed the successful inclusion of oxygen vacancies in MnMoO4. Further drop casting S-MnMoO4 on nickel foam revealed significant improvements in electrochemical performance. It showed a specific capacitance of about 1131F g&#8722;1 at 1 A/g, which is six-fold that of pristine MnMoO4. S-MnMoO4 demonstrated excellent cyclic stability with 90% of capacitive retention across 5000 cycles and a coulombic efficiency of 98%. These results highlight the potential of S-MnMoO4 as an efficient electrode material for advanced energy storage applications.</description>
      <author>Arumugam Sudalai, K. Vinoth Kumar, A. Aseema Banu, Sujin P. Jose</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.135892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe(OH)x modified ultra-small Ru nanoparticles for highly efficient hydrogen evolution reaction and its application in water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.018</link>
      <description>Yufan Mo, Dongdong Du, Yiyun Du, Yongjun Feng, Pinggui Tang, Dianqing Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390650504

                Developing highly active electrocatalysts for overall water splitting is of remarkable significance for industrial production of H2. Herein, exceptionally active Fe(OH)x modified ultra-small Ru nanoparticles on Ni(OH)2 nanosheets array (Fe(OH)x-Ru/Ni(OH)2) for both hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are reported. The Fe(OH)x-Ru/Ni(OH)2 nanosheets array prepared with Fe/Ru molar ratio of 5 only requires extremely low overpotentials of 61, 127 and 170 mV to reach current densities of 100, 500 and 800 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 M KOH, respectively, exceeding Pt/C catalyst (75, 160 and 177 mV). Meanwhile, the Fe(OH)x/Ni(OH)2 nanosheets array derived from Fe(OH)x-Ru/Ni(OH)2 exhibits excellent OER activity. It gains current densities of 100, 500 and 800 mA cm&#8722;2 at considerably low overpotentials of 265, 285 and 296 mV, respectively, much lower than those of RuO2 and most reported electrocatalysts. The introduction of Fe(OH)x significantly improves the HER activity of Ru nanoparticles by tunning the electronic structure and forming interfaces between Ru and Fe(OH)x. Dramatically, the integrated alkaline electrolyzer based on Fe(OH)x-Ru/Ni(OH)2 and Fe(OH)x/Ni(OH)2 nanosheets array pair just needs 1.649 V to yield a current density up to 500 mA cm&#8722;2, exceeding most reported water-splitting electrocatalysts. The strategy reported in this work can be facilely extended to prepare other similar Ru based materials and their derivatives with outstanding catalytic performance for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yufan Mo, Dongdong Du, Yiyun Du, Yongjun Feng, Pinggui Tang, Dianqing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unbiased Photoelectrochemical Carbon Dioxide Reduction Shaping the Future of Solar Fuels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123707</link>
      <description>Haijiao Lu, Luyao Wang, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390650933

                As atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) levels surge due to human activities, addressing this global crisis is paramount. This article delves into the realm of photoelectrochemical (PEC) CO2 reduction, a promising solution that combines solar energy conversion and electrochemical processes to transform CO2 into clean energy fuels. The primary focus of this article lies in the cutting-edge unbiased PEC tandem configurations, specifically reviewing recent breakthroughs in coupling PEC CO2 reduction with the oxygen evolution reaction through water oxidation. By consolidating the latest insights and knowledge, this comprehensive review guides readers through the evolving landscape of advanced PEC technologies. Furthermore, it provides insights into prospective developments in this evolving field, shedding light on the paths toward sustainable energy solutions and climate mitigation.</description>
      <author>Haijiao Lu, Luyao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123707</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing delocalized electronic structures to motivate the oxygen reduction activity of zinc selenide for high-performance zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148598</link>
      <description>Lei Yang, Xiuyun Yao, Changliang Du, Zhanli Han, Mingwei Jin, Shichao Peng, Xiaoqing Ma, Youqi Zhu, Meishuai Zou, Chuanbao Cao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390651045

                Rechargeable zinc-air battery (ZAB) typically necessitates highly efficient, durable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts to accelerate oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Zinc selenide (ZnSe) has been demonstrated as a superior energy storage material due to its unique electronic structure for various energy-related applications but is still rarely developed in electrocatalysis field. Herein, the efficient interfacial engineering is reported to motivate and sufficiently boost the ORR performances of ZnSe to an unprecedented level. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrate that the introduction of robust Se-C interactions and N species regulation could efficiently modulate the local electronic structure of ZnSe and improve the interaction with oxygen-containing intermediate, thus producing lower reaction energy barrier of O2 &#8594; OOH* conversion. The optimized ZnSe@PNC catalyst manifests remarkable ORR activity with a half-wave potential of 0.905 VRHE in alkaline. Furthermore, the assembled Zn-air batteries with ZnSe@PNC cathodes show large peak power density (126 mW cm&#8722;2), high specific capacity (818 mAh/g) and long cycling life (200 h). This work provides more possibilities for the electrocatalytic applications of nonprecious metal selenide electrocatalyst for future energy storage.</description>
      <author>Lei Yang, Xiuyun Yao, Changliang Du, Zhanli Han, Mingwei Jin, Shichao Peng, Xiaoqing Ma, Youqi Zhu, Meishuai Zou, Chuanbao Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.148598</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-step microwave synthesis of self-supported NiCoMn medium-entropy alloy with long cycling stability for supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.112681</link>
      <description>Jinjuan Dong, Ning Lv, Xiaoning Kang, Xianrui Liu, H. Li, Tianbao Li, Zhen Guo, Jun Luo, Materials Research Bulletin. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390651117

                This work reports the preparation of NiCoMn medium-entropy alloys and Ag-Bi bimetallic alloys grown on nickel foam using the microwave method. X-ray diffraction confirms the single face-centered cubic phase organization of NiCoMn. Electrochemical analyses show that it has a high capacitance of 3206 F g&#8211;1 at 1 A g&#8211;1 and remarkable cycle stability (83.0% retention over 70,000 cycles). The Ag-Bi alloys manifest a decent storage capacity of 2462.5 F g&#8211;1. To meet the demand for high energy density, the prepared NiCoMn and Ag-Bi are used as positive and negative electrodes to assemble an asymmetric supercapacitor, respectively. The energy density of 218.8 Wh kg&#8211;1 is exhibited when the operating voltage is set to 1.5. The NiCoMn alloys also show favorable oxygen evolution reaction catalytic activity, with a low overpotential (186.6 mV) at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and a small Tafel slope (79.6 mV dec&#8211;1).</description>
      <author>Jinjuan Dong, Ning Lv, Xiaoning Kang, Xianrui Liu, H. Li, Tianbao Li, Zhen Guo, Jun Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.materresbull.2024.112681</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co3O4/NiCo2O4 heterojunction as oxygen evolution reaction catalyst for efficient luminol anode electrochemiluminescence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.015</link>
      <description>Chulei Zhao, Chaoyun Ma, Fuping Zhang, Wenjun Li, Chenglin Hong, Fuxi Bao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390651512

                Luminol has garnered significant attention from analysts as one of the most effective and commonly used electrochemiluminescence (ECL) reagents. However, the efficient luminescence of luminol anode is limited by the excitation of various reactive oxygen species (ROS). Typically, ROS are generated through co-reactive reagents and dissolved oxygen. Unfortunately, the former suffers from two drawbacks, namely biotoxicity and instability, while the latter cannot offer sufficient oxygen due to its limited solubility in aqueous solutions. Consequently, a low decomposition rate is usually obtained, leading to insufficient ROS. Therefore, there is an urgent need to develop efficient luminol anode systems. This study focuses on the use of zeolitic imidazolate framework-67 (ZIF-67) as a template, employing a controlled chemical etching method to create a ZIF-67/Ni-Co-layered double hydroxide (LDH). The intermediate composite is then annealed in air, resulting in the formation of a Co3O4/NiCo2O4 double-shelled nanobox (DSNB) heterostructure. Due to its structural advantages, the DSNB exhibits excellent electrocatalytic performance in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Furthermore, it was found that both the intermediates and products of OER can directly participate in the luminol chemiluminescence process, ultimately resulting in a 700-fold increase in the electrochemiluminescence (ECL) signal compared to an equal molar concentration of luminol solution. This work not only establishes the OER-mediated ECL system but also deepens the understanding of the relationship between ROS and luminol, providing a new pathway to study the luminol anodic ECL luminescence system.</description>
      <author>Chulei Zhao, Chaoyun Ma, Fuping Zhang, Wenjun Li, Chenglin Hong, Fuxi Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Non&#8208;precious Trifunctional Cobalt&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts for Industrial Water Splitting and Ultra&#8208;High&#8208;Temperature Flexible Zinc&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308355</link>
      <description>Tengteng Gu, Jiadong Shen, Zhaoyu Sun, Fangkun Li, Chunyi Zhi, Min Zhu, Jiangwen Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390655066

                Abstract Developing efficient, robust, and cost&#8208;effective trifunctional catalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) at high current density and high temperature is crucial for water splitting at industry&#8208;level conditions and ultra&#8208;high&#8208;temperature Zinc&#8208;air battery (ZAB). Herein, cobalt nanoparticles well&#8208;integrated with nitrogen&#8208;doped porous carbon leaves (Co@NPCL) by direct annealing of core&#8208;shell bimetallic zeolite imidazolate frameworks is synthesized. Benefiting from the homogeneous distribution of metallic Co nanoparticles, the conductive porous carbon, and the doped N species, the as&#8208;fabricated Co@NPCL catalysts exhibit outstanding trifunctional performances with low overpotentials at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for HER (87 mV) and OER (276 mV), long&#8208;lasting lifetime of over 2000 h, and a high half&#8208;wave potential of 0.86 V versus RHE for ORR. Meanwhile, the Co@NPCL catalyst can serve as both cathode and anode for water splitting at industrial conduction, and exhibit a stable cell voltage of 1.87 V to deliver a constant catalytic current of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 over 60 h. Moreover, the excellent trifunctional activity of Co@NPCL enables the flexible ZAB to operate efficiently at ultra&#8208;high temperature of 70 &#176;C, delivering 162 mW cm &#8722;2 peaks power density and an impressive stability for 4500 min at 2 mA cm &#8722;2 .</description>
      <author>Tengteng Gu, Jiadong Shen, Zhaoyu Sun, Fangkun Li, Chunyi Zhi, Min Zhu, Jiangwen Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202308355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Borate Anion&#8208;Intercalated NiV&#8208;LDH Nanoflakes/NiCoP Nanowires Heterostructures for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Selectivity in Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315949</link>
      <description>Taotao Gao, Yuqing Zhou, Xiao&#8208;Jun Zhao, Zhi&#8208;Hong Liu, Juan Bai, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390656116

                Abstract Resourceful and inexpensive seawater direct splitting omits the desalination process and effectively increases the efficiency of hydrogen energy generation. However, the development of seawater splitting is hampered by the competing selectivity challenges from anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and chlorine evolution reaction and the issues of electrode corrosion. Herein, the borate anion&#8208;intercalated NiV&#8208;LDH nanoflakes/NiCoP nanowires heterostructures supported on Ni foam (2D/1D NiV&#8208;BLDH/NiCoP/NF) is synthesized. Theoretical calculations show that a small amount of V atom doping in Ni(OH) 2 is favorable for changing the electronic environment around Ni atoms via bridging Ni&#9472;O, which can construct Ni&#9472;O&#9472;V to accelerate electron transfer and promote catalytic activity. The borate anions (B(OH) 4 &#8722; ) intercalation not only results in the good hydrophilicity and high OH &#8722; selectivity but also weakens the adsorption of chlorine (Cl &#8722; ), which effectively restrains the chlorine evolution reaction. Thus, the component optimized NiV 0.1 &#8208;BLDH/NiCoP/NF electrocatalyst only requires 268 mV overpotential to reach 100 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER in an alkaline environment. Particularly, the NiCoP/NF||NiV 0.1 &#8208;BLDH/NiCoP/NF cell exhibits attractive overall water splitting performance with a low voltage of 1.46 and 1.53 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline freshwater and alkaline seawater, respectively. The design strategy of this electrocatalyst provides a new avenue for seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>Taotao Gao, Yuqing Zhou, Xiao&#8208;Jun Zhao, Zhi&#8208;Hong Liu, Juan Bai</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202315949</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Si-doped ZnAl-LDH nanosheets by layer-engineering for efficient photoelectrocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123706</link>
      <description>Wentao Bao, Ying Tang, Jie Yu, Wenxia Yan, Chenxu Wang, Yangyang Li, Zhimou Wang, Jinfeng Yang, Li Li Zhang, Feng Ye, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390661684

                A highly efficient Si-doped ZnAl-LDH (denoted as Si-ZnAl-LDH nanosheet) catalyst that is derived from large-area chemical exfoliation for photoelectrocatalytic water splitting. The formation of amorphous Si-ZnAl-LDH nanosheets through chemical exfoliation or layer engineering leads to much more accessible surfaces that originally are not accessible in highly crystalline ZnAl-LDH sheets. The incorporation of Si to highly exfoliated ZnAl-LDH nanosheets generates more oxygen vacancies, increases the number of active sites, redistributes the local charge density of the active centers and effectively suppresses the recombination of the generated electron-hole pairs. Specifically, the overpotential of HER and OER for Si-ZnAl-LDH nanosheet is 108 mV and 260 mV, respectively, at current density of 10 mA cm-2 under light-assisted conditions. Total applied voltage is 1.673 V for water splitting in a full cell. This work provides a novel chemical exfoliation or layer-engineering strategy for the synthesis of scalable and cost-effective LDH nanosheets with efficient photoelectric response.</description>
      <author>Wentao Bao, Ying Tang, Jie Yu, Wenxia Yan, Chenxu Wang, Yangyang Li, Zhimou Wang, Jinfeng Yang, Li Li Zhang, Feng Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.123706</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Cnt/Ru/Cobalt Oxide Composites as Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysts Via Ball Milling Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4687449</link>
      <description>Tongya Tian, Sen Zhang, Song Yang, Chang Ming Li, Xi Zhou, Zhenghua Yang, Qizhe Ji, Xianglong Zhao, Feiyong Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390661742

                Ruthenium (Ru) and cobalt oxides (CoxOy) nanoparticles are uniformly decorated on surfaces of carbon nanotubes (CNTs), via ball milling of mixtures consisting of CNTs, triphenylphosphine ruthenium chlorides and cobalt nitrates. Due to collective contributions of Ru and CoxOy, the obtained CNT/Ru/CoxOy composites exhibit excellent electrocatalytic activities and durability for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), both of which outperform those of the state-of-the-art iridium oxide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tongya Tian, Sen Zhang, Song Yang, Chang Ming Li, Xi Zhou, Zhenghua Yang, Qizhe Ji, Xianglong Zhao, Feiyong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4687449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalyst Derived by High-Temperature Pyrolysis of 3-Amino-1,2,4-Triazole-Modified Fe-ZIF Nanostructures for Oxygen Reduction and Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05011</link>
      <description>Duc&#8208;Viet Nguyen, Ravi Nivetha, Nam Le, Jin Suk Chung, Won Mook Choi, Seung Hyun Hur, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390663908

                Recently, the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) have received great attention for the development of renewable energy and energy storage systems. In the context of catalyst standpoint, developing single-atom catalysts (SACs) with bifunctional electrocatalytic reactions (ORR/OER) has emerged as a fascinating research field in recent years. However, a majority of SACs that have been reported have a complicated synthesis route that involves many steps and harmful solvents and suffer from aggregation phenomena, which makes them unsustainable for industrial use. Herein, a bifunctional C-Atz-20 electrocatalyst was fabricated by inserting a secondary organic linker, 3-amino-1,2,4-triazole (Atz), into Fe-ZIF followed by high-temperature pyrolysis and its ORR/OER elucidated. To fully comprehend the function of Atz addition, the nanostructured materials underwent an extensive characteristic analysis. The results showed that the C-Atz-20 exhibited better long-term ORR and OER stability tests when compared with Pt/C and RuO2, respectively. Interestingly, the high ORR activity of C-Atz-20 originally contributed to the presence of a large fraction of pyridinic and graphitic N. Rotating ring-disk electrode (RRDE) measurement illustrates the ORR mechanism in the catalytic process, giving a better understanding of electron transport, thus paving the way for the design and development of heterogeneous catalysts with simple preparation and operating procedures.</description>
      <author>Duc&#8208;Viet Nguyen, Ravi Nivetha, Nam Le, Jin Suk Chung, Won Mook Choi, Seung Hyun Hur</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manganese Dissolution in alkaline medium with and without concurrent oxygen evolution in LiMn&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ya00434a</link>
      <description>Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Max Baumung, Michael Tatzel, Cynthia A. Volkert, Marcel Risch, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390667978

                Manganese dissolution during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been a persistent challenge that impedes the practical implementation of Mn-based electrocatalysts including the Li x Mn 2 O 4 system in aqueous alkaline electrolyte. The...</description>
      <author>Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Max Baumung, Michael Tatzel, Cynthia A. Volkert, Marcel Risch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ya00434a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Effect of Mxene@Cop2 on Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4683573</link>
      <description>Xiongming Du, Yan Wang, Zicong Ye, Wei Wang, Yuqiao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390581925

                0D/2D MXene@CoP2 was fabricated by hydrothermal and chemical vapor deposition phosphate methods. MXene nanosheets were employed as substrate to increase dispersion and stability of the multicomponent catalyst. The morphology of CoP2 was regulated by the addtion of Co precursor in hydrothermal process. MXene@CoP2-0.5 showed a uniform growth of CoP2 and formed aboundant reaction sites. The interfacial electron transfer between MXene and CoP2 modulated the electron structure of CoP2 and stimulated the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. The optimized MXene@CoP2-0.5 exhibited the OER overpotential of 263 mV and a long-term stability over 16 h. Modulating the interfacial electron transfer of multicomponent catalysts provided a guidance for electrocatalyst design and synthesis.</description>
      <author>Xiongming Du, Yan Wang, Zicong Ye, Wei Wang, Yuqiao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4683573</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling oxygen vacancy changes of WO3 photoanodes for promoting oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2023.123682</link>
      <description>Lianglin Yan, Guojun Dong, Xiaojuan Huang, Yun Zhang, Yingpu Bi, Applied Catalysis B: Environmental. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390578149

                Oxygen vacancy (VO) on semiconductor photoanode plays an important role in enhancing photoelectrochemical water oxidation performances. Nonetheless, there is still a lack of definitive elucidation regarding the structural changes and their impact on charge transport during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, oxygen vacancies were rationally introduced on WO3 nanoflake photoanodes via Ar-plasma engraving, resulting in a threefold increase in the photocurrent density of 2.76 mA cm-2 at 1.23 VRHE under AM 1.5 G solar irradiation compared to the pristine WO3 photoanode. Comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations reveal that the self-healing process of surface oxygen vacancies on WO3 photoanodes should be more easily achieved by capturing oxygen atoms from adsorbed H2O molecules. However, some survived oxygen vacancies in the subsurface could effectively increase the charge carrier density and provide the additional driving force to accelerate the interfacial charge transport, leading to enhanced photoelectrochemical (PEC) activities. More importantly, the oxygen vacancy self-healing on metal-oxide semiconductors is a universal phenomenon, which might bring new insights for design and construction of highly efficient photoanodes for PEC water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Lianglin Yan, Guojun Dong, Xiaojuan Huang, Yun Zhang, Yingpu Bi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2023.123682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The strategies to improve TMDs represented by MoS2 electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109515</link>
      <description>Junan Pan, Xin-Yi Liu, Hangjie Ji, Yi Zhu, Yanling Zhuang, Kang Chen, Ning Sun, Yongqi Liu, Yongquan Lei, Kun Wang, Bowen Zang, Longlu Wang, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843576

                The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are the two half reactions that make up the over water splitting reaction. Increasing oxygen evolution reaction rate wound immensely raise the efficiency of over water splitting reaction because it is the rate limiting reaction in water splitting reaction. The key to improve OER performance is the development and utilization of advanced catalysts. As one of the most potential catalysts for HER, it has gradually attracted the attention of researchers in the aspect of catalytic OER. It is very necessary to review the research progress of Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) in catalytic OER to promote the research process in the field. In this review, we comprehensively and systematically summarized the strategies to improve TMDs electrocatalytic OER. First of all, structural regulation of TMDs-based electrocatalyst was summarized in detail, mainly including size engineering, defect engineering, doping engineering, phase engineering and heterojunction engineering. Once more, magnetic field regulation as a representative of external field regulation to improve TMDs electrocatalytic OER performance was discussed in depth. Last but not least, the strategies to improve TMDs electrocatalytic OER is prospected and some views on the development of this field are also put forward, which are expected to enhance the catalytic efficiency of TMDs for OER.</description>
      <author>Junan Pan, Xin-Yi Liu, Hangjie Ji, Yi Zhu, Yanling Zhuang, Kang Chen, Ning Sun, Yongqi Liu, Yongquan Lei, Kun Wang, Bowen Zang, Longlu Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Material Dynamics of Manganese-Based Oxychlorides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02362</link>
      <description>Ruihan Li, Dennis Nordlund, Linsey C. Seitz, Chemistry of Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390918522

                Earth-abundant manganese-based oxides have emerged as promising alternatives to noble-metal-based catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acidic conditions; however, their inferior activity and stability present critical challenges for the sustainable production of hydrogen via water electrolysis. Moving beyond oxides, heteroanionic materials, which incorporate anions with lower electronegativity than oxygen, have shown potential for improving the OER performance, but a detailed understanding of the underlying mechanisms is lacking. Here, we investigate manganese-based oxychlorides (Mn8O10Cl3 and FeMn7O10Cl3) that exhibit excellent activity and stability for acidic OER to elucidate material property dynamics and correlate them with OER behaviors. Our rigorous electrochemical stability testing reveals that the high operating potential mitigates Mn dissolution over prolonged exposure to the OER conditions. Through a combination of ex situ and in situ surface and bulk-sensitive X-ray spectroscopy analyses, we observe a trade-off between increasing Mn valence and maintaining structural integrity, which results in dynamic bond length changes within the [MnCl6] octahedra during the activation and degradation processes of these oxychloride catalysts. This study provides insights into the fundamental relationships between the chemical, electronic, and geometric properties of the catalysts and their electrocatalytic outcomes.</description>
      <author>Ruihan Li, Dennis Nordlund, Linsey C. Seitz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.chemmater.3c02362</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the effects of solvent on oxygen evolution reactions on the surface of magnesium oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rinma.2024.100527</link>
      <description>Parisa Taherpoor, Farzaneh Farzad, Ameneh Zaboli, Results in Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390563400

                In this research, due to the importance of oxygen evolution reactions (OER) in the production of hydrogen gas, the effects of the solvent on the OER steps on the magnesium oxide surface have been studied. For this purpose, the difference in free energy value in OER steps on the Magnesium oxide surface for two systems (in the presence and the absence of solvent) have been investigated using molecular dynamics (MD) simulation and thermodynamic integration (TI). These results are in perfect agreement with the results obtained from ab initio molecular dynamics simulations and quantum mechanics calculations. Our findings show that the presence of water solvent around the surface of magnesium oxide has a crucial role on OER and leads to an increase more than twofold in the free energy of all steps. Also, the presence of the solvent has the most effect on the third step of OER, and its &#916;G increases by about 1.9 eV. This fact can be attributed to the approach of the water molecules to the substrate spontaneously, which increases the probability of forming hydrogen bonds and the number of contacts, leading to more favorable thermodynamic reactions. Close inspection of the calculated binding energies between the substrate and the intermediates confirms that the binding energy of OER's second step is significantly higher than the other steps and is the velocity determining step.</description>
      <author>Parisa Taherpoor, Farzaneh Farzad, Ameneh Zaboli</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rinma.2024.100527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Mechanism of Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Nanostructured Copper-Based Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05313</link>
      <description>Chi Xie, Kaili Zhang, Yongyong Lai, Lili Du, Jing Ma, Shouwu Xu, Ping Qiu, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390806435

                In water splitting processes, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the main kinetic control steps that should be triggered by high-efficiency catalysts. A series of Cu-based catalysts are considered potential candidates. This work provides a simple and effective strategy for fabricating large-scale copper-based catalysts by anodization on a copper foil at room temperature in a KOH solution. The representative petal-shaped CuO and Cu(OH)2 nanorods are obtained. The corresponding surface areas are 0.0197 and 1.966 m2/g, respectively. The surface wettability of Cu(OH)2 is lower than that of CuO. The catalytic performance is studied by linear sweep voltammetry (LSV). The results show that the potential of the OER for CuO at 10 mA/cm2 is 1.67 V, which reduces by 130 mV compared to Cu(OH)2. The CuO could keep 10 mA/cm2 after a 1 h chronoamperometry test, which is about 3 times higher than that of Cu(OH)2. To verify the distinguishing catalytic difference between CuO and Cu(OH)2, in situ Raman spectra have been recorded. Inspiringly, the CuIII active specie at 603 cm&#8211;1 is captured during the OER process on CuO instead of Cu(OH)2. The related mechanism has been discussed in detail.</description>
      <author>Chi Xie, Kaili Zhang, Yongyong Lai, Lili Du, Jing Ma, Shouwu Xu, Ping Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c05313</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-entropy borides with frame structure: Efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.12.082</link>
      <description>Tingyue Gu, Zhiyuan Jing, Fang Miao, Wei Wu, Yuhong Zhao, Hua Hou, Xiubing Liang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 56(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390758147

                Innovative methods for producing catalytic nanomaterials are crucial for advancing environmental conversion and storage technologies. This study introduces a novel approach to fabricate a high-entropy boride alloy with a frame structure, FeCoNiMgB/NF, using in situ growth of high-entropy alloy powder on nickel foam (NF). The resulting frame-structured FeCoNiMgB/NF high-entropy boride alloy exhibits superior electrocatalytic performance for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) compared to pure FeCoNiMgB powder and other counterparts. It demonstrates a low overpotential of 183 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a Tafel slope of 34 mV dec&#8722;1 in 1 M KOH, and excellent stability over 72 h without significant decay. The outstanding catalytic performance of the frame-structured FeCoNiMgB/NF high-entropy alloy can be attributed to the synergistic effects of FeCoNiMgB&#8211;NF, a larger specific surface area, and excellent frame-structure conductivity. The alloy's long-term stability is a result of the gradual formation of the FeCoNiMgOOH lath structure array during the reaction process, facilitating low adsorption and charge transfer energies as per theoretical calculations. This study presents a new method for constructing advanced frame-structured high-entropy boride alloys, promising advancements in energy conversion and storage technologies.</description>
      <author>Tingyue Gu, Zhiyuan Jing, Fang Miao, Wei Wu, Yuhong Zhao, Hua Hou, Xiubing Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.12.082</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile synthesis of hierarchical CoFe2O4 nanosheets for efficient oxygen evolution in neutral medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.124553</link>
      <description>Xinqi Wang, Zhaoyuan Wang, Yuanyuan Cao, Xinxin Liu, Liping Zhou, Jianjun Shi, Bao&#8208;Zhu Guo, Di Li, Rongrong Ye, Zhao Zhang, Journal of Solid State Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390674249

                It is of great significance to develop electrocatalysts that are abundant in Earth's crust, highly efficient, and exceptionally durable for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), particularly in neutral media. Herein, the hierarchical CoFe2O4 nanosheets supported on iron foam (CoFe2O4/IF) are prepared by the ambient spontaneous redox reaction between iron foam and Co2+ at room temperature. The as-obtained CoFe2O4/IF electrode presents excellent electrocatalytic OER activity with an overpotential of 429 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and maintains the stability of 50 h in 1 M PBS. The outstanding electrocatalytic OER activity of CoFe2O4/IF can be credited to the decreased transfer resistance and unique structural features. In addition, the CoFe2O4/IF presented here holds promise for noble-metal-free OER electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Xinqi Wang, Zhaoyuan Wang, Yuanyuan Cao, Xinxin Liu, Liping Zhou, Jianjun Shi, Bao&#8208;Zhu Guo, Di Li, Rongrong Ye, Zhao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.124553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A p-d block synergistic effect enables robust electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109496</link>
      <description>Xiaohui Zhao, Rui Zhao, Qian Liu, H.R. Chen, Jing Wang, Yongfeng Hu, Yan Li, Qiuming Peng, John S. Tse, Chinese Chemical Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390733560

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER), occurring at the anode of electrochemical water splitting requires a comprehensive understanding of oxygen electrocatalysis mechanism to optimize its efficiency. Atomically dispersed transition metal supported by nitrogen-doped carbon is featured with excellent catalytic performance. Herein, we report a Mg/Co bimetal site which utilizes Mg 3p electrons with strong binding of *OH (the first key reaction intermediates in the free energy diagram) to trigger the OER reaction and Co 3d itinerant character to regulate the binding strength of *O. Benefiting from the fine-tuned adsorption/desorption possesses, the optimized catalyst delivers superior OER activity with low overpotential, i.e., 310 mV at a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and 455 mV at 100 mA/cm2. Moreover, the current density is able to be maintained at 10 mA/cm2 for 10 h, consistent with the theoretical simulations for oxidization process, which demonstrates stable configurations after multiple *OH modification, revealing robust applicability in alkaline medium.</description>
      <author>Xiaohui Zhao, Rui Zhao, Qian Liu, H.R. Chen, Jing Wang, Yongfeng Hu, Yan Li, Qiuming Peng, John S. Tse</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109496</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiSe-modified CoMoO4 nanosheets as bifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173495</link>
      <description>Menghe Jiang, Zhicong Hu, Yongjin Zou, Cuili Xiang, Fen Xu, Lin Sun, Xiaoyun Hu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390755768

                Selecting self-supporting substrates with large specific surface areas is an effective strategy to avoid the agglomeration of nanomaterials and improve the structural stability of materials while increasing their electrical conductivity. In this study, CoMoO4 nanosheet structures were first grown on a nickel foam (NF) substrate by hydrothermal and calcination processes. Then, NiSe nanoparticles were deposited on NF/CoMoO4 by a constant potential method to construct NF/CoMoO4@NiSe nanosheet electrode materials with graded layered structures. This nanosheet structure grown on NF substrates provided enough space for mass transfer and fully exposed the electrochemical active sites. Meanwhile, the self-supported electrode reduced the indirect contact resistance between the electrocatalyst and the substrate, which promoted the timely release of generated bubbles from the electrode. The NF/CoMoO4@NiSe electrode exhibited excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalytic activities under alkaline conditions. Overpotentials of only 58 mV and 184 mV were needed to achieve a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm-2 for the HER and OER, respectively. This study presents new ideas for the construction of nanosheet structures and the design of efficient HER and OER bifunctional electrocatalysts using transition metal selenides.</description>
      <author>Menghe Jiang, Zhicong Hu, Yongjin Zou, Cuili Xiang, Fen Xu, Lin Sun, Xiaoyun Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.173495</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrNi Nanoparticles as Highly Efficient Electrocatalysts Towards the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in an Acidic Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-99-8581-4_11</link>
      <description>Yongwen Sun, Hong Lv, Gao Da, Cunman Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390746910

                The development of efficient and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), still poses huge challenges. Herein, we utilize a facile hydrothermal method to synthesize a novel IrNi nanocrystals. In particular, the electronic structure is altered when a portion of the iridium atom is replaced by a Ni atom, which causes the center of the d band to shift downward, favoring the catalytic reaction. The overpotentials for OER of 273 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, exceed the capabilities of commercial Ir catalysts. The alloying of Ir with Ni reduces the adsorption energy of oxygen intermediates to achieve a fast oxygen evolution reaction. This work highlights a potentially powerful strategy toward the general synthesis of novel, Ir-based alloy as highly active and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts for high-performance electrochemical overall-water-splitting devices.</description>
      <author>Yongwen Sun, Hong Lv, Gao Da, Cunman Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/978-981-99-8581-4_11</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anisotropic structural carbon skeleton decorated with Co nanoparticles towards oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133228</link>
      <description>Changshui Wang, Qian Zhang, B. Li, Zhenlu Liu, Cenlin He, Guangli Yang, Longjun Jiang, Chunmei Zhang, Kunming Liu, Shuijian He, Colloids and Surfaces A: Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843849

                Hierarchical carbon skeletons derived from natural wood can be employed as the substrates to fabricate self-supported catalysts. The typically three sections (cross section, radial section, and tangential section) of wood would significantly affect the electrocatalytic performance. Therefore, the correlations between anisotropy structure of wood derived hierarchical carbon skeletons and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performances was systematically investigated. The cross-sectional wood-derived carbon decorated with Co nanoparticles requires an overpotential of 370 mV to deliver 50 mA cm-2 superior to those of radial-sectional and tangential-sectional counterparts. The cross-section of wood derived carbon skeleton possesses higher content of Co nanoparticles, which is accounted for the enhanced OER catalytic activity. This work highlights the critical contribution of anisotropy of carbon skeletons in promoting the OER properties and provides a new paradigm for designing advanced electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Changshui Wang, Qian Zhang, B. Li, Zhenlu Liu, Cenlin He, Guangli Yang, Longjun Jiang, Chunmei Zhang, Kunming Liu, Shuijian He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.133228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on cationic vacancy engineering application of oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalyst in seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111946</link>
      <description>Hong Liang, Bo Li, Chenchen Jing, Zihan Zhuang, Yuji Zhang, Huajie Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang, Journal of Environmental Chemical Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390858649

                Seawater oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a kind of feasible method to solve energy problems. Through studying seawater OER, it can not only reduce the dependence on traditional energy sources, but also protect the environment and reducing pollution. Cationic defect engineering can effectively enhance the properties of seawater OER. This way can make more catalysts active sites exposed and simultaneously change the electronic properties of materials to improve the conductivity of materials. Meanwhile, defects lead to electron delocalization, promote carrier migration and increase the charge transfer rate of materials. Cationic vacancy defects can effectively improve the OER properties of materials. Therefore, studying relationship between structure and function of vacancy defect electrocatalysts is beneficial to improve the seawater OER performance better. The transition metal-based vacancy catalyst has good seawater OER performance, for example, Fe, Co and Ni based vacancy catalysts. The influence of cationic vacancy on the improvement of OER performance in seawater was further expounded by the DFT of analysis of cationic vacancy catalyst. With the continuous progress of technology, the cost of seawater electrolysis technology will be gradually reduced, which can greatly promote the development of sustainable and renewable clean energy.</description>
      <author>Hong Liang, Bo Li, Chenchen Jing, Zihan Zhuang, Yuji Zhang, Huajie Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.111946</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field enhanced surface reconstruction of Fe2P and the promotional effect in electrochemical oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159357</link>
      <description>Fu&#8208;Rong Chen, Shen Chen, Yujun Zhu, Yidan Liu, Difan Zhou, Lei Huang, Liyi Shi, Hongbin Zhang, Shixun Cao, Rongrong Jia, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390755203

                In recent years, the utilization of magnetic fields to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of catalysts has emerged as an effective approach. However, current research primarily focusing on the impact on magnetic transition metal oxides, and the relevant mechanisms are still worth further exploration. Here, the OER performance of Fe2P loaded on carbon paper (Fe2P/CP) and nickel foam (Fe2P/NF) substrates under in situ magnetic field was investigated. It is revealed that magnetic fields can substantially enhance the OER performance of Fe2P/CP and Fe2P/NF. With a magnetic field of 1.0 T, the current density of 75&#8211;Fe2P/CP increases by 28 times (1.8 V vs. RHE), leading to a maximum magnetic current density percentage of 2770%. According to our results, the magnetic enhancement effect is highly correlated with the surface reconstruction of Fe2P to &#945;-FeOOH with lower OER energy barriers. Additionally, the spin pinning effect is observed on the &#945;-FeOOH/ Fe2P interfaces, which leads to the rapid alignment of spin electrons on the surface of catalysts under magnetic field, lowering the O&#8211;O coupling energy barrier, and therefore improve OER kinetics. These discoveries have the potential to contribute to a fundamental and comprehensive understanding of electrochemical reactions involving magnetic fields.</description>
      <author>Fu&#8208;Rong Chen, Shen Chen, Yujun Zhu, Yidan Liu, Difan Zhou, Lei Huang, Liyi Shi, Hongbin Zhang, Shixun Cao, Rongrong Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159357</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Charge Engineering in Black Phosphorene with Tunable Electronic Structures as Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4694215</link>
      <description>Huating Liu, Zongyu Huang, Hui Qiao, Xiang Qi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390837510

                Layered black phosphorus (BP) has unique electronic structure, which makes it an ideal candidate material for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Charge doping effectively improves the environmental stability and catalytic activity of BP by providing electron transfer channels and reducing the charge transfer barrier. Therefore, based on the method of first principles calculation, this paper theoretically discusses how the intrinsic charge doping without introducing impurities changes the electronic structure and improves the catalytic activity of BP. It is found that charge engineering can stimulate the hybridization between different P-p orbitals, effectively regulate and change the electronic structure and work function while maintaining the direct bandgap semiconductor characteristics of monolayer BP system. More importantly, in the catalytic process of OER, electrons and hole doping as free charges provide different donor and acceptor energy levels for the system depending on the doping concentration, and affect the adsorption capacity of monolayer BP to different reaction intermediates. When the doping concentration is 0.15 e/u.c, monolayer BP can achieves the optimal Gibbs free energy and overpotential, the rate-determining step of reaction free-energy diagram is downhill and exothermal, and carrier mobility is significantly increased. These results provide new opportunities and possibilities for designing charge-engineered BP catalysts with adjustable electronic structure and excellent OER activity.</description>
      <author>Huating Liu, Zongyu Huang, Hui Qiao, Xiang Qi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4694215</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo2S4 octahedral configuration doped by Mn, Zn and Cu for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc06171j</link>
      <description>Yi-Ting Chen, Wu H, Ning Tang, Mengjie Zhang, Yuqiao Wang, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390883323

                Transition metals with similar atomic radius were used to doping spinel NiCo2S4 to adjust octahedral configuration. Mn dopants adjusted the morphology and surface charge distribution, optimized the electron transport and...</description>
      <author>Yi-Ting Chen, Wu H, Ning Tang, Mengjie Zhang, Yuqiao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3cc06171j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The electronic structure of the active center of Co3Se4 electrocatalyst was adjusted by Te doping for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.026</link>
      <description>Hao Wang, Xueya Deng, A.R. Bari, Mingzheng Gu, Man Lin, Gaoyun An, Xiaomin Huang, Xiaojun Zhang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390725329

                In order to enhance the energy efficiency of water electrolysis, it is imperative to devise electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction that are both non-precious metal-based and highly efficient. Efficient catalyst design is generally based on electronic structural engineering. Considering the electronegativity disparity between selenium (Se) and tellurium (Te), the tunable bandgaps, and the conductive metallic nature of Te. We designed a material wherein Te atoms are uniformly doped onto the surface of Cobalt tetra selenide (Co3Se4) nanorods, leading to the synthesis of a defect-rich material. Experimental results demonstrate that Te doping in Co3Se4 increases active sites and optimizes the electronic structure of Co cations, enhancing the design of multi-defect structures. This promotes the generation of the Co(oxy) hydroxide (CoOOH) active phase, enhancing catalytic activity by maximizing the binding strength between Co sites and oxygenated intermediates. Te-Co3Se4 nanorods exhibit good catalytic activity for oxygen evolution reactions, with an overpotential of 269 mV at a driving current density of 50 mA cm&#8722;2 and excellent stability in alkaline media (over 100 h). This discovery indicates the feasibility of strategically combining various imperfect structures, thereby unlocking the latent potential of diverse catalysts in electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Hao Wang, Xueya Deng, A.R. Bari, Mingzheng Gu, Man Lin, Gaoyun An, Xiaomin Huang, Xiaojun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow CoVOx/Ag nanoprism with tailored electronic structure for high efficiency oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.073</link>
      <description>Siru Chen, Yingying Yao, Jing Xu, Junyan Chen, Zhuo Wang, Pengyu Li, Yanqiang Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843673

                Developing high-active and inexpensive electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is very important in the field of water splitting. The catalytic performance of electrocatalysts can be significantly improved by optimizing the electronic structure and designing suitable nanostructure. In this work, we represent the synthesis of hollow CoVOx/Ag-5 for OER. Due to the interaction of CoVOx and Ag nanoparticles, the electronic structure is optimized to improve the intrinsic catalytic activity. Additionally, the extrinsic catalytic activity of CoVOx/Ag is enhanced by the abundant active sites from the hollow structure. As a result, the CoVOx/Ag-5 demonstrates significantly enhanced OER catalytic activity with a low overpotential of 247 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2. In addition, it also exhibits excellent durability, without obvious attenuation in performance after continuous operation for 60 h. Furthermore, the catalyst can enable full water splitting with appropriate 100 % Faraday efficiency, demonstrating its practical application.</description>
      <author>Siru Chen, Yingying Yao, Jing Xu, Junyan Chen, Zhuo Wang, Pengyu Li, Yanqiang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile and scalable synthesis of Ni3S2/Fe3O4 nanoblocks as an efficient and stable electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.072</link>
      <description>Jing Mei, Yu Deng, Xiaohong Cheng, Qi Wu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390858579

                This study employed a one-step hydrothermal process to synthesize Ni3S2/Fe3O4 nanoblocks in situ on nickel foam (NF). The resulting Ni3S2/Fe3O4/NF catalyst demonstrates exceptional electrocatalytic activity for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and robust long-term stability. It achieves a low overpotential of only 220 mV for a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 with a Tafel slope of 54.1 mV dec&#8722;1 and remains stable in 1.0 M KOH for 66 h. The binder-free self-supported three-dimensional nanoblocks enhance the reaction region and long-term stability. Electronic interactions between Fe3O4 and Ni3S2, coupled with heterogeneous interfaces, optimize the electronic structure, fostering the formation of highly reactive species. Density-functional theory (DFT) calculations confirm that Ni3S2/Fe3O4, with a heterogeneous interfacial structure, modulates the chemisorption of reaction intermediates on the catalyst surface, optimizing the Gibbs free energies (&#916;G) of oxygen-containing intermediates. The synergistic effect between the two active materials within the heterogeneous structure enhances OER catalytic performance. This finding offers a valuable approach to designing efficient and stable OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jing Mei, Yu Deng, Xiaohong Cheng, Qi Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.01.072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Ru&#8208;O Bonding Interactions by Ir Doping Boosts the Acid Oxygen Evolution Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301222</link>
      <description>Jianxin Zeng, Zhengxin Qian, Qing-Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Hua Zhang, Jianfeng Li, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390615127

                Highly active and stable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts are crucial for the large&#8208;scale application of proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers. However, the dynamic reconfiguration of the catalyst surface structure and active centers is still undefined, which greatly hinders the development and application of efficient OER catalysts. Herein, we report an IrRuOx/C catalyst with a facile low&#8208;temperature synthesis route, which can reach 10 mA cm&#8208;2 at an overpotential of 217 mV with a Tafel slope as low as 39.4 mV dec&#8208;1, and yields a mass activity 61 times that of commercial IrO2/C at an overpotential of 300 mV. The lattice oxygen structure of RuOx is stabilized by the introduction of Ir species, thus greatly promoting the OER activity and durability. Further in situ Raman reveals that RuOx emerges as the active species at high potentials, and Ru&#8208;O bonding interactions are enhanced with Ir regulation, stabilizing the solvation of Ru at high potentials and accelerating the nucleophilic attack of water molecules, leading to the improved OER performance. This work deepens the fundamental understanding of OER and offers an effective way to advance the utilization of Ru&#8208;based OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Jianxin Zeng, Zhengxin Qian, Qing-Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Hua Zhang, Jianfeng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202301222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polypyrrole-wrapped Hofmann type metal&#8211;organic framework nanoflowers to boost oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.124559</link>
      <description>Yuhang Wu, Yuwen Li, Ling Shen, Quanwen Pan, Ye Tao, Junkuo Gao, Journal of Solid State Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390843720

                The exploration of efficient and stable metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has received increasing attention. However, the limited electronic conductivity of MOFs hinders the electron transfer rate. Herein, we report the preparation of conducting polypyrrole (PPy)-modified MOF nanoflowers (MOF-NFs@PPy) as promising electrocatalysts for OER. The PPy layer significantly increases the electrical conductivity and modulates the ionic transmittance between MOF-NFs and the electrolyte. The interaction of PPy with the MOF-NFs modifies the electronic structure and improves the reaction efficiency at the active sites. The obtained MOF-NFs@PPy exhibits excellent electrocatalytic activity with an OER overpotential of only 218 mV@10 mA cm&#8722;2 and small Tafel slope of 47.4 mV dec&#8722;1. In addition, the MOF-NFs@PPy exhibited excellent long-term stability (&gt;24 h). This work may provide a new idea and a novel construction strategy for MOFs to improve OER performance.</description>
      <author>Yuhang Wu, Yuwen Li, Ling Shen, Quanwen Pan, Ye Tao, Junkuo Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.124559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-based CoSe/CoO heterostructure: A catalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.12.278</link>
      <description>Muhammad Sohail, Muhammad Ayyob, Anjie Wang, Zhichao Sun, Asad Syed, Abdallah M. Elgorban, Ali H. Bahkali, Rustem Zairov, Iqbal Ahmad, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390580498

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muhammad Sohail, Muhammad Ayyob, Anjie Wang, Zhichao Sun, Asad Syed, Abdallah M. Elgorban, Ali H. Bahkali, Rustem Zairov, Iqbal Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2023.12.278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic stabilization of nickel-based oxygen evolution electrocatalysts in the presence of chloride ions using a phosphate additive</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta05566c</link>
      <description>Hiroki Komiya, Keisuke Obata, Tetsuo Honma, Kazuhiro Takanabe, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4390796596

                The phosphate stabilizes Ni and borate maintains an appropriate pH for durable oxygen evolution, even with Cl &#8722; .</description>
      <author>Hiroki Komiya, Keisuke Obata, Tetsuo Honma, Kazuhiro Takanabe</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta05566c</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
