<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:59:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction catalysis with polythiophene-based composite electrodes incorporating NiCo-LDH and NiCo2S4</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.226</link>
      <description>Rahadian Zainul, Ali Basem, Dheyaa J. Jasim, Subhash Chandra, Julio Cesar L&#243;pez Ayala, Mohammed Al&#8208;Bahrani, Nizomiddin Juraev, Mamata Chahar, Yasser Elmasry, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 81(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400900759

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rahadian Zainul, Ali Basem, Dheyaa J. Jasim, Subhash Chandra, Julio Cesar L&#243;pez Ayala, Mohammed Al&#8208;Bahrani, Nizomiddin Juraev, Mamata Chahar, Yasser Elmasry</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two&#8208;Dimensional MXene&#8208;Based Electrocatalysts: Challenges and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400047</link>
      <description>Muhammad Kaleem Shabbir, Fozia Arif, Haleema Asghar, Sanam Irum Memon, Urooj Khanum, Javeed Akhtar, Akbar Ali, Zeeshan Ramzan, Abdul Aziz Abdul Raman, Ayaz Ali Memon, Khalid Hussain Thebo, The Chemical Record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400901939

                Abstract MXene, regarded as cutting&#8208;edge two&#8208;dimensional (2D) materials, have been widely explored in various applications due to their remarkable flexibility, high specific surface area, good mechanical strength, and interesting electrical conductivity. Recently, 2D MXene has served as a ideal platform for the design and development of electrocatalysts with high activity, selectivity, and stability. This review article provides a detailed description of the structural engineering of MXene&#8208;based electrocatalysts and summarizes the uses of 2D MXene in hydrogen evolution reactions, nitrogen reduction reactions, oxygen evolution reactions, oxygen reduction reactions, and methanol/ethanol oxidation. Then, key issues and prospects for 2D MXene as a next&#8208;generation platform in fundamental research and real&#8208;world electrocatalysis applications are discussed. Emphasis will be given to material design and enhancement techniques. Finally, future research directions are suggested to improve the efficiency of MXene&#8208;based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Kaleem Shabbir, Fozia Arif, Haleema Asghar, Sanam Irum Memon, Urooj Khanum, Javeed Akhtar, Akbar Ali, Zeeshan Ramzan, Abdul Aziz Abdul Raman, Ayaz Ali Memon, Khalid Hussain Thebo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/tcr.202400047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoNi alloy catalyzed N-doped carbon nanotube-anchored CoMn2O4 as highly efficient oxygen electrocatalysts for rechargeable Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112976</link>
      <description>Zhe Xiong, Zheng Zhang, Xiaoxue Jiang, Yan Li, Cuiqin Li, Keliang Wang, Journal of Energy Storage. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400904179

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhe Xiong, Zheng Zhang, Xiaoxue Jiang, Yan Li, Cuiqin Li, Keliang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112976</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Facets&#8208;Activity Correlation for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Compositional Complex Alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202404095</link>
      <description>Hongwei Zhao, J.Q. Yao, Ya&#8208;Song Wang, Gao Niu, Tao Zhang, Li Li, Yuyao Liu, Zheng&#8208;Jie Chen, Jing Peng, Xinwang Liu, Hai&#8208;Bin Yu, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400905267

                Compositional complex alloys, including high and medium-entropy alloys (HEAs/MEAs) have displayed significant potential as efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), but their structure-activity relationship remains unclear. In particular, the basic question of which crystal facets are more active, especially considering the surface reconstructions, has yet to be answered. This study demonstrates that the lowest index {100} facets of FeCoNiCr MEAs exhibit the highest activity. The underlying mechanism associated with the {100} facet's low in-plane density, making it easier to surface reconstruction and form amorphous structures containing the true active species is uncovered. These results are validated by experiments on single crystals and polycrystal MEAs, as well as DFT calculations. The discoveries contribute to a fundamental comprehension of MEAs in electrocatalysis and offer physics-based strategies for developing electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Hongwei Zhao, J.Q. Yao, Ya&#8208;Song Wang, Gao Niu, Tao Zhang, Li Li, Yuyao Liu, Zheng&#8208;Jie Chen, Jing Peng, Xinwang Liu, Hai&#8208;Bin Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202404095</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pilot Study on the Production of Negative Oxygen Ions Based on Lower Voltage Ionization Method and Application in Air Purification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15070860</link>
      <description>Haotian Weng, Yao-Zhong Zhang, Xiaolu Huang, Xuan Liu, Yunhui Tang, Hewei Yuan, Xu Yang, Kun Li, Yafei Zhang, Atmosphere. 15(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400905982

                In the current highly industrialized living environment, air quality has become an increasing public health concern. Natural environments like forests have excellent air quality due to high concentrations of negative oxygen ions originating from low-voltage ionization, without harmful ozone. Traditional negative oxygen ion generators require high voltage for corona discharge to produce ions. However, high voltage can increase electron collisions and excitations, leading to more dissociation and recombination of oxygen molecules and consequently higher ozone production. To address the challenge of generating negative oxygen ions without accompanying ozone production, this study designed and constructed a low-voltage negative oxygen ion generator based on nanometer-tip carbon fiber electrodes. The advantage of this device lies in the high curvature radius of carbon fibers, which provides high local electric field strength. This allows for efficient production of negative oxygen ions at low operating voltages without generating ozone. Experiments demonstrated that the device can efficiently generate negative oxygen ions at a working voltage as low as 2.16 kV, 28% lower than the lowest voltage reported in similar studies. The purification device manufactured in this study had a total decay constant for PM2.5 purification of 0.8967 min&#8722;1 within five minutes, compared to a natural decay constant of only 0.0438 min&#8722;1, resulting in a calculated Clean Air Delivery Rate (CADR) of 0.1535 m3/min. Within half an hour, concentrations of PM2.5, PM1, PM10, formaldehyde, and TVOC were reduced by 99.09%, 99.40%, 99.37%, 94.39%, and 99.35%, respectively, demonstrating good decay constants and CADR. These findings confirm its effectiveness in improving indoor air quality, highlighting its significant application value in air purification.</description>
      <author>Haotian Weng, Yao-Zhong Zhang, Xiaolu Huang, Xuan Liu, Yunhui Tang, Hewei Yuan, Xu Yang, Kun Li, Yafei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/atmos15070860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural engineering evoked multifunctionality in molybdate nanosheets for industrial oxygen evolution and dual energy storage devices inspired by multi-method calculations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.128</link>
      <description>Mengru Huang, Haiyu Yao, Feng Cao, Peijie Wang, Xue&#8208;Rong Shi, Min Zhang, Shusheng Xu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 676(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400906452

                Structural engineering, including electronic and geometric modulations, is a good approach to improve the activity of electrocatalysts. Herein, we employed FeOOH and the second metal center Ni to modulate the electronic structure of CoMoO</description>
      <author>Mengru Huang, Haiyu Yao, Feng Cao, Peijie Wang, Xue&#8208;Rong Shi, Min Zhang, Shusheng Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robust Nanoporous NiMn oxide Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction through Defect Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02679a</link>
      <description>Arpit Thomas, Ambrish Kumar, Ram K. Sharma, Edgar C. Buck, Bharat Gwalani, Meha Bhogra, Harpreet Singh Arora, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400913184

                The sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a major bottleneck in hydrogen generation through electrolysis, particularly at large current operations. Thus, there is a huge interest in the development of...</description>
      <author>Arpit Thomas, Ambrish Kumar, Ram K. Sharma, Edgar C. Buck, Bharat Gwalani, Meha Bhogra, Harpreet Singh Arora</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02679a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of morphology and charge transfer mechanism: Oxygen vacancy-rich Mn0.2Cd0.8S/CoMoO4 S-type heterojunction promoting photocatalytic hydrogen production through hydrothermal in-situ synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175692</link>
      <description>Yan Shang, Jing Xu, Jia Li, Mingxia Zheng, Xutao Ning, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400913998

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yan Shang, Jing Xu, Jia Li, Mingxia Zheng, Xutao Ning</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175692</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnesium-promoted rapid self-reconstruction of NiFe-based electrocatalysts toward efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.183</link>
      <description>Boxuan Jin, Wenwen Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Kai Zhang, Li Wang, Guihua Liu, Jingde Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400914862

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boxuan Jin, Wenwen Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Kai Zhang, Li Wang, Guihua Liu, Jingde Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>State-of-the-Art In Situ Technologies for Unravelling the Dynamic Structure Evolution during Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03623</link>
      <description>Qinglei Meng, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, Jianbing Zhu, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400915861

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qinglei Meng, Meiling Xiao, Changpeng Liu, Wei Xing, Jianbing Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c03623</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Empowering multicomponent alloys with unique nanostructure for exceptional oxygen evolution performance through self-replenishment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.023</link>
      <description>Zhibin Li, Ruoyu Wu, Dabo Duan, Xiongjun Liu, Rui Li, Jing Wang, Houwen Chen, Shiwei Chen, Yuan Wu, Hai Wang, Suihe Jiang, Xiaobin Zhang, Xiongjun Liu, Joule. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400916666

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhibin Li, Ruoyu Wu, Dabo Duan, Xiongjun Liu, Rui Li, Jing Wang, Houwen Chen, Shiwei Chen, Yuan Wu, Hai Wang, Suihe Jiang, Xiaobin Zhang, Xiongjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.joule.2024.06.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Impact of Morphology and Oxygen Vacancy Content in Ni, Fe co-doped Ceria for Efficient Electrocatalyst Based Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00500g</link>
      <description>Abhaya Kumar Mishra, Joshua Willoughby, Shanna L. Estes, Kelliann Koehler, Kyle S. Brinkman, Nanoscale Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400917039

                Designing a highly efficient, low-cost, sustainable electrocatalyst for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) through water splitting is a current challenge for renewable energy technologies. This...</description>
      <author>Abhaya Kumar Mishra, Joshua Willoughby, Shanna L. Estes, Kelliann Koehler, Kyle S. Brinkman</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4na00500g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating Metal-Oxygen Covalency of Tio2 by Ru Doping and Phase Transition for Boosted Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902818</link>
      <description>Fengting Li, Nannan Cui, Yanan Zhou, Shuangqing Sun, Chunling Li, Zhikun Wang, Songqing Hu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400917844

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengting Li, Nannan Cui, Yanan Zhou, Shuangqing Sun, Chunling Li, Zhikun Wang, Songqing Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902818</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poly(3&#8208;hexylthiophene) film coated on plastic substrate as an organic photoanode for water oxidation/oxygen evolution with light illumination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/pat.6524</link>
      <description>H. Shinohara, Hiroyuki Nishide, Polymers for Advanced Technologies. 35(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400921986

                Abstract Poly(3&#8208;hexylthiophene) (P3HT) film was applied as a photoanode on an electron&#8208;extracting layer&#8208;coated upon a current&#8208;collecting plastic substrate. The film soaked in an aqueous solution (pH 12) exhibited an enhanced anodic current with light illumination, and the photocurrent density ( J ) reached almost 100 &#956;A/cm 2 for its wound cylinder, which was accompanied by oxygen bubble evolution. The light ON/OFF response, light&#8208;intensity proportion, and wavelength&#8208;dependency of the J value supported the photo&#8208;electrolytic function of the P3HT film. The hole&#8208;injection efficiency of the film estimated for water oxidation using a solution involving a sacrificial reagent, was relatively high in the range of 46%&#8211;86%. Although an apparent activation energy of 39 kJ/mol for the electrolytic water oxidation in the dark suggested a chemical but catalytic pathway for the film anode, the temperature independence of the photocurrent indicated direct hole&#8208;injection into water or hydroxide ions. The photoanode performance of the P3HT film for water oxidation was discussed in relation to the energy diagram including the highest occupied molecular orbital level.</description>
      <author>H. Shinohara, Hiroyuki Nishide</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/pat.6524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low-Crystalline Cobalt Iron Oxide-Supported Single Ru Atoms and Ru Clusters for 2,5-Hydroxymethylfurfural Electro-Oxidation Coupled with Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03806</link>
      <description>Shasha Cui, Fen Wang, Guangjin Wang, Tingting Li, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400925789

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shasha Cui, Fen Wang, Guangjin Wang, Tingting Li, Zhijuan Liu, Yanyong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insulator&#8208;transition&#8208;induced Degradation of Pyrochlore Ruthenates in Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution and Stabilization through Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412139</link>
      <description>Haibo Liu, Hengyu Guo, Qingren Zhang, Masatsugu Fujishige, Morinobu Endo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400930376

                Ru&#8208;based pyrochlores (e.g., Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d) are promised to replace IrO2 in polymer electrolyte membrane (PEM) electrolyzers. It is significant to reveal the cliff attenuation on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of these pyrochlores. In this work, we monitor the structure changes and electrochemical behavior of Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d over the OER process, and it is found that the reason of decisive OER inactivation is derived from an insulator transition occurred within Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d due to its inner &#178;perfecting&#178; lattice induced by continuous atom rearrangement. Therefore, a stabilization strategy of the Ir&#8208;substituted Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d is proposed to alleviate this undesirable behavior. The double&#8208;exchange interaction between Ru and Ir in [RuO6] and [IrO6] octahedra leads the charge redistribution with simultaneous spin configuration adjustment. The electronic state in newly formed octahedrons centered with Ru 4d3 (with the state of eg'2&#173;&#173;a1g&#173;1 eg0) and Ir 5d6 (eg'4a1g&#173;2 eg0) relieves the uneven electron distributions in [RuO6] orbital. The attenuated Jahn&#8208;Teller effect alleviates atom rearrangement, represented as the mitigation of insulator transition, surface reconstruction, and metal dissolution. As results, the Ir&#8208;substituted Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d presents the greatly improved OER stability and PEM durability. This study unveils the OER degradation mechanism and stabilization strategy for material design of Ru&#8208;based OER catalysts for electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Haibo Liu, Hengyu Guo, Qingren Zhang, Masatsugu Fujishige, Morinobu Endo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insulator&#8208;transition&#8208;induced Degradation of Pyrochlore Ruthenates in Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution and Stabilization through Doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412139</link>
      <description>Haibo Liu, Hengyu Guo, Qingren Zhang, Masatsugu Fujishige, Morinobu Endo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400930451

                Ru&#8208;based pyrochlores (e.g., Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d) are promised to replace IrO2 in polymer electrolyte membrane (PEM) electrolyzers. It is significant to reveal the cliff attenuation on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of these pyrochlores. In this work, we monitor the structure changes and electrochemical behavior of Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d over the OER process, and it is found that the reason of decisive OER inactivation is derived from an insulator transition occurred within Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d due to its inner &#178;perfecting&#178; lattice induced by continuous atom rearrangement. Therefore, a stabilization strategy of the Ir&#8208;substituted Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d is proposed to alleviate this undesirable behavior. The double&#8208;exchange interaction between Ru and Ir in [RuO6] and [IrO6] octahedra leads the charge redistribution with simultaneous spin configuration adjustment. The electronic state in newly formed octahedrons centered with Ru 4d3 (with the state of eg'2&#173;&#173;a1g&#173;1 eg0) and Ir 5d6 (eg'4a1g&#173;2 eg0) relieves the uneven electron distributions in [RuO6] orbital. The attenuated Jahn&#8208;Teller effect alleviates atom rearrangement, represented as the mitigation of insulator transition, surface reconstruction, and metal dissolution. As results, the Ir&#8208;substituted Y2Ru2O7&#8211;d presents the greatly improved OER stability and PEM durability. This study unveils the OER degradation mechanism and stabilization strategy for material design of Ru&#8208;based OER catalysts for electrochemical applications.</description>
      <author>Haibo Liu, Hengyu Guo, Qingren Zhang, Masatsugu Fujishige, Morinobu Endo, Zhengping Zhang, Feng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Ni-Doped Dual Mof-Derived Urchin-Like Co-Fe Layered Double Hydroxides for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902826</link>
      <description>Zikang Tang, Ningzhao Shang, Mingjie Hu, Huan Wang, Yufan Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400932947

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zikang Tang, Ningzhao Shang, Mingjie Hu, Huan Wang, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4902826</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Transition Metals (Mn, Co, Ni, and Zn) in Size-Controlled Metal Ferrite Nanocrystals on the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03007</link>
      <description>Vijayakrishnan Jeyavani, Shanmugasundaram Manoj, Shatabdi Porel Mukherjee, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400935288

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Vijayakrishnan Jeyavani, Shanmugasundaram Manoj, Shatabdi Porel Mukherjee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c03007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe,Ce Co&#8208;Doped Ni3S2/NiS Polymorphism Nanosheets with Improved Electrocatalytic Activity and Stability for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400896</link>
      <description>Shaoxia Wang, Huihui Li, Shifeng Li, Yonghong Ni, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400936838

                Balancing the relationship between electrocatalytic activity and stability of sulfide catalysts during oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been attracting extensive research interest. Here, a simple electrodeposition&#8208;vulcanization two&#8208;step route was designed to successfully construct nickel foam supported sheet&#8208;like Fe,Ce&#8208;codoped Ni3S2/NiS polymorphism catalyst (labeled as Fe,Ce&#8208;Ni3S2/NiS/NF). Electrochemical measurements showed that the as&#8208;obtained Fe,Ce&#8208;Ni3S2/NiS/NF electrode presented excellent OER electrocatalytic performances. In 1 M KOH solution, merely 173 and 234 mV of overpotentials were required to deliver the current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8208;2, respectively. Further investigations revealed that the Fe,Ce co&#8208;doping regulated the electron density around Ni, which promoted the conversion of Ni towards the higher valence state and simultaneously, avoided the stability decrease of the catalyst caused by excessive oxidation corrosion. Moreover, the defects generated during vulcanization also contributed to promoting water oxidation. The present work provides a facile and feasible approach to balance the relationship between the stability and the activity of sulfide catalysts for OER.</description>
      <author>Shaoxia Wang, Huihui Li, Shifeng Li, Yonghong Ni</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400896</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen deficient BaTiO3 loading sub-nm PtOx for photocatalytic biological wastewater splitting to green hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154261</link>
      <description>Guilin Chen, Yujin Ji, Xintong Shi, Pengfei An, Jing Zhang, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400942716

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guilin Chen, Yujin Ji, Xintong Shi, Pengfei An, Jing Zhang, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt; Hydrogel with Immobilized Mn-Porphyrin for Reactive Oxygen Species Scavenging, Oxygen Generation, and Risedronate Delivery in Bone Defect Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08350</link>
      <description>Kim M, Soo Bin Yoon, Han Bi Ji, Cho Rim Kim, Jae Hoon Han, Sena Kim, Chang Hee Min, Chul Lee, Lan Sook Chang, Young Bin Choy, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400948237

                We propose a hydrogel immobilized with manganese porphyrin (MnP), a biomimetic superoxide dismutase (SOD), and catalase (CAT) to modulate reactive oxygen species (ROS) and hypoxia that impede the repair of large bone defects. Our hydrogel synthesis involved thiolated chitosan and polyethylene glycol-maleimide conjugated with MnPs (MnP-PEG-MAL), which enabled</description>
      <author>Kim M, Soo Bin Yoon, Han Bi Ji, Cho Rim Kim, Jae Hoon Han, Sena Kim, Chang Hee Min, Chul Lee, Lan Sook Chang, Young Bin Choy</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium oxide supported molybdenum-nickel-iron oxide electrocatalyst for efficient and durable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132509</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Xiangchao Meng, Haisheng Han, Guihua Liu, Fuel. 375(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400952027

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Xiangchao Meng, Haisheng Han, Guihua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132509</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Efficiency Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Effect of Phosphorus Doped on the Surface Reconstruction of High-Entropy Spinel Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175696</link>
      <description>Ziming Bai, Ghulam Mustafa, Zhe Zhang, Changgong Meng, Yuzhen Pan, Zhen Chen, Wei Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400953696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziming Bai, Ghulam Mustafa, Zhe Zhang, Changgong Meng, Yuzhen Pan, Zhen Chen, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cofe-Ldhs Were Grown on Co-Layered Hydroxides to Achieve 3d-Hierarchical Flower Like Architecture for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4903722</link>
      <description>Haibo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Gao Y, Huan Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400966452

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibo Liu, Yufan Zhang, Ningzhao Shang, Gao Y, Huan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4903722</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Electrocatalytic Activity of Cobalt Oxide with Bismuth for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02845g</link>
      <description>Tewodros Asefa, Belvin Thomas, Bowen Peng, Xiaoxi Huang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400970409

                Highly durable, low-cost electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are very essential for the commercial success of proton exchange membrane-based water electrolysis. The catalysts currently available for this reaction...</description>
      <author>Tewodros Asefa, Belvin Thomas, Bowen Peng, Xiaoxi Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02845g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru Single-Atom Nanoarchitectonics on Co-Based Conducting Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02804</link>
      <description>Ruyu Xue, Zhe Chuan Feng, Yantao Wang, Junfeng Huang, Wei Dou, Cailing Xu, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400971488

                The development of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is essential for the production of green hydrogen from water electrolysis, but it is challenging. Herein, ruthenium (Ru) single-atom-modified Co-HHTP (HHTP = 2,3,6,7,10,11-hexahydroxytriphenylene) (Ru@Co-HHTP) was prepared via a solvothermal and ion exchange method. Systematic experiments highlight that the atomically dispersed Ru can optimize the electronic structure and electronic conductivity of Co-HHTP. As a result, the obtained Ru@Co-HHTP shows a low overpotential of 247 mV at 100 mA cm</description>
      <author>Ruyu Xue, Zhe Chuan Feng, Yantao Wang, Junfeng Huang, Wei Dou, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02804</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Regulation of NiFe LDH under Spontaneous Corrosion to Enhance the Oxygen Evolution Properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400640</link>
      <description>Yingjun Ma, Hangning Liu, Lin Wang, Changhui Sun, Liangyu Gong, Jie Wang, Jiangmin Jiang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400977781

                Electrochemical water splitting holds promise for sustainable hydrogen production but restricted by the sluggish reaction kinetics at the anodic oxygen evolution. Herein, we present a room-temperature spontaneous corrosion strategy to convert inexpensive iron (Fe) on iron foam substrates into highly active and stable self-supporting nickel iron layered hydroxide (NiFe LDH) catalysts. The corrosion evolution mechanisms are elucidated combining ex-situ scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and X-ray photo electron spectroscopy (XPS) techniques, demonstrating precise control over the concentration of Ni2+ and reaction time to achieve controllable micro-structures of NiFe LDH. Taking advantage of the self-supporting morphology and hierarchical micro-/nano- structure, the NiFe LDH with optimized Ni2+ concentration and reaction time exhibits significant small overpotentials of 160 mV and 200 mV for the OER at current densities of 10 mA cm-2 and 100 mA cm-2 respectively, showcasing excellent OER activities. Furthermore, this catalyst demonstrates superior reaction kinetics, high electrochemical stability, and excellent integral water splitting performance when coupled with a commercial Pt/C cathode. The energy-efficient, cost-effective, and scalable spontaneous corrosion strategy opens new avenues for the development of high-electrochemical-interface catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yingjun Ma, Hangning Liu, Lin Wang, Changhui Sun, Liangyu Gong, Jie Wang, Jiangmin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating Dual-Metal Catalytic Activities toward Organic Upgrading in Upcycling Plastic Wastes with Inhibited Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04219</link>
      <description>Dengke Xiong, Xiaoyang He, Xuan Liu, Kaiyan Zhang, Zhentao Tu, Jianying Wang, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun, Zuofeng Chen, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400978536

                Electrorefinery of polybutylene terephthalate (PBT) waste plastic, specifically conversion of a PBT-derived 1,4-butanediol (BDO) monomer into value-added succinate coupled with H</description>
      <author>Dengke Xiong, Xiaoyang He, Xuan Liu, Kaiyan Zhang, Zhentao Tu, Jianying Wang, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun, Zuofeng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c04219</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High performance oxygen reduction and evolution reactions by graphitization of nickel &#8211;cobalt framework system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.309</link>
      <description>Karim Kakaei, A. Rahmati, Mohammad Ghadiri, Fatemeh Asgharnezhad, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 81(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400981045

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karim Kakaei, A. Rahmati, Mohammad Ghadiri, Fatemeh Asgharnezhad</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper dopants facilitated generation of high-valent cobalt sites for improved oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01507j</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Jieshu Zhou, Hao Zhang, Haibin Wang, Kangning Liu, Xuhui Sun, Lihua Liu, Hongyan Liang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400982018

                Developing a reliable strategy to adjust dynamic reconstruction and formation of active oxygen species on electrocatalyst surfaces is crucial for enhancing OER performance and still needs further elaborate elucidation. Here,...</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Jieshu Zhou, Hao Zhang, Haibin Wang, Kangning Liu, Xuhui Sun, Lihua Liu, Hongyan Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01507j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ evolution of bulk-active &#947;-CoOOH with immobilized Gd dopants enabling an efficient oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01743a</link>
      <description>Tianjue Hou, Ruotao Yang, Jiaxin Xu, Xiaodie He, Hongyuan Yang, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400986166

                Promoting the in-situ reconstruction of transition metal (TM)-based precatalysts into low-crystalline and well-modified TM (oxy)hydroxides (TMOxHy) during alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for enhancing their catalytic performances. In...</description>
      <author>Tianjue Hou, Ruotao Yang, Jiaxin Xu, Xiaodie He, Hongyuan Yang, Prashanth W. Menezes, Ziliang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01743a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface oxygen engineered ZnCo2O4 planar hybrid supercapacitor electrode for high energy applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112954</link>
      <description>Muthukumar Ganesan, Srinivasan Alagar, Vivek Bagchi, Shakkthivel Piraman, Journal of Energy Storage. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400986943

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Muthukumar Ganesan, Srinivasan Alagar, Vivek Bagchi, Shakkthivel Piraman</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.112954</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron doping enhances ZIF-67 based hierarchical carbon bifunction catalyst for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113004</link>
      <description>Kanjun Sun, Xiaofei Lei, Xuan Xie, Wenjuan Li, Wenbo Hou, Hui Peng, Guofu Ma, Journal of Energy Storage. 98(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400986969

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kanjun Sun, Xiaofei Lei, Xuan Xie, Wenjuan Li, Wenbo Hou, Hui Peng, Guofu Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Built-in electric field construction and lattice oxygen activation for boosting alkaline electrochemical water/seawater oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154279</link>
      <description>Xinyu Wang, Xu Yu, Pinyi He, Guohui Yang, Fu Qin, Yongkang Yao, Lili Ren, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401002555

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyu Wang, Xu Yu, Pinyi He, Guohui Yang, Fu Qin, Yongkang Yao, Lili Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Ru&#8208;Au&#8208;Mn Trimetallic Nanostructure for High&#8208;Performance Acidic Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400751</link>
      <description>Minna Cao, Yuhang Zhang, Shuai Yue, Jun Liang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401006709

                Developing highly efficient and stable electrocatalysts in acidic media is essential for proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs). Especially for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), high overpotential is needed to overcome the high thermodynamic energy barrier of water splitting. Herein, we report a high&#8208;efficiency self&#8208;supported ternary alloy OER catalyst with high activity and good durability in acidic electrolytes by a simple electrodeposition method. The as&#8208;prepared electrocatalyst consists of Ru, Au, and Mn alloy which is deposited on the carbon fiber paper (denoted as RuAuMn&#8208;CFP). The RuAuMn&#8208;CFP exhibits superior activity and only requires an overpotential of 131 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and outstanding stability of 30 h (10 mA cm&#8722;2) in acidic media, which outperforms the commercial Ru/C and Ir/C catalysts. Besides, at an overpotential of 140 mV, the RuAuMn&#8208;CFP catalyst exhibited a remarkable mass activity of 29.63 mA/mg for OER. It is 7.9 times and 23.8 times higher than the commercial Ru/C and Ir/C catalysts (3.73 mA/mg, 1.24 mA/mg, respectively).</description>
      <author>Minna Cao, Yuhang Zhang, Shuai Yue, Jun Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hexavalent iridium boosts oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.greenca.2024.07.003</link>
      <description>Mengtian Huo, Y. T. Liang, Kaichi Qin, Guanzhi Wang, Zihao Xing, Jinfa Chang, Green Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401014289

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengtian Huo, Y. T. Liang, Kaichi Qin, Guanzhi Wang, Zihao Xing, Jinfa Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.greenca.2024.07.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium Dioxide Induced Nickel-iron Alloy-based Precatalyst towards Efficient and Durable Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175729</link>
      <description>Ran Qiao, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Hongtao Bai, Xiangchao Meng, Jingde Li, Guihua Liu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401025947

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ran Qiao, Kai Zhang, Shuaichong Wei, Hongtao Bai, Xiangchao Meng, Jingde Li, Guihua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying Stern Layer Water Alignment Prior to and During the Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2023-m9d1z-v4</link>
      <description>Raiden Speelman, Franz M. Geiger, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401026900

                While water's oxygen is the electron source in the industrially important oxygen evolution reaction, the strong absorber problem clouds our view of how the Stern layer water molecules orient themselves in response to applied potentials. Here, we report nonlinear optical measurements on nickel electrodes held at pH 13 indicating a disorder-to-order transition in the Stern layer water molecules prior to the onset of Faradaic current. A full water monolater (1.1 x 10^15 cm-2) aligns with oxygen atoms pointing towards the electrode at +0.8 V and the associated work is 80 kJ mol-1. Our experiments identify water flipping energetics as a target for understanding overpotentials, advance molecular electrochemistry, provide benchmarks for electrical double layer models, and serve as a diagnostic tool for understanding electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Raiden Speelman, Franz M. Geiger</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2023-m9d1z-v4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimal Doping Approach to Activate Lattice Oxygen Participation in K2WO4 Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124423</link>
      <description>Selvaraj Seenivasan, M. H. Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401027067

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Selvaraj Seenivasan, M. H. Kim, Jeong Woo Han, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-deficient annealing boosts performance of CoNiFe oxide electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115675</link>
      <description>Thi-Thu-Hien Pham, Michaela Plevov&#225;, Stephan Bartling, Nils Rockstroh, Armin Springer, Adam Slabon, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke, Journal of Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401032956

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Thi-Thu-Hien Pham, Michaela Plevov&#225;, Stephan Bartling, Nils Rockstroh, Armin Springer, Adam Slabon, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Annette&#8208;Enrica Surkus, Robert Francke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115675</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cation-Triggered Growth of Nanowires for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02315</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Weiying Ye, Zhilin Zhang, Yuan&#8208;Zhao Hua, Chenyang Cai, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Wenshu Yang, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401034705

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which occurs in a variety of energy-related devices, necessitates optimization of the reaction pathways for efficient and scalable deployment. Nevertheless, fully harnessing the advanced structure of synthetic electrocatalysts remains a significant challenge due to the inevitable surface reconstruction process during OER. Here we present an efficient and flexible method to control the surface reconstruction process by engineering an electrolyte containing trace Co</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Weiying Ye, Zhilin Zhang, Yuan&#8208;Zhao Hua, Chenyang Cai, Zhenghao Zhang, Yitian Wu, Kui Wang, Wenshu Yang, Weidong Shi, Jinhui Hao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02315</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core&#8211;Shell Co&#8208;Co&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;P Nanoparticle&#8208;Embedded N&#8208;Doped Carbon Nanowhiskers Hollow Sphere for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409390</link>
      <description>Wei Zhu, Wenhui Hu, Ying Wei, Yongcai Zhang, Kunming Pan, Songtao Zhang, Xinxin Hang, Mingbo Zheng, Huan Pang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401035151

                Abstract The development of efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is critical to overcome the efficiency bottleneck in hydrogen generation via water electrolysis. Hollow nanostructured materials have emerged as a hot topic for electrocatalysis research because of their advantages, including abundant active sites, a large contact area between the catalyst and the electrolyte, and a short transmission path. As highly efficient and stable OER electrocatalysts, cobalt&#8208;based nanostructured materials have attracted more and more attention. In this work, cobalt metal/cobalt phosphides/nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon composites (Co&#8208;Co x P/NC) with a hierarchical hollow structure are designed by using hollow ZIF&#8208;67 microspheres as precursors. By coating ZIF&#8208;8 on the surface of hollow ZIF&#8208;67 microspheres and further carbonizing, carbon nanowhiskers are successfully formed on the surface of hollow carbon spheres under the catalytic effect of Co nanoparticles at a high temperature. In the subsequent phosphating process, solid Co nanocrystalline particles are transformed into core&#8211;shell CoP and Co 2 P nanoparticles on account of the Kirkendall effect. Through the optimization of the microstructure of the material and the synergistic effect of transition metal, transition metal phosphide, and nitrogen doping, the overpotential of the optimal material is only 287 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 current density in 1 m KOH.</description>
      <author>Wei Zhu, Wenhui Hu, Ying Wei, Yongcai Zhang, Kunming Pan, Songtao Zhang, Xinxin Hang, Mingbo Zheng, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409390</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Different N/C Coordination Electronic Structures on the Activity of Bifunctional Rare-Earth Ytterbium Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01797</link>
      <description>Tao Xu, Daomiao Wang, Qiming Fu, Chao Liu, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401035209

                The research and development of bifunctional electrocatalysts for the oxygen electrode is of great significance to solve the problem of electrochemical energy. Herein, the effect of different structure-activity relationships on the performance of YbN</description>
      <author>Tao Xu, Daomiao Wang, Qiming Fu, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeNi&#8208;LDH COATED WITH ORANGE&#8208;PEEL CARBON AEROGEL FOR OXYGEN EVOLUTION REACTION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401276</link>
      <description>Hai Jia, Peng-Cheng Ji, Yang Teng, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401038504

                In this work, the waste orange-peel was used as carbon source, and the orange-peel derived carbon material can be obtained through simple pyrolysis. Then, we designed the structure of orange-peel carbon aerogel grown on iron-nickel layered double hydroxides in situ to achieve the effect of carbon coating (FeNi-LDH/CA). The oxygen evolution reaction catalytic performance of FeNi-LDH/CA is excellent, far exceeding that of commercial RuO2. In 1 M KOH, the overpotential of FeNi-LDH/CA is only 250 mV (10 mA cm-2), obviously better than that of commercial RuO2 (295 mV). FeNi-LDH/CA shows good cycling stability, and after long-term i-t testing, the performance only decays by 3% after running at 100 mA cm-2 for 100 h. When used as an anode, the voltage of water-splitting is only 1.48 V at 10 mA cm-2. The rechargeable liquid zinc-air battery based on Pt/C-FeNi-LDH/CA catalyst has higher open-circuit voltage (1.543 V) and galvanostatic discharge capacity at 1.23 V (830 min, 10 mA cm-2). Moreover, the zinc-air battery based on Pt/C-FeNi-LDH/CA has a small charge-discharge voltage gap (0.65 V) at 10 mA cm-2, after 200 consecutive cycles (66 h), the charge-discharge voltage gap only increased by about 30 mV, indicating good cycling stability.</description>
      <author>Hai Jia, Peng-Cheng Ji, Yang Teng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401276</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selection of metal halide redox mediator suitable for lithium air battery by evaluating oxygen evolution efficiency</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.53619/kobs.2024.6.4.1.58</link>
      <description>Juhyoung Kim, Dongwook Kim, Journal of the Korean Battery Society. 4(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401040180

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juhyoung Kim, Dongwook Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.53619/kobs.2024.6.4.1.58</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Surface Reconstruction in Spinel Oxides via Tetrahedral&#8208;Octahedral Phase Boundary Construction for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409912</link>
      <description>Anqi Zou, Chao Wu, Qi Zhang, Ying Tang, Junhua Li, Hecheng Meng, Zhen Wang, Caozheng Diao, Zhi Gen Yu, Junmin Xue, Shibo Xi, Xiaopeng Wang, Jiagang Wu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400981749

                Understanding the origin of surface reconstruction is crucial for developing highly efficient lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) based spinel oxides. Traditionally, the reconstruction has been achieved through electrochemical procedures, such as cyclic voltammetry (CV), linear sweep voltammetry (LSV). In this work, we found that the surface reconstruction in LOM&#8208;based CoFe0.25Al1.75O4 catalyst was an irreversible oxygen redox chemical reaction. And a lower oxygen vacancy formation energy (EO&#8208;V) could benefit the combination of the activated lattice oxygen atoms with adsorbed water molecular. Motivated by this finding, a strategy of phase boundary construction from Co tetrahedral to octahedral was employed to decrease EO&#8208;V in CoFe0.25Al1.75O4. The results showed that as the Co octahedral occupancy ratio rose to 64%, a 3.5 nm&#8208;thick reconstructed layer formed on the catalyst surface with a 158 mV decrease in overpotential. Further experiments indicated that the coexistence of tetrahedral&#8208;octahedral (O&#8208;T) phase would result in lattice mismatch, promoting non&#8208;bonding oxygen states and lowering EO&#8208;V. Then more active lattice oxygen combined with H2O molecules to generate hydroxide ions (OH&#8208;), followed by soluble cation leaching, which enhanced the reconstruction process. This work provided new insights into the relationship between the intrinsic structure of pre&#8208;catalysts and surface reconstruction in LOM&#8208;based spinel electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Anqi Zou, Chao Wu, Qi Zhang, Ying Tang, Junhua Li, Hecheng Meng, Zhen Wang, Caozheng Diao, Zhi Gen Yu, Junmin Xue, Shibo Xi, Xiaopeng Wang, Jiagang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202409912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promoting Surface Reconstruction in Spinel Oxides via Tetrahedral&#8208;Octahedral Phase Boundary Construction for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409912</link>
      <description>Anqi Zou, Chao Wu, Qi Zhang, Ying Tang, Junhua Li, Hecheng Meng, Zhen Wang, Caozheng Diao, Zhi Gen Yu, Junmin Xue, Shibo Xi, Xiaopeng Wang, Jiagang Wu, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400981750

                Understanding the origin of surface reconstruction is crucial for developing highly efficient lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism (LOM) based spinel oxides. Traditionally, the reconstruction has been achieved through electrochemical procedures, such as cyclic voltammetry (CV), linear sweep voltammetry (LSV). In this work, we found that the surface reconstruction in LOM-based CoFe0.25Al1.75O4 catalyst was an irreversible oxygen redox chemical reaction. And a lower oxygen vacancy formation energy (EO-V) could benefit the combination of the activated lattice oxygen atoms with adsorbed water molecular. Motivated by this finding, a strategy of phase boundary construction from Co tetrahedral to octahedral was employed to decrease EO-V in CoFe0.25Al1.75O4. The results showed that as the Co octahedral occupancy ratio rose to 64%, a 3.5 nm-thick reconstructed layer formed on the catalyst surface with a 158 mV decrease in overpotential. Further experiments indicated that the coexistence of tetrahedral-octahedral (O-T) phase would result in lattice mismatch, promoting non-bonding oxygen states and lowering EO-V. Then more active lattice oxygen combined with H2O molecules to generate hydroxide ions (OH-), followed by soluble cation leaching, which enhanced the reconstruction process. This work provided new insights into the relationship between the intrinsic structure of pre-catalysts and surface reconstruction in LOM-based spinel electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Anqi Zou, Chao Wu, Qi Zhang, Ying Tang, Junhua Li, Hecheng Meng, Zhen Wang, Caozheng Diao, Zhi Gen Yu, Junmin Xue, Shibo Xi, Xiaopeng Wang, Jiagang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202409912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction activity of carbon aerogel supported Pd&#8211;Ni&#8211;Al catalysts synthesized by microwave irradiation method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.287</link>
      <description>A.M.P. Hussain, Muhammad Asim, Meryem Samanc&#305;, Naveed Kausar Janjua, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 81(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400900496

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A.M.P. Hussain, Muhammad Asim, Meryem Samanc&#305;, Naveed Kausar Janjua, Ay&#351;e Bayrak&#231;eken Yurtcan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the origins and evolution of oxygenic and anoxygenic photosynthesis in deeply branched Cyanobacteriota.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msae151</link>
      <description>Sha Tan, Lan Liu, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Mengmeng Li, Chao-Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yanling Qi, Yuxian Li, Yang-Zhi Rao, Yan-Ni Qu, Hongchen Jiang, Rochelle M. Soo, Paul N. Evans, Zheng-Shuang Hua, Wenjun Li, PubMed. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400932417

                Cyanobacteriota, the sole prokaryotes capable of oxygenic photosynthesis (OxyP), occupy a unique and pivotal role in Earth's history. While the notion that OxyP may have originated from Cyanobacteriota is widely accepted, its early evolution remains elusive. Here, by using both metagenomics and metatranscriptomics, we explore 36 metagenome-assembled genomes (MAGs) from hot spring ecosystems, belonging to two deep-branching cyanobacterial orders: Thermostichales and Gloeomargaritales. Functional investigation reveals that Thermostichales encode the crucial thylakoid membrane biogenesis protein, Vipp1. Based on the phylogenetic results, we infer that the evolution of the thylakoid membrane predates the divergence of Thermostichales from other cyanobacterial groups and that Thermostichales may be the most ancient lineage known to date to have inherited this feature from their common ancestor. Apart from OxyP, both lineages are potentially capable of sulfide-driven anoxygenic photosynthesis (AnoxyP) by linking sulfide oxidation to the photosynthetic electron transport chain. Unexpectedly, this AnoxyP capacity appears to be an acquired feature, as the key gene sqr was horizontally transferred from later-evolved cyanobacterial lineages. The presence of two D1 protein variants in Thermostichales suggests the functional flexibility of photosystems, ensuring their survival in fluctuating redox environments. Furthermore, all MAGs feature streamlined phycobilisomes with a preference for capturing longer-wavelength light, implying a unique evolutionary trajectory. Collectively, these results reveal the photosynthetic flexibility in these early-diverging cyanobacterial lineages, shedding new light on the early evolution of Cyanobacteriota and their photosynthetic processes.</description>
      <author>Sha Tan, Lan Liu, Jian&#8208;Yu Jiao, Mengmeng Li, Chao-Jian Hu, LV Ai-ping, Yanling Qi, Yuxian Li, Yang-Zhi Rao, Yan-Ni Qu, Hongchen Jiang, Rochelle M. Soo, Paul N. Evans, Zheng-Shuang Hua, Wenjun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/molbev/msae151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A nanocoral like carbon composite based on dual-MOFs for catalytic reduction and evolution of oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102213</link>
      <description>Junyuan Zhang, Wei Liu, Linfeng Liang, Ziwei Deng, Changyu Liu, Xiaolong Xu, Jianbo Jia, Materials Today Chemistry. 40(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400966451

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junyuan Zhang, Wei Liu, Linfeng Liang, Ziwei Deng, Changyu Liu, Xiaolong Xu, Jianbo Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co-Zn single atoms anchored carbon nanotubes derived from anti-perovskite carbides for boosted hydrogen evolution and oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154255</link>
      <description>Liangliang Feng, Mengfei Zhou, Danyang He, Hongyan Yin, Yixuan Huang, Liyun Cao, Yuan Fang, Dewei Chu, Yipu Liu, Hui Chen, Guodong Li, Jianfeng Huang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400934242

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liangliang Feng, Mengfei Zhou, Danyang He, Hongyan Yin, Yixuan Huang, Liyun Cao, Yuan Fang, Dewei Chu, Yipu Liu, Hui Chen, Guodong Li, Jianfeng Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial decoupling strategy boosted alkaline hydrogen evolution for an efficient solar-driven AEM electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03872j</link>
      <description>Minghui Cui, Yansong Zhou, Rongjing Guo, Wenqi Zhao, Ying Liu, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400907575

                Substrate modification achieves spatial decoupling of the oxygen evolution reaction process, thereby greatly improving the efficiency and stability of the catalyst.</description>
      <author>Minghui Cui, Yansong Zhou, Rongjing Guo, Wenqi Zhao, Ying Liu, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03872j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transparent TiO2 nanotubes supporting silver sulfide for photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01440e</link>
      <description>Wiktoria Lipi&#324;ska, Stefania Wolff, Katharina E. Dehm, Simon Hager, Justyna Gumieniak, Agnieszka Kramek, Ryan W. Crisp, Emerson Coy, Katarzyna Grochowska, Katarzyna Siuzdak, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401029688

                Differences between photoelectrochemical and electrochemical activity were thoroughly investigated for the oxygen evolution reaction mediated by Ag 2 S deposited on two types of ordered titania substrates. Titanium dioxide in the form...</description>
      <author>Wiktoria Lipi&#324;ska, Stefania Wolff, Katharina E. Dehm, Simon Hager, Justyna Gumieniak, Agnieszka Kramek, Ryan W. Crisp, Emerson Coy, Katarzyna Grochowska, Katarzyna Siuzdak</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01440e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Universal synthesis of coral-like Ternary MOF-Derived Sulfides as efficient OER electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01725k</link>
      <description>Tianpeng Liu, Yangping Zhang, Jun Yu, Mengyun Hu, Zhengying Wu, Xiao Wei, Shudi Yu, Yukou Du, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400969813

                The strategy of synthesizing a high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts by sacrificing metal-organic frameworks (MOF) templates is considered promising. However, few reports have focused on improving the intrinsic electrocatalytic...</description>
      <author>Tianpeng Liu, Yangping Zhang, Jun Yu, Mengyun Hu, Zhengying Wu, Xiao Wei, Shudi Yu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01725k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries: A Comprehensive Review of Cathode and Anode Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10080260</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Xue Meng, Qing Wang, Yahui Zhang, Shengxue Yan, Shaohua Luo, Batteries. 10(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400915387

                As modern society continues to advance, the depletion of non-renewable energy sources (such as natural gas and petroleum) exacerbates environmental and energy issues. The development of green, environmentally friendly energy storage and conversion systems is imperative. The energy density of commercial lithium-ion batteries is approaching its theoretical limit, and even so, it struggles to meet the rapidly growing market demand. Lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries have garnered significant attention from researchers due to their exceptionally high theoretical energy density. However, challenges such as poor electrolyte stability, short cycle life, low discharge capacity, and high overpotential arise from the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) during discharge and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) during charging. This article elucidates the fundamental principles of lithium&#8211;oxygen batteries, analyzes the primary issues currently faced, and summarizes recent research advancements in air cathodes and anodes. Additionally, it proposes future directions and efforts for the development of lithium&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Xue Meng, Qing Wang, Yahui Zhang, Shengxue Yan, Shaohua Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10080260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solvothermal Synthesis of Quaternary Cu-Fe-Bi-S Nanostructure as a Promising Electrode Material for OER and Supercapacitor Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4654670/v1</link>
      <description>Muhammad Umer, Muhammad Awais, Sidra Aslam, Anas Bilal, Javaria Javaria, Waseem Abbas, Misbah Mirza, Muhammad Safdar, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400918067

                Abstract The rational development and synthesis of renewable nanostructured materials hold significant importance within the realm of energy storage applications. In this study, the quaternary chalcogenide of Cu2FeBiS4 was fabricated using a facile solvothermal method and evaluated for its performance in Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) and Supercapacitor applications. The material underwent characterization employing various analytical techniques, including X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy dispersive spectroscopy (EDX), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), and Raman analysis. Cu2FeBiS4 demonstrates an improved super-capacitive performance, exhibiting an outstanding specific capacity (Cs) of 1530 F g&#8211;1 at 2 A g&#8211;1. The admirable electrochemical activity is mainly due to the synergistic effect of mixed metal sulfide nanostructure that can escalate the rapid diffusion of ions and electrons, which is beneficial to the electrode/electrolyte contact area, thereby boosting the rate of charge transfer. Additionally, Cu2FeBiS4 exhibits a commendable energy density of 43.17 Wh kg&#8722; 1 at a power density of 327.87 W kg&#8722; 1, accompanied by a retention rate of 96.2% after 1000 cycles. As a result, the Cu2FeBiS4 electrode developed in this study is evinced to be a promising electrode material for high-performance energy storage devices. Moreover, Cu2FeBiS4 demonstrates proficient electrocatalytic properties for the oxygen evolution reaction, displaying a minimal overpotential of 202 mV versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) at 10 mA cm&#8722; 2 and exhibiting operational stability for up to 10 hours.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Umer, Muhammad Awais, Sidra Aslam, Anas Bilal, Javaria Javaria, Waseem Abbas, Misbah Mirza, Muhammad Safdar</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4654670/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clarification of Degradation Mechanisms of the OER Activity of Ir-Based Electrocatalyst with Potentiodynamic Accelerated Stress Test</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6716</link>
      <description>Raghunandan Sharma, P. Morgen, Darko Makovec, Sa&#353;o Gyergyek, Shuang Ma Andersen, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400937411

                Abstract It is vital to understand the degradation mechanisms for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity under acidic electrolyser operating conditions. To this end, we have studied a commercial benchmark Ir-Oxide electrocatalyst during an accelerated stress test (AST) of potential cycling (2000 cycles at 100 mV/s) between 1.0 and 1.7 V in 0.1 M HClO4. The OER activity degradation (&gt;60%) has been investigated due to (i) bulk structure changes from metal dissolution, (ii) particle growth and, (iii) surface chemical state changes. Microscopic images of the Ir-Oxide catalyst before and after the AST show no significant change in the particle size or agglomeration; moreover, negligible mass loss of the element. Therefore, the OER activity degradation is found to be dominantly (99%) associated with changes of the surface chemical state of Ir, i.e., increase in the Ir4+/Ir3+ ratio at the surface of Ir-Oxide during the AST.</description>
      <author>Raghunandan Sharma, P. Morgen, Darko Makovec, Sa&#353;o Gyergyek, Shuang Ma Andersen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-atom nickel on defective g-C4N3 as a promising bifunctional electrocatalyst for the OER and ORR: a first-principles analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2053-1591/ad674b</link>
      <description>Teng fei Gao, Xiao-Kuan Wu, Dan Wen, Xin Zhi, Yu Fang, Liang Wang, Jie Zhang, Jimmy Yun, Materials Research Express. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401007558

                Abstract Searching for inexpensive and highly active materials to replace noble metals for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is an important challenge. The two-dimensional semi-metallic carbon nitride g-C4N3 is an excellent candidate for electrochemical reactions owing to its eminent conductivity and stability. Here, using density functional theory (DFT) a series of low-budget non-noble transition metal single-atom (SAC) loaded on the g-C4N3 (named as TM@C4N3, TM=Cr, Mn, Fe, Co, Ni, Cu) were investigated as electrocatalysts for OER and ORR. Ni@C4N3 shows an enormous application potential as electrode material, with OER and ORR overpotentials of 0.59 V and 0.23 V, respectively. The second lowest binding energy between Ni and support g-C4N3 indicates that Ni@C4N3 possesses good overall stability. The d-band center as well as metal valence as the descriptor exhibit good agreement with the adsorption energy of the intermediate. A linear relationship exists among the adsorption energies of the three intermediates O, OH, and OOH, given the similarity that they are all bonded to the metal through one oxygen atom. By adjusting the adsorption energy of these intermediates, the catalytic activity of electrocatalysts can be tuned for OER and ORR. This study confirmed that Ni@C4N3 is a good bifunctional catalyst and provides important guidance for the design of bifunctional electrocatalysts for OER and ORR.</description>
      <author>Teng fei Gao, Xiao-Kuan Wu, Dan Wen, Xin Zhi, Yu Fang, Liang Wang, Jie Zhang, Jimmy Yun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2053-1591/ad674b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation strategies of electrocatalysts for 5-hydroxymethylfurfural oxidation-assisted water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.93</link>
      <description>Tongxue Zhang, Hua Yin, Fumin Wang, Wenxian Liu, Xinyuan He, Qian Liu, Xubin Zhang, Xijun Liu, Microstructures. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400961728

                To address energy shortages and environmental issues, prioritizing renewable energy development and usage is crucial. Employing renewable sources for water electrolysis offers a sustainable method for hydrogen generation. Reducing the water electrolysis potential is vital for efficient clean energy conversion and storage. Substituting the anodic oxygen evolution reaction in conventional hydrogen production from water electrolysis with the more thermodynamically favorable 5-hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) oxidation reaction can greatly decrease overpotential and yield the valuable product 2,5-furan dicarboxylic acid. The key to this process is developing effective electrocatalysts to minimize the potential of the HMF electrooxidation-hydrogen production system. Therefore, this review provides a comprehensive introduction to the modulation strategies that affect the electronic and geometric structure of electrocatalysts for HMF oxidation-assisted water splitting. The strategies encompass heteroatom doping, defect projection, interface engineering, structural design, and multi-metal synergies. The catalysts are assessed from various angles, encompassing structural characterization, reaction mechanisms, and electrochemical performance. Finally, current challenges in the catalyst design and potential development of this promising field are proposed.</description>
      <author>Tongxue Zhang, Hua Yin, Fumin Wang, Wenxian Liu, Xinyuan He, Qian Liu, Xubin Zhang, Xijun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.93</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@N&#8208;CNH as Bifunctional Hybrid Catalysts for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400415</link>
      <description>Sudheer Kumar Yadav, Daniel Deckenbach, Sandeep Yadav, Christian Njel, Vanessa Trouillet, J&#246;rg J. Schneider, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400935985

                Abstract Improving the efficiency of bifunctional electrocatalysts is a decisive challenge in the area of long&#8208;lasting rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries. Enhancing the catalysts' performance is crucial for advancing zinc&#8208;air batteries. Transition&#8208;metal oxides have emerged as promising non&#8208;precious, noble&#8208;metal&#8208;free catalysts. Herein, a unique precursor directed approach is introduced for preparing a cobalt ferrite@nitrogen doped carbon nanohorns (CoFe 2 O 4 @N&#8208;CNHs) nanohybrid catalyst in a single step annealing process involving stoichiometric amounts of single&#8208;source cobalt and iron molecular precursors and carbon nanohorns (CNHs) under an argon/ammonia (Ar/NH 3 ) atmosphere. This procedure enables a simultaneous CoFe 2 O 4 ferrite synthesis and nitrogen functionalization of CNHs. The precious metal free nanohybrid CoFe 2 O 4 @N&#8208;CNHs&#8208;30% containing 30% of carbon presents an oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) half wave potential and onset potential comparable to the standard ORR catalyst 20% Pt/C. CoFe 2 O 4 @N&#8208;CNHs&#8208;30% also establishes superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance with a low overpotential and a small Tafel slope than benchmark OER catalyst RuO 2 . Furthermore, the rechargeable zinc&#8208;air battery with the CoFe 2 O 4 @N&#8208;CNHs&#8208;30% nanohybrid as air electrode demonstrates steadier and more durable charge&#8211;discharge cycles, and outstanding energy density relative to the state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art 20% Pt/C&#8208;RuO 2 catalyst.</description>
      <author>Sudheer Kumar Yadav, Daniel Deckenbach, Sandeep Yadav, Christian Njel, Vanessa Trouillet, J&#246;rg J. Schneider</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400415</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long&#8208;Durability, Surfactant&#8208;Free, and Bifunctional Ir&#8208;Doped Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Co/MWCNTs Electrocatalysts towards ORR and OER in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202402029</link>
      <description>Yan Wang, Chuang Li, Guangwei Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Shiping Luo, Danmin Xing, Changhai Liang, ChemistrySelect. 9(28)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400948633

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective, high&#8208;performance, and durable electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is pivotal for advancing hydrogen energy conversion and storage technologies. Simultaneously, establishing scalable methods for their production is essential for the widespread adoption of these renewable energy solutions. In this study, we present a successful large&#8208;scale synthesis of surfactant&#8208;free iridium&#8208;doped Pt&#8722;cobalt nanoparticles supported on multiwalled carbon nanotubes (Ir&#8722;Pt 3 Co/MWCNTs). This composite demonstrates significantly enhanced ORR and OER activity compared to commercial Pt/C and IrO 2 in acidic environments. The Ir&#8722;Pt 3 Co/MWCNTs catalyst composite exhibits a low overpotential of 357 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a remarkable mass activity of 0.594 A/mg Pt . Investigating the influence of Ir doping content on ORR and OER, we found that Pt 3 Co 0.6 Ir 0.4 /MWCNTs showcased the most superior activity in both reactions. We present a reproducible protocol for the synthesis of surfactant&#8208;free Ir&#8722;Pt 3 Co nanoparticles supported on MWCNTs, yielding a bifunctional catalyst capable of efficiently catalyzing both ORR and OER with outstanding efficiency and stability in acidic media. Detailed X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis elucidates the electron transfer between atoms, optimizing the electronic structure and adjusting the position of the d&#8208;band. This optimization enhances the electrocatalytic activity and structural stability of the catalysts, contributing to their superior performance in ORR and OER.</description>
      <author>Yan Wang, Chuang Li, Guangwei Li, Xiaoqiang Li, Shiping Luo, Danmin Xing, Changhai Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202402029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Performance of a Hybrid NiCo2O4@NiFelt Electrode at Different Operating Temperatures and Electrolyte pH</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153703</link>
      <description>Ataollah Niyati, Arianna Moranda, Pouya Beigzadeh Arough, Federico Navarra, Ombretta Paladino, Energies. 17(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401015177

                Transition metals such as nickel and cobalt as an alternative to Pt and Pd can be used for oxygen evolution reactions (OERs) and hydrogen production reactions (HERs) in alkaline environments, facilitating green hydrogen production as a sustainable alternative to fossil fuels. In this study, an NiCo2O4 catalyst was produced by a sono-hydrothermal method using urea as a hydrolysis agent. The electrochemical performance of the catalyst-coated NiFelt electrode was evaluated at different KOH concentrations (0.25, 0.5, and 1 M) and four operating temperatures in the interval of 20&#8211;80 &#176;C. The electrode characteristics were investigated via electrochemical spectroscopy (cyclic voltammetry, EIS, multistep chronopotentiometry, multistep chronoamperometry) using two different reference electrodes (Ag/AgCl and Hg/HgO), to obtain insight into the anodic and cathodic peaks. XRD, SEM, EDS, and TEM analyses confirmed the purity, structure, and nanoscale particle size (20&#8211;45 nm) of the NiCo2O4 catalyst. The electrode showed symmetric CV with Ag/AgCl, making this reference electrode more appropriate for capacitance measurements, while Hg/HgO proved advantageous for EIS in alkaline solutions due to reduced noise. The overpotential of the catalyst-coated NiFelt decreased by 108 mV at 10 mA/cm2 compared to bare NiFelt, showing a good potential for its application in anion exchange membranes and alkaline electrolyzers at an industrial scale.</description>
      <author>Ataollah Niyati, Arianna Moranda, Pouya Beigzadeh Arough, Federico Navarra, Ombretta Paladino</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153703</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Modification of Aluminum Oxide Inclusions in Bearing Steel under Different Cleanliness Conditions by Rare Earth Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/met14080861</link>
      <description>Ning Wang, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Guang-da Bao, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang, Metals. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401014801

                The impact of rare earth treatment on the chemical morphology evolution of non-metallic inclusions in bearing steel under different initial cleanliness conditions was studied through simulation. Thermodynamic calculations indicate that at an oxygen content of 0.001%, the evolution route of inclusions with increasing Ce content was Al2O3 &#8594; CeAl11O18 + CeAlO3 &#8594; CeAlO3 + Ce2O2S &#8594; Ce2O2S &#8594; Ce2O2S + CeS. As the initial oxygen content decreases, the proportion of CeAlO3 decreases, leading to easier conversion of CeAlO3 to Ce2O2S. Vacuum induction furnace experiments demonstrated that with an oxygen content of 0.001%, an increase in Ce content results in a gradual rise in the proportion of inclusions in steel sized 1~2 &#956;m. In contrast, the proportion of inclusions sized 2~5 &#956;m decreases. Consequently, the overall content of inclusions in steel decreases, along with a reduction in both the number density and average size of inclusions. Introducing bearing steel melt with approximately 0.01% Ce rare earth to bearing steel with initial oxygen contents of 0.0005%, 0.001%, and 0.0015% showed an evolution of inclusions from Ce2O2S and CeS to Ce2O3, CeAlO3, etc. The average inclusion size significantly increased from 0.7 &#956;m to 2.16 &#956;m. Morphologically, the transition of inclusions from precipitated to polymerized forms occurred as the initial oxygen content rose. High-temperature laser confocal microscopy experiments demonstrated that inclusions in low cleanliness conditions tend to agglomerate more than those in high cleanliness conditions, contributing to the increase in average size.</description>
      <author>Ning Wang, Wen-zhi Xia, Yun Zhou, Aijun Deng, Guang-da Bao, Zhiyou Liao, Haichuan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/met14080861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Evolution of Antisite Defect and Coupling Anionic Redox in High&#8208;Voltage Ultrahigh&#8208;Ni Cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410326</link>
      <description>Kang Wu, Peilin Ran, Wen Yin, Lunhua He, Bao&#8208;Tian Wang, Jinming Jian, Enyue Zhao, Jinkui Zhao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401037985

                High-voltage ultrahigh-Ni cathodes (LiNixCoyMn1-x-yO2, x &#8805; 0.9) can significantly enhance the energy density and cost-effectiveness of Li-ion batteries beyond current levels. However, severe Li-Ni antisite defects and their undetermined dynamic evolutions during high-voltage cycling limit the further development of these ultrahigh-Ni cathodes. In this study, we quantify the dynamic evolutions of the Li-Ni antisite defect using operando neutron diffraction and reveal its coupling relationship with anionic redox, another critical challenge restricting ultrahigh-Ni cathodes. We detect a clear Ni migration coupled with an unstable oxygen lattice, which accompanies the oxidation of oxygen anions at high voltages. Based on these findings, we propose that minimized Li-Ni antisite defects and controlled Ni migrations are essential for achieving stable high-voltage cycling structures in ultrahigh-Ni cathodes. This is further demonstrated by the optimized ultrahigh-Ni cathode, where reduced dynamic evolutions of the Li-Ni antisite defect effectively inhibit the anionic redox, enhancing the 4.5 V cycling stability.</description>
      <author>Kang Wu, Peilin Ran, Wen Yin, Lunhua He, Bao&#8208;Tian Wang, Jinming Jian, Enyue Zhao, Jinkui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Evolution of Antisite Defect and Coupling Anionic Redox in High&#8208;Voltage Ultrahigh&#8208;Ni Cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410326</link>
      <description>Kang Wu, Peilin Ran, Wen Yin, Lunhua He, Bao&#8208;Tian Wang, Jinming Jian, Enyue Zhao, Jinkui Zhao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401038097

                High&#8208;voltage ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathodes (LiNixCoyMn1&#8722;x&#8722;yO2, x &#8805; 0.9) can significantly enhance the energy density and cost&#8208;effectiveness of Li&#8208;ion batteries beyond current levels. However, severe Li&#8208;Ni antisite defects and their undetermined dynamic evolutions during high&#8208;voltage cycling limit the further development of these ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathodes. In this study, we quantify the dynamic evolutions of the Li&#8208;Ni antisite defect using operando neutron diffraction and reveal its coupling relationship with anionic redox, another critical challenge restricting ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathodes. We detect a clear Ni migration coupled with an unstable oxygen lattice, which accompanies the oxidation of oxygen anions at high voltages. Based on these findings, we propose that minimized Li&#8208;Ni antisite defects and controlled Ni migrations are essential for achieving stable high&#8208;voltage cycling structures in ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathodes. This is further demonstrated by the optimized ultrahigh&#8208;Ni cathode, where reduced dynamic evolutions of the Li&#8208;Ni antisite defect effectively inhibit the anionic redox, enhancing the 4.5 V cycling stability.</description>
      <author>Kang Wu, Peilin Ran, Wen Yin, Lunhua He, Bao&#8208;Tian Wang, Jinming Jian, Enyue Zhao, Jinkui Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410326</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique myoglobin adaptation to endothermy and flight since the origin of birds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1749-4877.12870</link>
      <description>Shengjing Song, H. D. Chen, Yu Zhang, Xiaojia Zhu, David M. Irwin, Kai He, Yang Liu, Integrative Zoology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401006652

                Myoglobin (Mb) mediates oxygen diffusion and storage in muscle tissue and thus is important for the energy utilization and activity of animals. Birds generally have a high body temperature, and most species also possess the capability of powered flight. Both of these require high levels of aerobic metabolism. Within endothermic mammals, bats also independently evolved flight. Although the functional evolution of myoglobins in deep-diving amniote vertebrates has been well-studied, the functional evolution of myoglobin since the origins of both birds and bats is unclear. Here, with Mb-coding sequences from &gt;200 extant amniote species, we reconstructed ancestral sequences to estimate the functional properties of myoglobin through amniote evolution. A dramatic change in net surface charge on myoglobin occurred during the origin of Aves, which might have been driven by positively selected amino acid substitutions that occurred on the lineage leading to all birds. However, in bats, no change in net surface charge occurred and instead, the Mb genes show evidence of strong purifying selection. The increased net surface charge on bird myoglobins implies an adaptation to flight-related endothermic and higher body temperatures, possibly by reducing harmful protein aggregations. Different from the findings of net surface charge, myoglobins of extant birds show lower stability compared with other amniotes, which probably accelerates the rate of oxygen utilization in muscles. In bats and other mammals, higher stability of Mb may be an alternative pathway for adaptation to endothermy, indicating divergent evolution of myoglobin in birds and bats.</description>
      <author>Shengjing Song, H. D. Chen, Yu Zhang, Xiaojia Zhu, David M. Irwin, Kai He, Yang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1749-4877.12870</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Interfacial Interactions and Oxygen Vacancies in Tuning Magnetic Anisotropy in LaCrO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/LaMnO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400243</link>
      <description>Xuanyi Zhang, Athby H. Al&#8208;Tawhid, P. Sch&#228;fer, Zhan Zhang, Divine P. Kumah, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400963754

                Abstract The interplay of lattice, electronic, and spin degrees of freedom at epitaxial complex oxide interfaces provides a route to tune their magnetic ground states. Unraveling the competing contributions is critical for tuning their functional properties. The relationship between magnetic ordering and magnetic anisotropy and the lattice symmetry, oxygen content, and film thickness in compressively strained LaMnO 3 (LMO)/LaCrO 3 (LCO) superlattices is investigated. Mn&#8211;O&#8211;Cr antiferromagnetic superexchange interactions across the heterointerface result in a net ferrimagnetic magnetic structure. Bulk magnetometry measurements reveal isotropic in&#8208;plane magnetism for as&#8208;grown oxygen&#8208;deficient thin samples due to equal fractions of orthorhombic a+a&#8208;c&#8208;, and a&#8208;a+c&#8208; twin domains. As the superlattice thickness is increased, in&#8208;plane magnetic anisotropy emerges as the fraction of the a+a&#8208;c&#8208; domain increases. On annealing in oxygen, the suppression of oxygen vacancies results in a contraction of the lattice volume, and an orthorhombic to rhombohedral transition leads to isotropic magnetism independent of the film thickness. The complex interactions are investigated using high&#8208;resolution synchrotron diffraction and X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy. These results highlight the role of the evolution of structural domains with film thickness, interfacial spin interactions, and oxygen&#8208;vacancy&#8208;induced structural phase transitions in tuning the magnetic properties of complex oxide heterostructures.</description>
      <author>Xuanyi Zhang, Athby H. Al&#8208;Tawhid, P. Sch&#228;fer, Zhan Zhang, Divine P. Kumah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400243</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary Origins of Self-sustained Kai Protein Circadian Oscillators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.23.604570</link>
      <description>Atsushi Mukaiyama, Yoshihiko Furuike, Kumiko Ito-Miwa, Yasuhiro Onoue, Kota Horiuchi, Eiki Yamashita, Shuji Akiyama, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400937324

                Light-dark cycles affect photosynthetic efficiency in autotrophic cyanobacteria; therefore, determining whether ancient cyanobacteria possessed a self-sustained circadian clock when oxygenic photosynthetic systems were established is an important issue in chronobiology. Here we examined the oscillation of the clock protein KaiC in modern cyanobacteria, as well as the function and structure of ancestral Kai proteins, to determine the evolutionary origin of the self-sustained Kai-protein oscillators. The results show that the oldest double-domain KaiC in ancestral bacteria lacked the factors functionally and structurally essential for rhythmicity. The ancestral Kai proteins had acquired these factors through molecular evolution that occurred around Global Oxidation and Snowball Earth events, and were eventually inherited as a self-sustained circadian oscillator by the most recent common ancestor of cyanobacteria capable of oxygenic photosynthesis. This autonomous Kai protein oscillator was further inherited by most freshwater and marine cyanobacteria present today as an autotrophic basis for time-optimal acquisition and consumption of energy from oxygenic photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Atsushi Mukaiyama, Yoshihiko Furuike, Kumiko Ito-Miwa, Yasuhiro Onoue, Kota Horiuchi, Eiki Yamashita, Shuji Akiyama</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.07.23.604570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of MELTS program to Fractional Crystallization of Low Alumina Alkaline Magma in Jeju Volcanic Island</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4651465/v1</link>
      <description>Huy L&#234;, Cheolwoo Chang, Sung-Hyo Yun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400918573

                Abstract Jeju Volcanic Island is the largest island in South Korea which is known as the continental shelf intraplate volcanic island. MELTS, one of the powerful programs utilizing for modeling magmatic evolution processes, is applied to simulate fractional crystallization process of low-alumina alkaline volcanic rock suite in Jeju Island. At many isobaric pressure conditions from 2.0 GPa to 0.1 GPa as well as different oxygen fugacities (fO2) from FMQ-3 to FMQ + 3 and H2O content, MELTS modeling were conducted as various calculations. The results demonstrate that the most suitable fractionation model for Jeju low-alumina alkaline magma would occur from 0.2 GPa to 0.1 GPa with oxygen fugacity FMQ buffer. These contain 0.5 wt.% H2O in the system leading to more consistent with evolution trending of as well as mineral composition in natural rock suite on Jeju Island. Although MELTS still possesses several limitations in the stability of calibration such as spinel overestimation as well as a lack of experiments for hydrous minerals which have been renovated, MELTS exhibits its affection on temperature and pressure prediction as well as assess other factor of fractional crystallization process on Jeju Island. Consequently, to evaluate a magmatic process in a particular region, it would be better to combine MELTS with other analyses rather than operating independently.</description>
      <author>Huy L&#234;, Cheolwoo Chang, Sung-Hyo Yun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4651465/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Divergent molecular strategies drive evolutionary adaptation to competitive fitness in biofilm formation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae135</link>
      <description>Mingxing Tang, Ruixue Yang, Zilin Zhuang, Shuhong Han, Yehuan Sun, Peiyu Li, Kewei Fan, Cai Zhao, Yang Qiong, Zhijian Yu, Liang Yang, Shuo Li, The ISME Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400974308

                Abstract Biofilm is a group of heterogeneously structured and densely packed bacteria with limited access to nutrients and oxygen. These intrinsic features can allow a mono-species biofilm to diversify into polymorphic subpopulations, determining the overall community&#8217;s adaptive capability to changing ecological niches. However, the specific biological functions underlying biofilm diversification and fitness adaptation are poorly demonstrated. Here, we launched and monitored the experimental evolution of Pseudomonas aeruginosa biofilms, finding that two divergent molecular trajectories were adopted for adaptation to higher competitive fitness in biofilm formation: one involved hijacking bacteriophage superinfection to aggressively inhibit kin competitors, whereas the other induced a subtle change in c-di-GMP signaling to gain a positional advantage via enhanced early biofilm adhesion. Bioinformatics analyses implicated that similar evolutionary strategies were prevalent among clinical P. aeruginosa strains, indicative of parallelism between natural and experimental evolution. Divergence in the molecular bases illustrated the adaptive values of genomic plasticity for gaining competitive fitness in biofilm formation. Finally, we demonstrated that these fitness-adaptive mutations reduced bacterial virulence. Our findings revealed how the mutations intrinsically generated from the biofilm environment influence the evolution of P. aeruginosa.</description>
      <author>Mingxing Tang, Ruixue Yang, Zilin Zhuang, Shuhong Han, Yehuan Sun, Peiyu Li, Kewei Fan, Cai Zhao, Yang Qiong, Zhijian Yu, Liang Yang, Shuo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/ismejo/wrae135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure and oxidation behaviour of Mo&#8211;Si&#8211;B&#8211;Hf alloys at 800 &#176;C and 1100 &#176;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/02670836241266451</link>
      <description>Shuo Sun, Xiaohui Lin, Xuanqiao Gao, Yanchao Li, Jing Liang, Wei Zai, Wen Zhang, Materials Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401033451

                The influences of the microstructure evolution and oxidation behaviour of Hf-modified Mo&#8211;12Si&#8211;12B alloys were systematically studied at 800 &#176;C and 1100 &#176;C. Vickers hardness tests show that the Hf addition increases the hardness of Mo&#8211;Si&#8211;B&#8211;Hf alloys. The oxidation experiments were conducted at 800 &#176;C and 1100 &#176;C for 12 h; the detailed analysis revealed that the formation of HfSiO 4 in Mo&#8211;12Si&#8211;12B&#8211;10Hf alloy can effectively decrease the content of oxygen and make the surface of the oxide layer more complete at 800 &#176;C. At 1100&#176;C, the distinct difference in the expansion coefficient among the oxide films results in the formation of cracks and holes in Mo&#8211;12Si&#8211;12B&#8211;10Hf alloy, so the Mo&#8211;12Si&#8211;12B&#8211;10Hf alloy shows poor oxidation resistance.</description>
      <author>Shuo Sun, Xiaohui Lin, Xuanqiao Gao, Yanchao Li, Jing Liang, Wei Zai, Wen Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/02670836241266451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing the limits: expanding the temperature tolerance of a coral photosymbiont through differing selection regimes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19996</link>
      <description>Hugo Scharfenstein, Lesa M. Peplow, Carlos Alvarez&#8208;Roa, Matthew R. Nitschke, Wing Yan Chan, Patrick Buerger, Madeleine J. H. van Oppen, New Phytologist. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400995935

                Coral thermal bleaching resilience can be improved by enhancing photosymbiont thermal tolerance via experimental evolution. While successful for some strains, selection under stable temperatures was ineffective at increasing the thermal threshold of an already thermo-tolerant photosymbiont (Durusdinium trenchii). Corals from environments with fluctuating temperatures tend to have comparatively high heat tolerance. Therefore, we investigated whether exposure to temperature oscillations can raise the upper thermal limit of D. trenchii. We exposed a D. trenchii strain to stable and fluctuating temperature profiles, which varied in oscillation frequency. After 2.1 yr (54-73 generations), we characterised the adaptive responses under the various experimental evolution treatments by constructing thermal performance curves of growth from 21 to 31&#176;C for the heat-evolved and wild-type lineages. Additionally, the accumulation of extracellular reactive oxygen species, photophysiology, photosynthesis and respiration rates were assessed under increasing temperatures. Of the fluctuating temperature profiles investigated, selection under the most frequent oscillations (diurnal) induced the greatest widening of D. trenchii's thermal niche. Continuous selection under elevated temperatures induced the only increase in thermal optimum and a degree of generalism. Our findings demonstrate how differing levels of thermal homogeneity during selection drive unique adaptive responses to heat in a coral photosymbiont.</description>
      <author>Hugo Scharfenstein, Lesa M. Peplow, Carlos Alvarez&#8208;Roa, Matthew R. Nitschke, Wing Yan Chan, Patrick Buerger, Madeleine J. H. van Oppen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of hypogenesis in the evolution of karst in the Taurus Mountains Range, Turkey</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5038/1827-806x.53.2.2501</link>
      <description>Serdar Bayar&#305;, Naciye Nur &#214;zyurt, L&#252;tfi Nazik, Koray T&#246;rk, Noyan G&#252;ner, Emrah Pekkan, P&#305;nar Avc&#305;, International Journal of Speleology. 53(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400947810

                Field observations and laboratory data collected from the Taurus Mountains Range, Turkey during the last two decades provided evidence for the link between the evolution of hypogene karst and the geodynamic history. Major evidence includes; carbonate-hosted secondary ore deposits that are converted from primarily hypogene minerals by epigene, oxygen-rich groundwater circulating at local to intermediate depths. Another piece of evidence of hypogene karst in the Tauride is the K&#305;rkg&#246;z springs&#8217; huge submerged cave/conduit system, which formed the Antalya Travertine Plateau, which is the world&#8217;s largest deposit precipitated by cool karst groundwater. The obruks in central Tauride are giant collapse dolines formed by ascending hypogene fluids in the upper continental crust, rich in volcanogenic carbondioxide. The groundwater&#8217;s noble gas and carbon isotope data are helpful in determining the existing but asymptomatic hypogene activity in the upper crust. Hypogene karst development seems common in parts of the world with current or past geodynamic activity. However, a hydrogeological overview of the geodynamic history is essential to assess the hypogene processes and their reflections on the land surface.</description>
      <author>Serdar Bayar&#305;, Naciye Nur &#214;zyurt, L&#252;tfi Nazik, Koray T&#246;rk, Noyan G&#252;ner, Emrah Pekkan, P&#305;nar Avc&#305;</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5038/1827-806x.53.2.2501</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An in situ exploration of how Fe/N/C oxygen reduction catalysts evolve during synthesis under pyrolytic conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50629-x</link>
      <description>Shuhu Yin, H. Yi, Mengli Liu, Jian Yang, Shuangli Yang, Binwei Zhang, Long Chen, Xiaoyang Cheng, Huan Huang, Rui Huang, Yanxia Jiang, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400965814

                Abstract In pursuing cheap and effective oxygen reduction catalysts, the Fe/N/C system emerges as a promising candidate. Nevertheless, the structural transformations of starting materials into Fe- and N-doped carbon catalysts remains poorly characterized under pyrolytic conditions. Here, we explore the evolution of Fe species and track the formation of Fe&#8211;N 4 site development by employing diverse in-situ diagnostic techniques. In-situ heating microscopy reveals the initial formation of FeO x nanoparticles and subsequent internal migration within the carbon matrix, which stops once FeO x is fully reduced. The migration and decomposition of nanoparticles then leads to carbon layer reconstruction. Experimental and theoretical analysis reveals size-dependent behavior of FeO x where nanoparticles below 7 nm readily release Fe atoms to form Fe&#8211;N 4 while nanoparticles with sizes &gt;10 nm tend to coalesce and impede Fe&#8211;N 4 site formation. The work visualizes the pyrolysis process of Fe/N/C materials, providing theoretical guidance for the rational design of catalysts.</description>
      <author>Shuhu Yin, H. Yi, Mengli Liu, Jian Yang, Shuangli Yang, Binwei Zhang, Long Chen, Xiaoyang Cheng, Huan Huang, Rui Huang, Yanxia Jiang, Hong&#8208;Gang Liao, Shi&#8208;Gang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-50629-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reactively Processed Poly(butylene adipate terephthalate) Composite&#8211;Based Multilayered Films with Improved Properties for Sustainable Packaging Applications: Structural Characterization and Biodegradation Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/macp.202400067</link>
      <description>Jayita Bandyopadhyay, Orebotse Joseph Botlhoko, Caroline Mphahlele, Rakgoshi Lekalakala, Sudhakar Muniyasamy, Suprakas Sinha Ray, Macromolecular Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400903936

                Abstract In this study, it is attempted to enhance the properties and biodegradability of poly(butylene adipate terephthalate) (PBAT) using nanocomposite technology to meet the demand for sustainable packaging applications. Two nanoclays containing PBAT composites are reactively processed and integrated into the multilayered films. Reactive processing facilitates the dispersion and distribution of nanoclay particles in the PBAT matrix. The multilayered films comprising reactively processed PBAT composites exhibited a 24.5%&#8211;31.5% reduction in the oxygen transmission rate and improved dimensional stability and tensile properties. Moreover, the degradability of the multilayered film comprising reactively processed PBAT composites reached 82% in 180 days. In contrast, a neat PBAT film of similar thickness attained only 53% degradation in the same period. The biodegradation mechanism is proposed based on the topology of the disintegrated films studied using scanning electron microscopy, chemical bond vibrations determined by Fourier&#8208;transform infrared spectroscopy, and structural evolution by small&#8208; and wide&#8208;angle X&#8208;ray scattering (SWAXS). The SWAXS analysis is used to understand the changes in the degree of crystallinity, long&#8208;range periodic order, and crystalline and amorphous layer thickness of the multilayered films before and after degradation. Such multilayered films can find applications where packaging or biomedical devices cannot be recycled.</description>
      <author>Jayita Bandyopadhyay, Orebotse Joseph Botlhoko, Caroline Mphahlele, Rakgoshi Lekalakala, Sudhakar Muniyasamy, Suprakas Sinha Ray</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/macp.202400067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emerging insights into the pathogenesis and therapeutic strategies for vascular endothelial injury-associated diseases: focus on mitochondrial dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10456-024-09938-4</link>
      <description>Boxian Pang, Guangtong Dong, Tieliang Pang, Xinyao Sun, Xin Liu, Yifeng Nie, Xing Chang, Angiogenesis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401010620

                As a vital component of blood vessels, endothelial cells play a key role in maintaining overall physiological function by residing between circulating blood and semi-solid tissue. Various stress stimuli can induce endothelial injury, leading to the onset of corresponding diseases in the body. In recent years, the importance of mitochondria in vascular endothelial injury has become increasingly apparent. Mitochondria, as the primary site of cellular aerobic respiration and the organelle for "energy information transfer," can detect endothelial cell damage by integrating and receiving various external stress signals. The generation of reactive oxygen species (ROS) and mitochondrial dysfunction often determine the evolution of endothelial cell injury towards necrosis or apoptosis. Therefore, mitochondria are closely associated with endothelial cell function, helping to determine the progression of clinical diseases. This article comprehensively reviews the interconnection and pathogenesis of mitochondrial-induced vascular endothelial cell injury in cardiovascular diseases, renal diseases, pulmonary-related diseases, cerebrovascular diseases, and microvascular diseases associated with diabetes. Corresponding therapeutic approaches are also provided. Additionally, strategies for using clinical drugs to treat vascular endothelial injury-based diseases are discussed, aiming to offer new insights and treatment options for the clinical diagnosis of related vascular injuries.</description>
      <author>Boxian Pang, Guangtong Dong, Tieliang Pang, Xinyao Sun, Xin Liu, Yifeng Nie, Xing Chang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10456-024-09938-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Element abundances of galactic RGB stars in the APO-K2 catalogue. Dissimilarity in the scaling with [alpha/Fe]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449755</link>
      <description>G. Valle, M. Dell&#8217;Omodarme, P. G. Prada Moroni, S. Degl&#8216;Innocenti, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400917527

                We conducted an investigation on the chemical abundances of 4,316 stars in the red giant branch (RGB) phase from the recently released APO-K2 catalogue. Our aim was to characterize the abundance trends of the single elements with afe , mainly focusing on C, N, and O, which are the most relevant for the estimation of stellar ages. The chemical analysis of the RGB sample involved cross-matching data from the APO-K2 catalogue with individual element abundances from APOGEE DR17. The analysis detected a statistically significant difference in the (C+N+O)/Fe -- afe trend with respect to the simple alpha -enhancement scenario. This difference remained robust across different choices for the reference solar mixture and potential zero-point calibrations of C and N abundances. The primary discrepancy was a steeper increase in O/Fe with afe , reaching a 0.1 dex difference at $ = 0.3$. Notably, the impact on the evolutionary timescale of such oxygen over-abundance with respect to the commonly adopted uniform alpha -enhancement is rather limited. We verified that stellar models computed using an ad hoc O-rich mixture sped up the evolution by only 1&lt;!PCT!&gt; at $ = 0.3$, due to the counterbalancing effects of O enrichment on both the evolutionary timescale and the Fe/H relationship.</description>
      <author>G. Valle, M. Dell&#8217;Omodarme, P. G. Prada Moroni, S. Degl&#8216;Innocenti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449755</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of the Surface Magnetic Dead Layer in Rare&#8208;Earth Titanates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400489</link>
      <description>Rapha&#235;l Aeschlimann, Manuel Bib&#232;s, Alexandre Gloter, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401038578

                Abstract Perovskite rare&#8208;earth titanates RTiO 3 display a rich array of magnetic and electronic properties, with a Mott&#8208;insulating ground state and ferro&#8208; or antiferromagnetic spin orders depending on the rare&#8208;earth R. The nominal Ti valence is 3+ with a corresponding 3 d 1 configuration. Yet, at the surface of both bulk and thin films of RTiO 3 , the Ti valence has been found to strongly deviate towards the more stable 4+ state, adversely affecting magnetic properties. While this finding is rather ubiquitous, its exact origin is still poorly understood, which hampers the integration of RTiO 3 into complex heterostructures harnessing their rich physics. Here, scanning transmission electron microscope and electron energy loss spectroscopy experiments are used to analyze the top part of an epitaxial DyTiO 3 thin film displaying a well&#8208;developed Ti 4+ &#8208;rich layer over several nanometres. It shows that this valence evolution is related to a combination of short&#8208;range ordered interstitial oxygen planes and Ti&#8208;Dy cationic imbalance. Both defects synergistically contribute to enough hole doping for a complete transition toward Ti 4+ over a few unit&#8208;cells from the surface while a structure primarily of the perovskite&#8208;type is maintained.</description>
      <author>Rapha&#235;l Aeschlimann, Manuel Bib&#232;s, Alexandre Gloter</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An investigation into Venusian atmospheric chemistry based on an open-access photochemistry-transport model at 0-112 km</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450552</link>
      <description>Longkang Dai, Wencheng Shao, Biao Chen, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400932900

                Atmospheric chemistry plays a crucial role in the evolution of climate habitability on Venus. It has been widely explored by chemistry-transport models, but some characteristics are still poorly interpreted. This study is devoted to developing an open-access chemistry-transport model spanning both the middle and lower atmospheres of Venus. It provides a scheme for the structure of the chemistry, especially for the sulfur and oxygen, and investigates the influence of the cloud diffusivity and the SO$_ $ dissolution that are adopted in the clouds. The developed model is based on the VULCAN framework and was updated with the state-of-the-art Venusian atmospheric chemistry. It includes vertical eddy diffusion retrieved recently with the Venus Express observations, and it resolves radiative transfer containing gas absorption and scattering, Mie scattering of the cloud droplets, and absorption of the unknown UV absorber. The obtained abundance profiles of SO, SO$_ $, CO, COS, O, O$_ $, O$_ $, HCl, and NO are in overall agreement with the observations. The results show that the increase in cloud diffusivity has slight effects on the chemical structure. The SO$_ $ mainly dissolves in 50-90 km and evaporates below the clouds. The rapid dissolution-release cycle is responsible for the large upward flux of SO$_ $ at 58 km. At around 70 km, SO has a significant peak that is larger than that of previous studies by an order of magnitude, and S and SO$_ $ also show slight increases. They are attributed to the buffering effects of liquid SO$_ $ in the clouds. O$_ $ is significantly eliminated by SO in this layer. We emphasize the superior regulation of the sulfur cycle on O$_ $ at 70 km and its potential contributions to the long-standing problem of the overestimated O$_ $ abundance.</description>
      <author>Longkang Dai, Wencheng Shao, Biao Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202450552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Detection of CO Isotopologues in a High-redshift Main-sequence Galaxy: Evidence of a Top-heavy Stellar Initial Mass Function</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad4da2</link>
      <description>Ziyi Guo, Zhi-Yu Zhang, Zhiqiang Yan, Eda Gjergo, Allison Man, R. J. Ivison, X. Fu, Yong Shi, The Astrophysical Journal. 970(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400999003

                Abstract Recent observations and theories have presented a strong challenge to the universality of the stellar initial mass function (IMF) in extreme environments. A notable example has been found for starburst conditions, where evidence favors a top-heavy IMF, i.e., there is a bias toward massive stars compared to the IMF that is responsible for the stellar mass function and elemental abundances observed in the Milky Way. Local starburst galaxies have star formation rates similar to those in high-redshift main-sequence galaxies, which appear to dominate the stellar mass budget at early epochs. However, the IMF of high-redshift main-sequence galaxies is yet to be probed. Since 13 CO and C 18 O isotopologues are sensitive to the IMF, we have observed these lines toward four strongly lensed high-redshift main-sequence galaxies using the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array. Of our four targets, SDSS J0901+1814, at z &#8776; 2.26, is seen clearly in 13 CO and C 18 O, the first detection of CO isotopologues in the high-redshift main-sequence galaxy population. The observed 13 C/ 18 O ratio, 2.4 &#177; 0.8, is significantly lower than that of local main-sequence galaxies. We estimate the isotope ratio, oxygen abundance, and stellar mass using a series of chemical evolution models with varying star formation histories and IMFs. All models favor an IMF that is more top-heavy than that of the Milky Way. Thus, as with starburst galaxies, main-sequence galaxies in the high-redshift Universe have a greater fraction of massive stars than a Milky Way IMF would imply.</description>
      <author>Ziyi Guo, Zhi-Yu Zhang, Zhiqiang Yan, Eda Gjergo, Allison Man, R. J. Ivison, X. Fu, Yong Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad4da2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The origin and migration laws of hydrocarbons in uranium&#8208;bearing Luohe Formation, Pengyang area, &lt;scp&gt;SW&lt;/scp&gt; Ordos Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/gj.5017</link>
      <description>Qinghong Si, Xueming Teng, Qiang Zhu, Zongxing Li, Hualei Zhao, Guo&#8208;Ming Wang, Haikui Tong, Hongliang Dang, Geological Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401007272

                The hydrocarbon activity in Pengyang area, situated in the southwestern Ordos Basin, is notably prominent. Investigation on the migration laws of hydrocarbons is imperative for comprehending the involvement in uranium mineralization. Based on the analysis of spatial distribution of hydrocarbon containing fluid and hydrocarbon generation conditions of sandstone in the Luohe Formation, the organic geochemical characteristics including hydrocarbon components, carbon isotopes and biomarker compounds were analysed. The research results indicate that: (1) hydrocarbon fluid activities in the Luohe Formation are predominantly observed in layers exhibiting higher uranium mineralization. The mudstone of the Luohe Formation had low organic matter content and low thermal maturity, which was not conducive to hydrocarbon generation. (2) Hydrocarbon&#8208;containing fluid in the sandstone of Luohe Formation not only contained reducing gases such as methane and hydrogen but also chloroform asphalt components. The carbon isotopes of hydrocarbon in sandstone inform Luohe Formation resemble oil and gas in the Mesozoic. The biomarker parameter inferred that the parent rock of hydrocarbons in the Luohe Formation was formed under reducing and freshwater conditions, and hydrocarbon generation occurred at the mature stage. As above mentioned, a comparison was carried out between the affinity of hydrocarbon&#8208;containing fluid in the Luohe Formation and different layers of hydrocarbon source rocks. The migration behaviour of hydrocarbon&#8208;containing fluid in the Pengyang area has been summarized, and the involvement of hydrocarbon&#8208;containing fluid in uranium mineralization has been discussed. The main concepts are as follows: the sedimentary environment and thermal evolution conditions of hydrocarbons in the sandstone of Luohe Formation resemble those of the primary hydrocarbon source rocks in the Yanchang Formation. The main hydrocarbon charging events in the Luohe Formation occurred before the Late Cretaceous period, which is primarily related to two hydrocarbon generation events from 130 to 100 Ma in the Yanchang Formation and fault conduits connecting the Triassic to the Cretaceous Strata. The hydrocarbon&#8208;containing fluid released from Yanchang Formation migrating to the Luohe Formation provides reducing conditions for the precipitation of uranium in oxygen&#8208;bearing water bodies.</description>
      <author>Qinghong Si, Xueming Teng, Qiang Zhu, Zongxing Li, Hualei Zhao, Guo&#8208;Ming Wang, Haikui Tong, Hongliang Dang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/gj.5017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>eROSITA narrowband maps at the energies of soft X-ray emission lines</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449398</link>
      <description>Xueying Zheng, G. Ponti, Nicola Locatelli, A. Merloni, Werner Becker, Johan Comparat, K. Dennerl, M. J. Freyberg, Chandreyee Maitra, M. Sasaki, A. W. Strong, M. C. H. Yeung, Astronomy and Astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400917386

                Hot plasma plays a crucial role in regulating the baryon cycle within the Milky Way, flowing from the energetic sources in the Galactic center and plane, to the corona and the halo. This hot plasma represents an important fraction of the Galactic baryons, plays a key role in galactic outflows and is an important ingredient in galaxy evolution models. Taking advantage of the Spectrum-Roentgen-Gamma (SRG first all-sky survey (eRASS1), in this work our aim is to provide a panoramic view of the hot circumgalactic medium (CGM) of the Milky Way. Compared to the previous all-sky X-ray survey performed by ROSAT, the improved energy resolution of enabled us to map, for the first time, the sky within the narrow energy bands characteristic of soft X-ray emission lines. These lines provide essential information on the physical properties of the hot plasma. Here we present the eRASS1\ half sky maps in narrow energy bands corresponding to the most prominent soft X-ray lines and which allowed us to constrain the distribution of the hot plasma within and surrounding the Milky Way. We corrected the maps by removing the expected contribution associated with the cosmic X-ray background, the time-variable solar wind charge exchange, and the local hot bubble. We applied corrections to mitigate the effect of absorption, therefore highlighting the emission from the CGM of the Milky Way. We used the line ratio of the oxygen lines as a proxy to constrain the temperature of the warm-hot CGM, and we defined a pseudo-temperature $ T $ map. The map highlights how different regions are dominated by different thermal components. Toward the outer halo, the temperature distribution of the CGM on angular scales of 2--20 deg is consistent with being constant $ T T 4&lt;!PCT!&gt;$ with a marginal detection of $ T T = 2.7 &lt;!PCT!&gt; 0.2&lt;!PCT!&gt;$ (statistical) $ 0.6&lt;!PCT!&gt;$ (systematic) in the southern hemisphere. Instead significant variations of $ 12&lt;!PCT!&gt;$ are observed on scales of many tens of degrees when comparing the northern and southern hemispheres. The pseudo-temperature map shows significant variations across the borders of the bubbles, suggesting temperature variations, possibly linked to shocks, between the interior of the Galactic outflow and the unperturbed CGM. In particular, a shell characterized by a lower line ratio appears close to the edge of the bubbles.</description>
      <author>Xueying Zheng, G. Ponti, Nicola Locatelli, A. Merloni, Werner Becker, Johan Comparat, K. Dennerl, M. J. Freyberg, Chandreyee Maitra, M. Sasaki, A. W. Strong, M. C. H. Yeung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202449398</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lithium Ions as Modulators of Complex Biological Processes: The Conundrum of Multiple Targets, Responsiveness and Non-Responsiveness, and the Potential to Prevent or Correct Dysregulation of Systems during Aging and in Disease</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/biom14080905</link>
      <description>David A. Hart, Biomolecules. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400980549

                Lithium is one of the lightest elements on Earth and it has been in the environment since the formation of the galaxy. While a common element, it has not been found to be an essential element in biological processes, ranging from single cell organisms to Homo sapiens. Instead, at an early stage of evolution, organisms committed to a range of elements such as sodium, potassium, calcium, magnesium, zinc, and iron to serve essential functions. Such ions serve critical functions in ion channels, as co-factors in enzymes, as a cofactor in oxygen transport, in DNA replication, as a storage molecule in bone and liver, and in a variety of other roles in biological processes. While seemingly excluded from a major essential role in such processes, lithium ions appear to be able to modulate a variety of biological processes and &#8220;correct&#8221; deviation from normal activity, as a deficiency of lithium can have biological consequences. Lithium salts are found in low levels in many foods and water supplies, but the effectiveness of Li salts to affect biological systems came to recent prominence with the work of Cade, who reported that administrating Li salts calmed guinea pigs and was subsequently effective at relatively high doses to &#8220;normalize&#8221; a subset of patients with bipolar disorders. Because of its ability to modulate many biological pathways and processes (e.g., cyclic AMP, GSK-3beta, inositol metabolism, NaK ATPases, neuro processes and centers, immune-related events, respectively) both in vitro and in vivo and during development and adult life, Li salts have become both a useful tool to better understand the molecular regulation of such processes and to also provide insights into altered biological processes in vivo during aging and in disease states. While the range of targets for lithium action supports its possible role as a modulator of biological dysregulation, it presents a conundrum for researchers attempting to elucidate its specific primary target in different tissues in vivo. This review will discuss aspects of the state of knowledge regarding some of the systems that can be influenced, focusing on those involving neural and autoimmunity as examples, some of the mechanisms involved, examples of how Li salts can be used to study model systems, as well as suggesting areas where the use of Li salts could lead to additional insights into both disease mechanisms and natural processes at the molecular and cell levels. In addition, caveats regarding lithium doses used, the strengths and weaknesses of rodent models, the background genetics of the strain of mice or rats employed, and the sex of the animals or the cells used, are discussed. Low-dose lithium may have excellent potential, alone or in combination with other interventions to prevent or alleviate aging-associated conditions and disease progression.</description>
      <author>David A. Hart</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/biom14080905</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Controls on Early Cretaceous South Atlantic Ocean circulation and carbon burial &#8211; a climate model&#8211;proxy synthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/cp-20-1537-2024</link>
      <description>Sebastian Steinig, Wolf Dummann, Peter Hofmann, Martin Frank, Wonsun Park, Thomas Wagner, Sascha Fl&#246;gel, Climate of the past. 20(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4400929548

                Abstract. Black shale sediments from the Barremian to Aptian South Atlantic document the intense and widespread burial of marine organic carbon during the initial stages of seafloor spreading between Africa and South America. The enhanced sequestration of atmospheric CO2 makes these young ocean basins potential drivers of the Early Cretaceous carbon cycle and climate perturbations. The opening of marine gateways between initially restricted basins and related circulation and ventilation changes are a commonly invoked explanation for the transient formation and disappearance of these regional carbon sinks. However, large uncertainties in palaeogeographic reconstructions limit the interpretation of available palaeoceanographic data and prevent any robust model-based quantifications of the proposed circulation and carbon burial changes. Here, we present a new approach to assess the principal controls on the Early Cretaceous South Atlantic and Southern Ocean circulation changes under full consideration of the uncertainties in available boundary conditions. Specifically, we use a large ensemble of 36 climate model experiments to simulate the Barremian to Albian progressive opening of the Falkland Plateau and Georgia Basin gateways with different configurations of the proto-Drake Passage, the Walvis Ridge, and atmospheric CO2 concentrations. The experiments are designed to complement available geochemical data across the regions and to test circulation scenarios derived from them. All simulations show increased evaporation and intermediate water formation at subtropical latitudes that drive a meridional overturning circulation whose vertical extent is determined by the sill depth of the Falkland Plateau. The densest water masses formed in the southern Angola Basin and potentially reached the deep Cape Basin as Walvis Ridge Overflow Water. Palaeogeographic uncertainties are as important as the lack of precise knowledge of atmospheric CO2 levels for the simulated temperature and salinity spread in large parts of the South Atlantic. Overall temperature uncertainties reach up to 15 &#176;C and increase significantly with water depth. The ensemble approach reveals temporal changes in the relative importance of geographic and radiative forcings for the simulated oceanographic conditions and, importantly, nonlinear interactions between them. The progressive northward opening of the highly restricted Angola Basin increased the sensitivity of local overturning and upper-ocean stratification to atmospheric CO2 concentrations due to large-scale changes in the hydrological cycle, while the chosen proto-Drake Passage depth is critical for the ocean dynamics and CO2 response in the southern South Atlantic. Finally, the simulated processes are integrated into a recent carbon burial framework to document the principal control of the regional gateway evolution on the progressive shift from the prevailing saline and oxygen-depleted subtropical water masses to the dominance of ventilated high-latitude deep waters.</description>
      <author>Sebastian Steinig, Wolf Dummann, Peter Hofmann, Martin Frank, Wonsun Park, Thomas Wagner, Sascha Fl&#246;gel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/cp-20-1537-2024</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
