<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 01:19:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced asymmetric supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction performance by sugarcane molasses-generated Co3O4 nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.253</link>
      <description>Asma Hayat, Aneela Tahira, Gulzar Ali, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Ihsan Ali Mahar, Elmuez A. Dawi, Matteo Tonezzer, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885386

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asma Hayat, Aneela Tahira, Gulzar Ali, Muhammad Ali Bhatti, Aqeel Ahmed Shah, Ihsan Ali Mahar, Elmuez A. Dawi, Matteo Tonezzer, Ayman Nafady, Riyadh H. Alshammari, Zafar Hussain Ibupoto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling New Insights into Photocatalytic Enhancement of p-n BiVO4-OV/NiMoO4 Heterojunctions through Oxygen Defect Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hazadv.2024.100515</link>
      <description>Bavani Thirugnanam, Mani Preeyanghaa, S. Munusamy, Journal of Hazardous Materials Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403896436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bavani Thirugnanam, Mani Preeyanghaa, S. Munusamy</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.hazadv.2024.100515</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating surface reconstruction and lattice oxygen mechanism of nickel (oxy)hydroxide by defect engineering for industrial electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156977</link>
      <description>Xiangling Wang, Zhimin Li, Yu Tang, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Guo Chen, Jinsong Wang, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403897159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiangling Wang, Zhimin Li, Yu Tang, Zhengfu Zhang, Chengping Li, Rui Bao, Guo Chen, Jinsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Nickel-Based Perovskite Oxides for the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Electrolytes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01471</link>
      <description>Juliana B. Falqueto, Natasha Hales, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, ACS Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403900758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Juliana B. Falqueto, Natasha Hales, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c01471</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical heterostructure regulated by nickel-iron oxyhydroxides on carbon-incorporated cobalt oxide nanorod arrays for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.355</link>
      <description>Jing Li, Yuanqiang Wang, Zhili Xue, Ting Wang, Haozhen Zhu, Yichuan Rui, Chengjie Wang, Dezhi Pan, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403902652

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Li, Yuanqiang Wang, Zhili Xue, Ting Wang, Haozhen Zhu, Yichuan Rui, Chengjie Wang, Dezhi Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A fluffy sphere-like NiCoCu-carbonate hydroxide based electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction in pH neutral electrolyte solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04511d</link>
      <description>Li Yu, Xiaocai Ma, Qin Liang, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403904488

                Highly efficient, serviceable, and cost-efficient electrode materials for electrochemical water oxidation to evolve O2 is an important factor in renewable chemical fuels, including water splitting and reusable metal&#8722;air battery. Herein,...</description>
      <author>Li Yu, Xiaocai Ma, Qin Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj04511d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lanthanum-based nanomaterials for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.10.008</link>
      <description>Miao He, Ping Wang, Jiasai Yao, Y. Li, Senyao Meng, Zhenxing Li, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403904817

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miao He, Ping Wang, Jiasai Yao, Y. Li, Senyao Meng, Zhenxing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.10.008</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-efficiency Photocatalytic Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Properties by Z-scheme Electron Transfer in BiVO4/C3N5 Heterostructure</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124766</link>
      <description>Wuyou Wang, Biqing Li, Jia Shi, Kai Zhu, Yeru Zhang, Xuexin Liu, Claudia Li, Feiyang Hu, Xinguo Xi, Sibudjing Kawi, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403905019

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wuyou Wang, Biqing Li, Jia Shi, Kai Zhu, Yeru Zhang, Xuexin Liu, Claudia Li, Feiyang Hu, Xinguo Xi, Sibudjing Kawi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dopant-induced electronic state modulation of ruthenium oxide for enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157107</link>
      <description>Lu Lu, Zijing Xu, Shuaichong Wei, Songan Zhao, Xiaohang Du, Yanji Wang, Lanlan Wu, Guihua Liu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403905255

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lu Lu, Zijing Xu, Shuaichong Wei, Songan Zhao, Xiaohang Du, Yanji Wang, Lanlan Wu, Guihua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe2O4 nanoparticle embedded carbon nanofibers: A promising non-noble metal catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.353</link>
      <description>Trupti Kamble, S.R. Shingte, Vijay D. Chavan, Deok&#8208;kee Kim, S.H. Mujawar, Tukaram D. Dongale, P.B. Patil, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403906342

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Trupti Kamble, S.R. Shingte, Vijay D. Chavan, Deok&#8208;kee Kim, S.H. Mujawar, Tukaram D. Dongale, P.B. Patil</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V-doped transition metal selenides derived from NiFe Prussian blue analogues for efficient oxygen evolution reaction and urea oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.267</link>
      <description>Youwei Cheng, Lian Zhu, Yaqiong Gong, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403906511

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youwei Cheng, Lian Zhu, Yaqiong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.267</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress of Ir/Ru-based catalysts for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction in acidic environments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.277</link>
      <description>Jiayang Li, Chunmei Tang, Yangdong Zhou, Ruijiang Hong, Fang Meng, Lixin Xing, Sheng Wang, Ling Meng, Siyu Ye, Lei Du, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403906548

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiayang Li, Chunmei Tang, Yangdong Zhou, Ruijiang Hong, Fang Meng, Lixin Xing, Sheng Wang, Ling Meng, Siyu Ye, Lei Du</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A binary mixture of ionic liquids as a sustainable electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.126385</link>
      <description>Bidyutjyoti Dutta, Madhabi Konwar, Lakhyajyoti Borthakur, Diganta Sarma, Journal of Molecular Liquids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403910583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bidyutjyoti Dutta, Madhabi Konwar, Lakhyajyoti Borthakur, Diganta Sarma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.molliq.2024.126385</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and synthesis of a 3D urchin-like Ni/WC@NSCNT electrocatalyst for enhanced bifunctional performance in oxygen evolution and reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177221</link>
      <description>Eunsu Jang, Subin Lee, Jangwoo Cho, Ji Hoon Kim, Jooheon Kim, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. 1010(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403912631

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eunsu Jang, Subin Lee, Jangwoo Cho, Ji Hoon Kim, Jooheon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Co/CoTe heterostructure internal hairy fibers towards high-efficiency oxygen electrocatalysis for flexible Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.183</link>
      <description>Jin Wang, Bing Li, Tiantian Tang, Caiyun Li, Hongrui Yang, Hanwen He, Xiaoqing Lin, Yang Song, Sen Zhang, Chao Deng, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403915344

                The design of highly efficient catalysts to enhance the kinetics of oxygen reduction (OER) and oxygen evolution (ORR) reactions is the key issue for the development of high-performance Zn-air battery. In this work, we report the design of Co-CoTe heterostructured fibers as the bifunctional oxygen catalyst for Zn-air battery. Firstly, the theoretical analysis was carried out on Co-CoTe heterostructure. The large work function difference is favorable to construct strong interfacial built-in electric field (BIEF), and the low energy barrier endows high catalytic activities. Moreover, the in-situ grown carbon shell was designed to build "core-shell" Co-CoTe/C unit to realize its high performance. They assemble the Co-CoTe@HFS fiber with good self-supporting and flexible features. Taken the advantages of the strong BIEF, the "core-shell" basic unit, and the freestanding substrate, the Co-CoTe@HFS fiber achieves the good electrocatalytic properties and high reliability. The full Zn-air battery (ZAB) with the Co/CoTe@HFS air cathode achieves the high peak power density and cycling stability over long-term cycling. Therefore, this work provides a clue to design bifunctional oxygen catalysts for high-performance ZABs.</description>
      <author>Jin Wang, Bing Li, Tiantian Tang, Caiyun Li, Hongrui Yang, Hanwen He, Xiaoqing Lin, Yang Song, Sen Zhang, Chao Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.183</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Density Atomic Level Defect Engineering of 2D Fe&#8208;Based Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks Boosts Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202405936</link>
      <description>Xin Zhao, Shixun Wang, Yanhui Cao, Yun Li, Arsenii S. Portniagin, Bing Tang, Qi Liu, Peter Kas&#225;k, Tianshuo Zhao, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Andrey L. Rogach, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403917276

                Abstract Electrocatalysts based on metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) attracted significant attention for water splitting, while the transition between MOFs and metal oxyhydroxide poses a great challenge in identifying authentic active sites and long&#8208;term stability. Herein, we employ on&#8208;purpose defect engineering to create high&#8208;density atomic level defects on two&#8208;dimensional Fe&#8208;MOFs. The coordination number of Fe changes from 6 to 4.46, and over 28% of unsaturated Fe sites are formed in the optimized Fe&#8208;MOF. In situ characterizations of the most optimized Fe&#8208;MOF 0.3 electrocatalyst during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process using Fourier transform infrared and Raman spectroscopy have revealed that some Fe unsaturated sites become oxidized with a concomitant dissociation of water molecules, causing generation of the crucial *OH intermediates and Fe oxyhydroxide. Moreover, the presence of Fe oxyhydroxide is compatible with the Volmer and Heyrovsky steps during the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) process, which lower its energy barrier and accelerate the kinetics. As a result, the optimized Fe&#8208;MOF electrodes delivered remarkable OER (259 mV at 10 mA cm -2 ) and HER (36 mV at 10 mA cm -2 ) performance. Our study offers comprehensive understanding of the effect of phase transformation on the electrocatalytic process of MOF&#8208;based materials.</description>
      <author>Xin Zhao, Shixun Wang, Yanhui Cao, Yun Li, Arsenii S. Portniagin, Bing Tang, Qi Liu, Peter Kas&#225;k, Tianshuo Zhao, Xuerong Zheng, Yida Deng, Andrey L. Rogach</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202405936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ligand engineering enhances (photo) electrocatalytic activity and stability of zeolitic imidazolate frameworks via in-situ surface reconstruction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53385-0</link>
      <description>Zheao Huang, Zhouzhou Wang, Hannah Rabl, Shaghayegh Naghdi, Qiancheng Zhou, Sabine Schwarz, Do&#287;ukan Hazar Apayd&#305;n, Ying Yu, Dominik Eder, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403918762

                Abstract The current limitations in utilizing metal-organic frameworks for (photo)electrochemical applications stem from their diminished electrochemical stability. In our study, we illustrate a method to bolster the activity and stability of (photo)electrocatalytically active metal-organic frameworks through ligand engineering. We synthesize four distinct mixed-ligand versions of zeolitic imidazolate framework-67, and conduct a comprehensive investigation into the structural evolution and self-reconstruction during electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions. In contrast to the conventional single-ligand ZIF, where the framework undergoes a complete transformation into CoOOH via a stepwise oxidation, the ligand-engineered zeolitic imidazolate frameworks manage to preserve the fundamental framework structure by in-situ forming a protective cobalt (oxy)hydroxide layer on the surface. This surface reconstruction facilitates both conductivity and catalytic activity by one order of magnitude and considerably enhances the (photo)electrochemical stability. This work highlights the vital role of ligand engineering for designing advanced and stable metal-organic frameworks for photo- and electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Zheao Huang, Zhouzhou Wang, Hannah Rabl, Shaghayegh Naghdi, Qiancheng Zhou, Sabine Schwarz, Do&#287;ukan Hazar Apayd&#305;n, Ying Yu, Dominik Eder</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53385-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo-MOF-74/Mn-MOF-74 Nanocomposite as a electrocatalyst for improved oxygen evolution reaction catalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133516</link>
      <description>Lan Xiao, Jian Wen, Guanghui Wu, Pinghua Chen, Mengxue Wang, Hualin Jiang, Xinming Zhou, Jianan Yan, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403931276

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lan Xiao, Jian Wen, Guanghui Wu, Pinghua Chen, Mengxue Wang, Hualin Jiang, Xinming Zhou, Jianan Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous network of boron-doped IrO2 nanoneedles with enhanced mass activity for acidic oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01358a</link>
      <description>Fei Hu, P. Huang, Feng Xu, Changjian Zhou, Xinjuan Zeng, Congcong Liu, Guangjin Wang, Xiaowei Yang, Huawen Hu, Materials Horizons. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403931327

                While the proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is essential for realizing practical hydrogen production, the trade-off among activity, stability, and cost of state-of-the-art iridium (Ir)-based oxygen evolution reaction (OER)...</description>
      <author>Fei Hu, P. Huang, Feng Xu, Changjian Zhou, Xinjuan Zeng, Congcong Liu, Guangjin Wang, Xiaowei Yang, Huawen Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4mh01358a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Isolated Cationic Vacancies on Nickel-Iron Layered Double Hydroxides for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5006017</link>
      <description>Qiulu Gao, Chao Lin, Zheng Lin, Xiaopeng Liu, Qianfan Zhang, Peng Diao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403942874

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiulu Gao, Chao Lin, Zheng Lin, Xiaopeng Liu, Qianfan Zhang, Peng Diao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5006017</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover: Full&#8208;Spectrum Light&#8208;Harvesting Solar Thermal Electrocatalyst Boosts Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420448</link>
      <description>Mingxia Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu, Dehui Deng, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403944607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingxia Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202420448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back Cover: Full&#8208;Spectrum Light&#8208;Harvesting Solar Thermal Electrocatalyst Boosts Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420448</link>
      <description>Mingxia Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu, Dehui Deng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403944680

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mingxia Xu, Qiming Bing, Yunchuan Tu, Yunlong Zhang, Mo Zhang, Yafeng Cai, Jinlei Li, Xianguang Meng, Jia Zhu, Liang Yu, Dehui Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202420448</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active Site Customizing of Metal&#8211;Organic Materials for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407933</link>
      <description>Na Sun, Xiuwen Si, Xiaoqi Wei, Xue Zhou, Yu Han, Fu Ding, Xiangru Kong, Ya&#8208;Guang Sun, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403953999

                Abstract Elucidating the correlation of active sites and catalytic activity in multi&#8208;component metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) is key to understanding the mechanism of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), yet it remains nebulous. Herein, a direct pathway combining theoretical prediction with anchoring high&#8208;valence metals is proposed on MOFs to reveal the mechanism of the OER reaction. Density functional theory (DFT) predicts that the co&#8208;modulation by Mo and Co atoms can enhance the conductance of CoMOF and optimize the adsorption&#8208;free energies of the OER intermediates. Guided by the theoretical prediction, the Co&#8208;based MOFs grown on Ni foams are doped with high valence Mo, which is used as model catalysts for the quantitative study of the composition&#8208;dependent OER performance. With Co/Mo in the ratio of 5:1 for the highest OER activity (impressively overpotential of 324 mV at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 96.07 mV dec &#8722;1 ) and excellent stability (maintains for 200 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 ), the catalysts in this work is superior to commercial benchmarks electrocatalysts (RuO 2 /NF, 420 mV, 199.12 mV dec &#8722;1 ). This work sheds light on the tailoring of the active sites of MOFs, which is highly correlated with the activity of the OER.</description>
      <author>Na Sun, Xiuwen Si, Xiaoqi Wei, Xue Zhou, Yu Han, Fu Ding, Xiangru Kong, Ya&#8208;Guang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407933</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Interfacial Ni/Fe&#9472;O&#9472;Y Bonds Contribute to High&#8208;Efficiency Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407860</link>
      <description>Zhen Xin Hui, Hui Li, Zhiwen Chen, Zi Wen, Guoyong Wang, Chandra Veer Singh, Chun Cheng Yang, Qing Jiang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403954087

                Abstract Developing economical and efficient electrocatalysts is critical for hydrogen energy industrialization through water electrolysis. Herein, a novel dual&#8208;site synergistic NiFe/Y 2 O 3 hybrid with abundant interfacial Ni/Fe&#9472;O&#9472;Y bonds is designed by density functional theory (DFT) simulations. In situ Raman spectra combined with DFT calculations reveal that the interfacial Ni/Fe&#9472;O&#9472;Y units greatly promote H 2 O dissociation and optimize the adsorption of both H* and oxygen species, achieving excellent activity and durability for hydrogen evolution reaction. As expected, NiFe/Y 2 O 3 exhibits a low overpotential of 27 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and robust stability of over 200 h at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 , and also outstanding water splitting performance with a low cell voltage of 1.64 V at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , showing significant potential for real&#8208;world applications.</description>
      <author>Zhen Xin Hui, Hui Li, Zhiwen Chen, Zi Wen, Guoyong Wang, Chandra Veer Singh, Chun Cheng Yang, Qing Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical reconstruction of metal-organic gels into crystalline oxy-hydroxide heterostructures for efficient oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc05799f</link>
      <description>Kang Liu, Haikuo Lan, Yuting Chen, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Yuchen Wang, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403956301

                Metal-organic gels (MOGs) are emerging soft materials with distinct metal active centers, multifunctional ligands and hierarchical porous structures, showing promising potential in the field of electrocatalysis. However, the reconfiguration of...</description>
      <author>Kang Liu, Haikuo Lan, Yuting Chen, Weihua Tang, Zhenyu Xiao, Yunmei Du, Jun Xing, Zexing Wu, Yuchen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc05799f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membrane&#8208;Free Water Electrolysis for Hydrogen Generation with Low Cost</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417987</link>
      <description>Xintong Gao, Pengtang Wang, Xiaojie Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403963388

                Conventional water electrolysis relies on expensive membrane&#8208;electrode assemblies and sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode. Here, we develop an innovative and efficient membrane&#8208;free water electrolysis system to overcome these two obstacles simultaneously. This system utilizes the thermodynamically more favorable urea oxidation reaction (UOR) to generate clean N2 over a new class of Cu&#8208;based catalyst (CuXO), fundamentally eliminating the explosion risk of H2 and O2 mixing while removing the need for membranes. Notably, this membrane&#8208;free electrolysis system exhibits the highest H2 Faradaic efficiency among reported membrane&#8208;free electrolysis work. In situ spectroscopic studies reveal that the new N2Hy intermediate&#8208;mediated UOR mechanism on the CuXO catalyst ensures its unique N2 selectivity and OER inertness. More importantly, an industrial&#8208;type membrane&#8208;free water electrolyser (MFE) based on this system successfully reduces electricity consumption to only 3.87 kWh Nm&#8722;3, significantly lower than the 5.17 kWh Nm&#8722;3 of commercial alkaline water electrolyzers (AWE). Comprehensive techno&#8208;economic analysis (TEA) suggests that the membrane&#8208;free design and reduced electricity input of the MFE plants reduce the green H2 production cost to US$1.81 kg&#8722;1, which is lower than those of grey H2 while meeting the technical target (US$2.00&#8211;2.50 kg&#8722;1) set by European Commission and United States Department of Energy.</description>
      <author>Xintong Gao, Pengtang Wang, Xiaojie Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202417987</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon quantum dot-mediated binary metal&#8211;organic framework nanosheets for efficient oxygen evolution at ampere-level current densities in proton exchange membrane electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06855f</link>
      <description>Qingbao Ni, Shi&#8208;Yuan Zhang, Kang Wang, Huazhang Guo, Jiye Zhang, Minghong Wu, Liang Wang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403966280

                The widespread utilization of noble metal-based catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is hindered by their rarity and substantial expense, posing significant challenges for large-scale applications.</description>
      <author>Qingbao Ni, Shi&#8208;Yuan Zhang, Kang Wang, Huazhang Guo, Jiye Zhang, Minghong Wu, Liang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06855f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moss-like CoB/CeO2 heterojunction as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction under alkaline conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02325k</link>
      <description>Weijie Fang, Chaofan Liu, Jiang Wu, Weikai Fan, Le Chen, Zaiguo Fu, Lin Peng, Ping He, Jia Lin, Zhongwei Chen, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403967473

                Heterostructure construction has become increasingly recognized as an effective strategy to enhance oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance due to the exposed active surfaces and improved mass/charge transfer. Inspired by natural...</description>
      <author>Weijie Fang, Chaofan Liu, Jiang Wu, Weikai Fan, Le Chen, Zaiguo Fu, Lin Peng, Ping He, Jia Lin, Zhongwei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02325k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-derived CeO2 Catalysts with Pr Doping: Engineering Oxygen Vacancies for Improved CO2 Conversion to Dimethyl Carbonate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05554c</link>
      <description>Jungseob So, Min Hye Jeong, Jungwon Yun, Bo An, Seung-Ik Kim, Geun-yeong Kim, Hyun&#8208;Tak Kim, Tae Sun Chang, Jin Hee Lee, Iljeong Heo, Jinjoo An, Young&#8208;Woo You, Min Kyu Kim, Young&#8208;Jin Kim, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403967478

                Producing dimethyl carbonate (DMC) from CO2 and methanol offers significant potential for carbon utilization. Ceria (CeO2) is a key catalyst due to its abundant oxygen vacancies essential for CO2 activation,...</description>
      <author>Jungseob So, Min Hye Jeong, Jungwon Yun, Bo An, Seung-Ik Kim, Geun-yeong Kim, Hyun&#8208;Tak Kim, Tae Sun Chang, Jin Hee Lee, Iljeong Heo, Jinjoo An, Young&#8208;Woo You, Min Kyu Kim, Young&#8208;Jin Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05554c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon-Modified Multicomponent-Doped Cr2o3 Oxide: An Efficient and Ultra Stable Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5007135</link>
      <description>Zeyu Jin, Yuelin Wang, Liulong Zhu, Jingzi Zhang, Xi Lin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403968639

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyu Jin, Yuelin Wang, Liulong Zhu, Jingzi Zhang, Xi Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5007135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing persimmon-liked FeOOH-(CrCo)Ox on the plasma-treated cobalt foam for a highly efficient oxygen evolution in an alkaline-seawater electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157098</link>
      <description>Ruixian Liu, Guangliang Chen, Yingchun Guo, Tongtong Li, Jinfeng Qiu, Bin He, Peisong Tang, Chemical Engineering Journal. 500(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403970831

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruixian Liu, Guangliang Chen, Yingchun Guo, Tongtong Li, Jinfeng Qiu, Bin He, Peisong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.157098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of strain, pH and oxygen-deficient on catalytic performance of Ruddlesden-Popper oxide Srn+1RunO3n+1 (n=1, 2) for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.405</link>
      <description>Jiahao Zhang, Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403971281

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiahao Zhang, Congcong Li, Chen Kang, Junfeng Ren, Meina Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.405</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wet sulfuration of molybdate and reconstruction regulation of trace Fe doping for oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.411</link>
      <description>Wenjing Li, Liu Xin, Hao Zhang, Jin&#8208;Long Tan, Yu Ma, Bin Liu, Ren&#8208;Qing Lv, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403971298

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenjing Li, Liu Xin, Hao Zhang, Jin&#8208;Long Tan, Yu Ma, Bin Liu, Ren&#8208;Qing Lv, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ route to sulfur-doped cobalt telluride nanowires for efficient oxygen evolution in alkaline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.416</link>
      <description>Zugao Pi, Jiangchu Hao, Shaofu Kuang, Ruijie Shi, Xinwei Li, Jianxin Wang, Hua Lin, Ming Nie, Qing Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403971373

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zugao Pi, Jiangchu Hao, Shaofu Kuang, Ruijie Shi, Xinwei Li, Jianxin Wang, Hua Lin, Ming Nie, Qing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.416</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and characterization of MoO3: application to the photo production of oxygen under visible light</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06589-1</link>
      <description>N. Koriche, Moussa Abbas, M. Trari, Journal of Sol-Gel Science and Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403972319

                No abstract</description>
      <author>N. Koriche, Moussa Abbas, M. Trari</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10971-024-06589-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic activities of iron-supported N-doped porous carbon towards the oxygen/hydrogen evolution reaction.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.121788</link>
      <description>Daniel Kobina Sam, Yan Cao, Renewable Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403972897

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Daniel Kobina Sam, Yan Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.renene.2024.121788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/Carbon Paper Electrocatalysts in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis by Atmospheric-Pressure Plasma Jet Treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03557</link>
      <description>Chu&#8208;Chen Chueh, Shuo-En Yu, Hsing-Chen Wu, Cheng&#8208;Che Hsu, I&#8208;Chih Ni, Chih&#8208;I Wu, I&#8208;Chun Cheng, Jian&#8208;Zhang Chen, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403972906

                NiMoO4 was grown on carbon paper (CP) by a hydrothermal method. A rapid and high-temperature atmospheric-pressure plasma jet (APPJ) process was used to generate more oxygen-deficient NiMoO4 on the CP surface to serve as an electrode material for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). After 60 s of APPJ treatment, the overpotential of the electrode at 100 mA/cm2 decreased to 790 mV and that at 10 mA/cm2 decreased to 368 mV. Additionally, the charge transfer resistance decreased from 2.8 to 1.2 &#937;, indicating that APPJ treatment effectively reduced the electrode overpotential and impedance. The effect of NiMoO4/CP/APPJ-60 s on the anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEMWE) system was also tested. At a system temperature of 70 &#176;C and current density of 100 mA/cm2, the energy efficiency reached 95.1%, and the specific energy consumption decreased from 4.02 to 3.83 kWh/m3. These results demonstrate that the APPJ-treated NiMoO4/CP electrode can effectively enhance the OER performance in water electrolysis and improve the energy efficiency of the AEMWE system. This approach shows promise in replacing precious metal electrodes, thereby potentially reducing the cost and providing an environmentally friendly alternative.</description>
      <author>Chu&#8208;Chen Chueh, Shuo-En Yu, Hsing-Chen Wu, Cheng&#8208;Che Hsu, I&#8208;Chih Ni, Chih&#8208;I Wu, I&#8208;Chun Cheng, Jian&#8208;Zhang Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03557</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique role of Mn(II) in enhancing electro-oxidation of organic pollutants on anodes with low oxygen evolution potential at low current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136332</link>
      <description>Erdan Hu, Yuhua Ye, Bing Wang, Hefa Cheng, Journal of Hazardous Materials. 480(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403973037

                This study systematically explored the role of Mn(II) in the removal of 4-chlorophenol (4-CP) by electro-oxidation (EO) employing anodes with low oxygen evolution potential (OEP), i.e., Ti/RuO</description>
      <author>Erdan Hu, Yuhua Ye, Bing Wang, Hefa Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jhazmat.2024.136332</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strontium doping RuO2 electrocatalyst with abundant oxygen vacancies for boosting OER performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02070g</link>
      <description>Bei An, Xiaoqian Li, L. Yuan, Fanfan Shang, Huijie He, Hairui Cai, Xiaoxiao Zeng, Weitong Wang, Shengchun Yang, Bin Wang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403973173

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a crucial role as the anode reaction of electrolytic water in various applications. To date, it is still a great challenge to develop highly active...</description>
      <author>Bei An, Xiaoqian Li, L. Yuan, Fanfan Shang, Huijie He, Hairui Cai, Xiaoxiao Zeng, Weitong Wang, Shengchun Yang, Bin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02070g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of reconstruction on CoOOH active species and oxygen evolution performance for Co9S8/Cu2S catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113413</link>
      <description>Fan He, Jing Wen, Ting Zhang, Yanyan Wang, Dongmei Zeng, Minmin Zou, You Zhang, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403973658

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fan He, Jing Wen, Ting Zhang, Yanyan Wang, Dongmei Zeng, Minmin Zou, You Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113413</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution enabled by porous Eu-Ni(PO3)2 nanosheet arrays</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.11.001</link>
      <description>Pu Wang, Xiangrui Wu, Meng Li, Xuan Wang, Huiyu Wang, Qiuzi Huang, Hao Li, Yawen Tang, Gengtao Fu, Journal of Rare Earths. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403978086

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pu Wang, Xiangrui Wu, Meng Li, Xuan Wang, Huiyu Wang, Qiuzi Huang, Hao Li, Yawen Tang, Gengtao Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jre.2024.11.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced electrocatalysts for hydrogen and oxygen evolution in proton exchange membrane electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24062-1.00002-4</link>
      <description>Williane da Silva Freitas, Barbara Mecheri, Alessandra D&#8217;Epifanio, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403978627

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Williane da Silva Freitas, Barbara Mecheri, Alessandra D&#8217;Epifanio</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-443-24062-1.00002-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous CoFePO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; hollow nanocubes decorated with g-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; quantum dots to achieve efficient electrocatalytic performance in the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02564d</link>
      <description>Ke Yuan, Wei Zhou, Xiaoyan Zhu, Weihua Ou, Minzhe Chen, Chuheng Zhu, Ningning Chen, Haofeng Zuo, Aocheng Wang, Dengke Zhao, Maozhong An, Ligui Li, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403983909

                g-C 3 N 4 quantum dots decorated on amorphous CoFePOx hollow nanocubes can effectively adjust the electronic structure of CoFePOx substrates and substantially improve the electrocatalytic activity of amorphous CoFePOx nanocubes for oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Ke Yuan, Wei Zhou, Xiaoyan Zhu, Weihua Ou, Minzhe Chen, Chuheng Zhu, Ningning Chen, Haofeng Zuo, Aocheng Wang, Dengke Zhao, Maozhong An, Ligui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02564d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron (III)-Facilitated reconstruction in NiMn layered double hydroxides for initiating rapid oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.257</link>
      <description>Qiang Lv, Haoran Guo, Yuling Zhai, Hua Wang, Tao Zhu, Xing Zhu, Kongzhai Li, Zhishan Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403985914

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiang Lv, Haoran Guo, Yuling Zhai, Hua Wang, Tao Zhu, Xing Zhu, Kongzhai Li, Zhishan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.257</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;A review of efficient electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction at large current density&#8221; [DeCarbon 5 (2024) 100062]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.decarb.2024.100080</link>
      <description>Youtao Yao, Jiahui Lyu, Xingchuan Li, Cheng Chen, Francis Verpoort, John Wang, Zhenghui Pan, Zongkui Kou, DeCarbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403986635

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Youtao Yao, Jiahui Lyu, Xingchuan Li, Cheng Chen, Francis Verpoort, John Wang, Zhenghui Pan, Zongkui Kou</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.decarb.2024.100080</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppression of structural distortion in Vanadium-doped nickel MOFs for enhanced stability and activity in oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.375</link>
      <description>Jiaqing Liu, Wenhao Li, Shijuan Song, Hao Cui, Wenhao Lu, Tingting Du, Shouxin Zhang, Fengchun Yang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 93(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403999033

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqing Liu, Wenhao Li, Shijuan Song, Hao Cui, Wenhao Lu, Tingting Du, Shouxin Zhang, Fengchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.375</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot synthesis of graphene nanosheets&#8209;nickel cobalt LDHs nanocomposite for electrocatalysis of oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111738</link>
      <description>Masoud Moradi, Shahram Ghasemi, Farimah Mousavi, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404005935

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Masoud Moradi, Shahram Ghasemi, Farimah Mousavi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111738</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-Entropy Prussian Blue Analogue Derived Heterostructure Nanoparticles as Bifunctional Oxygen Conversion Electrocatalysts for the Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13387</link>
      <description>Wuttichai Tanmathusorachai, Sofiannisa Aulia, Mia Rinawati, Ling&#8208;Yu Chang, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Ming&#8208;Hsien Lin, Wei&#8208;Nien Su, Brian Yuliarto, Min&#8208;Hsin Yeh, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404019340

                In response to energy challenges, rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (RZABs) serve as an ideal platform for energy storage with a high energy density and safety. Nevertheless, addressing the sluggish oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in RZAB requires highly active and robust electrocatalysts. High-entropy Prussian blue analogues (HEPBAs), formed by mixing diverse metals within a single lattice, exhibit enhanced stability due to their increased mixing entropy, which lowers the Gibbs free energy. HEPBAs innately enable sacrificial templating, an effective way to synthesize complex structures. Impressively, in this study, we successfully transform HEPBAs into exquisite multiphase (multimetallic alloy, metal carbide, and metal oxide) heterostructure nanoparticles through a controlled synthesis process. The elusive multiphase heterostructure nanoparticles manifested two active sites for selective ORR and OER. By integrating CNT into HEPBA-derived nanoparticles (HEPBA/CNT-800), the HEPBA/CNT-800 demonstrates superior activity toward both ORR (E1/2 = 0.77 V) in a 0.1 M KOH solution and the OER (&#951; = 330 mV at 50 mA cm&#8211;2) in a 1 M KOH solution. The RZAB with a HEPBA/CNT-based air electrode demonstrated an open-circuit voltage of 1.39 V and provided a significant energy density of 71 mW cm&#8211;2. Moreover, the charge and discharge cycles lasting up to 40 h at a current density of 5 mA cm&#8211;2 demonstrate its excellent stability. This work provides an alternative avenue for the rational design of HEPBA's derivative for a sustainable rechargeable metal&#8211;air battery platform.</description>
      <author>Wuttichai Tanmathusorachai, Sofiannisa Aulia, Mia Rinawati, Ling&#8208;Yu Chang, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Wei&#8208;Hsiang Huang, Ming&#8208;Hsien Lin, Wei&#8208;Nien Su, Brian Yuliarto, Min&#8208;Hsin Yeh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13387</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local compressive strain-induced anti-corrosion over isolated Ru-decorated Co3O4 for efficient acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53763-8</link>
      <description>Shouwei Zuo, Zhi&#8208;Peng Wu, Deting Xu, Rafia Ahmad, Lirong Zheng, Jing Zhang, Lina Zhao, Wenhuan Huang, Hassan Al Qahtani, Han Yu, Luigi Cavallo, Huabin Zhang, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404020591

                Enhancing corrosion resistance is essential for developing efficient electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we report the strategic manipulation of the local compressive strain to reinforce the anti-corrosion properties of the non-precious Co3O4 support. The incorporation of Ru single atoms, larger in atomic size than Co, into the Co3O4 lattice (Ru-Co3O4), triggers localized strain compression and lattice distortion on the Co-O lattice. A comprehensive exploration of the correlation between this specific local compressive strain and electrocatalytic performance is conducted through experimental and theoretical analyses. The presence of the localized strain in Ru-Co3O4 is confirmed by operando X-ray absorption studies and supported by quantum calculations. This local strain, presented in a shortened Co-O bond length, enhances the anti-corrosion properties of Co3O4 by suppressing metal dissolutions. Consequently, Ru-Co3O4 shows satisfactory stability, maintaining OER for over 400 hours at 30 mA cm&#8722;2 with minimal decay. This study demonstrates the potential of the local strain effect in fortifying catalyst stability for acidic OER and beyond. Enhancing corrosion resistance is crucial for efficient electrocatalysts in the acidic oxygen evolution reaction. Here, the authors report the strategic manipulation of local compressive strain to improve the anti-corrosion properties of Co3O4, demonstrating stability for over 400 hours at 30 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Shouwei Zuo, Zhi&#8208;Peng Wu, Deting Xu, Rafia Ahmad, Lirong Zheng, Jing Zhang, Lina Zhao, Wenhuan Huang, Hassan Al Qahtani, Han Yu, Luigi Cavallo, Huabin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53763-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Manipulating the d- and p-Band centers of amorphous alloys by variable composition for robust oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.007</link>
      <description>Yuci Xin, Yong Wu, Xing&#8217;an Dong, Yuhan Li, Zhenxiang Cheng, Jianli Wang, Xiaolong Guo, Peng Yu, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404025876

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuci Xin, Yong Wu, Xing&#8217;an Dong, Yuhan Li, Zhenxiang Cheng, Jianli Wang, Xiaolong Guo, Peng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the synergistic mechanism of Co-Cu catalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.137659</link>
      <description>Zeliang Ju, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Chengfeng Yin, Qingxin Kang, Materials Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404026191

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeliang Ju, Xiujuan Tan, X.Y. Zhang, Yong Wang, Chengfeng Yin, Qingxin Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.137659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interference mechanism of electrolyte cations on vanadium-oxygen binary doped carbon nitride for hydrogen evolution from artificial seawater splitting: coupling experiments, DFT calculations and machine learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124781</link>
      <description>Longde Jiang, Jingde Luan, Haowei Zhang, Yu Bai, Yu Zhang, Wengang Liu, Zheng Yan, Haiting Zhao, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404029121

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Longde Jiang, Jingde Luan, Haowei Zhang, Yu Bai, Yu Zhang, Wengang Liu, Zheng Yan, Haiting Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124781</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique Nano-Flower Structure Catalyst: Feconi-S/Nf for High Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5009597</link>
      <description>Nana Gao, Zhengyuan Liu, Yaqiong Gong, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404029253

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nana Gao, Zhengyuan Liu, Yaqiong Gong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5009597</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structurally ordered FeCo@FeCoO @NC dual-shell nanoparticles synthesized under micro-oxygen conditions: an efficient cocatalyst for BiVO4 photoelectrochemical water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124779</link>
      <description>Kaixin Zhang, Jiarui Du, Dongni Luo, Huibin Shi, Jiangxin Wang, Juan Zhang, Xiutao Liu, Minmin Liu, Kuanhong Mei, Daliang Liu, Yu Zhang, Shuo Li, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404029385

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaixin Zhang, Jiarui Du, Dongni Luo, Huibin Shi, Jiangxin Wang, Juan Zhang, Xiutao Liu, Minmin Liu, Kuanhong Mei, Daliang Liu, Yu Zhang, Shuo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124779</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen vacancy-rich Nd-doped RuO2 for efficient acid overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118756</link>
      <description>Boyan Ai, Guoxiang Wang, Peng Liang, Jueming Bing, Majie Zhang, Qingwang Min, Shouxin Zhang, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404031696

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Boyan Ai, Guoxiang Wang, Peng Liang, Jueming Bing, Majie Zhang, Qingwang Min, Shouxin Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118756</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I3&#8208;&#8208;Mediated Oxygen Evolution Activities to Boost Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Battery Performance with Low Charging Voltage and Long Cycling Life</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416235</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Zou, Qian L&#252;, Lizhen Wu, Kouer Zhang, Mingcong Tang, Haijiao Xie, Xiao Zhang, Zongping Shao, Liang An, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404041800

                An effective strategy to facilitate oxygen redox chemistry in metal&#8208;air batteries is to introduce a redox mediator into the liquid electrolyte. The rational utilization of redox mediators to accelerate the charging kinetics while ensuring the long lifetime of alkaline Zn&#8208;air batteries is challenging. Here, we apply commercial acetylene black catalysts to achieve an I3&#8208;&#8208;mediated Zn&#8208;air battery by using ZnI2 additives that provide I3&#8208; to accelerate the cathodic redox chemistry and regulate the uniform deposition of Zn2+ on the anode. The Zn&#8208;air battery performs an ultra&#8208;long cycle life of over 600 h at 5 mA cm&#8208;2 with a final charge voltage of 1.87 V. We demonstrate that I&#8208; mainly generates I3&#8208; on the surface of carbon catalysts during the electrochemically charging process, which can further chemically react with OH&#8208; to generate oxygen and further revert to I&#8208;, thus obtaining a stable electrochemical system. This work offers a strategy to simultaneously improve the cycling life and reduce the charging voltage of Zn&#8208;air batteries through redox mediator methods.</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Zou, Qian L&#252;, Lizhen Wu, Kouer Zhang, Mingcong Tang, Haijiao Xie, Xiao Zhang, Zongping Shao, Liang An</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I3&#8208;&#8208;Mediated Oxygen Evolution Activities to Boost Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Battery Performance with Low Charging Voltage and Long Cycling Life</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416235</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Zou, Qian L&#252;, Lizhen Wu, Kouer Zhang, Mingcong Tang, Haijiao Xie, Xiao Zhang, Zongping Shao, Liang An, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404041886

                An effective strategy to facilitate oxygen redox chemistry in metal-air batteries is to introduce a redox mediator into the liquid electrolyte. The rational utilization of redox mediators to accelerate the charging kinetics while ensuring the long lifetime of alkaline Zn-air batteries is challenging. Here, we apply commercial acetylene black catalysts to achieve an I3--mediated Zn-air battery by using ZnI2 additives that provide I3- to accelerate the cathodic redox chemistry and regulate the uniform deposition of Zn2+ on the anode. The Zn-air battery performs an ultra-long cycle life of over 600 h at 5 mA cm-2 with a final charge voltage of 1.87 V. We demonstrate that I- mainly generates I3- on the surface of carbon catalysts during the electrochemically charging process, which can further chemically react with OH- to generate oxygen and further revert to I-, thus obtaining a stable electrochemical system. This work offers a strategy to simultaneously improve the cycling life and reduce the charging voltage of Zn-air batteries through redox mediator methods.</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Zou, Qian L&#252;, Lizhen Wu, Kouer Zhang, Mingcong Tang, Haijiao Xie, Xiao Zhang, Zongping Shao, Liang An</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416235</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hypothesis on the Function of High&#8208;Valent Fe in NiFe (Hydr)oxide in the Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418798</link>
      <description>Nader Akbari, Jafar Hussain Shah, Cejun Hu, Subhajit Nandy, P. Aleshkevych, Rile Ge, Sumbal Farid, Changchang Dong, Shouxin Zhang, Keun Hwa Chae, Wei Xie, Taifeng Liu, Junhu Wang, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404043796

                This study investigated the dynamic changes in NiFe (hydr)oxide and identified the role of high&#8208;valent Fe in the oxygen&#8208;evolution reaction (OER) within alkaline media via in&#8208;situ techniques. Several high&#8208;valent Fe ions were found to remain considerably stable in the absence of potential in NiFe (hydr)oxide, even 96 hours after the OER. For Ni2+ hydroxide treated with 57Fe ions, where Fe sites are introduced onto the surface of Ni2+ hydroxide, no Fe4+ species were detected at the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS). The findings of this study suggested that the oxidation of bulk Fe ions, similar to Ni ions, to high valent forms, is charge accumulation without a direct role in OER; these results offered a novel perspective on manipulating Fe states to optimize OER efficacy. The prevailing hypothesis suggested that trace amounts of high&#8208;valent Fe ions, notably those on the surface, directly participate in OER.</description>
      <author>Nader Akbari, Jafar Hussain Shah, Cejun Hu, Subhajit Nandy, P. Aleshkevych, Rile Ge, Sumbal Farid, Changchang Dong, Shouxin Zhang, Keun Hwa Chae, Wei Xie, Taifeng Liu, Junhu Wang, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202418798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hypothesis on the Function of High&#8208;Valent Fe in NiFe (Hydr)oxide in the Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418798</link>
      <description>Nader Akbari, Jafar Hussain Shah, Cejun Hu, Subhajit Nandy, P. Aleshkevych, Rile Ge, Sumbal Farid, Changchang Dong, Shouxin Zhang, Keun Hwa Chae, Wei Xie, Taifeng Liu, Junhu Wang, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404043975

                This study investigated the dynamic changes in NiFe (hydr)oxide and identified the role of high&#8208;valent Fe in the oxygen&#8208;evolution reaction (OER) within alkaline media via in&#8208;situ techniques. Several high&#8208;valent Fe ions were found to remain considerably stable in the absence of potential in NiFe (hydr)oxide, even 96 hours after the OER. For Ni2+ hydroxide treated with 57Fe ions, where Fe sites are introduced onto the surface of Ni2+ hydroxide, no Fe4+ species were detected at the rate&#8208;determining step (RDS). The findings of this study suggested that the oxidation of bulk Fe ions, similar to Ni ions, to high valent forms, is charge accumulation without a direct role in OER; these results offered a novel perspective on manipulating Fe states to optimize OER efficacy. The prevailing hypothesis suggested that trace amounts of high&#8208;valent Fe ions, notably those on the surface, directly participate in OER.</description>
      <author>Nader Akbari, Jafar Hussain Shah, Cejun Hu, Subhajit Nandy, P. Aleshkevych, Rile Ge, Sumbal Farid, Changchang Dong, Shouxin Zhang, Keun Hwa Chae, Wei Xie, Taifeng Liu, Junhu Wang, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202418798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt phosphate nanorod bundles for efficient supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction applications and their temperature dependence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03712j</link>
      <description>Sushama M. Nikam, Suhas H. Sutar, S. D. Jituri, Akbar I. Inamdar, S.H. Mujawar, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404044590

                Cobalt phosphates have been synthesized using a successive ionic layer adsorption and reaction (SILAR) method and studied their supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction performances.</description>
      <author>Sushama M. Nikam, Suhas H. Sutar, S. D. Jituri, Akbar I. Inamdar, S.H. Mujawar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03712j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Defect Site Filling Strategy Induced Moderate Enrichment of Reactants for Efficient Electrocatalytic Biomass Upgrading</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202410725</link>
      <description>Baixue Cheng, Haoyu Zhan, Yankun Lu, Danning Xing, Xingshuai Lv, Thomas Frauenheim, Peng Zhou, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404045918

                Abstract The electrocatalytic oxidation of 5&#8208;hydroxymethylfurfural (HMF) provides a feasible approach for the efficient utilization of biomass. Defect regulation is an effective strategy in the field of biomass upgrading to enhance the adsorption capacity of reactants and thus increase the activity. However, how to select appropriate strategies to regulate the over&#8208;enrichment of reactants induced by excessive oxygen vacancy is still a huge challenge. In this work, the defect&#8208;filling strategy to design and construct an element&#8208;filled oxygen vacancy site layered double hydroxide (S&#9472;Ov&#9472;LDH) is adopted, which achieves a significant reduction in the electrolysis potential of biomass platform molecule HMF oxidation reaction and a significant increase in current density. Physical characterizations, electrochemical measurements, and theoretical calculations prove that the formation of metal&#9472;S bond in the second shell effectively regulates the electronic structure of the material, thus weakening the over&#8208;strong adsorption of HMF and OH &#8722; induced by excessive oxygen vacancy, promoting the formation of high&#8208;valence Co 3+ during the reaction, and forming new adsorption sites. This work discusses the catalytic enhancement mechanism of defect filling in detail, fills the gap of defect filling in the field of biomass upgrading, and provides favorable guidance for the further development of defect regulation strategies.</description>
      <author>Baixue Cheng, Haoyu Zhan, Yankun Lu, Danning Xing, Xingshuai Lv, Thomas Frauenheim, Peng Zhou, Shuangyin Wang, Yuqin Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202410725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ROLE OF SURFACTANTS ON ELECTROCATALYTIC ACTIVITY OF Co/Al LAYERED DOUBLE HYDROXIDES FOR HYDROGEN AND OXYGEN GENERATION</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401377</link>
      <description>Honey John, Sijla Rosely, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404048424

                Layered double hydroxides (LDHs) have recently attracted much attention in the scientific community as a prominent catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) because they are economical, extremely stable and highly active. Here, we synthesized Co/Al based LDH systems that efficiently perform as bi&#8208;functional electrocatalysts for both HER and OER. Exfoliation of this layered material via anion intercalation into a few layers further enhanced its activity. In this work, we reported the synthesis of Co/Al LDHs via co&#8208;precipitation followed by hydrothermal method and different surfactant functionalized LDHs (with anionic surfactant &#8211;SDS, cationic surfactant &#8211; CTAB and non&#8208;ionic surfactant &#8211; PEG 4000). SDS modified LDH (s LDH) showed notable stability and competent results in hydrogen evolution in addition to oxygen evolution. The exfoliation of s LDH caused enhancement in the high specific surface area about 6.8 times compared to pristine LDH, as evident from BET data. The onset potential for HER as obtained from the polarisation curve for s LDH is &#8208;0.41 V vs RHE with Tafel slope of 67.4 mV/dec. Similarly, OER onset potential and corresponding Tafel slope are 1.53 V vs RHE at 10 mA/cm2 and 90.2 mV/dec, respectively.</description>
      <author>Honey John, Sijla Rosely</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401377</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy&#8208;Electron Polarons Featured InSnRuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxides: Orderly and Concerted In&#8208;Ov&#8208;Ru&#8208;O&#8208;Sn Substructures for Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414579</link>
      <description>Yanhui Sun, Mingyue Xiao, Feng Liu, Jun Gan, Shixin Gao, Jingjun Liu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404051498

                Abstract Polymetallic oxides with extraordinary electrons/geometry structure ensembles, trimmed electron bands, and way&#8208;out coordination environments, built by an isomorphic substitution strategy, may create unique contributing to concertedly catalyze water oxidation, which is of great significance for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). Herein, well&#8208;defined rutile InSnRuO 2 oxides with density&#8208;controllable oxygen vacancy (Ov)&#8208;free electron polarons are firstly fabricated by in situ isomorphic substitution, using trivalent In species as Ov generators and the adjacent metal ions as electron donors to form orderly and concerted In&#8208;Ov&#8208;Ru&#8208;O&#8208;Sn substructures in the tetravalent oxides. For acidic water oxidation, the obtained InSnRuO 2 displays an ultralow overpotential of 183 mV (versus RHE) and a mass activity (MA) of 103.02 A mg Ru &#8722;1 , respectively. For a long&#8208;term stability test of PEMWE, it can run at a low and unchangeable cell potential (1.56 V) for 200 h at 50 mA cm &#8722;2 , far exceeding current IrO 2 ||Pt/C assembly in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 . Accelerated degradation testing results of PEMWE with pure water as the electrolyte show no significant increase in voltage even when the voltage is gradually increased from 1 to 5 A cm &#8722;2 . The remarkably improved performance is associated with the concerted In&#8208;Ov&#8208;Ru&#8208;O&#8208;Sn substructures stabilized by the dense Ov&#8208;electron polarons, which synergistically activates band structure of oxygen species and adjacent Ru sites and then boosting the oxygen evolution kinetics. More importantly, the self&#8208;trapped Ov&#8208;electron polaron induces a decrease in the entropy and enthalpy, and efficiently hinder Ru atoms leaching by increasing the lattice atom diffusion energy barrier, achieves long&#8208;term stability of the oxide. This work may open a door to design next&#8208;generation Ru&#8208;based catalysts with polarons to create orderly and asymmetric substructures as active sites for efficient electrocatalysis in PEMWE application.</description>
      <author>Yanhui Sun, Mingyue Xiao, Feng Liu, Jun Gan, Shixin Gao, Jingjun Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202414579</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the role of solvents in structural regulation during ultrasonic synthesis of Co/Ni-layered double hydroxide for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matre.2024.100296</link>
      <description>Zhaojin Li, Qian Ma, Zezhao Li, Di Zhang, Qujiang Sun, Qiujun Wang, Huilan Sun, Bo Wang, Materials Reports Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404053566

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaojin Li, Qian Ma, Zezhao Li, Di Zhang, Qujiang Sun, Qiujun Wang, Huilan Sun, Bo Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matre.2024.100296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Front Cover: Exploring the Impact of Oxygen Vacancies in Co/Pr&#8208;CeO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts on H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production via the Water&#8208;Gas Shift Reaction (Chem. Asian J. 21/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202482101</link>
      <description>Pallavi Saini, Paramita Koley, Devaiah Damma, Deshetti Jampaiah, Suresh K. Bhargava, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. 19(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404055436

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Pallavi Saini, Paramita Koley, Devaiah Damma, Deshetti Jampaiah, Suresh K. Bhargava</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202482101</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sea urchin-like sulfur-doped Ni(OH)2 as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05909-3</link>
      <description>Fang Wu, Jinlong Ge, Yujun Zhu, Yuhong Jiao, Zhong Wu, Chao Feng, Yupei Zhao, Lin Qiu, Ionics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404060637

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fang Wu, Jinlong Ge, Yujun Zhu, Yuhong Jiao, Zhong Wu, Chao Feng, Yupei Zhao, Lin Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11581-024-05909-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Proof-of-Principle Demonstration: Exploring the Effect of Anode Layer Microstructure on the Alkaline Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31224/4088</link>
      <description>Adarsh Jain, Christian Marcks, Lars Grebener, Jacob Johny, Ahammed Suhail Odungat, Mohit Chatwani, Mena&#8208;Alexander Kr&#228;enbring, Ashin Shaji, Marc F. Tesch, Anna K. Mechler, Vineetha Vinayakumar, Doris Segets, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061807

                This study explores the effect of Ni-Co-O anode layer microstructure on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Four anodes with similar Ni-Co-O loadings and chemical characteristics but distinct morphologies are fabricated by ultrasonic spraying catalyst inks of varying solvent composition (pure water vs a water-ethanol mixture) and drying temperatures (50 &#176;C and 150 &#176;C) on Ni plates. Upon varying solvent composition, particles in the water-based ink exhibited lower stability than particles in the water-ethanol-based ink, boosting the particle connectivity in the layers. This particle connectivity correlated with the mechanical strength of the layers, resulting in reduced contact resistance and enhanced activity. Our second observation is that at 50 &#176;C, the surface morphology exhibited hill-like islands with higher roughness, while at 150 &#176;C, concave hemispherical shapes with lower roughness were observed. From 2D-distribution data, we found that surface roughness correlated with the wettability with electrolyte. Roughness increased the lyophobicity and enhanced the activity through more accessible active sites and efficient bubble transport. Taken together, this work highlights how microstructure affects macroscopic layer properties, and how these in turn can enhance or diminish the performance of the OER compared to bare nickel, offering insights into the knowledge-based design of anode layers.</description>
      <author>Adarsh Jain, Christian Marcks, Lars Grebener, Jacob Johny, Ahammed Suhail Odungat, Mohit Chatwani, Mena&#8208;Alexander Kr&#228;enbring, Ashin Shaji, Marc F. Tesch, Anna K. Mechler, Vineetha Vinayakumar, Doris Segets</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31224/4088</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of oxygen evolution reaction performance for Ni and Co using isostructural &lt;i&gt;trans&#8208;cinnamate&lt;/i&gt; complexes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/bkcs.12910</link>
      <description>Hyewon Shin, Sunwoo Geum, Jimin Lee, Minkyun Shin, Kang Min Ok, Seong Jung Kwon, Junghwan Do, Bulletin of the Korean Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404062455

                Abstract Efforts are underway to develop highly active catalysts to reduce the high overpotential of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Metal&#8211;organic frameworks or coordination polymers are promising candidates because of their tunable structures and high surface areas. In this study, Nickel and Cobalt trans &#8208; cinnamate ( t&#8208;ca ) were synthesized via a hydrothermal method. Their structures were analyzed and found to be isostructural. Both complexes exhibited superior electrocatalytic properties in the OER compared to those of IrO 2 , with overpotentials of 373 and 390 mV and Tafel slopes of 58 and 66 mV/dec. These excellent characteristics were attributed to the electron delocalization of the metal centers via interactions with &#960;&#8208;&#960; delocalized organic ligands. Ni t&#8208;ca , with stronger ligand interactions, displayed an enhanced OER catalytic performance, emphasizing the importance of metal&#8211;ligand interactions and suggesting that further exploration of diverse &#960;&#8211;&#960; delocalized organic ligands and metal centers may lead to further advancements in electrocatalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Hyewon Shin, Sunwoo Geum, Jimin Lee, Minkyun Shin, Kang Min Ok, Seong Jung Kwon, Junghwan Do</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/bkcs.12910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolessly Deposited Cobalt-Phosphorous Coatings for Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202411.0177.v1</link>
      <description>Huma Amber, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Zita Sukackien&#279;, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Eugenijus Norkus, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404063158

                Hydrogen production by water splitting is one of the low-cost green hydrogen production technologies. The challenge is to develop inexpensive and highly active catalysts. Herein, we present the preparation of electrocatalysts based on cobalt-phosphorus (Co-P) coatings with different P contents for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER). The Co-P coatings were deposited on the copper (Cu) surface using the inexpensive and simple method of electroless metal deposition. The morphology, structure, and composition of the Co-P coatings deposited on the Cu surface were studied by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDX), while their activity for HER and OER in 1 M KOH was investigated by linear sweep voltammetry (LSVs) and chrono-techniques. It was found that the catalyst activity for both HER and OER depends on the P content of the catalyst and varies to the highest efficiency for each reaction. The Co-P coating with the 11 wt% of P exhibited the lowest overpotential value of &#8211;115.4 mV for the HER to obtain a current density of 10 mA cm-2 compared to the Co-P coatings with 8 wt% (&#8211;121.5 mV) and 5 wt% (&#8211;182.9 mV) of P. In contrast, the lowest OER overpotential (394 mV) was observed for the Co-P coating with the 8 wt% of P to obtain a current density of 10 mA cm-2 as compared to the Co-P coatings with 5 wt% (416 mV) and 11 wt% (432 mV) of P. These results suggest that the obtained catalysts are suitable for HER and OER in alkaline media.</description>
      <author>Huma Amber, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Zita Sukackien&#279;, Loreta Tama&#353;auskait&#279;&#8211;Tama&#353;i&#363;nait&#279;, Eugenijus Norkus</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202411.0177.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ formation of oxygen-deficient WO3-x nanosheets for enhanced photocatalytic activity in water splitting and plastic reforming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100421</link>
      <description>Yangsen Xu, Wenwu Shi, Baoling Huang, Shuang Tang, Zhou Jin, Yonghao Xiao, Feifei Lu, Xinzhong Wang, Next Materials. 6(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404063674

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yangsen Xu, Wenwu Shi, Baoling Huang, Shuang Tang, Zhou Jin, Yonghao Xiao, Feifei Lu, Xinzhong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100421</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sacrificial Fe sites making 2D heterostructure an efficient catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07179d</link>
      <description>Suraj Loomba, Muhammad Waqas Khan, Ashakiran Maibam, Muhammad Haris, Sharafadeen Gbadamasi, Vasundhara Nettem, Seyed Mahdi Mousavi, Anton Tadich, Lars Thomsen, K. D. Jain, Babar Shabbir, Asif Mahmood, Ravichandar Babarao, Xian Jian, Nasir Mahmood, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404065387

                Hydrogen via direct seawater splitting is a viable option, but anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) faces challenges when seawater is used, and to realize seawater splitting at full potential, efficient...</description>
      <author>Suraj Loomba, Muhammad Waqas Khan, Ashakiran Maibam, Muhammad Haris, Sharafadeen Gbadamasi, Vasundhara Nettem, Seyed Mahdi Mousavi, Anton Tadich, Lars Thomsen, K. D. Jain, Babar Shabbir, Asif Mahmood, Ravichandar Babarao, Xian Jian, Nasir Mahmood</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta07179d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enabling High&#8208;Rate and Long&#8208;Cycling Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries with a &#916;&lt;i&gt;E&lt;/i&gt; = 0.56 V Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413562</link>
      <description>Juan Wang, Xuan&#8208;Qi Fang, Jia&#8208;Ning Liu, Yun&#8208;Wei Song, Meng Zhao, Bo&#8208;Quan Li, Jia&#8208;Qi Huang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404068062

                Abstract Zn&#8211;air batteries (ZABs) are promising next&#8208;generation energy storage devices due to their low cost, intrinsic safety, and environmental benignity. However, the sluggish kinetics of the cathodic reactions severely limits the ZAB performances in practical use, calling for high&#8208;efficiency bifunctional oxygen reduction and evolution electrocatalysts. Herein, an ultrahigh&#8208;active bifunctional electrocatalyst is developed with a record&#8208;low &#916; E of 0.56 V, significantly outperforming the noble&#8208;metal&#8208;based benchmark (Pt/C+Ir/C, &#916; E = 0.77 V) and many other reported bifunctional electrocatalysts (mostly &#916; E &#8805; 0.60 V). The nanoscale composite of Fe&#8208;based single&#8208;atom sites and nanosized layered double hydroxides endows the bifunctional electrocatalyst with high conductivity and a large active surface that afford strengthened electron conduction and ion transport pathways. Furthermore, a remarkable improvement in stability is realized following the current division principle. ZABs with the bifunctional electrocatalyst deliver a high peak power density of 198 mW cm &#8722;2 and excellent cycling durability for over 6000 cycles. Moreover, ampere&#8208;hour&#8208;scale ZABs are constructed and cycled under 1.0 A and 1.0 Ah conditions. This work breaks the activity record for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis and expands the potential of ZABs for sustainable energy storage.</description>
      <author>Juan Wang, Xuan&#8208;Qi Fang, Jia&#8208;Ning Liu, Yun&#8208;Wei Song, Meng Zhao, Bo&#8208;Quan Li, Jia&#8208;Qi Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating Oxygen Evolution with Low Symmetry Complex Ion of Tricyanidoferrate as a Catalytic Precursor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5006014</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhou, Yingzi Li, Xuan Hao, Zi Wei, Yan Zhong, Zhiwei Lai, Lei Zhu, Zhenyuan Ji, Guoxing Zhu, Xiaoping Shen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403942873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhou, Yingzi Li, Xuan Hao, Zi Wei, Yan Zhong, Zhiwei Lai, Lei Zhu, Zhenyuan Ji, Guoxing Zhu, Xiaoping Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.5006014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The effects of Co doping for Fe metal on boosting hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133558</link>
      <description>Xuxin Song, Chunyan Fan, Yao Tang, Yangyang Ren, Zehao Zang, Lanlan Li, Xiaofei Yu, Zunming Lu, Xiaojing Yang, Xinghua Zhang, Fuel. 381(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403917411

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuxin Song, Chunyan Fan, Yao Tang, Yangyang Ren, Zehao Zang, Lanlan Li, Xiaofei Yu, Zunming Lu, Xiaojing Yang, Xinghua Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.133558</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Calcium titanate corrosion inhibitor enabling carbon as inert anode for oxygen evolution in molten chlorides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1003-6326(24)66616-1</link>
      <description>Kaifa Du, Wenmiao Li, Peilin Wang, Lei Guo, Di Chen, Yongsong Ma, Rui Yu, Huayi Yin, Dihua Wang, Transactions of Nonferrous Metals Society of China. 34(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404061639

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kaifa Du, Wenmiao Li, Peilin Wang, Lei Guo, Di Chen, Yongsong Ma, Rui Yu, Huayi Yin, Dihua Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1003-6326(24)66616-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-MOF-based catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction: Microenvironment regulated by organic ligands, metals and carbonization synergistically</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120888</link>
      <description>Chenchen Ding, Weiwei Zhong, Yuqi Cao, Tingting Ma, Huimin Ye, Zheng Fang, Yirong Feng, Shuangfei Zhao, Jiming Yang, Yuguang Li, L. Shen, Wei He, Chemical Engineering Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403936537

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chenchen Ding, Weiwei Zhong, Yuqi Cao, Tingting Ma, Huimin Ye, Zheng Fang, Yirong Feng, Shuangfei Zhao, Jiming Yang, Yuguang Li, L. Shen, Wei He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ces.2024.120888</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breaking the Limitations of Activity and Stability in Powdered Materials for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: The Critical Role of Catalyst-Inducing Seeds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124777</link>
      <description>Weiliang Peng, Shaobo Li, Yuyin Li, Charles B. Musgrave, Bin Yuan, Basit Ali Shah, Renzong Hu, William A. Goddard, Zhengtang Luo, Min Zhu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404049313

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weiliang Peng, Shaobo Li, Yuyin Li, Charles B. Musgrave, Bin Yuan, Basit Ali Shah, Renzong Hu, William A. Goddard, Zhengtang Luo, Min Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124777</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling activity of transition metal single-atom sites on the graphene-like BC2P monolayer for oxygen evolution reaction: A density functional theory study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114648</link>
      <description>Xi Fu, Jian Lin, Guangyao Liang, Wenhu Liao, Haixia Gao, Xiaowu Li, Liming Li, Molecular Catalysis. 569(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403943389

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xi Fu, Jian Lin, Guangyao Liang, Wenhu Liao, Haixia Gao, Xiaowu Li, Liming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;The latest advances in the deep reconstruction of pre-catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction&#8221; [J. Alloys Compd. 1010, 5 January 2025, 177225]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177328</link>
      <description>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403991672

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterointerfacial engineering of N,P-doped carbon nanosheets supported Co/Co2P nanoparticles for boosting oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions towards rechargeable Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.011</link>
      <description>Wenhao Xi, Tongchen Wu, Pan Wang, Wenlong Huang, Bifen Gao, Liwen He, Yilin Chen, Bi&#8208;Zhou Lin, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404025895

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wenhao Xi, Tongchen Wu, Pan Wang, Wenlong Huang, Bifen Gao, Liwen He, Yilin Chen, Bi&#8208;Zhou Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.11.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal and Coordinating Atoms Synergistically Achieve High Activity and Stability in Single-Atom Catalysts within the Framework of TM&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;X for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Lithium Peroxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02447</link>
      <description>Luhong Chen, Qiang Ke, Xueling Lei, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403945735

                A critical challenge in the advancement of lithium-oxygen batteries (LOBs) is the difficulty in decomposing lithium peroxide, leading to high charge overpotentials and poor cycling stability. Single-atom catalysts (SACs), known for their ultrahigh catalytic activity in various electrochemical reactions, are expected to enhance the kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) for LOBs. Herein, 24 SACs within the framework of TM-N</description>
      <author>Luhong Chen, Qiang Ke, Xueling Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c02447</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Carrier Dynamics of BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanode via Dual Incorporation of Au and Co(OH)&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Cooperative Modification for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416091</link>
      <description>Xinchao Chen, Xiang Li, Youming Peng, Hao Yang, Yexiang Tong, Muhammad&#8208;Sadeeq Balogun, Yongchao Huang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403886209

                Abstract Photoelectrochemical solar to hydrogen production is a promising way to achieve carbon neutrality, but severe charge recombination in photoanodes limits the conversion efficiency. Herein, Au nanoparticles and Co(OH) x co&#8208;sensitized bismuth vanadate (BiVO 4 ) to construct AuCo(OH) x /BiVO 4 photoanode for significantly enhancing the performance of photoelectrochemical water splitting. This process significantly improves the bulk charge carrier separation efficiency, the surface kinetics of water oxidation, and the electron density of BiVO 4 photoanode through Au surface plasmon resonance (SPR) and Co(OH) x oxygen evolution catalysts effect. Additionally, the enhancement of the *O and the *OOH generation accelerate the oxygen evolution reaction kinetics. Consequently, the constructed AuCo(OH) x /BiVO 4 photoanode demonstrates an excellent photocurrent of 6.2 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode and a stable continuous output within 42 h. This work contributes to developing high&#8208;efficiency and high&#8208;stability photoanodes for solar H 2 production through SPR effect and oxygen evolution catalysts.</description>
      <author>Xinchao Chen, Xiang Li, Youming Peng, Hao Yang, Yexiang Tong, Muhammad&#8208;Sadeeq Balogun, Yongchao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416091</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing self-standing Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-Pt/NF nanoflowers with synergistic active sites for efficient electrocatalytic overall (sea) water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03572k</link>
      <description>Weiping Xiao, Yue Zhang, Changwang Ke, Qin Zhao, Fengyan Han, Junpo Guo, Xiaofei Yang, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404018533

                Designing cost-effective and high-stable heterostructures with synergistic active sites could simultaneously catalyze oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) for the (sea) water splitting. However, there are still...</description>
      <author>Weiping Xiao, Yue Zhang, Changwang Ke, Qin Zhao, Fengyan Han, Junpo Guo, Xiaofei Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03572k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing HER rate over Pt-TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles under Controlled Periodic Illumination: Role of light modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00775a</link>
      <description>E. Bianco, Fabrizio Sordello, Francesco Pellegrino, Valter Maurino, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403955529

                In hydrogen production through water splitting, two reactions are involved: Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER) and Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), both with efficiency issues. In previous works, our group demonstrated the...</description>
      <author>E. Bianco, Fabrizio Sordello, Francesco Pellegrino, Valter Maurino</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00775a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of CoII, NiII and FeII/FeIII in trimetallic MOFs for enhancing electrocatalytic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00953c</link>
      <description>Zheng Yan, Xuebo Cao, Ya Ling Wu, Zhong Sun, Yu Liu, Ying&#8208;Ying Chen, Zhibo Li, Meng-Li Li, Dan Liu, CrystEngComm. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404051177

                Metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) can catalyze the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process. Despite the established link between pristine MOFs and electrocatalysts, a number of limitations still hamper the understanding of the...</description>
      <author>Zheng Yan, Xuebo Cao, Ya Ling Wu, Zhong Sun, Yu Liu, Ying&#8208;Ying Chen, Zhibo Li, Meng-Li Li, Dan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ce00953c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Dots embedded CoNi bimetallic phosphides nanorods as efficient electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04340e</link>
      <description>Yantong Long, Guo-Liang Zhao, Liuxin Yang, Yongjun Xu, Xu Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403952039

                Efficient bifunctional catalysts for Hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) are critical for industrial application of overall water splitting. Herein, a self-supported nanostructure consisting of CoNi-P and embedded carbon dots (denoted as...</description>
      <author>Yantong Long, Guo-Liang Zhao, Liuxin Yang, Yongjun Xu, Xu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04340e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development and Demonstration of In-House Design Green Hydrogen Production Technologies with Reduced CAPEX and OPEX</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/222255-ms</link>
      <description>Bharati Panigrahy, B. Ramachandra Rao, Vipul Kumar Maheshwari, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404014486

                Abstract Design of highly efficient cost effective and self-supported bi-functional electrocatalyst for the production of green Hydrogen is significant for renewable and sustainable energy conversion to achieve future carbon neutral. Meanwhile, as we know that the overall water splitting is an uphill reaction requires 285.8 kJ of energy, corresponds to the HHV of hydrogen, state-of-the-art developments are necessary to greatly improve the efficiency by rationally designing non-precious metal-based robust bi-functional catalysts for promoting both the cathodic hydrogen evolution and anodic oxygen evolution reactions. The performance of metal phosphide towards hydrogen and oxygen evolution was examined under application relevant conditions in an alkaline and anion exchange membrane (AEM) electrolyzer cell stack. The in-house designed stacked electrolyzer exhibited stable performances with a hydrogen production rate of few Nm3 per hour without any decay, pave the path towards large scale application with substantial reduction in CAPEX and OPEX cost. Key Words: Water splitting, Green Hydrogen, Electrolyzer, Electrolysis, HER, OER</description>
      <author>Bharati Panigrahy, B. Ramachandra Rao, Vipul Kumar Maheshwari</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/222255-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating nonmetal atom doping in two-dimensional VSe2 monolayers for hydrogen and oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232667</link>
      <description>Rabia Hassan, Fei Ma, Yan Li, Rehan Hassan, Muhammad Farhan Qadir, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403981233

                The electrocatalytic performance of VSe2 doped with nonmetals (NMs) was studied using density functional theory, in which NM atoms (C, N, O, P, S, F, Cl, Br, and I) replaced Se or V (denoted as NM@Se or NM@V). Notably, P@V and Br@V monolayers exhibit high catalytic hydrogen evolution reaction activity with the lowest &#916;GH* = 0.08 eV and &#8722;0.03 eV, respectively, surpassing Pt (&#916;GH* = &#8722;0.1 eV). By applying the scaling relationship of &#916;GH* of H*, which is an intermediate for each volcano, the exchange current density diagrams are established. Based on thermodynamic analysis, P@V and Br@V monolayers produce exchange currents of about &#8722;1.42 and &#8722;0.70i0/(A cm&#8722;2), respectively. The oxygen evolution reaction activity of the I@Se monolayer (&#951;OER = 0.95 V) is the best among all the monolayers. Among the oxygen reduction reaction catalysts, the O@Se monolayer displays high activity with a low &#951;ORR (0.82 V), which is even better than that of binary Pt and Pd alloys (0.9&#8211;0.87 V).</description>
      <author>Rabia Hassan, Fei Ma, Yan Li, Rehan Hassan, Muhammad Farhan Qadir</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0232667</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air-condition process for Constructing MeAl-LDHs/rGO (Me = Co, Ni, Fe) hybrids toward efficient oxygene evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.146</link>
      <description>Dongdong Zhang, Binyuan Tang, Kai Wang, Lin Wang, Kai Tang, Shanliang Chen, Xiaoqiang Zhan, Hongli Yang, Weiyou Yang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 679(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403918636

                Transition-metal-based layered double hydroxides (LDHs) are emerging as one of the most promising candidates with superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. However, their fabrication under mild conditions remains a significant challenge. Here, we propose a low-cost, high-production-rate strategy for controlled preparation of AlOOH/reduced graphene oxide (rGO) with strong adsorption capacity for transition metal cations, and then in-situ conversion to CoAl-LDH/rGO, NiAl-LDH/rGO and FeAl-LDH/rGO under ambient conditions. Based on Density Functional Theory calculations, it is witnessed that the rational electronic coordination between Co and Al enables the charge absorption by surrounding oxygen atoms, thereby playing a critical role in reducing the adsorption free energy and overpotential of OER intermediates toward efficient OER. Consequently, the resultant CoAl-LDH/rGO hybrids exhibit an overpotential of just 368 mV at the current density of 100 mA/cm</description>
      <author>Dongdong Zhang, Binyuan Tang, Kai Wang, Lin Wang, Kai Tang, Shanliang Chen, Xiaoqiang Zhan, Hongli Yang, Weiyou Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.146</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocarrier Dynamics of Two-Dimensional Aza-Fused Covalent Organic Frameworks as Bifunctional Photocatalysts toward Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13429</link>
      <description>Priya Das, Atish Ghosh, Pranab Sarkar, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403935211

                Designing high-efficiency bifunctional photocatalysts toward photoinduced overall water splitting is one of the most promising and challenging research directions for clean energy generation. By employing static electronic structure calculation and nonadiabatic molecular dynamics (NAMD) simulation, we herein established a recently synthesized two-dimensional (2D) aza-fused covalent organic framework (aza-COF) as a potential bifunctional photocatalyst toward overall water splitting reactions. Our calculated results reveal that the overpotentials for hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction are only 0.06 and 0.31 V, respectively, at pH = 4. The dynamics of photoexcited charge carriers studied through NAMD simulation predicts the electron&#8211;hole recombination time (25.15 ns), and this confirms that the photogenerated electron and hole carriers migrate to the active sites for the occurrence of reaction before they recombine. Therefore, our results suggest that the 2D aza-COFs exhibit great potential as metal-free and single-material photocatalysts toward overall water splitting under visible light.</description>
      <author>Priya Das, Atish Ghosh, Pranab Sarkar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13429</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seawater Electrolysis at Ultra-High Current Density: A Comparative Analysis of Cylindrical versus Conical Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/osf.io/3b5qw</link>
      <description>S&#248;ren Torn&#248;e, John Koster, Andy V. Surin, Jacob H. Sands, Nobuhiko P. Kobayashi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404043802

                Seawater electrolysis preferentially leans towards Chlorine Evolution Reaction (CER) over Oxygen Evolution Reactions (OER) under conventional conditions, but OER becomes more dominant at sufficiently higher current densities. In this study, we evaluated the effector of cylindrical and conical electrode geometries on CER and hydrogen production at high current density (i.e., &amp;gt;1 A/cm2). We found the point of lowest CER within a voltage range of 40 V to 90 V. Conical electrodes, optimized to reduce CER, produced a magnitude less chloride (502 ppb) than cylindrical electrodes (1485 ppb) at nearly double the current density (~12 and ~6 A/cm2 respectively). However, this reduction in CER with conical electrodes was accompanied by a 25% decrease in hydrogen production. In addition, both cylindrical and conical electrodes were able to heat 500 ml of seawater by approximately 6-7 degrees Celsius over a two-minute period with cylindrical electrodes heating slightly less than conical electrodes.</description>
      <author>S&#248;ren Torn&#248;e, John Koster, Andy V. Surin, Jacob H. Sands, Nobuhiko P. Kobayashi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/osf.io/3b5qw</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Electrolyte Solvation Structure for High&#8208;Voltage and Low&#8208;Temperature Magnesium&#8208;ion Supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/batt.202400620</link>
      <description>Xiaohong Tan, Chi Fang, Zhongqi Liang, Zhengjie Xu, Jiaxin Zheng, Xianqi Xu, Yufeng Jin, Guoshen Yang, Hang Zhou, Batteries &amp; Supercaps. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403921239

                Aqueous electrolytes supercapacitors have great potential in energy storage devices due to their high&#8208;power density and safety. However, due to the water hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the electrochemical stabilization window of aqueous electrolytes needs to be widened. Moreover, the application of aqueous electrolyte at low temperature is often limited by the freezing point of water. In this paper, we modulate the solvation structure of aqueous magnesium&#8208;ion supercapacitors by using sulfolane as a co&#8208;solvent. The modulated low salt concentration hybrid electrolyte extends the electrochemical stability window of the electrolyte to 2.9V and enhances the stability of the electrolyte at extreme temperatures, as well as provides safe and non&#8208;flammable properties. Based on the hybrid electrolyte, the water&#8208;organic hybrid magnesium&#8208;ion supercapacitors (HMSCs) are able to operate within an enlarged voltage range of 0 &#8211; 2.2 V at a low temperature of &#8208;30&#176;C. The HMSC shows a specific capacitance of up to 58 F/g at room temperature and retains a specific capacitance of 39 F/g at a current density of 15 A/g. Furthermore, it has an outstanding cycling performance at &#8208;30 &#176;C, maintaining a specific capacitance of more than 92% after 20,000 cycles.</description>
      <author>Xiaohong Tan, Chi Fang, Zhongqi Liang, Zhengjie Xu, Jiaxin Zheng, Xianqi Xu, Yufeng Jin, Guoshen Yang, Hang Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/batt.202400620</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron&#8208;Induced Localized Oxide Path Mechanism Enables Efficient and Stable Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416141</link>
      <description>Bohan Yao, Yu&#8208;Ting Chen, Yueying Yan, Jing Wang, Huanhuan Xing, Yanchao Xu, Dongxu Jiao, Zhicai Xing, Dewen Wang, Xiurong Yang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404059880

                The sluggish reaction kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the inadequate catalytic performance of non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts represent substantial barriers to the development of anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE). This study performed the synthesis of a three&#8208;dimensional (3D) nanoflower&#8208;like electrocatalyst (CFMO) via a simple one&#8208;step method. The substitution of Co with Fe in the structure induces a localized oxide path mechanism (LOPM), facilitating direct O&#8211;O radical coupling for enhanced O2 evolution. The optimized CFMO&#8208;2 electrocatalyst demonstrates superior OER performance, achieving an overpotential of 217 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, alongside exceptional long&#8208;term stability with minimal degradation after 1000 h of operation in 1.0 M KOH. These properties surpass most of conventional noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Furthermore, the assembled AEMWE system, utilizing CFMO&#8208;2, operates with a cell voltage of 1.65 V to deliver 1.0 A cm&#8211;2. In situ characterizations reveal that, in addition to the traditional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) at isolated Co sites, a new LOPM occurred around the Fe and Co bimetallic sites. First&#8208;principles calculations confirm the LOPM greatly reduced the energy barriers. This work highlights the potential of LOPM for improving the design of non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts and the development of AEMWE.</description>
      <author>Bohan Yao, Yu&#8208;Ting Chen, Yueying Yan, Jing Wang, Huanhuan Xing, Yanchao Xu, Dongxu Jiao, Zhicai Xing, Dewen Wang, Xiurong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202416141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron&#8208;Induced Localized Oxide Path Mechanism Enables Efficient and Stable Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416141</link>
      <description>Bohan Yao, Yuting Chen, Yueying Yan, Yang Yang, Huanhuan Xing, Yanchao Xu, Dongxu Jiao, Zhicai Xing, Dewen Wang, Yang Xiu-rong, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404059879

                The sluggish reaction kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the inadequate catalytic performance of non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts represent substantial barriers to the development of anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE). This study performed the synthesis of a three&#8208;dimensional (3D) nanoflower&#8208;like electrocatalyst (CFMO) via a simple one&#8208;step method. The substitution of Co with Fe in the structure induces a localized oxide path mechanism (LOPM), facilitating direct O&#8211;O radical coupling for enhanced O2 evolution. The optimized CFMO&#8208;2 electrocatalyst demonstrates superior OER performance, achieving an overpotential of 217 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2, alongside exceptional long&#8208;term stability with minimal degradation after 1000 h of operation in 1.0 M KOH. These properties surpass most of conventional noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts. Furthermore, the assembled AEMWE system, utilizing CFMO&#8208;2, operates with a cell voltage of 1.65 V to deliver 1.0 A cm&#8211;2. In situ characterizations reveal that, in addition to the traditional adsorbate evolution mechanism (AEM) at isolated Co sites, a new LOPM occurred around the Fe and Co bimetallic sites. First&#8208;principles calculations confirm the LOPM greatly reduced the energy barriers. This work highlights the potential of LOPM for improving the design of non&#8208;noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts and the development of AEMWE.</description>
      <author>Bohan Yao, Yuting Chen, Yueying Yan, Yang Yang, Huanhuan Xing, Yanchao Xu, Dongxu Jiao, Zhicai Xing, Dewen Wang, Yang Xiu-rong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202416141</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three rate-determining protein roles in photosynthetic O2-evolution addressed by time-resolved experiments on genetically modified photosystems</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5291688/v1</link>
      <description>Holger Dau, Sarah M. M&#228;usle, Ricardo Assun&#231;&#227;o, Gianluca Parisse, Cristina De Santis, Leonardo Guidoni, Daniele Narzi, Philipp S. Simon, Richard J. Debus, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403900396

                Abstract Light-driven water splitting by plants, algae and cyanobacteria is pivotal for global bioenergetics and biomass formation. A manganese cluster bound to the photosystem-II proteins catalyzes the complex reaction at high rate, but the rate-determining factors are insufficiently understood. Here we traced the oxygen-evolution transition by time-resolved polarography and infrared spectroscopy for cyanobacterial photosystems genetically modified at two strategic sites, complemented by computational chemistry. We conclude three rate-determining functions of the protein environment of the metal cluster: acceleration of proton-coupled electron transfer, acceleration of substrate-water insertion after O2-formation, and balancing of rate-determining enthalpic and entropic contributions. Whereas in general the substrate-water insertion step may be unresolvable in time-resolved experiments, here it likely became traceable because of deceleration by genetic modification. Our results may stimulate new time-resolved experiments on substrate-water insertion in photosynthesis, clarification of enthalpy-entropy compensation in enzyme catalysis, and knowledge-guided development of inorganic catalyst materials.</description>
      <author>Holger Dau, Sarah M. M&#228;usle, Ricardo Assun&#231;&#227;o, Gianluca Parisse, Cristina De Santis, Leonardo Guidoni, Daniele Narzi, Philipp S. Simon, Richard J. Debus</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5291688/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrodeposition of Thin Film Cu-Zn-Sn Alloy for Water Splitting Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.56425/cma.v3i3.82</link>
      <description>Reinardo Ramawijaya Widakusuma, Fathir Azzaki Iradata, Mokhamad Ali Rizqi Maulana, Ikhwan Nur Rahman, Chemistry and Materials. 3(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403953406

                An energy transition to renewable energy sources is necessary due to the scarcity of fossil fuels and their detrimental effects on the environment. Water splitting process is one of the practical and effective way that does not occur spontaneously. This study investigates catalytic activity of Cu-Zn-Sn (CZT) photocatalyst in hydrogen evolution and oxygen evolution reaction. The CZT deposited with varied electrolyte&#8217;s pH of 6 and 9 on indium tin oxide substrate at the room temperature for 600 seconds. According to the X-ray diffraction patterns, there were Cu6Sn5, Cu5Zn8, and Sn metal phases with monoclinic, cubic, and cubic crystal systems. The scanning electron microscopy technique results of all CZT alloy sample showed a dense, non-uniform, and polycrystalline surface structure. The CZT alloys were found to have an average particle size of 0.35 &#956;m. CZT alloys can produce a photocurrent density of 0.19 mA/cm&#178; at a potential of 1.29 V vs RHE. the charge transfer resistance of CZT synthesized at pH 6 is lower (21.48 &#937;) compared to pH 9 (28.36 &#937;). The Tafel slope of HER for pH 9 CZT was -133 mV/dec, which was lower than that of pH 6 CZT (-88 mV/dec), indicating faster H2 production and corrosion resistance on pH 9 CZT.</description>
      <author>Reinardo Ramawijaya Widakusuma, Fathir Azzaki Iradata, Mokhamad Ali Rizqi Maulana, Ikhwan Nur Rahman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.56425/cma.v3i3.82</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Experimental Realization of Fluoroborophene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407763</link>
      <description>Mukul M. Morey, Rohan Bahadur, Zhixuan Li, Nithinraj Panangattu Dharmarajan, Mohammed Fawaz, Arkamita Bandyopadhyay, Sumit Chahal, Solomon Ansah, R. Raman, Humberto Terrones, Prashant Kumar, Ajayan Vinu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403954104

                Abstract Borophene, an anisotropic metallic Dirac material exhibits superlative physical and chemical properties. While the lack of bandgap restricts its electronic chip applications, insufficient charge carrier density and electrochemical/catalytically active sites, restricts its energy storage and catalysis applications. Fluorination of borophene can induce bandgap and yield local electron injection within its crystallographic lattice. Herein, a facile synthesis of fluoroborophene with tunable fluorine content through potassium fluoride&#8208;assisted solvothermal&#8208;sonochemical combinatorial approach is reported. Fluoroborophene monolayers with lateral dimension 50 nm&#8211;5 &#181;m are synthesized having controlled fluorine content (12&#8211;35%). Fluoroborophene exhibits inter&#8208;twinned crystallographic structure, with fluorination&#8208;tunable visible&#8208;range bandgap &#8776;1.5&#8211;2.5 eV, and density functional theory calculations also corroborate it. Fluoroborophene is explored for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction in an alkaline medium and bestow a good stability. Tunable bandgap, electrophilicity and molecular anchoring capability of fluoroborophene will open opportunities for novel electronic/optoelectronic/spintronic chips, energy storage devices, and in numerous catalytic applications.</description>
      <author>Mukul M. Morey, Rohan Bahadur, Zhixuan Li, Nithinraj Panangattu Dharmarajan, Mohammed Fawaz, Arkamita Bandyopadhyay, Sumit Chahal, Solomon Ansah, R. Raman, Humberto Terrones, Prashant Kumar, Ajayan Vinu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Gel method MXene&#8208;Supported Dual&#8208;Site PtNi&#8208;NiO for Electrocatalytic Water Reduction and Urea Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409461</link>
      <description>Xintong Shi, Ding Zhou, Guilin Chen, Pengfei An, Jing Zhang, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403953935

                Abstract Compared to the traditional oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the urea oxidation reaction (UOR) generally exhibits a lower overpotential during the electrolytic process, which is conducive to the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode. The superior structure and abundant sites play a crucial role in promoting the adsorption and cleavage of urea molecules. Therefore, this paper introduces a simple metal cation&#8208;induced gelation method to prepare an electrocatalyst with PtNi alloy&#8208;NiO dual sites supported on Ti 3 C 2 T x , which simultaneously exhibits excellent UOR and HER performance. PtNi&#8208;NiO x /Ti 3 C 2 T x demonstrates good catalytic activity for the urea oxidation reaction, requiring only 1.364 V (overpotential of 0.994 V) to achieve a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in UOR, and also exhibits remarkable catalytic activity in the hydrogen evolution reaction, with PtNi&#8208;NiO x /Ti 3 C 2 T x achieving a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in HER with only 24 mV of overpotential. In the UOR//HER two&#8208;electrode electrolysis cell, it requires only 1.361 and 1.538 V to reach current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. According to density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the dual active sites can intelligently adsorb the electron&#8208;donating/electron&#8208;withdrawing groups in urea molecules, activate chemical bonds, and thereby initiate urea decomposition.</description>
      <author>Xintong Shi, Ding Zhou, Guilin Chen, Pengfei An, Jing Zhang, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202409461</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Corrosion&#8208;Resistant and Multi&#8208;Scenario MoNiP Electrode for Efficient Industrial&#8208;Scale Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403009</link>
      <description>Weiju Hao, Xunwei Ma, Lincai Wang, Y. P. Guo, Qingyuan Bi, Jinchen Fan, Hexing Li, Guisheng Li, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885883

                Abstract The construction of efficient and durable multifunctional electrodes for industrial&#8208;scale hydrogen production presents a main challenge. Herein, molybdenum&#8208;modulated phosphorus&#8208;based catalytic electrodes (Mo&#8208;NiP@NF) are prepared via mild electroless plating. Heteroatoms doping or heterostructures construction can reconfigure the intrinsic electronic structure of the pre&#8208;catalyst and optimizes the key intermediates adsorption. Moreover, the (hypo/meta&#8208;)phosphite anions (PO x &#948;&#8722; ) and molybdate ions (MoO x &#948;&#8722; ) on the electrode surface of Mo&#8208;NiP@NF afford resistance to chloride (Cl &#8722; ) corrosion. Mo&#8208;NiP@NF exhibits ultralow overpotentials of 278/550 and 282/590 mV at 1 A cm &#8722;2 during the hydrogen/oxygen evolution reaction (HER/OER) in alkaline simulated and real seawater, respectively, whereas catalytic overall seawater splitting (OWS) reach 1 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.96 and 1.97 V cell . Remarkably, Mo&#8208;NiP@NF maintains stable operation for 1500 h in OWS. The scalability of Mo&#8208;NiP@NF allowing the assembly of proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer powered by photovoltaic energy, simulating a portable hydrogen&#8208;oxygen respirator provides an oxygen/hydrogen flows of 160/320 mL min &#8722;1 . Expanding further, the trace ruthenium&#8208;loaded Mo&#8208;NiP@NF catalyst sodium borohydride (NaBH 4 ) hydrolysis achieving a hydrogen generation rate (HGR) of 11049.2 mL min &#8722;1 g &#8722;1 . This work provides strategic innovations and optimization solutions for the economical and mild construction of multi&#8208;scenario durable green energy conversion materials at industrial&#8208;scale application.</description>
      <author>Weiju Hao, Xunwei Ma, Lincai Wang, Y. P. Guo, Qingyuan Bi, Jinchen Fan, Hexing Li, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boron-Intercalation Engineering toward Defected 1T Phase-Rich MoB&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-Supported IrO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; Clusters for Acidic OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03113</link>
      <description>Jia-Wei Huang, Jinlan Nie, Xinyi Li, Lu Zou, Yuanxing Wang, Hao Chen, Guanghua Wei, Junfang Cheng, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403935587

                The construction of supported Ir-based catalysts can effectively reduce the amount of Ir and generate a synergistic effect that enhances the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and stability, making it one of the effective solutions for optimizing acidic OER catalysts. However, most reported metal oxide supports suffer from poor acid resistance and low electrical conductivity, which are critical for the OER process. Herein, we synthesized a nanosheet-like defected 1T phase-rich MoBxS2&#8211;x via a molten salt calcination process, during which the 1T phase was formed, and B was intercalated into MoS2 to protect the 1T phase structure during annealing procedure. After the wet refluxing process, IrOx clusters were uniformly deposited on the surface of MoBxS2&#8211;x to form IrOx@MoBxS2&#8211;x, which exhibited an overpotential of 168 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 with an Ir loading amount of 25.8 wt %. By comparing the OER performance of IrOx@MoBxS2&#8211;x, IrOx@MoS2(Calcinated), and IrOx@MoS2, it is demonstrated that calcination and B intercalation of MoS2 can significantly increase acidic OER performance. This work digs into the application of 1T-MoS2 as an OER catalyst support, providing strategies for the phase and morphology control of 1T-MoS2.</description>
      <author>Jia-Wei Huang, Jinlan Nie, Xinyi Li, Lu Zou, Yuanxing Wang, Hao Chen, Guanghua Wei, Junfang Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03113</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyaniline prepared by Fe3O4 catalysed eco-friendly synthesis as electrocatalyst for efficient water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5599/jese.2438</link>
      <description>Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Jana Mi&#353;urovi&#263;, Lazar Rako&#269;evi&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, Gordana &#262;iri&#263;&#8208;Marjanovi&#263;, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Journal of Electrochemical Science and Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403956565

                Preparing cost-effective and highly active catalysts for electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction is crucial for developing hydrogen-based technologies. Hence, four conductive polyanilines, prepared by the environmentally-friendly approach using Fe3O4 nanoparticles/H2O2 as the catalyst/main oxidant system (PANI/Fe3O4), were investi&#172;gated for the first time as electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acidic media (0.1 M H2SO4) by using voltammetry and chronoamperometry. PANI/Fe3O4 electrodes exhibited Tafel slope values in the -171 to -246 mV dec-1 range depending on the synthesis conditions &#8210; Fe3O4/aniline mass ratio and polymerization time. The sample PANI/Fe3O4-II(3) prepared with shorter reaction time and higher Fe3O4/aniline mass ratio showed the best electrocatalytic behaviour reflected in the lowest onset potential (-0.286 V), the lowest overpotential to reach a current density of -10 mA cm-2, the highest current density, the lowest HER activation energy (10 kJ mol-1), and the lowest charge-transfer resistance (5.3 &#937;) under HER conditions. Materials were characterized by scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy, X-ray photo&#172;electron spectroscopy and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy, and differences in their electrocatalytic HER performance were explained by differences in their content of Fe3O4, surface and electrical properties. Moreover, the possibility of using PANI/Fe3O4-II(3) as HER electrocatalyst in a wider range of pH (i.e. in alkaline media as well) and as a bifunc&#172;tional electrocatalyst, i.e., for oxygen evolution reaction beside HER, was also examined.</description>
      <author>Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Jana Mi&#353;urovi&#263;, Lazar Rako&#269;evi&#263;, Igor A. Pa&#353;ti, Gordana &#262;iri&#263;&#8208;Marjanovi&#263;, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5599/jese.2438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Membrane&#8208;Free Water Electrolysis for Hydrogen Generation with Low Cost</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417987</link>
      <description>Xin Gao, Pengtang Wang, Xun Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403963387

                Conventional water electrolysis relies on expensive membrane&#8208;electrode assemblies and sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode. Here, we develop an innovative and efficient membrane&#8208;free water electrolysis system to overcome these two obstacles simultaneously. This system utilizes the thermodynamically more favorable urea oxidation reaction (UOR) to generate clean N2 over a new class of Cu&#8208;based catalyst (CuXO), fundamentally eliminating the explosion risk of H2 and O2 mixing while removing the need for membranes. Notably, this membrane&#8208;free electrolysis system exhibits the highest H2 Faradaic efficiency among reported membrane&#8208;free electrolysis work. In situ spectroscopic studies reveal that the new N2Hy intermediate&#8208;mediated UOR mechanism on the CuXO catalyst ensures its unique N2 selectivity and OER inertness. More importantly, an industrial&#8208;type membrane&#8208;free water electrolyser (MFE) based on this system successfully reduces electricity consumption to only 3.87 kWh Nm&#8722;3, significantly lower than the 5.17 kWh Nm&#8722;3 of commercial alkaline water electrolyzers (AWE). Comprehensive techno&#8208;economic analysis (TEA) suggests that the membrane&#8208;free design and reduced electricity input of the MFE plants reduce the green H2 production cost to US$1.81 kg&#8722;1, which is lower than those of grey H2 while meeting the technical target (US$2.00&#8211;2.50 kg&#8722;1) set by European Commission and United States Department of Energy.</description>
      <author>Xin Gao, Pengtang Wang, Xun Sun, Mietek Jaroniec, Yao Zheng, Shi Zhang Qiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202417987</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Hydrogen Evolution Reaction through the Improved Mass Transfer and Charge Transfer by Bimetal Nodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11560</link>
      <description>Zhihui Li, Xinyu Zhang, Yiran Teng, Hanming Zhang, Tongguang Xu, Fei Teng, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403955258

                The high cost of hydrogen production by water electrolysis severely challenges its commercial application. It is highly desirable to develop efficient electrocatalysts and innovative electrolytic cells. Introducing additional metal nodes to form bimetallic metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) is a simple, feasible strategy to overcome the poor electrocatalytic performance of single-metal MOF. In this study, the hydrothermal method is used to synthesize bimetallic NixCoy-BTC. It is found that for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), Ni0.8Co0.2-BTC merely requires a potential of &#8722;0.203 V (vs reverse hydrogen electrode, RHE) to achieve 10 mA cm&#8211;2, which is significantly lower than that of Ni-BTC (&#8722;0.341 V vs RHE). Notably, electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) and distribution of relaxation time (DRT) analysis indicate that NixCoy-BTC has improved charge transfer and mass transfer process, compared with Ni-BTC. Electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) confirms that Ni0.8Co0.2-BTC has more unpaired electrons than Ni-BTC. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that compared with Ni-BTC, NixCoy-BTC is more thermodynamically favorable for the adsorption of H+, OH&#8211;, and H2O. It demonstrates that the change of mass transfer caused by bimetallic nodes and the delicate variation of MOF surface play an important role in the electrochemical process. Moreover, a novel electrolytic cell was developed using a methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) to replace oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this MOR-based electrolytic cell, a current density of 50 mA cm&#8211;2 can be achieved at only a cell voltage of 1.85 V, which is lower than the 2.22 V of OER-based electrolytic cell, suggesting that 16.7% electric energy can be saved. At the same time, the Faraday efficiency (FE, 98.2%) of the MOR-based cell is higher than that (94.5%) of the OER-based cell. This research offers a promising strategy for low-cost hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Zhihui Li, Xinyu Zhang, Yiran Teng, Hanming Zhang, Tongguang Xu, Fei Teng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c11560</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Hydrogen Evolution Efficiency in Alkaline Water Electrolysis Using Optimized Raney Nickel Coatings on Stainless Steel Electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2118/222831-ms</link>
      <description>Surendra K. Gond, Ashutosh Mishra, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404013904

                Abstract Hydrogen, as a clean and high-energy-density fuel, holds immense promise for future energy systems. The aim of this study is to enhance the efficacy and durability of hydrogen evolution reactions (HER) in alkaline water electrolysis by optimizing Raney Nickel coatings on stainless steel electrodes. This work aims to reduce costs and improve the performance of electrolysis systems, making hydrogen production more feasible for large-scale applications. The study involved the electrodeposition of Raney Nickel on stainless steel substrates using a modified Watt&#8217;s bath. The pretreatment process included degreasing, acid pickling, and Nickel Strike coating to prepare the electrode surface. Functional coatings were applied in a solution containing NiSO4, NiCl2, H3BO3, and ZnCl2 at 50&#176;C. The obtained coating substrates were characterized both chemically and morphogically by XRF analysis and confocal laser scanning microscopy. The performance of the electrodes was evaluated through electrochemical measurements, determining the electrochemical surface area (ECSA) and overpotentials for HER and oxygen evolution reactions (OER) The optimized Raney Nickel coatings, referred to as Raney 2, demonstrated a significant improvement in both HER and OER performance compared to traditional coatings. The Raney 2 coating exhibited a threefold increase in ECSA. The accelerated aging tests showed that the Raney 2 coating outperformed Raney 1, with lower peak voltages and improved stability over time. The roughness factor of the Raney 2 electrode is higher, indicating has an extensive reactive surface area. Furthermore, the study confirmed that the incorporation of elements from the 316-grade stainless steel counter-electrode, such as iron, contributed to enhanced catalytic activity, particularly for OER. These findings suggest that the modified coating process can significantly extend the operational life and efficiency of electrolysis electrodes. This work presents a novel approach to enhancing the performance of Raney Nickel coatings by incorporating a 316-grade stainless steel counter-electrode during deposition, which has not been extensively explored in existing literature. The resulting hybrid coating demonstrates superior electrochemical performance and durability, offering a cost-effective solution for improving alkaline water electrolysis systems. This advancement can significantly contribute to the development of more sustainable and efficient hydrogen production technologies.</description>
      <author>Surendra K. Gond, Ashutosh Mishra</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2118/222831-ms</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Annealing Temperature on the OER Activity of NiO(111) Nanosheets Prepared via Microwave and Solvothermal Synthesis Approaches</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14277</link>
      <description>Dereje H. Taffa, Elliot Brim, Konstantin K. R&#252;cker, Darius Hayes, Julian Lorenz, Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Marcel Risch, Corinna Harms, Ryan M. Richards, Michael Wark, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403973034

                Earth-abundant transition metal oxides are promising alternatives to precious metal oxides as electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and are intensively investigated for alkaline water electrolysis. OER electrocatalysis, like most other catalytic reactions, is surface-initiated, and the catalyst performance is fundamentally determined by the surface properties. Most transition metal oxide catalysts show OER activities that depend on the predominantly exposed crystal facets/surface structure. Therefore, the design of synthetic strategies to obtain the most active crystal facets is of significant research interest. In this work, rock salt NiO OER catalysts with (111) predominantly exposed facets were synthesized by a solvothermal (ST) method either heated under supercritical or microwave-assisted (MW) conditions. Particular emphasis was placed on the influence of the post annealing temperature on the structural configuration and OER activity to compare their catalytic performances. The as-prepared electrocatalysts are pure &#945;-Ni hydroxides which were converted to rock salt NiO (111) nanosheets with hexagonal pores after heat treatment at different temperatures. The OER activity of the electrodes has been evaluated in 0.1 M KOH using geometric and intrinsic current densities via normalization by the disk area and BET area, respectively. The lowest overpotential at a geometric current density of 10 mA/cm2 is found for samples pretreated by heating between 400 and 500 &#176;C with a catalyst loading of 115 &#956;g/cm2. Despite the very similar nature of the catalysts obtained from the two methods, the ST electrodes show a higher geometric and intrinsic current density for 500 &#176;C pretreatment. The MW electrodes, however, achieve an optimal geometric current density for 400 &#176;C pretreatment, while their intrinsic current density requires pretreatment over 600 &#176;C. Interestingly, pretreated electrodes show consistently higher OER activity as compared to the poorly crystalline/less ordered hydroxide as-prepared electrocatalysts. Thus, our study highlights the importance of the synthesis method and pretreatment at an optimal temperature.</description>
      <author>Dereje H. Taffa, Elliot Brim, Konstantin K. R&#252;cker, Darius Hayes, Julian Lorenz, Omeshwari Yadorao Bisen, Marcel Risch, Corinna Harms, Ryan M. Richards, Michael Wark</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c14277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of platinum content on semiconductor and electrochemical properties of materials based on titanium suboxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.32434/0321-4095-2024-156-5-131-137</link>
      <description>V. A. Knysh, O. Shmychkova, T. V. Luk&#8217;yanenko, A. Velichenko, Voprosy Khimii i Khimicheskoi Tekhnologii. None(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404021020

                The effect of platinum content on the surface morphology, phase composition and electrochemical properties of materials based on titanium suboxides was investigated. Titanium suboxides are formed at the stage of coating reduction under cathodic polarization, which allows the formation of a porous developed surface for electrodeposition of catalytic platinum layers. The main allotropic modification of TiOx in the studied composite materials is anatase, which contains particles of elemental titanium and platinum. The investigated materials are highly doped semiconductors with a high concentration of charge carriers. With an increase in the platinum content, an extreme dependence of the potential of flat zones is observed, which is associated with the formation of a composite material. The electrocatalytic activity was studied in the reactions of oxygen and hydrogen evolution. The overvoltage of oxygen production on platinum-containing materials is much lower than on the TiOx electrode. The slope of the linear dependence of the potential on the current density decreases with an increase in platinum content. The Tafel slope for the studied materials in the hydrogen evolution reaction was 160 mV&#61655;dec&#8211;1 for coatings containing 0.25 mg&#61655;cm&#8211;2 Pt; whereas it was equal to 42 and 43 mV&#61655;dec&#8211;1 for electrodes with 0.5 and 2 mg&#61655;cm&#8211;2 Pt, respectively.</description>
      <author>V. A. Knysh, O. Shmychkova, T. V. Luk&#8217;yanenko, A. Velichenko</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.32434/0321-4095-2024-156-5-131-137</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive theoretical study of the effects of facet, oxygen vacancies, and surface strain on iron and cobalt impurities in different surfaces of anatase TiO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74423-3</link>
      <description>Danil W. Boukhvalov, V. Yu. Osipov, Anna Baldycheva, Benjamin T. Hogan, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403914609

                Abstract We report the results of systematic ab initio modelling of various configurations of iron and cobalt impurities embedded in the (110), (101), and (100) surfaces of anatase TiO 2 , with and without oxygen vacancies. The simulation results demonstrate that incorporation into interstitial voids at the surface level is significantly more favourable than other configurations for both iron and cobalt. The calculations also demonstrate the crucial effect of the facet as well as the lesser effects of other factors, such as vacancies and strain on the energetics of defect incorporation, magnetic moment, bandgap, and catalytic performance. It is further shown that there is no tendency towards the segregation or clustering of impurities on the surface. The calculated free energies of the hydrogen evolution reaction in acidic media predict that iron impurities embedded in the (101) surface of anatase TiO 2 can be a competitive catalyst for this reaction.</description>
      <author>Danil W. Boukhvalov, V. Yu. Osipov, Anna Baldycheva, Benjamin T. Hogan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-74423-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Promiscuous and unbiased recombination underlies the sequence-discrete species of the SAR11 lineage in the deep ocean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.10.30.621061</link>
      <description>Jianshu Zhao, Maria Pachiadaki, Roth E. Conrad, Janet K. Hatt, Laura A. Bristow, Luis M. Rodr&#237;guez-R, Ramon Rossell&#243;&#8208;M&#243;ra, Frank J. Stewart, Konstantinos T. Konstantinidis, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403885946

                Surveys of microbial communities (metagenomics) or isolate genomes have revealed sequence-discrete species. That is, members of the same species usually show &gt;95% Average Nucleotide Identity (ANI) of shared genes among themselves vs. &lt;83% ANI to members of other species while genome pairs showing between 83-95% ANI are comparatively rare. In these surveys, aquatic bacteria of the ubiquitous SAR11 clade (Class Alphaproteobacteria), which play a major role in carbon cycling, are an outlier and often do not exhibit discrete species boundaries, suggesting the potential for alternate modes of genetic differentiation. To explore evolution in SAR11, we analyzed high-quality, single-cell amplified genomes (SAGs) and companion metagenomes from an oxygen minimum zone (OMZ) in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Ocean, where the SAR11 make up ~20% of the total microbial community. Our results show that SAR11 do form several sequence-discrete species, but their ANI range of discreteness is shifted to lower identities between 86-91%, with intra-species ANI ranging between 91-100%. Measuring recent gene exchange among these genomes based on a newly developed methodology revealed higher frequency of homologous recombination within compared to between species that affects sequence evolution at least twice as much as diversifying point mutation across the genome. Recombination in SAR-11 appears to be more promiscuous compared to other prokaryotic species and has facilitated the spreading of adaptive mutations within the species, further promoting the high intra-species diversity observed. These results implicate rampant, genome-wide homologous recombination as the mechanism that underlies the evolution of SAR11 into discrete species.</description>
      <author>Jianshu Zhao, Maria Pachiadaki, Roth E. Conrad, Janet K. Hatt, Laura A. Bristow, Luis M. Rodr&#237;guez-R, Ramon Rossell&#243;&#8208;M&#243;ra, Frank J. Stewart, Konstantinos T. Konstantinidis</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.10.30.621061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ FTIR spectroscopy of epoxy resin degradation: kinetics and mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1476965</link>
      <description>Marianna Pannico, Giuseppe Mensitieri, Pellegrino Musto, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403901304

                We report on an in situ FTIR study of the thermo-oxidative degradation of a flexible epoxy resin. Different and complementary approaches to the analysis of the spectral data were employed, providing a detailed description of the process in terms of kinetics and mechanisms. A preliminary normal coordinate analysis, based on the DFT method, allowed for a reliable interpretation of the observed spectrum, increasing the amount of available structural information. Two-dimensional correlation spectroscopy provided details on the evolution of the reacting network structure. The relative stability of the various functional groups was ranked, and the most likely sites of initiation were identified. Oxygen fixation on the network chains produced amide and ketone groups, with the latter developing at a higher rate. The kinetic profiles of various functional groups were accurately simulated by a first-order, biexponential model, which allowed a quantitative comparison among their relative stabilities. The spectroscopic analysis allowed us to propose likely mechanisms and to identify those that occur preferentially.</description>
      <author>Marianna Pannico, Giuseppe Mensitieri, Pellegrino Musto</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1476965</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Bacterial Cellulose Production: A Scoping Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14111401</link>
      <description>M. Cruz, Omar Flor-Unda, A Avila, M.D. Garcia, Liliana Cerda-Mej&#237;a, Coatings. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404040237

                The versatility, contribution to sustainability, and diversity of applications of bacterial cellulose require large-scale production processes and new alternatives in terms of biological systems that, under controlled conditions, favor the growth and production of this biomaterial. This review article describes the technologies developed and the advances achieved in regard to the production of bacterial cellulose on a small and large scale, according to the findings evidenced in the scientific literature in the last ten years. A review, based on the guidelines in the PRISMA&#174; methodology, of a selection of articles was carried out, with a Cohen&#8217;s Kappa coefficient of 0.465; scientific databases, such as Web of Science, SCOPUS, PubMed, Taylor and Francis, and ProQuest, were considered. There is a wide variety of bacterial pulp production systems and the design of such a system is based on the type of cellulose-producing bacteria, oxygen requirements, mixing and agitation, temperature control, sterilization and cleaning requirements, and production scalability. The evolution in the development of bioreactors for bacterial cellulose has focused on improving the production process&#8217;s efficiency, productivity, and control, and adapting to the specific needs of bacterial strains and industrial applications.</description>
      <author>M. Cruz, Omar Flor-Unda, A Avila, M.D. Garcia, Liliana Cerda-Mej&#237;a</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/coatings14111401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Charge Imbalance on Field&#8208;Induced Instability of HfO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Based Ferroelectric Tunnel Junctions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aelm.202400299</link>
      <description>W. Shin, Changhyeon Han, Jangsaeng Kim, Ryun&#8208;Han Koo, Kyung Kyu Min, Daewoong Kwon, Advanced Electronic Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404049544

                Abstract Ferroelectricity in hafnium&#8208;based materials has attracted significant research attention and is used in various applications owing to their complementary metal&#8208;oxide&#8208;semiconductor compatibility, scalability, and low&#8208;power operation. However, their widespread integration into various technologies is hindered by reliability and stability problems, particularly field&#8208;induced instability, which causes fluctuations in polarization characteristics during operation. Herein, on the underlying mechanism of field&#8208;induced instability is reported in pure hafnium oxide films within metal&#8208;ferroelectric&#8208;insulator&#8208;semiconductor (MFIS) ferroelectric tunnel junctions (FTJs). The comprehensive material analysis combined with low&#8208;frequency noise (LFN) measurements reveals that the presence of oxygen vacancies and interface traps within the ferroelectric and dielectric layers induces a charge imbalance in the FTJ, leading to distortion in its polarization characteristics and the onset of cyclic evolution in field&#8208;induced instability. Furthermore, high&#8208;pressure annealing effectively mitigates field&#8208;induced instability by reducing the defects within the film, thereby alleviating the associated charge imbalance. These findings contribute to a deeper understanding of the internal dynamics of FTJs and provide an efficient approach to enhancing their stability.</description>
      <author>W. Shin, Changhyeon Han, Jangsaeng Kim, Ryun&#8208;Han Koo, Kyung Kyu Min, Daewoong Kwon</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aelm.202400299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improvement of succinate production from methane by combining rational engineering and laboratory evolution in Methylomonas sp. DH-1</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s12934-024-02557-0</link>
      <description>Jae-Hwan Jo, Jeong&#8208;Ho Park, Byung Kwon Kim, Seon Jeong Kim, Chan Mi Park, Chang Keun Kang, Yong Jun Choi, Hye-Jin Kim, Eun Yeol Lee, Myounghoon Moon, Gwon Woo Park, Sangmin Lee, Soo Youn Lee, Jin&#8208;Suk Lee, Won-Heong Lee, Jeong&#8208;Il Kim, Min&#8208;Sik Kim, Microbial Cell Factories. 23(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404020279

                Recently, methane has been considered a next-generation carbon feedstock due to its abundance and it is main component of shale gas and biogas. Methylomonas sp. DH-1 has been evaluated as a promising industrial bio-catalyst candidate. Succinate is considered one of the top building block chemicals in the agricultural, food, and pharmaceutical industries. In this study, succinate production by Methylomonas sp. DH-1 was improved by combining adaptive laboratory evolution (ALE) technology with genetic engineering in the chromosome of Methylomonas sp. DH-1, such as deletion of bypass pathway genes (succinate dehydrogenase and succinate semialdehyde dehydrogenase) or overexpression of genes related with succinate production (citrate synthase, pyruvate carboxylase and phosphoenolpyruvate carboxylase). Through ALE, the maximum consumption rate of substrate gases (methane and oxygen) and the duration maintaining high substrate gas consumption rates was enhanced compared to those of the parental strain. Based on the improved methane consumption, cell growth (OD600) increased more than twice, and the succinate titer increased by ~ 48% from 218 to 323 mg/L. To prevent unwanted succinate consumption, the succinate semialdehyde dehydrogenase gene was deleted from the genome. The first enzyme of TCA cycle (citrate synthase) was overexpressed. Pyruvate carboxylase and phosphoenolpyruvate carboxylase, which produce oxaloacetate, a substrate for citrate synthase, were also overproduced by a newly identified strong promoter. The new strong promoter was screened from RNA sequencing data. When these modifications were combined in one strain, the maximum titer (702 mg/L) was successfully improved by more than three times. This study demonstrates that successful enhancement of succinic acid production can be achieved in methanotrophs through additional genetic engineering following adaptive laboratory evolution.</description>
      <author>Jae-Hwan Jo, Jeong&#8208;Ho Park, Byung Kwon Kim, Seon Jeong Kim, Chan Mi Park, Chang Keun Kang, Yong Jun Choi, Hye-Jin Kim, Eun Yeol Lee, Myounghoon Moon, Gwon Woo Park, Sangmin Lee, Soo Youn Lee, Jin&#8208;Suk Lee, Won-Heong Lee, Jeong&#8208;Il Kim, Min&#8208;Sik Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s12934-024-02557-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolutionary choice between cholesterol and ergosterol</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0233475524050071</link>
      <description>&#1057;. &#1057;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1082;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, Sergey A. Akimov, Fedor F. Severin, &#1041;&#1080;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1080;&#1077; &#1084;&#1077;&#1084;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1099; &#1046;&#1091;&#1088;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083; &#1084;&#1077;&#1084;&#1073;&#1088;&#1072;&#1085;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1080; &#1082;&#1083;&#1077;&#1090;&#1086;&#1095;&#1085;&#1086;&#1081; &#1073;&#1080;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1075;&#1080;&#1080;. 41(5-6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404019958

                Sterol biosynthesis has evolved early in the history of eukaryotes. In most animals, as well as in primitive fungi, the main sterol is cholesterol. During the process of evolution, fungi acquired the ability to synthesize ergosterol. The pathway of its biosynthesis is more complex than the one of cholesterol biosynthesis. However, the evolutionary choice of most fungi was ergosterol, and the reason for this choice is still debated. In the majority of the works on this issue, the choice of most fungi is associated with the transition to life on land, and, consequently, the danger of cell dehydration. In our review we oppose this point of view. Probably, compared to cholesterol, ergosterol has more pronounced antioxidant properties. Indeed, the presence of three double bonds in the structure of the ergost&#1077;rol molecule, as compared to one in cholesterol, relatively increases the likelihood of interaction with reactive oxygen species. Perhaps, the transition to life on land required additional antioxidant protection. Due to the aforementioned structural differences, the molecule of cholesterol is apparently more flexible than that of ergosterol. Experimental data indicate that this feature provides greater membrane flexibility as compared to fungal membranes, as well as a greater ability to compensate for disturbances in the packing of membrane phospholipids. Presumably, for animal cells these qualities turned out to be relatively more important than antioxidant ones, which predetermined their evolutionary choice of sterol.</description>
      <author>&#1057;. &#1057;. &#1057;&#1086;&#1082;&#1086;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;, Sergey A. Akimov, Fedor F. Severin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0233475524050071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Endometriosis development in relation to hypoxia: a murine model study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-024-00973-x</link>
      <description>Marta Hoffmann, Rados&#322;aw Maksym, Katarzyna Pucia, Monika Kuciak, Andrzej Ma&#263;kiewicz, Claudine Kieda, Molecular Medicine. 30(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403891593

                Abstract Background Endometriosis, due to its ambiguous symptoms, still remains one of the most difficult female diseases to treat, with an average diagnosis time of 7&#8211;9 years. The changing level of hypoxia plays an important role in a healthy endometrium during menstruation and an elevated expression of the hypoxia-inducible factor 1-alpha (HIF-1&#945;) has been demonstrated in ectopic endometria. HIF-1&#945; mediates the induction of proangiogenic factors and the development of angiogenesis is a critical step in the establishment and pathogenesis of endometriosis. Although the inhibition of angiogenesis has been proposed as one of the actionable therapeutic modalities, vascular normalization and re-oxygenation may become a possible new approach for therapeutic intervention. Methods Our goal was to investigate whether a selected murine model of endometriosis would be suitable for future studies on new methods for treating endometriosis. Non-invasive, high-resolution ultrasound-monitored observation was selected as the preclinical approach to obtain imaging of the presence and volume of the endometriotic-like lesions. The EF5 (2-(2-Nitro-1H-imidazol-1-yl)-N-(2,2,3,3,3-pentafluoropropyl)acetamide) compound that selectively binds to reduced proteins in hypoxic cells was used for hypoxia detection. The expression of Pten and other crucial genes linking endometriosis and hypoxia were also assessed. Results Using EF5, a pentafluorinated derivative of the 2-nitroimidazole that is metabolically reduced by oxygen-inhibitable nitroreductase, we confirmed that hypoxia did develop in the selected model and was detected in uterine and ectopic endometriotic lesions. Moreover, the changes in oxygen tension also influenced the expression level of significant genes related to endometriosis, like Pten , Trp53 , Hif1a , Epas1 , and Vegfa . Their strong modulation evidenced here is indicative of model reliability. Using high-resolution ultrasound-based imaging, we present a non-invasive method of visualization that enables the detection and observation of lesion evolution throughout the duration of the experiment, which is fundamental for further preclinical studies and treatment evaluation. Conclusions The selected model and method of visualization appear to be suitable for the study of new treatment strategies based on hypoxia alleviation and blood flow restoration.</description>
      <author>Marta Hoffmann, Rados&#322;aw Maksym, Katarzyna Pucia, Monika Kuciak, Andrzej Ma&#263;kiewicz, Claudine Kieda</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1186/s10020-024-00973-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The molecular composition of birch tar and its infrared spectrum</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12520-024-02102-5</link>
      <description>Patrick Schmidt, Tabea J. Koch, Archaeological and Anthropological Sciences. 16(12)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404038627

                Abstract Birch tar was the first substance made by humans that is otherwise not available in nature. The oldest artefacts date to ~ 200 thousand years ago in Europe but birch tar becomes more frequent around 45 thousand years ago and even more so from the Mesolithic onwards. Their study has important implication for our understanding of evolutionary processes such as cognitive capacity and cultural evolution. What remains unknown is the overall molecular composition of birch tar. Several approaches based on gas chromatography-mass spectrometry have shown the potential of studying solvent soluble molecules to understand the botanical origin of different tars, their manufacturing techniques and their post-depositional alteration mechanisms. However, birch tar&#8217;s soluble fraction cannot shed light on its mechanical properties. In this study, we conduct gas chromatography-mass spectrometry and spectroscopic analysis of seven bulk birch tar samples, including infrared band assignment and structural refinement of organic molecules in the insoluble fraction. We find that the overall proportion that cannot be analysed by gas chromatography accounts for 85&#8211;90% in birch tar. This phase consists of polymerised molecules with a structure analogous to asphaltenes but containing a significantly greater amount of oxygen-related functional groups. Our findings have implications for understanding the viscosity, adhesiveness and stiffness of birch tar and they call for caution in applying analytical techniques that only target soluble molecules in birch tar.</description>
      <author>Patrick Schmidt, Tabea J. Koch</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12520-024-02102-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Oxygen Reconstruction Enables Dual&#8208;Ion Active Sites in Carbon Cathode for High Energy Density Sodium&#8208;Ion Capacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417059</link>
      <description>Jie Li, Chang Liu, Xinyu Hu, Jieming Cai, Huimin Lian, Dongxiao Li, Biao Zhong, Wentao Deng, Hongshuai Hou, Guoqiang Zou, Xiaobo Ji, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403896231

                Abstract Carbon materials are the promising cathode material for sodium&#8208;ion capacitors (SICs) with high energy/power density, however, clarifying the evolution processes of functional groups in carbon materials and revealing their energy storage mechanisms are full of challenges. Inspired by the ancient practice of alchemy, which sought to purify Dan medicine and remove impurities through precise control of the refining temperature, the local oxygen reconstruction strategy, to alter the functional groups species in SP 3 &#8208;C, is pioneeringly utilized, achieving targeted regulation of carbonyl groups with increase from 27.9 to 43.3 at%, which efficiently change the electronic structure of the carbon framework and realize the dual&#8208;ion adsorption of Na + and ClO 4 &#8722; , according well with the theoretical calculations. As expected, the obtained carbon cathode delivers a specific capacity of 145 mAh g &#8722;1 , higher than that of the parent carbon material (95 mAh g &#8722;1 ). Impressively, the ex situ X&#8208;ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy and in situ Raman reveals that carbonyl can act as dual&#8208;ion active sites for Na + and ClO 4 &#8722; through pseudocapacitive behavior under different voltage states. Notably, the assembled SIC using the carbonyl&#8208;rich carbon cathode exhibits an ultrahigh energy density of 162 Wh kg &#8722;1 . This work opens a novel avenue for regulating the carbonyl content of carbon materials.</description>
      <author>Jie Li, Chang Liu, Xinyu Hu, Jieming Cai, Huimin Lian, Dongxiao Li, Biao Zhong, Wentao Deng, Hongshuai Hou, Guoqiang Zou, Xiaobo Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202417059</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Defect-Dependent Conductivity-Type Switching in CuFe2O4 for Enhanced Photoelectrocatalytic Reduction of Benzaldehyde</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-9brl5</link>
      <description>Yen-Chun Huang, Jun-Lin Fong, Abdul M. Reyes, Sebastian E. Reyes&#8208;Lillo, Chang&#8208;Ming Jiang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403990593

                Photoelectrocatalytic (PEC) reduction of carbonyl-containing compounds provides a sustainable approach to upgrading biomass-derived feedstocks with reduced energy requirements. However, PEC reduction has primarily focused on hydrogen evolution and carbon dioxide reduction reactions, limited by the availability of stable photocathode materials. In this study, we demonstrate the extended PEC performance of defect-engineered CuFe2O4 films, achieving over 18 hours of stable benzaldehyde reduction to benzyl alcohol. Modulating CuFe2O4 conductivity from n-type to p-type through controlled annealing conditions enhanced its hole concentration, achieving a cathodic photocurrent density of 1.5 mA/cm2 at 0.5 V vs. RHE. Using 1,4-benzoquinone as a redox mediator in a mixed acetonitrile/water electrolyte, the PEC system produced benzyl alcohol at a rate of 2.57 &#956;mol/h with a Faradaic efficiency of 51.3% at 0.50 V vs. Ag/AgNO&#8323;. Photoelectrochemical impedance spectroscopy (PEIS) revealed that oxygen-rich annealing conditions improved charge transport and surface catalytic activity, resulting in a threefold increase in benzyl alcohol production rate. This PEC approach lowered the required applied potential by ~1 V compared to traditional electrocatalysis methods, offering a more energy-efficient route for carbonyl reduction. These findings underscore the potential of CuFe&#8322;O&#8324; as a viable photocathode material for sustainable organic transformations under mild reaction conditions.</description>
      <author>Yen-Chun Huang, Jun-Lin Fong, Abdul M. Reyes, Sebastian E. Reyes&#8208;Lillo, Chang&#8208;Ming Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-9brl5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genome-Wide Analysis of the Class III Peroxidase Gene Family in Physcomitrium patens and a Search for Clues to Ancient Class III Peroxidase Functions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ijpb15040079</link>
      <description>Vincent P. M. Aparato, Fazle Rabbi, Taylor Madarash, Wyllie A. Brisbourne, Elizabeth I. Barker, Dae&#8208;Yeon Suh, International Journal of Plant Biology. 15(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404060254

                Plant class III peroxidases (PRXs) catalyze generation of reactive oxygen species and oxidation of various compounds including lignin precursors. PRXs function in cell wall metabolism, defense, and stress responses. However, gene redundancy and catalytic versatility have impeded detailed functional characterization of PRX genes. The genome of the model moss Physcomitrium patens harbors a relatively small number (49) of PRX genes. Conserved architecture of four exons and three &#8216;001&#8217; introns, found in some algal PRX genes and in the PpPRX family, suggests that this architecture predated divergence of the green algal and land plant lineages. The PpPRX family expanded mainly through whole-genome duplications. All duplicated pairs but one were under purifying selection and generally exhibited similar expression profiles. An expanded phylogenetic tree revealed a conserved land plant-wide clade that contained PRXs implicated in stress responses in non-lignifying cells, providing a clue to ancient functions of land plant PRXs. Functional clustering was not observed, suggesting convergent evolution of specific PRX functions (e.g., lignification) in different plant lineages. With its small complement of PRXs, P. patens may be useful for functional characterization of land plant PRXs. Several PpPRXs were proposed for further study, including PpPRX34 and PpPRX39 in the ancient land plant-wide clade.</description>
      <author>Vincent P. M. Aparato, Fazle Rabbi, Taylor Madarash, Wyllie A. Brisbourne, Elizabeth I. Barker, Dae&#8208;Yeon Suh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ijpb15040079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An advanced approach for definition of the "Milky Way
  galaxies-analogues"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.04411</link>
      <description>I. B. Vavilova, Petr M. Fedorov, D. V. Dobrycheva, O. Sergijenko, Anatolii A. Vasylenko, Artem Dmytrenko, Vlad P. Khramtsov, O. V. KOMPANIIETS, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403963900

                Our Galaxy - the Milky Way - has certain features of the structure and evolution. The morphological, photometric, kinematic, and chemodynamical properties are usually considered in the search for the Milky Way galaxies-analogues (MWAs). The discovery of MWA galaxies with a larger number of simultaneous selection parameters and more stringent constraints on a given parameter yields a sample of MWA galaxies with properties closer to the true properties of the Milky Way. So, in general, such MW parameters as the morphological type, luminosity, color indices, structural parameters (size, bar, bulge, thin and thick disks, inner ring, halo), bulge to total ratio, stellar mass, star formation rate, metallicity, and rotation velocity were used in various combinations for comparison with other galaxies. However, the offset of some MW features in the multiparameter space of MWAs features should be significant. The paper aims to give a brief overview of the problematics and to present our approach for studying Milky Way and MWAs matching characteristics (this project is supported by the National Research Fund of Ukraine). We propose to enlarge as much as possible the number of Milky Way features and compile various samples of MWAs in our comoving cosmological volume for their further optimization. Such features can include 3Dkinematics of star's movement in certain regions, low oxygen content on the periphery, low nuclear activity, and the lack of significant merging over the past 10 Gyrs (isolation criterion). This approach will make it possible to widely formulate the necessary and sufficient conditions for the detection of MWA galaxies as well as to reveal other MW multiwavelength features.</description>
      <author>I. B. Vavilova, Petr M. Fedorov, D. V. Dobrycheva, O. Sergijenko, Anatolii A. Vasylenko, Artem Dmytrenko, Vlad P. Khramtsov, O. V. KOMPANIIETS</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.04411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure-Driven Performance Enhancement in Palladium&#8211;Graphene Oxide Catalysts for Electrochemical Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17215296</link>
      <description>Krishnamoorthy Sathiyan, Chang Gao, Toru Wada, Poulami Mukherjee, Kalaivani Seenivasan, Toshiaki Taniike, Materials. 17(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403943964

                Graphene oxide (GO) has recently gained significant attention in electrocatalysis as a promising electrode material owing to its unique physiochemical properties such as enhanced electron transfers due to a conjugated &#960;-electron system, high surface area, and stable support for loading electroactive species, including metal nanoparticles. However, only a few studies have been directed toward the structural characteristics of GO, elaborating on the roles of oxygen-containing functional groups, the presence of defects, interlayer spacing between the layered structure, and nonuniformity in the carbon skeleton along with their influence on electrochemical performance. In this work, we aim to understand these properties in various GO materials derived from different graphitic sources. Both physiochemical and electrochemical characterization were employed to correlate the above-mentioned features and explore the effect of the location of the palladium nanoparticles (Pd NPs) on various GO supports for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The interaction of the functional groups has a crucial role in the Pd dispersion and its electrochemical performance. Among the different GO samples, Pd supported on GO derived from graphene nanoplate (GNP), Pd/GO-GNP, exhibits superior HER performance; this could be attributed to the optimal balance among particle size, defect density, less in-plane functionalities, and higher electrochemical surface area. This study, thus, helps to identify the optimal conditions that lead to the best performance of Pd-loaded GO, contributing to the design of more effective HER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Krishnamoorthy Sathiyan, Chang Gao, Toru Wada, Poulami Mukherjee, Kalaivani Seenivasan, Toshiaki Taniike</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17215296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantifying systematic uncertainties in white dwarf cooling age
  determinations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.14014</link>
      <description>Prashant Pathak, Simon Blouin, Falk Herwig, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403995443

                Cooling ages of white dwarfs are routinely determined by mapping effective temperatures and masses to ages using evolutionary models. Typically, the reported uncertainties on cooling ages only consider the error propagation of the uncertainties on the spectroscopically or photometrically determined $T_{\rm eff}$ and mass. However, cooling models are themselves uncertain, given their dependence on many poorly constrained inputs. This paper estimates these systematic model uncertainties. We use MESA to generate cooling sequences of $0.5-1.0 M_{\odot}$ hydrogen-atmosphere white dwarfs with carbon-oxygen cores under different assumptions regarding the chemical stratification of their core, the thickness of their helium envelope, their hydrogen content, and the conductive opacities employed in the calculations. The parameter space explored is constrained by the range of values predicted by a variety of stellar evolution models and inferred from asteroseismological studies. For a $0.6 M_{\odot}$ white dwarf, we find an uncertainty of 0.03 Gyr at 10,000 K (corresponding to a 5% relative uncertainty) and 0.8 Gyr at 4000 K (9%). This uncertainty is significant, as it is comparable to the age uncertainty obtained by propagating the measurement errors on $T_{\rm eff}$ and mass for a typical white dwarf. We also separately consider the potential impact of $^{22}$Ne shell distillation, which plausibly leads to an additional uncertainty of $\sim 1$ Gyr for crystallized white dwarfs. We provide a table of our simulation results that can be used to evaluate the systematic model uncertainty based on a white dwarf's $T_{\rm eff}$ and mass. We encourage its use in all future studies where white dwarf cooling ages are measured.</description>
      <author>Prashant Pathak, Simon Blouin, Falk Herwig</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.14014</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>JWST/NIRSpec WIDE survey: a z=4.6 low-mass star-forming galaxy hosting a
  jet-driven shock with low ionisation and solar metallicity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.03982</link>
      <description>Francesco D&#8217;Eugenio, R. Maiolino, V. H. Mahatma, Giovanni Mazzolari, Stefano Carniani, Anna de Graaff, Michael V. Maseda, Eleonora Parlanti, Andrew J. Bunker, Xihan Ji, Gareth C. Jones, R. Morganti, Jan Scholtz, Sandro Tacchella, C. N. Tadhunter, Hannah &#220;bler, G. Venturi, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403966326

                We present NIRSpec/MSA observations from the JWST large-area survey WIDE, targeting the rest-frame UV-optical spectrum of Ulema, a radio-AGN host at redshift z=4.6348. The low-resolution prism spectrum displays high equivalent width nebular emission, with remarkably high ratios of low-ionisation species of oxygen, nitrogen and sulphur, relative to hydrogen; auroral O$^+$ emission is clearly detected, possibly also C$^+$. From the high-resolution grating spectrum, we measure a gas velocity dispersion $\sigma$~400 km s$^{-1}$, broad enough to rule out star-forming gas in equilibrium in the gravitational potential of the galaxy. Emission-line ratio diagnostics suggest that the nebular emission is due to a shock which ran out of pre-shock gas. To infer the physical properties of the system, we model simultaneously the galaxy spectral energy distribution (SED) and shock-driven line emission under a Bayesian framework. We find a relatively low-mass, star-forming system (M* = 1.4$\times$10^{10} M$_\odot$, SFR = 70 M$_\odot$ yr$^{-1}$), where shock-driven emission contributes 50 per cent to the total H$\beta$ luminosity. The nebular metallicity is near solar - three times higher than that predicted by the mass-metallicity relation at z=4.6, possibly related to fast-paced chemical evolution near the galaxy nucleus. We find no evidence for a recent decline in the SFR of the galaxy, meaning that, already at this early epoch, fast radio-mode AGN feedback was poorly coupled with the bulk of the star-forming gas; therefore, most of the feedback energy must end up in the galaxy halo, setting the stage for future quenching.</description>
      <author>Francesco D&#8217;Eugenio, R. Maiolino, V. H. Mahatma, Giovanni Mazzolari, Stefano Carniani, Anna de Graaff, Michael V. Maseda, Eleonora Parlanti, Andrew J. Bunker, Xihan Ji, Gareth C. Jones, R. Morganti, Jan Scholtz, Sandro Tacchella, C. N. Tadhunter, Hannah &#220;bler, G. Venturi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2408.03982</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A 45-year hydrological and planktonic time series in the South Bight of the North Sea</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-2024-479</link>
      <description>David Devreker, Guillaume Wacquet, Alain Lefebvre, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4404044141

                Abstract. This article presents a 45-year data series (from 1978 to 2023) acquired under the IGA (&#8220;Impact des Grands Am&#233;nagements&#8221; in French; Impacts of Major Developments) program, conducted by Ifremer for EDF (&#201;lectricit&#233; de France, the French multinational electricity utility company). The IGA program was established to monitor the ecological and environmental quality of the coastal area surrounding the Gravelines Nuclear Power Plant (NPP), located in the southern bight of the North Sea. The main objective of this program is to assess medium- and long-term environmental evolution by providing means to identify possible changes in the local marine habitats. Since 1978, the IGA program has measured key parameters, including temperature, salinity, nutrient concentrations, oxygen levels, chlorophyll-a concentrations, as well as the abundance of phytoplankton and zooplankton species. These measurements have been taken at different sampling stations around the NPP, including the &#8220;Canal d&#8217;amen&#233;e&#8221; sampling station, for which hydrological and biological characteristics are considered as representative of broader coastal area of the southern bight of the North Sea. This data paper provides an overview of the main statistical characteristics of the time series, including long-term trends and shifts analysis. Despite the importance and length of this dataset, one of the longest available for this region, its application in advancing knowledge of hydrological and biological processes has been surprisingly limited. The aim of this paper is to make this valuable dataset available to the scientific community, stakeholders, and society to help decipher the local and global influence of anthropogenic activities in a world increasingly affected by climate change. Since all the main statistics and patterns are still available thanks to our analysis, the user should be able to use this data and combine it with other sources (in situ, satellite, modelling), in order to dive into deeper analyses, and to investigate new key scientific challenges as well as more specific ones.</description>
      <author>David Devreker, Guillaume Wacquet, Alain Lefebvre</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/essd-2024-479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isotopic composition of natural waters of Kuzbass in coalbed methane production areas</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.18799/24131830/2024/10/4775</link>
      <description>&#1054;. &#1045;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1091;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Evgeniia V. Domrocheva, Bulletin of the Tomsk Polytechnic University Geo Assets Engineering. 335(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403903281

                Relevance. In Kuzbass, a coalbed methane production project is being implemented for the first time in Russia. Formation water extracted together with coalbed methane plays an important role, since it has been in contact with the coal-bearing rocks for a long time, therefore it contains rich geochemical information. Over the period 2002&#8211;2022, new isotopic data were accumulated both on the waters of the region coal deposits and on overlying waters, including surface waters. Aim. Based on the material accumulated on the isotopic composition (&#948;D, &#948;18O, &#948;13C, 34S, 3H, 14C) of natural waters in coal-bearing areas, create an evolutionary scheme for the formation of waters within the framework of the developed hypothesis on the interaction of water-rock-coal-methane. Objects. River, underground waters of the zone of active water exchange, upper and lower parts of the zone of slow water exchange (extracted together with coalbed methane). Methods. Studies of the isotopic composition of waters were carried out in several laboratories: in the Multielement and Isotope Research Center of the SB RAS, the Technical Branch of the Federal State Unitary Enterprise &#8220;SNIIGGIMS&#8221;, in the radiocarbon AMS laboratory based on the Center for Collective Use &#8220;Cenozoic Geochronology&#8221; and in the Pacific Oceanological Institute Far Eastern Branch Russian Academy of Sciences (POI) FEB RAS. Results and conclusions. The paper introduces the data on &#948;D, &#948;18&#1054;, &#948;13&#1057; &#1080; &#948;34S for surface and groundwater in Kuzbass in coalbed methane production areas. It is shown that all the waters under consideration are infiltration based on their isotopic composition (&#948;D and &#948;18&#1054;). The waters of the lower part of the slow water exchange, produced together with coalbed methane, are characterized by a positive oxygen shift and very light hydrogen. A diagram of the evolution of the isotopic composition of water-dissolved carbon in the region has been compiled according to the data obtained. It is noted that the atmospheric source of CO2 is characteristic only of river waters, and only biogenic carbon dioxide is present in groundwater. The wide range of &#948;13&#1057;DIC values of the latter is explained by the varying degrees of participation of light soil carbon dioxide and heavy biochemical carbon dioxide formed during methane formation in the coal seam. The heaviest values are typical for waters produced together with coalbed methane, which is associated with long-term interaction with coal and methane. The time of such interaction was determined using the radiocarbon method: 17&#8211;30 thousand years. In areas where coalbed methane is produced, an increase in &#948;13&#1057;DIC values for all natural waters is observed, which requires further study.</description>
      <author>&#1054;. &#1045;. &#1051;&#1077;&#1087;&#1086;&#1082;&#1091;&#1088;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, Evgeniia V. Domrocheva</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.18799/24131830/2024/10/4775</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Variability of CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CH&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; in a coastal peatland rewetted with brackish water from the Baltic Sea derived from autonomous high-resolution measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3246</link>
      <description>Daniel Lars P&#246;nisch, Henry C. Bittig, Martin Kolbe, Ingo Schuffenhauer, Stefan Otto, Peter Holtermann, K. Premaratne, Gregor Rehder, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403901945

                Abstract. Rewetting peatlands is an important measure to reduce greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from land use change. After rewetting, the areas can be highly heterogeneous in terms of GHG exchange and depend on water level, vegetation, previous use, and duration of rewetting. Here, we present a study of a coastal peatland that was rewetted by brackish water from the Baltic Sea and thus became part of the coastal shallow Baltic Sea water system through a permanent hydrological connection. Rewetting suppresses carbon dioxide (CO2) emissions by preventing aerobic decomposition of organic matter. Conversely, the anoxic conditions in the soil lead to an increase in methane (CH4) emissions, which counteracts CO2 mitigation effects. Unlike to rewetting with freshwater, the effects of rewetting with brackish, sulfate-containing water are less studied, although positive effects are expected as sulfate-reducing bacteria may become established and might out-compete methane-producing archaea (methanogens) for substrates, resulting in lower CH4 emissions. Both aspects, environmental heterogeneity and the brackish water column formation, require improved quantification techniques to assess local sinks and sources of atmospheric GHGs. We conducted nine weeks of autonomous and high-resolution, sensor-based bottom water measurements of marine physical and chemical variables at two locations in a permanently flooded peatland in summer 2021, and derived GHG fluxes. Results show considerable temporal fluctuations of CO2 and CH4, expressed as multi-day, diurnal and event-based variability and spatial differences for variables dominantly influenced by biological processes. The multi-day variability resulted in a pronounced magnitude of measured GHG partial pressures during the deployment ranging between 295.0&#8211;8937.8 &#181;atm (CO2) and 22.8&#8211;2681.3 &#181;atm (correspond to 42.7&#8211;3568.6 nmol L&#8722;1; CH4), respectively. In addition, the variability of the GHGs, temperature, and oxygen was characterized by pronounced diurnal cycles, resulting e.g., in a mean daily variability of 4066.9 &#181;atm for CO2 and 1769.6 &#181;atm for CH4. The diurnal variability led to a pronounced discrepancy between the measurements during the day and at night as well as depending on the location, resulting in CO2 and CH4 fluxes that varied by a factor of 2.1&#8211;2.3 and 2.3&#8211;3.0, respectively. The rewetted peatland was further impacted by fast system changes (events) such as storm, precipitation and major water level changes, which impacted biogeochemical cycling and GHG partial pressures. The derived average GHG exchange amounted to 0.12 &#177; 0.16 g m&#8722;2 h&#8722;1 (CO2) and 0.51 &#177; 0.56 mg m&#8722;2 h&#8722;1 (CH4), respectively. These fluxes are high (CO2) to low (CH4) compared to studies from temperate peatlands rewetted with freshwater. Comparing these fluxes with the previous year (i.e., results from a reference study), the fluxes decreased by a factor of 1.9 and 2.6, respectively. This was potentially due to a progressive consumption of organic material, a suppression of CH4 production, and aerobic and anaerobic oxidation of CH4, indicating a positive evolution of the rewetted peatland into a site with moderate GHG emissions within the next years.</description>
      <author>Daniel Lars P&#246;nisch, Henry C. Bittig, Martin Kolbe, Ingo Schuffenhauer, Stefan Otto, Peter Holtermann, K. Premaratne, Gregor Rehder</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-3246</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolyte Effects in Electrocatalytic Kinetics&lt;sup&gt;&#8224;&lt;/sup&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400458</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Li, Zhiming Zhang, Xinxin Zhuang, Zhen Jia, Tao Wang, Chinese Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403984726

                Comprehensive Summary Tuning electrolyte properties is a widely recognized strategy to enhance activity and selectivity in electrocatalysis, drawing increasing attention in this domain. Despite extensive experimental and theoretical studies, debates persist about how various electrolyte components influence electrocatalytic reactions. We offer a concise review focusing on current discussions, especially the contentious roles of cations. This article further examines how different factors affect the interfacial solvent structure, particularly the hydrogen&#8208;bonding network, and delves into the microscopic kinetics of electron and proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer. We also discuss the overarching influence of solvents from a kinetic modeling perspective, aiming to develop a robust correlation between electrolyte structure and reactivity. Lastly, we summarize ongoing research challenges and suggest potential directions for future studies on electrolyte effects in electrocatalysis. Key Scientists In 1956, Marcus theory was developed to describe the mechanism of outer&#8208;sphere electron transfer (OS&#8208;ET). In 1992, Nocera et al. directly measured proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer (PCET) kinetics for the first time, and their subsequent research in 1995 investigated the effects of proton motion on electron transfer (ET) kinetics. In 1999 and 2000, Hammes&#8208;schiffer et al. developed the multistate continuum theory for multiple charge reactions and deduced the rate expressions for nonadiabatic PCET reactions in solution, laying the theoretical foundation for the analysis of PCET kinetics in electrochemical processes. In 2006, Saveant et al. verified the concerted proton and electron transfer (CPET) mechanism in the oxidation of phenols coupled with intramolecular amine&#8208;driven proton transfer (PT). Their subsequent work in 2008 reported the pH&#8208;dependent pathways of electrochemical oxidation of phenols. Electrolyte effects in electrocatalysis have gained emphasis in recent years. In 2009, Markovic's pioneering work proposed non&#8208;covalent interactions between hydrated alkaline cations and adsorbed OH species in oxygen reduction reaction (ORR)/hydrogen oxidation reaction (HOR). In 2011, Markovic et al. significantly enhanced hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activity in alkaline solution by improving water dissociation, which was assumed to dominate the sluggish HER kinetics in such media. In comparation, Yan et al. applied hydrogen binding energy (HBE) theory in 2015 to explain the pH&#8208;dependent HER/HOR activity. Cations play a significant role in regulating the selectivity and activity of carbon dioxide reduction (CO 2 RR). In 2016 and 2017, Karen Chan et al. introduced the electric field generated by solvated cations to explain the cation effects on electrochemical CO2RR. Conversely, in 2021, Koper et al. suggested that short&#8208;range electrostatic interactions between partially desolvated metal cations and CO 2 stabilized CO 2 and promoted CO 2 RR. Recent researches have combined the exploration of the electrical double layer (EDL) structure with theoretical analysis of PCET kinetics. In 2019, Huang et al. developed a microscopic Hamiltonian model to quantitatively understand the sluggish hydrogen electrocatalysis in alkaline media. In 2021, two meticulous studies from Shao&#8208;Horn's group analyzed the effects of cations on reorganization energy and the impacts of hydrogen bonds between proton donors and acceptors on proton tunneling kinetics, respectively. Electrolyte effects on proton transport process were researched in recent years. In 2022, Hu et al. and Chen et al. proposed that the cation&#8208;induced electric field distribution and pH&#8208;dependent hydrogen bonding network connectivity played essential roles in proton transport, separately.</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Li, Zhiming Zhang, Xinxin Zhuang, Zhen Jia, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cjoc.202400458</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Are we prepared for the next pandemic: Monitor on increasing human and animal H5N1 avian influenza infection</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1097/cm9.0000000000003375</link>
      <description>Wei Wang, Yanxia Sun, Zhongjie Li, Weizhong Yang, Shuo Feng, Chinese Medical Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403891616

                Human infection with highly pathogenic avian influenza (HPAI) caused by certain strains of avian influenza A viruses, such as H5N1 and H7N9, results in severe acute respiratory disease with a high mortality rate, among which the former is pathogenic to birds.[1] In recent years, HPAI H5 has spread globally, causing human infections. The first reported case of bovine H5N1 infection, which was subsequently transmitted to humans, garnered significant international attention. Drawing on the historical influenza pandemic experience and biological characteristics of the virus, under specific conditions, such as reassortment with human and swine influenza viruses, avian influenza viruses (AIV) may achieve efficient human-to-human transmission, potentially leading to a global pandemic. Here, we aimed to review the historical trends of H5N1 avian influenza infections in humans and the recent developments in epidemiological situations, evaluate the transmission risk of H5N1 avian influenza, and propose avian influenza control recommendations for public health decision-making. Global trends in human H5N1 infection. The avian influenza A H5N1 was first detected in southern China in 1996. In 1997, a significant outbreak of H5N1 avian influenza occurred among farmed chickens in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, marking the first reported case of H5N1 crossing the species barrier to infect humans. This initial outbreak resulted in 18 human infections and 6 fatalities. Although the outbreak was controlled at that time, H5N1 persisted in avian species. It re-emerged in 2003 and widely spread among birds across Asia and subsequently to Africa, Europe, and the Middle East, leading to poultry outbreaks and sporadic human infections. By late 2003, Southeast Asia had experienced successive H5N1 outbreaks, with the number of infections and deaths peaking in 2006. Since then, almost all such cases have been annually reported. From 1997 to May 26, 2024, 911 human H5N1 infections were reported across 24 countries, with most cases reported between 2004 and 2016, predominantly in Asia and Africa [Figure 1A]. Between 2003 and 2024, 896 individuals were confirmed to have contracted HPAI H5N1 with 463 reported deaths, resulting in an approximate fatality rate of 52%.[2]Figure 1: The global trend of human infection with H5N1 avian influenza and H5N1 avian influenza outbreaks. (A) represents the global trend in human H5N1 infections from January 1997 to August 2024, sourced from https://www.cdc.gov/flu/avianflu/chart-epi-curve-ah5n1.html. The yellow from light to dark corresponds to the increasing number of human cases infected with H5N1. (B) represents the global trend in highly pathogenic avian influenza H5N1 outbreaks from January 2005 to August 2024, sourced from https://wahis.woah.org/#/dashboards/qd-dashboard. The blue from light to dark corresponds to the increasing number of avian H5N1 outbreaks. AFRO: African Region of WHO; AMRO: Americas Region of WHO; EMRO: Eastern Mediterranean Region of WHO; EURO: European Region of WHO; SEARO: South-East Asia Region of WHO; WPRO: Western Pacific Region of WHO.H5 has spread to &gt;150 avian and 50 mammalian species.[3] The H5N1 currently circulating among wild birds and poultry in most parts of the world predominantly belongs to the 2.3.4.4b clade.[4] Genetically distinct from earlier genotypes, it emerged in 2020 from previously prevalent H5NX subtype viruses and has spread primarily through migratory birds to regions, including Africa, Asia, and Europe. By late 2021, this clade reached North America and subsequently spread to South America by October 2022. The genetic flexibility of HPAI H5N1 from clade 2.3.4.4b allows for extensive reassortment with other AIVs, yielding a diverse array of H5N1&#8211;H5N8 viruses.[5] This efficient reassortment has led to the emergence of &gt;50 genotypes.[6] Although there has been an increase in HPAI H5N1 infections in mammals, reports on mammal-to-mammal transmission remain limited. Between 2021 and April 2024, 28 human cases of H5N1 infection have been reported globally. Among the human cases identified as hemagglutinin (HA) H5 clade infections, 13 were caused by the 2.3.4.4b clade.[7] The severity of human illnesses resulting from AIV infection widely varies, ranging from asymptomatic or mild illness to severe disease leading to death. Characteristics of the recent A(H5N1) outbreak. Recent analyses have highlighted that the emergence of H5N1 2.3.4.4b is associated with outbreaks in the United States. This lineage is characterized by increased pathogenicity at non-traditional interfaces, underscoring the ability of the virus to cross species barriers.[8] On March 25, 2024, the United States detected the HPAI H5N1 strain in dairy cows. Infected cows showed symptoms, such as high fever, dehydration, and reduced milk production.[9] As of August 9, 2024, at least 189 dairy farms across 13 states in the United States have reported H5N1 infections, and there have been four human cases associated with an ongoing multistate outbreak of A(H5N1) in dairy cows.[10,11] The patients were dairy farm workers with epidemiological links to infected cows who presented with conjunctivitis, representing the first instance of human infection following transmission from infected dairy cows. This contrasts with the first United States H5N1 case reported in 2022, in which the patient reported only fatigue and has since recovered. Genomic data suggested that the recent H5N1 outbreak in the United States likely originated from infected birds transmitting the virus to dairy cows in late 2023 or early 2024, with subsequent spread among cow populations for several months. The spread of HAPI H5N1 in cattle poses a risk to humans through close contact with farm workers. Infected lactating cows produce milk containing high levels of the influenza virus, which, if not pasteurized, can contaminate milking equipment and act as a transmission vector for dairy farm workers. The latest study also indicated that both bovine H5N1 and the human 2009 H1N1 pandemic influenza viruses remained infectious on common milking equipment surfaces for several hours.[12] The H5N1 2.3.4.4b lineage exhibits strong transmission capabilities, with the potential to spread between birds and mammals. Recent outbreaks have suggested that the 2.3.4.4b lineage may have adapted to infect dairy cows, leading to its spread and infection in cattle. This adaptation allows the virus to be transmitted from cows to humans, specifically in close-contact environments, such as dairy farms, which are highly pathogenic in birds and cause severe disease. In cattle, the virus causes noticeable clinical symptoms, such as high fever and reduced milk production. Humans infected with this lineage show more severe symptoms than earlier H5N1 infections, including conjunctivitis, indicating a possible increase in pathogenicity. Current information suggests that AIV, particularly lineage 2.3.4.4b, may have adapted to mammalian hosts, increasing the likelihood of human infection through interspecies transmission. Public health risk assessment. From a food safety perspective, the consumption of pasteurized milk and properly cooked beef is safe for the public. To verify the safety of the meat supply in the context of H5N1, the United States Department of Agriculture (USDA), Food Safety and Inspection Service (FSIS), Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, and Agricultural Research Service conducted three studies on the safety of beef from cattle affected by avian influenza. As of May 24, 2024, none of the diseased cattle culled at the slaughterhouses had entered the food supply chain, and ground beef samples collected from retail stores in the affected states tested negative for viral particles. Cooking beef to the FSIS-recommended temperatures of 145&#176;F (medium rare) or 160&#176;F (well done) can eliminate the virus, and cooking to 120&#176;F (rare) is sufficient to inactivate the virus substantially.[13] As of May 10, 2024, the USDA and Food and Drug Administration (FDA) have confirmed that the commercial milk supply is safe, as all sold milk undergoes pasteurization, and milk from infected cows has been either diverted or destroyed. Additionally, none of the 297 samples collected by the FDA at retail points tested positive for live HPAI H5N1.[14] Based on genetic sequencing of US-confirmed cases, the current risk of human-to-human transmission remains low.[15] The HA gene in the conjunctival samples from the Michigan H5N1 patient was identified as clade 2.3.4.4b. Each gene segment was closely related to the B3.13 genotype virus detected in cows by the USDA. These data indicated that the virus detected in both cows and humans retained avian genetic characteristics and lacked the gene expression necessary for efficient human-to-human transmission. However, specific mutations, such as PB2-M631L in Michigan and PB2-E627K in Texas, may enhance the ability of the virus to spread in mammals. Although H5N1 typically prefers binding to &#945;-2,3-sialic acid (SA &#945;-2,3), which is less common in humans, the PB2-E627K and PB2-M631L mutations may enhance the virus's ability to bind to SA &#945;-2,6 on the surface of human lower respiratory epithelial cells. This increased binding capability can improve viral replication efficiency, potentially enhancing the adaptability and transmissibility of H5N1 in mammals, leading to severe respiratory infections and pneumonia.[16] A pathogenicity study based on mice and ferrets revealed that HPAI H5N1 derived from lactating dairy cattle had dual receptor binding specificity, which may induce severe disease after oral ingestion or respiratory infection. Infection by either the oral or respiratory route can lead to systemic spread of the virus to non-respiratory tissues, including the eye, mammary gland, teat, and/or muscle.[17] The rest of the Michigan patient genome closely matched the sequences detected in infected cows, suggesting direct transmission from cows to humans. This sentence is almost identical to the previous statement, so it has been deleted. According to the World Organization for Animal Health, 13,755 H5N1 outbreaks were reported worldwide from 2005 to May 2024, with most occurring in Europe and North America over the past 3 years [Figure 1B]. H5N1 predominantly spreads among birds and poultry and occasionally infects mammals and humans. Prior to the reported cases of H5N1 transmission from dairy cows to humans in the United States, nearly all human H5N1 cases worldwide had a history of contact with poultry or exposure to live bird markets. Although some family clusters were observed, there was no evidence of efficient human-to-human transmission. Based on current data, H5N1 avian influenza outbreaks in wild birds, poultry, cattle, and other animals pose a low risk to the public. However, there is a low-to-moderate risk of infection for individuals who come into contact with H5N1-infected birds or animals or are exposed to environments contaminated by the virus. In addition, the eight major migratory bird routes worldwide can increase the risk of AIV introduction into countries along these routes. The continuous evolution and spread of AIV in animals indicate that the risk of human exposure persists. Consequently, the potential for sporadic cases or even small clusters of human infections remains a concern. Countermeasures for prevention and control. Recombinations and mutations suggest that H5N1 poses a potential threat to the pandemic, necessitating proactive preparedness. This involves focusing on the development and application of tools, such as vaccines, therapeutics, and diagnostic reagents, and capacity building in the areas of surveillance, early warning systems, and response preparedness. The "One Health" concept provides a comprehensive strategy for the control of HPAI, emphasizing the interconnectedness of humans, animals, and the environment. Promoting collaboration, interdisciplinary communication, and coordinated actions among veterinarians, public health experts, environmental scientists, and policymakers can enhance the effectiveness of disease surveillance, prevention, and control measures. Based on this "One Health" concept, current environmental monitoring of H5N1 avian influenza involves comprehensive surveillance strategies targeting both wildlife and domestic poultry, with a focus on detecting and mitigating outbreaks early. Surveillance includes testing migratory birds and poultry for H5N1; sampling environmental materials, such as water and soil; and using advanced diagnostic techniques to identify and characterize virus strains. Despite these efforts, global and local conflicts have challenged information sharing. International bodies, such as the World Health Organization, coordinate data exchange and facilitate global response efforts, whereas regional and local entities work to overcome the barriers posed by geopolitical tensions and conflict zones. Effective communication channels are maintained through public health messaging, collaborative networks, and emergency response planning to ensure the timely and accurate dissemination of information to curb the spread of H5N1 and enhance preparedness across affected areas. Based on this, we offer insights and recommendations for key linkage measures for further responses to H5N1 infection. "Human&#8211;Animal&#8211;Environment" multichannel surveillance and risk assessment. The proactive surveillance of severe syndromes among occupational groups in contact with animals is essential. This primarily involves health monitoring of individuals at a higher risk of exposure to animal pathogens, such as workers in large-scale animal farming, veterinarians, animal slaughter and processing workers, and staff in wildlife conservation areas. Additionally, surveillance for pneumonia of an unknown etiology should be initiated in the general population. Strengthening the reporting awareness of clinical doctors will help collect samples for pathogen identification and conduct epidemiological investigations in a timely manner once cluster cases or serious hospitalized cases are discovered, thereby identifying the potential risk of animal pathogens infecting humans as soon as possible. Close attention should be paid to the global dynamics of avian influenza outbreaks, with particular emphasis on surveillance in high-risk areas. Regular sampling and testing of poultry and wild birds in farms, markets, and natural habitats are recommended to monitor the transmission and mutation of AIV. Enhanced information sharing among the health, agriculture, and forestry departments is necessary to integrate data from various surveillance channels, such as public sentiment, drug sales, respiratory syndrome reports, testing, and imaging. Key monitoring focuses include the epidemiological characteristics of human infections with avian influenza, viral mutations, transmission capabilities, and clinical severity. Increasing the frequency of risk assessments, early warning systems, and the development of precise and effective early warning technologies enables multipoint triggering and timely implementation of relevant preventive and control measures. Conventional surveillance methods, including pathogen genome sequencing, laboratory diagnostics, and mortality surveillance, are inadequate in the face of complex and rapidly evolving threats. Wastewater monitoring is a critical tool, as demonstrated during the coronavirus disease 2019 pandemic.[18] Strengthening animal disease surveillance is also highly recommended, particularly to gain a deeper understanding of the activities and movements of migratory birds. It is essential to enhance monitoring of poultry around migratory bird habitats, increase environmental and animal surveillance along migratory bird migration routes, and boost sampling proportions and frequencies. Utilizing monitoring devices and regular patrols enables real-time monitoring of high-risk areas, ensuring the prompt detection and management of outbreak events. Protection for occupational groups and objective Public Health education. For individuals who come into contact with infected birds or other animals owing to their occupation, including those working in wildlife reserves, poultry farms, or dairies, individuals raising birds, and personnel responding to avian influenza outbreaks in birds or other animals, it is crucial to enhance their awareness of protective measures. When directly or closely interacting with deceased poultry or livestock, they must strictly adhere to protocols for wearing personal protective equipment. Additionally, before entering spaces where these animals reside or have not yet been disinfected, they should undergo comprehensive personal protection training. Physicians should be alert from a clinical perspective to recognize a history of avian exposure, such as in cattle, in patients with associated H5N1 symptoms, such as conjunctivitis, and assist in confirming the diagnosis of H5N1 infection with polymerase chain reaction testing and lung imaging to assess the presence of pneumonia or acute respiratory distress syndrome. Following confirmation of the diagnosis, antiviral drugs, such as oseltamivir, should be administered immediately, and treatment should be initiated at an earlier onset if possible. Support, such as oxygen therapy or mechanical ventilation, may be required for critically ill patients and to prevent secondary bacterial infections. Patients should be hospitalized and isolated, and healthcare workers should be strictly protected. Influenza vaccination is recommended in high-risk occupational groups. Furthermore, to avoid unnecessary panic, we recommend providing the public with accurate and truthful reports on the outbreak and conducting objective and appropriate health education without exaggerating the situation. The public should be reminded to avoid contact with sick or deceased animals, including wild birds, poultry, domesticated birds; and other wild or domestic animals, and animal waste, litter, or materials contaminated with birds or animals that are suspected or confirmed to be infected with AIV. Additionally, it is important to avoid slaughtering or consuming diseased or dead poultry and livestock and to refrain from consuming undercooked foods, such as raw milk or cheese that have not been pasteurized. Development of novel vaccines and technological preparedness. Currently, seasonal influenza vaccines do not prevent the spread of AIV in humans globally. Several countries are developing H5N1 avian influenza vaccines for emergency preparedness. In the United States, three H5N1 vaccines, developed from earlier strains of HPAI H5N1 (A/Vietnam, clade 1, and A/Indonesia, clade 2.1), with (MF59-CSL, Seqirus, Melbourne, Australia or AS03-GSK, Brentford, United Kingdom) or without adjuvants (Sanofi Pasteur, Lille, France), are licensed and stockpiled for pre-pandemic preparedness.[19] A recent study showed that adults who received three licensed adjuvanted H5N1 vaccines generated cross-neutralizing antibodies against the circulating HPAI H5N1 clade 2.3.4.4b in humans.[20] Individuals vaccinated with the two licensed adjuvanted H5N1 vaccines generated cross-reactive binding and cross-neutralizing antibodies against the HPAI clade 2.3.4.4b A/Astrakhan/3212/2020 virus. Seroconversion rates of 60&#8211;95% against H5 clade 2.3.4.4b were recorded after two doses of AS03-adjuvanted-A/Indonesia or three doses of MF59-adjuvanted-A/Vietnam vaccine. Additionally, a monovalent messenger RNA (mRNA) lipid nanoparticle vaccine expressing 2.3.4.4b was immunogenic and protective in preclinical animal models, with H5-reactive antibody levels increasing approximately eightfold after the second dose compared with those before the booster.[21] The advantage of this vaccine is that it can be rapidly produced without the need to isolate and adapt to a viral strain that grows effectively in fertilized chicken eggs or cell cultures. The manufacture of a novel mRNA vaccine can begin within hours of sequencing a new pandemic viral strain. Considering the pandemic potential of H5N1, efforts should be made to develop stockpiled vaccines, antiviral drugs, and diagnostic tools. It is important to monitor the latest internationally shared AIV sequences, further survey relevant variants that may affect outbreak trends, and analyze key mutations and dynamic changes in virus sequences. For example, PB2-E627K and PB2-M631L in PB2 influence how well a vaccine protects against different influenza strains. If vaccines are developed based on strains lacking these mutations, they may be less effective against the strains carrying either E627K or M631L. Thus, inclusion of these mutations in vaccine strain selection is crucial for maintaining vaccine effectiveness. The presence of these mutations highlights the need for continuous surveillance and updating vaccines to ensure that they cover the most current and relevant strains. This may involve modifying vaccine composition or developing new vaccines to address emerging viral variants. This will allow for timely updates on vaccine strains, diagnostic primers, and sequences, thereby ensuring readiness for potential pandemics. In addition, continued support for the development of universal influenza vaccines is crucial. Establishing a stable pandemic simulation team for emerging infectious diseases can aid scenario-based pandemic preparedness and intervention evaluation studies and enhance decision-making capabilities for pandemic response readiness. Other valuable practices for reference. The "physical isolation and culling" strategy is commonly used in many countries. However, large-scale culling measures can cause economic losses to the poultry industry. For example, owing to recurring avian influenza outbreaks in the United Kingdom, over 5.5 million birds were culled between October 2021 and November 2022. In the United States, the avian influenza outbreak in 2022 led to the deaths of approximately 40 million animals, resulting in economic losses estimated between US$2.5 billion and US$3 billion.[22] As a large global producer and consumer of agricultural products, China has maintained its stability during recent outbreaks over the past 5 years. There have been no widespread poultry infections or culling, and poultry production has remained relatively steady, despite frequent global avian influenza outbreaks. Since 2004, China has implemented immunization against H5 and/or H7 HPAI in all domestically raised poultry. Furthermore, China mandates a 100% vaccination coverage rate and ensures that the annual qualification rate of immunization antibodies remains &gt;70%.[23] By the end of 2022, over 300 billion doses of various vaccines developed in China were administered, both domestically and internationally. Currently, two H5 vaccine seed viruses, H5-Re13, which targets the clade 2.3.4.4h virus that emerged in China in 2017, and H5-Re14, which addresses the clade 2.3.4.4b virus circulating globally, are used alongside the H7N9 vaccine seed virus H7-Re4 in the production of the trivalent vaccine.[24] Between 2002 and 2010, more than 113 billion vaccines were administered worldwide. Five countries have adopted national routine interpoultry immunization programs, accounting for 99% of vaccine use: China (90.9%), Egypt (4.6%), Indonesia (2.3%), Vietnam (1.4%), and Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (&lt;0.01%). The high vaccine coverage enabled the prevention of clinical diseases and deaths in poultry, such as poultry fowl, reduction of human cases, maintenance of rural livelihoods, and food security.[25] Thus, this "culling and vaccination" strategy, distinctive to China, has significantly reduced losses during avian influenza outbreaks and offers valuable lessons for global control efforts against highly pathogenic H5N1. Conflicts of interest None. Funding This work was supported by grants from the Chinese Academy of Medical Sciences Innovation Fund for Medical Sciences (Nos. 2022-I2M-CoV19-006, 2021-I2M-1-044) and the Science &amp; Technology Fundamental Resources Investigation Program (No. 2023FY100600).</description>
      <author>Wei Wang, Yanxia Sun, Zhongjie Li, Weizhong Yang, Shuo Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1097/cm9.0000000000003375</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
