<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 01:14:52 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>A Universal Molecular Oxygen-mediated Photocatalysis Strategy to Boost Visible-light Induced Hydrogen Evolution through Partial Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124536</link>
      <description>Nan Lu, Xiaoqing Yan, Biling Wu, Hisayoshi Kobayashi, L Renhong, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401877402

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nan Lu, Xiaoqing Yan, Biling Wu, Hisayoshi Kobayashi, L Renhong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124536</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cover Feature: Self&#8208;Modification of Defective TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; under Controlled H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Ar Gas Environment and Dynamics of Photoinduced Surface Oxygen Vacancies (ChemSusChem 16/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202481603</link>
      <description>Tim Tjardts, Marie Elis, Josiah Shondo, Lennart Vo&#223;, Ulrich Sch&#252;rmann, Franz Faupel, Lorenz Kienle, Salih Veziro&#287;lu, Oral Cenk Aktas, ChemSusChem. 17(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401881215

                The Cover Feature abstractly depicts the influence of a mixture of argon (symbolized by pink) and hydrogen (symbolized by blue) on a TiO2 pellet sample in the hydrogenation process. The blue cylinder in the center shows a defective TiO2 pellet sample with an enhanced photocatalytic activity. The green and yellow corona around the cylinder embodies this activity. The grey ellipse to the right shows the induced defects; the Ti3+ site and the oxygen vacancy Vo. More information can be found in the Research Article by S. Veziroglu, O. C. Aktas and co-workers.</description>
      <author>Tim Tjardts, Marie Elis, Josiah Shondo, Lennart Vo&#223;, Ulrich Sch&#252;rmann, Franz Faupel, Lorenz Kienle, Salih Veziro&#287;lu, Oral Cenk Aktas</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202481603</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights from Ca2+&#8594;Sr2+ substitution on the mechanism of O-O bond formation in photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01117-2</link>
      <description>Gabriel Bury, Yulia Pushkar, Photosynthesis Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401884144

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gabriel Bury, Yulia Pushkar</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01117-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Efficient CoFeP Nanoparticle Catalysts for Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14171384</link>
      <description>Abhishek Meena, Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Aditya Narayan Singh, Vijaya Gopalan Sree, Hyunsik Im, S. K. Cho, Nanomaterials. 14(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401891652

                Developing effective and long-lasting electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical for increasing sustainable hydrogen production. This paper describes the production and characterization of CoFeP nanoparticles (CFP NPs) as high-performance electrocatalysts for OER. The CFP NPs were produced using a simple hydrothermal technique followed by phosphorization, yielding an amorphous/crystalline composite structure with improved electrochemical characteristics. Our results reveal that CFP NPs have a surprisingly low overpotential of 284 mV at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2, greatly exceeding the precursor CoFe oxide/hydroxide (CFO NPs) and the commercial RuO2 catalyst. Furthermore, CFP NPs demonstrate exceptional stability, retaining a constant performance after 70 h of continuous operation. Post-OER characterization analysis revealed transformations in the catalyst, including the formation of cobalt&#8211;iron oxides/oxyhydroxides. Despite these changes, CFP NPs showed superior long-term stability compared to native metal oxides/oxyhydroxides, likely due to enhanced surface roughness and increased active sites. This study proposes a viable strategy for designing low-cost, non-precious metal-based OER catalysts, which will help advance sustainable energy technology.</description>
      <author>Abhishek Meena, Abu Talha Aqueel Ahmed, Aditya Narayan Singh, Vijaya Gopalan Sree, Hyunsik Im, S. K. Cho</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14171384</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated MXenes and Metal Oxide Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Synthesis, Mechanisms, and Advances</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc04141k</link>
      <description>Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Abdul Hanan, Yuan Wang, Hiang Kwee Lee, Hamidreza Arandiyan, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401893313

                Electrochemical water splitting is a promising approach to produce H2 through renewable electricity, but its energy efficiency is severely constrained by the kinetically slow anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which...</description>
      <author>Muhammad Nazim Lakhan, Abdul Hanan, Yuan Wang, Hiang Kwee Lee, Hamidreza Arandiyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc04141k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of novel FeSe&#8211;GO composite: a highly efficient electro-catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00434-5</link>
      <description>Khadim Hussain, Ali Junaid, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Muhammad Shoaib, Nigarish Bano, Razan A. Alshgari, Nosheen Blouch, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Journal of the Korean Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401893438

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Khadim Hussain, Ali Junaid, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Muhammad Shoaib, Nigarish Bano, Razan A. Alshgari, Nosheen Blouch, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00434-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Cladding Engineering via Oxygen Sulfur Distribution for Stable Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413348</link>
      <description>An Li, Shengjie Zi, Jiamin Zhu, Yue Zhai, Yang Hu, Zhaodong Nan, Shuhui Li, Luohua Liu, Pinxian Xi, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401894520

                Inevitable leaching and corrosion under anodic oxidative environment greatly restrict the lifespan of most catalysts with excellent primitive activity for oxygen production. Here, based on Fick&#8217; s Law, we present a surface cladding strategy to mitigate Ni dissolution and stabilize lattice oxygen triggering by directional flow of interfacial electrons and strong electronic interactions via constructing elaborately cladding&#8208;type NiO/NiS heterostructure with controlled surface thickness. Multiple in&#8208;situ characterization technologies indicated that this strategy can effectively prevent the irreversible Ni ions leaching and inhibit lattice oxygen from participating in anodic reaction. Combined with density functional theory calculations, we reveal that the stable interfacial O&#8208;Ni&#8208;S arrangement can facilitate the accumulation of electrons on surficial NiO side and weaken its Ni&#8208;O covalency. This would suppress the overoxidation of Ni and simultaneously fixing the lattice oxygen, thus enabling catalysts with boosted corrosion resistance without sacrificing its activity. Consequently, this cladding&#8208;type NiO/NiS heterostructure exhibits excellent performance with a low overpotential of 256 mV after 500 h. Based on Fick&#8217;s law, this work demonstrates the positive effect of surface modification through precisely adjusting of the oxygen&#8208;sulfur exchange process, which has paved an innovative and effective way to solve the instability problem of anodic oxidation.</description>
      <author>An Li, Shengjie Zi, Jiamin Zhu, Yue Zhai, Yang Hu, Zhaodong Nan, Shuhui Li, Luohua Liu, Pinxian Xi, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Cladding Engineering via Oxygen Sulfur Distribution for Stable Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413348</link>
      <description>Li An, Shengjie Zi, Jiamin Zhu, Yue Zhai, Yang Hu, Nan Zhang, Hui Yao, Luohua Liu, Pinxian Xi, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401894569

                Inevitable leaching and corrosion under anodic oxidative environment greatly restrict the lifespan of most catalysts with excellent primitive activity for oxygen production. Here, based on Fick&#8217; s Law, we present a surface cladding strategy to mitigate Ni dissolution and stabilize lattice oxygen triggering by directional flow of interfacial electrons and strong electronic interactions via constructing elaborately cladding&#8208;type NiO/NiS heterostructure with controlled surface thickness. Multiple in&#8208;situ characterization technologies indicated that this strategy can effectively prevent the irreversible Ni ions leaching and inhibit lattice oxygen from participating in anodic reaction. Combined with density functional theory calculations, we reveal that the stable interfacial O&#8208;Ni&#8208;S arrangement can facilitate the accumulation of electrons on surficial NiO side and weaken its Ni&#8208;O covalency. This would suppress the overoxidation of Ni and simultaneously fixing the lattice oxygen, thus enabling catalysts with boosted corrosion resistance without sacrificing its activity. Consequently, this cladding&#8208;type NiO/NiS heterostructure exhibits excellent performance with a low overpotential of 256 mV after 500 h. Based on Fick&#8217;s law, this work demonstrates the positive effect of surface modification through precisely adjusting of the oxygen&#8208;sulfur exchange process, which has paved an innovative and effective way to solve the instability problem of anodic oxidation.</description>
      <author>Li An, Shengjie Zi, Jiamin Zhu, Yue Zhai, Yang Hu, Nan Zhang, Hui Yao, Luohua Liu, Pinxian Xi, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413348</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co&#8211;Mn Bimetallic Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks Nanosheets for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202401049</link>
      <description>Yongchao Hao, Sheng Wang, Shuling Cheng, Huiya Cheng, Qianyun He, Lizhi Yi, Energy Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401911685

                Developing an efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst is the footstone of many electrochemical energy conversion devices. Herein, a cobalt&#8211;manganese bimetallic metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) is developed as an efficient OER catalyst (denoted as Co 3 Mn 1 BDC). The Co 3 Mn 1 BDC nanosheets demonstrate advantages in specific surface area, pore size distribution comparing with monometallic Co BDC and Mn BDC. The performance investigations demonstrate that the doping of Mn in Co&#8208;based MOFs facilitates the electrochemical area, charge transfer efficiency, reaction kinetics, and turnover frequency. As a consequence, the Co 3 Mn 1 BDC exhibits a low overpotential of 289 mV at current of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a favorable Tafel slope of 56.8 mV dec &#8722;1 on glassy carbon electrode, which is better than IrO 2 . When the catalyst is loaded on Ni foam, the overpotential and Tafel slope are further decreased to 231 mV and 50.8 mV dec &#8722;1 . Moreover, the Raman spectrum confirms that the Co 3 Mn 1 BDC can be transformed into active CoOOH, suggesting the bright prospect in electrocatalysis devices as &#8220;precatalyst&#8221;.</description>
      <author>Yongchao Hao, Sheng Wang, Shuling Cheng, Huiya Cheng, Qianyun He, Lizhi Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ente.202401049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity on Two-Dimensional vdW Ferromagnetic Cr2Ge2Te6 Through A Two-Active-Sites Synergism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01941e</link>
      <description>Zongxiang Kang, Wei Su, Qiuhong Li, Hu Jing-Guo, Jing Pan, Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401921914

                To design an efficient, low-cost, and easily recoverable oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts, we focus on two-dimensional vdW ferromagnetic Cr2Ge2Te6. Based on the density functional theory (DFT) calculation, the adsorption...</description>
      <author>Zongxiang Kang, Wei Su, Qiuhong Li, Hu Jing-Guo, Jing Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp01941e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bifunctional Iron-Nickel Oxygen Reduction / Oxygen Evolution Catalyst for High-Performance Rechargeable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-d4885</link>
      <description>Carsten Streb, Zheng-Fan Chen, Weiyi Cheng, Kecheng Cao, Jin Meng, Sarra Rahali, Elnaz Ebrahimi, Soressa Abera Chala, Nana Ma, Rongji Liu, Keseven Lakshmanan, Chun W Cheung, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Helen Luo, Yongkang Wang, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401928011

                Efficient and robust electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial for developing high-performance rechargeable zinc-air batteries (ZABs). Here, we report a highly stable, efficient bifunctional OER/ORR electrocatalyst and demonstrate its integration and robust performance in an aqueous ZAB. The catalyst is based on dual iron/nickel sites which are atomically dispersed on porous nitrogen-doped carbon particles and wrapped in electrically conductive multi-walled carbon nanotubes. Comprehensive experimental analyses and complementary density functional theory (DFT)-level computations provide in-depth understanding of the physical and electronic structure of the catalyst. Electrocatalytic analyses show high performance as OER and ORR catalyst (OER/ORR voltage difference = 0.71 V (at j = 10 mA cm-2). Catalyst integration in a ZAB results in excellent performance metrics: open circuit voltage 1.44 V, specific capacity (782 mAh g-1 at j = 15 mA cm&#8722;2, peak power density 218 mW cm&#8722;2 at j = 260 mA cm&#8722;2) and long-term durability over 600 charge/discharge cycles. This work highlights how high-performance bifunctional OER/ORR catalysts based on atomically dispersed non-critical metals can be designed and deployed in advanced energy storage systems.</description>
      <author>Carsten Streb, Zheng-Fan Chen, Weiyi Cheng, Kecheng Cao, Jin Meng, Sarra Rahali, Elnaz Ebrahimi, Soressa Abera Chala, Nana Ma, Rongji Liu, Keseven Lakshmanan, Chun W Cheung, Chia&#8208;Yu Chang, Helen Luo, Yongkang Wang, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-d4885</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomically Dispersed Vanadium&#8208;Induced Ru&#8210;V Dual Active Sites Enable Exceptional Performance for Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413657</link>
      <description>Qing Qin, Zijian Li, Xuhao Zhao, Hongyan Zhao, Li Zhai, Min Gyu Kim, Jaephil Cho, Haeseong Jang, Shangguo Liu, Xien Liu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401931638

                Regulating the catalytic reaction pathway to essentially break the activity/stability trade&#8208;off that limits RuO2 and thus achieves exceptional stability and activity for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is important yet challenging. Herein, we propose a novel strategy of incorporating atomically dispersed V species, including O&#8208;bridged V dimers and V single atoms, into RuO2 lattices to trigger direct O&#8208;O radical coupling to release O2 without the generation of *OOH intermediates. Vn&#8208;RuO2 showed high activity with a low overpotential of 227 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 and outstanding stability during a 1050 h test in acidic electrolyte. Operando spectroscopic studies and theoretical calculations revealed that compared with the V single atom&#8208;doping case, the introduction of the V dimer into RuO2 further decreases the Ru&#8210;V atomic distance and weakens the adsorption strength of the *O intermediate to the active V site, which supports the more energetically favorable oxygen radical coupling mechanism (OCM). Furthermore, the highly asymmetric Ru&#8208;O&#8208;V local structure stabilizes the surface Ru active center by lowering the valence state and increasing the resistance against overoxidation, which result in outstanding stability. This study provides insight into ways of increasing the intrinsic catalytic activity and stability of RuO2 by atomically dispersed species modification.</description>
      <author>Qing Qin, Zijian Li, Xuhao Zhao, Hongyan Zhao, Li Zhai, Min Gyu Kim, Jaephil Cho, Haeseong Jang, Shangguo Liu, Xien Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413657</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasonic-Induced Surface Disordering Promotes Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution of TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10977</link>
      <description>Chunyao Liu, Changhua Wang, Sheng Wang, Dashuai Li, Dexin Jin, Bunsho Ohtani, Baoshun Liu, He Ma, Jinglun Du, Yichun Liu, Xintong Zhang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401933572

                Surface disordering has been considered an effective strategy for tailoring the charge separation and surface chemistry of semiconductor photocatalysts. A simple but reliable method to create surface disordering is, therefore, urgently needed for the development of high-performance semiconductor photocatalysts and their practical applications. Herein, we report that the ultrasonic processing, which is commonly employed in the dispersion of photocatalysts, can induce the surface disordering of TiO2 and significantly promote its performance for photocatalytic hydrogen evolution. A 40 min ultrasonic treatment of TiO2 (Degussa P25) enhances the photocatalytic hydrogen production by 42.7 times, achieving a hydrogen evolution rate of 1425.4 &#956;mol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 without any cocatalyst. Comprehensive structural, spectral, and electrochemical analyses reveal that the ultrasonic treatment induces the surface disordering of TiO2, and consequently reduces the density of deep electron traps, extends the separation of photogenerated charges, and facilitates the hydrogen evolution reaction relative to oxygen reduction. The ultrasonic treatment manifests a more pronounced effect on disordering the surface of anatase than rutile, agreeing well with the enhanced photocatalysis of anatase rather than rutile. This study demonstrates that ultrasonic-induced surface disordering could be an effective strategy for the activation of photocatalysts and might hold significant implications for the applications in photocatalytic hydrogen evolution, small molecule activation, and biomass conversion.</description>
      <author>Chunyao Liu, Changhua Wang, Sheng Wang, Dashuai Li, Dexin Jin, Bunsho Ohtani, Baoshun Liu, He Ma, Jinglun Du, Yichun Liu, Xintong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c10977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935618

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935662

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935697

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935698

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Ultrathin iridium carbonyl formate for efficient and durable acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysis"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401935802

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04064c/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937743

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937824

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/response1</link>
      <description>Rodney D. L. Smith, Elif P&#305;nar Alsa&#231;, Marlyn Boke, Justine R Bissonnette, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937842

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rodney D. L. Smith, Elif P&#305;nar Alsa&#231;, Marlyn Boke, Justine R Bissonnette</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937912

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401937913

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938081

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v3/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938123

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938303

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v4/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938401

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v4/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v4/response1</link>
      <description>Rodney D. L. Smith, Elif P&#305;nar Alsa&#231;, Marlyn Boke, Justine R Bissonnette, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938482

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rodney D. L. Smith, Elif P&#305;nar Alsa&#231;, Marlyn Boke, Justine R Bissonnette</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v4/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Interplay Between Element-Specific Distortions and Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution for Cobalt-Iron Hydroxides"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401938503

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc01841a/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scale-Up, Continuous and Low-Temperature Production of Multimetal Based Electrocatalysts toward Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08677</link>
      <description>Pak Kin Wong, Jun Zhang, Jia&#8208;qi Bai, Yong Jiang, Jingshuai Chen, Mingyuan Wu, Song Sun, Jingshuai Chen, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401942075

                Electrocatalytic water splitting is a crucial strategy for advancing hydrogen energy and addressing the global energy crisis. Despite its significance, the need for a straightforward and swift method to synthesize electrocatalysts with exceptional performance remains pressing. In this study, we demonstrate a novel approach for the preparation of multimetal-based electrocatalysts in a continuous flow reactor, enabling the quick synthesis of a large number of products through a streamlined process. The resultant NiFe-LDH comprises nanoflakes with a high specific surface area and requires only 255.4 mV overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 in 1 M KOH, surpassing samples fabricated by conventional hydrothermal methods. Our method can also be applied to craft a spectrum of other multimetal-based electrocatalysts, including CoFe-LDH, CoAl-LDH, NiMn-LDH, and NiCoFe-LDH. Additionally, the NiFe-LDH electrocatalyst is further applied to anodic methanol electrooxidation coupled with cathodic hydrogen evolution. Moreover, the simplicity and generality of our fabrication method render it applicable for the facile preparation of various multimetal-based electrocatalysts, offering a scalable solution to the quest for high-performance catalysts in advancing sustainable energy technologies.</description>
      <author>Pak Kin Wong, Jun Zhang, Jia&#8208;qi Bai, Yong Jiang, Jingshuai Chen, Mingyuan Wu, Song Sun, Jingshuai Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing new electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction via high throughput experiments and artificial intelligence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01386-4</link>
      <description>S. L. XU, Zhuyang Chen, Mingyang Qin, Bijun Cai, Weixuan Li, Ronggui Zhu, Chen Xu, X.&#8208;D. Xiang, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401944607

                The development of non-noble metal electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) is advancing towards the use of multi-element materials. To reveal the complex correlations of multi-element OER electrocatalysts, we developed an iterative workflow combining high-throughput experiments and AI-generated content (AIGC) processes. An increased number of 909 (compared to 145 in previous literature) universal descriptors for inorganic materials science were constructed and used as Artificial Neural Network (ANN) input. A large number of statistical ensembles with each ANN individual ensemble having a reduced number of descriptors were integrated with a new Hierarchical Neural Network (HNN) algorithm. This algorithm addresses the longstanding challenge of balancing overwhelming descriptor numbers with insufficient datasets in traditional ANN approaches to materials science problems. As a result, the combination of AIGC and experimental validation significantly enhanced prediction accuracy, increase the R2 values from 0.7 to 0.98 for Tafel slopes.</description>
      <author>S. L. XU, Zhuyang Chen, Mingyang Qin, Bijun Cai, Weixuan Li, Ronggui Zhu, Chen Xu, X.&#8208;D. Xiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01386-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multiphase interface coupling of Ni-based sulfide composites for high-current-density oxygen evolution electrocatalysis in alkaline freshwater/simulated seawater/seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01673d</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Zhifeng Zhao, Zhanhua Su, Wei-Li Qu, Ruibin Guo, Xiaofeng Li, Yongchen Shang, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401947665

                NNSN/NF-11h is prepared by a solvothermal method, which offers promising OER activity in alkaline freshwater/simulated seawater/seawater at high current densities.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Zhifeng Zhao, Zhanhua Su, Wei-Li Qu, Ruibin Guo, Xiaofeng Li, Yongchen Shang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt01673d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the potential application of Cr2AlC MAX phase as an emerging electrocatalyst for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00815-w</link>
      <description>R Madhushree, K.R. Sunaja Devi, Emergent Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401958081

                No abstract</description>
      <author>R Madhushree, K.R. Sunaja Devi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42247-024-00815-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanocarbon-based Bifunctional Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00297</link>
      <description>Shouvik Mete, Kushagra Goel, Santosh K. Singh, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401959818

                For the sustainable development of green and clean electrochemical energy technologies, the advancement of high-performance electrode materials is essential. Precious metal catalysts such as those based on Pt, Ir, and Ru show high catalytic performance, but their scarcity and high cost restrict their application in energy technologies. Hence nanocarbon-based bifunctional electrocatalysts have emerged as a promising class of materials that hold the key to addressing critical challenges in energy conversion and storage technologies. Nanocarbon materials, such as carbon nanotubes, graphene, and their derivatives, have shown remarkable electrical conductivity, high surface area, and exceptional chemical stability, making them ideal candidates for electrocatalysis. However, these nanocarbon materials as such are electroneutral and catalytically inactive. Heteroatom doping and functionalization change the electronic properties of the nanocarbons and permit multifunctional electrocatalytic activity. These modified nanocarbons can catalyze the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in electrochemical systems, making them applicable in fuel cells, water electrolyzers, metal&#8211;air batteries, etc. This dual functionality of the materials in energy devices enhances the overall efficiency of energy conversion devices. Applications of nanocarbon-based bifunctional electrocatalysts extend beyond energy storage and conversion, encompassing electrochemical sensors, environmental remediation, etc. The multifunctional nature of nanocarbon materials, coupled with their versatility, holds great promise for developing efficient, durable, and cost-effective electrochemical devices. This chapter provides an insight into the promising field of nanocarbon-based bifunctional electrocatalysts and underscores their significance in shaping a sustainable energy future.</description>
      <author>Shouvik Mete, Kushagra Goel, Santosh K. Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Metal&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00185</link>
      <description>Ganesh D. Jadhav, Arti A. Jadhav, Sumita S. Patil, S.S. Shinde, Nayantara K. Wagh, Sharad B. Patil, C.D. Lokhande, Umakant M. Patil, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401959858

                Metal&#8211;air batteries (MABs) have been gaining attention as a promising solution for next-generation electrochemical energy storage devices since they have a higher theoretical energy density than metal ion batteries, making them ideal for applications such as electric vehicles and grid energy storage. These attributes are essential for achieving the ultimate objective of phasing out the world&#8217;s reliance on fossil fuels in the long term. However, efficient bifunctional oxygen evolution/reduction reaction (OER/ORR) catalysts are crucial for the further development of MABs. This chapter summarizes the exploration of materials such as metal oxides and conductive polymers that have been identified as promising candidates exhibiting strong catalytic activity and stability in MABs. These materials demonstrate adaptability to diverse environments, whether aqueous or non-aqueous electrolytes, employing various methods for energy storage. These advances are a crucial step towards realizing the potential of MABs, meeting the increasing demand for reliable, high-energy density batteries in emerging technologies. The study of bifunctional electrocatalysts for MABs has provided valuable insights into their performance across different electrolytes and battery types, including Zn, Li, Mg, Na, and Al systems. Bifunctional electrocatalysts play a pivotal role by significantly enhancing both ORR and OER, essential for processes governing the efficiency of MABs. The applicability of bifunctional electrocatalysts underscores their potential to drive advances in various MAB technologies, facilitating the development of more efficient, durable, and versatile energy storage solutions. Ongoing research on and enhancement of these catalysts could lead to more efficient and sustainable energy storage solutions, ushering in a new era in MAB technology.</description>
      <author>Ganesh D. Jadhav, Arti A. Jadhav, Sumita S. Patil, S.S. Shinde, Nayantara K. Wagh, Sharad B. Patil, C.D. Lokhande, Umakant M. Patil</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00185</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Unitized Regenerative Fuel Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00119</link>
      <description>Tapan K. Gupta, Biswajit Mondal, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401960118

                During the transition from conventional energy sources to sustainable alternatives, the role of energy storage and conversion is pivotal. Unitized regenerative fuel cells (URFCs) have attracted significant attention as promising energy storage and conversion devices owing to their ability to operate in both fuel cell (FC) and electrolyser (EL) modes within a compact single cell. They possess several advantages, including high power density, high specific energy density, light-weight design, low-cost production, high efficiency, long lifespan, and near-zero environmental impact. The development of efficient and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts is essential for the practical implementation and outstanding performance of URFCs. In URFCs, oxygen holds greater significance than hydrogen because its electrochemical reactions at the interface between the electrolyte and the electrode tend to be slow and intricate, primarily due to the pronounced irreversibility of oxygen-related processes. This chapter begins with a brief introduction to various types of FCs, setting the context for the subsequent discussion on URFCs. It provides an overview of bifunctional electrocatalysts in URFCs, highlighting their role in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). It also discusses bifunctional oxygen catalysts (BOCs) reported in the literature, along with a brief discussion of bifunctional hydrogen catalysts (BHCs). The chapter systematically summarizes the recent advances, challenges, and prospects related to bifunctional catalysts, which are critical for the performance of URFCs.</description>
      <author>Tapan K. Gupta, Biswajit Mondal</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;Organic Framework-derived Bifunctional Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00226</link>
      <description>Debal Kanti Singha, Tapan Ping, Bibhuranjan Nayak, Rupali Ipsita Mohanty, Bikash Kumar Jena, Royal Society of Chemistry eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401960715

                This chapter provides an introduction to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and discusses the fundamental aspects and their significance in different applications. Measurements of different electrochemical parameters needed for the measurement of the OER and ORR performance of a catalyst are considered. A novel class of advanced porous hybrid materials has emerged: metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) with variable pore sizes and large surface areas characterized by various periodic patterns. Because of their immense porosity and mechanical and thermal durability, they are used in a wide variety of applications. However, the low electrical conductivity and poor stability of MOFs make their use in electrocatalysis difficult. The benefits of using MOF-derived materials as bifunctional electrocatalysts for OER and ORR are discussed.</description>
      <author>Debal Kanti Singha, Tapan Ping, Bibhuranjan Nayak, Rupali Ipsita Mohanty, Bikash Kumar Jena</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/9781837674497-00226</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating gas escape efficiency by parallel alignment of nanosheets arrays for high-current oxygen evolution and urea oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235302</link>
      <description>Chengjie Wu, Tao You, Kuan Deng, Xuesong Liu, Qiang Niu, Tao Yang, Wen Tian, Junyi Ji, Journal of Power Sources. 621(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401968946

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chengjie Wu, Tao You, Kuan Deng, Xuesong Liu, Qiang Niu, Tao Yang, Wen Tian, Junyi Ji</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.235302</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Aggregation of M&#8722;N&#8722;C Single&#8208;Atom Electrocatalysts into Highly Efficient MOOH Nanoclusters during Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413308</link>
      <description>Shanshan Lu, Zhipu Zhang, Chuanqi Cheng, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401970934

                M&#8722;N&#8722;C&#8208;type single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) are highly efficient for the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). And the isolated metal atoms are usually considered real active sites. However, the oxidative structural evolution of coordinated N during the OER will probably damage the structure of M&#8722;N&#8722;C, hence resulting in a completely different reaction mechanism. Here, we reveal the aggregation of M&#8722;N&#8722;C materials during the alkaline OER. Taking Ni&#8722;N&#8722;C as an example, multiple characterizations show that the coordinated N on the surface of Ni&#8208;N&#8208;C is almost completely dissolved in the form of NO3&#8722;, accompanied by the generation of abundant O functional groups on the surface of the carbon support. Accordingly, the Ni&#8722;N bonds are broken. Through a dissolution&#8208;redeposition mechanism and further oxidation, the isolated Ni atoms are finally converted to NiOOH nanoclusters supported by carbon as the real active sites for the enhanced OER. Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C and Co&#8722;N&#8722;C also have similar aggregation mechanism. Our findings provide unique insight into the structural evolution and activity origin of M&#8722;N&#8722;C&#8208;based catalysts under electrooxidative conditions.</description>
      <author>Shanshan Lu, Zhipu Zhang, Chuanqi Cheng, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Aggregation of M&#8722;N&#8722;C Single&#8208;Atom Electrocatalysts into Highly Efficient MOOH Nanoclusters during Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413308</link>
      <description>Shanshan Lu, Zhipu Zhang, Chuanqi Cheng, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401971036

                M&#8722;N&#8722;C&#8208;type single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) are highly efficient for the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). And the isolated metal atoms are usually considered real active sites. However, the oxidative structural evolution of coordinated N during the OER will probably damage the structure of M&#8722;N&#8722;C, hence resulting in a completely different reaction mechanism. Here, we reveal the aggregation of M&#8722;N&#8722;C materials during the alkaline OER. Taking Ni&#8722;N&#8722;C as an example, multiple characterizations show that the coordinated N on the surface of Ni&#8208;N&#8208;C is almost completely dissolved in the form of NO3&#8722;, accompanied by the generation of abundant O functional groups on the surface of the carbon support. Accordingly, the Ni&#8722;N bonds are broken. Through a dissolution&#8208;redeposition mechanism and further oxidation, the isolated Ni atoms are finally converted to NiOOH nanoclusters supported by carbon as the real active sites for the enhanced OER. Fe&#8722;N&#8722;C and Co&#8722;N&#8722;C also have similar aggregation mechanism. Our findings provide unique insight into the structural evolution and activity origin of M&#8722;N&#8722;C&#8208;based catalysts under electrooxidative conditions.</description>
      <author>Shanshan Lu, Zhipu Zhang, Chuanqi Cheng, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution: Dual-Functional Electrocatalyst of Zinc Iron Layered Double Hydroxides and Nickel Cobalt Sulfides on Nickel Foam for Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01290</link>
      <description>Mahalakshmi Vedanarayanan, Chih&#8208;Ming Chen, Mathur Gopalakrishnan Sethuraman, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401976583

                Hydrogen, derived from water splitting, holds promise as a sustainable energy carrier. However, replacing fossil fuels demands large volumes of pure water, a resource that is scarce in numerous regions globally. This study focuses on developing an efficient electrocatalyst for seawater splitting, aiming to conserve freshwater resources and overcome the challenges associated with direct utilization of seawater. Zinc iron layered double hydroxides combined with nickel cobalt sulfides on nickel foam (ZnFe LDH@NiCoS/NF) are produced to operate efficiently in alkaline seawater splitting, which involves the evolution reactions of hydrogen and oxygen. Through the utilization of an alkalinized electrolyte and suitable nickel foam substrates, the adverse effects of corrosion and chlorine oxidation reactions are effectively mitigated. The composite ZnFe LDH@NiCoS/NF exhibits exceptional electrocatalytic efficacy in alkaline seawater, needing remarkably minimal overpotentials of 246.3 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 284.8 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to attain the targeted current density. Additionally, the composite electrocatalyst exhibits decreased Tafel values of 74.6 mV dec&#8211;1 for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 81.5 mV dec&#8211;1 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), suggesting enhanced kinetics. This improved electrocatalytic performance is attributed to the increased surface area and decreased charge transfer resistance. Additionally, the catalytic electrode exhibits impressive long-term stability, maintaining efficiency for approximately 50 h at a constant current density for both the HER and the OER. This study emphasizes the innovative character of ZnFe LDH@NiCoS/NF as a crucial breakthrough in research on bifunctional electrocatalysts for the HER and the OER, presenting a hopeful direction for harnessing renewable energy from seawater.</description>
      <author>Mahalakshmi Vedanarayanan, Chih&#8208;Ming Chen, Mathur Gopalakrishnan Sethuraman</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01290</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Internal Electric Field Engineering Induced by Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;/Bi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;MoO&lt;sub&gt;6&lt;/sub&gt; Nanotubes for Trifunctional Electrocatalytic and Photocatalytic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03204</link>
      <description>Xinpei Zhao, Yukui Zhang, Zhihui Shang, Qifang Lu, Xiujun Han, Xue-Yang Ji, Huayang Zhang, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401989955

                Electrocatalytic water splitting is an intriguing technique for clean energy production, and engineering heterojunctions with an internal electric field (IEF) can significantly enhance the electrocatalytic performance. In this paper, Co3O4/Bi2MoO6 heterojunction nanotubes have been prepared via electrospinning and calcination and show stronger activity and stability than single-phase Co3O4 and Bi2MoO6 due to the so-called "1 + 1 &gt; 2" synergistic effect induced by IEF. In particular, 1.00Co3O4/Bi2MoO6 nanotube catalyst performed the overpotential toward hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with 197 mV and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with 332 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2. Based on the enhancement of IEF verified by density functional theory calculation, the extended photocatalytic degradation of tetracycline (TC) showed an efficiency of 68.5% within 200 min under visible light irradiation. This work provides a facile "one stone, three birds' strategy to construct nanotube heterojunctions and develops the IEF mechanism from photocatalytic to electrocatalytic application.</description>
      <author>Xinpei Zhao, Yukui Zhang, Zhihui Shang, Qifang Lu, Xiujun Han, Xue-Yang Ji, Huayang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c03204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of Highly Active Ln&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;IrO&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402333</link>
      <description>Jane Edgington, R. Vicente, Sejal Vispute, Ruihan Li, Matthew E. Sweers, Simone R. Sullivan, Pablo S. Fern&#225;ndez, Linsey C. Seitz, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402013247

                Abstract An improved understanding of catalyst dynamics for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acid is critical for informing the development of highly efficient, stable, and cost&#8208;effective OER catalysts for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis applications. Herein highly tunable, active, and dynamic Ir 5+ materials are studied, Ln 3 IrO 7 (Ln = Pr, Nd, Sm, and Eu). Leveraging a combination of in situ and ex situ characterization, as well as an advanced mercury underpotential deposition technique for Ir surface site quantification, the dynamic nature of Ln 3 IrO 7 materials throughout electrochemical activation under OER conditions is characterized. The trends are elucidated between intrinsic OER activity, surface Ir site quantity, and metal site dissolution behavior as tuned by the Ln site's atomic number. A critical relationship is uncovered to show that maintenance of excellent OER activity throughout performance testing is correlated with a catalysts&#8217; ability to preserve a high degree of Ir enrichment, where heightened stability of Ir sites interestingly parallels reduced stability of Ln sites throughout testing. It is found that as the Ln site's atomic number is decreased, the materials&#8217; intrinsic OER performance improves, due to an increased thermodynamic driving force for Ln dissolution, which is hypothesized to enable the maintenance of highly active Ir&#8208;based surface motifs.</description>
      <author>Jane Edgington, R. Vicente, Sejal Vispute, Ruihan Li, Matthew E. Sweers, Simone R. Sullivan, Pablo S. Fern&#225;ndez, Linsey C. Seitz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the electrochemical oxygen evolution performance of CuS by using P element as an anionic dopant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176166</link>
      <description>Xue&#8217;er Ming, Ning Liu, Qi Wang, Lefu Mei, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402036176

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue&#8217;er Ming, Ning Liu, Qi Wang, Lefu Mei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Structure Derived Phosphide Nanosheets for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406105</link>
      <description>Ying Dong, Jixiang Jiao, Yadong Wang, Jun Yu, Shichun Mu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402047325

                Abstract Avoiding the stacking of active sites in catalyst structural design is a promising route for realizing active oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, using a CoFe Prussian blue analoge cube with hollow structure (C&#8208;CoFe PBA) as a derived support, a highly effective Ni 2 P&#8208;FeP 4 &#8208;Co 2 P catalyst with a larger specific surface area is reported. Benefiting from the abundant active sites and fast charge transfer capability of the phosphide nanosheets, the Ni 2 P&#8208;FeP 4 &#8208;Co 2 P catalyst in 1 m KOH requires only overpotentials of 248 and 277 mV to reach current density of 10 and 50 mA cm &#8722;2 and outperforms the commercial catalyst RuO 2 and most reported non&#8208;noble metal OER catalysts. In addition, the two&#8208;electrode system consisting of Ni 2 P&#8208;FeP 4 &#8208;Co 2 P and Pt/C is able to achieve a current density of 10 and 50 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.529 and 1.65 V. This work provides more ideas and directions for synthesizing transition metal catalysts for efficient OER performance.</description>
      <author>Ying Dong, Jixiang Jiao, Yadong Wang, Jun Yu, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406105</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance of Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;Electrodes by Tailored Conditioning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400318</link>
      <description>Clara Gohlke, Julia Gallenberger, Nico Niederpr&#252;m, Hannah Ingendae, J&#252;rgen KAUTZ, Jan P. Hofmann, Anna K. Mechler, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402055136

                Abstract To meet the rising demand for green hydrogen, efficient alkaline water electrolysis demands highly active and low&#8208;cost electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We address this issue by focusing our work on optimizing the conditioning of promising Ni&#8208;(Fe)&#8208;based electrodes to improve their electrocatalytic performances. Systematic parameter variation for cyclic voltammetry conditioning revealed that a large potential window, low scan rate, and a high number of cycles result in improved activation. If the conditioning time is fixed, a high scan rate was found beneficial. A remarkable 47&#177;6 mV potential drop at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 was achieved for Ni 70 Fe 30 when conditioning between &#8722;0.35&#8211;1.6 V at 100 mV s &#8722;1 for just 30 min. We could demonstrate that this activation persisted over 100 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , underscoring its enduring efficacy. We suggest that this activation effect results from the growth of a hydrous hydroxide layer, which is supported by energy dispersive X&#8208;ray spectroscopy and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy. Fe incorporation or dissolution played only a minor role in the differences in electrode activation, as demonstrated by variation of the Fe content in the electrolyte. Our work stresses the importance of conditioning in enhancing OER performance and explores how to improve the catalysts&#8242; effectiveness by tailoring oxides.</description>
      <author>Clara Gohlke, Julia Gallenberger, Nico Niederpr&#252;m, Hannah Ingendae, J&#252;rgen KAUTZ, Jan P. Hofmann, Anna K. Mechler</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photo&#8208;induced Intercalation of Cobalt(II) Tellurium Oxide as an Oxygen Evolution (Photo)electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400047</link>
      <description>R. J. Kriek, Oluwaseun A. Oyetade, Nyengerai Zingwe, Emanuela Carleschi, B. P. Doyle, Jaco Koch, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402055885

                Abstract Herein, we report on (a) the application of cobalt(II) tellurium oxide (Co 3 TeO 6 ) as a photo&#8208;electrocatalyst, to enhance the photo&#8208;electrocatalytic (PEC) oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, compared to the electrocatalytic (EC) OER (in the absence of light), and (b) to store charge upon illumination and release charge upon the termination of illumination under OER potential bias conditions. These nanomaterials were synthesized employing the sol&#8208;gel method and calcined at temperatures ranging from 400 to 1100 &#176;C. They were physically characterized and tested for their capacity to (i) act as a catalyst towards the OER, under EC and PEC conditions, and (ii) to convert and store light&#8208;energy as chemical&#8208;energy. Under PEC conditions CTO&#8208;900, which predominantly consisted of Co 3 TeO 6 , exhibited a five&#8208;fold increase in activity compared to EC conditions as current density increased from 0.58 mA cm &#8722;2 (EC) to 3.10 mA cm &#8722;2 (PEC) at 1.8 V ( vs . RHE). Additionally, CTO&#8208;900 displayed the ability to not only store charge (upon illumination), but to also release this stored charge (after the termination of illumination), realising a current density of 2.07 mA cm &#8722;2 in the dark (under OER potential bias conditions). Photo&#8208;induced charge storage is due to the intercalation of potassium ions into Co 3 TeO 6 .</description>
      <author>R. J. Kriek, Oluwaseun A. Oyetade, Nyengerai Zingwe, Emanuela Carleschi, B. P. Doyle, Jaco Koch</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400047</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Record-breaking bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst accomplished by a data-driven approach for zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.040</link>
      <description>Deviprasath Chinnadurai, Zhi Wei Seh, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402071756

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Deviprasath Chinnadurai, Zhi Wei Seh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.08.040</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MnS doping regulating Co active sites on fibrous cobalt nitride as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst for high-performance Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176153</link>
      <description>Xinmeng Yu, Xiaorong Chen, Dandan Yue, Fenghua Zheng, Qingyu Li, Zhaoling Ma, Hongqiang Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402072787

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinmeng Yu, Xiaorong Chen, Dandan Yue, Fenghua Zheng, Qingyu Li, Zhaoling Ma, Hongqiang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chromium Promotes Phase Transformation to Active Oxyhydroxide for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03974</link>
      <description>Yong Wang, Sijia Liu, Yunpu Qin, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Jianfang Liu, Yadong Liu, Aimin Chu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079069

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for renewable energy technologies like metal&#8211;air batteries and water splitting. However, it suffers from sluggish kinetics, necessitating a high-activity and stable catalyst. In this study, we used Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations to demonstrate that Cr doping favors the phase transition of metal (Fe, Co, Ni) hydroxide to the active phase oxyhydroxide. We synthesized FeCoNiCr hydroxide using an aqueous sol&#8211;gel method, ensuring that the four elements Fe, Co, Ni, and Cr are uniformly distributed at the atomic level. As an OER catalyst, FeCoNiCr hydroxide exhibits a very low overpotential of 224 mV in alkaline media, which is 52 mV lower than that of FeCoNi hydroxide, placing it among the best nonprecious metal catalysts reported so far. Additionally, it demonstrates long-term catalytic stability of 150 h. An assembled Zn-Air battery with FeCoNiCr hydroxides was cycled stably for 160 h with a low discharge/charge voltage difference of 0.70 V. DFT calculations and microkinetic modeling demonstrated that Cr doping significantly optimized the adsorption energies of OER intermediates at the Ni and Co sites, thereby enhancing overall OER activity. Bader charge calculations further revealed that Ni and Co in the catalysts consistently maintained a +3 valence throughout the OER process, which is beneficial for OER catalysis.</description>
      <author>Yong Wang, Sijia Liu, Yunpu Qin, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Di Zhang, Jianfang Liu, Yadong Liu, Aimin Chu, Haoyang Wu, Baorui Jia, Xuanhui Qu, Hao Li, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the evolution of interfacial species via B, N-codoped Pt sites for oxygen reduction electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155311</link>
      <description>Baojie Li, Wanlin Zhou, Xuan Sun, Qian Zhang, Qian Zhang, Jianglong Guo, Jingjing Jiang, Qizheng An, Shuowen Bo, Jing Wang, Qinghua Liu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402080095

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Baojie Li, Wanlin Zhou, Xuan Sun, Qian Zhang, Qian Zhang, Jianglong Guo, Jingjing Jiang, Qizheng An, Shuowen Bo, Jing Wang, Qinghua Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.155311</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Molybdenum triggers the bifunctional mechanism of oxygen evolution reaction of Fe34-xNi25Co25MoxB8P8amorphous alloy with boosted catalytic activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118612</link>
      <description>Yong Wu, Xiaolong Guo, Chen Hong-guo, Yuci Xin, Xing&#8217;an Dong, Xiaolin Hu, L. Xia, Peng Yu, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402082543

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yong Wu, Xiaolong Guo, Chen Hong-guo, Yuci Xin, Xing&#8217;an Dong, Xiaolin Hu, L. Xia, Peng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118612</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Engineering Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C Catalysts for Oxygen Electrocatalysis in Zn&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401186</link>
      <description>Le Li, Meisheng Han, Penggang Zhang, Donglei Yang, Meng Zhang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402096056

                Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have emerged as one of the most promising candidates for oxygen electrocatalysis due to their maximized atom utilization efficiency, high intrinsic activity, and strong metal&#8208;support interaction. Significant progress has been made in engineering Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C SACs for oxygen electrocatalysis in Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). This review provides a comprehensive overview of the recent advancements in Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C SACs, with a special focus on effective engineering strategies, their performance in oxygen electrocatalysis, and their potential applications in ZABs. The review also discusses the key challenges and future directions in the development of Fe&#8208;N&#8208;C SACs for efficient and durable oxygen electrocatalysis in ZABs. This review aims to offer valuable insights into the current state of research in this field and to guide future efforts in the development of advanced oxygen electrocatalysts for ZABs.</description>
      <author>Le Li, Meisheng Han, Penggang Zhang, Donglei Yang, Meng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401186</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unusual photosynthetic oxygen evolution. I. Cerulenin-induced 3-(3,4-dichlorophenyl)-1,1-dimethylurea insensitive oxygen evolution in Chlorella pyrenoidosa</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00633-0</link>
      <description>E. Lehoczki, Yu. Zeinalov, No host. 7(3)] 1984. https://openalex.org/W4402036701

                No abstract</description>
      <author>E. Lehoczki, Yu. Zeinalov</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 1984 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00633-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopic and functional characterization of a highly oxygen evolving Photosystem II reaction center complex from spinach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00383-0</link>
      <description>Lars&#8208;Gunnar Franz&#233;n, Stenbj&#246;rn Styring, Anne&#8208;Lise Etienne, &#214;rjan Hansson, Claudie Vemotte, No host. 13(1-2)] 1986. https://openalex.org/W4402037545

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lars&#8208;Gunnar Franz&#233;n, Stenbj&#246;rn Styring, Anne&#8208;Lise Etienne, &#214;rjan Hansson, Claudie Vemotte</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 1986 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00383-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fractionation of an oxygen-evolving Photosystem II preparation: characterization of the light-harvesting antennae and reaction center components</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00629-9</link>
      <description>Eric Lam, Barbara G. Baltimore, William Ortiz, Richard Malkin, No host. 7(2)] 1984. https://openalex.org/W4402037878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Eric Lam, Barbara G. Baltimore, William Ortiz, Richard Malkin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 1984 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00629-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Zeolite Imidazolide with Cobalt Porphyrin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12677/japc.2024.133049</link>
      <description>&#33150;&#22372; &#24352;, Journal of Advances in Physical Chemistry. 13(03)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401962699

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#33150;&#22372; &#24352;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12677/japc.2024.133049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of the Precursor Metal Salt on the Oxygen Evolution Reaction for NiFe Oxide Materials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400151</link>
      <description>A. Zuber, Ilias M. Oikonomou, Lee Gannon, I. I. Chunin, L.A. Reith, Berrin Zeliha Can, Mailis Lounasvuori, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Cormac McGuinness, Prashanth W. Menezes, Valeria Nicolosi, Michelle P. Browne, ChemElectroChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402055549

                Abstract Bimetallic nickel&#8208;iron based oxides are regarded as one of the most promising catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, we show that the precursor metal salts can affect the OER activity of the resulting Ni/Fe oxide under the same hydrothermal synthesis conditions. Pure sulfate, pure nitrate and mixed sulfate/nitrate metal salts were used to fabricate NiFe based oxide materials and to study the importance of the precursor choice for the OER. The results show that the nature of the precursor used in the synthesis of the bimetallic nickel&#8208;iron materials can influence different multi&#8208;phase catalysts to form which effects the OER.</description>
      <author>A. Zuber, Ilias M. Oikonomou, Lee Gannon, I. I. Chunin, L.A. Reith, Berrin Zeliha Can, Mailis Lounasvuori, Thorsten Schultz, Norbert Koch, Cormac McGuinness, Prashanth W. Menezes, Valeria Nicolosi, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/celc.202400151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Individual Marcus-type kinetics controls singlet and triplet oxygen evolution from superoxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3vrzz</link>
      <description>Soumyadip Mondal, Hung Duc Nguyen, Robert Hauschild, Stefan A. Freunberger, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401955824

                Oxygen evolution from superoxide is a critical aspect of oxygen redox chemistry. However, the factors determining the formation of often harmful singlet oxygen are unclear. Here, we report that the release of triplet or singlet oxygen is governed by individual Marcus normal and inverted region behavior. Using a wide range of chemical oxidants, we found that as the driving force increases, the initially dominant evolution of triplet oxygen slows down, and singlet oxygen evolution becomes predominant with higher maximum kinetics. This behavior also applies to superoxide disproportionation, the oxidation of one superoxide by another, in both non-aqueous and aqueous systems, where Lewis and Br&#248;nsted acidity control driving forces. Our findings suggest ways to understand and control spin states and kinetics in oxygen redox chemistry.</description>
      <author>Soumyadip Mondal, Hung Duc Nguyen, Robert Hauschild, Stefan A. Freunberger</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3vrzz</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of CoFe2O4 decorated on polyaniline for optimizing oxygen evolution process in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41779-024-01082-y</link>
      <description>Zeid A. ALOthman, Suryyia Manzoor, Jafar Hussain Shah, S. Noor Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem, Journal of the Australian Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402054979

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeid A. ALOthman, Suryyia Manzoor, Jafar Hussain Shah, S. Noor Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Shahroz Saleem</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41779-024-01082-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Engineering of Non&#8208;van der Waals 2D Magnetene for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution and Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401157</link>
      <description>Pedro Guerra Demingos, Zhiwen Chen, Xiang Ni, Chandra Veer Singh, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402035785

                Non&#8208;van der Waals two&#8208;dimensional materials containing exposed transition metal atoms are promising catalysts for green energy storage and conversion. For instance, hematene and ilmenene have been successfully applied as catalysts. Building on these reports, this work is the first investigation of recently synthesized magnetene towards the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) and Oxygen Reduction Reaction (ORR). Using Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations, we unveil the mechanism, performance and ideal conditions for OER and ORR on magnetene. With overpotentials of &#951;OER = 0.50 V and &#951;ORR = 0.41 V, the material is not only a bifunctional catalyst, but also superior to state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art systems such as Pt and IrO2. Additionally, its catalytic properties can be further enhanced through engineering strategies such as point defects and in&#8208;plane compression. It reaches &#951;ORR = 0.28 V at a compressive strain of only 2%, while the presence of Ni boosts it to &#951;OER = 0.39 V and &#951;ORR = 0.31 V, comparable to many reported single&#8208;atom catalysts. Overall, this work demonstrates that magnetene is a promising bifunctional catalyst for applications such as regenerative fuel cells and metal&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Pedro Guerra Demingos, Zhiwen Chen, Xiang Ni, Chandra Veer Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401157</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cholate Extraction of a Heme-Protein from Spinach Thylakoids and its Possible Involvement in PS-II Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00190-9</link>
      <description>H.Y. Nakatani, James Barber, No host. 2(1-2)] 1981. https://openalex.org/W4402020885

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H.Y. Nakatani, James Barber</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 1981 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s0165-8646(24)00190-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood-Derived Continuously Oriented Channels Coupled with Tunable Built-in Electric Fields for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124550</link>
      <description>Luosong Zheng, Heping Luo, Yuxin Zhong, Wanqian Li, Han Xu, Fuquan Xiong, Jiahao Pi, Yan Qing, Yiqiang Wu, Applied Catalysis B Environment and Energy. 360(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4401945891

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luosong Zheng, Heping Luo, Yuxin Zhong, Wanqian Li, Han Xu, Fuquan Xiong, Jiahao Pi, Yan Qing, Yiqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcatb.2024.124550</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot synthesis of supported PtCox bifunctional catalysts for oxygen reduction and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.472</link>
      <description>Xin Zeng, Sushanta K. Mitra, Xianguo Li, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 86(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402081208

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xin Zeng, Sushanta K. Mitra, Xianguo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.08.472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Efficient Trifunctional Spinel&#8208;Based Electrode for Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reactions and Nonoxidative Ethane Dehydrogenation on Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408044</link>
      <description>Yangsen Xu, Hua Zhang, Kang Xu, Xirui Zhang, Feng Zhu, Wanqing Deng, Fan He, Ying Liu, Yu Chen, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401953624

                Protonic ceramic electrochemical cells (PCECs) have received considerable attention as they can directly generate electricity and/or produce chemicals. Development of the electrodes with the trifunctionalities of oxygen reduction/evolution and nonoxidative ethane dehydrogenation is yet challenging. Here these findings are reported in the design of trifunctional electrodes for PCECs with a detailed composition of Mn</description>
      <author>Yangsen Xu, Hua Zhang, Kang Xu, Xirui Zhang, Feng Zhu, Wanqing Deng, Fan He, Ying Liu, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-Coordinated Cobalt Single Atom Steered by Doped-O and Coo for Efficient Hydrogen Evolution at Industrial Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4942439</link>
      <description>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Renyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Xue Z. Wang, P.X. Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402090352

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Renyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Xue Z. Wang, P.X. Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4942439</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ferroelectric Polarization-Induced Performance Enhancements in BiFeO3-Based Photoanodes for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-lh925</link>
      <description>Michael Gunawan, Owen Bowdler, Yingtang Zhou, Xueqing Fang, Qi Zhang, Yasuhiro Sakamoto, Kaiwen Sun, Denny Gunawan, Shery L. Y. Chang, Rose Amal, V. Nagarajan, Jason Scott, Judy N. Hart, Cui Ying Toe, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402014748

                Photoelectrochemical (PEC) processes will play a crucial role in future clean energy systems, however severe charge recombination and sluggish charge transfer kinetics have hindered their practical adoption. Exploiting ferroelectric polarization-controlled charge dynamics promises an additional lever that can potentially enable the performance limits of traditional static photoelectrodes to be surpassed. Here we report one of the most notable ferroelectric polarization-induced photocurrent enhancements, using a heterostructure of the multiferroic bismuth ferrite (BFO) and the photoactive bismuth vanadate (BVO) in a neutral pH electrolyte. In contrast to previous works, we report enhancements for both poling directions, of 136% for down-poled BFO/BVO and of 70% for the up-poled BFO/BVO, at 1.23 VRHE in comparison to the unpoled, delivering a Faradaic efficiency of more than 95% for prolonged oxygen evolution reaction. Extensive PEC and surface analyses complemented by DFT calculations reveal the improvements are attributed to the modulation of gradients in BFO band energies, changes in band-bending and offsets at the interfaces. Given the scalability of the employed sol-gel synthesis method and the use of environmentally benign materials and PEC conditions, our findings pave the way for multifunctional materials as new-generation agile and dynamic catalyst and photoelectrode systems.</description>
      <author>Michael Gunawan, Owen Bowdler, Yingtang Zhou, Xueqing Fang, Qi Zhang, Yasuhiro Sakamoto, Kaiwen Sun, Denny Gunawan, Shery L. Y. Chang, Rose Amal, V. Nagarajan, Jason Scott, Judy N. Hart, Cui Ying Toe</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-lh925</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correction to &#8220;Regenerating Spent Lithium-Ion Battery Cathodes as Dual-Functional Biocatalysts for Highly-Efficient Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Using &lt;i&gt;Aspergillus niger&lt;/i&gt; Soluble Extracellular Polymers&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06724</link>
      <description>Ge Lin, Yiyang Kang, Guang Li, Jiajie Wu, Yuxi Chen, Chang Liu, Xinwei Wen, Jialiang Li, Lei Li, Qing Qu, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401942114

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef. ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; EngineeringASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse ORIGINAL ARTICLE This notice is a correctionAddition/CorrectionAugust 28, 2024Correction to "Regenerating Spent Lithium-Ion Battery Cathodes as Dual-Functional Biocatalysts for Highly-Efficient Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Using Aspergillus niger Soluble Extracellular Polymers"Click to copy article linkArticle link copied!Lin GeLin GeMore by Lin GeYiyang KangYiyang KangMore by Yiyang KangGuang LiGuang LiMore by Guang LiJiajie WuJiajie WuMore by Jiajie WuYuxi ChenYuxi ChenMore by Yuxi ChenChang LiuChang LiuMore by Chang LiuXinwei WenXinwei WenMore by Xinwei WenJialiang LiJialiang LiMore by Jialiang LiLei Li*Lei LiMore by Lei LiQing Qu*Qing QuMore by Qing Quhttps://orcid.org/0000-0001-7475-7063Open PDFACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; EngineeringCite this: ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06724https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06724Published August 28, 2024 Publication History Received 14 August 2024Published online 28 August 2024correction&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietyIn the original article, panels a&#8211;c of Figure 3 are incorrect. Due to an error in operating the fluorescence microscopy system, the scaling of the images has been compromised. This resulted in an inadequate representation of the changes in fungal mycelial growth in the original article. While this issue does not impact the visibility or the final results of our study, the authors have undertaken the initiative to recapture fluorescence images of Aspergillus niger at growth periods of 7, 14, and 21 days to enhance accuracy. This effort aims to present our findings more clearly and reliably, ensuring that all results are thoroughly represented. The corrected panels a&#8211;c of Figure 3 are presented here. Importantly, the overall growth trends remain unchanged. We would like to emphasize that these corrections do not alter the conclusions drawn in the original article. The authors sincerely apologize to the editor, reviewers, and readers for any confusion or inconvenience caused by these unintentional errors. We appreciate your understanding as we rectify this matter.Figure 3Figure 3. FM images of A. niger cultured for (a) 7 days, (b) 14 days, and (c) 21 days.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideAuthor InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorsLei Li; Email: Qing Qu; https://orcid.org/0000-0001-7475-7063; Email: AuthorsLin GeYiyang KangGuang LiJiajie WuYuxi ChenChang LiuXinwei WenJialiang LiCited By Click to copy section linkSection link copied!This article has not yet been cited by other publications.Download PDFFiguresReferencesOpen PDF Get e-AlertsGet e-AlertsACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; EngineeringCite this: ACS Sustainable Chem. Eng. 2024, XXXX, XXX, XXX-XXXClick to copy citationCitation copied!https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06724Published August 28, 2024 Publication History Received 14 August 2024Published online 28 August 2024&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsArticle Views-Altmetric-Citations-Learn about these metrics closeArticle Views are the COUNTER-compliant sum of full text article downloads since November 2008 (both PDF and HTML) across all institutions and individuals. These metrics are regularly updated to reflect usage leading up to the last few days.Citations are the number of other articles citing this article, calculated by Crossref and updated daily. Find more information about Crossref citation counts.The Altmetric Attention Score is a quantitative measure of the attention that a research article has received online. Clicking on the donut icon will load a page at altmetric.com with additional details about the score and the social media presence for the given article. Find more information on the Altmetric Attention Score and how the score is calculated.Recommended Articles FiguresReferencesFigure 3Figure 3. FM images of A. niger cultured for (a) 7 days, (b) 14 days, and (c) 21 days.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideThis publication has no References.</description>
      <author>Ge Lin, Yiyang Kang, Guang Li, Jiajie Wu, Yuxi Chen, Chang Liu, Xinwei Wen, Jialiang Li, Lei Li, Qing Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06724</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparations of Fluorine-doped &#945;-Ni hydroxides as Alkaline Water Electrolysis Catalysts via Liquid Phase Deposition Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00983e</link>
      <description>Tomoyuki Watanabe, Kanji Tsuchimoto, Tomohiro Fukushima, Kei Murakoshi, Minoru Mizuhata, Hiro Minamimoto, Sustainable Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401926234

                The room-temperature liquid phase process was used to prepare &#945;-Ni(OH)2 thin films with high crystallinity for use as oxygen evolution reaction catalysts under strong alkaline conditions. It was found that...</description>
      <author>Tomoyuki Watanabe, Kanji Tsuchimoto, Tomohiro Fukushima, Kei Murakoshi, Minoru Mizuhata, Hiro Minamimoto</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4se00983e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Ni2+ on OER Kinetics and Photoluminescence Properties of ZnSnO3 Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113042</link>
      <description>B. Vishwalinga Prasad, H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, C. Ningappa, B. Daruka Prasad, R. Sahana, K.N. Sridhar, K. Manjunath, Sheng Yun Wu, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402105989

                Ni2+ doped ZnSnO3 nanoparticles (NPs) were synthesized using Aloe vera mediated solution combustion method, followed by an investigation into their luminescence and oxygen evolution reaction properties. The Bragg reflections of ZnSnO3: Ni(1-9 mol%) NPs revealed a cubic structure, with the addition of the dopant inducing lattice strain and resulting in peak shifting towards higher angles. No impurity-related peaks were observed. The estimated crystallite size and optical band gap decrease (3.1 to 2.94 eV) with an increase in dopant concentration. The surface morphology consists of irregular-sized and shaped NPs with hallows. The EDAX spectra show the purity of the sample. Photoluminescence emission spectra were recorded at a 230 nm excitation wavelength, where intense blue emission observed at 482 nm was attributed to a direct transition between the conduction band edge and the valence band edge, corresponding to the direct recombination of free excitons. Another satellite peak observed at 525 nm can be attributed to oxygen deficiency. Moreover, the nanoparticles exhibited outstanding performance in oxygen evolution reaction studies, showing low over potentials between 300 and 318 mV, a minimal Tafel slope of range 63-72 mV dec-1, and stable electrochemical behavior over 12 hours at a current density of 23 mA/cm2. These results highlight their effectiveness as electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>B. Vishwalinga Prasad, H.C. Manjunatha, Y.S. Vidya, S. Manjunatha, R. Munirathnam, M. Shivanna, C. Ningappa, B. Daruka Prasad, R. Sahana, K.N. Sridhar, K. Manjunath, Sheng Yun Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.113042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Research Progress on the Electrocatalytic Degradation of Organic Pollutants by PbO2-Based Electrode"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26717/bjstr.2024.58.009143</link>
      <description>Wenlong Liu, Biomedical Journal of Scientific &amp; Technical Research. 58(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402051867

                As an inactive electrode, PbO2-based electrode can produce abundant hydroxyl radicals which are beneficial to the degradation of organic pollutants. In recent years, as a widely used material in electrochemical oxidation technology, more and more PbO2-based electrodes have attracted much attention due to their high oxygen evolution potential, high catalytic activity and good stability. Presently, most of the articles are devoted to the modification of the electrode. To better understand electrochemical degradation of pollutants from waste water, this review summarizes the research progress of wastewater treatment in recent years.</description>
      <author>Wenlong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26717/bjstr.2024.58.009143</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctional Coordination Materials for Green Energy Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003345886-12</link>
      <description>Saira Ajmal, Mohammad Tabish, Safana Haqani, Tuan Anh Nguyen, Ghulam Yasin, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401975689

                The growing need for clean and renewable energy sources, driven by a shortage of fossil fuels and serious environmental concerns, has made finding catalysts for energy conversion applications a significant challenge. The key reactions essential for converting and producing green energy include the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO2RR), and nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR). Recently, the novel and rapid expansion of coordination materials, such as covalent organic frameworks (COFs), porous coordination polymers (PCPs), and metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have led to the creation of remarkable properties, allowing the development of heterostructures for various applications in different fields. Enhancing clean energy production efficiency is considered the essential promise of coordination materials, with their controlled structures, effective functionalizations, large surface areas, and high porosity. In this chapter, we summarize the brief overview of multifunctional coordination materials and their applications for green energy production.</description>
      <author>Saira Ajmal, Mohammad Tabish, Safana Haqani, Tuan Anh Nguyen, Ghulam Yasin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003345886-12</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Computational Investigation on Cr-Doped Sc&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; MXene under Strain for Electronic Properties, Quantum Capacitance, and Photocatalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02282</link>
      <description>Ruiwen Yan, Xiao&#8208;Hong Li, Rui-Zhou Zhang, Hong&#8208;Ling Cui, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402031714

                Sc2CO2 MXene has potential applications in energy storage and optoelectronics due to its superior structure and excellent properties. The electronic properties, quantum capacitance, and photocatalytic activity of Cr-doped Sc2CO2 under strain are studied by the density functional theory. Cr doping makes the system produce magnetism. The spin-down states of Sc2CO2&#8211;Cr under strain are direct semiconductors, while their spin-up states are indirect semiconductors. Sc2CO2&#8211;Cr under +5, &#8722;5, &#8722;3, and &#8722;2% strains in an aqueous system are suitable for cathode material. A large voltage drastically modulates the type of electrode materials. Sc2CO2&#8211;Cr under strains from 0 to +2% can perform the oxygen evolution reaction at an alkaline environment, while the Sc2CO2&#8211;Cr system under strain is a good for CO2 photocatalysis at pH 0 and 7.</description>
      <author>Ruiwen Yan, Xiao&#8208;Hong Li, Rui-Zhou Zhang, Hong&#8208;Ling Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02282</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stabilizing Pure Water-Fed Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers through Membrane&#8211;Electrode Interface Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05327</link>
      <description>Sinwoo Kang, Yeongin Kim, Vincent Wilke, Sooan Bae, Jagoda Justyna Chmielarz, Daniel Garc&#237;a S&#225;nchez, Kahyun Ham, Aldo Saul Gago, K. Andreas Friedrich, Jaeyoung Lee, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401917495

                Nickel&#8211;iron (oxy)hydroxide (NiFeOxHy) stands as a cutting-edge nonprecious electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the intrinsic thermodynamic instability of nickel and iron as anode materials in pure water-fed electrolyzers poses a significant durability challenge. In this study, an anion exchange ionomer coating was applied to NiFeOxHy to modify the local pH between a membrane and an electrode. This effectively extended the diffusion length of hydroxide anions toward the electrode, establishing an alkaline local pH environment. Stability tests with the ionomer coating showed reduced Ni dissolution. Moreover, locally resolved current density measurements were used to demonstrate a notably lower degradation rate during stability testing, revealing a 6-fold increase in stability with the ionomer on NiFeOxHy. In situ Raman spectroscopy in a neutral pH electrolyte confirmed inhibited Ni oxidation with the ionomer, mitigating Ni dissolution and enhancing stability of state-of-the-art NiFeOxHy catalysts in pure water-fed water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Sinwoo Kang, Yeongin Kim, Vincent Wilke, Sooan Bae, Jagoda Justyna Chmielarz, Daniel Garc&#237;a S&#225;nchez, Kahyun Ham, Aldo Saul Gago, K. Andreas Friedrich, Jaeyoung Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c05327</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Growth of trimetallic CeFeNi-MOF-74 on nickel foam as a bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4815956/v1</link>
      <description>Jun Zhang, Tao Long, Yangwen Liu, Zhiyong Zhong, Yang Zhang, X. H. Chen, Guanghuan Li, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401887147

                Abstract In order to facilitate the industrial synthesis of hydrogen from electrolytic water on a wide scale, high-performance non-precious metal electrocatalysts that can substitute precious metal electrocatalysts must be developed. This paper reports a trimetallic CeFeNi-MOF-74 electrocatalyst grown on nickel foam (NF) by solvothermal method. The introduction of trimetallics gives the metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) materials synergistic and complementary properties, resulting in better catalytic properties of the materials. Tuning the electronic structure of materials to optimize electrocatalytic performance by modulating metal ratios. It was found that the prepared Ce0.9FeNi-MOF-74 exhibited excellent electrocatalytic activity and stability in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In 1 M KOH, the overpotential is only 262 mV for HER at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722; 2 and 257 mV for OER at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722; 2. For overall water splitting (OWS), a low voltage of only 1.68 V is required to achieve a 10 mA cm&#8722; 2 current density. The excellent catalytic performance of Ce0.9FeNi-MOF-74 exceeds that of many commercial catalysts. This study provides new insights into the synthesis of high-performance and stable MOF electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Jun Zhang, Tao Long, Yangwen Liu, Zhiyong Zhong, Yang Zhang, X. H. Chen, Guanghuan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4815956/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Electrocatalyst&#8211;Driven Hybrid Water Splitting for Energy&#8208;Saving Coproduction of Green H &lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and Valuable Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394234110.ch10</link>
      <description>Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Bao Yu Xia, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402030913

                Electrocatalytic water splitting to generate green H 2 with renewable energy inputs is attractive to relieve the environmental contamination and energy dilemma. Restricted by the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and single functionality of cathode/anode catalysts, conventional overall water splitting (OWS) suffers from high overpotentials and respective synthesis of monofunctional electrocatalysts, leading to high cost. Moreover, the generated O 2 bears low value and its possible mixing with H 2 poses safety issues. In response, hybrid water splitting (HWS) that integrates hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) with favorable oxidative upgrading reactions over bifunctional electrocatalysts can generate H 2 and value-added chemicals simultaneously with lower energy input and avoid the explosive H 2 /O 2 mixtures. Hence, this chapter focuses on the recent progress in bifunctional electrocatalyst&#8211;driven HWS for energy-saving coproduction of highly valuable chemicals and green H 2 . Firstly, the fundamentals of HER, OER, OWS, and HWS are introduced, followed by a discussion on the electrochemical reconstruction of bifunctional electrocatalysts during OWS and HWS. Next, the HWS based on bifunctional electrocatalysts is summarized, wherein the alternative oxidation reactions include upgrading of alcohol, aldehydes, amines, biomass, and plastic waste. Finally, a brief overview of current challenges and perspective for bifunctional electrocatalyst&#8211;driven HWS is discussed.</description>
      <author>Hui Jiang, Guoliang Mei, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9781394234110.ch10</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spiral&#8208;concave Prussian Blue Crystals with Rich Steps: Growth Mechanism and Coordination Regulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414650</link>
      <description>Guangxun Zhang, Jia Li, Guangyu Du, Jing Wang, Wang Qiujing, Kejian J. Wu, Songtao Zhang, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Yizhou Zhang, Huaiguo Xue, Mohsen Shakouri, Zheng Liu, Huan Pang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402011550

                Investigating the formation and transformation mechanisms of spiral&#8208;concave crystals holds significant potential for advancing innovative material design and comprehension. We examined the kinetics&#8208;controlled nucleation and growth mechanisms of Prussian Blue crystals with spiral concave structures, and constructed a detailed crystal growth phase diagram. The spiral&#8208;concave hexacyanoferrate (SC&#8208;HCF) crystals, characterized by high&#8208;density surface steps and a low stress&#8208;strain architecture, exhibit enhanced activity due to their facile interaction with reactants. Notably, the coordination environment of SC&#8208;HCF can be precisely modulated by the introduction of diverse metals. Utilizing X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy and in&#8208;situ ultraviolet&#8208;visible spectroscopy, we elucidated the formation mechanism of SC&#8208;HCF to Co&#8208;HCF facilitated by oriented adsorption&#8208;ion exchange (OA&#8208;IE) process. Both experimental data, and density functional theory confirm that Co&#8208;HCF possesses an optimized energy band structure, capable of adjusting the local electronic environment and enhancing the performance of the oxygen evolution reaction. This work not only elucidates the formation mechanism and coordination regulation for rich steps HCF, but also offers a novel perspective for constructing nanocrystals with intricate spiral&#8208;concave structures.</description>
      <author>Guangxun Zhang, Jia Li, Guangyu Du, Jing Wang, Wang Qiujing, Kejian J. Wu, Songtao Zhang, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Yizhou Zhang, Huaiguo Xue, Mohsen Shakouri, Zheng Liu, Huan Pang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202414650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Synergism of Brominated Phthalocyanine and Carbon Nanoparticle-Based Nanocomposite for Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01987</link>
      <description>Naseem Kousar, Elena A. Gorbunova, Tatiana V. Dubinina, Lokesh Koodlur Sannegowda, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401907274

                The efficiency of rechargeable metal-air batteries can be significantly improved by utilizing bifunctional oxygen catalysts that are capable of facilitating both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). Continuous research efforts are crucial to develop highly efficient and cost-effective bifunctional catalysts for oxygen electrode reactions in various energy conversion and storage applications. This study introduces an innovative approach by harnessing the interfacial synergism of brominated phthalocyanine and carbon nanoparticles. Herein, a cost-effective metal&#8211;organic macrocycle featuring octa-bromo-substituted cobalt phthalocyanine, CoOBrPc, is synthesized and comprehensively characterized for its properties and evaluated performance in bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis. To boost its synergistic performance, an organic-hybrid composite is prepared by strategically incorporating Ketjen black (KB) nanoparticles. The optimized CoOBrPc + KB (4:1 respectively) organic hybrid exhibited outstanding bifunctional oxygen catalytic activity, bearing a minimal potential difference (&#916;E) of 518 mV at Eonset and 811 mV at Ej10 and E1/2, on a glassy carbon-rotating disc electrode in a 1.0 M KOH electrolyte at a 5 mV s&#8211;1 scan rate and a rotation speed of 1600 rpm. Additionally, the hybrid catalyst exhibited the same overpotential as the standard catalyst (IrO2) toward OER on a Ni foam substrate at j60. Furthermore, the designed hybrid catalyst exhibited a Tafel slope of 64.02 and 63.88 mV dec&#8211;1, j0 of 8.24 &#215; 10&#8211;6 and 1.33 &#215; 10&#8211;5 A cm&#8211;2, lower charge transfer resistance, and higher electrochemical active surface area for the OER and ORR, respectively. These promising results are attributed to a combination of factors, including enhanced mass transport at the interface, tailored electronic structure, and tuned surface morphology. Moreover, the composite's chemical stability and resistance to degradation ensure sustained catalytic activity in demanding operational conditions, positioning it as a compelling choice for energy conversion and storage applications such as electrolyzers and fuel cells, catalyzing both OER and ORR.</description>
      <author>Naseem Kousar, Elena A. Gorbunova, Tatiana V. Dubinina, Lokesh Koodlur Sannegowda</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01987</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing photoelectrochemical performance and stability of Ti-doped hematite photoanode via pentanuclear Co-based MOF modification</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1454524</link>
      <description>Guofa Dong, Fengyan Xie, Fangxia Kou, Tingting Chen, Caihong Xiao, Shaowu Du, Jiaqi Liang, Chenfang Lou, Jiandong Zhuang, Frontiers in Chemistry. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402070648

                Modifying photoanodes with metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) as oxygen evolution reaction (OER) cocatalysts has emerged as a promising approach to enhance the efficiency of photoelectrochemical (PEC) water oxidation. However, designing OER-active MOFs with both high photo- and electrochemical stability remains a challenge, limiting the advancement of this research. Herein, we present a facile method to fabricate a MOF-modified photoanode by directly loading a pentanuclear Co-based MOF (Co-MOF) onto the surface of a Ti-doped hematite photoanode (Ti:Fe 2 O 3 ). The resulting Co-MOF/Ti:Fe 2 O 3 modified photoanode exhibits an enhanced photocurrent density of 1.80 mA&#8729;cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V, surpassing those of the Ti:Fe 2 O 3 (1.53 mA&#8729;cm &#8722;2 ) and bare Fe 2 O 3 (0.59 mA&#8729;cm &#8722;2 ) counterparts. Additionally, significant enhancements in charge injection and separation efficiencies, applied bias photon-to-current efficiency (ABPE), incident photon to current conversion efficiency (IPCE), and donor density (N d ) were observed. Notably, a minimal photocurrent decay of only 5% over 10 h demonstrates the extraordinary stability of the Co-MOF/Ti:Fe 2 O 3 photoanode. This work highlights the efficacy of polynuclear Co-based MOFs as OER cocatalysts in designing efficient and stable photoanodes for PEC water splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Guofa Dong, Fengyan Xie, Fangxia Kou, Tingting Chen, Caihong Xiao, Shaowu Du, Jiaqi Liang, Chenfang Lou, Jiandong Zhuang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fchem.2024.1454524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Anticorrosion Engineering by Polyphosphate Oxyanions for Durable Seawater Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402883</link>
      <description>Xunlu Wang, Huashuai Hu, Jizhong Song, Junqing Ma, Hanxiao Du, Jiacheng Jayden Wang, Min Wang, Wei Chen, Yin Zhou, Jiacheng Wang, Minghui Yang, Lingxia Zhang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402006344

                Abstract Electrolysis of seawater represents great potentials for sustainable hydrogen production. However, both competitive Cl &#8722; adsorption and catalysts corrosion caused by chlorine oxidation reaction (ClOR) are major challenges in seawater electrolysis. Inspired by the concept of hard and soft acids and bases (HSAB), polyphosphate oxyanions (P 3 O 10 5&#8722; ) on Ni(OH) 2 surface is coordinated to obtain harder acid Ni sites, which could obtain 160 times stability enhancement compared to pure Ni(OH) 2 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline seawater at 800 mA cm &#8722;2 . Also, the turnover frequency value on Ni(OH) 2 &#8208;P 3 O 10 5&#8722; is 50 times that on Ni(OH) 2 , implying higher intrinsic OER activity of Ni(OH) 2 &#8208;P 3 O 10 5&#8722; . Theoretical and experimental investigations show that P 3 O 10 5&#8722; could facilitate transition of Ni 3+ to harder acid Ni &gt;3+ , thus preferring adsorption of hard base OH &#8722; rather than soft base Cl &#8722; . This could enhance OER selectivity and inhibit undesirable ClOR. Furthermore, molecular dynamics simulations indicate that the Cl &#8722; concentration near the electrode could be reduced by nearly half due to electrostatic repulsion of Cl &#8722; by surface P 3 O 10 5&#8722; oxyanions. When assembled into an electrolyzer for alkaline seawater splitting, it could operate at 2.2 V with large current up to 1.4 A for 240 h.</description>
      <author>Xunlu Wang, Huashuai Hu, Jizhong Song, Junqing Ma, Hanxiao Du, Jiacheng Jayden Wang, Min Wang, Wei Chen, Yin Zhou, Jiacheng Wang, Minghui Yang, Lingxia Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402883</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Bi3+ Doping on Electrochemical Properties of Ti/Sb-SnO2/PbO2 Electrode for Zinc Electrowinning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29174062</link>
      <description>Jia Wu, Xuanqi Kang, Shuang Xu, Zhen Wei, Shangyuan Xu, Kang Liu, Qing Feng, Bo Jia, Yun&#8208;Hai Wang, Molecules. 29(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401909119

                Bi3+ doped Ti/Sb-SnO2/PbO2 electrode materials were fabricated by electrodeposition to improve their electrochemical performance in zinc electrowinning. The surface morphology, chemical composition, and hydrophilicity of the as-prepared electrodes were characterized using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS), X-ray diffraction (XRD), X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), and contact angle. An electrochemical measurement and an accelerated lifetime experiment were also conducted to investigate the electrocatalytic performance and stability of the electrodes. The results show that the Bi3+ modification electrode has an important effect on the coating morphology, the crystal structure, the surface hydrophilicity, the electrocatalytic activity, and the stability. The electrode prepared from the solution containing 2 mmol&#183;L&#8722;1 Bi(NO3)3 (marked as the Ti/Sb-SnO2/2Bi-PbO2 electrode) exhibits the best hydrophilicity performance (&#952; = 21.6&#176;) and the longest service life (1196 h). During the electrochemical characterization analysis, the Ti/Sb-SnO2/2Bi-PbO2 electrode showed the highest oxygen evolution activity, which can be attributed to it having the highest electroactive surface (qT* = 21.20 C&#183;cm&#8722;2) and the best charge-transfer efficiency. The DFT calculation demonstrated that the doping of Bi3+ leads to a decrease in the OER reaction barrier and an increase in the DOS of the electrode, which further enhances the catalytic activity and the conductivity of the electrode. Moreover, the simulated zinc electrowinning experiment demonstrated that the Ti/Sb-SnO2/2Bi-PbO2 electrode consumes less energy than other electrodes. Therefore, it is expected that the Bi3+ modified electrode will become a very promising electrode material for zinc electrowinning in the future.</description>
      <author>Jia Wu, Xuanqi Kang, Shuang Xu, Zhen Wei, Shangyuan Xu, Kang Liu, Qing Feng, Bo Jia, Yun&#8208;Hai Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29174062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History and Social Implications of the Pulse Oximeter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.68250</link>
      <description>Dean K Zacharis, Dongye Zhao, Latha Ganti, Cureus. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402097669

                The pulse oximeter is a portable, bedside tool that allows for the measurement of oxygen saturation in a patient's red blood cells. The technology is based on oxygenated and deoxygenated hemoglobin absorbing light at different wavelengths. The device calculates the ratio of oxygenated to deoxygenated hemoglobin in the blood, and an algorithm produces a percentage oxygen saturation value. Due to its portability and ease of use, it is a ubiquitous medical tool that is commonly used in medical practice. This paper reviews the history and evolution of this tool, and the scientific laws behind oximetry. It also introduces the importance of the pulse oximeter and its basic functions. In addition, the limitations of pulse oximetry are discussed, especially as they pertain to pigmented skin.</description>
      <author>Dean K Zacharis, Dongye Zhao, Latha Ganti</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7759/cureus.68250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Verification of Key Physical Models in Oxide Fuel Performance Analysis Code FEATURE Based on COMSOL</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/00295639.2024.2384225</link>
      <description>Rui Yu, Guan Wang, Wei Jiang, Yanlei Zhu, Changping Qin, Long Gu, Nuclear Science and Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402077524

                Nuclear performance analysis is of great significance for fuel design optimization and the safe operation of a reactor. Considering the design requirements of the China initiative Accelerator Driven System (CiADS) project, it is necessary to develop relevant fuel performance analysis tools to predict fuel performance evolution during service. The Fuel Element Analysis Tool for Undercritical Reactor Engineering (FEATURE) code, based on the advanced multiphysics coupling platform COMSOL software, is under development in this context, with a current focus on oxide fuel for fast reactors. This paper mainly conducts preliminary comparative verification of the oxygen redistribution, plutonium redistribution, and fission gas release modules of the FEATURE code through model examples, code-to-code evaluation, and experimental data. The results indicate that the FEATURE code exhibits good accuracy and reliability in simulating oxygen and plutonium redistribution, as well as fission gas release, making it suitable for integrated coupling calculations.</description>
      <author>Rui Yu, Guan Wang, Wei Jiang, Yanlei Zhu, Changping Qin, Long Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/00295639.2024.2384225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Minimal transcriptional regulation of horizontally transferred photosynthesis genes in phototrophic bacterium &lt;i&gt;Gemmatimonas phototrophica&lt;/i&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1128/msystems.00706-24</link>
      <description>Karel Kopejtka, J&#252;rgen Tomasch, Sahana Shivaramu, Mohit Saini, David Kaftan, Michal Kobl&#237;&#382;ek, mSystems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401912429

                ABSTRACT The first phototrophic member of the bacterial phylum Gemmatimonadota , Gemmatimonas phototrophica AP64 T , received all its photosynthesis genes via distant horizontal gene transfer from a purple bacterium. Here, we investigated how these acquired genes, which are tightly controlled by oxygen and light in the ancestor, are integrated into the regulatory system of its new host. G. phototrophica grew well under aerobic and semiaerobic conditions, with almost no difference in gene expression. Under aerobic conditions, the growth of G. phototrophica was optimal at 80 &#181;mol photon m &#8722;2 s &#8722;1 , while higher light intensities had an inhibitory effect. The transcriptome showed only a minimal response to the dark&#8211;light shift at optimal light intensity, while the exposure to a higher light intensity (200 &#181;mol photon m &#8722;2 s &#8722;1 ) induced already stronger but still transient changes in gene expression. Interestingly, a singlet oxygen defense was not activated under any conditions tested. Our results indicate that G. phototrophica possesses neither the oxygen-dependent repression of photosynthesis genes known from purple bacteria nor the light-dependent repression described in aerobic anoxygenic phototrophs. Instead, G. phototrophica has evolved as a low-light species preferring reduced oxygen concentrations. Under these conditions, the bacterium can safely employ its photoheterotrophic metabolism without the need for complex regulatory mechanisms. IMPORTANCE Horizontal gene transfer is one of the main mechanisms by which bacteria acquire new genes. However, it represents only the first step as the transferred genes have also to be functionally and regulatory integrated into the recipient&#8217;s cellular machinery. Gemmatimonas phototrophica , a member of bacterial phylum Gemmatimonadota, acquired its photosynthesis genes via distant horizontal gene transfer from a purple bacterium. Thus, it represents a unique natural experiment, in which the entire package of photosynthesis genes was transplanted into a distant host. We show that G. phototrophica lacks the regulation of photosynthesis gene expressions in response to oxygen concentration and light intensity that are common in purple bacteria. This restricts its growth to low-light habitats with reduced oxygen. Understanding the regulation of horizontally transferred genes is important not only for microbial evolution but also for synthetic biology and the engineering of novel organisms, as these rely on the successful integration of foreign genes.</description>
      <author>Karel Kopejtka, J&#252;rgen Tomasch, Sahana Shivaramu, Mohit Saini, David Kaftan, Michal Kobl&#237;&#382;ek</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1128/msystems.00706-24</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystalline Oxygen-Modified Carbon Nitride Photocatalyst with Enhanced Internal Electric Field and Strong Resistance to Ionic Interference for Robust Seawater Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03031</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, N. Cao, Xiaoming Liu, Fengting He, Yang&#8208;Ming Lu, Shuling Wang, Chaocheng Zhao, Yongqiang Wang, Jinqiang Zhang, Shaobin Wang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402079090

                Photocatalytic seawater splitting to produce clean hydrogen from nonpotable water using sunlight is a crucial endeavor. However, the scarcity of high-performance photocatalysts in the promising yet fledgling field presents a formidable challenge. Herein, we successfully synthesized a crystalline oxygen-modified carbon nitride (CCNO) polymeric semiconductor that served as an effective photocatalyst for seawater splitting. Comprehensive characterizations and theoretical calculations revealed that nitrogen vacancies and bridging oxygen in the CCNO lattice acted as potent Lewis acid&#8211;base pairs, creating an enhanced built-in electric field. This advancement significantly accelerated charge dynamics and bolstered resistance to ionic interference in seawater. Consequently, CCNO exhibited a robust photocatalytic H2 evolution activity of 29.51 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1 in natural seawater, with an impressive apparent quantum efficiency of 66.86% under 420 nm monochromatic light. Seawater splitting for H2 production reached 16.83 mmol g&#8211;1 under natural light irradiation for 3 h (9&#8211;12 o'clock), showcasing its great potential for practical applications. This work presents strategies for developing a metal-free photocatalyst and elucidates its reaction mechanism in the seawater splitting process, laying the foundation for scalable production of clean hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, N. Cao, Xiaoming Liu, Fengting He, Yang&#8208;Ming Lu, Shuling Wang, Chaocheng Zhao, Yongqiang Wang, Jinqiang Zhang, Shaobin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Lattice Strain&#8208;Induced Vacancy Evolution Facilitating Highly Reversible Dendrite&#8208;Free Zinc Metal Anodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402586</link>
      <description>Tian Wang, Liangliang Xu, Weiwei Xiang, Shaocong Tang, Ya Xiao, Jae Su Yu, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401969660

                Abstract Interfacial stress caused by semi&#8208;coherent and incoherent interfaces during zinc (Zn) plating and its effect on subsequent Zn deposition are important considerations for designing electrode/electrolyte interfaces to improve the electrochemical performance of Zn anodes. Although some studies have paid attention to this issue, the influence of lattice strain induced by Zn ion diffusion in the interface coating on Zn deposition is infrequently discussed. Herein, a tin&#8208;doped indium oxide (ITO) interfacial is constructed, and the evolution of interfacial lattice oxygen to vacancy oxygen (O V ) induced by lattice stress generated by Zn ion migration in the interface during Zn deposition is confirmed. The formed O V &#8208;rich ITO interface exhibits strong affinity and a low Zn ion diffusion barrier, accelerating the Zn ion transport kinetics. Meanwhile, the interface layer can appropriately capture anions in the electrolyte and improve the corrosion resistance of the electrode through the electrostatic repulsion effect. As a result, the O V &#8208;rich ITO&#8208;decorated Zn anode achieves stable Zn plating/stripping for more than 4500 h and delivers a high average Coulombic efficiency of 99.6% after 1400 cycles at 1.0 mA cm &#8722;2 . This work provides a new horizon for the rational construction of the interface layer to achieve a highly reversible dendrite&#8208;free Zn metal anode.</description>
      <author>Tian Wang, Liangliang Xu, Weiwei Xiang, Shaocong Tang, Ya Xiao, Jae Su Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402586</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversity and Ecological Functions of Anthocyanins</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.2272.v1</link>
      <description>Nele Gr&#252;nig, Jakob Maximilian Horz, Boas Pucker, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402116169

                Anthocyanins are well known as colorants of flowers, but many other invisible functions might have been more important during the evolution of complex biosynthesis networks in plants. The number of anthocyanin decorating enzymes, the subtle control of structural genes by numerous transcription factors, and routes of intracellular anthocyanin transport are reviewed here. Various ecological functions of anthocyanins hold the key to understanding evolutionary trajectories that lead to the success of these pigments. Proposed functions include carbon sinks that prevent excessive sugar levels, sun blockers protecting the photosynthesis apparatus, antioxidants scavenging reactive oxygen species, providing camouflage, and attraction of pollinators and seed dispersers. Anthocyanins clearly fulfill different functions in different plant organs. It is currently believed that protective functions in leaves gave rise to the biosynthesis network and that flower and fruit coloration evolved later.</description>
      <author>Nele Gr&#252;nig, Jakob Maximilian Horz, Boas Pucker</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20944/preprints202408.2272.v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;scp&gt;POM&lt;/scp&gt; &#8208;based Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527842711.ch8</link>
      <description>In&#234;s S. Marques, Renata Matos, Diana M. Fernandes, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402030867

                This chapter is related to the application of polyoxometalates (POMs), POM-based composites and POM-derived electrocatalysts in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This reaction is a crucial part of the water splitting and, therefore, fundamental for hydrogen electroproduction. Given that POMs are made of transition-metal (TM) oxygen anion clusters with a d 0 electronic structure, they are the most promising class of hydrogen evolution electrocatalysts. Herein is presented a brief description of the HER process, while the important role of POMs electrocatalysts towards HER is discussed in detail. This chapter is organized in five sections, namely HER (Section 8.1), POMs electrocatalysts (Section 8.2), composites/hybrids materials (Section 8.3), POM-derived electrocatalysts (Section 8.4) and concluding remarks (Section 8.5). In the first section, the HER mechanism, state-of-the-art electrocatalysts and important electrochemical parameters to be evaluated are described. In the second section, the advantages of POMs as HER electrocatalysts are discussed, along with several examples of POMs application in HER. The third section is related to the most common POM-based composites used in HER electrocatalysis, namely POM/carbon, POM/metal organic frameworks (MOF), POM/metal and POM/polymers. The fourth section encompasses several classes of HER electrocatalysts obtained using POMs as metal precursor, including single-atom catalysts (SACs) and TM carbides, chalcogens, nitrates, phosphates and oxides. Lastly, the fifth section consists of an overview of the discussed electrocatalysts and the main results, also including some proposed future perspectives for POM-based/derived electrocatalysts towards HER.</description>
      <author>In&#234;s S. Marques, Renata Matos, Diana M. Fernandes</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/9783527842711.ch8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seasonal Variations and Controls on Triple Oxygen and Hydrogen Isotopes in Precipitation&#8212;A Case Study From Monitoring in Southwest China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2023jd040654</link>
      <description>Qi-sheng Liang, Lijuan Sha, Jun&#8208;Yun Li, Jian Zhang, Xuejie Wang, Siyun Zhou, Fangyuan Lin, Yan&#8208;Xia Xue, Rong Duan, Yating He, Huiyang Li, Chenyi Wang, Bao Liu, Yong&#8208;Kang Hou, Chao&#8208;Jun Chen, Hai Cheng, Ting&#8208;Yong Li, Journal of Geophysical Research Atmospheres. 129(17)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401877885

                Abstract Precipitation &#948; 18 O has offered valuable insights into the evolution of the Asian monsoon. Recent researches focusing on precipitation &#916;&#8242; 17 O has enhanced our understanding by offering new perspectives beyond those of &#948; 18 O, revealing insights into vapor sources and continental recycling. Nevertheless, there remains a lack of interannual triple oxygen isotope data, particularly in the Asian monsoon region. In this study, we analyzed the triple oxygen isotopes and hydrogen isotopes in monthly precipitation samples collected from Chongqing in Southwest China between 2019 and 2022 A.D. Seasonal variations in &#948;D, &#948; 18 O, &#948; 17 O, and d&#8208;excess values were observed, with lower values during the rainy season and higher values during the dry season, highlighting the impact of changes in moisture sources and local meteorological conditions on seasonal shifts in &#948;D, &#948; 18 O, and &#948; 17 O. While, mean &#916;&#8242; 17 O values were higher in rainy season and lower in dry season. Notably, during rainy season, there is a negative correlation between monthly &#916;&#8242; 17 O values and the RH of the vapor source area, as well as a positive correlation with d&#8208;excess . Recalculated &#916;&#8242; 17 O values based on RH of oceanic moisture source, are higher than the measured values for this period, indicating the contribution of terrigenous moisture to precipitation in SW China. Precipitation &#916;&#8242; 17 O values provide a more precise reflection of changes in moisture source, continental recycling, and evapotranspiration processes that drive water cycling compared Integrating modeling works in future will facilitate the use of precipitation &#916;&#8242; 17 O values to quantify the impact of different moisture source on precipitation.</description>
      <author>Qi-sheng Liang, Lijuan Sha, Jun&#8208;Yun Li, Jian Zhang, Xuejie Wang, Siyun Zhou, Fangyuan Lin, Yan&#8208;Xia Xue, Rong Duan, Yating He, Huiyang Li, Chenyi Wang, Bao Liu, Yong&#8208;Kang Hou, Chao&#8208;Jun Chen, Hai Cheng, Ting&#8208;Yong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2023jd040654</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nebulized enriched heparin improves respiratory parameters in patients with COVID-19: a phase I/II randomized and triple-blind clinical trial</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-70064-8</link>
      <description>Vinicius Tadeu Ramos da Silva Grillo, Matheus Bertanha, Lenize da Silva Rodrigues, Marcelo Andrade de Lima, Pedro Luciano Mellucci Filho, Rafael Rahal Guaragna Machado, Edison Lu&#237;z Durigon, Nath&#225;lia Dias Sert&#243;rio, M&#225;rjorie de Assis Golim, Andrei Moroz, Aline M&#225;rcia Marques Braz, Leonardo Naz&#225;rio de Moraes, Marco Ant&#244;nio Leite, Helena B. Nader, Gustavo Constantino de Campos, Cristiane Rodrigues Guzzo, F&#225;bio Floren&#231;a Cardoso, &#194;ngelo J. Magro, Helga Caputo Nunes, Rejane Maria Tommasini Grotto, Rita de C&#225;ssia Alvarado, Maria In&#234;s de Moura Campos Pardini, Marcone Lima Sobreira, &#201;rika Alessandra Pellison Nunes da Costa, Alexandre Naime Barbosa, Carlos Magno Castelo Branco Fortaleza, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401900049

                To evaluate the safety and the potential antiviral treatment of inhaled enriched heparin in patients with COVID-19. The specific objectives were to investigate the anticoagulation profile, antiviral and anti-inflammatory effects, and respiratory evolution of inhaled enriched heparin. We conducted a randomized, triple-blind, placebo-controlled Phase I/II clinical trial in hospitalized adults with COVID-19 receiving inhalation of enriched heparin or saline (placebo) every 4 h for 7 days. Among the 27 patients who completed the study, no changes in blood coagulation parameters were observed, indicating the safety of inhaled enriched heparin. The group receiving enriched heparin showed a significant reduction in the need for supplemental oxygen and improvement in respiratory parameters, such as the PaO2/FiO2 ratio. Inhalation of enriched heparin is shown to be safe and has also demonstrated potential therapeutic benefits for patients with COVID-19. These promising results justify the continuation of the study to the next phase, Phase II/III, to further evaluate the therapeutic efficacy of inhaled enriched heparin in the treatment of COVID-19-associated viral pneumonia. Trial registration: ClinicalTrials.gov. 08/02/2021. Identifier: NCT04743011.</description>
      <author>Vinicius Tadeu Ramos da Silva Grillo, Matheus Bertanha, Lenize da Silva Rodrigues, Marcelo Andrade de Lima, Pedro Luciano Mellucci Filho, Rafael Rahal Guaragna Machado, Edison Lu&#237;z Durigon, Nath&#225;lia Dias Sert&#243;rio, M&#225;rjorie de Assis Golim, Andrei Moroz, Aline M&#225;rcia Marques Braz, Leonardo Naz&#225;rio de Moraes, Marco Ant&#244;nio Leite, Helena B. Nader, Gustavo Constantino de Campos, Cristiane Rodrigues Guzzo, F&#225;bio Floren&#231;a Cardoso, &#194;ngelo J. Magro, Helga Caputo Nunes, Rejane Maria Tommasini Grotto, Rita de C&#225;ssia Alvarado, Maria In&#234;s de Moura Campos Pardini, Marcone Lima Sobreira, &#201;rika Alessandra Pellison Nunes da Costa, Alexandre Naime Barbosa, Carlos Magno Castelo Branco Fortaleza</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-70064-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagnosis and mitigation of the systemic impact of genome reduction in &lt;i&gt;Escherichia coli&lt;/i&gt; DGF-298</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1128/mbio.00873-24</link>
      <description>Antoine Champie, Jean&#8208;Christophe Lachance, Anand Sastry, Dominick Matteau, Colton J. Lloyd, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Grenier, Cameron Lamoureux, Simon Jeanneau, Adam M. Feist, Pierre&#8208;&#201;tienne Jacques, Bernhard &#216;. Palsson, S&#233;bastien Rodrigue, mBio. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402001164

                ABSTRACT Microorganisms with simplified genomes represent interesting cell chassis for systems and synthetic biology. However, genome reduction can lead to undesired traits, such as decreased growth rate and metabolic imbalances. To investigate the impact of genome reduction on Escherichia coli strain DGF-298, a strain in which ~ 36% of the genome has been removed, we reconstructed a strain-specific metabolic model ( i AC1061), investigated the regulation of gene expression using iModulon-based transcriptome analysis, and performed adaptive laboratory evolution to let the strain correct potential imbalances that arose during its simplification. The model notably predicted that the removal of all three key pathways for glycolaldehyde disposal in this microorganism would lead to a metabolic bottleneck through folate starvation. Glycolaldehyde is also known to cause self-generation of reactive oxygen species, as evidenced by the increased expression of oxidative stress resistance genes in the SoxS iModulon. The reintroduction of the aldA gene, responsible for one native glycolaldehyde disposal route, alleviated the constitutive oxidative stress response. Our results suggest that systems-level approaches and adaptive laboratory evolution have additive benefits when trying to repair and optimize genome-engineered strains. IMPORTANCE Genomic streamlining can be employed in model organisms to reduce complexity and enhance strain predictability. One of the most striking examples is the bacterial strain Escherichia coli DGF-298, notable for having over one-third of its genome deleted. However, such extensive genome modifications raise the question of how similar this simplified cell remains when compared with its parent, and what are the possible unintended consequences of this simplification. In this study, we used metabolic modeling along with iModulon-based transcriptomic analysis in different growth conditions to assess the impact of genome reduction on metabolism and gene regulation. We observed little impact of genomic reduction on the regulatory network of E. coli DGF-298 and identified a potential metabolic bottleneck leading to the constitutive activity of the SoxS iModulon. We then leveraged the model's predictions to successfully restore SoxS activity to the basal level.</description>
      <author>Antoine Champie, Jean&#8208;Christophe Lachance, Anand Sastry, Dominick Matteau, Colton J. Lloyd, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Grenier, Cameron Lamoureux, Simon Jeanneau, Adam M. Feist, Pierre&#8208;&#201;tienne Jacques, Bernhard &#216;. Palsson, S&#233;bastien Rodrigue</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1128/mbio.00873-24</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Antioxidant-Ciprofloxacin Combinations on the Evolution of Antibiotic Resistance in Pseudomonas aeruginosa Biofilms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4756544/v1</link>
      <description>Oana Ciofu, Doaa Higazy, Marwa Ahmed, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401881589

                Abstract Antibiotic resistance in biofilms is a critical challenge driven by mechanisms such as increased oxidative stress, which could lead to enhanced mutagenesis. Experimental evolution studies have shown that biofilm growth fosters antimicrobial resistance and tolerance. The bactericidal antibiotic ciprofloxacin (CIP) exacerbates oxidative stress, enhancing reactive oxygen species (ROS) production and mutagenesis at sub-inhibitory concentrations. This study tests the hypothesis that antioxidants (AOs) such as N-acetyl-cysteine (NAC), and Edaravone (ED) could serve as anti-evolutionary drugs to prevent or reduce antimicrobial resistance in P. aeruginosa biofilms exposed to sub-inhibitory concentrations of ciprofloxacin (CIP), with Thiourea (THU) used as a control. In vitro experimental evolution studies using the monitor strain PAO1-mCherry-PCD-gfp + were conducted in flow cells and glass beads biofilm models. The harvested biofilm populations underwent population analysis and the flow-cell populations were also whole genome sequenced (WGS). The results showed that the CIP-AO combination of CIP-THU could reduce the fast increase of mutagenic resistance in both biofilm models. The confocal laser microscopy of flow cells biofilms showed a reduction in the percentage of nfxB mutants in biofilms treated with all the three CIP-AO combinations compared to the CIP treatment alone following 24h of treatment. The population analysis revealed a significant reduction of the subpopulations growing on 0.5 mg/L of CIP-supplemented plates in all the combined treatments of CIP-AO as compared to CIP populations. The WGS results showed CIP-specific mutants in the CIP-treated populations including nfxB and nalC mutations which were not observed in CIP-AO-treated ones. Flagellar gene mutations appeared in CIP-ED (fliG) and CIP-NAC (flhA) treatments. Additionally, wspA, which regulates biofilm formation, had a transversion mutation in CIP-ED and a deletion mutation in CIP-NAC. The minimum inhibitory concentrations (MICs) level for CIP-treated isolates was significantly higher than all isolates from CIP-AO treatments in both tested biofilm models of flow cells and glass beads. Overall, these findings suggest that the two clinical antioxidants may have a potential role in mitigating the development of antibiotic resistance in biofilms.</description>
      <author>Oana Ciofu, Doaa Higazy, Marwa Ahmed</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4756544/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Titanium Substitutions in Garnet at Magmatic, Granulite Facies, and High-Pressure Granulite Facies Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2138/am-2024-9442</link>
      <description>Jay J. Ague, Duncan S. Keller, Michael R. Ackerson, Megan Holycross, American Mineralogist. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402049737

                Abstract Crystallographically oriented lamellar to acicular rutile &#177; ilmenite inclusions in garnet may record important information about the pressure (P), temperature (T), and petrotectonic evolution of the lithosphere. However, reading this record requires a robust understanding of titanium (Ti) substitution mechanisms and solubility in garnet. To this end, we examine the Ti substitution systematics revealed by 87 garnet analyses from previously published experimental studies relevant for granulites, high-pressure granulites, and deep crustal magmatic rocks. The experimental P&#8211;T conditions range mostly between 850&#8211;1230 &#176;C and 1.0&#8211;2.7 GPa; four 3.2 GPa, 1075&#8211;1150 &#176;C ultrahigh-P, ultrahigh-T examples are also included. We find that normalizing garnet formulas based on 2 octahedral sites per 12 oxygens provides better Fe3+ estimates than the standard 8-total-cation scheme. The Fe3+ must be constrained as both it and Ti substitute on octahedral sites. Graphical analysis reveals that the main substitutions are Tschermak-Ti (VITi4+ + IVAl3+ &#8596; VIAl3+ + IVSi4+) and Andradite (VIAl3+ &#8596; VIFe3+), with lesser but nonetheless important contributions by Andradite-Ti (VITi4+ + IVAl3+ &#8596; VIFe3+ + IVSi4+) and alkali-Ti (VITi4+ + VIII(Na+,K+) &#8596; VIAl3+ + VIIIM2+). Here, VIIIM2+ denotes dodecahedrally coordinated divalent cations (Ca, Fe2+, Mg, Mn). We also posit a small role for Ti substitution coupled to dodecahedral vacancies. These inferences were independently tested using a Monte Carlo modeling procedure developed herein that quantitatively reproduces both the nature and extent of the observed substitutions. We also compared the experimental data with a representative suite of natural garnet analyses. In general, the natural garnets have far lower Ti and alkali (Na &#177; K) contents than the experimental ones. We attribute this to Ti and alkali loss in nature during exhumation and cooling by processes including diffusion and interface-coupled dissolution-reprecipitation. Some fraction of the lost Ti can be hosted by exsolved precipitates of crystallographically oriented rutile &#177; ilmenite. However, in many cases, these are absent and the Ti must have left the garnet structure entirely. The lost alkalis may be hosted by exsolved amphibole or mica precipitates, but these are relatively uncommon suggesting that alkalis are typically transferred from garnet to the matrix or to non-precipitate inclusions.</description>
      <author>Jay J. Ague, Duncan S. Keller, Michael R. Ackerson, Megan Holycross</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2138/am-2024-9442</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acute maternal hyperoxygenation protocol: consensus opinion from the Fetal Heart Society</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/uog.29097</link>
      <description>Nitin Madan, Mary T. Donofrio, Anita Szwast, Anita J. Moon&#8208;Grady, Sarvar Patel, Ultrasound in Obstetrics and Gynecology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402010025

                Acute maternal hyperoxygenation (MH) testing leverages two aspects of fetal cardiovascular physiology: (1) the normally high fetal pulmonary vascular resistance (PVR); and (2) changes in PVR upon exposure to increased fetal oxygen tension1, 2. Normal fetal PVR is high relative to systemic vascular resistance, directing the blood ejected from the right ventricle preferentially across the ductus arteriosus, with a small proportion entering the pulmonary arteries (PAs)1. By extension, a modest amount of left atrial filling is via the pulmonary veins. After delivery, mechanical expansion of the lungs and increased oxygen levels result in a rapid drop in PVR1. Exposure of the fetus to acute MH also results in a reduction in PVR, although less drastic than that at delivery. This response has been demonstrated in the second trimester3, but tends to become more prevalent2, albeit remaining variable4, 5, in the third trimester. Acute MH response is reflected by a decrease in pulsatility index (PI) in the PA branches (Figure 1) and increased pulmonary venous flow as assessed by Doppler on fetal echocardiography (FE). A 10&#8211;20% drop in branch PA-PI is considered reactive4, 6-8. The presence or absence of fetal pulmonary vascular reactivity is useful information. Some literature suggests that a lack of pulmonary vascular reactivity in certain cardiac and non-cardiac defects may signal poor postnatal outcome and, by extension, indicate the need for urgent postnatal resuscitation6, 7, 9, 10. However, given the reported variability in pulmonary vascular reactivity in the third trimester of healthy pregnancies4, 5, lack of reactivity in high-risk fetuses should be interpreted with caution. Fetuses demonstrating reactive PVR experience acute cardiovascular changes similar to postnatal circulatory shifts, including increased pulmonary blood flow, increased left-sided filling and changes in foramen ovale geometry. This simulation might predict unfavorable changes that may occur postnatally, such as profound hypoxemia due to persistent pulmonary hypertension, restrictive atrial septum in hypoplastic left heart syndrome (HLHS) or d-transposition of the great arteries (d-TGA), and increased venous obstruction in total anomalous pulmonary venous connection (TAPVC)7, 10, 11. In summary, acute MH testing may be useful to understand fetal pulmonary vascular reactivity and to mimic postnatal redistribution of blood flow and associated changes in anatomy and/or physiology. Despite the safety7, 12-14 and potential of acute MH testing in predicting postnatal hemodynamic instability with certain congenital cardiac and non-cardiac defects, this test remains underutilized secondary to the absence of a published standardized protocol and limited guidance regarding test interpretation. To address this, the Program Leaders Committee at the Fetal Heart Society formed a writing group of experts to develop an acute MH testing protocol. This document represents a consensus opinion on the various facets of acute MH testing, including timing, oxygen administration, FE assessments and test interpretation, providing a framework for fetal cardiac centers interested in implementing acute MH for clinical testing. For those fetal cardiac centers already conducting the test, it offers a standardized approach to foster collaborative learning and research in the field. Under the sponsorship of the Fetal Heart Society, a benchmarking survey aimed at elucidating current trends in fetal cardiology programs was carried out in 2023. Among the inquiries in this survey, one query focused on whether acute MH testing was performed at the surveyed site. Following the survey findings to this query, we assembled a panel of clinicians and researchers spanning the USA, Canada and the UK to collaborate on formulating a consensus protocol on acute MH testing. Group discussions were held to define objectives, and subsequently, the document underwent numerous iterations and was reviewed meticulously by all members until a consensus was achieved. Use of PWD is recommended Recovery phase after removing oxygen for 5 min (optional): FE assessment in the recovery phase is not required routinely; however, this is strongly recommended if concerning findings develop during acute MH, such as new or worsening tricuspid regurgitation, ductal constriction, new arrhythmia, foramen ovale closure and/or decrease in cardiac function. We present a consensus opinion on a standardized approach to conducting acute MH testing in both clinical and research settings. We provide indications, an image library and a basic guide to interpreting acute MH test results, based on the available literature. Additionally, we pinpoint knowledge gaps to serve as a compass for future research endeavors. This publication was developed with the support of the Fetal Heart Society sponsoring institutions. Without their contributions, the evolution of the Fetal Heart Society and this and ongoing research would not be possible. A full listing of sponsoring institutions can be found at www.fetalheartsociety.org. L. Freud, Division of Paediatric Cardiology, Department of Paediatrics, The Hospital for Sick Children, Toronto, ON, Canada M. Geiger, Division of Pediatric Cardiology, Mount Sinai Hospital, Icahn School of Medicine at Mount Sinai, New York, NY, USA L. K. Hornberger, Fetal and Neonatal Cardiology Program, Division of Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Stollery Children's Hospital, Edmonton, AB, Canada J. Johnson, Johns Hopkins All Children's Hospital, St Petersburg, FL, USA A. McBrien, Fetal and Neonatal Cardiology Program, Division of Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Stollery Children's Hospital, Edmonton, AB, Canada S. A. Morris, Division of Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Texas Children's Hospital, Baylor College of Medicine, Houston, TX, USA S. Peyvandi, Division of Pediatric Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, University of California San Francisco, San Francisco, CA, USA J. Pruetz, Division of Pediatric Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Children's Hospital Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA D. Schidlow, Department of Cardiology, Boston Children's Hospital, Harvard Medical School, Boston, MA, USA T. A. Tacy, Division of Cardiology, Department of Pediatrics, Stanford University, Palo Alto, CA, USA T. V. Vigneswaran, Department of Congenital Heart Disease, Evelina London Children's Hospital, Guy's &amp; St Thomas' NHS Trust, London, UK Data sharing not applicable - no new data generated. Figure S1 Fetal Heart Society patient information leaflet for maternal hyperoxygenation. Please note: The publisher is not responsible for the content or functionality of any supporting information supplied by the authors. Any queries (other than missing content) should be directed to the corresponding author for the article.</description>
      <author>Nitin Madan, Mary T. Donofrio, Anita Szwast, Anita J. Moon&#8208;Grady, Sarvar Patel</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/uog.29097</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Bansk&#225; &#352;tiavnica ore district</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5382/gb.31.09</link>
      <description>Jaroslav Lexa, J. &#352;tohl, Vlastimil Kone&#269;n&#253;, No host. None(None)] 1999. https://openalex.org/W4401944450

                Abstract The Bansk&#225; &#352;tiavnica ore district is in the central zone of the largest stratovolcano in the Central Slovakia Neogene Volcanic Field, which is situated at the inner side of the Carpathian arc over the Hercynian basement with the Late Paleozoic and Mesozoic sedimentary cover. Volcanic rocks of the High-K orogenic suite are of the Badenian through Pannonian age (16.5&#8211; 8.5 Ma). Their petrogenesis is closely related to subduction of flysch belt oceanic basement underneath the advancing Carpathian arc and to back-arc extension processes. The stratovolcano includes a large caldera 20 km in diameter and a late-stage resurgent horst in its centre, exposing a basement and extensive subvolcanic intrusive complex. The following stages have been recognized in the evolution of the stratovolcano: (1) formation of a large pyroxene/hornblende-pyroxene andesite stratovolcano; (2) denudation, emplacement of a diorite intrusion; (3) emplacement of a large granodiorite bell-jar pluton within the basement; (4) emplacement of granodiorite/quartz-diorite porphyry stocks and dyke clusters around the pluton; (5) caldera subsidence and its filling by biotite-hornblende andesite volcanics, emplacement of quartz-diorite porphyry sills and dykes at the subvolcanic level; (6) renewed activity of andesites from dispersed centres on slopes of the volcano; (7) uplift of a resurgent horst accompanied by rhyolite volcanics and granite porphyry dykes. The following types of ore deposits (mineralizations) have been identified in the Bansk&#225; &#352;tiavnica ore district: 1. Quartz-pyrophyllite-pyrite high-sulphidation system at &#352;obov, related to the diorite intrusion. 2. Magnetite skarn deposits and occurrences at contacts of the granodiorite pluton with Mesozoic carbonate rocks. Magnetite ores occur as lenses in the calcic skarns. 3. Stockwork/disseminated base metal deposit along an irregular network of fractures in apical parts of the granodiorite pluton and in remnants of basement rocks. Mineral paragenesis is simple, with leading sphalerite and galena and minor chalcopyrite and pyrite. In overlying andesites the mineralization is accompanied by metasomatic quartzites and argillites with pyrophyllite, kaolinite, illite and pyrite. 4. Porphyry /skarn copper deposits and occurrences related to granodiorite/quartz-diorite porphyry dyke clusters and stocks around the granodiorite intrusion. The mineralized zone is represented by accumulations of chalcopyrite in exo- and endo-skarns, usually of the magnesian type affected by serpentinization. Besides chalcopyrite, pyrhotite, minor bornite, chalcosite, tennantite and magnetite, rare molybdenite and gold are present. The alteration pattern around productive intrusions includes an external zone of propylitization, a zone of argillitic alteration (kaolinite &#8212; illite &#8212; pyrite) and an internal zone of phyllic alteration (quartz &#8212; sericite &#8212; pyrite). Biotitization is rare and limited to porphyry intrusions. 5. Intrusion related &#8220;mesothermal&#8221; gold deposit in an andesitic environment just above the granodiorite intrusion. Gold of high fineness with base metal mineralization is contained in brecciated and/or banded quartz veins of subhorizontal orientation, parallel to the surface of granodiorite pluton. At least the first phase of mineralization is older than quartz-diorite porphyry sills, which separate granodiorite and blocks of mineralized andesite. 6. Hot spring type advanced argillic systems in the caldera filling. Silicites and opalites accompanied by kaolinite, alunite and pyrite grade downward into smectite dominated argillites. 7. Vein type epithermal precious/base metal deposits and occurrences as a result of the long lasting interaction among structural evolution of the resurgent horst and evolving hydrothermal system, extensive intrusive complex and deep seated siliceous magma chamber serving as heat and magmatic fluid source. Three types of epithermal veins occur in a zonal arrangement: (a) base metal veins &#177; Au with transition to Cu &#177; Bi mineralization at depth in the east/central part of the horst, (b) Ag &#8212; Au veins with minor base metal mineralization and (c) Au &#8212; Ag veins located at marginal faults of the horst. Isotopic composition of oxygen and hydrogen in hydrothermal fluids indicate mixing of magmatic and meteoric component (with generally increasing proportion of meteoric component towards younger mineralization periods?). Veins are accompanied by zones of silicification, adularization and sericitization, indicating a low sulphidation environment. 8. Replacement base metal mineralization of a limited extent in the Mesozoic carbonate rocks next to sulphide rich epithermal base metal veins.</description>
      <author>Jaroslav Lexa, J. &#352;tohl, Vlastimil Kone&#269;n&#253;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 1999 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5382/gb.31.09</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applicability of Graphite as Anodic Counter Electrode for Electrocatalyst Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01869</link>
      <description>Weiran Zheng, Lijie Du, ACS Energy Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401873398

                InfoMetricsFiguresRef.SI ACS Energy LettersASAPArticle This publication is free to access through this site. Learn More CiteCitationCitation and abstractCitation and referencesMore citation options ShareShare onFacebookX (Twitter)WeChatLinkedInRedditEmailJump toExpandCollapse ViewpointAugust 26, 2024Applicability of Graphite as Anodic Counter Electrode for Electrocatalyst EvaluationClick to copy article linkArticle link copied!Weiran Zheng*Weiran ZhengDepartment of Chemistry, Guangdong Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Shantou 515063, ChinaTechnion-Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa 32000, IsraelGuangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Materials and Technologies for Energy Conversion, Guangdong Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Shantou 515063, China*[email protected]More by Weiran Zhenghttps://orcid.org/0000-0002-9915-6982Lijie DuLijie DuDepartment of Chemistry, Guangdong Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Shantou 515063, ChinaMore by Lijie DuOpen PDFSupporting Information (1)ACS Energy LettersCite this: ACS Energy Lett. 2024, 9, XXX, 4581&#8211;4586Click to copy citationCitation copied!https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01869https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01869Published August 26, 2024 Publication History Received 10 July 2024Accepted 14 August 2024Published online 26 August 2024article-commentary&#169; 2024 American Chemical Society. This publication is available under these Terms of Use. Request reuse permissionsThis publication is licensed for personal use by The American Chemical Society. ACS Publications&#169; 2024 American Chemical SocietySubjectswhat are subjectsArticle subjects are automatically applied from the ACS Subject Taxonomy and describe the scientific concepts and themes of the article.Anode materialsCarbonElectrochemical cellsElectrolytesOxidationGraphite rod is a popular counter electrode (CE) material due to its affordability, ease of use, and relatively stable chemical and electrochemical properties. (1&#8722;3) As suggested by the literature survey (Figure S1), it is generally favored over Pt CE (67% vs 29%) when serving as the anode (e.g., as CE for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) catalyst evaluation) due to the Pt dissolution, (4,5) yet several issues arise. The primary concern is carbon corrosion, causing graphite particle detachment and CO/CO2 production (Figure 1). (6) These byproducts can harm the accuracy and reliability of electrocatalyst evaluations. Lee et al. and Ji et al. demonstrated that carbon fiber paper and graphite are susceptible to oxidation in acidic conditions and can deactivate Pt electrodes via CO poisoning. (7,8) Separating the CE compartment from the working electrode (WE) can minimize byproduct diffusion, as demonstrated by Sheng et al. using a graphite CE housed in a glass tube in acidic conditions. (9) These suggestions offer a general judgment on the applicability of graphite CE. However, the behavior of the CE depends significantly on factors such as the electrolyte (acidic or basic), the electrochemical methods (e.g., polarization, steady state), and the electrochemical parameters (e.g., scan rate, scan range, and CE area). Therefore, a comprehensive analysis and guidance on the applicability of graphite CE is needed. This Viewpoint aims to provide such guidance by offering a fundamental analysis of graphite CE followed by best practice recommendations.Figure 1Figure 1. Potential/current relationship in a three-electrode cell and possible interferents generated from the CE diffusing to the WE. &#981;WE: WE potential; &#981;CE: CE potential; &#981;REF: reference electrode potential; EWE: WE voltage; ECE: CE voltage; ECELL: cell voltage; i, iCELL, iWE, and iCE: identical currents in the circuit, cell, WE, and CE; QWE, QCE: charge input/output at WE and CE.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint Slide Role of the CEFirst, we need to revisit the role of the CE. In a three-electrode cell, the current flows between the WE and CE (Figure 1). The WE hosts the electrochemical reaction of interest with a precisely controlled voltage (EWE), while the CE completes the circuit by matching the charge requirements. The charge at the WE (QWE) equals the charge at the CE (QCE) at all times, meaning the current at the WE (iWE = QWE/t) always equals the current at the CE (iCE = QCE/t). This current determines the potential applied by the potentiostat on the CE (ECE) (Figure 2A). As the demand for iWE or QWE increases, ECE is increased to drive the corresponding iCE or QCE through Faradaic and/or non-Faradaic processes. Yet, the instrument's compliance voltage (12 V in our case) limits the applicable range of ECE and EWE.Figure 2Figure 2. (A) Changes in &#981;WE, Q, i, and &#981;CE during an HER polarization study: as &#981;WE exceeds the HER onset potential, Q (and i) rises, requiring an increase in &#981;CE to produce matching Q and i, involving OER. (B) Potential drops across WE and CE (from EDL of WE, bulk electrolyte, to EDL of CE) in two cases: top, rising i (blue: low current; red: high current); bottom, less active CE (blue: high activity; red: low activity). Ru: solution resistance between WE and REF; EDL: electric double layer.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideAlthough some suggest that a slow kinetic process on the CE (i.e., a less active CE) can limit the current on the WE, (7) this is fundamentally unlikely in a three-electrode cell. The iWE is determined exclusively by the EWE (&#981;WE &#8211; &#981;REF) and the nature of the reaction. Regardless of the CE's activity, the potentiostat will increase or decrease the ECE to achieve the required current at the specific EWE. (10) Assuming the same WE and CE, an increase in i results in a larger potential drop across the bulk electrolyte between the WE and CE (Figure 2B, top), while for a less active CE, a higher ECE within the electric double layer (EDL) of the CE is required to meet the same i requirement (Figure 2B, bottom). (10,11) Therefore, to maximize the i and EWE range, especially with potentiostats having low compliance voltage (e.g., 6 V for many compact models), a shorter WE&#8211;CE distance and a CE with faster kinetics (i.e., more active) are recommended.For accurate WE analysis, electrochemical processes at the CE must not interfere with the reaction at the WE. Acceptable scenarios include confined species production (the iCE or QCE is generated by electrochemical processes at the CE that produce species confined to the CE surface or separated from the WE) and nonreactive species production (the iCE or QCE results from electrochemical processes at the CE that produce diffusible but nonreactive species concerning the WE). Inevitably, non-Faradaic charging/discharging at the CE contributes to iCE or QCE, but this contribution is minor and does not interfere with the WE. Anodic Behavior of Graphite CETo analyze how graphite as a CE provides QCE, we used a graphite rod as the WE and another as the CE (cell configuration denoted as C|C). In an acidic electrolyte (0.5 M H2SO4), the current increases around 0 V (all potential values in this contribution are calibrated against a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE), see Supporting Information) and rises rapidly from &#8764;1.52 V (Figure 3A), due to sulfate ion intercalation. (12) In an alkaline electrolyte (1.0 M KOH), noticeable current onset occurs at &#8764;1.70 V. Charge accumulation (Figure 3B) shows that the graphite electrode contributes more charge in acidic conditions than in alkaline ones, indicating a smaller ECE requirement in acid for the same QCE. Differential electrochemical mass spectra (DEMS) (Figure 3C) reveal that in acidic conditions, CO and O2 evolve from &#8764;2.02 V and CO2 from &#8764;1.61 V. In comparison, only O2 is produced in alkaline conditions from &#8764;1.79 V (CO2 is undetectable due to carbonation), which agrees with the DEMS study by Schuhmann et al. that OER can hinder carbon corrosion in alkaline. (6) After a few cycles, black particles appear from &#8764;1.50 V in the acidic electrolyte, indicating graphite exfoliation and detachment. (12) The cycled graphite surface is rougher in acidic electrolytes than in alkaline ones (Figure S2), suggesting more intense exfoliation in acidic conditions.Figure 3Figure 3. (A) Cyclic voltammograms of graphite electrodes in Ar-saturated 0.5 M H2SO4 (orange) and 1.0 M KOH (blue) electrolytes (scan rate: 10 mV s&#8211;1). (B) Corresponding charge plots. (C) DEMS signals of O2, CO, and CO2 as a function of potential. (D) Schematic representation of the anodic polarization processes of graphite electrodes.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideFigure 3D outlines the anodic polarization processes on the graphite CE, (6,13) including anion adsorption/intercalation, exfoliation, particle detachment, surface oxidation, OER, and complete oxidation to CO/CO2. Although most processes are surface-bound, released particles and CO/CO2 can diffuse to the WE, potentially interfering with the desired reaction. Thus, the suitability of graphite as a CE depends on the applied ECE and the durations of these processes, which vary with different electrochemical methods. We will focus the discussion on two key methods: cyclic voltammetry (CV) and steady-state electrolysis. CV Using Graphite CE: One vs Two CompartmentsA two-compartment cell (H-cell) is often recommended to mitigate corrosion product diffusion from a carbon CE. (9) We start by analyzing the electrochemical response of Pt WE and graphite CE in two cell configurations under acidic and alkaline conditions.Figures 4A and 4B show the evolution of EWE, ECE, and i in acidic and alkaline conditions within a one-compartment cell (denoted as Pt|C) during 100 cycles of CV study. In the first cycle (insets), as EWE decreases from 0 to &#8722;0.20 V, i increases due to HER catalyzed by Pt, requiring a matching iCE from the graphite CE, causing ECE to rise. Two major kinetic zones are identified in both conditions, indicating that graphite CE undergoes at least two processes to provide the matching iCE or QCE (Figure S3). Since ECE exceeds 2.50 V, all anodic processes of graphite are present, producing exfoliated particles and O2 (acid and base) and CO/CO2 (acid). When EWE returns to 0 V, ECE drops to &#8764;1.50 V, indicating irreversible graphite oxidation as it remains higher than the reduction potentials of surface oxidation species (Figure 3A). Notably, the initial ECE (&#8764;1.07 V) at i = 0 A is never achieved again, as i returns to 0 A in each cycle (ECE &#8776; 1.62 V), suggesting a permanent change in the graphite CE surface after the first cycle. Continuous cycling leads to a decline in i and QCE (Figure S3) at EWE = 0.20 V, resulting in a lower ECE demand.Figure 4Figure 4. (A, B) EWE (blue), ECE (orange), and i (green) correlation during CV analysis (100 cycles) in (A) H2-saturated 0.5 M H2SO4 and (B) H2-saturated 1.0 M KOH electrolytes (scan rate: 10 mV s&#8211;1; EWE range: 0 &#8764; &#8722;0.20 V). (C) Correlation between the i and ECE at EWE = &#8722;0.20 V of each cycle in H2SO4 (blue) and KOH (red) electrolytes with (square) and without (circle) involving IEM.High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideTo verify if the decline is caused by anodic corrosion products (such as CO, a well-known poisoning species for Pt) (14) of the graphite CE, we separated the Pt WE and graphite CE in an H-cell (denoted as Pt|IEM|C) using a Nafion-117 ion exchange membrane (IEM) to minimize product diffusion (Figure S4). Cycling data and the ECE&#8211;QCE correlation (Figures S5 and S6) show similar graphite CE behavior to Pt|C cells. Figure 4C compares ECE and i at EWE = &#8722;0.2 V in both configurations. In acidic conditions, the current decline is significantly reduced, from 82% (Pt|C) to 21% (Pt|IEM|C) after 100 cycles, indicating a major negative impact of the unseparated graphite CE on Pt-based HER catalyst benchmarking, likely due to overwhelming CO production and poisoning at Pt WE when ECE &gt; 2.5 V. In alkaline conditions, adding IEM does not affect the current decline (51% for Pt|IEM|C, 55% for Pt|C), suggesting a minor contribution from the graphite CE in Pt|C, which is reasonable because no noticeable CO production of graphite is observed in alkaline electrolyte. The deactivation of polycrystalline Pt in alkaline electrolytes may relate to surface/crystalline structure changes during cycling, (15) though this is beyond our current focus.However, using an IEM has drawbacks. Cells with IEM show smaller currents in the initial 5 cycles due to hindered ion transport between the WE and CE, as indicated by the higher WE-CE resistance (RWE-CE) in the electrochemical impedance spectra (EIS) (Figure S7). Since iR compensation only corrects RWE-REF (&#8764;0.3 ohms for all cells), (16) the activity of the Pt WE can be underestimated (by &#8764;15% from first cycle data). Additionally, the extra voltage loss requires a higher ECE to achieve the same current, limiting the usable EWE range. (17) As shown in Figure 4C, the IEM increases ECE by &#8764;0.32 V in alkaline conditions and 0.05 V in acidic conditions.Therefore, separating the graphite CE from the Pt WE is generally preferred for long-term cycling analysis, such as stability evaluation, especially in acidic electrolytes. For accurate Pt activity assessment, the Pt WE and graphite CE should share the same compartment to minimize cell voltage loss. In these cases, using single-run linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) or CV with fewer cycles (&lt;5 in our study) is recommended to avoid the accumulation of oxidation products from the graphite, particularly in acidic conditions. Impact of CV Scan Range and Scan Rate on Graphite CEThe cycle number reflects the total charge associated with the anodic corrosion of the graphite CE under varying ECE, influenced by CV parameters such as scan range (EWE range) and scan rate.Figure 5A compares the highest current in each cycle (imax) and the required ECE at different EWE ranges. Lower EWE results in higher current and higher ECE on the graphite. For instance, cycling between 0 and &#8722;0.30 V generally requires an ECE higher than 3.0 V (ECELL &gt; 3.3 V). In alkaline electrolytes, ECE is generally higher than in acidic ones, likely due to sulfate ion intercalation in H2SO4 contributing to iCE at lower potentials.Figure 5Figure 5. (A) Correlation between the max i and ECE of each cycle in H2-saturated H2SO4 (blue) and KOH (red) electrolytes with different EWE range: 0.1 V (0 &#8764; &#8722;0.10 V), 0.2 V (0 &#8764; &#8722;0.20 V), 0.3 V (0 &#8764; &#8722;0.30 V). (B) Correlation between the i and ECE of each cycle at EWE = &#8722;0.2 V with different WE/CE ratios: 1:5 and 1:2 (cell configuration: Pt|IEM|C; scan rate: 10 mV s&#8211;1).High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideA smaller EWE range (lower i) can significantly improve stability, as supported by data with (Figure 5A) and without IEM (Figure S8). Higher scan rates in CV result in higher currents due to increased electron transfer reactions and double-layer capacitive charging, (18) requiring higher ECE (Figure S9). However, higher scan rates also shorten the duration of extensive anodic corrosion on the graphite CE, leading to a lower current decline rate.Overall, while adjusting the scan rate and range is often necessary to obtain electrochemical properties, it is important to consider their impact on the graphite CE. A small scan range and high scan rate with IEM can minimize current decline due to accumulated graphite corrosion products in stability evaluations. However, high scan rates and IEM increase ECE on graphite to achieve the same current as in one-compartment cells, reducing the usable EWE range and potentially reaching the compliance voltage limit. Impact of Graphite CE Properties: Surface Area and Surface StateTwo frequently mentioned suggestions for a good CE are high surface area and activity. (9) Since the CE's sole function is to provide a matching current, a higher surface area offers more charge transfer sites, and a more active CE enables faster charge transfer (i.e., higher current) at the same ECE.The geometric surface area ratio between WE and CE in the previous discussion is fixed at 1:5. Herein, we decrease the CE area, and Figure 5B compares cyclic performance with WE/CE ratios of 1:2 and 1:5. Smaller CE area does not significantly impact iWE, suggesting CE is not limiting WE kinetics. However, ECE increases by &#8764;0.4 V (acid) and &#8764;0.5 V (base) with a 60% reduction in graphite area, indicating that the potentiostat compensates areal loss by increasing ECE to match i. The ECE trend is noisier with a 1:2 ratio, indicating higher instability with a smaller CE.In principle, a larger CE area improves charge transport between WE and CE due to a larger liquid projection containing more charge carriers (Figure 6A), allowing for a lower and more stable ECE demand, enabling a wider ECE and i range. While a WE/CE ratio of 1:10 is widely suggested in the literature, (7,9) our results show no significant differences between 1:5 and 1:10 (Figure S10), likely due to the larger electrochemical surface area (ECSA) of graphite compared to its geometrical area (GA), which is 3.6:1 for ECSA/GA according to our study, meaning that the actual ECSA ratio of WE/CE is 1:18.Figure 6Figure 6. (A) Impact of WE/CE ratio on the RWE-CE: smaller CE leads to larger RWE-CE and lower i allowance. (B) Current profile during 10h-CA analysis in an alkaline electrolyte with different WE/CE ratios (cell configuration: Pt|IEM|C; EWE = &#8722;0.20 V).High Resolution ImageDownload MS PowerPoint SlideDuring cycling, the graphite CE undergoes varying ECE (1.75&#8211;2.50 V), leading to reversible (charging/discharging) and irreversible (surface oxidation, particle detachment, full oxidation) anodic behavior. Irreversibility from surface oxidation is evident as ECE never returns to the initial &#8764;1.0 V at i = 0 A (insets of Figures 4A, 4B, S5A, and S5B). DEMS results (Figure S11) show that cycling alters the graphite CE surface state and anodic behavior. In acidic conditions, overwhelming CO production starts at a lower potential after just 3 cycles, likely due to the oxidized graphite surface being more prone to further oxidation into CO. To avoid significant CO production in initial cycles, it is necessary to remove the oxide layer formed in previous experiments. Polishing the graphite rod with sandpaper to achieve a smooth surface can effectively remove the oxide layer and increase the onset potential of graphite corrosion. (Figures S12 and S13, more details in the Experimental Section of Supporting Information) Steady-State Analysis Using Graphite CESteady-state analysis examines a system under constant conditions. In chronoamperometry (CA), EWE is fixed to monitor changes in i, with the potentiostat adjusting ECE. As the catalyst deactivates, i decreases, resulting in a lower ECE (i.e., a smaller ECELL) (Figure 6B). In chronopotentiometry (CP), i is fixed to monitor changes in EWE. If the CE maintains its activity, EWE remains constant. However, as the catalyst deactivates, EWE increases, leading to a larger ECELL. In this regard, using a larger and more active CE benefits wider i and EWE ranges.For graphite CE, unlike in CV studies, non-Faradaic i from charging/discharging is negligible since ECE does not vary rapidly. Complete oxidation of the graphite surface can be quickly achieved. Thus, during long-term steady-state analysis, iCE or QCE is sustained by exfoliation, OER, and full oxidation to CO/CO2. In alkaline conditions, the electrolyte initially turns brown due to the production of few-layer graphene. In acidic conditions, black particles from the graphite CE settle at the bottom. The graphite surface becomes significantly rougher after 10 h of CA testing (Figure S14) compared to 100 cycles of CV (Figure S2). Similar to CV treatment, irreversible surface changes in graphite after electrolysis are evident (Figure S15), highlighting the importance of polishing the graphite surface to ensure a reproducible experimental setup.To avoid WE surface contamination, using an IEM is essential in steady-state studies. However, some particles may attach to the IEM, potentially reducing ion exchange efficiency. A CE with a larger surface area can mitigate this issue since a lower ECE is needed, decreasing the exfoliation rate. Beyond Pt-Based ElectrocatalystsThe above discussions are based on Pt WE, known to be poisoned by CO. (14) For the CV analysis of other HER catalysts (e.g., MoS2) that do not suffer from CO and significant structural evolution, (8,19) it is expected that graphite CE can still be usable without IEM. Figure S16 confirms that no major current decrement occurs within 100 cycles with and without IEM (by &#8764;1.8% over 100 cycles). Similar to the previous comparison between Pt|C and Pt|IEM|C, using IEM increases the ECE by &#8764;170 mV. Therefore, if the graphite corrosion species are known as non-interfering species for the WE reaction, IEM is not essential. However, in reality, such information is mostly unknown, and using IEM is generally suggested despite the higher iR and cell voltage. Best Practices with Graphite CEIn summary, using a Pt WE, we have explored the applicability of graphite as an anodic CE in both acidic and alkaline conditions for HER activity evaluation. We examined several aspects related to two fundamental electrochemical methods, CV and steady-state analysis, focusing on the anodic behavior of the graphite CE and its impact on current and cell voltage. Although the specific WE and condition of the graphite CE may vary from lab to lab, making exact current and potential values less universally applicable, we can draw a few general best practice guidelines:1)Separate graphite CE from WE for long-term cycling and steady-state analysis in acidic conditions: In acidic conditions, aged graphite CE generates lots of CO/CO2 and large particles. Using an H-cell minimizes contamination and ensures accuracy. In alkaline conditions, OER and graphite exfoliation dominate, and while the impact is less distinguishable, a separator prevents unknown interferences. However, a separator can also introduce additional resistance between the WE and CE, lowering the i and EWE&#8211;ECE range. A larger CE and shorter WE&#8211;CE distance can reduce the resistance.2)Use a shared compartment for accurate activity assessment with single-run LSV or limited CV cycles: The WE and graphite CE should share the same compartment to minimize cell voltage loss introduced by the separator and to ensure precise evaluation. However, the test duration should be as short as possible (&lt;5 cycles) to prevent the accumulation of oxidation products from the graphite in the electrolyte, especially in acidic conditions.3)Perform large current and high potential tests on a potentiostat with large compliance voltage: In principle, the activity of the CE does not matter if sufficient ECE can be provided to meet the current demand. However, the data becomes meaningless if the instrumental compliance voltage is reached. Therefore, researchers need to check the cell voltage regularly. A potentiostat with a larger compliance voltage is generally recommended, as it enables a wider EWE&#8211;ECE range.4)Reduce the WE&#8211;CE distance to enable a larger current range for testing: A shorter WE&#8211;CE distance can reduce the RWE-CE resistance, therefore decreasing the potential drop in the bulk electrolyte between the WE and CE. For a fixed iRWE-CE limited by the compliance voltage, lower RWE-CE means higher i allowance.5)Choose scan range and scan rate wisely: A larger scan range and higher scan rate often lead to increased ECE, while a smaller scan rate prolongs graphite corrosion. Therefore, when selecting CV parameters, a pre-experimental evaluation of the graphite anodic behavior is necessary.6)Use a WE/CE ratio of 1:5 or lower: A larger CE area can decrease the ECE demand and RWE-CE, allowing a wider EWE range and higher current for testing. A WE/CE ratio lower than 1:5 is preferred for graphite CE, especially when using a potentiostat with a small compliance voltage.7)Polish graphite CE before and after each experiment: Graphite CE undergoes irreversible surface oxidation as an anode, making it more susceptible to oxidation in subsequent tests. For reproducible analysis, the surface should be polished with sandpaper to achieve a smooth surface before and after each test to ensure a similar open circuit potential (OCV, i.e., similar surface state). Furthermore, we also recommend storing graphite CE in ion-free water to release the intercalated species from previous experiments.8)Replace the graphite CE regularly: Based on the above discussion, changes (oxidation and intercalation) in the graphite CE can gradually accumulate, leading to permanent deterioration. Researchers should replace the graphite CE if a consistent OCV cannot be achieved or if the ECE becomes abnormally high and unstable compared to a new graphite CE.Supporting InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!The Supporting Information is available free of charge at https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01869.Experimental details; Literature survey; Graphite morphology before and after CV study; ECE&#8211;QCE correlation during the first and 100th cycles in Pt|C and Pt|IEM|C cells; H-cell configuration; CV profile in Pt|IEM|C cell; Resistance introduced by IEM; Impact of CV scan rate/scan range on ECE and i in Pt|C and Pt|IEM|C cells; Impact of WE/CE ratio: from 1:5 to 1:10; DEMS results of repeated staircase voltammetry: aging of graphite surface; Aged graphite surface treatment; ECE&#8211;i correlation using MoS2 as WE and graphite as CE (PDF)nz4c01869_si_001.pdf (14.34 MB) Terms &amp; Conditions Most electronic Supporting Information files are available without a subscription to ACS Web Editions. Such files may be downloaded by article for research use (if there is a public use license linked to the relevant article, that license may permit other uses). Permission may be obtained from ACS for other uses through requests via the RightsLink permission system: http://pubs.acs.org/page/copyright/permissions.html. Author InformationClick to copy section linkSection link copied!Corresponding AuthorWeiran Zheng - Department of Chemistry, Guangdong Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Shantou 515063, China; Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Haifa 32000, Israel; Guangdong Provincial Key Laboratory of Materials and Technologies for Energy Conversion, Guangdong Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Shantou 515063, China; https://orcid.org/0000-0002-9915-6982; Email: [email protected]AuthorLijie Du - Department of Chemistry, Guangdong Technion-Israel Institute of Technology, Shantou 515063, ChinaNotesViews expressed in this Viewpoint are those of the author and not necessarily the views of the ACS.The authors declare no competing financial interest.AcknowledgmentsClick to copy section linkSection link copied!W.Z. is grateful for the support of the Guangdong Basic and Applied Basic Research Foundation (Grant Number: 2023A1515012277) and the Guangdong Technion-Israel Institute of Technology (Grant Number: ST2200002).ReferencesClick to copy section linkSection link copied! This article references 19 other publications. 1McCrory, C. C.; Jung, S.; Ferrer, I. M.; Chatman, S. M.; Peters, J. C.; Jaramillo, T. F. Benchmarking hydrogen evolving reaction and oxygen evolving reaction electrocatalysts for solar water splitting devices. J. Am. Chem. Soc. 2015, 137 (13), 4347&#8211; 4357, DOI: 10.1021/ja510442p Google Scholar1Benchmarking Hydrogen Evolving Reaction and Oxygen Evolving Reaction Electrocatalysts for Solar Water Splitting DevicesMcCrory, Charles C. L.; Jung, Suho; Ferrer, Ivonne M.; Chatman, Shawn M.; Peters, Jonas C.; Jaramillo, Thomas F.Journal of the American Chemical Society (2015), 137 (13), 4347-4357CODEN: JACSAT; ISSN:0002-7863. (American Chemical Society) Objective comparisons of electrocatalyst activity and stability using std. methods under identical conditions are necessary to evaluate the viability of existing electrocatalysts for integration into solar-fuel devices as well as to help inform the development of new catalytic systems. Herein, the authors use a std. protocol as a primary screen for evaluating the activity, short-term (2 h) stability, and electrochem. active surface area (ECSA) of 18 electrocatalysts for the H evolution reaction (HER) and 26 electrocatalysts for the O evolution reaction (OER) under conditions relevant to an integrated solar H2O-splitting device in aq. acidic or alk. soln. The primary figure of merit is the overpotential necessary to achieve a magnitude c.d. of 10 mA cm-2 per geometric area, the approx. c.d. expected for a 10% efficient solar-to-fuels conversion device under 1 sun illumination. The specific activity per ECSA of each material is also reported. Among HER catalysts, several could operate at 10 mA cm-2 with overpotentials &lt;0.1 V in acidic and/or alk. solns. Among OER catalysts in acidic soln., no nonnoble metal based materials showed promising activity and stability, whereas in alk. soln. many OER catalysts performed with similar activity achieving 10 mA cm-2 current densities at overpotentials of &#8764;0.33-0.5 V. Most OER catalysts showed comparable or better specific activity per ECSA when compared to Ir and Ru catalysts in alk. solns., while most HER catalysts showed much lower specific activity than Pt in both acidic and alk. solns. For select catalysts, addnl. secondary screening measurements were conducted including faradaic efficiency and extended stability measurements. &gt;&gt; More from SciFinder &#174;https://chemport.cas.org/services/resolver?origin=AC</description>
      <author>Weiran Zheng, Lijie Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c01869</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
