<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 01:20:09 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Is the oxygen plasma cleaning technique indicated for any electrochemical purpose?: the case of FTO electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145149</link>
      <description>P. D&#305;&#769;az, G. Riveros, Mart&#237;n Fa&#250;ndez, A. Enrique Caballero, Rodrigo Wittwer, F. Mart&#305;&#769;n, Cecilia Silva Cabrera, Daniel Gau, Enrique A. Dalchiele, Ricardo E. Marotti, Daniel Ram&#237;rez, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402826225

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P. D&#305;&#769;az, G. Riveros, Mart&#237;n Fa&#250;ndez, A. Enrique Caballero, Rodrigo Wittwer, F. Mart&#305;&#769;n, Cecilia Silva Cabrera, Daniel Gau, Enrique A. Dalchiele, Ricardo E. Marotti, Daniel Ram&#237;rez</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145149</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma surface treatment for enhanced supercapacitor and oxygen evolution reaction: Single-step preparation of carbon-coated nickel nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176644</link>
      <description>K. K. Lakshmanan, B. Narayanan, V. H., G. Shanmugavelayutham, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402829577

                No abstract</description>
      <author>K. K. Lakshmanan, B. Narayanan, V. H., G. Shanmugavelayutham</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176644</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical (Ni,Co)0.85Se Sheets for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalysis: A Combined Approach of Fabrication Control and Mechanistic Understanding</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04285a</link>
      <description>Muhammad Sohail Riaz, Qirui Huang, Jingjing Duan, Sheng Chen, Fuqiang Huang, Pedro F. Costa, Chemical Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402837050

                We present a fabrication process for hierarchical (Ni,Co)0.85Se sheets, achieving efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity with a 10 mA cm&#8722;2 current density at an overpotential of 290 mV. Porous...</description>
      <author>Muhammad Sohail Riaz, Qirui Huang, Jingjing Duan, Sheng Chen, Fuqiang Huang, Pedro F. Costa</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc04285a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Potential Electrocatalyst: Highly Multiporous WO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;rGO Nanocomposites for Enhancing Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202402770</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Mondal, P. C. Srivastava, Anand Prakash Singh, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Kotesh Kumar Mandari, ChemistrySelect. 9(36)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402839871

                Abstract The development of sustainable energy technologies, such as fuel cells and metal&#8211;air batteries, necessitates the use of a highly efficient electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution process. The fabrication of WO 3 &#8211;rGO nanocomposites results in the formation of a multiporous nanostructure. The catalytic activity of highly multiporous WO 3 &#8211;rGO nanocomposites containing multiporous nanostructures is shown to be significant. The catalyst has the potential to facilitate highly reactive anodic oxygen reactions, hence augmenting the synergistic impact of interfacial charge transfer and the porous structure of WO 3 &#8211;rGO nanocomposites. The findings of this work indicate that the use of WO 3 &#8211;rGO nanocomposites as electrocatalysts exhibits a considerable overpotential value of 350 mV, a Tafel slope of 67 mV dec &#8722;1 , good stability, roughness factor, and turnover frequency for the process of oxygen evolution in real&#8208;world scenarios.</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Mondal, P. C. Srivastava, Anand Prakash Singh, Amanullah Fatehmulla, Kotesh Kumar Mandari</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202402770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studies on Porous Nanostructured Palladium&#8211;Cobalt&#8211;Silica as Heterogeneous Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700344</link>
      <description>P.C. P&#225;ndey, Chetna Singh, Russian Journal of Electrochemistry. 60(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402840311

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P.C. P&#225;ndey, Chetna Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Triethanolamine-assisted surface reconstruction of nickel oxide for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00420e</link>
      <description>Jiayun Zhang, Ruth Knibbe, I. Gentle, Energy Advances. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402841563

                Developing low-cost and highly efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is highly desired for the renewable energy production. Ni-based electrocatalysts have been widely investigated as candidates for OER, but...</description>
      <author>Jiayun Zhang, Ruth Knibbe, I. Gentle</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ya00420e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Production of Hydrogen from an Overall Urea Splitting Reaction Using a Tri&#8208;Functional Scandium&#8211;Cobalt Electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405939</link>
      <description>S. Tamilarasi, Ramasamy Santhosh Kumar, Dong Jin Yoo, Hyun Jin Kim, Dong Jin Yoo, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402844573

                Abstract The creation of highly efficient and economical electrocatalysts is essential to the massive electrolysis of water to produce clean energy. The ability to use urea reaction of oxidation (UOR) in place of the oxygen/hydrogen evolution process (OER/HER) during water splitting is a significant step toward the production of high&#8208;purity hydrogen with less energy usage. Empirical evidence suggests that the UOR process consists of two stages. First, the metal sites undergo an electrochemical pre&#8208;oxidation reaction, and then the urea molecules on the high&#8208;valence metal sites are chemically oxidized. Here, the use of scandium&#8208;doped CoTe supported on carbon nanotubes called Sc@CoTe/CNT is reported and CoTe/CNT as a composite to efficiently promote hydrogen generation from highly durable and active electrocatalysts for the OER/UOR/HER in urea and alkali solutions. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy indicates that the UOR facilitates charge transfer across the interface. Furthermore, the Sc@CoTe/CNT nanocatalyst has high performance in KOH and KOH&#8208;containing urea solutions as demonstrated by the HER, OER, and UOR (215 mV, 1.59, and 1.31 V, respectively, at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH) and CoTe/CNT shows 195 mV, 1.61 and 1.3 V, respectively. Consequently, the total urea splitting system achieves 1.29 V, whereas the overall water splitting device obtaines 1.49 V of Sc@CoTe/CNT and CoTe/CNT shows 1.54, 1.48 V, respectively. This work presents a viable method of combining HER with UOR for maximally effective hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>S. Tamilarasi, Ramasamy Santhosh Kumar, Dong Jin Yoo, Hyun Jin Kim, Dong Jin Yoo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405939</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in the Synthesis of Transition Metal Hydroxyl Oxide Catalysts and Their Application in Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02400a</link>
      <description>Yan Feng, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Zhan Qi-Ni, Gao&#8208;Ren Li, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402851665

                With the extensive use of fossil energy, people will face the depletion of fossil energy and increasingly severe problems. As a non-polluting, high specific energy density energy source, hydrogen energy...</description>
      <author>Yan Feng, Huimin Xu, Chen&#8208;Jin Huang, Ting&#8208;Yu Shuai, Zhan Qi-Ni, Gao&#8208;Ren Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02400a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance Using Amorphous Hollow Cerium-Doped Cobalt Phosphate Derived from ZIF-67 Structures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176697</link>
      <description>Sina Maghool, Ali Akbar Asgharinezhad, Afsanehsadat Larimi, Cyrus Ghotbi, Farhad Khorasheh, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402851739

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sina Maghool, Ali Akbar Asgharinezhad, Afsanehsadat Larimi, Cyrus Ghotbi, Farhad Khorasheh</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176697</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iridium Single&#8208;Atom&#8208;Ensembles Stabilized on Mn&#8208;Substituted Spinel Oxide for Durable Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202401648</link>
      <description>Ashwani Kumar, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, Jinsun Lee, Viet Q. Bui, Yue Wang, Serena DeBeer, Min Gyu Kim, Serena DeBeer, Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402851866

                Abstract Exploring single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts for the acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is of paramount importance for cost&#8208;effective hydrogen production via acidic water electrolyzers. However, the limited durability of most single&#8208;atom&#8208;catalysts and Ir/Ru&#8208;based oxides under harsh acidic OER conditions, primarily attributed to excessive lattice oxygen participation resulting in metal&#8208;leaching and structural collapse, hinders their practical application. Herein, an innovative strategy is developed to fabricate short&#8208;range Ir single&#8208;atom&#8208;ensembles (Ir SAE ) stabilized on the surface of Mn&#8208;substituted spinel Co 3 O 4 (Ir SAE &#8208;CMO), which exhibits excellent mass activity and significantly improved durability (degradation&#8208;rate: &#8776;2 mV h &#8722;1 ), outperforming benchmark IrO 2 (&#8776;44 mV h &#8722;1 ) and conventional Ir single&#8208;atoms on pristine&#8208;Co 3 O 4 for acidic OER. First&#8208;principle calculations reveal that Mn&#8208;substitution in the octahedral sites of Co 3 O 4 substantially reduces the migration energy barrier for Ir single&#8208;atoms on the CMO surface compared to pristine&#8208;Co 3 O 4 , facilitating the migration of Ir single&#8208;atoms to form strongly correlated Ir SAE during pyrolysis. Extensive ex situ characterization, operando X&#8208;ray absorption and Raman spectroscopies, pH&#8208;dependence activity tests, and theoretical calculations indicate that the rigid Ir SAE with appropriate Ir&#8211;Ir distance stabilized on the CMO surface effectively suppresses lattice oxygen participation while promoting direct O&#9472;O radical coupling, thereby mitigating Ir&#8208;dissolution and structural collapse, boosting the stability in an acidic environment.</description>
      <author>Ashwani Kumar, Marcos Gil&#8208;Sepulcre, Jinsun Lee, Viet Q. Bui, Yue Wang, Serena DeBeer, Min Gyu Kim, Serena DeBeer, Harun T&#252;ys&#252;z</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202401648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of Nanoporous Materials as Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction&#8212;A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29194562</link>
      <description>Zhen Cao, Wenbin Zhang, Tingting Zhou, Wenhui Yan, Kaili Wang, Molecules. 29(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402854460

                With the growing demand for new energy sources, electrochemical water splitting for hydrogen production is a technology that must be vigorously promoted. Therefore, to improve the efficiency of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode, high-performance OER catalysts are essential. Given their advantages in electrocatalysis, nanoporous materials have garnered considerable attention in previous studies for OER applications. This review provides a comprehensive overview of various strategies to optimize active site utilization in nanoporous materials. These strategies include regulating pore size and porosity, constructing hierarchical nanoporous structures, and enhancing material conductivity. Additionally, it covers approaches to boost the intrinsic OER activity of nanoporous materials, such as tuning the composition of anions and cations, creating vacancies, constructing interfaces, and forming boundary active sites. While nanoporous materials offer significant potential for advancing OER, challenges remain, including difficulties in quantifying activity within nanopores, the unclear impact of nanoporous material morphology, challenges in accessing nanopore interiors with in situ techniques, and a lack of theoretical calculations on pore structure. However, these challenges also present opportunities, and we hope this review provides a fresh perspective to inspire future research.</description>
      <author>Zhen Cao, Wenbin Zhang, Tingting Zhou, Wenhui Yan, Kaili Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29194562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic Copper Complexes for Electrocatalytic Bidirectional O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Conversion in Aqueous Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401228</link>
      <description>Afsar Ali, Divyansh Prakash, Abhishek Saini, Chandan Das, Naseer Ahmed Shah, Arnab Dutta, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402855176

                Abstract The distinctive interplay between abundant transition metal&#8208;containing active sites and their surrounding outer coordination sphere (OCS) is pivotal in achieving remarkable catalytic responses. In this context, copper complexes continue to garner attention as promising catalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this article, we report two macrocyclic binuclear Cu complexes having variable peripheral functionalities around a common N 2 O 2 like core. A mononuclear complex bearing the salophen&#8208;type ligand design was used as a control. The complex featuring peripheral OH groups demonstrates the highest catalytic activity in ORR (3050 s &#8722;1 ) and OER (6700 s &#8722;1 ), suggesting the crucial role of the alcoholic group during catalysis. In contrast, the mononuclear complex necessitates an additional thermodynamic stimulus to attain catalytic conditions for ORR and OER obverse to the case of binuclear complexes. Hence, this study establishes a template for designing molecular catalysts to mediate energy&#8208;relevant multielectron/multiproton reactions in both oxidizing and reducing environments.</description>
      <author>Afsar Ali, Divyansh Prakash, Abhishek Saini, Chandan Das, Naseer Ahmed Shah, Arnab Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401228</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance with rGO/CoNi-Prussian Blue-Derived Oxyhydroxide Nanocomposite Electrocatalyst: A Strategic Synthetic Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09452</link>
      <description>Pedro H. S. Borges, Josu&#233; M. Gon&#231;alves, Carmel B. Breslin, Edson Nossol, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402855498

                Electrochemical water splitting is a promising approach in the development of renewable energy technologies, providing an alternative to fossil fuels. It has attracted considerable attention in recent years. The benchmark materials used in water splitting are precious metals that are expensive and scarce. Therefore, this work proposes a strategic electrochemical synthesis of a reduced graphene oxide and cobalt-nickel hexacyanoferrate (rGO/CoNiHCF)-derived composite (rGO/CoNiPBd-OOH) to achieve optimized OER performance. The optimum rGO/CoNiHCF was fabricated with the Co:Ni precursors in a 3:1 ratio with a ferricyanide solution of pH = 1.0. Using an alkaline electrochemical treatment, the well-distributed globular particles of CoNiHCF over rGO sheets were converted into layered frameworks of metallic (oxy)hydroxide species, giving the final rGO/CoNiPBd-OOH nanocomposite. This nanocomposite presented favorable kinetic activity resulting in a Tafel slope of 33 mV dec</description>
      <author>Pedro H. S. Borges, Josu&#233; M. Gon&#231;alves, Carmel B. Breslin, Edson Nossol</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c09452</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green mediated sol-gel synthesis of MxCu1-xO (M = La,Ce x = 0.02&#8211;0.06) as an efficient catalyst for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118677</link>
      <description>Elizabath Johnson, Anandhu Thejas Prasannakumar, R. Rohith, Raji R. Krishnan, Shine R. Chandran, K. H. Prema, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402858216

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elizabath Johnson, Anandhu Thejas Prasannakumar, R. Rohith, Raji R. Krishnan, Shine R. Chandran, K. H. Prema</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118677</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In situ&lt;/i&gt; construction of surface oxygen vacancies on N/TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for promoting visible light photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03098b</link>
      <description>Yuandong Shen, Yang Nan, Ke Wang, B.L. Xiao, Yijun He, Zhishi Qiu, Tong Zhou, Weijie Zhan, Rui Hu, Genlin Zhang, Qian Zhang, Zhonglin Zhu, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Qingju Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402862144

                A simple method of mixed sintering of thiourea and NH 2 -MIL-125(Ti) is adopted to obtain N-doped TiO 2 with abundant surface O V , which significantly improves the photocatalytic performance of TiO 2 under visible light.</description>
      <author>Yuandong Shen, Yang Nan, Ke Wang, B.L. Xiao, Yijun He, Zhishi Qiu, Tong Zhou, Weijie Zhan, Rui Hu, Genlin Zhang, Qian Zhang, Zhonglin Zhu, Feng Liu, Hao Cui, Qingju Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4tc03098b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flower-Shaped NiCo2S4 Microspheres for Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11449-3</link>
      <description>Ashish Gupta, Ashavani Kumar, Journal of Electronic Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402862892

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashish Gupta, Ashavani Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11449-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insight into Oxygen Transport in Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers by In Situ X&#8208;Ray Characterization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202405658</link>
      <description>P.W. Li, Zihan Zhou, Diankai Qiu, Linfa Peng, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402864300

                Abstract The proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer (PEMWE) is one of the most promising electrochemical energy conversion devices for hydrogen production, while still limited by performance bottlenecks at high current densities, due to the lack of mass transfer insights. To investigate the mechanisms of oxygen transport inside the PEMWE at high current density and its relation to electrolytic performance. Operational in situ x&#8208;ray imaging is utilized to simultaneously characterize the bubble behavior and voltage response in a novel designed visual mini&#8208;cell, and it is identified that oxygen evolution and transport in the PEMWE follow the process of bubble nucleation, growth, and detachment. Based on the results of mini&#8208;cells with three porous transport layers (PTLs) up to 9 A cm &#8722;2 operation, it revealed that critical current densities exist for both carbon&#8208;based and titanium&#8208;based PTLs. Once exceeding the critical current density, the cell voltage can no longer be stabilized and the cell exhibits a significant oxygen overpotential. To illustrate this, the concept of interfacial separation zone (ISZ) is first proposed, which is an effective pathway for bubble growth and separation and the pattern of the ISZ exhibits specific regimes with the critical current density. Ultimately, a new approach for better understanding the mechanisms of oxygen transport is revealed.</description>
      <author>P.W. Li, Zihan Zhou, Diankai Qiu, Linfa Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202405658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of H2O2 in Near-Neutral Zn-air Batteries Enables Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3k21g</link>
      <description>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402869936

                Rechargeable Zn-air batteries with near-neutral electrolytes hold promise as cheap, safe and sustainable devices, but they suffer from slow charge kinetics and remain poorly studied. Here we reveal a charge storage mechanism of near-neutral Zn-air batteries that is mediated by H2O2 formation upon cell discharge and its oxidation upon charge. The manifestation of this mechanism strongly depends on the electrolyte composition and positive electrode material, being pronounced when ZnSO4 solutions and carbon nanotubes are employed. Oxidation of dissolved H2O2 is facile, enabling oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at low potentials (~1.5 V vs. Zn2+/Zn) which, in contrast to conventional four-electron OER, does not induce corrosion of carbon electrodes. Facilitation of the H2O2-mediated pathway might therefore be helpful for developing high-performance near-neutral Zn-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3k21g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen and oxygen evolution using cobalt- substituted polyoxometalates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rechem.2024.101824</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Fang, Wenlong Sun, Results in Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402883678

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Fang, Wenlong Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rechem.2024.101824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of nickel nanoparticles anchored on a 2D double transition metal MXene for efficient hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.189</link>
      <description>Nagaraj Murugan, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, Priyadarshini Venkatachalam, Mrunal Bhosale, Min Seok Kang, Min Seo Yu, Tae Hwan Oh, Yoong Ahm Kim, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402884071

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nagaraj Murugan, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, Priyadarshini Venkatachalam, Mrunal Bhosale, Min Seok Kang, Min Seo Yu, Tae Hwan Oh, Yoong Ahm Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.189</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the synthesis of CoFe/CoFe2O4@NCNTs derived from ZnFeCo-ZIF with abundant heterostructures and oxygen vacancies as bifunctional catalyst for ORR/OER in zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113668</link>
      <description>Zheng Zhang, Mingjiao Yan, Zhe Xiong, Shijie Wang, Cuiqin Li, Journal of Energy Storage. 101(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402885038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zheng Zhang, Mingjiao Yan, Zhe Xiong, Shijie Wang, Cuiqin Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.113668</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design and Application of a Liquid Metal Ball-Supported Layered Double Hydroxide Core-Shell Structure as Highly Efficient Catalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Rechargeable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4968676</link>
      <description>Liqing Qiao, Wenwei Liu, Na Du, Wangwang Xu, Yankun Li, Haofeng Wu, Zhonghua Bao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402889971

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liqing Qiao, Wenwei Liu, Na Du, Wangwang Xu, Yankun Li, Haofeng Wu, Zhonghua Bao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4968676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction Performance on NiFe-Based Catalysts Through d-Orbital Hybridization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01528-9</link>
      <description>Xing Wang, Wei Pi, Sheng Hu, Haifeng Bao, Na Yao, Wei Wang, Nano-Micro Letters. 17(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402892165

                Abstract Anion-exchange membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWEs) for green hydrogen production have received intensive attention due to their feasibility of using earth-abundant NiFe-based catalysts. By introducing a third metal into NiFe-based catalysts to construct asymmetrical M-NiFe units, the d -orbital and electronic structures can be adjusted, which is an important strategy to achieve sufficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance in AEMWEs. Herein, the ternary NiFeM (M: La, Mo) catalysts featured with distinct M-NiFe units and varying d -orbitals are reported in this work. Experimental and theoretical calculation results reveal that the doping of La leads to optimized hybridization between d orbital in NiFeM and 2 p in oxygen, resulting in enhanced adsorption strength of oxygen intermediates, and reduced rate-determining step energy barrier, which is responsible for the enhanced OER performance. More critically, the obtained NiFeLa catalyst only requires 1.58 V to reach 1 A cm &#8722;2 in an anion exchange membrane electrolyzer and demonstrates excellent long-term stability of up to 600 h.</description>
      <author>Xing Wang, Wei Pi, Sheng Hu, Haifeng Bao, Na Yao, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01528-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the electronic structure of cobalt selenide by doping engineering for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135446</link>
      <description>ChaoLing Du, Xiaoguang Zhang, Baohua Jia, Chuanyu Feng, Lianwen Zhou, Da&#8208;Shuai Zhang, Lumin Wang, Bijiang Geng, Chuanqi Feng, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402897882

                No abstract</description>
      <author>ChaoLing Du, Xiaoguang Zhang, Baohua Jia, Chuanyu Feng, Lianwen Zhou, Da&#8208;Shuai Zhang, Lumin Wang, Bijiang Geng, Chuanqi Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.135446</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-S dually modulated adsorbate evolution and lattice oxygen compatible mechanism for water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52682-y</link>
      <description>Xu Luo, Hongyu Zhao, Xin Tan, Lin Sheng, Kesong Yu, Xueqin Mu, Zhenhua Tao, Pengxia Ji, Shichun Mu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402901029

                Simultaneously activating metal and lattice oxygen sites to construct a compatible multi-mechanism catalysis is expected for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by providing highly available active sites and mediate catalytic activity/stability, but significant challenges remain. Herein, Fe and S dually modulated NiFe oxyhydroxide (R-NiFeOOH@SO</description>
      <author>Xu Luo, Hongyu Zhao, Xin Tan, Lin Sheng, Kesong Yu, Xueqin Mu, Zhenhua Tao, Pengxia Ji, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52682-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sea urchin-like sulfur-doped Ni(OH)2 as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4988201/v1</link>
      <description>Fang Wu, Jinlong Ge, Yujun Zhu, Yuhong Jiao, Zhong Wu, F. Chen, Yupei Zhao, Lin Qiu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402903001

                Abstract The development of high-performance and cost-effective electrocatalysts toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is remarkably desirable but challenging. Herein, we design and fabricate a sea urchin-like S-doped Ni(OH)2 electrocatalyst on nickel foam using a simple hydrothermal method, followed by treatment with Na2S solution. The introduction of S not only modulates the electronic structure of Ni(OH)2, but also improve the electronic conductivity, thus enhancing the OER performance of Ni(OH)2. Owing to the free-standing feature, modified electronic structure and sea urchin-like structure, the optimized S-Ni(OH)2-30 min delivered excellent OER performance with overpotentials of 306 and 392 mV at 10 and 100 mA cm&#8722; 2, respectively, Tafel slope of 89.2 mV dec&#8722; 1 and stability for 12 h at 20 mA cm&#8722; 2. This work demonstrates the importance of incorporating S in Ni(OH)2 to optimize the electronic structure for improving OER activity and provides a promising pathway to synthesize Ni(OH)2-based electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Fang Wu, Jinlong Ge, Yujun Zhu, Yuhong Jiao, Zhong Wu, F. Chen, Yupei Zhao, Lin Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4988201/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quaternary layered double hydroxides from spent battery as electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.344</link>
      <description>Angga Hermawan, Nadia Sekar Rossestiningtyas Kinasih, Rizeni Radiana, Annas Nursyahid, Sri Rahayu, Dita Adi Saputra, Vinda Puspasari, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Andri Hardiansyah, Muhammad Dikdik Gumelar, Eniya Listiani Dewi, Muhammad Aziz, Shu Yin, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 89(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402906291

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Angga Hermawan, Nadia Sekar Rossestiningtyas Kinasih, Rizeni Radiana, Annas Nursyahid, Sri Rahayu, Dita Adi Saputra, Vinda Puspasari, Ni Luh Wulan Septiani, Andri Hardiansyah, Muhammad Dikdik Gumelar, Eniya Listiani Dewi, Muhammad Aziz, Shu Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.09.344</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A(CoFe)(S2)2/CoFe heterostructure constructed in S, N co-doped carbon nanotubes as an efficient oxygen electrocatalyst for zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.213</link>
      <description>Bowen Yuan, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Xin Meng, Jiahao Xie, Yidong Song, Peng Gu, Yanjie Chen, Chunmiao Han, Jinlong Zou, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402908091

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bowen Yuan, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Xin Meng, Jiahao Xie, Yidong Song, Peng Gu, Yanjie Chen, Chunmiao Han, Jinlong Zou</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regular-Hexahedron-Shaped Ion-Copper Bimetallic Oxides Engineered on the Plasma-Treated Ion Foam for a Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution in an Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4970079</link>
      <description>Ziyan Wang, GL Chen, Yingchun Guo, Tongtong Li, Bin He, Peisong Tang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402909219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ziyan Wang, GL Chen, Yingchun Guo, Tongtong Li, Bin He, Peisong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4970079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discarded Pen Spring-Supported Cobalt-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Catalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4969832</link>
      <description>Chandra Sekhar S, Bhimanaboina Ramulu, Junied Arbaz Junied Shaik, Jae Su Yu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402914247

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chandra Sekhar S, Bhimanaboina Ramulu, Junied Arbaz Junied Shaik, Jae Su Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4969832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Secondary Template Strategy for Synthesis of Hierarchical Porous Carbon-Hosted Single-Atomic Fenx and Coo Towards Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction Reaction and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4969837</link>
      <description>Hao Song, Xue Liu, Jie Song, Zhuang Shi, Zhen Fu, Feng Hao, Hongyan Zhuo, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402914507

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Song, Xue Liu, Jie Song, Zhuang Shi, Zhen Fu, Feng Hao, Hongyan Zhuo, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4969837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Porous Amorphous High Entropy Oxide Coated Dimensionally Stable Anode for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4969524</link>
      <description>Wushuai Dai, Cong Wang, Keyi Li, Wei Wang, Yunlong Bai, Jia Li, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402919774

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wushuai Dai, Cong Wang, Keyi Li, Wei Wang, Yunlong Bai, Jia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4969524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Fe,Ce doping of Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02187h</link>
      <description>Yu He, Kefan Shi, Xueqin Wang, Xingzi Zheng, Lanke Luo, Liu Lin, Zemin Sun, Genban Sun, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402920142

                Fe,Ce-Ni 3 S 2 @NF nanoneedle catalysts synthesised via a one-step hydrothermal route showed good OER performance.</description>
      <author>Yu He, Kefan Shi, Xueqin Wang, Xingzi Zheng, Lanke Luo, Liu Lin, Zemin Sun, Genban Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi02187h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing Multi&#8208;Asymmetric Engineering: A New Horizon in Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysis with Iron&#8208;Group Atom&#8208;Cluster Nanohybrid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202414379</link>
      <description>Qiaoling Xu, Lei Zhang, Luhan Li, Shijing Zhang, Yingtang Zhou, Guangzhi Hu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402920365

                Abstract Integrating active sites for oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR and OER) is pivotal for advancing bifunctional oxygen electrodes. Addressing the geometric/electronic properties of these sites is essential to disrupt the linear scaling relationship between the adsorption and desorption of complex intermediates. Herein, a proof&#8208;of&#8208;concept is presented for constructing asymmetric trinuclear sites employing both composition&#8208; and size&#8208;based asymmetric coupling strategies. These sites comprise ORR&#8208;active Fe single atom (Fe SA ), OER&#8208;active atomically clustered Fe species (Fe AC ), and Ni SA sites as modulators. This Fe AC&#8208;SA &#8208;Ni SA @N&#8208;doped carbon exhibits excellent bifunctional catalytic activities, with a narrow potential gap of 0.661 V between an ORR half&#8208;wave potential of 0.931 V and an OER potential of 1.592 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . The Zn&#8208;air battery employing this material achieves a peak power density of 293 mW cm &#8722;2 , a specific capacity of 748 mAh g Zn &#8722;1 , and remarkable stability. Experimental findings and theoretical simulations reveal that Ni SA sites induced strong electronic coupling among the trinuclear centers, facilitating charge redistribution and optimizing the adsorption and desorption barriers for intermediates. This enhances the rapid release of * OH during ORR and the efficient transformation from * O to * OOH during OER. This study presents a novel strategy for developing robust bifunctional oxygen electrodes.</description>
      <author>Qiaoling Xu, Lei Zhang, Luhan Li, Shijing Zhang, Yingtang Zhou, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202414379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical Insights into Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution on Se-Doped TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04841</link>
      <description>Niranji Thilini Ekanayake, Nicholas J. Mosey, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402921973

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Niranji Thilini Ekanayake, Nicholas J. Mosey</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04841</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Concurrent oxygen evolution reaction pathways revealed by high-speed compressive Raman imaging</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52536-7</link>
      <description>Raj Pandya, Florian Dorchies, Davide Romanin, Jean&#8208;Fran&#231;ois Lemineur, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Kanoufi, Sylvain Gigan, Alex W. Chin, Hilton B. de Aguiar, Alexis Grimaud, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402922965

                Abstract Transition metal oxides are state-of-the-art materials for catalysing the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), whose slow kinetics currently limit the efficiency of water electrolysis. However, microscale physicochemical heterogeneity between particles, dynamic reactions both in the bulk and at the surface, and an interplay between particle reactivity and electrolyte makes probing the OER challenging. Here, we overcome these limitations by applying state-of-the-art compressive Raman imaging to uncover concurrent bias-dependent pathways for the OER in a dense, crystalline electrocatalyst, &#945;-Li 2 IrO 3 . By spatially and temporally tracking changes in stretching modes we follow catalytic activation and charge accumulation following ion exchange under various electrolytes and cycling conditions, comparing our observations with other crystalline catalysts (IrO 2 , LiCoO 2 ). We demonstrate that at low overpotentials the reaction between water and the oxidized catalyst surface is compensated by bulk ion exchange, as usually only found for amorphous, electrolyte permeable, catalysts. At high overpotentials the charge is compensated by surface redox active sites, as in other crystalline catalysts such as IrO 2 . Hence, our work reveals charge compensation can extend beyond the surface in crystalline catalysts. More generally, the results highlight the power of compressive Raman imaging for chemically specific tracking of microscale reaction dynamics in catalysts, battery materials, or memristors.</description>
      <author>Raj Pandya, Florian Dorchies, Davide Romanin, Jean&#8208;Fran&#231;ois Lemineur, Fr&#233;d&#233;ric Kanoufi, Sylvain Gigan, Alex W. Chin, Hilton B. de Aguiar, Alexis Grimaud</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52536-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of multiple heterogeneous interfaces and oxygen evolution reaction of hollow CoFe bimetallic phosphides derived from MOF template</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.09.001</link>
      <description>Haiqi Zhang, Qingqing Zhang, Xiaojun Zeng, Progress in Natural Science Materials International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402923922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haiqi Zhang, Qingqing Zhang, Xiaojun Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pnsc.2024.09.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Cation Deficiency and the Inductive Effect in Ti-Doped NiO for Developing Superior Electrocatalysts for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01774</link>
      <description>Shree Prakash Jaiswal, Vaishali Soni, Preetam Singh, Asha Gupta, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402928472

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shree Prakash Jaiswal, Vaishali Soni, Preetam Singh, Asha Gupta</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01774</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isomerization of Covalent Organic Frameworks for Efficiently Activating Molecular Oxygen and Promoting Hydrogen Peroxide Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406527</link>
      <description>Xiaogang Wang, Qian Zhang, Hongqi Chu, Zhen Zhan, Yong Du, Zhenzi Li, Xuepeng Wang, Fu&#8208;Quan Bai, Wei Zhou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402929372

                Abstract Constitutional&#8208;isomerized covalent organic frameworks (COFs), constructed by swapping monomers around imine bonds, have attracted attention for their distinct optoelectronic properties, which significantly impact photocatalytic performance. However, limited research has delved into the inherent relationship between isomerization and the enhancement of H 2 O 2 photosynthesis. Herein, a pair of isomeric COFs linked by imine bonds (PB&#8208;PT&#8208;COF and PT&#8208;PB&#8208;COF) is synthesized, and it is proved that isomeric COFs exhibit different rate&#8208;determining steps in the generation process of H 2 O 2 , resulting in a twofold increase in photocatalytic efficiency. Specifically, PT&#8208;PB&#8208;COF demonstrates effective adsorption and activation of molecular oxygen (O 2 + e &#8722; &#8594; &#8226;O 2 &#8722; + e &#8722; &#8594; H 2 O 2 ), leading to a significant improvement in H 2 O 2 photocatalytic efficiency. In contrast, PB&#8208;PT&#8208;COF exhibits robust interaction with H 2 O, enabling direct oxidation of H 2 O (H 2 O + h + &#8594; H 2 O 2 ). This study provides a thorough understanding of the intrinsic mechanism underlying the constitutional&#8208;isomerized COFs in the photocatalytic H 2 O 2 generation, offering insights for further optimizing building units.</description>
      <author>Xiaogang Wang, Qian Zhang, Hongqi Chu, Zhen Zhan, Yong Du, Zhenzi Li, Xuepeng Wang, Fu&#8208;Quan Bai, Wei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202406527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Coordination Fields of Asymmetric MO&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;&#8208;Type Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks Catalysts for Accelerated Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413856</link>
      <description>Tengjia Ni, Xianbiao Hou, Jian Zhou, Canhui Zhang, Shuixing Dai, Lei Chu, Huanlei Wang, Heqing Jiang, Minghua Huang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402929464

                Abstract Asymmetric coordination has emerged as a promising approach to enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, yet achieving a controlled synthesis of asymmetric structures to comprehensively understand the structure&#8208;activity relationship remains challenging. In this study, a facile and effective symmetry&#8208;breaking strategy is reported for tailoring the asymmetric MO 5 S 1 &#8208;type metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) catalyst, establishing the correlation between the sulfur (S)&#8208;mediated electron rearrangement and the adsorption/desorption dynamics of oxygen&#8208;related intermediates in OER. Experimental and theoretical calculations reveal that a well&#8208;designed asymmetric structure can effectively lower the d&#8208;band center, optimizing the adsorption behavior of OH * and significantly decreasing the reaction energy barrier for the rate&#8208;determining step (OH * &#8594; O * ) with enhanced O&#8211;H bond cleavage process. The S&#8208;NiFe&#8208;MOF/CFP catalyst demonstrates a remarkable OER performance in an alkaline electrolyte environment. More importantly, the self&#8208;assembled anion exchange membrane water electrolysis cell showcases a low voltage of 1.84 V to deliver the current density of 1 A cm &#8722;2 , maintaining long&#8208;term stability for over 100 h. This study unveils a precise asymmetric synthesis strategy employing S, highlighting the critical role of manipulating electron redistribution through asymmetric coordination to promote catalytic activity and develop advanced MOF&#8208;based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tengjia Ni, Xianbiao Hou, Jian Zhou, Canhui Zhang, Shuixing Dai, Lei Chu, Huanlei Wang, Heqing Jiang, Minghua Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202413856</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4 &lt;/sub&gt;as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/11405.0545ecst</link>
      <description>Rajangam Vinodh, Shankara S. Kalanur, Bruno G. Pollet, ECS Transactions. 114(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402930996

                Electrocatalysts derived from earth-abundant transition metals offer a viable alternative to noble metals for water electrolysis, yet they often suffer from poor catalytic behaviour and limited lifespan. In this study, nanostructured nickel molybdate on nickel foam (NiMoO 4 /NF) were synthesized via a straightforward hydrothermal process at three different durations (6, 12, and 24 h) to assess their oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. The electrodes, specifically NiMoO 4 -6h, NiMoO 4 -12h, and NiMoO 4 -24h, demonstrated significant OER activity in 1.0 M KOH solution, achieving overpotentials of 315 mV, 290 mV and 320 mV for respectively. Notably, the NiMoO 4 -12h electrode showed an exceptional stability, with only a 1.28% activity decrease after 200 hours at a current density of 10 mA cm -2 . This study presents a novel approach to enhancing the electrocatalytic efficiency of these catalysts through optimizing their electrical conductivity, active surface sites, and surface reaction dynamics.</description>
      <author>Rajangam Vinodh, Shankara S. Kalanur, Bruno G. Pollet</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/11405.0545ecst</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Evolution Behavior of Ni-Containing Alloy Electrodes in NaOH&#8211;KOH Hydrate Melt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/11406.0053ecst</link>
      <description>Kenji Kawaguchi, Toshiyuki Nohira, ECS Transactions. 114(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402931234

                We investigated the oxygen evolution behavior of nine types of commercially available Ni-containing alloys in a NaOH&#8211;KOH hydrate melt. The oxygen overpotential of all Ni-containing alloys was lower than that of the Ni electrode (453 mV) at 500 mA cm &#8211;2 and 150&#176;C. The Kovar (Fe&#8211;Ni&#8211;Co alloy) electrode exhibited the lowest oxygen overpotentials of 280 mV at 150&#176;C and 227 mV at 200&#176;C. The Tafel slope of the Kovar electrode at 150&#176;C was 63 mV dec &#8211;1 , which was slightly lower than that of the Ni electrode (67 mV dec &#8211;1 ). The upper limit of the Tafel region for the Kovar electrode was extended to a higher current density of 300 mA cm &#8211;2 compared to that for the Ni electrode (100 mA cm &#8211;2 ) at 150&#176;C. It further extended to 1000 mA cm &#8211;2 at 200&#176;C, indicating that highly efficient water electrolysis can be expected.</description>
      <author>Kenji Kawaguchi, Toshiyuki Nohira</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/11406.0053ecst</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4 &lt;/sub&gt;as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/11405.0531ecst</link>
      <description>Rajangam Vinodh, Shankara S. Kalanur, Bruno G. Pollet, ECS Transactions. 114(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402931522

                Electrocatalysts derived from earth-abundant transition metals offer a viable alternative to noble metals for water electrolysis, yet they often suffer from poor catalytic behaviour and limited lifespan. In this study, nanostructured nickel molybdate on nickel foam (NiMoO 4 /NF) were synthesized via a straightforward hydrothermal process at three different durations (6, 12, and 24 h) to assess their oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. The electrodes, specifically NiMoO 4 -6h, NiMoO 4 -12h, and NiMoO 4 -24h, demonstrated significant OER activity in 1.0 M KOH solution, achieving overpotentials of 315 mV, 290 mV and 320 mV for respectively. Notably, the NiMoO 4 -12h electrode showed an exceptional stability, with only a 1.28% activity decrease after 200 hours at a current density of 10 mA cm -2 . This study presents a novel approach to enhancing the electrocatalytic efficiency of these catalysts through optimizing their electrical conductivity, active surface sites, and surface reaction dynamics.</description>
      <author>Rajangam Vinodh, Shankara S. Kalanur, Bruno G. Pollet</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/11405.0531ecst</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Oxygen Evolution: The Impact of Hetero Atom Doping on NiFe-Based Pre-Catalysts and Their Transformation into Ultrathin Layered Double Hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21275/sr24924124936</link>
      <description>Manoj Kumar, Raghvendra Singh, International Journal of Science and Research (IJSR). 13(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402939337

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Manoj Kumar, Raghvendra Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21275/sr24924124936</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The role of ERFVIIs as oxygen-sensing transducers in the evolution of land plant response to hypoxia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.27.615240</link>
      <description>Laura Dalle Carbonare, Hans van Veen, Vinay Shukla, Monica Perri, Liem T. Bui, Michael J. Holdsworth, Francesco Licausi, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402939594

                The transcriptional response to low oxygen (hypoxia) in the flowering plant Arabidopsis thaliana is transduced through group VII Ethylene Response Factor (ERFVII) transcription factors, whose proteolysis is oxygen-dependent via the PLANT CYSTEINE OXIDASE (PCO) N-degron pathway. When and how this response to hypoxia evolved in land plants remains unknown. Here we investigated the conservation and divergence of transcriptional responses to hypoxia in major land plant clades. We identified induction of gene functions associated with glycolysis and fermentation as part of a conserved response across all land plant divisions. Our results indicate that ERFVIIs appeared in the last common ancestor of vascular plants with true roots, concurrently with oxygen-dependent destabilisation, to regulate hypoxia-adaptive genes. Proteins from other ERF groups have been recruited multiple times in different clades as substrates of the PCO N-degron pathway. Our results demonstrate that the response of land plants to hypoxia has been refined in derived clades through the evolution of ERFVIIs as transcriptional transducers, that occurred concomitantly with the appearance of vascular systems and roots as foraging systems through hypoxic soil.</description>
      <author>Laura Dalle Carbonare, Hans van Veen, Vinay Shukla, Monica Perri, Liem T. Bui, Michael J. Holdsworth, Francesco Licausi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.27.615240</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancies-Enriched Manganese Dioxide/Carbon Nanotubes Enabling High-Energy Aqueous Ammonium-Ion Hybrid Supercapacitors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4970431</link>
      <description>Miaomiao Xie, Junsen Zhong, Hanbing Wang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Menghan Li, Litao Kang, Lingyu Du, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402940847

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Miaomiao Xie, Junsen Zhong, Hanbing Wang, &#1041;&#1086; &#1051;&#1102;, Menghan Li, Litao Kang, Lingyu Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4970431</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TiO2 nanotubes as enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction catalyst for water splitting in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsurfi.2024.100312</link>
      <description>V.S.Jim Abish, A. Charles HepzyRoy, D. Jonas Davidson, D. Henry Raja, P. Sakthivel, Results in Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402945689

                No abstract</description>
      <author>V.S.Jim Abish, A. Charles HepzyRoy, D. Jonas Davidson, D. Henry Raja, P. Sakthivel</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsurfi.2024.100312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effective Oxygen&#8208;Deficient Li&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;Ti&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; Anode Material Displaying Excellent Rate Performance and Outstanding Cyclic Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403479</link>
      <description>Parakandy Muzhikara Pratheeksha, S. Sivakanali, Shreyas J. Kashyap, Gyanesh Chandra, D. Paul Joseph, R. Vijay, Tata N. Rao, Srinivasan Anandan, ChemistrySelect. 9(37)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402948573

                Abstract Currently, developing materials with high power capability is crucial to the rapid deployment of electric vehicles. The Li 4 Ti 5 O 12 (LTO) anode material with zero strain rate upon lithium insertion and extraction. The successful implementation of this anode material depends on strategies to overcome the low electronic and ionic conductivity. In this study, Li 4 Ti 5 O 12 was synthesized using solid&#8208;state approach in which different phases (anatase and rutile) of TiO 2 as precursors were used. X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and Raman analysis confirmed the formation of oxygen vacancies with the existence of Ti 3+ ions, which is believed to greatly enhance the electronic conductivity of Li 4 Ti 5 O 12 . The electrochemical performance revealed that the rutile TiO 2 precursor concentration significantly affects the resultant Li 4 Ti 5 O 12 capacity and power capability. The Li 4 Ti 5 O 12 synthesized using 80% anatase and 20% rutile TiO 2 (N2&#8208;LTO) exhibits a specific capacity of 169, 145, 140, 133, 122, 101, and 84 mAh g &#8722;1 at 1C, 3C, 5C, 7C, 10C, 20C, and 30C. In addition, LFP||N2&#8208;LTO pouch&#8208;cell was fabricated which showed promising results with 95% capacity retention after 1000 cycles at 1C rate. The oxygen vacancies created due to the presence of Ti 3+ /Ti 4+ mixed valances and reduced particle size for faster lithium&#8208;ion diffusion significantly enhanced the overall electrochemical performance.</description>
      <author>Parakandy Muzhikara Pratheeksha, S. Sivakanali, Shreyas J. Kashyap, Gyanesh Chandra, D. Paul Joseph, R. Vijay, Tata N. Rao, Srinivasan Anandan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>{Co4O4} Cubanes in a conducting polymer matrix as bio-inspired molecular oxygen evolution catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52514-z</link>
      <description>Shangkun Li, Zeyi Zhang, Walker R. Marks, Xinan Huang, Hang Chen, Dragos Stoian, Rolf Erni, Carlos A. Triana, Greta R. Patzke, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402952433

                Exploration of efficient molecular water oxidation catalysts for long-term application remains a key challenge for the conversion of renewable energy sources into fuels. Cuboidal {Co</description>
      <author>Shangkun Li, Zeyi Zhang, Walker R. Marks, Xinan Huang, Hang Chen, Dragos Stoian, Rolf Erni, Carlos A. Triana, Greta R. Patzke</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52514-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spinel-type calcium manganese oxide adorned on g-CN composite: A highly proficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111629</link>
      <description>Zarghuna Firdous, A. Alhadhrami, Khursheed Ahmad, Muhammad Arslan Aslam, Mohamed M. Ibrahim, Abdulraheem S. A. Almalki, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy, Diamond and Related Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402955853

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zarghuna Firdous, A. Alhadhrami, Khursheed Ahmad, Muhammad Arslan Aslam, Mohamed M. Ibrahim, Abdulraheem S. A. Almalki, Zeinhom M. El&#8208;Bahy</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.diamond.2024.111629</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Passivation of Mn2+&#8208;Doped CsPbX3(X=Cl,Br) Perovskite Nanocrystals as Electriccatalyst for Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400798</link>
      <description>Haiyun Zhou, Pingping Li, Tingting Zhong, Yang Teng, Siqi Li, Xiaofeng Luo, Sheng Wang, Min Yang, Guowei Deng, Chemistry - An Asian Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402964302

                Mn:CsPbX3 (X= Cl, Br) nanosheets with excellent electrocatalytic properties are reported in this paper. Compared to conventional catalyst arrays, the band gap of Mn:CsPbBr3 nanocrystalline is easily tuned, the carrier diffusion distance is remote, the band edge position of the band structure is favorable for a wide range of electrocatalytic redox reactions, and the catalytic active site is maximally exposed. The Mn:CsPbBr3 exhibited preferable electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution (HER) performance in 1 mol/L KOH. The excess potential of the oxygen evolution reaction(OER) required to drive current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8208;2 is only 114.4 and 505.4 mV, with a Tafel slope of 43 mV dec&#8208;1. At a current density of 10 mA cm&#8208;2, the excess potential required for the HER is 158.6 mV and it exhibited excellent electrochemical stability. The Mn:CsPbBr3 nanocrystalline consists of two electrodes for the overall water splitting, requiring a voltage of only 1.45 V. Which in turn provides implications for the optimization of electrocatalysts in alkaline electrolytes with the aim of developing the next generation of 2D electrocatalysts for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Haiyun Zhou, Pingping Li, Tingting Zhong, Yang Teng, Siqi Li, Xiaofeng Luo, Sheng Wang, Min Yang, Guowei Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/asia.202400798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetal Metaphosphate/Molybdenum Oxide Heterostructure Nanowires for Boosting Overall Freshwater/Seawater Splitting at High Current Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407892</link>
      <description>Pan Wang, Pan Wang, Tongwei Wu, Xuping Sun, Yanning Zhang, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402967691

                Abstract Exploring excellent non&#8208;noble bifunctional electrocatalysts for freshwater/seawater splitting at high current densities has attracted extensive interest owing to strong anodic oxidation and severe chloride corrosion challenges. Herein, hierarchical bimetal Ni&#8208;Co metaphosphate/molybdenum oxide heterostructure nanowires (NiCoMoPO) are rationally designed and fabricated to efficiently boost oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in alkaline freshwater/seawater, where the favorable electronic structure from heterostructures, signified by X&#8208;ray absorption spectra, endows NiCoMoPO with the enhanced intrinsic activity, while its hierarchical nanowire structure and heterostructures provide abundant active sites. Additionally, the PO 3 &#8722; improves the chloride&#8208;corrosion resistance and efficiently facilitates the OER kinetics verified by theoretical and experimental studies. Therefore, NiCoMoPO drives 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 at low overpotentials of 467 and 442 mV for OER and HER in alkaline freshwater respectively, as well as a small cell voltage of 2.135 V for overall freshwater splitting with robust durability of 300 h. Impressively, due to the strong corrosion resistance, at 500 mA cm &#8722;2 of overall seawater splitting, NiCoMoPO maintains almost 2.096 V for 1200 h, indicating promising practical applications. This work sheds light on the rational design and fabrication of outstanding electrocatalysts at high current densities of seawater/freshwater splitting.</description>
      <author>Pan Wang, Pan Wang, Tongwei Wu, Xuping Sun, Yanning Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202407892</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring of Zinc Oxide-based microstructures to efficiently promote piezocatalytic water oxidation and oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114312</link>
      <description>Paola Semeraro, Rosanna Pagano, Donato Valli, Michela Ottolini, Sudipto Pal, Johan Hofkens, Maarten B. J. Roeffaers, Gabriele Giancane, Salvatore Sortino, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402968254

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Paola Semeraro, Rosanna Pagano, Donato Valli, Michela Ottolini, Sudipto Pal, Johan Hofkens, Maarten B. J. Roeffaers, Gabriele Giancane, Salvatore Sortino</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrathin B:NiCoOx-modified BiVO4 photoanode with abundant oxygen vacancies for photoelectrochemical glycerol conversion coupled with hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156324</link>
      <description>Zihu Kang, Yue Zheng, Haotong Li, Yujie Shen, Wanru Zhang, Meilan Huang, Xia Tao, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402970418

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zihu Kang, Yue Zheng, Haotong Li, Yujie Shen, Wanru Zhang, Meilan Huang, Xia Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3d-Orbital Overlap Modulated D-Band Center of High-Entropy Oxyhydroxide for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972232</link>
      <description>Shaobing Tang, Shuang Wei, Yujun Wu, Zhichao Jia, Zhengyu Bai, Lin Yang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402970947

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaobing Tang, Shuang Wei, Yujun Wu, Zhichao Jia, Zhengyu Bai, Lin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nano-Etched Silver Electrodes Loaded with Iron/Cobalt Catalysts for Enhanced Plasmon-Induced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972231</link>
      <description>Jian Wu, Zehua Dong, Yiming Niu, Xuguang Chen, Yuchuan Cheng, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402970948

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jian Wu, Zehua Dong, Yiming Niu, Xuguang Chen, Yuchuan Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First principles study of V2CT2-based MXenes materials in oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118686</link>
      <description>Wang Zhang, Shanmin Gao, Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Zhongzhou Dong, Journal of Electroanalytical Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402973557

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wang Zhang, Shanmin Gao, Xinyu Yang, Long Lin, Zhongzhou Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118686</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel N-Doped Biomass Carbon Spheres Loaded with In-Situ Grown Feco Layered Double Hydroxide for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972166</link>
      <description>Chong Cai, Ningzhao Shang, Danhua Sun, Li Wang, Yufan Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402974013

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chong Cai, Ningzhao Shang, Danhua Sun, Li Wang, Yufan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4972166</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction via a Surface Reconstruction-Induced Lattice Oxygen Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03594</link>
      <description>Subin Choi, Sejun Kim, Sunghoon Han, Jian Wang, Juwon Kim, Bonho Koo, Alexander A. Ryabin, Sebastian Kunze, Hyejeong Hyun, Jeongwoo Han, Shu-Chih Haw, Keun Hwa Chae, Chang Hyuck Choi, Hyungjun Kim, Jongwoo Lim, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402976597

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Subin Choi, Sejun Kim, Sunghoon Han, Jian Wang, Juwon Kim, Bonho Koo, Alexander A. Ryabin, Sebastian Kunze, Hyejeong Hyun, Jeongwoo Han, Shu-Chih Haw, Keun Hwa Chae, Chang Hyuck Choi, Hyungjun Kim, Jongwoo Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c03594</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-Doped Fe&#8211;N&#8211;C/Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;C Nanosheets as an Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalyst under Alkaline and Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04024</link>
      <description>Luyan Wang, Xili Liu, Keke Su, Wenfeng Liu, Fuquan Niu, Xiangnan Li, Hongyun Yue, Hongyu Dong, Shuting Yang, Yanhong Yin, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402977655

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Luyan Wang, Xili Liu, Keke Su, Wenfeng Liu, Fuquan Niu, Xiangnan Li, Hongyun Yue, Hongyu Dong, Shuting Yang, Yanhong Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Axial modulation of catalysis mechanism via charge-asymmetric for enhanced electrocatalytic performance toward hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129934</link>
      <description>Bin Wang, Tianmin Zhang, Wang Gui, Xiyue Han, Xingqun Zheng, Guangtao Mao, Qingmei Wang, Separation and Purification Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402979999

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bin Wang, Tianmin Zhang, Wang Gui, Xiyue Han, Xingqun Zheng, Guangtao Mao, Qingmei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.129934</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structure&#8211;Activity Relationships in Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408139</link>
      <description>Jingqi Guan, Jingru Sun, Siyu Chen, Siying Zhang, Luoluo Qi, Anaer Husile, Jingqi Guan, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402994393

                Abstract Oxygen electrocatalysis, as the pivotal circle of many green energy technologies, sets off a worldwide research boom in full swing, while its large kinetic obstacles require remarkable catalysts to break through. Here, based on summarizing reaction mechanisms and in situ characterizations, the structure&#8211;activity relationships of oxygen electrocatalysts are emphatically overviewed, including the influence of geometric morphology and chemical structures on the electrocatalytic performances. Subsequently, experimental/theoretical research is combined with device applications to comprehensively summarize the cutting&#8208;edge oxygen electrocatalysts according to various material categories. Finally, future challenges are forecasted from the perspective of catalyst development and device applications, favoring researchers to promote the industrialization of oxygen electrocatalysis at an early date.</description>
      <author>Jingqi Guan, Jingru Sun, Siyu Chen, Siying Zhang, Luoluo Qi, Anaer Husile, Jingqi Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Formation of H2O2 in Near-Neutral Zn-air Batteries Enables Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3k21g-v2</link>
      <description>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402996465

                Rechargeable Zn-air batteries with near-neutral electrolytes hold promise as cheap, safe and sustainable devices, but they suffer from slow charge kinetics and remain poorly studied. Here we reveal a charge storage mechanism of near-neutral Zn-air batteries that is mediated by H2O2 formation upon cell discharge and its oxidation upon charge. The manifestation of this mechanism strongly depends on the electrolyte composition and positive electrode material, being pronounced when ZnSO4 solutions and carbon nanotubes are employed. Oxidation of dissolved H2O2 is facile, enabling oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at low potentials (~1.5 V vs. Zn2+/Zn) which, in contrast to conventional four-electron OER, does not induce corrosion of carbon electrodes. Facilitation of the H2O2-mediated pathway might therefore be helpful for developing high-performance near-neutral Zn-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Roman R. Kapaev, Nicole Leifer, Alagar Raja Kottaichamy, Amit Ohayon, Langyuan Wu, Menny Shalom, Malachi Noked</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-3k21g-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mn&#9472;O Covalency as a Lever for Na&#8314; Intercalation Kinetics: The Role of Oxygen Edge&#8208;Sharing Co Octahedral Sites in MnO&#8322;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407690</link>
      <description>Yuanming Liu, Weijie Fu, Shuyun Yao, Shiyu Wang, Yingjie Ji, Jingxian Li, Lanlan Shi, Sheng Wang, Feike Zhang, Jing Wang, Renhuai Liu, Jiangzhou Xie, Zhiyu Yang, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402999596

                Abstract The strategic enhancement of manganese&#8211;oxygen (Mn&#9472;O) covalency is a promising approach to improve the intercalation kinetics of sodium ions (Na&#8314;) in manganese dioxide (MnO 2 ). In this study, an augmenting Mn&#9472;O covalency in MnO 2 by strategically incorporating cobalt at oxygen edge&#8208;sharing Co octahedral sites is focused on. Both experimental results and density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal an increased electron polarization from oxygen to manganese, surpassing that directed toward cobalt, thereby facilitating enhanced electron transfer and strengthening covalency. The synthesized Co&#8211;MnO 2 material exhibits outstanding electrochemical performance, demonstrating a superior specific capacitance of 388 F g &#8722;1 at 1 A g &#8722;1 and maintaining 97.21% capacity retention after 12000 cycles. Additionally, an asymmetric supercapacitor constructed using Co&#8211;MnO 2 achieved a high energy density of 35 Wh kg &#8722;1 at a power density of 1000 W kg &#8722;1 , underscoring the efficacy of this material in practical applications. This work highlights the critical role of transition metal&#8211;oxygen interactions in optimizing electrode materials and introduces a robust approach to enhance the functional properties of manganese oxides, thereby advancing high&#8208;performance energy storage technologies.</description>
      <author>Yuanming Liu, Weijie Fu, Shuyun Yao, Shiyu Wang, Yingjie Ji, Jingxian Li, Lanlan Shi, Sheng Wang, Feike Zhang, Jing Wang, Renhuai Liu, Jiangzhou Xie, Zhiyu Yang, Yi&#8208;Ming Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407690</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing oxygen evolution promoting hole defect states at BiVO4 surface for enhanced photoelectrochemical activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.09.009</link>
      <description>Fatima Chmali, Basanth S. Kalanoor, Shankara S. Kalanur, Bruno G. Pollet, Nano Materials Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403000453

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fatima Chmali, Basanth S. Kalanoor, Shankara S. Kalanur, Bruno G. Pollet</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.09.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological Synthesis of 2D High&#8208;Entropy Multimetallic (Oxy)hydroxide for Enhanced Lattice Oxygen Oxidation Mechanism</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409530</link>
      <description>Sijia Liu, Baorui Jia, Sheng Wang, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Fengmei Fan, Yunpu Qin, Jianfang Liu, Yirui Jiang, Bin Sun, Hong Zhao, Hao Li, Wenxiang Zhou, Haoyang Wu, Deyin Zhang, Xuanhui Qu, Mingli Qin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403002748

                Abstract Owing to sluggish reaction kinetics and high potential, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts face a trade&#8208;off between activity and stability. Herein, an innovative topological strategy is presented for preparing 2D multimetallic (oxy)hydroxide, including ternary CoFeZn, quaternary CoFeMnZn, and high&#8208;entropy CoFeMnCuZn. The key to the synthesis lies in using Ca&#8208;rich brownmillerite oxide as a precursor, which possesses inherent structural flexibility enabling tailored elemental adjustments and topologically transforms from a point&#8208;shared structure of metal&#8208;oxygen octahedrons into an edge&#8208;shared structure under alkaline conditions. The presence of Zn in the catalysts causes a shift in the center of the O2p band toward the Fermi level, resulting in more Co 4+ species, which drive holes into oxygen ligands to promote intramolecular oxygen coupling. The triggered lattice oxidation mechanism is identified by detecting peroxo&#8208;like (O 2 2&#8722; ) negative species using tetramethylammonium chemical probe, along with 18 O isotope labeling experiments. As a result, the catalyst demonstrates an overpotential of 267 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , ranking it among the top&#8208;performing non&#8208;Ni&#8208;based catalysts. Importantly, the catalysts also show high Fe&#8208;leaching resistance during OER compared to conventional NiFe and CoFe hydroxides/(oxy)hydroxides. The assembled zinc&#8208;air battery enables stable operation for over 225 h at a low charging voltage of 1.93 V.</description>
      <author>Sijia Liu, Baorui Jia, Sheng Wang, Yongzhi Zhao, Luan Liu, Fengmei Fan, Yunpu Qin, Jianfang Liu, Yirui Jiang, Bin Sun, Hong Zhao, Hao Li, Wenxiang Zhou, Haoyang Wu, Deyin Zhang, Xuanhui Qu, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202409530</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;B Electronic Effects in Layered Double Hydroxides for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407564</link>
      <description>Yuke Bai, Zhaojun Liu, Xiaoxiao Wang, Zhixue Zhang, Kai Liu, Chuanbo Gao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403005540

                Abstract NiFe layered double hydroxides (LDHs) are state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline media, yet they still face significant overpotentials. Here, quantitative boron (B) doping is introduced in NiFe LDHs (ranging from 0% to 20.3%) to effectively tailor the Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;B electronic interactions for enhanced OER performance. The co&#8208;hydrolysis synthesis approach synchronizes the hydrolysis rates of Ni and Fe precursors with the formation rate of B&#9472;O&#9472;M (M: Ni, Fe) bonds, ensuring precise B doping into the NiFe LDHs. It is demonstrated that B, as an electron&#8208;deficient element, acts as an &#8220;electron sink&#8221; at doping levels from 0% to 13.5%, facilitating the transition of Ni 2+ to the active Ni 3+&#948; , thereby accelerating OER kinetics. However, excessive B doping (13.5&#8211;20.3%) effectively generates oxygen vacancies in the LDHs, which increases electron density at Ni 2+ sites and hinders their transition to Ni 3+&#948; , thereby reducing OER activity. Optimal OER performance is achieved at a B doping level of 13.5%, with an overpotential of only 208 mV to reach a current density of 500 mA cm &#8722;2 , placing it among the most effective OER catalysts to date. This Ni&#8208;Fe&#8208;B electronic engineering opens new avenues for developing highly efficient anode catalysts for water&#8208;splitting hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Yuke Bai, Zhaojun Liu, Xiaoxiao Wang, Zhixue Zhang, Kai Liu, Chuanbo Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407564</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Construction of SnS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@SnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterostructure for Photo&#8208;Assisted Electrocatalysis of Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407659</link>
      <description>J. Wang, Ze Wang, Jie He, L.F. Han, Xin Li, Keyi Han, Tianen Chen, Qianyu Zhou, Lizhong Yang, Dongye Zhao, Yuanhao Wang, Shifeng Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403005567

                Abstract Photo&#8208;assisted electrocatalysis has arisen as a promising approach for hydrogen generation by incorporating photocatalysts into electrocatalysts. 2D SnS 2 is a photocatalyst that absorbs visible light. However, the rapid recombination of photo&#8208;generated electron&#8208;hole pairs significantly reduces the overall photocatalytic efficiency of SnS 2 , limiting its practical application. Thus, this study prepares an in situ heterojunction SnS 2 @SnO 2 using a one&#8208;step hydrothermal method. The degradation efficiency of methyl orange (MO) using SnS 2 @SnO 2 is measured, achieving a degradation rate of 92.75% within 1 h, which is 1.9 times higher than that of pure SnS 2 . Additionally, FeNiS/SnS 2 @SnO 2 is synthesized and exhibited significant improvements in the photo&#8208;assisted oxygen evolution reaction (OER). It achieves an overpotential of 260 mV and a Tafel slope of 65.1 mV dec &#8722;1 at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , showing reductions of 11.8% and 31.8%, respectively, compared to FeNiS alone. These enhancements highlight the strong photo&#8208;response capability of SnS 2 @SnO 2 . Under the internal electric field of SnS 2 @SnO 2 , the photogenerated electrons in the conduction band of SnS 2 quickly move toward SnO 2 , facilitating efficient photocatalytic reactions. FeNiS, with a lower Fermi energy level (E F ), facilitates electron transfer from SnS 2 @SnO 2 and enhances OER performance by efficiently participating in the reaction. This study paves a new path for 2D photocatalyst materials.</description>
      <author>J. Wang, Ze Wang, Jie He, L.F. Han, Xin Li, Keyi Han, Tianen Chen, Qianyu Zhou, Lizhong Yang, Dongye Zhao, Yuanhao Wang, Shifeng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407659</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An impedance spectroscopy study to unravel the effect of water on proton and oxygen transport in PEM fuel cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145172</link>
      <description>Tatyana V. Reshetenko, Ying Sun, Thomas Kadyk, Michael Eikerling, Andrei Kulikovsky, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403014868

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tatyana V. Reshetenko, Ying Sun, Thomas Kadyk, Michael Eikerling, Andrei Kulikovsky</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403017663

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403017949

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403018525

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bimetallic carbide armored by nitrogen-doped carbon for oxygen evolution reaction and wastewater treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102328</link>
      <description>Nagaraj Murugan, Gowthami Palanisamy, Nimisha Baby, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, DY Ryu, Priyadarshini Venkatachalam, Yu Rim Choi, Min Kang, Tae Hwan Oh, Yoong Ahm Kim, Materials Today Chemistry. 41(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402945910

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nagaraj Murugan, Gowthami Palanisamy, Nimisha Baby, Sadhasivam Thangarasu, DY Ryu, Priyadarshini Venkatachalam, Yu Rim Choi, Min Kang, Tae Hwan Oh, Yoong Ahm Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102328</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Urchin-like CuCo2O4/CuO decorated on carbon nanostructure for oxygen evolution reaction in an alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s41204-024-00387-4</link>
      <description>A. Thangaraj, Aruna K. Kunhiraman, V. Samuel, Nanotechnology for Environmental Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402827253

                No abstract</description>
      <author>A. Thangaraj, Aruna K. Kunhiraman, V. Samuel</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s41204-024-00387-4</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DFT screening of dual-atom catalysts on carbon nanotubes for enhanced oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction: comparing dissociative and associative mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03519d</link>
      <description>Xiangyi Zhou, Mohsen Tamtaji, Weijun Zhou, William A. Goddard, GuanHua Chen, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402927665

                Compared with associative mechanism, dual-atom catalysts under different surface curvature conditions show enhanced activity for oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction in dissociative mechanism.</description>
      <author>Xiangyi Zhou, Mohsen Tamtaji, Weijun Zhou, William A. Goddard, GuanHua Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03519d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-valence metal doping on cobalt-iron (oxy) hydroxide to activate the lattice oxygen for boosting oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176678</link>
      <description>Yuhao Fan, Ruopeng Li, Youzheng Wu, Yaqiang Li, Hao Xu, Penghui Ren, Fan Meng, Jinqiu Zhang, Maozhong An, Peixia Yang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402898124

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhao Fan, Ruopeng Li, Youzheng Wu, Yaqiang Li, Hao Xu, Penghui Ren, Fan Meng, Jinqiu Zhang, Maozhong An, Peixia Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.176678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defects trigger redox reactivities between metal and lattice oxygen in high-entropy layered double hydroxide for boosting oxygen evolution in alkaline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.231</link>
      <description>Shaofu Kuang, Zugao Pi, Caoyu Yang, Jianxin Wang, Hua Lin, Ming Nie, Junhui Sun, Honglin Zhang, Qing Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402950979

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shaofu Kuang, Zugao Pi, Caoyu Yang, Jianxin Wang, Hua Lin, Ming Nie, Junhui Sun, Honglin Zhang, Qing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.09.231</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yolk&#8211;Shell &#945;-/&#946;-Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Carbon Nanostructure for an Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.4c00747</link>
      <description>Gargi Dey, Shadab Saifi, Ashish Kumar Yadav, Shalini Awasthi, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, A. Aijaz, Crystal Growth &amp; Design. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402889955

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gargi Dey, Shadab Saifi, Ashish Kumar Yadav, Shalini Awasthi, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, A. Aijaz</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.cgd.4c00747</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange peel derived activated carbon supported Ni&#8211;Co3O4 as an efficient electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution and reduction reaction in alkaline media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129983</link>
      <description>Ashalatha Vazhayil, Shyamli Ashok C, Sutripto Majumder, A. Anto Jeffery, Mohammad Altaf, Young&#8208;Ho Ahn, Nygil Thomas, Materials Chemistry and Physics. 328(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402943005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ashalatha Vazhayil, Shyamli Ashok C, Sutripto Majumder, A. Anto Jeffery, Mohammad Altaf, Young&#8208;Ho Ahn, Nygil Thomas</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g</link>
      <description>Shujin Li, Shinichi Hata, Zhengying Wu, Yukou Du, Wei Xiao, Shudi Yu, Jie Li, Tianpeng Liu, Yukihide Shiraishi, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402986707

                Heteroatom doped metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have been widely used in OER catalysis. However, the effects of doping methods on these materials are still rarely reported. Herein, the structure and activity...</description>
      <author>Shujin Li, Shinichi Hata, Zhengying Wu, Yukou Du, Wei Xiao, Shudi Yu, Jie Li, Tianpeng Liu, Yukihide Shiraishi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403017676

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Ce-Doped Nanorod-like NiFe-MOF with Coordination Substitution Based on In-situ Co-Doping Method for Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403018667

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03929g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting oxygen toxicity: evolution and adaptation to superoxide in a SOD-deficient bacterial pathogen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.25.614947</link>
      <description>Samuel G. Huete, Alejandro Leyva, &#201;tienne Kornobis, Thomas Cokelaer, P Lechat, Marc Monot, Rosario Dur&#225;n, Mathieu Picardeau, Nadia Benaroudj, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402895631

                Defenses against oxidants are crucial for the virulence of pathogens, with superoxide scavenging enzymes (SOSEs) playing a vital role for most aerobes. However, our knowledge of superoxide adaptation primarily stems from the study of SOSE-encoding bacteria. Here, we investigated the evolution of a naturally SOSE-deficient pathogen (Leptospira spp.), along with the alternative mechanisms it recruits to combat superoxide stress. We demonstrate that emergence of pathogenic Leptospira correlated with SOD loss, but that a long-lasting adaptation to superoxide remains possible. We reveal that cysteine and leucine biosynthesis are the most induced pathways in response to superoxide and demonstrate the importance of sulfur metabolism in superoxide adaptation in this SOSE-deficient model. We also propose cysteine oxidation as a key mediator of superoxide toxicity in the absence of SOSEs. This study challenges our conventional understanding of the oxygen toxicity theory and proposes a new model of superoxide adaptation through metabolic rewiring in bacteria.</description>
      <author>Samuel G. Huete, Alejandro Leyva, &#201;tienne Kornobis, Thomas Cokelaer, P Lechat, Marc Monot, Rosario Dur&#225;n, Mathieu Picardeau, Nadia Benaroudj</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.25.614947</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Atomic Insights into the Competitive Edge of Nanosheets Splitting Water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c10312</link>
      <description>Lorenz J. Falling, Woosun Jang, Sourav Laha, Thomas G&#246;tsch, Maxwell W. Terban, Sebastian Bette, Rik V. Mom, Juan&#8208;Jes&#250;s Velasco&#8208;V&#233;lez, Frank Girgsdies, Detre Teschner, Andrey Tarasov, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Thomas Lunkenbein, Axel Knop&#8208;Gericke, Daniel Weber, Robert E. Dinnebier, Bettina V. Lotsch, Annette Trunschke, Travis E. Jones, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402838801

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) provides the protons for many electrocatalytic power-to-X processes, such as the production of green hydrogen from water or methanol from CO</description>
      <author>Lorenz J. Falling, Woosun Jang, Sourav Laha, Thomas G&#246;tsch, Maxwell W. Terban, Sebastian Bette, Rik V. Mom, Juan&#8208;Jes&#250;s Velasco&#8208;V&#233;lez, Frank Girgsdies, Detre Teschner, Andrey Tarasov, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Thomas Lunkenbein, Axel Knop&#8208;Gericke, Daniel Weber, Robert E. Dinnebier, Bettina V. Lotsch, Annette Trunschke, Travis E. Jones</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c10312</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Fe Ions on Anode Performance and the Mechanism of Action during Copper Electrowinning Process</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29194578</link>
      <description>Cheng Jiang, Yiwen Chen, Yingping Zhou, Buming Chen, Hui Huang, Jun Guo, Ruidong Xu, Guo Zhong-cheng, Molecules. 29(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402862201

                The performance of the anode varies from the impurity ions in the copper electrowinning process. This work focused on the variation of the electrochemical behavior of the Pb-0.06%Ca-1.2%Sn anode as the Fe ions (Fe3+ and/or Fe2+) existed in the electrolyte by electrochemical characterization. Copper electrodeposition experiments were conducted under a current density of 300 A/m2, with the Fe ion concentration in the electrolyte controlled within the range of 0 to 20 g/L and the Cu ion concentration maintained at 45 g/L at a temperature of 45 &#176;C. The variation in the corrosion resistance, catalytic activity, and structural composition of the anode film layer was analyzed in-depth according to the presence of Fe ions. The results show that the structure of PbO2 on the surface of the film was changed as Fe ions doped into the anode film, and the oxygen evolution activity of the anode was also improved. However, the corrosion resistance decreased with increasing Fe3+ concentration. Furthermore, the addition of 2 g/L Fe2+ in the electrolyte containing 2 g/L Fe3+ led to an elevation in the corrosion resistance of the anode to some extent and further increased the oxygen evolution activity.</description>
      <author>Cheng Jiang, Yiwen Chen, Yingping Zhou, Buming Chen, Hui Huang, Jun Guo, Ruidong Xu, Guo Zhong-cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29194578</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Artificial Leaf with Patterned Photocatalysts for Sunlight-Driven Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c10807</link>
      <description>Chao Zhen, Honglei Zhu, Ruotian Chen, Zhaoke Zheng, Fengtao Fan, Bei Li, Xiaoxiang Xu, Yufei Du, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Kazunari Domen, Gang Liu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402874271

                Plant leaves can turn entirely absorbed light into chemical energy due to their spatially separated photosystems I and II in the thylakoid membrane that enables unidirectional Z-scheme type charge transfer between them. In artificial systems that mimic leaves, a lack of spatial and interfacial control of active units (i.e., hydrogen evolution photocatalyst/HEP and oxygen evolution photocatalyst/OEP) introduces competitive charge transfer channels between them, resulting in deficient Z-scheme type charge transfer. Herein, we demonstrate that a patterned photocatalyst sheet, namely, an artificial leaf, comprising an ordered and separated distribution of the OEP and HEP strips on a conductive substrate, achieves unidirectional Z-scheme type charge transfer as the leaves do. It represents a next-generation photocatalytic system that mimics the leaves to bring breakthrough in photocatalytic over water splitting performance with the combination of highly active HEP and OEP photocatalysts, opening up a promising avenue toward solar energy conversion by artificial photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Chao Zhen, Honglei Zhu, Ruotian Chen, Zhaoke Zheng, Fengtao Fan, Bei Li, Xiaoxiang Xu, Yufei Du, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Kazunari Domen, Gang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c10807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis: A Distribution of Relaxation Times Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/11405.0469ecst</link>
      <description>Matthias Ranz, Bianca Grabner, Bernhard Schweighofer, Hannes Wegleiter, Alexander Trattner, ECS Transactions. 114(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402931663

                Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEM-WE) is a promising method for hydrogen production, offering advantages over proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEM-WE), such as the use of nonprecious metal catalysts and perfluorosulfonic acid free membranes. Despite achieving impressive current densities, challenges in efficiency and stability remain. This study employs electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), the equivalent circuit model (ECM) and distribution of relaxation times (DRT) analysis to investigate AEM-WE cells. DRT analysis identifies and quantifies five loss mechanisms within the AEM-WE system, including hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions and ionic transport losses. Long-term experiments reveal catalyst degradation and its impact on performance, providing insights for targeted optimisation. The findings enhance understanding of the electrochemical processes in AEM-WE, offering pathways to improve stability and efficiency.</description>
      <author>Matthias Ranz, Bianca Grabner, Bernhard Schweighofer, Hannes Wegleiter, Alexander Trattner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/11405.0469ecst</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis: A Distribution of Relaxation Times Approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/11405.0483ecst</link>
      <description>Matthias Ranz, Bianca Grabner, Bernhard Schweighofer, Hannes Wegleiter, Alexander Trattner, ECS Transactions. 114(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402931809

                Anion exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEM-WE) is a promising method for hydrogen production, offering advantages over proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEM-WE), such as the use of nonprecious metal catalysts and perfluorosulfonic acid free membranes. Despite achieving impressive current densities, challenges in efficiency and stability remain. This study employs electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), the equivalent circuit model (ECM) and distribution of relaxation times (DRT) analysis to investigate AEM-WE cells. DRT analysis identifies and quantifies five loss mechanisms within the AEM-WE system, including hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions and ionic transport losses. Long-term experiments reveal catalyst degradation and its impact on performance, providing insights for targeted optimisation. The findings enhance understanding of the electrochemical processes in AEM-WE, offering pathways to improve stability and efficiency.</description>
      <author>Matthias Ranz, Bianca Grabner, Bernhard Schweighofer, Hannes Wegleiter, Alexander Trattner</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/11405.0483ecst</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Oxygen&#8208;Reaction Electrocatalysis and Corrosion Resistance of CoCrFeNi Thin Films by Tuned Microstructure and Surface Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400296</link>
      <description>Clara Linder, Robert Boyd, Grzegorz Greczy&#324;ski, Mikhail Vagin, Daniel Lundin, Karin T&#246;rne, Per Eklund, Emma M. Bj&#246;rk, Small Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402961289

                Oxygen electrocatalysts play a key role in renewable and fossil&#8208;free energy production. Bifunctional catalysts active for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) allow use of the same material system for both energy production (ORR) and fuel generation (OER). However, optimizing the performance of bifunctional catalysts requires in depth understanding of the catalyst structure, its surface chemistry in terms of active sites and the underlying catalytic mechanism. Here, the catalytic performance of CoCrFeNi thin films is investigated, synthesized using high&#8208;power impulse magnetron sputtering, as bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts. The film crystal structure and morphology, and thereby the catalytic performance, can be tuned by the ion acceleration (bias) to the substrate. To further enhance the catalytic activity, anodization is used to electrochemically modify the films, forming a thicker oxide layer enriched in Co and Ni cations which significantly improves the ORR performance. Anodization improves the catalyst stability during OER, with an OER potential of 1.45 V versus the reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for more than 24 h. While the corrosion resistance is high both before and after anodization, in terms of catalytic activity the anodized films outperformed the as&#8208;deposited ones. This makes anodized films excellent electrocatalyst candidates in corrosive alkaline environments such as fuel cells and electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Clara Linder, Robert Boyd, Grzegorz Greczy&#324;ski, Mikhail Vagin, Daniel Lundin, Karin T&#246;rne, Per Eklund, Emma M. Bj&#246;rk</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smsc.202400296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biology&#8208;Based Synthesis of Nickel Single Atoms on the Surface of &lt;i&gt;Geobacter sulfurreducens&lt;/i&gt; as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407261</link>
      <description>Rodrigo Jimenez&#8208;Sandoval, Krishna P. Katuri, Harshini V. Annadata, Chandrani Nayak, Nimer Wehbe, Georgian Melinte, Pascal E. Saikaly, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402883795

                Abstract Single&#8208;atom metal catalysts are promising electrocatalysts for water electrolysis. Nickel&#8208;based electrocatalysts have shown attractive application prospects for water electrolysis. However, synthesizing stable Ni single atoms using chemical and physical approaches remains a practical challenge. Here, a facile and precise method for synthesizing stable nickel single atoms on the surface of Geobacter sulfurreducens using a microbial&#8208;mediated extracellular electron transfer (EET) process is demonstrated. It is shown that G. sulfurreducens can effectively anchor nickel single atoms on their surface. X&#8208;ray absorption near&#8208;edge structure and Fourier&#8208;transformed extended X&#8208;ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy confirm that the nickel single atom is coordinated to nitrogen in the cytochromes. The as&#8208;synthesized nickel single atoms on G. sulfurreducens exhibit excellent bifunctional catalytic properties for alkaline water electrolysis with low overpotential ( &#951; ) to achieve current density (10 mA cm &#8722;2 ) for both hydrogen evolution reactions ( &#951; = 80 mV) and oxygen evolution reaction ( &#951; = 330 mV) with minimal catalyst loading of 0.0015 mg Ni cm &#8722;2 . The nickel single&#8208;atom catalyst shows long&#8208;term stability at a constant electrode potential. This synthesis method based on the EET capability of electroactive bacteria provides a simple and scalable approach for producing low&#8208;cost and highly efficient nonnoble transition metal single&#8208;atom catalysts for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Rodrigo Jimenez&#8208;Sandoval, Krishna P. Katuri, Harshini V. Annadata, Chandrani Nayak, Nimer Wehbe, Georgian Melinte, Pascal E. Saikaly</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Amorphous/Crystalline Nanoflower Heterostructures for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401472</link>
      <description>Rong Cao, Chang Liu, Bowen Zhang, Jun Liang, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402962724

                Efficient water electrolysis for green hydrogen production relies on the development of robust oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts, particularly for acidic environments. This study introduces amorphous/crystalline Mn&#8208;Ru binary oxides nanoflowers (a/c&#8208;Mn0.9Ru0.1O2) as a promising acidic OER catalyst, synthesized via a two&#8208;step phase engineering approach. The optimized a/c&#8208; Mn0.9Ru0.1O2&#8208;200 composition exhibits exceptional OER activity, requiring a low overpotential of 168 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA/cm2 and demonstrating remarkable stability over 28 hours. This significantly outperforms commercial RuO2 catalysts, which require an overpotential of 320 mV at 10 mA/cm2 and exhibit a stability of only 0.5 h under identical conditions. X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) and X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) analysis results reveals the formation of Mn&#8208;O&#8208;Ru linkages and an optimized d&#8208;band electronic structure, attributed to strong electronic coupling at the amorphous/crystalline interface. This unique architecture promotes optimal adsorption/desorption of OER intermediates, leading to enhanced catalytic performance. This study offers a novel strategy for the rational design and production of efficient acidic OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Rong Cao, Chang Liu, Bowen Zhang, Jun Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Laser solid-phase synthesis of graphene shell-encapsulated high-entropy alloy nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41377-024-01614-y</link>
      <description>Yuxiang Liu, Jianghuai Yuan, Jiantao Zhou, Kewen Pan, Ran Zhang, Rongxia Zhao, Lin Li, Yihe Huang, Zhu Liu, Light Science &amp; Applications. 13(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402892358

                Abstract Rapid synthesis of high-entropy alloy nanoparticles (HEA NPs) offers new opportunities to develop functional materials in widespread applications. Although some methods have successfully produced HEA NPs, these methods generally require rigorous conditions such as high pressure, high temperature, restricted atmosphere, and limited substrates, which impede practical viability. In this work, we report laser solid-phase synthesis of CrMnFeCoNi nanoparticles by laser irradiation of mixed metal precursors on a laser-induced graphene (LIG) support with a 3D porous structure. The CrMnFeCoNi nanoparticles are embraced by several graphene layers, forming graphene shell-encapsulated HEA nanoparticles. The mechanisms of the laser solid-phase synthesis of HEA NPs on LIG supports are investigated through theoretical simulation and experimental observations, in consideration of mixed metal precursor adsorption, thermal decomposition, reduction through electrons from laser-induced thermionic emission, and liquid beads splitting. The production rate reaches up to 30 g/h under the current laser setup. The laser-synthesized graphene shell-encapsulated CrMnFeCoNi NPs loaded on LIG-coated carbon paper are used directly as 3D binder-free integrated electrodes and exhibited excellent electrocatalytic activity towards oxygen evolution reaction with an overpotential of 293 mV at the current density of 10 mA/cm 2 and exceptional stability over 428 h in alkaline media, outperforming the commercial RuO 2 catalyst and the relevant catalysts reported by other methods. This work also demonstrates the versatility of this technique through the successful synthesis of CrMnFeCoNi oxide, sulfide, and phosphide nanoparticles.</description>
      <author>Yuxiang Liu, Jianghuai Yuan, Jiantao Zhou, Kewen Pan, Ran Zhang, Rongxia Zhao, Lin Li, Yihe Huang, Zhu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41377-024-01614-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long-term reduced lunar mantle revealed by Chang&#8217;e-5 basalt</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52710-x</link>
      <description>Huijuan Zhang, Wei Yang, Di Zhang, Heng&#8208;Ci Tian, Renhao Ruan, Sen Hu, Yi Chen, Hejiu Hui, Yanhao Lin, Ross N. Mitchell, Di Zhang, Shitou Wu, Lihui Jia, Lixin Gu, Yangting Lin, Xian&#8211;Hua Li, Fu&#8208;Yuan Wu, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402923032

                The redox state of a planetary mantle affects its thermal evolution. The redox evolution of lunar mantle, however, remains unclear due to limited oxygen fugacity (fO</description>
      <author>Huijuan Zhang, Wei Yang, Di Zhang, Heng&#8208;Ci Tian, Renhao Ruan, Sen Hu, Yi Chen, Hejiu Hui, Yanhao Lin, Ross N. Mitchell, Di Zhang, Shitou Wu, Lihui Jia, Lixin Gu, Yangting Lin, Xian&#8211;Hua Li, Fu&#8208;Yuan Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-52710-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Physiology, Not Nutrient Availability, May Have Limited Primary Productivity After the Emergence of Oxygenic Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/gbi.12622</link>
      <description>Christen L. Grettenberger, D. Y. Sumner, Geobiology. 22(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402862588

                ABSTRACT The evolution of oxygenic photosynthesis in Cyanobacteria was a transformative event in Earth's history. However, the scientific community disagrees over the duration of the delay between the origin of oxygenic photosynthesis and oxygenation of Earth's atmosphere, with estimates ranging from less than a hundred thousand to more than a billion years, depending on assumptions about rates of oxygen production and fluxes of reductants. Here, we propose a novel ecological hypothesis that a geologically significant delay could have been caused by biomolecular inefficiencies within proto&#8208;Cyanobacteria&#8212;ancestors of modern Cyanobacteria&#8212;that limited their maximum rates of oxygen production. Consideration of evolutionary processes and genomic data suggest to us that proto&#8208;cyanobacterial primary productivity was initially limited by photosystem instability, oxidative damage, and photoinhibition rather than nutrients or ecological competition. We propose that during the Archean era, cyanobacterial photosystems experienced protracted evolution, with biomolecular inefficiencies initially limiting primary productivity and oxygen production. Natural selection led to increases in efficiency and thus primary productivity through time. Eventually, evolutionary advances produced sufficient biomolecular efficiency that environmental factors, such as nutrient availability, limited primary productivity and shifted controls on oxygen production from physiological to environmental limitations. If correct, our novel hypothesis predicts a geologically significant interval of time between the first local oxygen production and sufficient production for oxygenation of environments. It also predicts that evolutionary rates were likely highly variable due to strong environmental selection pressures and potentially high mutation rates but low competitive interactions.</description>
      <author>Christen L. Grettenberger, D. Y. Sumner</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/gbi.12622</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical model of oxygen minimum zones in the vertical distribution of oxygen in the ocean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-72207-3</link>
      <description>Yazeed Alhassan, Ivo Siekmann, Sergei Petrovskii, Scientific Reports. 14(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402920164

                Processes determining the amount and spatial distribution of dissolved oxygen in the ocean have been a focus of intense research over the last two decades. Anomalies known as Oxygen Minimum Zones (OMZs) have been attracting growing attention, in particular because their growth is believed to be a result of the global environmental change. Comprehensive understanding of factors contributing to and/or controlling the emergence and evolution of OMZs is still lacking though. OMZs are usually thought to result from an interplay between the oxygen transport through the water column from the ocean surface and variable oxygen solubility at different water temperature. In this paper, we suggest a different, novel mechanism of the OMZ formation relating it to the oxygen production in phytoplankton photosynthesis in a stratified ocean. We consider a simple, conceptual model of the coupled phytoplankton-oxygen dynamics and show that the model predictions are in qualitative agreement with some relevant field observations.</description>
      <author>Yazeed Alhassan, Ivo Siekmann, Sergei Petrovskii</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41598-024-72207-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Topological Protection of Oxygen Redox in Li-Rich Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01929</link>
      <description>Zhefeng Chen, Wentao Zhang, Shunning Li, Feng Pan, The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402885847

                Lithium-rich layered oxides (LRLOs) are regarded as promising candidates for next-generation cathode materials because of their high energy density derived from anionic redox activity. Recent years have seen increasing efforts in promoting the cyclability of LRLO cathodes, at the core of which is the suppression of irreversible internal structural evolution during cycling. The present article aims to provide an informative perspective on the materials design strategies related to the issue of oxygen release. Emphasis is placed on the underlying chemistry of oxygen redox in LRLOs and the strategies based on material topology that can mitigate oxygen migration to the cathode surface. We speculate that these insights could guide researchers in developing high-capacity cathodes with intrinsically high reversibility of oxygen redox.</description>
      <author>Zhefeng Chen, Wentao Zhang, Shunning Li, Feng Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.4c01929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contribution of astrophysical events to the chemical evolution of a dwarf irregular galaxy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2210</link>
      <description>Nao Fukagawa, Nikos Prantzos, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402901438

                Abstract We study the contribution of various astrophysical events (AGB stars, core collapse and thermonuclear supernovae, neutron star mergers and collapsars) to the abundances of elements both up to and heavier than the iron peak in a Local Group dwarf irregular galaxy, Wolf-Lundmark-Melotte. Its star formation history has been recently determined by observations with the JWST and we use it to estimate the occurrence of the astrophysical sources. The rates of the gas accretion and the outflow are roughly determined based on the stellar metallicity distribution, the oxygen abundance of HII regions and the gas fraction. As discussed in the literature, the difference in time-scales on which the astrophysical events release the nucleosynthesis products is seen in the occurrence of the events and the evolution of abundance ratios. WLM has an extended star formation history and massive stars are recently and currently formed. Thus, the contribution of rotating massive stars through the weak s-process appears in the abundance ratios of light trans-iron elements to iron at later time of the evolution.</description>
      <author>Nao Fukagawa, Nikos Prantzos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2210</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buoyancy regulation in insects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1152/physiol.00017.2024</link>
      <description>Philip G. D. Matthews, Physiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402837241

                Multiple insect lineages have successfully reinvaded the aquatic environment, evolving to complete either part or all of their life cycle submerged in water. While these insects vary in their reliance on atmospheric oxygen, with many having the ability to extract dissolved oxygen directly from the water, all retain an internal air-filled respiratory system, their tracheal system, due to their terrestrial origins. However, carrying air within their tracheal system, and even augmenting this volume with additional air bubbles carried on their body, dramatically increases their buoyancy which can make it challenging to remain submerged. But by manipulating this air volume a few aquatic insects can deliberately alter or regulate their position in the water column. Unlike cephalopods and teleost fish that control the volume of gas within their hydrostatic organs by either using osmosis to pull liquid from a rigid chamber or secreting oxygen at high pressure to inflate a flexible chamber, insects have evolved hydrostatic control mechanisms that rely either on the temporary stabilization of a compressible air-bubble volume using O 2 unloaded from hemoglobin, or the mechanical expansion and contraction of a gas-filled volume with rigid, gas-permeable walls. The ability to increase their buoyancy while submerged separates aquatic insects from the buoyancy compensation achieved by other air-breathing aquatic animals which also use air within their respiratory systems to offset their submerged weight. The mechanisms they have evolved to achieve this are unique and provide new insights into the function and evolution of mechanochemical systems.</description>
      <author>Philip G. D. Matthews</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1152/physiol.00017.2024</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Atmospheric Oxygenated Organic Molecules in Urban Beijing Using Online Ultrahigh-Resolution Chemical Ionization Mass Spectrometry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c04214</link>
      <description>Yi Yuan, Xin Chen, Runlong Cai, Xiaoxiao Li, Yuyang Li, Rujing Yin, Dandan Li, Chao Yan, Yongchun Liu, Kebin He, Markku Kulmala, Jingkun Jiang, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402927351

                Gaseous oxygenated organic molecules (OOMs) are crucial precursors of atmospheric organic aerosols. OOMs in urban atmospheres have complex compositions, posing challenges to understanding their formation, evolution, and influences. In this study, we identify 2403 atmospheric gaseous OOMs in urban Beijing using online nitrate-based chemical ionization Orbitrap mass spectrometry based on one-year atmospheric measurements. We find that OOMs in urban atmospheres can be identified with higher accuracy and wider coverage, compared to previously used online mass spectrometry. With optimized OOM resolving capabilities, previous knowledge of OOMs in urban atmospheres can be expanded. First, clear homologous and oxygen-addition characteristics of the OOMs are revealed. Second, OOMs with lower concentrations or higher masses are identified and characterized with high confidence, e.g., OOMs with masses above 350 Da. In particular, dimers of OOMs (e.g., C</description>
      <author>Yi Yuan, Xin Chen, Runlong Cai, Xiaoxiao Li, Yuyang Li, Rujing Yin, Dandan Li, Chao Yan, Yongchun Liu, Kebin He, Markku Kulmala, Jingkun Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c04214</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#947;&#8208;Ray Driven Aqueous&#8208;Phase Methane Conversions into Complex Molecules up to Glycine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413296</link>
      <description>Fei Fang, Xiao Sun, Yuanxu Liu, Zhiwen Jiang, Mozhen Wang, Xuewu Ge, Weixin Huang, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402844950

                Fundamental understanding of initial evolutions of molecules in the universe is of great interest and importance. CH4 is one of the abundant simple molecules in the universe. Herein we report &#947;&#8208;ray, high&#8208;energy photons commonly existing in cosmic rays and unstable isotope decay, as an external energy to efficiently drives aqueous&#8208;phase CH4 conversions to various products with the presence of oxygen at room temperature. Glycine also forms with an additional introduction of ammonia. Both CH4 conversions and product distributions are modified by solid granules, and a CH3COOH selectivity as high as 82% is obtained when SiO2 is added. Our results point to &#947;&#8208;ray driven aqueous&#8208;phase CH4 conversions as a likely formation network of initial complex organic compounds in the universe and offer an alternative strategy for efficiently utilizing CH4 as the carbon source to produce value&#8208;added products at mild conditions, a long&#8208;standing challenging task in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Fei Fang, Xiao Sun, Yuanxu Liu, Zhiwen Jiang, Mozhen Wang, Xuewu Ge, Weixin Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&#947;&#8208;Ray Driven Aqueous&#8208;Phase Methane Conversions into Complex Molecules up to Glycine</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413296</link>
      <description>Fei Fang, Xiao Sun, Yuanxu Liu, Zhiwen Jiang, Mozhen Wang, Xuewu Ge, Wei Huang, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402844595

                Fundamental understanding of initial evolutions of molecules in the universe is of great interest and importance. CH4 is one of the abundant simple molecules in the universe. Herein we report &#947;&#8208;ray, high&#8208;energy photons commonly existing in cosmic rays and unstable isotope decay, as an external energy to efficiently drives aqueous&#8208;phase CH4 conversions to various products with the presence of oxygen at room temperature. Glycine also forms with an additional introduction of ammonia. Both CH4 conversions and product distributions are modified by solid granules, and a CH3COOH selectivity as high as 82% is obtained when SiO2 is added. Our results point to &#947;&#8208;ray driven aqueous&#8208;phase CH4 conversions as a likely formation network of initial complex organic compounds in the universe and offer an alternative strategy for efficiently utilizing CH4 as the carbon source to produce value&#8208;added products at mild conditions, a long&#8208;standing challenging task in heterogeneous catalysis.</description>
      <author>Fei Fang, Xiao Sun, Yuanxu Liu, Zhiwen Jiang, Mozhen Wang, Xuewu Ge, Wei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413296</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Middle Miocene Seawater Isotopes in the Eastern North Atlantic Ocean</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024pa004852</link>
      <description>Katrin H&#228;ttig, Stefan Schouten, Stephen Louwye, Marcel T. J. van der Meer, Paleoceanography and Paleoclimatology. 39(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402893255

                Abstract The Middle Miocene is characterized by a long&#8208;term increase in the stable oxygen isotopic composition of benthic foraminifera ( &#948; 18 O benthic ). However, it is unclear to what extent this increase reflects changes in seawater isotopic composition or deep water temperature. We present a high&#8208;resolution alkenone hydrogen isotope ( &#948; 2 H C37 ) record of the Middle Miocene from a core taken at the upper slope edge (about 409 m water depth) of the Porcupine Basin continental margin in the eastern North Atlantic Ocean, Site U1318 of the Integrated Ocean Drilling Program. The &#948; 2 H C37 values vary between &#8722;174 and &#8722;200&#8240; with an average of &#8722;191 &#177; 5&#8240;, similar to modern open&#8208;ocean values. Importantly, they do not show a long&#8208;term increase in surface seawater isotopes ( &#948; 2 H SSW ) during the Middle Miocene Climate Transition. Indeed, when &#948; 18 O benthic is corrected for subsurface temperature, the bottom seawater oxygen isotopes ( &#948; 18 O BSW ) show no significant increase in this period. When the latter record is translated into the hydrogen isotopic composition of bottom seawater using the modern open&#8208;ocean waterline, it has an average value of 5.8 &#177; 1.5&#8240;, similar to the &#948; 2 H SSW of 5.2 &#177; 3.1&#8240; derived from &#948; 2 H C37:2, suggesting a relatively small difference between bottom and surface waters. Our results suggest a stable global surface seawater isotope evolution during the Middle Miocene, coupled with a long&#8208;term decrease in bottom water temperature.</description>
      <author>Katrin H&#228;ttig, Stefan Schouten, Stephen Louwye, Marcel T. J. van der Meer</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024pa004852</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Powder Reuse on Electron Beam Melting for Biomedical Implants</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17194701</link>
      <description>M. Akshay, Paula Milena Giraldo&#8208;Osorno, Lars Nyborg, Anders Palmquist, Yu Cao, Materials. 17(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402828397

                The ability of additive manufacturing to generate intricate structures has led to its popularity and widespread use in a variety of applications, ranging from the production of biomedical implants to aircraft components. Additive manufacturing techniques can overcome the limitations of the traditional manufacturing methods to create complex near-net-form structures. A vast array of clinical applications effectively employ Ti-6Al-4V as a biomaterial. The evolution of additive manufacturing has accelerated the development of patient-specific implants. The surface characteristics play a critical role in tissue healing and adaptation to implants. The present research set out to examine the effects of powder recycling with respect to the powder itself and the surface properties resulting from the electron beam melting (EBM) of the implant material. The printed implants, as well as the powder samples, underwent morphological, surface chemistry, and microstructure analyses. The in vitro cytotoxicity was evaluated with THP-1 macrophages. The overall microstructure of the implant samples showed little variation in terms of powder recycling based on the results. Higher oxygen levels were found in the solid and lattice sections of those implants manufactured with batches of recycled powder, along with marginally better cell viability. This emphasizes how crucial powder quality is to the process of additive manufacturing.</description>
      <author>M. Akshay, Paula Milena Giraldo&#8208;Osorno, Lars Nyborg, Anders Palmquist, Yu Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17194701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Multifunctional Nanostructured Carbon and Inorganic Nanoparticles Based Nanocomposites for Electrochemical Energy Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.114238</link>
      <description>Mohammed Rafi Shaik, Mufsir Kuniyil, Mujeeb Khan, Mohammad Rafe Hatshan, Muhammad Tahir, Syed Farooq Adil, Mujeeb Khan, IntechOpen eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402994702

                Electrochemical energy conversion and storage technologies play a crucial role in ensuring a sustainable energy future. In these regards, nanostructured carbon-based materials (NCMs) are very critical in the development of novel energy technologies and devices. NCMs include CNTs, graphene, fullerene, and ordered mesoporous carbon materials, which exist in different morphologies. NCMs offer great opportunities for effective modifications through surface functionalization, doping with heteroatoms, and fabrication of composites with organic or inorganic species. Particularly, the composites of NCMs with inorganic materials such as metallic NPs, metal oxide NPs, and their other derivatives (MNPs) have gained considerable recognition in electrochemical energy applications. These materials demonstrate distinct properties, including excellent thermal and electrical conductivity, large surface area, and chemical stability. Herein, we have highlighted some of the trends and outlooks in this exciting area, including fundamentals of these substances according to material science perspective. Besides, the latest research and development of multifunctional MNPs@NCMs composites for electrochemical energy applications have also been illustrated. Particularly, the utilization of these composites from the perspective of different electrochemical energy applications has been summarized, such as energy conversion processes like hydrogen evolution reactions (HER), oxygen reduction reactions (ORR), and energy storage devices like batteries and supercapacitors.</description>
      <author>Mohammed Rafi Shaik, Mufsir Kuniyil, Mujeeb Khan, Mohammad Rafe Hatshan, Muhammad Tahir, Syed Farooq Adil, Mujeeb Khan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5772/intechopen.114238</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transcriptome and evolutionary analysis of Pseudotrichomonas keilini, a free-living anaerobic eukaryote</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.26.614816</link>
      <description>Hend Abu-Elmakarem, Stephen J. Taerum, C&#233;line Petitjean, Michael Kotyk, Chris Kay, Ivan &#268;epi&#269;ka, David Bass, Gillian H. Gile, Tom A. Williams, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402910980

                The early evolution of eukaryotes and their adaptations to low-oxygen environments are fascinating open questions in biology. Genome-scale data from novel eukaryotes, and particularly from free-living lineages, are key to answering these questions. The Parabasalia are an ancient lineage of anaerobes, and the most speciose lineage of Metamonada, a major lineage of eukaryotes. The most well-studied metamonads are parasitic parabasalids including Trichomonas vaginalis, Tritrichomonas foetus, and Giardia intestinalis, but very little genome-scale data is available for free-living members of the group. Here, we sequenced the transcriptome of Pseudotrichomonas keilini, a free-living parabasalian. Comparative genomic analysis indicated that P. keilini possesses a metabolism and gene complement that are in many respects similar to its parasitic relative Trichomonas vaginalis, and that in the time since their most recent common ancestor, it is the Trichomonas vaginalis lineage that has experienced more genomic change, likely due to the transition to a parasitic lifestyle. Features shared between P. keilini and Trichomonas vaginalis include a hydrogenosome (anaerobic mitochondrial homologue) that we predict to function much as in Trichomonas vaginalis, and a complete glycolytic pathway that is likely to represent one of the primary means by which P. keilini obtains ATP. Phylogenomic analysis indicates that P. keilini branches within a clade of endobiotic parabasalids, consistent with the hypothesis that different parabasalid lineages evolved towards parasitic or free-living lifestyles from an endobiotic, anaerobic or microaerophilic common ancestor.</description>
      <author>Hend Abu-Elmakarem, Stephen J. Taerum, C&#233;line Petitjean, Michael Kotyk, Chris Kay, Ivan &#268;epi&#269;ka, David Bass, Gillian H. Gile, Tom A. Williams</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.09.26.614816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Ones That Got Away: Chemical Tagging of Globular Cluster-Origin
  Stars with Gaia BP/RP Spectra</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.00197</link>
      <description>Sarah G. Kane, Vasily Belokurov, Miles Cranmer, Stephanie Monty, Hanyuan Zhang, Anke Arentsen, Elijah Kane, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402953154

                Globular clusters (GCs) are sites of extremely efficient star formation, and recent studies suggest they significantly contributed to the early Milky Way's stellar mass build-up. Although their role has since diminished, GCs' impact on the Galaxy's initial evolution can be traced today by identifying their most chemically unique stars--those with anomalous nitrogen and aluminum overabundances and oxygen depletion. While they are a perfect tracer of clusters, be it intact or fully dissolved, these high-[N/O], high-[Al/Fe] GC-origin stars are extremely rare within the current Galaxy. To address the scarcity of these unusual, precious former GC members, we train a neural network (NN) to identify high-[N/O], high-[Al/Fe] stars using low-resolution Gaia BP/RP spectra. Our NN achieves a classification accuracy of approximately $\approx99\%$ and a false positive rate of around $\approx7\%$, identifying 878 new candidates in the Galactic field. We validate our results with several physically-motivated sanity checks, showing, for example, that the incidence of selected stars in Galactic GCs is significantly higher than in the field. Moreover, we find that most of our GC-origin candidates reside in the inner Galaxy, having likely formed in the proto-Milky Way, consistent with previous research. The fraction of GC candidates in the field drops at a metallicity of [Fe/H]$\approx-1$, approximately coinciding with the completion of spin-up, i.e. the formation of the Galactic stellar disk.</description>
      <author>Sarah G. Kane, Vasily Belokurov, Miles Cranmer, Stephanie Monty, Hanyuan Zhang, Anke Arentsen, Elijah Kane</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.00197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the response mechanisms and evolution prediction of groundwater microbial&#8208;toxicological indicators</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/wer.11131</link>
      <description>Weichao Sun, Shuaiwei Wang, Junguo Bi, Ning Zhuo, Xiaogang Wang, Hongwei Hou, Water Environment Research. 96(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402933969

                Abstract This study aims to investigate the response mechanisms of groundwater microbial&#8208;toxicological indicators, specifically total bacteria count (TBC) and total coliform count (TCC), to water quality indicators and environmental conditions. Using data from a water source in the western plateau of China, a predictive model focusing on TBC and TCC was developed. An orthogonal experimental design was employed to manipulate environmental conditions such as temperature, pH, and porosity, facilitating laboratory experiments. These experiments measured pH, chemical oxygen demand (COD), oxidation&#8211;reduction potential (ORP), TBC, and TCC at varying depths and environmental conditions. Principal component analysis elucidated the mechanisms by which water quality indicators and environmental conditions affect groundwater microbial&#8211;toxicological indicators. A prediction model for these indicators in plateau regions was established based on a backpropagation neural network (BP&#8208;NN), using TBC and TCC as target variables and the newly extracted principal components as influencing factors. The results demonstrate that environmental conditions and water quality indicators primarily influence the evolution of groundwater microbial&#8211;toxicological indicators by altering the ionic charge quantities, redox conditions, and temperature of the groundwater. The predictive model for groundwater microbial&#8211;toxicological indicators shows trends consistent with experimental outcomes, with an average relative error of less than 15%, meeting engineering requirements. Practitioner points The values of total bacteria count (TBC) and total coliform count (TCC) under different conditions were obtained by column experiments. The influence mechanism of environmental conditions and groundwater indicators on TBC and TCC was elaborated by principal component analysis. TBC and TCC prediction models were established through the investigation of water sources in a plateau area and laboratory experiments.</description>
      <author>Weichao Sun, Shuaiwei Wang, Junguo Bi, Ning Zhuo, Xiaogang Wang, Hongwei Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/wer.11131</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrophenoxylation of alkynes by gold catalysts: a mini review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-024-06152-3</link>
      <description>Miguel Ramos, Miquel Sol&#224;, Albert Poater, Journal of Molecular Modeling. 30(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402975044

                Abstract Context The field of chemistry has significantly evolved, with catalysis playing a crucial role in transforming chemical processes. From Valerius&#8217; use of sulfuric acid in the sixteenth century to modern advancements, catalysis has driven innovations across various industries. The introduction of gold as a catalyst marked a pivotal shift, expanding its applications beyond ornamentation to homogeneous catalysis. Gold&#8217;s unique properties, such as its electrophilic nature and flexibility, have enabled its use in synthesizing complex molecules, including those in nanomedicine and sustainable chemical processes. The development of gold-based complexes, particularly in hydroalkoxylation and hydroamination reactions, showcases their efficiency in forming carbon&#8211;oxygen bonds under mild conditions. Recent studies on dual gold catalysis and heterobimetallic complexes further highlight gold&#8217;s versatility in achieving high turnover rates and selectivity. This evolution underscores the potential of gold catalysis in advancing environmentally sustainable methodologies and enhancing the scope of modern synthetic chemistry. The debate about the nature of monogold and dual-gold catalysis is open. Methods DFT calculations have played a key role in promoting the activation of alkynes, in particular the hydrophenoxylation of alkynes by metal-based catalysts. They not only help identify the most efficient and selective catalysts but also aid in screening for those capable of performing a dual metal catalytic mechanism. The most commonly used functionals are BP86 and B3LYP, with the SVP and 6-31G(d) basis sets employed for geometry optimizations, and M06 with TZVP or 6-311G(d,p) basis sets used for single-point energy calculations in a solvent. Grimme dispersion correction has been explicitly added either in the solvent single point energy calculations or in the gas phase geometry optimizations or in both. To point out that M06 implicitly includes part of this dispersion scheme.</description>
      <author>Miguel Ramos, Miquel Sol&#224;, Albert Poater</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00894-024-06152-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UNCOVERing the Faint-End of the z=7 [OIII] Luminosity Function with
  JWST's F410M Medium Bandpass Filter</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.19023</link>
      <description>Isak Wold, Sangeeta Malhotra, James E. Rhoads, John R. Weaver, Bingjie Wang, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4402963648

                Strong emission from doubly ionized oxygen is a beacon for some of the most intensely star forming galaxies known. JWST enables the search for this beacon in the early universe with unprecedented sensitivity. In this work, we extend the study of faint [OIII]$_{5008}$ selected galaxies by an order of magnitude in line luminosity. We use publicly available UNCOVER DR1 JWST/NIRCam and HST imaging data of the cluster lensing field, Abell 2744, to identify strong (rest-frame EW$&gt;500$\AA) [OIII]$_{5008}$ emitters at $z\sim7$ based on excess F410M flux. We find $N=68$ $z\sim7$ [OIII] candidates, with a subset of $N=33$ that have deep HST coverage required to rule-out lower redshift interlopers (13.68 arcmin$^2$ with F814W $5\sigma$ depth $&gt;28$ AB). Such strong emission lines can lead to very red colors that could be misinterpreted as evidence for old, massive stellar populations, but are shown to be due to emission lines where we have spectra. Using this deep HST sample and completeness simulations, which calculate the effective survey volume of the UNCOVER lensing field as a function of [OIII] luminosity, we derive a new [OIII] luminosity function (LF) extending to $41.09&lt;\rm{log}_{10}(L/\rm{erg\,s}^{-1})&lt;42.35$ which is an order of magnitude deeper than previous $z\sim6$ [OIII] LFs based on JWST slitless spectroscopy. This LF is well fit by a power law with a faint-end slope of $\alpha=-2.07^{+0.22}_{-0.23}$. There is little or no evolution between this LF and published [OIII] LFs at redshifts $3\lesssim z\lesssim7$, and no evidence of a turnover at faint luminosities. The sizes of these extreme [OIII] emitters are broadly similar to their low redshift counterparts, the green peas. The luminosity function of [OIII] emitters matches that of Lyman-$\alpha$ at the bright end, suggesting that many of them should be Lyman-$\alpha$ emitters.</description>
      <author>Isak Wold, Sangeeta Malhotra, James E. Rhoads, John R. Weaver, Bingjie Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2407.19023</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
