<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 01:18:38 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>CoFe2O4 with the In&#8208;Situ Formed Oxygen Vacancies and Co Particles as an Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Rechargeable Zinc&#8208;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403229</link>
      <description>Ren Z, Sujie Jiang, Keke Su, Wenfeng Liu, Fuquan Niu, Zhenpu Shi, Zhansheng Lu, Yuantao Cui, Shuting Yang, Yanhong Yin, Chemistry - A European Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403538257

                Rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries (RZABs) are considered as one of the most promising clean energy device due to their abundant resources, low cost and environmental friendliness. However, their energy efficiency and cycle life are far from satisfactory due to the poor activity and stability of bi&#8208;functional electrocatalyst in air cathode. In this work, an efficient bi&#8208;functional catalyst (rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4/Co) was derived from its precursor (rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4) through a simple annealing process. Electrochemical measurements prove that rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4/Co with the in&#8208;situ formed Co nano particles and rich oxygen vacancies appears excellent oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction catalytic activity compared to its counterpart. Its half&#8208;wave potential is 0.81 V (vs RHE) and the OER overpotential is only 310 mV (vs RHE). In addition, rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries assembled with rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4/Co show the highest peak power density (128.9 mW cm&#8208;2) and cycling stability compared to rGO&#8208;CoFe2O4 and commercial Pt/C&#8208;RuO2 catalysts. This work provides a simple strategy for the design of advanced bifunctional catalysts.</description>
      <author>Ren Z, Sujie Jiang, Keke Su, Wenfeng Liu, Fuquan Niu, Zhenpu Shi, Zhansheng Lu, Yuantao Cui, Shuting Yang, Yanhong Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202403229</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sequential oxygen evolution and decoupled water splitting via electrochemical redox reaction of nickel hydroxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53310-5</link>
      <description>Jie Wei, Yangfan Shao, Jingbo Xu, Fang Yin, Zejian Li, Haitao Qian, Yinping Wei, Liang Chang, Yu Han, Jia Li, Lin Gan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403540533

                Alkaline water electrolysis is a promising low-cost strategy for clean and sustainable hydrogen production but is largely limited by the sluggish anodic oxygen evolution reaction and the challenges in maintaining adequate separation between H2 and O2. Here, we reveal an anodic-cathodic sequential oxygen evolution process via electrochemical oxidation and subsequent reduction of Ni hydroxides, enabling much lower overpotentials than conventional anodic oxygen evolution. By using (isotope-labeled) differential electrochemical mass spectrometry and in situ Raman spectroscopy combined with density functional theory calculations, we evidence that the sequential oxygen evolution originates from the electrochemical oxidation of Ni hydroxides to NiOO&#8211; active species while undergoing a different, reductive step of NiOO&#8211; for the final release of O2 due to weakened Ni&#8211;O covalency. Based on this sequential process, we propose and demonstrate a hybrid water electrolysis and energy storage device, which enables time-decoupled hydrogen and oxygen evolution and electrochemical energy storage in the Ni hydroxides. The authors report a sequential oxygen evolution process via electrochemical oxidation and reduction of Ni hydroxides, allowing for decoupled oxygen evolution and hydrogen evolution during water splitting and energy storage in the Ni hydroxides.</description>
      <author>Jie Wei, Yangfan Shao, Jingbo Xu, Fang Yin, Zejian Li, Haitao Qian, Yinping Wei, Liang Chang, Yu Han, Jia Li, Lin Gan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53310-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Charge Transfer Modulation in Laser-Synthesized Catalysts for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06794k</link>
      <description>Dong Soo Lee, R. D. Kerkar, Deepak Arumugam, Theerthagiri Jayaraman, R. Shankar, Soorathep Kheawhom, Myong Yong Choi, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403542497

                Advancements in laser-based material development have enabled precise engineering of catalysts, thus promoting efficient and sustainable water-splitting reactions. This study presents a green approach for synthesizing a layered double hydroxide...</description>
      <author>Dong Soo Lee, R. D. Kerkar, Deepak Arumugam, Theerthagiri Jayaraman, R. Shankar, Soorathep Kheawhom, Myong Yong Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06794k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational construction of N-containing carbon sheets atomically doped NiP-CoP nanohybrid electrocatalysts for enhanced green hydrogen and oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145236</link>
      <description>Adewale K. Ipadeola, Mostafa H. Sliem, Patrick V. Mwonga, Kenneth I. Ozoemena, Aboubakr M. Abdullah, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403548371

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Adewale K. Ipadeola, Mostafa H. Sliem, Patrick V. Mwonga, Kenneth I. Ozoemena, Aboubakr M. Abdullah</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo&#8208;doped &#945;&#8208;MnO2 for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401553</link>
      <description>Ying Chen, Shujiao Yang, Ting Wang, Sisi Li, Xiaohan Liu, Jing Wang, Rui Cao, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403548549

                Manganese is a key metal involved in the catalysis of natural photosynthesis. Thus, the investigation of Mn&#8208;based electrocatalysts for water oxidation is of high importance. This work reports the doping of Mo into &#945;&#8208;MnO2 nanorods to improve the water oxidation performance. The doping of Mo can transform the microstructure of &#945;&#8208;MnO2 from nanorods into nanosphere superstructures. As a dopant, Mo expands the &#945;&#8208;MnO2 lattice to result in a decrease in the average oxidation state of Mn and the generation of oxygen vacancies, which are beneficial to water oxidation catalysis. Under optimized doping, the OER overpotential of Mo/&#945;&#8208;MnO2 is reduced by 80 mV (at 10 mA/cm2) compared with pure &#945;&#8208;MnO2.</description>
      <author>Ying Chen, Shujiao Yang, Ting Wang, Sisi Li, Xiaohan Liu, Jing Wang, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401553</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ synthesis of FeNi3/(Fe,Ni)9S8/Ni4S3/C nanorods and enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction properties</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.193.1333</link>
      <description>Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, S. J. Zhong, J. H. Chen, Mengyang Li, Yele Sun, Digest Journal of Nanomaterials and Biostructures. 19(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403549377

                NiFe-based nanomaterials have emerged as highly promising catalysts to replace platinum, ruthenium and iridium for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), in &#8220;green hydrogen&#8221; production process through water splitting. Using iron (2+) sulfate and nickel acetate as the raw materials, with the molar ratio of Ni acetate to iron (2+) sulfate controlled at 8:5, the concentration of metal-ion was 0.6 mol/L, and precursor fibers rich in Ni2+, Fe2+, and SO4 2&#8722; were prepared using electrospinning technology, with polyvinyl alcohol acting as the colloid. Subsequently, composite nanorods rich in the elements of Ni, Fe, S, and C were successfully obtained at a heat treatment temperature of 1000&#176;C in an Ar gas atmosphere. The results demonstrate that the nanorod samples possessed a surface diameter of ~200 nm, and the main phases of the nanorods after heat treatment at 1000&#176;C included FeNi3 alloy, (Fe,Ni)9S8, Ni4S3, and amorphous C. Electrochemical performance tests conducted in a 1.0 mol/L KOH solution exhibited excellent oxygen evolution reaction properties of the catalysts prepared using FeNi3/(Fe,Ni)9S8/Ni4S3/C nanorods as the materials. The overpotential was about 258.6 mV of the catalyst material at 10 mA&#61589;cm&#8722;2.</description>
      <author>Tianshu Li, Sanliang Ling, S. J. Zhong, J. H. Chen, Mengyang Li, Yele Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15251/djnb.193.1333</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Active learning accelerated exploration of single-atom local environments in multimetallic systems for oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01432-1</link>
      <description>Hoje Chun, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jeung Ku Kang, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Byungchan Han, npj Computational Materials. 10(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403560061

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hoje Chun, Jaclyn R. Lunger, Jeung Ku Kang, Rafael G&#243;mez&#8208;Bombarelli, Byungchan Han</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41524-024-01432-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recycling spent battery components into highly efficient hydrogen and oxygen evolution electro-nano-catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145268</link>
      <description>Basel A. Samy, Zaheer Khan, Shaeel A. Al&#8208;Thabaiti, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403574615

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Basel A. Samy, Zaheer Khan, Shaeel A. Al&#8208;Thabaiti</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145268</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Cocatalytic Sites Synergize NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402046</link>
      <description>Yue Shi, Lumin Song, Yan Liu, Tiantian Wang, Caixia Li, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403584566

                Abstract Nickel&#8208;iron layered double hydroxide (LDH) is a promising cost&#8208;efficient catalyst to replace noble metals for alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER), yet its intrinsic activity under high current density conditions is not satisfactory, which greatly constrains the industrial application of NiFe LDH catalysts. Herein, a new class of integrated Co and W co&#8208;doped NiFe LDH catalysts is reported with dual cocatalytic sites for alkaline OER catalysis. The optimized Co 2.8 , W 3.8 &#8208;NiFe LDH integrated catalyst has superior alkaline OER activity (255 mV@1000 mA cm &#8722;2 ) and excellent catalytic stability (200 h@500 mA cm &#8722;2 ). The turnover frequency value of Co 2.8 , W 3.8 &#8208;NiFe LDH can reach 4.02 s &#8722;1 at 1.49 V versus RHE, which is 9.6 times higher than that of NiFe LDH and superior to the noble metal catalysts. Moreover, it can achieve 1.0 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.86 V and maintain 300&#8208;h stable operation in anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer. Theoretical and experimental studies indicate that W sites promote the *OH adsorption and Co sites favor protons desorption of OH*. These dual cocatalytic sites jointly promote *O coverage, effectively accelerating alkaline OER kinetic.</description>
      <author>Yue Shi, Lumin Song, Yan Liu, Tiantian Wang, Caixia Li, Jianping Lai, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402046</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural, magnetic and electrocatalytic properties of rock salt oxide nanofibers (Ni0.2Mg0.2Zn0.2Cu0.2-xCo0.2+x)O produced by air-heated solution blow spinning (A-HSBS) for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161593</link>
      <description>Ronaldo M. Oliveira Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Mederios, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403590066

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ronaldo M. Oliveira Filho, Ricardo Francisco Alves, Rafael A. Raimundo, Johnnys da Silva Hort&#234;ncio, Caio M. S. Lopes, Emanuel Pereira do Nascimento, Allan J.M. Ara&#250;jo, Francisco J.A. Loureiro, U&#237;lame Umbelino Gomes, Eliton S. Mederios, Marco A. Morales, Daniel A. Macedo, Romualdo Rodrigues Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161593</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile fabrication of nickel selenide with manganese telluride (NiSe/MnTe) nanocomposite employed as strong electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00433-6</link>
      <description>Nirma Rasool, Haifa A. Alyousef, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Basel Al-Otaibi, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Khursheed Ahmad, Journal of the Korean Ceramic Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403596747

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nirma Rasool, Haifa A. Alyousef, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Basel Al-Otaibi, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Khursheed Ahmad</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43207-024-00433-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen-coordinated cobalt single atom Steered by Doped-O and CoO for efficient hydrogen evolution at industrial current densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156990</link>
      <description>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Ruyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Peng Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600199

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfeng Huang, Yantao Wang, Jian Li, Ruyu Xue, Lanyue Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Peng Zhang, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156990</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>D -Band Center Theory-Guided Mixed Metal Oxide-Based Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Ultra-Stable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994483</link>
      <description>Weipeng Zhao, Qicheng Zhang, P. W. Zhao, Bin Chen, Yang Li, Wenchao Peng, Xiaobin Fan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600651

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Weipeng Zhao, Qicheng Zhang, P. W. Zhao, Bin Chen, Yang Li, Wenchao Peng, Xiaobin Fan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biomass-Derived-Carbon-Supported Spinel Cobalt Molybdate as High-Efficiency Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29204953</link>
      <description>Baoli Wang, Xiujiu Yang, Yan Chen, Jiahan Wang, Mingguo Lan, Kai Tang, Feng Yang, Molecules. 29(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403603383

                Ananas comosus leaves were converted to a porous graphitized carbon (GPLC) material via a high-temperature pyrolysis method by employing iron salt as a catalyst. A cobalt molybdate (CoMoO4)-and-GPLC composite (CoMoO4/GPLC) was then prepared by engineering CoMoO4 nanorods in situ, grown on GPLC. N2 adsorption&#8211;desorption isothermal curves and a pore size distribution curve verify that the proposed composite possesses a porous structure and a large specific surface area, which are favorable for charge and reactant transport and the rapid escape of O2 bubbles. Consequently, the as-synthesized CoMoO4/GPLC shows low overpotentials of 289 mV and 399 mV to afford the current densities of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2 towards the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is superior to many CoMoO4-based catalysts in previous studies. In addition, the decrease in current density is particularly small, with a reduction rate of 3.2% after a continuous OER procedure for 30 h, indicating its good stability. The excellent performance of the CoMoO4/GPLC composite proves that the GPLC carrier can obviously impel the catalytic activity of CoMoO4 by improving electrical conductivity, enhancing mass transport and exposing more active sites of the composite. This work provides an effective strategy for the efficient conversion of waste ananas comosus leaves to a biomass-derived-carbon-supported Co-Mo-based OER electrocatalyst with good performance, which may represent a potential approach to the development of new catalysts for OER, as well as the treatment of waste biomass.</description>
      <author>Baoli Wang, Xiujiu Yang, Yan Chen, Jiahan Wang, Mingguo Lan, Kai Tang, Feng Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29204953</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrasmall RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; nanoparticles with robust interfacial interactions for the enhanced acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00719k</link>
      <description>Ming Wei, Liuhua Mu, Zhi&#8208;Wei Liu, Feng Gao, Guangjian Song, Qiankang Si, Mao Zhang, Fangfang Dai, Min Zhang, Rui Ding, Li Yang, Zhonggui Gao, Sanzhao Song, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403606874

                Ultrasmall RuO 2 /CoFe 2 O 4 nanoparticles with strong interfacial interactions exhibit enhanced oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance, driven by efficient charge transfer between RuO 2 and CoFe 2 O 4 .</description>
      <author>Ming Wei, Liuhua Mu, Zhi&#8208;Wei Liu, Feng Gao, Guangjian Song, Qiankang Si, Mao Zhang, Fangfang Dai, Min Zhang, Rui Ding, Li Yang, Zhonggui Gao, Sanzhao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00719k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Out-of-plane coordination of iridium single atoms with organic molecules and cobalt&#8211;iron hydroxides to boost oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-024-01807-x</link>
      <description>Jie Zhao, Yue Guo, Zhiqi Zhang, Xilin Zhang, Qianqian Ji, Han Zhang, Zhaoqi Song, Dongqing Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Erhuan Zhang, Yuhao Wang, Guangzhi Hu, Muhammad Asim Mushtaq, Waseem Raza, Xingke Cai, Francesco Ciucci, Nature Nanotechnology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403609594

                Abstract Advancements in single-atom-based catalysts are crucial for enhancing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance while reducing precious metal usage. A comprehensive understanding of underlying mechanisms will expedite this progress further. Here we report Ir single atoms coordinated out-of-plane with dimethylimidazole (MI) on CoFe hydroxide (Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI). This Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI catalyst, which was prepared using a simple immersion method, delivers ultralow overpotentials of 179 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and 257 mV at 600 mA cm &#8722;2 as well as an ultra-small Tafel slope of 24 mV dec &#8722;1 . Furthermore, Ir 1 /(Co,Fe)-OH/MI has a total mass activity exceeding that of commercial IrO 2 by a factor of 58.4. Ab initio simulations indicate that the coordination of MI leads to electron redistribution around the Ir sites. This causes a positive shift in the d -band centre at adjacent Ir and Co sites, facilitating an optimal energy pathway for OER.</description>
      <author>Jie Zhao, Yue Guo, Zhiqi Zhang, Xilin Zhang, Qianqian Ji, Han Zhang, Zhaoqi Song, Dongqing Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Cheng&#8208;Hao Chuang, Erhuan Zhang, Yuhao Wang, Guangzhi Hu, Muhammad Asim Mushtaq, Waseem Raza, Xingke Cai, Francesco Ciucci</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41565-024-01807-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Developments in Membrane&#8208;Free Hybrid Water Electrolysis for Low&#8208;Cost Hydrogen Production Along with Value&#8208;Added Products</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407845</link>
      <description>Neshanth Vadivel, Arun Prasad Murthy, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403610580

                Abstract Water electrolysis using renewable energy is considered as a promising technique for sustainable and green hydrogen production. Conventional water electrolysis has two components &#8211; hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) occurring at the cathode and anode respectively. However, electrolysis of water suffers from high overpotential due to the slow kinetics of OER. To overcome this hybrid water electrolysis has been developed by replacing conventional anode oxidation producing oxygen with oxidation of cost&#8208;effective materials producing value&#8208;added chemicals. This review summarizes recent advances in organic oxidative reactions such as alcohols, urea, hydrazine, and biomass at the anode instead of OER. Furthermore, the review also highlights the use of membrane&#8208;free hybrid water electrolysis as a method to overcome the cost and complexity associated with conventional membrane&#8208;based electrolyzer thereby improving overall efficiency. This approach holds promise for scalable and cost&#8208;effective large&#8208;scale hydrogen production along with value&#8208;added products. Finally, current challenges and future perspectives are discussed for further development in membrane&#8208;free hybrid water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Neshanth Vadivel, Arun Prasad Murthy</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202407845</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuCo@C Hollow Nanoprisms Derived from ZIF&#8208;67 for Enhanced Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401862</link>
      <description>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Samah A. Mahyoub, Fahim A. Qaraah, Abdo Hezam, Q.A. Drmosh, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403612479

                Zeolitic imidazolate frameworks (ZIFs) are commonly used to create complex hollow structures for energy applications. This study presents a simple method to produce a novel hollow nanoprism Co@C hierarchical composite from ZIF&#8208;67 through high&#8208;temperature treatment at 800 &#176;C. This composite serves as a platform for Ru nanoparticle deposition, forming RuCo@C hollow nanoprism (RuCo@C HNP). As an electrocatalyst in 1 M KOH, RuCo@C HNP exhibits excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance, with a low overpotential of 32 mV to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a Tafel slope of 39.67 mV dec&#8722;1, a high turnover frequency (TOF) of 3.83 s&#8722;1 at &#414;200, and stable performance over 50 h. It also achieves a low &#414;10 of 266 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with a Tafel slope of 45.22 mV dec&#8722;1. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that Ru doping in Ni/Co maintains a low water dissociation barrier, reduces the energy barrier for the OER rate&#8208;determining step, and creates active sites for H*, enhancing adsorption/desorption abilities. These results are attributed to the synergy between Co and Ru and the hollow prism structure's increased surface area. This method for synthesizing hollow structures using ZIF composites shows promise for applications in the energy sector.</description>
      <author>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Samah A. Mahyoub, Fahim A. Qaraah, Abdo Hezam, Q.A. Drmosh</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401862</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Conversion of Metal Organic Frameworks into Porous Rugby Phosphides by Plasma for Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03525</link>
      <description>Guochang Li, Mang Niu, Rongzheng An, Huayu Zhang, Bingxue Sun, Guoling Li, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403613070

                Electrolytic seawater is a green, sustainable, and promising approach for hydrogen production. Benefiting from the cost-effectiveness, crystal structures, and tailorable modification, transition metal phosphides become a highly attractive catalyst for the electrolysis of water. Considering the sufficient exposure and intrinsic catalytic activity of metal sites, here, carbon layer-coated NiFeP nanocrystals with a porous rugby structure are synthesized by Ar-H</description>
      <author>Guochang Li, Mang Niu, Rongzheng An, Huayu Zhang, Bingxue Sun, Guoling Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially Immobilized PtPdFeCoNi as an Excellent Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202414537</link>
      <description>Mingkuan Xie, Yu Lu, Xinke Xiao, Duojie Wu, Bing Shao, Hao Nian, Chunsheng Wu, Wenjuan Wang, Jun Gu, Songbai Han, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615140

                Abstract Developing efficient oxygen electrocatalysts with low cost, high catalytic activity, and robust stability remains a formidable challenge for rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Herein, highly dispersed ultrasmall PtPdFeCoNi high&#8208;entropy alloy nanoparticles with a size of &#8776; 2 nm and randomly distributed multimetallic single atoms spatially immobilized on the 3D hierarchically ordered porous nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon skeleton (denoted as PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC) are successfully synthesized via ultra&#8208;rapid Joule heating process. The spatial immobilization on 3D HOPNC skeleton is the key to the high dispersion of multi&#8208;active sites of oxygen electrocatalysts, and the formed hierarchical pore structure is conducive to the successful construction of the rapid mass transfer channel. As a result, the as&#8208;prepared PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC exhibits a positive half&#8208;wave potential of 0.866 V versus RHE for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), a low overpotential of 310 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and low Tafel slopes for both ORR and OER. Furthermore, ZAB using PtPdFeCoNi/HOPNC as bifunctional oxygen catalysts exhibits excellent rate performances and superior cycling stability, surpassing that of a commercial Pt/C&#8208;RuO 2 mixture. The spatial immobilization strategy of HOPNC provides a new idea for the design and synthesis of efficient catalysts for various applications.</description>
      <author>Mingkuan Xie, Yu Lu, Xinke Xiao, Duojie Wu, Bing Shao, Hao Nian, Chunsheng Wu, Wenjuan Wang, Jun Gu, Songbai Han, Meng Gu, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202414537</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c</link>
      <description>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615829

                The design of efficient and active electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for renewable energy generation. Here, crystalline iron-doped nickel sulfide core, amorphous iron-doped nickel phosphate shell heterostructured...</description>
      <author>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced oxygen evolution performance by single metal (tungsten, nickel and manganese) atom oxides anchored nanorods of CeO2-MnO2-rGO as electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105800</link>
      <description>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Yueshuai Wang, Tae Hwan Oh, Vanthana Jeyasingh, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, M. Swaminathan, Journal of the Taiwan Institute of Chemical Engineers. 165(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403623601

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Karuppaiah Selvakumar, M. Arunpandian, Yueshuai Wang, Tae Hwan Oh, Vanthana Jeyasingh, Aboud Ahmed Awadh Bahajjaj, M. Swaminathan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jtice.2024.105800</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asymmetric Site-Enabled O&#8211;O Coupling in Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</link>
      <description>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403624087

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Minghui Cui, Rongjing Guo, Yansong Zhou, Wenqi Zhao, Yanjing Liu, Wenbo Luo, Qiongrong Ou, Shuyu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04164</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Spin Channels in SrCoO3 through Triagonal&#8208;to&#8208;Cubic Structural Transformation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415797</link>
      <description>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403627497

                Oxygen evolution and reduction reactions (OER and ORR) play crucial roles in energy conversion processes such as water splitting and air batteries, where spin dynamics inherently influence their efficiency. However, the specific contribution of spin has yet to be fully understood. In this study, we intentionally introduce a spin channel through the transformation of trigonal antiferromagnetic SrCoO2.5 into cubic ferromagnetic SrCoO3, aiming to deepen our understanding of spin dynamics in catalytic reactions. Based on the results from spherical&#8208;aberration&#8208;corrected microscope, synchrotron absorption spectra, magnetic characterizations, and density functional theory calculations, it is revealed that surface electron transfer is predominantly governed by local geometric structures, while the presence of the spin channel significantly enhances the bulk transport of spin&#8208;polarized electrons, particularly under high current densities where surface electron transfer is no longer the limiting factor. The overpotential for OER is reduced by at least 70 mV at 150 mA cm&#8208;2 due to the enhanced conductivity from spin&#8208;polarized electrons facilitated by spin channels, with an expectation of even more significant reductions at higher current densities. This work provides a clearer picture of the role of spin in oxygen&#8208;involved electrocatalysis, providing critical insights for the design of more efficient catalytic systems in practical applications.</description>
      <author>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629653

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629654

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629734

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629769

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403629815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeyi Wang, Shuling Liu, Chenglong Wang, Dan Ren, Yanling Hu, Wei Ma, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403630496

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Iron-doped nickel sulfide @ phosphate heterostructures nanosheets constructed by solvothermal P2S5 and layered double hydroxides for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403630497

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta06350c/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemistry of Nickelocene-Ferrocene Organometallic Complexes for Electrodeposition of Nickel&#8211;Iron&#8211;Based Nanostructured Film under Ambient Conditions for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04084</link>
      <description>Kamlesh, Parul Aggarwal, Manish Mudgal, Avanish Kumar Srivastava, Pankaj Raizada, Archana Singh, Amit Paul, Archana Singh, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633314

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kamlesh, Parul Aggarwal, Manish Mudgal, Avanish Kumar Srivastava, Pankaj Raizada, Archana Singh, Amit Paul, Archana Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04084</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A facile synthesis of N-doped carbon encapsulated multimetallic carbonitride as a robust electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.120</link>
      <description>Xiaojuan Cao, Haozhou Feng, Yu Lin, Lei Shi, Ning Yan, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaojuan Cao, Haozhou Feng, Yu Lin, Lei Shi, Ning Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Coprecipitation-Thermal Synthesis of Nano-Ni-Co Alloy for Efficient Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00902-w</link>
      <description>Yuanjun Sun, Zelin Li, Zhu Fei, Yin Fei, Songwei Ge, Fairy Fan Yang, Lili Gao, Guoju Chen, Fan Yang, PingAn Hu, Electrocatalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403638522

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuanjun Sun, Zelin Li, Zhu Fei, Yin Fei, Songwei Ge, Fairy Fan Yang, Lili Gao, Guoju Chen, Fan Yang, PingAn Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12678-024-00902-w</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In&#8208;situ Reconstruction of Catalyst in Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411688</link>
      <description>Jinxian Feng, X.&#8208;S. Wang, Hui Pan, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403645863

                Abstract Reconstruction of catalysts is now well recognized as a common phenomenon in electrocatalysis. As the reconstructed structure may promote or hamper the electrochemical performance, how to achieve the designed active surface for highly enhanced catalytic activity through the reconstruction needs to be carefully investigated. In this review, the genesis and electrochemical effects of reconstruction in various electrochemical catalytic processes, such as hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CO 2 RR), and nitrate reduction reaction (NO 3 RR) are first described. Then, the strategies for optimizing the reconstruction, such as valence states control, active phase retention, phase evolution engineering, and surface poisoning prevention are comprehensively discussed. Finally, the general rules of reconstruction optimization are summarized and give perspectives for future study. It is believed that the review shall provide deep insights into electrocatalytic mechanisms and guide the design of pre&#8208;catalysts with highly improved activity.</description>
      <author>Jinxian Feng, X.&#8208;S. Wang, Hui Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202411688</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrospun Co&#8208;MoC Nanoparticles Embedded in Carbon Nanofibers for Highly Efficient pH&#8208;Universal Hydrogen Evolution Reaction and Alkaline Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401103</link>
      <description>Shan Zhang, Fuhe Le, Wei Jia, Xue Yang, Pengfei Hu, Xueyan Wu, Wanting Shu, Yanmei Xie, Wuyang Xiao, Dianzeng Jia, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403646373

                Abstract The construction of highly efficient and self&#8208;supported electrocatalysts with abundant active sites for pH&#8208;universal hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and alkaline water splitting is significantly challenging. Herein, Co and MoC nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen&#8208;doped carbon nanofibers (Co&#8208;MoC/NCNFs) which display a bamboo&#8208;like morphology are prepared by electrospinning followed by the carbonization method. The electrospun MoC possesses an ultrasmall size (&#8776;5 nm) which can provide more active sites during electrocatalysis, while the introduction of Co greatly optimizes the electronic structure of MoC. Both endow the Co&#8208;MoC/NCNFs with superior HER performances over a wide pH range, with low overpotentials of 86, 116, and 145 mV to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline, acidic, and neutral media, respectively. Additionally, the catalyst exhibits remarkable alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity with an overpotential of 254 mV to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Density functional theory calculations confirm that electron transfer from Co to MoC regulates the adsorption free energy for hydrogen, thereby promoting HER. Moreover, an electrolyzer assembled with Co&#8208;MoC/NCNFs requires only a cell voltage of 1.59 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in 1 m KOH. This work opens new pathways for the design of high&#8208;efficiency electrocatalysts for energy conversion applications.</description>
      <author>Shan Zhang, Fuhe Le, Wei Jia, Xue Yang, Pengfei Hu, Xueyan Wu, Wanting Shu, Yanmei Xie, Wuyang Xiao, Dianzeng Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-Cobalt Spinel-Based Oxygen Evolution Electrode for Zinc-Air Flow Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4995648</link>
      <description>P&#345;emysl Richtr, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Ji&#345;&#237; Charv&#225;t, Martin Bure&#353;, Jarom&#237;r Pocedi&#269;, Martin Paidar, Juraj Ko&#353;ek, Petr Maz&#250;r, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403647198

                No abstract</description>
      <author>P&#345;emysl Richtr, Jarom&#237;r Hn&#225;t, Ji&#345;&#237; Charv&#225;t, Martin Bure&#353;, Jarom&#237;r Pocedi&#269;, Martin Paidar, Juraj Ko&#353;ek, Petr Maz&#250;r</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4995648</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recognizing the Reactive Site of SnFe2O4 for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Synergistic Effect of SnII and FeIII in Stabilizing Reaction Intermediates</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03107e</link>
      <description>Anubha Rajput, Pandiyan Sivasakthi, Pralok K. Samanta, Biswarup Chakraborty, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403648589

                Among the reported spinel ferrites, the p-block metal containing SnFe2O4 is scarcely explored, but it is a promising water-splitting electrocatalyst. This study focuses on the reaction kinetics and atomic scale...</description>
      <author>Anubha Rajput, Pandiyan Sivasakthi, Pralok K. Samanta, Biswarup Chakraborty</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr03107e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Photo&#8208;Assisted Zinc&#8211;Air Battery with MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Oxygen Vacancies Rich TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction Photocathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408627</link>
      <description>Yongjian Wu, Yi Ding, Mengyu Chen, Hui Zhang, Yu Jing, Tongtong Jiang, Mingzai Wu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403657995

                Abstract Converting solar energy into electrochemical energy is a sustainable strategy, but the design of photo&#8208;assisted zinc&#8211;air battery (ZAB) with efficient utilization of sunlight faces huge challenges. Herein, a photo&#8208;assisted ZAB of a three&#8208;electrode system using MoS 2 /oxygen vacancies&#8208;rich TiO 2 heterojunction as charge cathode and Fe, N&#8208;doped carbon matrix (FeNC) as discharge cathode is constructed, where MoS 2 is chosen as solar light&#8208;responsive catalytic material and TiO 2 acts as electron transport layer and hole blocking layer, arising from a train of thought for efficient charging under sunlight irradiation and light&#8208;independent discharging. The introduction of oxygen vacancies in TiO 2 facilitates the temporary trapping of carriers and triggers rapid carrier transfer at the interface of the heterojunction, which hinders the recombination of photogenerated holes, thereby facilitating their further participation in the oxygen evolution reaction. Moreover, FeNC exhibits superior oxygen reduction reaction performance due to strong d&#8208;&#960; interactions. As a result, the well&#8208;built ZABs deliver a low charge voltage (0.71 V) under illumination at 0.1 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a high power density (167.6 mW cm &#8722;2 ) in dark. This work paves a special way for the development of ZABs by directly harvesting solar energy in charging and efficiently discharging regardless of lighting conditions.</description>
      <author>Yongjian Wu, Yi Ding, Mengyu Chen, Hui Zhang, Yu Jing, Tongtong Jiang, Mingzai Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408627</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning of Oxygen Vacancies in Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Electrocatalyst for Effectiveness in Urea Oxidation and Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403744</link>
      <description>Pandian Mannu, Ranjith Kumar Dharman, Ta Thi Thuy Nga, Athibala Mariappan, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yucheng Huang, Asokan Kandasami, Tae Hwan Oh, Wu&#8208;Ching Chou, Chi&#8208;Liang Chen, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403658604

                Abstract The development of an excellent multifunctional electrocatalyst that is based on non&#8208;precious metal is critical for improving the electrochemical processes of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and the urea oxidation reaction (UOR) in alkaline media. This study demonstrates that incorporating Mo into Co 3 O 4 facilitated the formation of rich oxygen vacancies (Vo), which promotes effective nitrate adsorption and activation in urea electrolysis. Subsequently, in situ/operando X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy is used to explore the active sites in Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 &#8208;3 under OER, indicating the oxygen vacancies are first filled with OH &#8226; in Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 ; facilitated the pre&#8208;oxidation of low&#8208;valence Co, and promoted the reconstruction/deprotonation of intermediate Co&#8208;OOH &#8226; . Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 &#8208;3 electrocatalysts show impressive HER, OER, and UOR with low overpotentials of 141 mV, 220 mV, and 1.32 V, respectively, at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 in an alkaline medium. Furthermore, in situ/Operando Raman spectroscopy results reveal the importance of CoOOH active sites for enhanced electrochemical performance in Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 &#8208;3 compared to the pure Co 3 O 4 . The urea electrolyzer with Mo&#8208;Co 3 O 4 electrocatalysts acts as an anode and the cathode delivers 1.42 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . A viable approach to creating effective UOR electrocatalysts involves synergistic engineering exploiting doping and oxygen vacancies.</description>
      <author>Pandian Mannu, Ranjith Kumar Dharman, Ta Thi Thuy Nga, Athibala Mariappan, Yu&#8208;Cheng Shao, Hirofumi Ishii, Yucheng Huang, Asokan Kandasami, Tae Hwan Oh, Wu&#8208;Ching Chou, Chi&#8208;Liang Chen, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Chung&#8208;Li Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403744</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rutile-structured high-entropy oxyfluorides: A platform for oxygen evolution catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.009</link>
      <description>Shengliang Qi, Kaixin Zhu, Ting Xu, Weiguang Ma, Xu Zong, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403660312

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shengliang Qi, Kaixin Zhu, Ting Xu, Weiguang Ma, Xu Zong</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.10.009</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on Titanate Perovskites with Different Morphologies for Oxygen-evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.10.306</link>
      <description>Jin Goo Lee, Ceramics International. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403660645

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jin Goo Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.10.306</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline media using Co-spinels and stainless steel based electrodes</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4403664806</link>
      <description>Garance Cossard, Gw&#233;na&#235;lle K&#233;rangu&#233;ven, Elena R. Savinova, Marian Chatenet, &#201;ric Sibert, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403664806

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Garance Cossard, Gw&#233;na&#235;lle K&#233;rangu&#233;ven, Elena R. Savinova, Marian Chatenet, &#201;ric Sibert</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4403664806</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar-Boosted Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Via a 2d/2d Heterostructure Constructed by Integrating Reduced Graphene Oxide on Nife-Ldh Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4993388</link>
      <description>Qian Liu, Jinyi Wang, Yuxia Zhang, Wa Gao, Hongzhi Cui, Jingxiang Low, Haiming Zhang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403667387

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qian Liu, Jinyi Wang, Yuxia Zhang, Wa Gao, Hongzhi Cui, Jingxiang Low, Haiming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4993388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating oxygen vacancies to optimize the electronic structure and catalytic activity of tungsten oxides for hydrogen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.287</link>
      <description>Jun Yang, Pengfei Jia, Yifan Cao, Peng Yu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403669922

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Yang, Pengfei Jia, Yifan Cao, Peng Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.287</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tetrahydroxybenzoquinone-Based Two-Dimensional Conductive Metal&#8211;Organic Framework via &#960;-d Conjugation Modulation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04977</link>
      <description>Yantao Wang, Xiaowan Bai, Junfeng Huang, Wangzu Li, Jinhua Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403671924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yantao Wang, Xiaowan Bai, Junfeng Huang, Wangzu Li, Jinhua Zhang, Hua Li, Yu Long, Yong Peng, Cailing Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04977</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The latest advances in the deep reconstruction of pre-catalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177225</link>
      <description>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403679718

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Haibin Wang, Hongxin Wang, Qiming Hu, Biao Wang, Xuefei Lei, Junhua You, Rui Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Study of Zinc Sulfide, Tin Selenide, and Their Composite Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Towards Efficient and Stable Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145279</link>
      <description>Rida Fatima, Kareem Yusuf, Muhammad Shuaib Khan, Mehar Un Nisa, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403681815

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rida Fatima, Kareem Yusuf, Muhammad Shuaib Khan, Mehar Un Nisa</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.145279</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effects in LaNiO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Perovskites between Nickel and Iron Heterostructures for Improving Durability in Oxygen Evolution Reaction for AEMWE (Small Methods 9/2024)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202470051</link>
      <description>Nam In Kim, Jun Ho Lee, Song Jin, Junyoung Park, Jae&#8208;Yeop Jeong, Jooyoung Lee, Young Do Kim, Chiho Kim, Sung Mook Choi, Small Methods. 8(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403684356

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nam In Kim, Jun Ho Lee, Song Jin, Junyoung Park, Jae&#8208;Yeop Jeong, Jooyoung Lee, Young Do Kim, Chiho Kim, Sung Mook Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202470051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress in carbon-free oxygen evolution electrocatalysts for high-current-density water electrolysis in acid media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05278a</link>
      <description>Haowen Xu, R. Liu, Jinxiu Zhao, Konghu Tian, Hongyu Gong, Linrui Hou, Changzhou Yuan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403689258

                Hydrogen production by water electrolysis technology has received great attention toward global mission of carbon neutrality. Industrial proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzers stand out from other water electrolysis techniques due...</description>
      <author>Haowen Xu, R. Liu, Jinxiu Zhao, Konghu Tian, Hongyu Gong, Linrui Hou, Changzhou Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05278a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decrypting Synergy of Alloy &amp;amp; Metal Nanoparticles Within Nitrogen&#8208;Doped Carbon Nanosheets for Zn&#8208;Air Batteries with Ultralong Cycling Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401338</link>
      <description>Baoyu Qing, Yijiang Liu, Duanguang Yang, Mei Yang, Bei Liu, Hongbiao Chen, Huaming Li, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403690200

                Abstract The exploration of efficient, robust, and low&#8208;cost bifunctional electrocatalysts to drive the commercial application of Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs) is of great significance but still remains a challenge. Herein, a 1D coordination polymer (1D&#8208;CP) derived FeNi alloy &amp; Co nanoparticles (NPs) co&#8208;implanted N&#8208;doped carbon nanosheets (FNC/NCS) is judiciously crafted and employed as a high&#8208;performance electrocatalyst for ultralong lifetime ZABs. The key to this strategy is the leveraging of metal&#8208;coordinated melamine to direct the pyrolysis of 1D&#8208;CP, enabling the in situ formation of well&#8208;dispersed FeNi alloy and Co NPs within the carbon matrix. The resulting FNC/NCS exhibits prominent oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity with a small overall oxygen potential difference (&#916;E = 0.68 V). Density functional theory (DFT) simulation demonstrates that the synergistic effect between FeNi alloy and Co NPs can reduce energy barriers, promote electron transfer, and optimize the formation of crucial intermediates, thereby largely boost ORR/OER activity of FNC/NCS. The FNC/NCS&#8208;assembled ZABs possess high specific capacity, large power density, and ultralong cycling life in both aqueous (&gt; 3300 h) and solid&#8208;state (150 h) electrolytes. This work provides a viable strategy for 1D&#8208;CP&#8208;derived bifunctional electrocatalysts and dissects the synergistic effect between different metal species, affording significant guidance for the development of renewable energy materials.</description>
      <author>Baoyu Qing, Yijiang Liu, Duanguang Yang, Mei Yang, Bei Liu, Hongbiao Chen, Huaming Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202401338</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet Engineering of Cobalt Manganese Oxide for Highly Stable Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402786</link>
      <description>Chi-Wing Lee, Claudio Cazorla, Yingtang Zhou, Ding Zhang, Hanyu Xu, Wenyu Zhong, Mingxing Zhang, Dewei Chu, Zhaojun Han, Rose Amal, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403699810

                Abstract Developing cost&#8208;effective, robust, and durable catalysts for water oxidation in acidic conditions remains a significant challenge for the practical application of proton exchange membrane electrolyzers. Cobalt&#8208;based spinel catalysts, known for their effective oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity in acidic environments, are promising alternatives to the costly iridium&#8208;based catalysts. However, their application is often limited by poor stability under corrosive acidic conditions and oxidative potential. Here it is demonstrated that doping Co 2 MnO 4 with Ni effectively regulates the structural and electronic properties of the catalysts, enabling stable operation for over 285 h at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 . This stability enhancement is primarily due to the increased exposure of the (400) facet, a result supported by theoretical studies. The proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE) performance of Ni(5%)Co 2 MnO 4 further demonstrates its potential, achieving 1 A cm &#8722; 2 at a cell voltage of 2.3 V, with minimal degradation over 100 h at 500 mA cm &#8722; 2 . This study not only provides insights into the design of advanced OER catalysts through the doping of heteroatoms but also offers a pathway to enhance the sustainability and economic viability of acidic OER applications.</description>
      <author>Chi-Wing Lee, Claudio Cazorla, Yingtang Zhou, Ding Zhang, Hanyu Xu, Wenyu Zhong, Mingxing Zhang, Dewei Chu, Zhaojun Han, Rose Amal</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402786</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strategic Defect Engineering Enabled Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Reconstructed Metal&#8208;Organic Frameworks</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202412406</link>
      <description>Yinqiang Zhang, Ming Liu, Letian Zhang, Nan L&#252;, Xuemin Wang, Zhigang Li, Xinghao Zhang, Na Li, Xian&#8208;He Bu, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403699912

                Abstract Metal&#8208;organic frameworks (MOFs) have emerged as promising pre&#8208;catalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their marvelous structural reconstruction process in strongly alkaline media. However, targeting design MOF structures to achieve excellent OER performance of reconstructed products is a challenge. Here, a strategic defect engineering is used to promote the OER performance of reconstructed products. Briefly, modified linkers with monocarboxylic acids (ferrocene carboxylic acid, FcCA) are incorporated into MOF (NiBDC&#8208;FcCA), leading to its stepwise reconstruction into Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 and NiOOH during the OER process, with the oxygen vacancy and strategic doping of metal Fe persisting throughout the multi&#8208;step reconstruction. Benefiting from the synergistic interaction of oxygen vacancies and Fe doping, NiBDC&#8208;FcCA delivers the extremely enhanced current density at 1.6 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode by &#8776;9 times compared with that of NiBDC. Moreover, the optimized NiBDC&#8208;FcCA/Fe foam exhibits excellent OER catalytic activity and stability with a low overpotential of 250 mV at 200 mA cm &#8722;2 and negligible activity decay after 1200 h at 1 A cm &#8722;2 . Density function theory calculations reveal that Fe doping weakens the interaction of oxygen intermediate with Ni sites, favoring the formation of OOH* to accelerate the OER process.</description>
      <author>Yinqiang Zhang, Ming Liu, Letian Zhang, Nan L&#252;, Xuemin Wang, Zhigang Li, Xinghao Zhang, Na Li, Xian&#8208;He Bu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202412406</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bioinspired Oxygen-Evolution Reaction: Achieving Oxygen-Evolution Reaction on Layered Manganese-Oxide Surface with Extremely Low Overpotential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02187</link>
      <description>Maryam Gharedaghloo, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403705363

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Maryam Gharedaghloo, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c02187</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Cationic Cobalt Vacancies in Molybdenum&#8211;Cobalt Selenide Derived from POM@ZIF-67 for Enhanced Electrocatalysis in Lithium&#8211;Oxygen Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03299</link>
      <description>Yongming Zhu, Hong Sun, Tianyu Zhang, Qiang Li, Zhichao Xue, Mingfu Yu, Jie Li, Li Wang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403706668

                Slow reaction kinetics during redox reactions limits the utilization of the high theoretical energy density of lithium-oxygen batteries (LOBs). Vacancy engineering, a potential strategy for modulating active sites, is critical in the development of high performance catalysts. This study investigates cobalt vacancies in Mo-CoSe</description>
      <author>Yongming Zhu, Hong Sun, Tianyu Zhang, Qiang Li, Zhichao Xue, Mingfu Yu, Jie Li, Li Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c03299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plasma Assisted Single-Step Synthesis of Carbon-Coated SrFe2O4 Electrodes for Enhancing Supercapacitor and Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105339</link>
      <description>Lakshmanan Kumaresan, Amarnath Pasupathi, B. Narayanan, Yugeswaran Subramaniam, G. Shanmugavelayutham, Surfaces and Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403707551

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lakshmanan Kumaresan, Amarnath Pasupathi, B. Narayanan, Yugeswaran Subramaniam, G. Shanmugavelayutham</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.105339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailored IrO2@ZIF-67 nanocomposites for efficient oxygen evolution reaction: Insights into catalyst design and performance enhancement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.255</link>
      <description>Seyeon Cho, Komal Patil, So Young Lee, Daim Choe, Yujin Cho, Jincheol Kim, Jae Sung Yun, Dong Han Seo, Jongsung Park, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403712536

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Seyeon Cho, Komal Patil, So Young Lee, Daim Choe, Yujin Cho, Jincheol Kim, Jae Sung Yun, Dong Han Seo, Jongsung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/crystalline Ni-Fe based electrodes with rich oxygen vacancies enable highly active oxygen evolution in seawater electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.128</link>
      <description>Jingcheng Zhang, Xinru Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403714494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingcheng Zhang, Xinru Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.10.128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toward High Corrosion Resistivity and High Efficiency in Seawater Oxygen Evolution: The Synergy of Fe and Ni Dopants in Co Layered Double Hydroxide Ultrathin Nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06117</link>
      <description>Cheng Luo, Dandan Cai, Yang Yang, Shipeng Geng, Yi Wang, Shuqin Song, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403716296

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cheng Luo, Dandan Cai, Yang Yang, Shipeng Geng, Yi Wang, Shuqin Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c06117</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe-Co bimetallic electrocatalysts atomically dispersed on zeolitic imidazolate frameworks (ZIFs) to enhance oxygen reduction reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0236710</link>
      <description>Narumon Jongmanwattana, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, Konlayutt Punyawudho, AIP conference proceedings. 3236(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403725810

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Narumon Jongmanwattana, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, Konlayutt Punyawudho</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0236710</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Valence electronic engineering of hollow-nanocube-structured CoFeNi-layered double hydroxides for highly efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156764</link>
      <description>H. Liu, Lingxing Zan, Yunchuan Tu, Hongling Zhang, Dan Zhu, Zhe Li, Jiawen Zheng, Zhuangzhuang Zhang, Yu Sun, Qihao Weng, Jian Li, Qingbo Wei, Huicong Xia, Xin Bo, Feng Fu, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728038

                No abstract</description>
      <author>H. Liu, Lingxing Zan, Yunchuan Tu, Hongling Zhang, Dan Zhu, Zhe Li, Jiawen Zheng, Zhuangzhuang Zhang, Yu Sun, Qihao Weng, Jian Li, Qingbo Wei, Huicong Xia, Xin Bo, Feng Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.156764</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating metal-oxygen covalency of TiO2 by Ru doping and phase transition for boosted hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177239</link>
      <description>Fengting Li, Nannan Cui, Yanan Zhou, Shuangqing Sun, Chunling Li, Zhikun Wang, Songqing Hu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403741271

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fengting Li, Nannan Cui, Yanan Zhou, Shuangqing Sun, Chunling Li, Zhikun Wang, Songqing Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.177239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superior Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activities of Highly Crystalline Ni&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;-LDH (0.20 &#8804; &lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt; &#8804; 0.51) Synthesized Using Soft Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05347h</link>
      <description>Atsunori Ikezawa, Shinji Koito, Hajime Arai, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403742483

                Developing oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is an urgent issue for the practical application of electrochemical devices such as water electrolysers and rechargeable batteries. NiFe-based layered double hydroxides (NiFe-LDH) are...</description>
      <author>Atsunori Ikezawa, Shinji Koito, Hajime Arai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta05347h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chirality Engineering of Nanostructured Copper Oxide for Enhancing Oxygen Evolution from Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</link>
      <description>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745745

                Abstract The exploration of a new conceptual strategy for improving the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) of earth&#8208;abundant electrocatalysts is critical. In this study, chiral copper oxide nanoflower is explored by a self&#8208;assembly method. The characterization suggests the chiral structure originates from the crystal plane&#8208;level helical stack of the secondary nanosheets. Of note, the assembly illustrates a record&#8208;high degree of spin polarization of 96%, indicating the ideal alignment of electron spin. Moreover, density function theory calculations show the chiral structure reducing the reaction energy barrier (REB) while switching the potential&#8208;determining step from *O&#8594;*OOH to *OH&#8594;*O. Together with the enhanced electrochemical active surface area and accelerated charge transfer, the production of ground&#8208;state triplet O 2 is improved via a spin&#8208;forbidden route that involves the singlet H 2 O/OH&#8226;. Consequently, the chiral nanoflower shows a overpotential of 308 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 93.5 mV dec &#8722;1 , which is even superior to the commercial RuO 2 (310 mV, 101 mV dec &#8722;1 ). This study presents a new strategy for improving the OER activity by simultaneously enhancing electronic properties and lowering the REB of an non&#8208;noble electrocatalyst via chirality engineering.</description>
      <author>Ying Li, Liang Qiu, Rui Tian, Zhongli Liu, Lin Yao, Lufei Huang, Wei Li, Yuyin Wang, Tao Wang, Baowen Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202408248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screening of agroindustry residues for their usage as oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114527</link>
      <description>Aida M. D&#237;ez, Mar&#237;a Bola&#241;os-V&#225;zquez, S. Chiussi, Marta Pazos, M.&#193;. Sanrom&#225;n, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403626228

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aida M. D&#237;ez, Mar&#237;a Bola&#241;os-V&#225;zquez, S. Chiussi, Marta Pazos, M.&#193;. Sanrom&#225;n</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.114527</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Spin Channels in SrCoO3 through Triagonal&#8208;to&#8208;Cubic Structural Transformation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution/Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415797</link>
      <description>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403627665

                Oxygen evolution and reduction reactions (OER and ORR) play crucial roles in energy conversion processes such as water splitting and air batteries, where spin dynamics inherently influence their efficiency. However, the specific contribution of spin has yet to be fully understood. In this study, we intentionally introduce a spin channel through the transformation of trigonal antiferromagnetic SrCoO2.5 into cubic ferromagnetic SrCoO3, aiming to deepen our understanding of spin dynamics in catalytic reactions. Based on the results from spherical&#8208;aberration&#8208;corrected microscope, synchrotron absorption spectra, magnetic characterizations, and density functional theory calculations, it is revealed that surface electron transfer is predominantly governed by local geometric structures, while the presence of the spin channel significantly enhances the bulk transport of spin&#8208;polarized electrons, particularly under high current densities where surface electron transfer is no longer the limiting factor. The overpotential for OER is reduced by at least 70 mV at 150 mA cm&#8208;2 due to the enhanced conductivity from spin&#8208;polarized electrons facilitated by spin channels, with an expectation of even more significant reductions at higher current densities. This work provides a clearer picture of the role of spin in oxygen&#8208;involved electrocatalysis, providing critical insights for the design of more efficient catalytic systems in practical applications.</description>
      <author>Xinwei Guan, Mingyue Wang, Zezhi Chen, Chaojie Cao, Zhixuan Li, Ruichang Xue, Yang Fu, Bernt Johannessen, Anton Tadich, Jiabao Yi, Hua Fan, Nana Wang, Baohua Jia, Xiaoning Li, Tianyi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Entropy Metallic-High Entropy Nonmetallic Community as High Performance Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc05326e</link>
      <description>Chunyan Zhang, Hang Li, Mengfei Su, Shengfa Li, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403607529

                The multi-element synergism in high-entropy materials (HEMs) provides great opportunities to promote the tandem reaction or meet the requirement of multi-functional catalysts. Herein, a high entropy precursor strategy is proposed...</description>
      <author>Chunyan Zhang, Hang Li, Mengfei Su, Shengfa Li, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc05326e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Oxygen Evolution Performance by Introducing Pd-Cu Alloy Supported Rod-Like Hollow Titanium Dioxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4995223</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Mingying Zhao, Lei E, Dan Zhao, Chengyi Wang, Zhifeng Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403659770

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Mingying Zhao, Lei E, Dan Zhao, Chengyi Wang, Zhifeng Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4995223</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of High-Valence Metal Dissolution in Oxygen Evolution Kinetics of the Advanced FeNiO&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04454</link>
      <description>Jun Ke, Jiaxi Zhang, Longhai Zhang, Shunyi He, Chengzhi Zhong, Li Du, Jiajun Huang, Xiaoming Fang, Zhengguo Zhang, Zhiming Cui, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403624235

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Ke, Jiaxi Zhang, Longhai Zhang, Shunyi He, Chengzhi Zhong, Li Du, Jiajun Huang, Xiaoming Fang, Zhengguo Zhang, Zhiming Cui</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c04454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur Doping and Heterostructure on Nise@Co(Oh)2 with Facilitated Surface Reconstruction and Interfacial Electron Regulation to Boost Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994506</link>
      <description>Fei Nie, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Xiaodan Chong, Xiaoping Dai, Yikai Yang, Jinsheng Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403600648

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Nie, Jing&#8208;Hong Wen, Xiaodan Chong, Xiaoping Dai, Yikai Yang, Jinsheng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4994506</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ab initio calculations of high-entropy clusters for oxygen reduction and evolution as well as CO2 reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161555</link>
      <description>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403561270

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mohsen Tamtaji, Mohammad Kazemeini, Jafar Abdi</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.161555</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N-doped carbon decorated by Cu3P nanoparticle derived from Aspartic acid - Cu MOF as suitable catalysts for oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.261</link>
      <description>Elham Soltani, Mohammad Bagher Gholivand, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 92(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403655663

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Elham Soltani, Mohammad Bagher Gholivand</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.10.261</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction/Evolution Reaction Activity of Transition Metal-Doped T-C&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Monolayer: A Density Functional Theory Study Assisted by Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04467</link>
      <description>Jing Zhang, Lin Ju, Zhenjie Tang, Shu Zhang, Genqiang Zhang, Wentao Wang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403674764

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Zhang, Lin Ju, Zhenjie Tang, Shu Zhang, Genqiang Zhang, Wentao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04467</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Electrocatalytic Activity of Bifunctional Iron&#8208;Niobium Double Perovskites for Overall Water Splitting: A&#8208;Site Cation Influence</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400559</link>
      <description>Celal Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Maged F. Bekheet, Suna Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Figen Kaya, Byung Chul Kim, Cengiz Kaya, Aleksander Gurlo, Advanced Materials Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403699860

                Abstract Capitalizing on the electrochemical conversion of water into hydrogen stands as a pivotal strategy in the global transition toward sustainable energy sources. This study investigates the influence of the A&#8208;site cation type within A 2 FeNbO 6 double perovskites (where A = Ca, Sr, or Ba) on their bifunctional electrocatalytic activities. The electrocatalytic performance is scrutinized in relation to charge transfer resistance, oxygen vacancy concentration, and metal&#8208;oxygen covalency. Among the variants, Sr 2 FeNbO 6 is distinguished as the optimal catalyst, achieving a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 at overpotentials of 260 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and 176 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), thus matching the performance of leading metal oxide electrocatalysts. The study reveals pH&#8208;dependent kinetics for Sr 2 FeNbO 6 , indicative of a lattice oxygen evolution mechanism for OER. An electrolyzer employing Sr 2 FeNbO 6 electrodes for both the anode and cathode delivers a current density of 10 mA cm&#8315; 2 at an efficient cell voltage of 1.76 V for complete alkaline water splitting, while also demonstrating exceptional stability. These insights advance the understanding of material optimization for electrocatalysis and position Sr 2 FeNbO 6 as a viable catalyst for the sustainable production of hydrogen.</description>
      <author>Celal Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Maged F. Bekheet, Suna Avc&#305;o&#287;lu, Figen Kaya, Byung Chul Kim, Cengiz Kaya, Aleksander Gurlo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/admi.202400559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ir Doping Modulates the Electronic Structure of Flower-Shaped Phosphides for Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</link>
      <description>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633322

                Electrolysis of water to produce hydrogen is an efficient, clean, and environmentally friendly hydrogen production method with unlimited development prospects. However, its overall efficiency is hampered by the slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with complex electron transfer processes. Therefore, designing efficient and low-cost OER catalysts is the key to solving this problem. In this paper, Ir-doped Co</description>
      <author>Huiyu Sun, Shudi Yu, Jiongting Yin, Jie Li, Jun Yu, Tianpeng Liu, Wanyu Liang, Nannan Zhang, Yangping Zhang, Changqing Ye, Mengyun Hu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c03771</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile Synthesis of Metal/Carbide Hybrid toward Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100730</link>
      <description>Jinpeng Mo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang, Catalysts. 14(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403601518

                The development of cost-effective and high-performance bifunctional catalysts for overall water splitting is crucial for achieving sustainable clean energy. In this study, a metal/carbide hybrid (NiFeMo/NiFeMoCx) was prepared through fast and facile cathodic plasma electrolytic deposition. Due to the synergistic effect between the metal and carbide, NiFeMo/NiFeMoCx exhibited high activity in both the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), with overpotentials of 230 mV and 60 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. In addition, robust stability was demonstrated during the overall water splitting (1.52 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, with little degradation after 18 h of catalysis). This work provides a useful strategy for designing advanced water splitting catalysts for real application.</description>
      <author>Jinpeng Mo, Nianqing Fu, Songlin Mu, Jihua Peng, Yan Liu, Guoge Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14100730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Co(II) Isostructural Bifunctional MOFs via Mixed-Ligand Strategy: Syntheses, Crystal Structure, Photocatalytic Degradation of Dyes, and Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29214989</link>
      <description>Si&#8208;Yu Yue, Meng&#8208;Qi Tuo, Yemeng Sheng, Xinyu Guo, Jiu-Fu Lu, Dong Wang, Molecules. 29(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403649818

                The solvothermal reactions involving cobalt ions with 5-methylisophthalic acid (H2MIP) and 1,3-bis(2-methylimidazol)propane (BMIP) yielded two cobalt(II) organic frameworks: {[Co4(MIP)4(BMIP)3]&#183;1/2DMA}n (SNUT-31) and {[Co4(MIP)4(BMIP)3]&#183;(EtOH)2&#183;H2O]}n (SNUT-32) where DMA represents N,N-dimethylacetamide and EtOH signifies ethyl alcohol. Single-crystal X-ray diffraction analyses reveal that SNUT-31 and SNUT-32 possess an isomorphic structure, featuring a unique 2-fold interpenetration of 3D frameworks in a parallel manner. Notably, both SNUT-31 and SNUT-32 demonstrate remarkable performance in electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reactions and exhibit exceptional photocatalytic degradation capabilities against a model comprising three distinct dyes: rhodamine B, methyl orange, and methyl blue.</description>
      <author>Si&#8208;Yu Yue, Meng&#8208;Qi Tuo, Yemeng Sheng, Xinyu Guo, Jiu-Fu Lu, Dong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29214989</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Modulation of RuCo Catalysts on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanotubes Promoting Durable Acidic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</link>
      <description>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745765

                Abstract The development of efficient and durable bifunctional electrocatalysts is essential for hydrogen production from acidic water splitting. Herein, a TiO 2 nanotube&#8208;loaded Co&#8208;doped Ru nanoparticle catalyst (RuCo/TiO 2 NTs) is reported that exhibits excellent activity and stability toward acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). The Ru&#9472;O&#9472;Ti bonding is enhanced by Co doping, and the metal carrier interaction between Ru nanoparticles and TiO 2 NTs is enhanced, which effectively stabilizes Ru species during OER and initiates hydrogen spillover accelerating HER kinetics. As a result, RuCo/TiO 2 NTs catalyst requires only 156 mV OER overpotential and 17 mV HER overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a stability more than 500 h in acidic conditions. More importantly, benefiting from the excellent bifunctional activities, the proton exchange membrane electrolyte assembled from RuCo/TiO 2 NTs has excellent activity and robust stability (1000 h). This work opens a new avenue for the efficient energy conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Hengyi Chen, Zehua Gao, Shijie Ren, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Limin Wu, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202403067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface Engineering Induced by Low Ru Doping in Ni/Co@NC Derived from Ni-ZIF-67 for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13769</link>
      <description>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Fahim A. Qaraah, Samah A. Mahyoub, Anas A. Ahmed, Q.A. Drmosh, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403666057

                Electrochemical water splitting is a promising approach for hydrogen evolution reactions (HER); however, the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a major bottleneck due to its high energy requirements. High-performance electrocatalysts capable of facilitating HER, OER, and overall water splitting (OWS) are highly needed to improve OER kinetics. In this work, we synthesized a trimetallic heterostructure of Ru, Ni, and Co incorporated into N-doped carbon (denoted as Ru/Ni/Co@NC) by first synthesizing Ni/Co@NC from Ni-ZIF-67 polyhedrons via high-temperature carbonization, followed by Ru doping using the galvanic replacement method. Benefiting from increased active surface sites, modulated electronic structure, and enhanced interfacial synergistic effects, Ru/Ni/Co@NC exhibited exceptional electrocatalytic performance for both HER and OER processes. The optimized Ru/Ni/Co@NC catalyst, with a minimal Ru mass ratio of &#8764;2.07%, demonstrated significantly low overpotential values of 34 mV for HER and 174 mV for OER at a current density of 10 mA/cm</description>
      <author>Abdulwahab Salah, Hong-Da Ren, Nabilah Al&#8208;Ansi, Adel Al&#8208;Salihy, Fahim A. Qaraah, Samah A. Mahyoub, Anas A. Ahmed, Q.A. Drmosh</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c13769</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface and doping engineering of V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;C&#8208;MXene&#8208;based electrocatalysts for enhanced electrocatalysis of overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.583</link>
      <description>Yousen Wu, Jinlong Li, Guozhe Sui, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Yue Li, Dongxuan Guo, Dawei Chu, Kun Liang, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403694082

                Abstract The restacking and oxidizable nature of vanadium&#8208;based carbon/nitride (V 2 C&#8208;MXene) poses a significant challenge. Herein, tellurium (Te)&#8208;doped V 2 C/V 2 O 3 electrocatalyst is constructed via mild H 2 O 2 oxidation and calcination treatments. Especially, this work rationally exploits the inherent easy oxidation characteristic associated with MXene to alter the interfacial information, thereby obtaining stable self&#8208;generated vanadium&#8208;based heterointerfaces. Meanwhile, the microetching effect of H 2 O 2 creates numerous pores to address the restacking issues. Besides, Te element doping settles the issue of awkward levels of absorption/desorption ability of intermediates. The electrocatalyst obtains an unparalleled hydrogen evolution reaction and oxygen evolution reaction with the overpotential of 83.5 and 279.8 mV at &#8722;10 and 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively. In addition, the overall water&#8208;splitting device demonstrates a low cell voltage of 1.41 V to obtain 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Overall, the inherent drawbacks of MXene can be turned into benefits based on the planning strategy to create these electrocatalysts with desirable reaction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Yousen Wu, Jinlong Li, Guozhe Sui, Dong&#8208;Feng Chai, Yue Li, Dongxuan Guo, Dawei Chu, Kun Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphene&#8208;Transition Metal Electrocatalysts for Sustainable Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403155</link>
      <description>Prerna Tripathi, Amit Verma, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, Shikha Singh, ChemistrySelect. 9(40)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403650622

                Abstract Transition metal compounds (TMCs) are potentially fruitful substitutes for noble metals for electrocatalytic splitting of water due to their intrinsic electrocatalytic activity, modifiable morphology, tunable electronic structure and their earth&#8208;abundance. The combination of TMCs with graphene improves the dispersion of loaded catalysts, providing more catalytic active sites, enhancing the conductivity of hybrids, affording accelerated charge&#8208;transfer kinetics, and minimizing catalyst bleaching, aggregation, and sintering under harsh reaction conditions. Additionally, graphene incorporation into TMCs modulates the electronic structure of active centers because of the synergistic interaction between them, thereby improving their catalytic performance. This review paper focuses on the recent progress made in designing different graphene&#8208;transition metal&#8208;based materials that can be used in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and overall water splitting (OWS). In&#8208;situ characterization methodologies and DFT calculations that facilitate catalyst development are discussed elaborately. Finally, the advancements made in the development of graphene&#8208;supported transition metal compounds for use in a functional water electrolyzer have been explored. In conclusion, a few specific recommendations have been made about the current challenges related to the widespread production of effective HER/OER electrocatalysts for water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Prerna Tripathi, Amit Verma, Akhoury Sudhir Kumar Sinha, Shikha Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Synthetic NiCoP Nanoparticles Encapsulated in N-Doped Carbon for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04798</link>
      <description>Xin Ye, Haodong Zhang, Fan Wu, He Ma, Shaoyang Wu, Xiangqun Zhuge, Yurong Ren, Wei Peng, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403705252

                Transition metal phosphides (TMPs) have drawn widespread attention as promising electrocatalysts due to their special electronic structure, good electrochemical activity, low cost, and high abundance. Although a great deal of effort has been expended in the pursuit of TMPs, the majority of synthesis processes are complex and hazardous due to the use of flammable and toxic phosphorus sources. Herein, we propose a nontoxic and scalable synthetic strategy for the synthesis of NiCoP@NC by using green and cheap diethylenetriaminepentakis (methylphosphonic acid) (DTPMP) as the phosphorus source. DTPMP can also act as a chelating agent and displays strong coordination ability with metal ions, thereby reducing particle size and forming nanoparticles. The NiCoP@NC exhibits outstanding stability and electrocatalytic activity in both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Furthermore, water electrolysis performance also is measured using NiCoP@NC as both anode and cathode, which delivers a cell voltage of 1.73 V at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 and can operate stably for 24 h. This work not only constructs efficient bifunctional catalysts, but also broadens the green synthesis method of nanosized TMPs, paving the way for further large-scale practical applications.</description>
      <author>Xin Ye, Haodong Zhang, Fan Wu, He Ma, Shaoyang Wu, Xiangqun Zhuge, Yurong Ren, Wei Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c04798</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoarchitectonics of Nickel Nitride&#8208;V&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CT&lt;sub&gt;X&lt;/sub&gt; Mxene: An Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Alkaline Water/Seawater Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400656</link>
      <description>Deepak Deepak, Tanuja Singh, Abhinav Mahapatra, Abhishek Panghal, C.H.R.V.S. Nagesh, Susanta Sinha Roy, Advanced Sustainable Systems. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403690186

                Abstract Seawater, being the most plentiful natural water source worldwide, is a highly abundant and cost&#8208;efficient medium for producing hydrogen by alkaline water electrolysis. However, the advancement of seawater electrolysis is hindered by notable impediments caused by chloride corrosion at the anode and the simultaneous chlorine evolution process. Only a limited number of non&#8208;noble electrocatalysts demonstrate noteworthy bifunctional catalytic efficacy and long&#8208;term durability. In this regard, Nickel Nitride tailored V 2 CT X Mxene nanostructures is reported as a bifunctional catalyst for overall water/seawater applications. The optimized sample Ni 3 N@3000&#8208;V 2 CT x exhibits low overpotential values of 90 and 300 mV in acidic and alkaline + seawater solutions respectively at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for hydrogen evolution reaction. Similarly, this catalyst shows 70 and 240 mV overpotential values in alkaline water and alkaline + seawater solutions respectively at the same current density for oxygen evolution reaction. Synergetic effects of Multiple Vanadium and Nickel valency along with compelling nitrogen bonds creates elevated density of exposed functional sites for electrocatalytic activity. Furthermore, the notable electrochemical active surface area and mass activity suggest an enhanced and significant presence of abundant active sites. Additionally, the high stability and significantly decreased charge transfer resistance expedited the overall water/seawater&#8208;splitting reaction rate.</description>
      <author>Deepak Deepak, Tanuja Singh, Abhinav Mahapatra, Abhishek Panghal, C.H.R.V.S. Nagesh, Susanta Sinha Roy</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adsu.202400656</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Of Cobalt Phosphates Co1-xmxpo4 Doped With Iron And Nickel Atoms</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044457x24040071</link>
      <description>M. D. Pecherskaya, O. A. Galkina, Olim Ruzimuradov, Sh.I. Mamatkulov, &#1046;&#1091;&#1088;&#1085;&#1072;&#1083; &#1085;&#1077;&#1086;&#1088;&#1075;&#1072;&#1085;&#1080;&#1095;&#1077;&#1089;&#1082;&#1086;&#1081; &#1093;&#1080;&#1084;&#1080;&#1080;. 69(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403558513

                In this research, the electronic states, band structures, and bond properties of the framework compounds of CoPO4, Co1-xFexPO4, and Co1&#8211;xNixPO4 were investigated by the density functional theory calculations. The potential capabilities of these systems in the photocatalytic water splitting to produce hydrogen were analyzed. The spin-up electron densities of states for the CoPO4, Co1&#8211;xFexPO4, and Co1&#8211;xNixPO4 systems have band gaps of 2.7, 3.4, and 3.45 eV, respectively. The band of spin-down electron states has several energy gaps above the Fermi level. The density of states of electron with spin up near the Fermi level is obviously greater than that of electrons with spin down. In this case, localized states of electrons appear in the band gap of doped semiconductors due to impurity atoms. The calculated value of the energy at the lower edge of the conduction band for CoPO4 was &#8211;0.7 eV, which is more negative than the energy required for water splitting. Meanwhile, the calculated value of the energy at the upper edge of the valence band was 2.01 eV, which is more positive than the oxygen evolution energy of 1.23 eV.</description>
      <author>M. D. Pecherskaya, O. A. Galkina, Olim Ruzimuradov, Sh.I. Mamatkulov</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0044457x24040071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Nanoalloy&#8208;Cluster&#8208;Single Atom Sites Based Aerophilic Carbon Fiber Membranes as Binder&#8208;Free Cathodes for Ultra&#8208;Long&#8208;Life Zn&#8208;air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416422</link>
      <description>Jian Zhu, Zesheng Li, Jingze Shao, Yu Xia, Chuanlai Jiao, Shaoqing Chen, Guangshe Li, Yingcai Zhu, Shi Chen, Rouxi Chen, Zian Xu, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403550838

                Abstract High&#8208;efficient and durable electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction (ORR/OER) are desirable to Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). However, most of catalysts in powder form with sole active sites remain challenging in achieving the satisfactory bifunctional catalysis and suffer from peeling off during the long&#8208;term operation. Herein, hybrid CoFe active sites are constructed containing nanoalloys (&#8776;10 nm), clusters (&lt; 2 nm), and single atoms on aerophilic carbon fiber membranes as binder&#8208;free air cathodes for ultra&#8208;long&#8208;life ZABs. In particular, the high air&#8208;permeability of membranes (0.2 s) can prevent the active sites from blocking by O 2 bubbles and promote the mass transfer. The theoretical and experimental results confirm that the hydrophilic CoFe 2 O 4 /CoFeOOH sites reconstructed on the surface of CoFe nanoalloys are mainly responsible for OER. While for single atoms and clusters on nitrogen (N)&#8208;doped carbon matrix, they play a synergetic role in optimizing the adsorption energy to enhance ORR activity. Thus, the as&#8208;prepared catalysts exhibit an ultra&#8208;low ORR/OER potential gap (0.64 V). When further assembled as freestanding air&#8208;electrodes, it exhibits an outstanding cycling lifespan of 1200 and 155 h in liquid&#8208; and quasi&#8208;solid&#8208;state ZABs respectively, which are fivefold and twofold higher than those of powder&#8208;based cathodes (240/67 h).</description>
      <author>Jian Zhu, Zesheng Li, Jingze Shao, Yu Xia, Chuanlai Jiao, Shaoqing Chen, Guangshe Li, Yingcai Zhu, Shi Chen, Rouxi Chen, Zian Xu, Hsing&#8208;Lin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202416422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition metal nanomaterial-based electrocatalysts for water and CO2 electrolysis: preparation, catalytic activity, and prospects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1433103</link>
      <description>Govindhan Maduraiveeran, Frontiers in Energy Research. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745372

                The production of hydrogen (H 2 ) and multi-carbon fuels through water electrolysis (oxygen evolution reaction (OER)/hydrogen evolution reaction (HER)) and water&#8211;CO 2 co-electrolysis (OER/CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR)), respectively, is supposed to be the emergent energy carrier. These electrochemical processes are essential chemical conversion pathways that initiate the changes toward production of renewable energy. This review summarizes the systematic design of earth-abundant transition metal-based nanomaterials and their electrocatalytic activities toward electrochemical energy conversion reactions such as OER, HER, and CO 2 RR. The primary focus is on fabricating highly effective, low-cost, and advanced transition metal-based nanostructures for both the OER/HER and OER/CO 2 RR systems. Developing synthetic strategies for surface morphology-controlled nanostructured electrocatalysts, engineering the electrode surface, enhancing the electrocatalytic activity, understanding the relationship between intrinsic catalytic activity and preparation approaches or precursor choices, and exploring the reaction mechanism are focused on. Furthermore, the current challenges, figure-of-merit, and prospects of transition metal-based nanomaterials and their electrocatalytic activities toward water electrolysis and water&#8211;CO 2 co-electrolysis are described. This study may open new opportunities to develop shape-controlled and high-performance electrocatalysts for electrochemical energy conversion and storage reactions.</description>
      <author>Govindhan Maduraiveeran</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1433103</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Performance of Novel d-Ti3CN@CdSe Nanocomposite for Efficient Water Splitting: Achieving Low Overpotential and High Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad88ac</link>
      <description>Maryam Bibi, Muhammad Asad Asghar, Saba Ahmad, Sajjad Haider, Khurshid Alam, Shahid Ali Khan, Muhammad Adil Mansoor, Mudassir Iqbal, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403527934

                Abstract The escalating global demand for clean and sustainable energy has ignited significant interest in hydrogen production through water splitting. A major challenge in this pursuit is the development of efficient and cost-effective electrocatalysts for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, we present the synthesis of a novel two-dimensional d-Ti&#8323;CN @CdSe nanocomposite, designed as a high-performance electrocatalyst for overall water splitting. Synthesized via hydrothermal methods, the nanocomposite was characterized using advanced characterization techniques viz. Raman spectroscopy, XRD, XPS, and SEM/EDS. Electrochemical evaluations demonstrate that the d-Ti&#8323;CN @CdSe nanocomposite significantly enhances catalytic performance compared to its individual components, achieving a low overpotential of 232 mV for HER at 10 mA cm&#8315;&#178; and reducing the OER overpotential from 498.3 mV for d-Ti&#8323;CN MXene to 382.2 mV in the nanocomposite at 30 mA cm&#8315;&#178;. Additionally, it exhibits excellent stability, retaining about 75.37% of its current density after 36 hours of continuous operation. This remarkable performance is attributed to the synergistic interactions between CdSe nanoparticles and Ti&#8323;CN MXene layers, which prevent restacking, increase the electrochemically active surface area, and enhance charge transfer efficiency. These features position the d-Ti&#8323;CN @CdSe nanocomposite as a promising candidate for scalable and sustainable water-splitting applications.</description>
      <author>Maryam Bibi, Muhammad Asad Asghar, Saba Ahmad, Sajjad Haider, Khurshid Alam, Shahid Ali Khan, Muhammad Adil Mansoor, Mudassir Iqbal</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad88ac</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrosynthesis of Valuable para&#8208;Benzoquinone from Aqueous Phenol on NiRu Hybrid Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415438</link>
      <description>Shuangyin Wang, Fuqiang Liu, Wei Chen, Tong Wang, J. Zhang, Deyong Yang, Yinhao Dai, Guizi Liu, Jian Zhou, Xiaohong Guan, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403565947

                Electrocatalytic oxidation of aqueous phenol to para&#8208;benzoquinone (p&#8208;BQ) offers a sustainable approach for both pollutant abatement and value&#8208;added chemicals production. However, achieving high phenol conversion and p&#8208;BQ yield under neutral conditions remains challenging. Herein, we report a Ni(OH)2&#8208;supported Ru nanoparticles (NiRu) hybrid electrocatalyst, which exhibits a superior phenol conversion of 96.5% and an excellent p&#8208;BQ yield of 83.4% at pH 7.0, significantly outperforming previously reported electrocatalysts. This exceptional performance benefits from the triple synergistic modulation of the NiRu catalyst, including enhanced phenol adsorption, increased p&#8208;BQ desorption, and suppressed oxygen evolution. By coupling a flow electrolyzer with an extraction&#8208;distillation separation unit, the simultaneous phenol removal and p&#8208;BQ recovery are realized. Additionally, the developed electrocatalytic system with the NiRu/C anode displays good stability, favorable energy consumption, and reduced greenhouse gas emissions for phenol&#8208;containing wastewater treatment, demonstrating its potential for practical applications. This work offers a promising strategy for achieving low&#8208;carbon emissions in phenol wastewater treatment.</description>
      <author>Shuangyin Wang, Fuqiang Liu, Wei Chen, Tong Wang, J. Zhang, Deyong Yang, Yinhao Dai, Guizi Liu, Jian Zhou, Xiaohong Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202415438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Electrosynthesis of Valuable para&#8208;Benzoquinone from Aqueous Phenol on NiRu Hybrid Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415438</link>
      <description>Shuangyin Wang, Fuqiang Liu, Wei Chen, Tong Wang, Juchao Zhang, Deyong Yang, Yinhao Dai, Guizi Liu, Jian Zhou, Xiaohong Guan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403565948

                Electrocatalytic oxidation of aqueous phenol to para&#8208;benzoquinone (p&#8208;BQ) offers a sustainable approach for both pollutant abatement and value&#8208;added chemicals production. However, achieving high phenol conversion and p&#8208;BQ yield under neutral conditions remains challenging. Herein, we report a Ni(OH)2&#8208;supported Ru nanoparticles (NiRu) hybrid electrocatalyst, which exhibits a superior phenol conversion of 96.5% and an excellent p&#8208;BQ yield of 83.4% at pH 7.0, significantly outperforming previously reported electrocatalysts. This exceptional performance benefits from the triple synergistic modulation of the NiRu catalyst, including enhanced phenol adsorption, increased p&#8208;BQ desorption, and suppressed oxygen evolution. By coupling a flow electrolyzer with an extraction&#8208;distillation separation unit, the simultaneous phenol removal and p&#8208;BQ recovery are realized. Additionally, the developed electrocatalytic system with the NiRu/C anode displays good stability, favorable energy consumption, and reduced greenhouse gas emissions for phenol&#8208;containing wastewater treatment, demonstrating its potential for practical applications. This work offers a promising strategy for achieving low&#8208;carbon emissions in phenol wastewater treatment.</description>
      <author>Shuangyin Wang, Fuqiang Liu, Wei Chen, Tong Wang, Juchao Zhang, Deyong Yang, Yinhao Dai, Guizi Liu, Jian Zhou, Xiaohong Guan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202415438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis and Electrochemical Characterization of Ru-Modified Iridium Oxide Catalysts for PEM Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/appliedchem4040022</link>
      <description>Stanford Chidziva, Dorcas Zide, Joshua John Bambo, Anele Sinto, Sivakumar Pasupathi, Bernard Jan Bladergroen, AppliedChem. 4(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403732683

                In the search of sustainable energy solutions, proton exchange membrane water electrolyzers (PEMWEs) have emerged as a promising alternative for sustainable clean hydrogen production. This study focuses on synthesis and characterization of Ruthenium (Ru)-modified iridium oxide (IrO2) catalysts. The anode is the principal reason for the high overpotential of PEMWEs and it also greatly increases the cost of the electrolyzers. IrO2 is highly stable and corrosion-resistant, particularly in acidic environments, making it a durable catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in PEMWEs, though it suffers from a relatively high overpotential. Ruthenium oxide (RuO2), on the other hand, is more catalytically active with a lower overpotential, but is less stable under the same conditions. In this study, the goal was to improve the catalytic activity and stability of the anode catalyst, IrO2, through the controlled incorporation of Ru and to reduce overall catalyst cost due to the reduced iridium content. This synergistic combination allows for better performance in terms of conductivity, efficiency, and durability, making Ru-modified IrO2 an ideal catalyst for OER in PEMWE applications. The Adams fusion method was adapted and used to synthesize the catalysts. The modified catalysts were characterized using analytical instruments. These analyses provided insights into the structural, morphological, and electrochemical properties of the Ru-modified IrO2 catalysts.</description>
      <author>Stanford Chidziva, Dorcas Zide, Joshua John Bambo, Anele Sinto, Sivakumar Pasupathi, Bernard Jan Bladergroen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/appliedchem4040022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni&#8211;Cu Bimetallic Oxides with Tailored Morphology for High&#8208;Performance Alkaline Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403451</link>
      <description>Anila Tabassum, Sadia Ata, Yulong Ding, Ijaz Ul Mohsin, Sajjad Ahmed Khan Leghari, Abdullah A. Al&#8208;Kahtani, Ayman Nafady, Manzar Sohail, ChemistrySelect. 9(39)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403529853

                Abstract Water oxidation, a crucial step in electrochemical water splitting, is often hindered by its complex kinetics. In our pursuit of designing efficient electrocatalysts, we have found that morphological modifications during synthesis are powerful tools. By manipulating various parameters, such as reaction time and temperature, we have tuned the morphology of the catalysts, leading to a significant enhancement in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) rate. Our thorough research involves using a simple hydrothermal method for synthesizing bimetallic Ni&#8211;Cu oxides, resulting in the emergence of different morphologies by varying reaction times from 4 to 24 h. The OER performance in an alkaline medium, using a 1 M KOH solution, has been meticulously investigated, and our results have unveiled the highest activity for Ni&#8211;Cu fabricated with a growth time of 24 h. Ni&#8211;Cu oxide 24 exhibits a remarkably low onset potential for OER at 222 mV with a Tafel slope of 373 mV/dec. The catalyst boasts the lowest R ct value of 2.788 ohm, ensuring faster charge transfer rates and stability up to 1000 cyclic voltammetry (CV) cycles, thereby supporting its electrochemical applications for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Anila Tabassum, Sadia Ata, Yulong Ding, Ijaz Ul Mohsin, Sajjad Ahmed Khan Leghari, Abdullah A. Al&#8208;Kahtani, Ayman Nafady, Manzar Sohail</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202403451</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy Transfer by Mechanical Alloying and Electrocatalytic Performance of the As&#8208;Sintered Self&#8208;Supported High&#8208;Entropy Alloy FeNiCoCuMo</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202400807</link>
      <description>Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, P. M&#225;rt&#237;n, E. P&#237;o, Jorg&#233; Pavez, Claudio Aguilar, C. Suryanarayana, Maritza P&#225;ez, Advanced Engineering Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403609811

                Efficient, stable, and cost&#8208;effective electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are essential for clean energy generation through water splitting. This study presents a FeNiCoCuMo high&#8208;entropy alloy (HEA) synthesized via mechanical alloying (MA) and sintering using hot&#8208;pressing. The energy transfer from the milling process influences phase transformations, with the High&#8208;Entropy Alloys Prediction Software (HEAPS) predicting the formation of an FCC phase. X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD) and scanning electron microscopy reveal an FCC phase after 150 h of milling, with no elemental segregation observed. The Burgio kinetic model estimates 448 kJ mol &#8722;1 is needed to achieve a 99% FCC phase. The crystallite size is 4 nm, with a lattice parameter of 0.371 nm. The as&#8208;milled phases were preserved during hot&#8208;pressing sintering. Electrodes (M1, M2, M3) fabricated from the HEA demonstrated high electrocatalytic efficiency, with an average overpotential of 380 mV and Tafel slope of 77 mV dec &#8722;1 . At a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , the electrodes maintained operation for up to 100 h. The synergy between constituent elements is key to the superior electrocatalytic performance of FeNiCoCuMo HEAs, demonstrating their potential as promising materials for OER electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, P. M&#225;rt&#237;n, E. P&#237;o, Jorg&#233; Pavez, Claudio Aguilar, C. Suryanarayana, Maritza P&#225;ez</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adem.202400807</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterogeneous oxide/sulfide materials as superior bifunctional electrocatalysts for carbon-neutral green hydrogen production: A short review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221098</link>
      <description>Akbar I. Inamdar, Amol S. Salunke, Nabeen K. Shrestha, Hyunsik Im, Applied Physics Reviews. 11(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403731581

                Maintaining an acceptable quality of life worldwide increasingly depends on the availability of clean and cost-effective energy, with power consumption expected to double by 2050. Therefore, the need for sustainable and affordable green energy has spurred innovative electrocatalysis research with the goal to develop materials and processes that are capable of producing environmentally friendly, carbon-neutral, clean, and green hydrogen fuel as an alternative to fossil fuel. In particular, heterostructured catalysts consisting of transition metal oxides and sulfides have emerged as a capable component of green energy technology. The dual functionality of these catalysts allows for water splitting, while the selectivity of the catalytic materials creates synergetic effects based on their electronic structure, surface composition, and electrochemical surface area. In this review, we examine the latest research and developments, synthesis methods, design strategies, reaction mechanisms, and performance outcomes for oxide/sulfide heterostructures. The review begins by introducing the current demand for hydrogen energy and electrocatalytic water-splitting and then describes the fundamental design principles for oxide/sulfide heterostructures and their hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. A large part of the review is then dedicated to a comprehensive discussion of the various transition metal oxide/sulfide heterostructures designed for the OER, the HER, and two-electrode electrolyzer applications. In addition, the use of in situ and operando techniques, which provide crucial information for the design of effective electrocatalysts, is described. We also discuss the present status of electrocatalysis technology, including the challenges it faces and its future prospects as a means to achieve carbon-neutral hydrogen production. Overall, this review delivers a summary of the latest developments in electrocatalysis based on oxide/sulfide heterostructures for use in green hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Akbar I. Inamdar, Amol S. Salunke, Nabeen K. Shrestha, Hyunsik Im</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0221098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Additive Manufacturing of Multiscale NiFeMn Multi-Principal Element Alloys with Tailored Composition</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/2752-5724/ad89e1</link>
      <description>Shahryar Mooraj, Jintao Fu, Shuai Feng, Alexander K. Ng, Eric B. Duoss, Sarah E. Baker, Cheng Zhu, Eric Detsi, Wen Chen, Materials Futures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403628641

                Abstract Nanostructured multi-principal element alloys (MPEAs) have been explored as next-generation engineering materials due to unique mechanical and functional properties which have significant advantages over traditional dilute alloys. However, the practical applications of nanostructured MPEAs are still limited due to the lack of scalable processing approaches to prepare a large quantity of nanostructured MPEAs, as well as lack of an efficient pathway for high-throughput discovery of better functional nanostructured MPEAs within their vast compositional space. Here we tackle these challenges by presenting an integrated approach by combining direct-ink-writing-based additive manufacturing, solid-state sintering, and chemical dealloying to manufacture hierarchically porous MPEAs. The hierarchical structure is comprised of macro- and micro-scale pores introduced via extrusion printing and polymer decomposition during sintering, as well as nanoscale pores formed via chemical dealloying. The macro- and micro-scale pores allow efficient dealloying of a large mass of material as the diffusion length that the corroding medium must penetrate remains at the scale of the ligaments formed after sintering (~10 &#956;m), despite the large volume of the 3D-printed samples. In addition, this integrated approach enables versatile control of the alloy composition via precisely tuning the ratio of elemental powders in the starting ink, thus offering a pathway for high-throughput discovery of novel functional MPEAs. As a case study, multiscale macro/micro/nanoporous NiFeMn MPEAs with three different compositions were investigated as catalysts to reduce the overpotential of oxygen evolution reaction (OER), where NiFeMn-based electrocatalysts display composition-dependent performance such that the overpotential measured at a current of 0.5 A/g for OER increases in the order of Ni58Fe29Mn13 &#8804; Ni64Fe26Mn10 &lt; Ni76Fe18Mn6. This introduced manufacturing process offers new opportunities for scalable fabrication and rapid screening of nanostructured multi-component complex alloys. &amp;#xD;</description>
      <author>Shahryar Mooraj, Jintao Fu, Shuai Feng, Alexander K. Ng, Eric B. Duoss, Sarah E. Baker, Cheng Zhu, Eric Detsi, Wen Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/2752-5724/ad89e1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2D single-faceted IrO2(101) monolayer enabling high-performing proton exchange membrane water electrolysis beyond 8,000 h stability at 1.5 A cm-2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</link>
      <description>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745568

                Abstract Both commercially available and laboratory-synthesized IrO2 catalysts typically possess rutile-type structures and diverse facet orientations. According to the theoretical results from density functional theory calculations, distinct IrO2 facets will result in divergent electrocatalytic properties, among which the (101) crystal facet is theoretically predicted as the most energetically favorable for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) owing to its lowest energy barrier. Maintaining a single-unit-cell thickness while exposing a desired facet of 2D IrO2 presents a significant opportunity and challenge for the development of high-performance OER anode catalysts. Herein, we develop an ammonia-induced facet engineering for oriented modulation of crystal facets in the ultimate limit of monolayer thickness, and successfully synthesize 2D monolayer IrO2 exposing unique (101) facet. At the current density of 10 mA cm-2geo, an ultralow overpotential of 230 mV has been achieved on the highly activated (101) facet in a three-electrode system. More importantly, in a proton exchange membrane (PEM) electrolyzer, the IrO2 anode reaches a low voltage of 1.74 V at an industrial-level current density of 2 A cm-2geo, much lower than that of all commercial IrO2 electrocatalysts. Though facet engineering primarily contributes to modulating the intrinsic activity rather than stability, the as-prepared IrO2(101) monolayer performs over 8,000 hours of PEM water electrolysis (PEMWE) stability at constant 1.5 A cm-2geo, with a negligible decay rate of 4.0 mV kh-1. Furthermore, even a long-term PEMWE test of 1000 h using the membrane electrode assembly (MEA) with ultra-low Ir loading of 0.2 mgIr cm-2geo under fluctuating operating conditions is performed, ECell remains highly electrochemically stable over time at 1.5 A cm-2geo, without any signs of catalyst degradation. This work proposes that ammonia-induced facet engineering of 2D monolayer IrO2 could represent a novel approach to selectively expose the desired (101) facet, thereby enabling unique facet-dependent OER performance and ultrahigh stability in industrial-scale PEM electrolysis, even under voltage fluctuations generated by solar and wind power.</description>
      <author>Jianguo Liu, Deren Yang, Shouwei Zuo, Aidong Tan, Chunyang Zhang, Yufeng Qin, Xiaoyun Shi, Kang Hua, Xuemin An, Yubo Liu, Yue Yang, Lihua Jin, Yipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-5187955/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermal Evaporating-Trapping Strategy to Synthesize Flexible and Robust Oxygen Electrocatalysts for Rechargeable Zinc-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee03005b</link>
      <description>Hongbo Zhang, Yu Meng, Lingzhe Fang, Fei Yang, Shangqian Zhu, Tao Li, Xiaohua Yu, Rong Ju, Weiwei Chen, Dong Su, Yi Mei, Peng&#8208;Xiang Hou, Chang Liu, Minhua Shao, Jincheng Li, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403567909

                Great efforts have been devoted to the development of bifunctional electrocatalysts to accelerate the sluggish kinetics of cathodic oxygen reduction/evolution reactions (ORR/OER) in zinc&#8211;air batteries (ZABs). Here we report a...</description>
      <author>Hongbo Zhang, Yu Meng, Lingzhe Fang, Fei Yang, Shangqian Zhu, Tao Li, Xiaohua Yu, Rong Ju, Weiwei Chen, Dong Su, Yi Mei, Peng&#8208;Xiang Hou, Chang Liu, Minhua Shao, Jincheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee03005b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the Active Oxygen Species of Two-Dimensional Borophene Oxide toward Advanced Metal-Free Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c09002</link>
      <description>Qingqing Gu, Haojian Lin, Chaowei Si, Zhen Wang, Aiqin Wang, Liu Fei, Bo Li, Bing Yang, ACS Nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403738330

                Two-dimensional (2D) borophene materials are predicted to be ideal catalytic materials due to their structural analogy to graphene. However, the lack of chemical functionalization of borophene hinders its practical application in catalysis. Herein, we reported a massive production of freestanding few-layer 2D borophene oxide (BO) sheets with tunable active oxygen species by a moderate oxidation-assisted exfoliation method. State-of-the-art characterizations demonstrated the evolution of active oxygen species from surface B-O species at the initial stage to the intermediate B</description>
      <author>Qingqing Gu, Haojian Lin, Chaowei Si, Zhen Wang, Aiqin Wang, Liu Fei, Bo Li, Bing Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c09002</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abiotic factors that prompt major ecological transitions: Are fish on land to escape an intolerable aquatic environment?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.14672</link>
      <description>Terry J. Ord, Elizabeth A. Surovic, Diego F. B. Vaz, Iker Irisarri, Functional Ecology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403551454

                Abstract Colonisation of novel habitats are important events in evolution, but the factors that initially prompt such ecological transitions are often unknown. The invasion of land by fish is an extreme habitat transition that offers an opportunity to empirically investigate the causes of major ecological transitions. The intertidal ecotone&#8212;and rock pools in particular&#8212;have been an important staging ground for transitions onto land. Classic hypotheses focus on the adverse abiotic conditions of rock pools at low tide as the instigator of fish voluntarily stranding themselves out of water, which can then lead to the evolution of an amphibious lifestyle. To test these hypotheses, we studied the abiotic conditions of 54 rock pools on the island of Guam where there are various species of aquatic, amphibious and terrestrial blenny fishes. We found little support for the expected deterioration of abiotic conditions in standing pools at low tide (salinity, pH and oxygen), and fish were not seen to be excluded from those pools that were found to exhibit poor abiotic conditions (temperature, salinity and pH). Hypoxia was the only factor that might account for the absence of blennies from certain rock pools. Next, we experimentally measured oxygen depletion by an aquatic, mildly amphibious and highly amphibious species of blenny found on Guam in a simulated rockpool to infer the proportion of rock pools at low tide outside the tolerable range of blennies. Rock pools were found to have oxygen levels within the requirements of most blennies and those of other marine fishes reported in the literature. We conclude that the abiotic environment of rock pools alone was unlikely to have instigated the evolution of amphibious behaviour in blennies, at least on Guam. Instead, the broad range of abiotic conditions experienced in rock pools suggests these conditions could have primed amphibious blennies to better endure the novel conditions on land. Any ecotone typified by fluctuations or gradients in abiotic conditions is likely a key transitional environment for the invasion of novel habitats and, as such, are an important location for adaptive evolution and species diversification. Read the free Plain Language Summary for this article on the Journal blog.</description>
      <author>Terry J. Ord, Elizabeth A. Surovic, Diego F. B. Vaz, Iker Irisarri</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/1365-2435.14672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic simulations of white dwarf-white dwarf mergers and the origin of R Coronae Borealis stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2343</link>
      <description>Sagiv Shiber, Orsola De Marco, Patrick M. Motl, Bradley Munson, Dominic Marcello, Juhan Frank, P. Diehl, Geoffrey C. Clayton, Bennett N. Skinner, Hartmut Kaiser, Gregor Dai&#223;, Dirk Pfl&#252;ger, Jan E. Staff, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403745654

                Abstract We study the properties of double white dwarf (DWD) mergers by performing hydrodynamic simulations using the new and improved adaptive mesh refinement code Octo-Tiger. We follow the orbital evolution of DWD systems of mass ratio q = 0.7 for tens of orbits until and after the merger to investigate them as a possible origin for R Coronae Borealis (RCB) type stars. We reproduce previous results, finding that during the merger, the helium WD donor star is tidally disrupted within 20-80 minutes since the beginning of the simulation onto the accretor carbon-oxygen WD, creating a high temperature shell around the accretor. We investigate the possible helium burning in this shell and the merged object&#8217;s general structure. Specifically, we are interested in the amount of oxygen-16 dredged-up from the accretor to the hot shell and the amount of oxygen-18 produced. This is critical as the discovery of very low oxygen-16 to oxygen-18 ratios in RCB stars pointed out the merger scenario as a favorable explanation for their origin. A small amount of hydrogen in the donor may help keep the oxygen-16 to oxygen-18 ratios within observational bounds, even if moderate dredge-up from the accretor occurs. In addition, we perform a resolution study to reconcile the difference found in the amount of oxygen-16 dredge-up between smoothed-particle hydrodynamics and grid-based simulations.</description>
      <author>Sagiv Shiber, Orsola De Marco, Patrick M. Motl, Bradley Munson, Dominic Marcello, Juhan Frank, P. Diehl, Geoffrey C. Clayton, Bennett N. Skinner, Hartmut Kaiser, Gregor Dai&#223;, Dirk Pfl&#252;ger, Jan E. Staff</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stae2343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Domain evolution in BiFeO3 epitaxial nanoisland array via post-annealing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237974</link>
      <description>Guo Tian, Xing&#8208;Chen Zhang, Gui Wang, Jun Jin, Huaichun Zhou, Jiyan Dai, Jun&#8208;Ming Liu, Xingsen Gao, Journal of Applied Physics. 136(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403548419

                We describe the impact of post-annealing on ferroelectric-domain structures in arrays of BiFeO3 (BFO) epitaxial nanoislands, which exhibit a domain evolution from an initial 71&#176; stripe/vortex domains to center-convergent topological domains. These results suggest that the increase and redistribution of charged defects, e.g., oxygen vacancies, in BFO nanoislands play a crucial role in driving the formation of center-type domain structures. The observation of defect-driven domain evolution in BFO nanoislands provides a path for further exploring their formation mechanism, topological properties, novel functionalities, and potential applications.</description>
      <author>Guo Tian, Xing&#8208;Chen Zhang, Gui Wang, Jun Jin, Huaichun Zhou, Jiyan Dai, Jun&#8208;Ming Liu, Xingsen Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0237974</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The mitochondrial genomes of the reef-dwelling spiny lobsters Panulirus echinatus and Panulirus interruptus with insights into the phylogeny and adaptive evolution of protein-coding genes in the Achelata</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00338-024-02569-7</link>
      <description>Alyssa Baker, Natalie C. Stephens, F&#225;bio Mendon&#231;a Diniz, Francisco J. Garc&#237;a&#8208;D&#233; Le&#243;n, J. Antonio Baeza, Coral Reefs. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403607195

                Abstract Temperature and oxygen levels drive the evolution of morphological, behavioral, and physiological traits in marine invertebrates, including crustaceans. Environmental conditions are also expected to prompt the adaptive evolution of mitochondrial protein-coding genes (PCGs), which are vital for energy production via the oxidative phosphorylation pathway. We formally tested for adaptive evolution in mitochondrial protein-coding genes in representatives of the decapod infraorder Achelata, including two spiny lobsters, Panulirus echinatus and P. interruptus , for which we sequenced complete mitochondrial genomes (15,644 and 15,659 bp long, respectively). A phylomitogenomic analysis supported the monophyly of the genus Panulirus , the families Palinuridae and Scyllaridae, and the infraorder Achelata. Over the strong negative selection background observed for mitochondrial PCGs in the Achelata, signatures of positive selective pressure were detected within PCGs in equatorial Panulirus spp. and deepwater Scyllaridae. In Panulirus spp. inhabiting equatorial latitudes with consistently high temperatures, the Datamonkey analysis RELAX suggested intensified purifying selection strength in 9 of the 13 PCGs and relaxation in purifying selection strength in atp6 , while aBSREL, BUSTED, and MEME recovered signatures of positive selection on PCGs within Complex I, III, and IV PCGs. Likewise, in Scyllaridae species inhabiting depths with low-oxygen levels, RELAX indicated relaxed selection strength in 6 of the 13 PCGs, while aBSREL, BUSTED, and MEME recovered signatures of positive selection on PCGs within Complexes I, III, IV, and V. The newly assembled mitochondrial genomes of P. echinatus and P. interruptus represent new genomic resources to aid with the conservation and management of lobsters targeted by major fisheries and contribute to our understanding of how environmental conditions drive adaptive evolution in spiny and slipper lobster mitochondrial PCGs.</description>
      <author>Alyssa Baker, Natalie C. Stephens, F&#225;bio Mendon&#231;a Diniz, Francisco J. Garc&#237;a&#8208;D&#233; Le&#243;n, J. Antonio Baeza</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00338-024-02569-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diverse Transient Chiral Dynamics in Evolutionary distinct
  Photosynthetic Reaction Centers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.06996</link>
      <description>Yong Yang, Zihui Liu, Fulu Zheng, Panpan Zhang, Hongxing He, Ajay Jha, Hong-Guang Duan, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403621288

                The evolution of photosynthetic reaction centers (RCs) from anoxygenic bacteria to oxygenic cyanobacteria and plants reflects their structural and functional adaptation to environmental conditions. Chirality plays a significant role in influencing the arrangement and function of key molecules in these RCs. This study investigates chirality-related energy transfer in two distinct RCs: Thermochromatium tepidum (BRC) and Thermosynechococcus vulcanus (PSII RC) using two-dimensional electronic spectroscopy (2DES). Circularly polarized laser pulses reveal transient chiral dynamics, with 2DCD spectroscopy highlighting chiral contributions. BRC displays more complex chiral behavior, while PSII RC shows faster coherence decay, possibly as an adaptation to oxidative stress. Comparing the chiral dynamics of BRC and PSII RC provides insights into photosynthetic protein evolution and function.</description>
      <author>Yong Yang, Zihui Liu, Fulu Zheng, Panpan Zhang, Hongxing He, Ajay Jha, Hong-Guang Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.06996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Nanoparticle Oxidation by NO2 and O2: Chemical Kinetics and Reaction Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413325</link>
      <description>Thomas Berkemeier, Ulrich P&#246;schl, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403707629

                Carbon nanoparticle interactions with gases are central to many environmental and technical processes, but the underlying reaction kinetics and mechanisms are not well understood. Here, we investigate the oxidation and gasification of carbon nanoparticles by NO2 and O2 under combustion exhaust conditions. We build on a comprehensive experimental data set and use a kinetic multilayer model (KM&#8208;GAP&#8208;CARBON) to trace the uptake and release of gas molecules alongside the temporal evolution of particle size and surface composition. The experimental results are captured by a model mechanism that involves different types of carbon atoms (edge/plane&#8208;like) and the formation of a reactive oxygen intermediate (activated CO complex) as the rate&#8208;limiting step. A transition between distinct chemical regimes driven by NO2 at lower temperatures and O2 at higher temperatures is reflected by an increase in the observable activation energy from ~60 kJ/mol to ~130 kJ/mol. We derive energy profiles for three alternative reaction pathways that involve uni&#8208; or bimolecular decomposition of reactive oxygen intermediates.</description>
      <author>Thomas Berkemeier, Ulrich P&#246;schl</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202413325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Nanoparticle Oxidation by NO2 and O2: Chemical Kinetics and Reaction Pathways</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413325</link>
      <description>Thomas Berkemeier, Ulrich P&#246;schl, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403728363

                Carbon nanoparticle interactions with gases are central to many environmental and technical processes, but the underlying reaction kinetics and mechanisms are not well understood. Here, we investigate the oxidation and gasification of carbon nanoparticles by NO2 and O2 under combustion exhaust conditions. We build on a comprehensive experimental data set and use a kinetic multilayer model (KM&#8208;GAP&#8208;CARBON) to trace the uptake and release of gas molecules alongside the temporal evolution of particle size and surface composition. The experimental results are captured by a model mechanism that involves different types of carbon atoms (edge/plane&#8208;like) and the formation of a reactive oxygen intermediate (activated CO complex) as the rate&#8208;limiting step. A transition between distinct chemical regimes driven by NO2 at lower temperatures and O2 at higher temperatures is reflected by an increase in the observable activation energy from ~60 kJ/mol to ~130 kJ/mol. We derive energy profiles for three alternative reaction pathways that involve uni&#8208; or bimolecular decomposition of reactive oxygen intermediates.</description>
      <author>Thomas Berkemeier, Ulrich P&#246;schl</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202413325</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Haemoglobin Gene Repertoire in Teleost and Cichlid Fishes Shaped by Gene Duplications and Genome Rearrangements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.17559</link>
      <description>Dmytro Omelchenko, Arnold Roger Bitja Nyom, Michael Matschiner, Milan Malinsky, Adrian Indermaur, Walter Salzburger, Old&#345;ich Barto&#353;, Zuzana Musilov&#225;, Molecular Ecology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403619473

                ABSTRACT Haemoglobin is a key molecule for oxygen transport in vertebrates. It exhibits remarkable gene diversity in teleost fishes, reflecting adaptation to various aquatic environments. In this study, we present the dynamic evolution of haemoglobin subunit genes based on a comparison of high&#8208;quality genome assemblies of 24 vertebrate species, including 17 teleosts (of which six are cichlids). Our findings indicate that teleost genomes contain a range of haemoglobin genes, from as few as five in fugu to as many as 43 in salmon, with the latter being the largest repertoire found in vertebrates. We find evidence that the teleost ancestor had at least four Hb&#945; and three or four Hb&#946; subunit genes, and that the current gene diversity emerged during teleost radiation, driven primarily by (tandem) gene duplications, genome compaction, and rearrangement dynamics. We provide insights into the genomic organisation of haemoglobin clusters in different teleost species. We further show that the evolution of paralogous rhbdf1 genes flanking both teleost clusters (LA and MN) supports the hypothesis for the origin of the LA cluster by rearrangement within teleosts, rather than by the teleost specific whole&#8208;genome duplication. We specifically focus on cichlid fishes, where adaptation to low oxygen environment plays role in species diversification. Our analysis of six cichlid genomes, including Pungu maclareni from the Barombi Mbo crater lake, for which we sequenced a representative genome, reveals 18&#8211;32 copies of the Hb genes, and elevated rates of non&#8208;synonymous substitutions compared to other teleosts. Overall, this work facilitates a deeper understanding of how haemoglobin genes contribute to the adaptive potential of teleosts.</description>
      <author>Dmytro Omelchenko, Arnold Roger Bitja Nyom, Michael Matschiner, Milan Malinsky, Adrian Indermaur, Walter Salzburger, Old&#345;ich Barto&#353;, Zuzana Musilov&#225;</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/mec.17559</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High Performance of Mn2O3 Electrodes for Hydrogen Evolution Using Natural Bischofite Salt from Atacama Desert: A Novel Application for Solar Saline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205129</link>
      <description>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Edward Fuentealba, Susana Leiva-Guajardo, Luis C&#225;ceres, Carlos Portillo, Felipe D. Sep&#250;lveda, Iv&#225;n Brito, J.A. Cobos-Murcia, Omar F. Rojas-Moreno, Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, Eduardo Schott, &#193;lvaro Soliz, Materials. 17(20)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403602520

                Solar saline water splitting is a promising approach to sustainable hydrogen production, harnessing abundant solar energy and the availability of brine resources, especially in the Atacama Desert. Bischofite salt (MgCl2&#183;6H2O) has garnered significant attention due to its wide range of industrial applications. Efficient hydrogen production in arid or hyper arid locations using bischofite solutions is a novel and revolutionary idea. This work studied the electrochemical performance of Mn2O3 electrodes using a superposition model based on mixed potential theory and evaluated the superficial performance of this electrode in contact with a 0.5 M bischofite salt solution focusing on the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) that occur during saline water splitting. The application of the non-linear superposition model provides valuable electrochemical kinetic parameters that complement the understanding of Mn2O3, this being one of the novelties of this work.</description>
      <author>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Edward Fuentealba, Susana Leiva-Guajardo, Luis C&#225;ceres, Carlos Portillo, Felipe D. Sep&#250;lveda, Iv&#225;n Brito, J.A. Cobos-Murcia, Omar F. Rojas-Moreno, Victor M. Jimenez&#8208;Arevalo, Eduardo Schott, &#193;lvaro Soliz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17205129</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of gas envelopes and outgassed atmospheres of rocky planets
  formed via pebble accretion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.11005</link>
      <description>Piia Maria Tomberg, Anders Johansen, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403706170

                We present here results of numerical simulations of the formation and early evolution of rocky planets through pebble accretion, with an with an emphasis on hydrogen envelope longevity and the composition of the outgassed atmosphere. We model planets with a range in mass from 0.1 to 5 Earth masses that orbit between 0.7 and 1.7 AU. The composition of the outgassed atmosphere is calculated with the partial pressure of free oxygen fit to geophysical models of magma ocean self-oxidation. XUV radiation powered photoevaporation is considered as the main driver of atmospheric escape. We model planets that remain below the pebble isolation mass and hence accrete tenuous envelopes only. We consider slow, medium or fast initial stellar rotation for the temporal evolution of the XUV flux. The loss of the envelope is a key event that allows the magma ocean to crystallise and outgas its bulk volatiles. The atmospheric composition of the majority of our simulated planets is dominated by CO$_2$. Our planets accrete a total of 11.6 Earth oceans of water, the majority of which enters the core. The hydrospheres of planets lighter than the Earth reach several times the mass of the Earth's modern oceans, while the hydrospheres of planets ranging from 1 to 3.5 Earth masses are comparable to those of our planet. However, planets of 4-5 Earth masses have smaller hydrospheres due to trapping of volatiles in their massive mantles. Overall, our simulations demonstrate that hydrogen envelopes are easily lost from rocky planets and that this envelope loss triggers the most primordial partitioning of volatiles between the solid mantle and the atmosphere.</description>
      <author>Piia Maria Tomberg, Anders Johansen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2409.11005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abundances of iron-peak elements in 58 bulge spheroid stars from APOGEE</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.13751</link>
      <description>B. Barbuy, A. C. S. Fria&#231;a, H. Ernandes, Patricia Siqueira Silva, S. O. Souza, J. G. Fern&#225;ndez-Trincado, K&#225;tia Cunha, V. V. Smith, T. Masseron, &#193;ngeles P&#233;rez-Villegas, C. Chiappini, A. B. A. Queiroz, B. X. Santiago, T. C. Beers, F. Anders, Ricardo P. Schiavon, M. Valentini, D. Minniti, D. Geisler, Diogo Souto, Vinicius M. Placco, M. Zoccali, S. Feltzing, M. Schultheis, C. Nitschelm, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403580076

                Stars presently identified in the bulge spheroid are probably very old, and their abundances can be interpreted as due to the fast chemical enrichment of the early Galactic bulge. The abundances of the iron-peak elements are important tracers of nucleosynthesis processes, in particular oxygen burning, silicon burning, the weak s-process, and alpha-rich freeze-out. Aims. The aim of this work is to derive the abundances of V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu in 58 bulge spheroid stars and to compare them with the results of a previous analysis of data from APOGEE. We selected the best lines for V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu located within the H-band of the spectrum, identifying the most suitable ones for abundance determination, and discarding severe blends. Using the stellar physical parameters available for our sample from the DR17 release of the APOGEE project, we derived the individual abundances through spectrum synthesis. We then complemented these measurements with similar results from different bulge field and globular cluster stars, in order to define the trends of the individual elements and compare with the results of chemical-evolution models. We verify that the H-band has useful lines for the derivation of the elements V, Cr, Mn, Co, Ni, and Cu in moderately metal-poor stars. The resulting abundances indicate that: V, Cr, and Ni vary in lockstep with Fe; Co tends to vary in lockstep with Fe, but could be showing a slight decrease with decreasing metallicity; and Mn and Cu decrease with decreasing metallicity. These behaviours are well reproduced by chemical-evolution models except for Cu, which appears to drop faster than the models predict for moderate metallicities. Finally, abundance indicators combined with kinematical and dynamical criteria appear to show that our 58 sample stars are likely to have originated in situ.</description>
      <author>B. Barbuy, A. C. S. Fria&#231;a, H. Ernandes, Patricia Siqueira Silva, S. O. Souza, J. G. Fern&#225;ndez-Trincado, K&#225;tia Cunha, V. V. Smith, T. Masseron, &#193;ngeles P&#233;rez-Villegas, C. Chiappini, A. B. A. Queiroz, B. X. Santiago, T. C. Beers, F. Anders, Ricardo P. Schiavon, M. Valentini, D. Minniti, D. Geisler, Diogo Souto, Vinicius M. Placco, M. Zoccali, S. Feltzing, M. Schultheis, C. Nitschelm</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.13751</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Reversible Zn Anode Design Through Oriented ZnO(002) Facets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408908</link>
      <description>Chengwu Yang, Pattaraporn Woottapanit, Sining Geng, Kittima Lolupiman, Qian Zhang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Guanjie He, Jiaqian Qin, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403615344

                Abstract The practical implementation of aqueous Zn&#8208;ion batteries presents formidable hurdles, including uncontrolled dendrite growth, water&#8208;induced side reactions, suboptimal Zn metal utilization, and intricate Zn anode manufacturing. Here, large&#8208;scale construction of a highly oriented ZnO(002) lattice plane on Zn anode (ZnO(002)@Zn) with thermodynamic inertia and kinetic zincophilicity is designed to address such problems. Both theoretical calculations and experiment results elucidate that the ZnO(002)@Zn possesses high Zn chemical affinity, hydrogen evolution reaction suppression, and dendrite&#8208;free deposition ability due to the abundant lattice oxygen species in ZnO(002) and its low lattice mismatch with Zn(002). These features synergistically promote ion transport and enable homogeneous Zn deposition. Consequently, the ZnO(002)@Zn anode displays a stable and prolonged cycling lifespan exceeding 500 h even under a larger depth of discharge (85.6%) and realizes an impressive average Coulombic efficiency of 99.7%. Moreover, its efficacy is also evident in V 2 O 5 &#8208;cathode coin cells and pouch cells with not only high discharge capacity but also exceptional cycling stability. This integrated approach presents a promising avenue for addressing the challenges associated with Zn metal anodes, thereby advancing the prospects of aqueous Zn&#8208;ion battery technologies.</description>
      <author>Chengwu Yang, Pattaraporn Woottapanit, Sining Geng, Kittima Lolupiman, Qian Zhang, Zhiyuan Zeng, Guanjie He, Jiaqian Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408908</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation of the Mechanism of Oxidative Potential Increase in Atmospheric Particulate Matter during Photoaging: Important Role of Aromatic Nitrogenous Compounds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03199</link>
      <description>Qingwen Wang, Qingcai Chen, Hao Lin, Jiale Ding, Tong Sha, Yuemei Han, Environmental Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403633329

                Particulate matter (PM) undergoing various aging processes in the atmosphere changes its toxicity. However, the mechanism of toxicity evolution is not fully clarified currently. This study demonstrates that photoaging promotes an increase in the oxidative potential (OP) of atmospheric PM by about 30%, and the increased OP is mainly attributed to the production of secondary organic compounds, while water-soluble metal ions contribute only 11%. The OP of nonextractable matters (NEMs) of atmospheric PM was mostly increased after photoaging, followed by water-soluble matters (WSMs). NEM can produce quinone-like functional groups and secondary persistent free radicals during photoaging, which are most likely to produce reactive oxygen species (ROS). For WSM, the conversion of low-oxidation humic-like substances (HULIS) to high-oxidation HULIS is the main reason for the increase in OP. Quinones, nitrophenols, and N-containing heterocycles are the OP contributors produced during the conversion process. Among them, quinones are the main secondary oxidizing active compounds, while nitro-phenolic compounds and N-containing heterocyclic compounds may play a catalyst-like role, facilitating the production of oxidizing active compounds and ROS in the newly converted high-oxidation HULIS. This study clarifies the secondary OP generation mechanism and provides new insights into the uncertainty of PM toxicity during atmospheric aging.</description>
      <author>Qingwen Wang, Qingcai Chen, Hao Lin, Jiale Ding, Tong Sha, Yuemei Han</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.est.4c03199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Giant Dynamical Paramagnetism in the driven pseudogap phase of $ \rm
  YBa_2Cu_3O_{6+x}$</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.12919</link>
      <description>Marios H. Michael, Duilio De Santis, Eugene Demler, Patrick A. Lee, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403578830

                In the past decade, photo-induced superconducting-like behaviors have been reported in a number of materials driven by intense pump fields. Of particular interest is the high-$T_c$ cuprate $\rm Y Ba_2 Cu_2 O_{6+x}$, where such effect has been reported up to the so-called pseudogap temperature $T^* \sim 300-400$ K. In a recent tour-de-force experiment, a transient magnetic field which is proportional to and in the same direction of an applied field has been observed outside the sample, suggestive of flux exclusion due to the Meissner effect. In this paper, we point out that the transient magnetic field could be explained by a model of bilayers of copper-oxygen planes with a local superconducting phase variable persisting up to the pseudo-gap temperature at equilibrium. Under pumping, the time evolution is described by a driven sine-Gordon equation. In the presence of an external magnetic field, this model exhibits a novel instability which amplifies the current at the edges of the bilayer formed by defects or grain boundaries, producing a giant paramagnetic magnetization in the same direction as the applied field. We present how this scenario can fit most of the available data and propose additional experimental tests which can distinguish our proposal from the Meissner flux exclusion scenario. To the extent that this model can account for the data, we conclude that the experiments have the important consequence of revealing the presence of local pairing in the pseudogap phase. More broadly, this work provides a new mechanism for amplifying external magnetic fields at ultra-fast time scales.</description>
      <author>Marios H. Michael, Duilio De Santis, Eugene Demler, Patrick A. Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2410.12919</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Restructuring the interfacial active sites to generalize the volcano curves for platinum-cobalt synergistic catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53474-0</link>
      <description>Wenyao Chen, Yao Shi, Changwei Liu, Zhouhong Ren, Zhigang Huang, Zhou Chen, Xiangxue Zhang, Shanshan Liang, Lei Xie, Cheng Lian, Gang Qian, Jing Zhang, Xi Liu, De Chen, Xinggui Zhou, Weikang Yuan, Xuezhi Duan, Nature Communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403546946

                Computationally derived volcano curve has become the gold standard in catalysis, whose practical application usually relies on empirical interpretations of composition or size effects by the identical active site assumption. Here, we present a proof-of-concept study on disclosing both the support- and adsorbate-induced restructuring of Pt-Co bimetallic catalysts, and the related interplays among different interfacial sites to propose the synergy-dependent volcano curves. Multiple characterizations, isotopic kinetic investigations, and multiscale simulations unravel that the progressive incorporation of Co into Pt catalysts, driven by strong Pt-C bonding (metal-support interfaces) and Co-O bonding (metal-adsorbate interfaces), initiates the formation of Pt-rich alloys accompanied by isolated Co species, then Co segregation to epitaxial CoOx overlayers and adjacent Co3O4 clusters, and ultimately structural collapse into amorphous alloys. Accordingly, three distinct synergies, involving lattice oxygen redox from Pt-Co alloy/Co3O4 clusters, dual-active sites engineering via Pt-rich alloy/CoOx overlayer, and electron coupling within exposed alloy, are identified and quantified for CO oxidation (gas-phase), ammonia borane hydrolysis (liquid-phase), and hydrogen evolution reaction (electrocatalysis), respectively. The resultant synergy-dependent volcano curves represent an advancement over traditional composition-/size-dependent ones, serving as a bridge between theoretical models and experimental observations in bimetallic catalysis. Volcano curves have become the gold standard in catalyst design. Here, the authors propose synergy-dependent volcano curves by disclosing both support- and adsorbate-induced catalyst restructuring, ideally bridging the gap between theoretical models and experimental observations.</description>
      <author>Wenyao Chen, Yao Shi, Changwei Liu, Zhouhong Ren, Zhigang Huang, Zhou Chen, Xiangxue Zhang, Shanshan Liang, Lei Xie, Cheng Lian, Gang Qian, Jing Zhang, Xi Liu, De Chen, Xinggui Zhou, Weikang Yuan, Xuezhi Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-53474-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accretion and Core Formation of Earth-like Planets: Insights from Metal&#8211;Silicate Partitioning of Siderophile and Volatile Elements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences14110281</link>
      <description>Dominik Loroch, S. Hackler, Arno Rohrbach, Jasper Berndt, Stephan Klemme, Geosciences. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4403646963

                The origin of volatile elements, the timing of their accretion and their distribution during Earth&#8217;s differentiation are fundamental aspects of Earth&#8217;s early evolution. Here, we present the result of a newly developed accretion and core formation model, which features the results of high P&#8211;T metal&#8211;silicate partitioning experiments. The model includes well-studied reference elements (Fe, Ni, Ca, Al, Mg, Si) as well as trace elements (V, Ga, Ag, Au, S) covering a wide range from refractory to volatile behavior. The accretion model simulates the different steps of planet formation, such as the effects of continuous, heterogenous core formation at high P&#8211;T, the effect of the Moon-forming giant impact and the addition of matter after the core formation was completed, the so-called &#8220;late veneer&#8221;. To explore the &#8220;core formation signature&#8221; of the volatile depletion patterns and the quantitative influence of a late veneer, we modeled planets that would have formed from known materials, such as CI, CM, CV, CO, EH and EL meteorites, and from a hypothetical volatile depleted material, CI*. Some of the resulting planets are Earth-like in key properties, such as overall core size, major element composition, oxygen fugacity and trace element composition. The model predicts the chemical signatures of the main planetary reservoirs, the metallic core and bulk silicate planet (BSP) of the modeled planets, which we compare with the chemical signature of Earth derived previously from core formation models and mass balance-based approaches. We show that planets accreted from volatile depleted carbonaceous chondrites (CM, CV, CO and CI*) are closest in terms of major element (Si, Mg, Fe, Ca, Al, Ni) and also siderophile volatile element (Ge, Ga, Au) concentrations to the components from which Earth accreted. Chalcophile volatile elements (S, Ag), instead, require an additional process to lower their concentrations in the BSP to Earth-like concentrations, perhaps the late segregation of a sulfide melt.</description>
      <author>Dominik Loroch, S. Hackler, Arno Rohrbach, Jasper Berndt, Stephan Klemme</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/geosciences14110281</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
