<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 01:02:02 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Tracking the structural evolution and activity origin of Co-doped NiFe layered double hydroxide for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151086</link>
      <description>Yanyan Wu, Ying Liu, Zijuan Xie, Yan Wang, Yanan Wang, Bo Wei, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566117

                Development non-precious electrocatalysts in oxygen evolution reactions (OER) with excellent activity and durability is of great significance but challenging for electrochemical water splitting. Herein, under the guidance of theoretical calculation, we report that in-situ Co-doped NiFe (NiFeCo) LDH is an excellent catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and its activity and durability are superior to NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH). The dynamic evolution of its structure/composition is uncovered by in-situ Raman and UV&#8211;vis spectroscopies, in which Co doping reduces the Ni oxidation potential and accelerates the formation of highly active Ni(Co)1-xFexOOH species during OER. The reconstructed product catalyzes the OER with low overpotential of 261 and 318 mV at 100 and 500 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively, and maintains outstanding stability for at least 300 h at 500 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1.0 M KOH. Our findings not only deepen the basic understanding of the OER process of this material, but also provide theoretical basis and practical guidance for the further development of new low-cost electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Yanyan Wu, Ying Liu, Zijuan Xie, Yan Wang, Yanan Wang, Bo Wei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polyaniline Induced Trivalent Ni in Laser-Fabricated Nickel Oxides for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03463</link>
      <description>Jingyu Zhang, Youwei Cao, Han Xu, Xinghan Liu, Junbo Gong, Yonggang Tong, Gufei Zhang, Yejun Li, Chuan&#8208;Jia Tong, Zhou Li, &#152;The &#156;journal of physical chemistry letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394568030

                Although it is generally acknowledged that transition metals at high oxidation states represent superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity, the preparation and stability of such a high-valence state are still a challenge, which requires relatively harsh reaction conditions and is unstable under ambient conditions. Herein, we report the formation of trivalent nickel (Ni3+) in laser-fabricated nickel oxides induced by polyaniline (PANI) under electrochemical activation via a significant charge transfer between Ni and N, as confirmed by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and density functional theory calculations. Thereafter, the presence of Ni3+ and the improved conductivity by PANI effectively increase the electrochemical OER activity of the samples together with excellent long-term stability. This work provides new insights for the rational manufacture of high-valence metal for electrochemical reactions.</description>
      <author>Jingyu Zhang, Youwei Cao, Han Xu, Xinghan Liu, Junbo Gong, Yonggang Tong, Gufei Zhang, Yejun Li, Chuan&#8208;Jia Tong, Zhou Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpclett.3c03463</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Promotion of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via Programmable Metal Oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00365</link>
      <description>Sallye R. Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar A. Abdelrahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394568896

                Hydrogen gas is a promising renewable energy storage medium when produced via water electrolysis, but this process is limited by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, we used a microkinetic model to investigate promoting the OER using programmable oxide catalysts (i.e., forced catalyst dynamics). We found that programmable catalysts could increase current density at a fixed overpotential (100&#8211;600&#215; over static rates) or reduce the overpotential required to reach a fixed current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 (45&#8211;140% reduction vs static). In our kinetic parametrization, the key parameters controlling the quality of the catalytic ratchet were the O*-to-OOH* and O*-to-OH* activation barriers. Our findings indicate that programmable catalysts may be a viable strategy for accelerating the OER or enabling lower-overpotential operation, but a more accurate kinetic parametrization is required for precise predictions of performance, ratchet quality, and resulting energy efficiency.</description>
      <author>Sallye R. Gathmann, Christopher J. Bartel, Lars C. Grabow, Omar A. Abdelrahman, C. Daniel Frisbie, Paul J. Dauenhauer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Amorphous/Crystalline Fe doped CoSe for Effective Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc00866a</link>
      <description>Wenjuan Chen, Qian Zhang, Youzheng Zhang, Caidi Han, Jian Wu, Jian Gao, Xiaodong Zhu, Yong&#8208;Chao Zhang, Chemical communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394573321

                Electrochemical water splitting provides a promising pathway to produce hydrogen, but the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with sluggish kinetics is the bottleneck. The design and synthesis of high efficiency catalysts...</description>
      <author>Wenjuan Chen, Qian Zhang, Youzheng Zhang, Caidi Han, Jian Wu, Jian Gao, Xiaodong Zhu, Yong&#8208;Chao Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cc00866a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advancements on Spin Engineering Strategies for Highly Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401057</link>
      <description>Wenli Zhao, Jieyu Yang, Fenghua Xu, Biing-Jyh Weng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394578692

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a widely employed half-electrode reaction in oxygen electrochemistry, in applications such as hydrogen evolution, carbon dioxide reduction, ammonia synthesis, and electrocatalytic hydrogenation. Unfortunately, its slow kinetics limits the commercialization of such applications. It is therefore highly imperative to develop highly robust electrocatalysts with high activity, long-term durability, and low noble-metal contents. Previously intensive efforts have been made to introduce the advancements on developing non-precious transition metal electrocatalysts and their OER mechanisms. Electronic structure tuning is one of the most effective and interesting ways to boost OER activity and spin angular momentum is an intrinsic property of the electron. Therefore, modulation on the spin states and the magnetic properties of the electrocatalyst enables the changes on energy associated with interacting electron clouds with radical absorbance, affecting the OER activity and stability. Given that few review efforts have been made on this topic, in this review, the-state-of-the-art research progress on spin-dependent effects in OER will be briefed. Spin engineering strategies, such as strain, crystal surface engineering, crystal doping, etc., will be introduced. The related mechanism for spin manipulation to boost OER activity will also be discussed. Finally, the challenges and prospects for the development of spin catalysis are presented. This review aims to highlight the significance of spin engineering in breaking the bottleneck of electrocatalysis and promoting the practical application of high-efficiency electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Wenli Zhao, Jieyu Yang, Fenghua Xu, Biing-Jyh Weng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile and adjustable production of self&#8211;standing oxygen&#8211;doped graphene membranes for optimized oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.03.003</link>
      <description>Liang Chen, Lanyun Yang, Liying Hu, Minghao Jin, Chenxi Xu, Binhong He, Wei Wang, Ying Liu, Gangyong Li, Zhaohui Hou, Nano materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394581525

                Owing to abundant resource and affordable price, metal&#8211;free carbon has been extensively studied in the field of oxygen reduction reaction, while the related studies on oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are quite few. In this work, a facile and scalable knife coating coupled with annealing strategy is proposed to produce self&#8211;standing oxygen&#8211;doped graphene membranes (marked as O&#8211;GM&#8211;T, T represents the annealing temperature). Through systematic characterization and analysis, it is discovered the annealing treatment not only decreases the amount of oxygenic groups, but allows for controlled regulation of the oxygen configurations, leaving only C&#8211;OH/C&#8211;O&#8211;C and CO. Meanwhile, theoretical calculations indicate that the OER activity trend of different oxygen configurations is as follows: &#8211;COOH &#8203;&gt; &#8203;CO &#8203;&#8776; &#8203;C&#8211;OH &#8203;&gt; &#8203;C&#8211;O&#8211;C. Despite the removal of highly active &#8211;COOH group through annealing treatment, the resulting O&#8211;GM&#8211;800 sample maintains good mechanical property and achieves a favorable balance on conductivity, hydrophilicity and catalytic sites. Consequently, it displays significantly improved OER performance compared to the counterparts, making it highly promising for applications in overall water splitting devices. Apparently, our work provides guidance for the rational design and controllable fabrication of self&#8211;standing carbon&#8211;based catalysts for energy&#8211;related reactions.</description>
      <author>Liang Chen, Lanyun Yang, Liying Hu, Minghao Jin, Chenxi Xu, Binhong He, Wei Wang, Ying Liu, Gangyong Li, Zhaohui Hou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.03.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homogenic Boundary Effect Boosted Oxygen Evolution Reaction in &#945;/&#946;&#8208;NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Rechargeable Aqueous Zn&#8208;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304554</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhu, Qiming Zhou, Linchuan Wang, Wanhai Zhou, Minghua Chen, Xin Liu, Daqiang Gao, Dongliang Chao, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394596125

                Abstract Rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries (ZAB) represent a promising avenue for sustainable energy storage, boasting high energy density, cost&#8208;effectiveness, scalability, and environmental friendliness. However, the sluggish redox kinetics and limited cycle life of bifunctional oxygen evolution/reduction (OER/ORR) electrocatalysts impede the further practical development of ZABs. In this study, homogenic boundary effect within &#945;/&#946;&#8208;NiMoO 4 is introduced as a superior electrocatalyst for ZAB. Through in situ poikilothermic X&#8208;ray diffraction, X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy, and theoretical investigations, the active Ni atoms exhibit more effective electron transfer at &#945;/&#946;&#8208;NiMoO 4 due to the homogenic boundary effect is unveiled. Furthermore, the presence of oxygen vacancies and lattice distortions at these boundaries significantly reduces the thermodynamic barrier of OER to a mere 0.46 V. Consequently, &#945;/&#946;&#8208;NiMoO 4 demonstrates a remarkably low overpotential of 270 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for the bottlenecked OER, along with prolonged durability (150 h) and a high specific capacity (745 mAh g &#8722;1 at 5 mA cm &#8722;2 ) for ZAB. This study underscores the efficacy of homogenic boundary effects in enhancing electrocatalytic activities, offering great promise for the advancement of sustainable energy systems.</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhu, Qiming Zhou, Linchuan Wang, Wanhai Zhou, Minghua Chen, Xin Liu, Daqiang Gao, Dongliang Chao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304554</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulated Synthesis of Diverse Carbon Nanostructures and Comparison of Their Electrochemical Performance in Oxygen Reduction, Oxygen Evolution and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4788423</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Niu, Zhenhua Ren, Xiujuan Zhang, Jadranka Trava&#353;-Sejdi&#263;, Xiaoqiang Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394602435

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Niu, Zhenhua Ren, Xiujuan Zhang, Jadranka Trava&#353;-Sejdi&#263;, Xiaoqiang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4788423</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface oxidation/spin state determines oxygen evolution reaction activity of cobalt-based catalysts in acidic environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47409-y</link>
      <description>Jinzhen Huang, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Dominika Baster, Mario El Kazzi, Claudia Schneider, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394604266

                Abstract Co-based catalysts are promising candidates to replace Ir/Ru-based oxides for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysis in an acidic environment. However, both the reaction mechanism and the active species under acidic conditions remain unclear. In this study, by combining surface-sensitive soft X-ray absorption spectroscopy characterization with electrochemical analysis, we discover that the acidic OER activity of Co-based catalysts are determined by their surface oxidation/spin state. Surfaces composed of only high-spin Co II are found to be not active due to their unfavorable water dissociation to form Co III -OH species. By contrast, the presence of low-spin Co III is essential, as it promotes surface reconstruction of Co oxides and, hence, OER catalysis. The correlation between OER activity and Co oxidation/spin state signifies a breakthrough in defining the structure-activity relationship of Co-based catalysts for acidic OER, though, interestingly, such a relationship does not hold in alkaline and neutral environments. These findings not only help to design efficient acidic OER catalysts, but also deepen the understanding of the reaction mechanism.</description>
      <author>Jinzhen Huang, Camelia N. Borca, Thomas Huthwelker, Nur Sena Y&#252;zbasi, Dominika Baster, Mario El Kazzi, Claudia Schneider, Thomas J. Schmidt, Emiliana Fabbri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-47409-y</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core&#8211;Shell CoS2@MoS2 with Hollow Heterostructure as an Efficient Electrocatalyst for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081695</link>
      <description>Donglei Guo, Jiaqi Xu, Guilong Liu, Xu Yu, Molecules/Molecules online/Molecules annual. 29(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394605927

                It is imperative to develop an efficient catalyst to reduce the energy barrier of electrochemical water decomposition. In this study, a well-designed electrocatalyst featuring a core&#8211;shell structure was synthesized with cobalt sulfides as the core and molybdenum disulfide nanosheets as the shell. The core&#8211;shell structure can prevent the agglomeration of MoS2, expose more active sites, and facilitate electrolyte ion diffusion. A CoS2/MoS2 heterostructure is formed between CoS2 and MoS2 through the chemical interaction, and the surface chemistry is adjusted. Due to the morphological merits and the formation of the CoS2/MoS2 heterostructure, CoS2@MoS2 exhibits excellent electrocatalytic performance during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process in an alkaline electrolyte. To reach the current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, only 254 mV of overpotential is required for CoS2@MoS2, which is smaller than that of pristine CoS2 and MoS2. Meanwhile, the small Tafel slope (86.9 mV dec&#8722;1) and low charge transfer resistance (47 &#937;) imply the fast dynamic mechanism of CoS2@MoS2. As further confirmed by cyclic voltammetry curves for 1000 cycles and the CA test for 10 h, CoS2@MoS2 shows exceptional catalytic stability. This work gives a guideline for constructing the core&#8211;shell heterostructure as an efficient catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Donglei Guo, Jiaqi Xu, Guilong Liu, Xu Yu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29081695</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reversing the Interfacial Electric Field in Metal Phosphide Heterojunction by Fe&#8208;Doping for Large&#8208;Current Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202308477</link>
      <description>Zhong Li, Xu Cheng, Zheye Zhang, Shan Xia, Dongsheng Li, Liren Liu, Peng Chen, Xiaochen Dong, Advanced science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394615348

                Developing non-precious-metal electrocatalysts that can operate with a low overpotential at a high current density for industrial application is challenging. Heterogeneous bimetallic phosphides have attracted much interest. Despite high hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) performance, the ordinary oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance hinders their practical use. Herein, it is shown that Fe-doping reverses and enlarges the interfacial electrical field at the heterojunction, turning the H intermediate favorable binding sites for HER into O intermediate favorable sites for OER. Specifically, the self-supported heterojunction catalysts on nickel foam (CoP@Ni2P/NF and Fe-CoP@Fe-Ni2P/NF) are readily synthesized. They only require the overpotentials of 266 and 274 mV to drive a large current density of 1000 mA cm-2 (j1000) for HER and OER, respectively. Furthermore, a water splitting cell equipped with these electrodes only requires a voltage of 1.724 V to drive j1000 with excellent durability, demonstrating the potential of industrial application. This work offers new insights on interfacial engineering for heterojunction catalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhong Li, Xu Cheng, Zheye Zhang, Shan Xia, Dongsheng Li, Liren Liu, Peng Chen, Xiaochen Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202308477</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Template-assisted strategy for synthesizing transition metal oxyhydroxide for high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174445</link>
      <description>Ting Wang, Xianxu Chu, Xuelin Dong, Yubing Lv, Lu Wang, Xiaopei Li, Yanli Zhou, Qiaoxia Li, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394618280

                Oxyhydroxides have been widely recognized as the true active species for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), while most of them are created via the complicated and time-consuming electrochemical activation process. Here, we develop a facile template-mediated method for directly synthesizing highly active oxyhydroxides toward OER. The optimal FeCoOOH prepared via using Cu2O as a sacrificial template could exhibit outstanding electrocatalytic OER performance, delivering a current density of 10 mA cm-2 with the overpotential of merely 320 mV, and a corresponding Tafel slope of 77.5 mV dec-1. Detailed mechanism study outlines that the extraordinary OER performance of such FeCoOOH originated from the intrinsically high OER activity of oxyhydroxide and the high specific surface area of the particular architecture. This work demonstrates a simple and direct route for the successful fabrication of highly active oxyhydroxides, which may open a new way for the synthesis of other active species.</description>
      <author>Ting Wang, Xianxu Chu, Xuelin Dong, Yubing Lv, Lu Wang, Xiaopei Li, Yanli Zhou, Qiaoxia Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174445</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Single-Atomic Co&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Sites with CrCo Nanoparticles for Metal&#8211;Air Battery-Driven Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c04443</link>
      <description>Shadab Saifi, Gargi Dey, Renna Shakir, J. Karthikeyan, Ravi Kumar, D. Bhattacharyya, A. Sinha, Arshad Aijaz, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394622624

                Designing highly active and robust earth abundant trifunctional electrocatalysts for energy storage and conversion applications remain an enormous challenge. Herein, we report a trifunctional electrocatalyst (CrCo/CoN4@CNT-5), synthesized at low calcination temperature (550 &#176;C), which consists of Co&#8211;N4 single atom and CrCo alloy nanoparticles and exhibits outstanding electrocatalytic performance for the hydrogen evolution reaction, oxygen evolution reaction, and oxygen reduction reaction. The catalyst is able to deliver a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in an alkaline electrolytic cell at a very low cell voltage of &#8764;1.60 V. When the catalyst is equipped in a liquid rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery, it endowed a high open-circuit voltage with excellent cycling durability and outperformed the commercial Pt/C+IrO2 catalytic system. Furthermore, the Zn&#8211;air battery powered self-driven water splitting system is displayed using CrCo/CoN4@CNT-5 as sole trifunctional catalyst, delivering a high H2 evolution rate of 168 &#956;mol h&#8211;1. Theoretical calculations reveal synergistic interaction between Co&#8211;N4 active sites and CrCo nanoparticles, favoring the Gibbs free energy for H2 evolution. The presence of Cr not only enhances the H2O adsorption and dissociation but also tunes the electronic property of CrCo nanoparticles to provide optimized hydrogen binding capacity to Co&#8211;N4 sites, thus giving rise to accelerated H2 evolution kinetics. This work highlights the importance of the presence of small quantity of Cr in enhancing the electrocatalytic activity as well as robustness of single-atom catalyst and suggests the design of the multifunctional robust electrocatalysts for long-term H2 evolution application.</description>
      <author>Shadab Saifi, Gargi Dey, Renna Shakir, J. Karthikeyan, Ravi Kumar, D. Bhattacharyya, A. Sinha, Arshad Aijaz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.3c04443</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FeCo alloy nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen-doped carbon nanospheres as efficient bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.012</link>
      <description>Lei Yu, Han Zhang, Guang Li, Juan Yang, Hui Huang, Yongqiang Shen, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xianyou Wang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394631878

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lei Yu, Han Zhang, Guang Li, Juan Yang, Hui Huang, Yongqiang Shen, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xianyou Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.012</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;&#947;&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; as an Electron Reservoir for RuO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Oxygen Evolution Catalyst in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310464</link>
      <description>Jia Wang, Xuejie Cao, Xiaojie Chen, Hongye Qin, Licheng Miao, Qing&#8208;Lun Wang, Lifang Jiao, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394683106

                Abstract Developing highly active and durable catalysts in acid conditions remains an urgent issue due to the sluggish kinetics of oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Although RuO 2 has been a state&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art commercial catalyst for OER, it encounters poor stability and high cost. In this study, the electronic reservoir regulation strategy is proposed to promote the performance of acidic water oxidation via constructing a RuO 2 /MnO 2 heterostructure supported on carbon cloth (CC) (abbreviated as RuO 2 /MnO 2 /CC). Theoretical and experimental results reveal that MnO 2 acts as an electron reservoir for RuO 2 . It facilitates electron transfer from RuO 2 , enhancing its activity prior to OER, and donates electrons to RuO 2 , improving its stability after OER. Consequently, RuO 2 /MnO 2 /CC exhibits better performance compared to commercial RuO 2 , with an ultrasmall overpotential of 189 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and no signs of deactivation even after 800 h of electrolysis in 0.5 m H 2 SO 4 at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . When applied as the anode in a proton exchange membrane water electrolyzer, the cost&#8208;efficient RuO 2 /MnO 2 /CC catalyst only requires a cell voltage of 1.661 V to achieve the water&#8208;splitting current of 1 A cm &#8722;2 , and the noble metal cost is as low as US$ 0.00962 cm &#8722;2 , indicating potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Jia Wang, Xuejie Cao, Xiaojie Chen, Hongye Qin, Licheng Miao, Qing&#8208;Lun Wang, Lifang Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310464</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Surface Oxygen Vacancies in Rutile Tio2 by Electrochemical Reduction for Enhanced Photoelectrochemical Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4789996</link>
      <description>Yujie Ding, Chenfeng Jiang, Yongming Sun, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xiaojun Ma, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394707857

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yujie Ding, Chenfeng Jiang, Yongming Sun, Xiaoyan Zhang, Xiaojun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4789996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noble-Metal-Free Metal Oxides for Catalyzing Acidic Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions: Recent Developments and Future Perspectives</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00837</link>
      <description>Zhongliang Dong, Bowen Li, Yinlong Zhu, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394711199

                Proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis has emerged as a highly promising technology for sustainable hydrogen (H2) production, but its widespread application relies heavily on the development of high-performance and cost-effective hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. Currently, noble-metal-based materials (such as Pt and Ir/Ru oxides) serve as benchmark electrocatalysts for HER and OER in acidic environments, but their high cost and limited availability pose major challenges toward industrialization. Low-cost noble-metal-free metal oxides are an important class of functional materials with rich compositions and structures, offering flexible electronic and crystal structures with tunable physical and chemical properties. In this Review, we present a comprehensive and timely summary of the remarkable progress achieved in the field of noble-metal-free metal oxides for catalyzing acidic HER and OER. First, we provide a brief description of the fundamental concepts of HER and OER in acidic media, including mechanisms, computational activity descriptors, and experimental parameters that are utilized for the evaluation of catalytic performance. Second, an overview is provided covering various types of noble-metal-free metal oxides for HER and OER in acidic media reported so far (e.g., simple transition metal oxides, spinel oxides, rutile antimonate oxides, perovskite oxides, specially structured metal oxides, and mixed-metal-oxide composites), with a focus on the designed strategies for enhancing performance and establishing correlations between properties and activity. Lastly, the challenges and future research directions regarding acidic HER and OER are summarized and discussed.</description>
      <author>Zhongliang Dong, Bowen Li, Yinlong Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00837</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Electronic Structures and Oxygen Vacancies of Manganese-Doped Nickel Molybdate Porous Nanosheets for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4791636</link>
      <description>Fei Miao, Peng Cui, Tiantian Gu, Bo Sun, Zhijie Yan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394713576

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fei Miao, Peng Cui, Tiantian Gu, Bo Sun, Zhijie Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4791636</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gold-Doped Cobalt&#8211;Nickel Sulfide Nanosheets for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00516</link>
      <description>Tingwei Liu, Congcong Xu, Yanglong Guo, Pei&#8208;Zhou Li, Shiling Yuan, Min-Sheng Lin, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394714067

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingwei Liu, Congcong Xu, Yanglong Guo, Pei&#8208;Zhou Li, Shiling Yuan, Min-Sheng Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00516</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigation into the Performance of Tremella-like LaNiO3-NiO Composite as an Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4229344/v1</link>
      <description>W. Li, Hui Xu, Yaru Pei, Haibo Lin, Zhong Yang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394714135

                Abstract Guided by the carbon peaking and carbon neutrality goals, the development of efficient, stable, and cost-effective electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions is of paramount importance. A unique; tremella-like LaNiO 3 -NiO composite has been fabricated through a simple and robust procedure. This material stands out as an effective catalyst in the Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), showcasing its potential to enhance the efficiency of electrochemical energy transformations. This composite exhibits a remarkably low overpotential of only 383 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm -2 , coupled with a Tafel slope of 76.66 mV dec -1 . Furthermore, it boasts the capability to sustain continuous operation for more than 30 h at a current density of 20 mA cm -2 . The unique morphology of the catalyst expands the electrochemically active surface area, providing more available active sites to improve catalytic performance. This discovery presents a promising opportunity for the development of non-precious metal electrocatalysts for OER.</description>
      <author>W. Li, Hui Xu, Yaru Pei, Haibo Lin, Zhong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4229344/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Catalytic CoSn Perovskites for High-Performance Asymmetric Hybrid Supercapacitor and Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Experimental Investigation and DFT Validation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00890</link>
      <description>Karthick Raja K, Vivek Kumar, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394717114

                Developing a bifunctional electrode material for efficient energy storage and an effective electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains of significant scientific interest. Here, the electrochemical properties of perovskite hydroxide CoSn(OH)6 (CTH) and perovskite oxide CoSnO3&#8211;x (CTO) are systematically evaluated for their applications in asymmetric hybrid supercapacitors (AHSs) and as a catalyst for OER. Dunn analysis is employed to investigate the charge storage mechanism, and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy has been employed to study the charge transfer kinetics and diffusion kinetics associated with both the CTH and CTO electrodes. CTH and CTO exhibit specific capacitances of 1414 and 681 F/g, respectively, revealing that CTH notably manifests superior electrochemical performance. The DFT calculations are performed to elucidate the interaction of OH&#8211; ions with Co and Sn octahedral sites in CTH. Furthermore, the performance of CTH is assessed in a two-electrode system, with CTH acting as the positive electrode and reduced graphene oxide (RGO) as the negative electrode. The constructed CTH//RGO system exhibits an energy density of 83.5 W h/kg and a power density of 461 W/kg, which is a promising performance for energy storage applications. Furthermore, the OER activity was examined, demonstrating CTH's superior electrocatalytic efficiency, making it an effective bifunctional electrode material for OER and AHS applications.</description>
      <author>Karthick Raja K, Vivek Kumar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c00890</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating 3d Charge State via Halogen Ions in Neighboring Molecules of Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for Improving Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400042</link>
      <description>Yitian Hu, Yalei Fan, Lili Li, Jing Zhou, Zhiwei Hu, Jianqiang Wang, Juncai Dong, Shenlong Zhao, Linjuan Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394725150

                Abstract Modulating the coordination environment of the metal active center is an effective method to boost the catalytic performances of metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, little attention has been paid to the halogen effects on the ligands engineering. Herein, a series of MOFs X&#9472;FeNi&#8208;MOFs (X = Br, Cl, and F) is constructed with different coordination microenvironments to optimize OER activity. Theoretical calculations reveal that with the increase in electronegativity of halogen ions in terephthalic acid molecular (TPA), the Bader charge of Ni atoms gets larger and the Ni&#8208;3d band center and O&#8208;2p bands move closer to the Fermi level. This indicates that an increase in ligand negativity of halogen ions in TPA can promote the adsorption ability of catalytic sites to oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and reduce the activation barrier for OER. Experimental also demonstrates that F&#9472;FeNi&#8208;MOFs exhibit the highest catalytic activity with an ultralow overpotential of 218 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , outperforming most otate&#8208;of&#8208;the&#8208;art Fe/Co/Ni&#8208;based MOFs catalysts, and the enhanced mass activity by seven times compared with that for the sample before ligands engineering. This work opens a new avenue for the realization of the modulation of NiFe&#9472;O bonding by halogen ion in TPA and improves the OER performance of MOFs.</description>
      <author>Yitian Hu, Yalei Fan, Lili Li, Jing Zhou, Zhiwei Hu, Jianqiang Wang, Juncai Dong, Shenlong Zhao, Linjuan Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the modulation essence of p bands in Co-based oxide stability on acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6593-6</link>
      <description>Yuhao Yang, Yun Xu, Haiquan Liu, Qi Zhang, B. Liu, Menghua Yang, Huan Dai, Zunjian Ke, Deyan He, Xuefei Feng, Xin Xiao, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394725691

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuhao Yang, Yun Xu, Haiquan Liu, Qi Zhang, B. Liu, Menghua Yang, Huan Dai, Zunjian Ke, Deyan He, Xuefei Feng, Xin Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6593-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Multi-Interfacial Material Design Leading Bifunctional Oxygen Reduction and Water Oxidation Electrocatalysis to Zinc&#8211;Air Battery Application</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03031</link>
      <description>S.K. Tarik Aziz, Anshu Kumar, Mahendra Kumar Awasthi, Kothandaraman Ramanujam, Imran Karajagi, Vikram Vishal, Prakash C. Ghosh, Deepak P. Dubal, Arnab Dutta, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394727388

                The presence of an energy efficient and stable electrocatalyst capable of inflicting a bidirectional oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is vital for the proper functioning of a rechargeable zinc&#8211;air battery (ZAB). Here, we rationally combined ORR-active nitrogen-doped graphitic carbon (N@C) around an OER-inflicting Ce-doped Ni&#8211;Co layered double hydroxide (LDH) to generate a unique N@C_LDH-CeO2 material, where all the segments operate synergistically to display bidirectional ORR/OER activity under analogous conditions. This multi-interfacial N@C_LDH-CeO2 material displayed exceptional energy efficiency, which was measured by its relatively low potential difference (&#916;E) of 0.74 V between the half-wave potential of ORR (E1/2) and the OER potential at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 (Ej@10). This material was active in a ZAB assembly, achieving one of the highest reported specific energies (894.3 Wh kg&#8211;1 of Zn), appreciable power density (243 mW cm&#8211;2), and excellent specific capacity (698 mAh g&#8211;1 @ 10 mA cm&#8211;2), along with a remarkable durability of 270.0 h for 1600 continuous cycles. The tactical presence of N- and Ce-doping modulated the ORR and OER activity, respectively, as N@C_LDH-CeO2 displayed ample active sites during electrocatalysis on either side. This material remains active even in a solid-state ZAB assembly, where it successfully transduces energy to an electronic device.</description>
      <author>S.K. Tarik Aziz, Anshu Kumar, Mahendra Kumar Awasthi, Kothandaraman Ramanujam, Imran Karajagi, Vikram Vishal, Prakash C. Ghosh, Deepak P. Dubal, Arnab Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.3c03031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFeCo-OH/NiTe nanoarrays with amorphous/crystalline interfaces for highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00772g</link>
      <description>Fei Liu, Da Lei, Xiuping Yan, Peifang Guo, Hongliang Xu, Peng Chen, Renbing Wu, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394730620

                Transition metal tellurides have drawn much interest as alternative electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on account of the high electrical conductivity and variable phase and composition. However, they...</description>
      <author>Fei Liu, Da Lei, Xiuping Yan, Peifang Guo, Hongliang Xu, Peng Chen, Renbing Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00772g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Irruo&#8339; Mixed Oxide Nanocatalyst for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysis in Acidic Water Splitting: A Comparative Study with Iro&#8322; and Ruo&#8322; Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4791663</link>
      <description>Mohammad Zhiani, Haideh Balali Dehkordi, Junwu Xiao, Chuanwei Yan, Hongyi Tan, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394730762

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Mohammad Zhiani, Haideh Balali Dehkordi, Junwu Xiao, Chuanwei Yan, Hongyi Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4791663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous Graphene-Supported Nanostructured Nickel Telluride For Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4791819</link>
      <description>Hyun Suk Jung, Loganathan Kulandaivel, JeongWon Park, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394731007

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Hyun Suk Jung, Loganathan Kulandaivel, JeongWon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4791819</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scalable and economical production of oxygen deficient vanadium oxide with tunable vacancies concentration for bendable zinc ion batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234524</link>
      <description>Cong Guo, Rui Si, Yixiao Wang, Chengfei Qian, He Li, Jingfa Li, Journal of power sources. 605(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394733998

                Although vanadium oxides have high theoretical capacity and low cost, their practical application in aqueous zinc ion batteries (AZIBs) is bottlenecked by sluggish diffusion kinetics and capacity decline. Herein, the oxygen-deficient V2O5-x&#183;nH2O (defined as VOd) with tunable oxygen vacancy concentration has been obtained via an economic and scalable method. The introduction of oxygen vacancies not only provides extra sites for Zn2+ storage, but also reduces the electrostatic barrier for Zn2+ intercalation, resulting in enhanced capacity and cycling stability. As a result, VOd cathode with proper amount of oxygen defect exhibits a high capacity of 415 mAh g&#8722;1 and energy density of 294 Wh kg&#8722;1 at 0.2 A g&#8722;1, estimating a roughly chemical costs of $64/kWH for VOd cathode. Besides, the VOd exhibits excellent stability at 20 A g&#8722;1 with average capacity decay of 0.004 % per cycle for 5000 cycles. Moreover, the bendable quasi-solid VOd//Zn battery maintains stable capacity of 200 mAh g&#8722;1 at 2 A g&#8722;1 even when repeatedly bending to straight angles. Therefore, the economical production of VOd cathode and construction of bendable quasi-solid battery provides a feasible way to boost the construction of efficient flexible energy storage devices and broadened application of AZIBs.</description>
      <author>Cong Guo, Rui Si, Yixiao Wang, Chengfei Qian, He Li, Jingfa Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234524</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering quantum characteristics of incipient evolutions at the
  photosynthetic oxygen evolving complex</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.07048</link>
      <description>Pei-Ying Huo, Wei-Zhou Jiang, Rong-Yao Yang, Xiurong Zhang, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394737148

                Water oxidation of photosynthesis at the oxygen evolving complex (OEC) is driven by the polarization field induced by the photoelectric hole. By highlighting the role of the polarization field in reshaping the spin-orbit coupling deduced from the Dirac quantum mechanics, we reveal in this work the characteristics and underlying mechanism in the relatively simpler OEC evolutions within the states S0 - S2 prior to the water oxidation. The characteristic shifts of the density of states (DOS) of the electron donor Mn atom are observed in the vicinity of the Fermi surface to occur with the spin flips of Mn atoms and the change of the Mn oxidation states during the electron transfer. Notably, the spin flips of Mn atoms point to the resulting spin configuration of the next states. It is found that the electron transfer tend to stabilize the catalyst OEC itself, whereas the proton transfer pushes the evolution forward by preparing a new electron donor. Meanwhile, it shows that the Mn-O bonds around the candidate Mn atom of the electron donor undergo characteristic changes in the bond lengths during the electron transfer. These concomitant phenomena uncovered in first-principle calculations characterize the essential equilibrium of the OEC between the state evolution and stability that forms a ground of the dynamic OEC cycles.</description>
      <author>Pei-Ying Huo, Wei-Zhou Jiang, Rong-Yao Yang, Xiurong Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.07048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning oxygen vacancies on Bi2MoO6 surface for efficient electrocatalytic N2 reduction reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144266</link>
      <description>Ruida Chen, Huimin Yang, Yibo Jia, Yi Zhang, Nan Cheng, Fanfan Gao, Jiaqi Yang, Xuemei Gao, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394741835

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ruida Chen, Huimin Yang, Yibo Jia, Yi Zhang, Nan Cheng, Fanfan Gao, Jiaqi Yang, Xuemei Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144266</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Crystal Structure Regulation of CoSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Induced by Fe Dopant for Promoted Surface Reconstitution toward Energetic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00568</link>
      <description>Shuo Chen, Kwok To Yue, Jiawei Shi, Zhicheng Zheng, Yuanqing He, Hao Wan, Gen Chen, Ning Zhang, Xiaohe Liu, Renzhi Ma, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394755115

                Most nonoxide catalysts based on transition metal elements will inevitably change their primitive phases under anodic oxidation conditions in alkaline media. Establishing a relationship between the bulk phase and surface evolution is imperative to reveal the intrinsic catalytic active sites. In this work, it is demonstrated that the introduction of Fe facilitates the phase transition of orthorhombic CoSe2 into its cubic counterpart and then accelerates the Co&#8211;Fe hydroxide layer generation on the surface during electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As a result, the Fe-doped cubic CoSe2 catalyst exhibits a significantly enhanced activity with a considerable overpotential decrease of 79.9 and 66.9 mV to deliver 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 accompanied by a Tafel slope of 48.0 mV&#183;dec&#8211;1 toward OER when compared to orthorhombic CoSe2 and Fe-doped orthorhombic CoSe2, respectively. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations reveal that the introduction of Fe on the surface hydroxide layers will tune electron density around Co atoms and raise the d-band center. These findings will provide deep insights into the surface reconstitution of the OER electrocatalysts based on transition metal elements.</description>
      <author>Shuo Chen, Kwok To Yue, Jiawei Shi, Zhicheng Zheng, Yuanqing He, Hao Wan, Gen Chen, Ning Zhang, Xiaohe Liu, Renzhi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00568</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guided Design of Efficient Oxygen Evolution Catalysts Using Patent Analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10195</link>
      <description>Weiwei Zhang, Yongzhi Zhao, Jian Xu, Baorui Jia, Wujun Zhang, Mingli Qin, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394755167

                The facile and rapid design of efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts holds paramount significance for energy conversion devices, such as water electrolyzers and fuel cells. Despite substantial progress in catalyst synthesis and performance exploration, the design and selection processes remain inefficient. In this context, we integrate patent analysis with catalyst design, leveraging the scholarly research functionalities within patent analyses to aid in the design and synthesis of a NiFeRu-carbon catalyst as a high-performance OER catalyst. The results demonstrate that the NiFeRu-Carbon catalyst with low Ru loading (0.3 wt %) exhibits an overpotential of only 219 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 under alkaline conditions, and after continuous operation for 200 h, the overpotential only attenuates by 15 mV. The incorporation of high-valence Ru dopants elevated the intrinsic activity of individual catalytic sites within NiFe-layered double hydroxides (LDHs). During the catalytic process, the partial dissolution of Ru might lead to the generation of numerous oxygen vacancies within NiFe- LDH, thereby enhancing the catalyst's activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Weiwei Zhang, Yongzhi Zhao, Jian Xu, Baorui Jia, Wujun Zhang, Mingli Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Air-Calcined Fe/Ni-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Nanosheets for Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00481</link>
      <description>Shengkang Zhang, Xin Yu, Qi Feng, Ziqiang Lei, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394761278

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) plays a pivotal role in the hydrolysis process of zinc&#8211;air batteries. Consequently, it is essential to develop cathode catalysts with both cost-effectiveness and high oxygen evolution activity. In this study, we synthesized the FeFFIVE-1-Ni two-dimensional (2D) metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nanosheets via a straightforward solvothermal approach and oxidized them in an air atmosphere. During the calcination process in an air atmosphere, the heteroatoms (O, F) within the FeFFIVE-1-Ni 2D MOF nanosheets combine with iron and nickel metal ions, forming FeOF and NiF2 compounds. The synergy between these compounds and the creation of surface cracks during calcination yield catalytic active power and catalytic active sites essential for the oxygen evolution reaction. Notably, the overpotential of FeFFIVE-1-Ni 2D MOF nanosheets calcined in air under alkaline test conditions (&#951;10 = 286 mV) was lower than that of commercial RuO2 catalysts (&#951;10 = 355 mV). This work presents an effective strategy for replacing noble metal catalysts such as RuO2 by simply treating fluorinated metal&#8211;organic frameworks.</description>
      <author>Shengkang Zhang, Xin Yu, Qi Feng, Ziqiang Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c00481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet-Dependent Lattice Oxygen Activation on Oxygen-Defective Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00701</link>
      <description>Xiang Chen, Xinyue Xu, Cuiping Shao, Zhao Ke, Yuwen Cheng, Hongqiang Jin, Yumin Da, Dongming Liu, Wei Chen, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394768116

                Introducing oxygen vacancies into Co-based oxides with different surface structures can significantly affect their coordination environments and electronic structures, possibly contributing to the variation of the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. Herein, the oxygen vacancies were introduced into Co3O4 cubes and truncated octahedrons to uncover the effects of facets (001) and (111) on the intrinsic OER activity of oxygen-defective Co3O4. The (001)-faceted Co3O4 cubes with oxygen vacancies exhibited a lower onset overpotential of 298 mV than that of multifaceted truncated octahedrons (335 mV) because of the sufficient lattice oxygen participation in the OER process. Theoretical calculations revealed that oxygen vacancy on (001) surfaces can upshift the O 2p band center and trigger the lattice oxygen oxidation mechanism while oxygen vacancy on (111) surfaces matched well with the absorbate evolution mechanism. This work offers a new insight for designing OER electrocatalysts by selectively introducing oxygen defects on well-defined crystal facets.</description>
      <author>Xiang Chen, Xinyue Xu, Cuiping Shao, Zhao Ke, Yuwen Cheng, Hongqiang Jin, Yumin Da, Dongming Liu, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Performance of 2D Ni&#8208;Fe Layered Double Hydroxides by Cabbage&#8208;Inspired Carbon Conjunction for Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400309</link>
      <description>Youming Chen, Xinrui Gu, Song Guo, Jingjing Zhang, Sami Barkaoui, Liangliang Xu, Li Gao, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394768894

                Layered double hydroxide (LDH) nanosheets as one type of two&#8208;dimensional materials have garnered increasing attention in the field of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in recent decades. To address the challenges associated with poor conductivity and limited electron and charge transfer capability in LDH materials, we have developed a straightforward one&#8208;pot synthesis method to successfully fabricate a composite material with a microstructure resembling cabbage, which encompasses NiFe&#8208;LDH and nanocarbon (referred as NiFe&#8208;LDH@C). Atomic force microscopy (AFM) and high&#8208;resolution transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM) revealed that the monolayer NiFe&#8208;LDH with a height of ~ 0.5&#8208;0.8 nm is uniformly distributed and closely bonded to the carbon support, leading to a significant enhancement in conductivity and facilitating faster electron and charge transfer. Moreover, the NiFe&#8208;LDH@C exhibits a substantial number of surface defect sites, which enhances the interaction with oxygen species. This dual enhancement in charge transfer and oxygen species&#8208;mediated transfer greatly improves the catalytic OER performance, which is further corroborated by theoretical calculations. Notably, the Ni10Fe6&#8208;LDH@C with the highest concentration of surface oxygen vacancies demonstrated superior water oxidation performance, surpassing commercially available RuO2 catalysts; an OER overpotential of 231 mV@10 mA cm&#8208;2 with a Tafel slope of 71 mV dec&#8208;1 was achieved.</description>
      <author>Youming Chen, Xinrui Gu, Song Guo, Jingjing Zhang, Sami Barkaoui, Liangliang Xu, Li Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>General and facile synthesis of Co/CoO nanoparticals supported by nitrogen&#8208;doped graphenic networks as efficient oxygen electrocatalyst for Zn&#8208;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400570</link>
      <description>Xin Tian, Mengnan Xu, Xiangyang Ma, Guanyu Mu, Junwu Xiao, Shuai Wang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394768946

                Reasonable design of low&#8208;cost, high&#8208;efficiency and stable bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysts is of great significance to improve the reaction efficiency of Zn&#8208;air batteries, which is still a huge challenge. Here, we report a highly efficient bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst with three&#8208;dimensional (3D) N&#8208;doped graphene network&#8208;supported cobalt and cobalt oxide nanoparticles (Co/CoO&#8208;NG), which can be in situ synthesized by inducing metal ions on metal plates via graphene oxide as an inducer. This 3D network structure and open active center show excellent bifunctional oxygen electrocatalytic activity under alkaline conditions, and can be used as an air electrode in rechargeable Zn&#8208;air batteries, with significantly better power density (244.28 mW cm&#8208;2) and stability (over 340 h) than commercial Pt/C + RuO2 mixtures. This work is conducive to advancing the practical application of graphene&#8208;based materials as air electrodes for rechargeable zinc&#8208;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Xin Tian, Mengnan Xu, Xiangyang Ma, Guanyu Mu, Junwu Xiao, Shuai Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400570</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of CNT/Ru/Cobalt oxide composites as oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts via ball milling approach</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136468</link>
      <description>Tongya Tian, Sen Zhang, Yang Song, Chang Ming Li, Xi Zhou, Zhenghua Yang, Qizhe Ji, Xianglong Zhao, Feiyong Chen, Materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394769989

                Ruthenium (Ru) and Cobalt oxides (CoO) nanoparticles are uniformly decorated on surfaces of carbon nanotubes (CNTs), via ball milling of mixtures consisting of commercial CNTs, triphenylphosphine ruthenium chlorides and Cobalt nitrates. Due to collective contributions of Ru and CoO, the obtained CNT/Ru/CoO composites exhibit excellent electrocatalytic activities and durability for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), both of which outperform those of the state-of-the-art iridium oxide catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tongya Tian, Sen Zhang, Yang Song, Chang Ming Li, Xi Zhou, Zhenghua Yang, Qizhe Ji, Xianglong Zhao, Feiyong Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matlet.2024.136468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strongly Facet-Dependent Activity of Iron-Doped &#946;-Nickel Oxyhydroxide for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00315b</link>
      <description>Ananth Govind Rajan, John Mark P. Martirez, Emily A. Carter, Physical chemistry chemical physics/PCCP. Physical chemistry chemical physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394772653

                Iron(Fe)-doped &#61538;-nickel oxyhydroxide (&#61538;-NiOOH) is a highly active, noble-metal-free electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), with the latter being the bottleneck in electrochemical water splitting for sustainable hydrogen production....</description>
      <author>Ananth Govind Rajan, John Mark P. Martirez, Emily A. Carter</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cp00315b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of inhibition of the oxygen-evolving complex of photosystem II by lanthanide cations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0006302923040038</link>
      <description>E. R. Lovyagina, A. V. Loktyushkin, N. S. Vasiliev, Boris K. Semin, Biofizika. 68(4)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394750332

                The process of the interaction of La3+and Tb3+ cations with the Ca-binding site of the oxygen-evolving complex of photosystem II samples depleted of calcium has been studied. The binding of cations to the Ca-binding site is irreversible and the bound cations cannot be washed out or replaced by Ca2+ cation. A feature of lanthanides to bind strongly to the Ca-binding site has been used to investigate if the bound Ln3+ cation has an effect on the high-affinity Mn-binding site of the oxygen-evolving complex. Therefore, in this work, hydroquinone was used for the extraction of manganese cations from the oxygen-evolving complex of the calcium-depleted photosystem II membranes with the Ca-binding site blocked by La3+ or Tb3+ and the activity of the high-affinity site was then examined using exogenous electron donors (Mn2+ + H2O2) and 1,5-di-phenylcarbazide. It was found that lanthanide cation bound to the Ca-binding site can significantly inhibit the oxidation rates of electron donors through the high-affinity Mn-binding site. The mechanism of the observed effect is discussed.</description>
      <author>E. R. Lovyagina, A. V. Loktyushkin, N. S. Vasiliev, Boris K. Semin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0006302923040038</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of Oxygen Evolution Electrode from Spinel NiCo2O4 by Composite-Plating Technique</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1998.6.74</link>
      <description>Cai Nai-cai, Keli Zhang, Julin Yuan, Yong Liu, Jutang Sun, Yingyong huaxue. 15(6)] 1998. https://openalex.org/W4394601018

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Cai Nai-cai, Keli Zhang, Julin Yuan, Yong Liu, Jutang Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 1998 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1998.6.74</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>KINETICS AND MECHANISMS OF OXYGEN EVOLUTION ON Pt ANODE IN HCIO4 and H2 S04 SOLUTIONS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1990.6.37</link>
      <description>Shixiong Jin, Lan Wang, Zhi'ang Zhu, Yingyong huaxue. 7(6)] 1990. https://openalex.org/W4394733133

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shixiong Jin, Lan Wang, Zhi'ang Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 1990 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1990.6.37</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation and Oxygen Evolution Activity of the Composite Oxides of Ni and Co</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1994.3.32</link>
      <description>Ping Cheng, Qiuzhi Shi, Jianming Zhang, Changchun Yang, Yingyong huaxue. 11(3)] 1994. https://openalex.org/W4394701798

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ping Cheng, Qiuzhi Shi, Jianming Zhang, Changchun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 1994 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1994.3.32</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electropolymerization of novel cobalt and iron complexes of thiophene-substituted quinoline-derivative for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.001</link>
      <description>Qi Yao, Dan Wang, Yichuang Xing, Yang Bai, Yanhang Ma, Chao Wang, International journal of hydrogen energy. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394590229

                Research on novel electrocatalysts with high activity, stability, and economic feasibility for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is important to the wide application of water electrolyzers. Here, two novel quinoline complexes, L-Co and L-Fe, are synthesized and their crystal structure and electrochemical properties are systematically investigated. Electropolymerization using these complexes are successfully carried out on carbon cloth. The copolymer (P&#8211;Co&#8211;Fe) is active towards OER in 1 M KOH, with 298 mV overpotential to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2 current densities. Kinetic analyses suggest the P&#8211;Co&#8211;Fe follows both the adsorbate evolution and lattice oxygen evolution mechanistic pathways. Lower Tafel slope value, lower charge transfer resistance and lower apparent activation energy all suggest enhacned intrinsic activity of the P&#8211;Co&#8211;Fe, which stem from the electron interaction between the Co and Fe moieties. The P&#8211;Co&#8211;Fe exhibits stability in 1 M KOH over 24 h, with partial decomposition and the formation of oxides/hydroxides.</description>
      <author>Qi Yao, Dan Wang, Yichuang Xing, Yang Bai, Yanhang Ma, Chao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.001</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Insights into mechanism of peroxymonosufate activation by Mo single-atom catalysts: Singlet oxygen evolution and role of Mo&#8211;N coordination</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120846</link>
      <description>Yinlong Guo, Chao Ma, Zhiyuan Gao, Mingzhen Wu, Chung&#8208;Hua Shen, Zhihua Xu, Journal of environmental management. 358(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394632837

                Recently, the Fenton-like reaction using peroxymonosulfate (PMS) has been acknowledged as a potential method for breaking down organic pollutants. In this study, we successfully synthesized a highly efficient and stable single atom molybdenum (Mo) catalyst dispersed on nitrogen-doped carbon (Mo-NC-0.1). This catalyst was then utilized for the first time to activate PMS and degrade bisphenol A (BPA). The Mo-NC-0.1/PMS system demonstrated the ability to completely degrade BPA within just 20 min. Scavenging tests and density functional theory (DFT) calculations have demonstrated that the primary reactive oxygen species was singlet oxygen (1O2) produced by Mo-N4 sites. The self-cycling of Mo facilitated PMS activation and the transition from a free radical activation pathway to a non-radical pathway mediated by 1O2. Simultaneously, the nearby pyridinic N served as adsorption sites to immobilize BPA and PMS molecules. The exceptionally high catalytic activity of Mo-NC-0.1 derived from its unique Mo-N coordination, which markedly reduced the distance for 1O2 to migrate to the BPA molecules. The Mo-NC-0.1/PMS system effectively reduced the acute toxicity of BPA and exhibited excellent cycling stability with minimal leaching. This study presented a new catalyst with high selectivity for 1O2 generation and provided valuable insights for the application of single atom catalysts in PMS-based AOPs.</description>
      <author>Yinlong Guo, Chao Ma, Zhiyuan Gao, Mingzhen Wu, Chung&#8208;Hua Shen, Zhihua Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvman.2024.120846</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative study on the molecular evolution of changqing petroleum coke during air and pure oxygen combustion: A ReaxFF method analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142104</link>
      <description>Junyi He, Xintong Yang, X.-J. Li, Wenhong Cao, Hao Xu, Qian Yin, Xin Jiang, Bo Liu, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394623031

                Based on reactive force field (ReaxFF) simulation, the molecular evolution mechanism of air combustion simulation and pure oxygen combustion simulation of Changqing petroleum coke was studied. On the basis of the original petroleum coke molecular model, N2 and O2 molecules were added to construct the air combustion simulation model and the pure oxygen combustion simulation model respectively. The number of molecules, main products, and typical hydrocarbon gases in the two simulation results were analyzed by setting up the LAMMPS in. file. Finally, the molecular changes of pyrrole and pyridine were described. The results show that the main reaction interval of pure oxygen combustion is earlier than that of air combustion. In the main reaction temperature range, the reaction rate of pure oxygen combustion is higher than that of simulated air combustion. At 170 ps, the two simulations reaction speed is the fastest time point; Pyridine is more stable than pyrrole. The research on the distinction and comparison of two kinds of simulation has certain guiding significance for the clean utilization of petroleum coke combustion process in industry.</description>
      <author>Junyi He, Xintong Yang, X.-J. Li, Wenhong Cao, Hao Xu, Qian Yin, Xin Jiang, Bo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142104</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in noble-metal-free electrocatalysts to achieve efficient alkaline water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta07418h</link>
      <description>Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Mohammed Ibrahim Jamesh, Dingqin Hu, Jing Wang, Farah Naz, Jianpei Feng, Li Yu, Zhao Cai, Juan Carlos Colmenares, Dong Hoon Lee, Paul K. Chu, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394626670

                Electrochemical water splitting is one of the promising approaches for generating hydrogen. Developing noble-metal-free electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are important to achieve efficient...</description>
      <author>Hsien&#8208;Yi Hsu, Mohammed Ibrahim Jamesh, Dingqin Hu, Jing Wang, Farah Naz, Jianpei Feng, Li Yu, Zhao Cai, Juan Carlos Colmenares, Dong Hoon Lee, Paul K. Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d3ta07418h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review of noble metal-free high entropy alloys for water splitting applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00690a</link>
      <description>Bin Kamaruddin Hamzah, Jianghong Zhang, Liang Yu, Yuefan Wei, Yizhong Huang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394730006

                Nano-sized high entropy alloy (HEA) catalysts have attracted much attention as extraordinary electrocatalysts in water-splitting applications, i.e., hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Recently, there has been...</description>
      <author>Bin Kamaruddin Hamzah, Jianghong Zhang, Liang Yu, Yuefan Wei, Yizhong Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00690a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing vacancy-rich metal phosphates by the spatial effect of ionic oligomers for enhanced OER activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01706d</link>
      <description>Ying Zhao, Xinlin He, Xiaoming Ma, Zhengxi Guo, Qiang Ma, Zhaoming Liu, Ruikang Tang, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394754314

                The Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER) is a critical half-reaction in green energy devices and has become a bottleneck in improving energy conversion efficiency. Introducing vacancies in electrocatalysts is recognized as...</description>
      <author>Ying Zhao, Xinlin He, Xiaoming Ma, Zhengxi Guo, Qiang Ma, Zhaoming Liu, Ruikang Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01706d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic effect of vanadium incorporation in Cobalt-based LDH on electron and proton transfer during electrocatalytic benzyl alcohol oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00728j</link>
      <description>Jingjing Bai, Liang Chen, Chenghang Lv, Hongyu Ruo, Y. Pan, Shoudong Xu, Jiaqi Chen, Bingchuan Yang, Ding Zhang, Huimin Yang, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394772303

                Electricity-driven water splitting is a promising approach for cost-effective and environmental-friendly hydrogen production. However, the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a major bottleneck for its industrial application. An alternative...</description>
      <author>Jingjing Bai, Liang Chen, Chenghang Lv, Hongyu Ruo, Y. Pan, Shoudong Xu, Jiaqi Chen, Bingchuan Yang, Ding Zhang, Huimin Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00728j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>THE ANODIC FORMATION OF FERRATE ION IN CONCENTRATED ALKALI SOLUTIONS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1988.3.86</link>
      <description>Shixiong Jin, Hua Zhang, Lan Wang, Z.Y. Ma, Dan Geng, Yingyong huaxue. 5(3)] 1988. https://openalex.org/W4394733547

                The kinetic data related to the anodic formation of FeO42- and oxygen evolution on iron and mild steel electrodes in concentrated alkaline solution were obtained by measuring the rate of O2 evolution. It is found that the two reactions Proceed simutaneously and two tafel regions can be separated. At low current density &#8706;&#968;/&#8706;lgi= 2,303 RT/ (I+&#946;)F, i.e. 0.040V (&#946;=0.5) and the reaction ordor with resPecet to &#945;OH- is 4 for FeO42- anodic formation and 2 for O2 evolution. At high current density &#8706;&#968;/&#8706;lgi= 2.303 RT/&#946;F, i.e. 0.120V and the reaction ordor is 2 and 1 for both reactions, resPectively. A mechanism for the two reactions is ProPosed.</description>
      <author>Shixiong Jin, Hua Zhang, Lan Wang, Z.Y. Ma, Dan Geng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 1988 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1988.3.86</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Combined Covalent and Supramolecular Polymerization To Reinforce Perylenebisimide Photosynthetic &#8220;Quantasomes&#8221;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401061</link>
      <description>Alisa Ranscht, Francesco Rigodanza, Thomas Gobbato, Ilaria Crea, Elsje Alessandra Quadrelli, J. Canivet, Marcella Bonchio, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394680726

                Abstract Invited for the cover of this issue are the groups of Marcella Bonchio at the University of Padova and J&#233;r&#244;me Canivet at the CNRS&#8211;University of Lyon. The image depicts the hierarchical self&#8208;organization of bio&#8208;inspired quantasomes, crosslinked within a polystyrene network to enchain their lateral and orthogonal proximity for long&#8208;lasting oxygen evolution using green photons. Read the full text of the article at 10.1002/chem.202303784 .</description>
      <author>Alisa Ranscht, Francesco Rigodanza, Thomas Gobbato, Ilaria Crea, Elsje Alessandra Quadrelli, J. Canivet, Marcella Bonchio</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Reversible Zn&#8211;Air Batteries Enabled by Tuned Valence Electron and Steric Hindrance on Atomic Fe&#8211;N&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;C Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01078</link>
      <description>Zheng He, Danni Deng, Xinran Zheng, Yingbi Chen, Bo Yu, Mengjie Liu, Jiabi Jiang, Huijie Zheng, Yuchao Wang, Jinxian Wang, Peiyao Yang, Yu Xiong, Xiang Xiong, Yongpeng Lei, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394566574

                The bifunctional oxygen electrocatalyst is the Achilles' heel of achieving robust reversible Zn-air batteries (ZABs). Herein, durable bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis in alkaline media is realized on atomic Fe-N4-C sites reinforced by NixCo3-xO4 (NixCo3-xO4@Fe1/NC). Compared with that of pristine Fe1/NC, the stability of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is increased 10 times and the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance is also improved. The steric hindrance alters the valence electron at the Fe-N4-C sites, resulting in a shorter Fe-N bond and enhanced stability of the Fe-N4-C sites. The corresponding solid-state ZABs exhibit an ultralong lifespan (&gt;460 h at 5 mA cm-2) and high rate performance (from 2 to 50 mA cm-2). Furthermore, the structural evolution of NixCo3-xO4@Fe1/NC before and after the OER and ORR as well as charge-discharge cycling is explored. This work develops an efficient strategy for improving bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis and possibly other processes.</description>
      <author>Zheng He, Danni Deng, Xinran Zheng, Yingbi Chen, Bo Yu, Mengjie Liu, Jiabi Jiang, Huijie Zheng, Yuchao Wang, Jinxian Wang, Peiyao Yang, Yu Xiong, Xiang Xiong, Yongpeng Lei</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AC-electrochemical synthesis of H2O2 by breathing O2 in three-phase interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109600</link>
      <description>Peng Du, Ruyue Wang, Bohan Deng, Wei Zhao, Xinyu Xie, Cheng Yang, Yuanzheng Long, Chong Yan, Xiwen He, Kai Huang, Ru Zhang, Ming Lei, Hui Wu, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394611320

                Conventional electrosynthesis of H2O2 through a two-electron oxygen reduction reaction (2e&#8722; ORR) requires continuous O2 feeding as the reactant, which is produced by oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water electrolysis. In principle, H2O2 can be directly synthesized from water once the 2e&#8722; ORR is coupled with OER in one electrode. Unfortunately, such effective coupling has not yet been established. Herein, we created a cyclic oxygen exhalation-inhalation for on-demand and on-site H2O2 production by coupling the OER and 2e&#8722; ORR with a facile alternating-current (AC) electrocatalytic process. By ingeniously manipulating the reaction interfaces and operating voltage, we achieved efficient and stable in-situ H2O2 production. The rapid oxygen transfer in the localized three-phase interface favors the sufficient electrochemical reactions. The AC-electrocatalytic system exhibits highest performance including H2O2 production rate of 90.16 mmol h-1 gcat-1. Moreover, such AC-electrocatalysis inspires a new strategy to combine multiple electrocatalytic reactions into one electrode for fundamental study and practical applications.</description>
      <author>Peng Du, Ruyue Wang, Bohan Deng, Wei Zhao, Xinyu Xie, Cheng Yang, Yuanzheng Long, Chong Yan, Xiwen He, Kai Huang, Ru Zhang, Ming Lei, Hui Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109600</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marine Phosphate Level During the Archean Constrained by the Global Redox Budget</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2023gl108077</link>
      <description>Yasuto Watanabe, Kazumi Ozaki, Eiichi Tajika, Geophysical research letters. 51(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394576720

                Abstract Understanding the oceanic phosphate concentration is critical for understanding marine productivity and oxygen evolution throughout Earth history. During the Archean, estimates of marine phosphate levels range from scarce to enriched conditions. However, biogeochemical conditions required for sustaining high phosphate concentrations while retaining an anoxic atmosphere during the Archean remain ambiguous. Here, we employ a biogeochemical model of the marine phosphate cycle to determine the conditions under which oceanic phosphate levels could have been higher than present&#8208;day values during the Archean after the emergence of oxygenic photoautotrophs (OP). We show that, under the presence of OP, phosphate&#8208;rich oceans require the limitation by factors other than phosphate, or a high outgassing rate of reducing gases. If these conditions were not met, the occurrence of oceanic phosphate levels higher than present&#8208;day values during the Archean would require the absence of OP.</description>
      <author>Yasuto Watanabe, Kazumi Ozaki, Eiichi Tajika</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2023gl108077</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paired photoelectrochemical conversion of CO2/H2O and glycerol at high rate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01134-3</link>
      <description>Anna Balog, Egon Kecsenovity, Gergely F. Samu, Jie He, D&#225;vid Fekete, Csaba Jan&#225;ky, Nature Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394608914

                Abstract Photoelectrochemistry holds the promise of directly converting sunlight to valuable chemical products. Photoelectrochemical (PEC) methods, however, lag behind their electrochemical counterparts in terms of current density. In this work, we demonstrate that, by using concentrated sunlight, we can achieve current densities similar to electrochemical methods, but with lower energy input. Specifically, we combined the direct PEC oxidation of glycerol with the dark hydrogen evolution or CO 2 reduction in a membrane-separated continuous-flow PEC cell. We achieved over 110 mA cm &#8722;2 photocurrent density, which is at least an order of magnitude larger than those typically reported in the literature. We demonstrated that the product distribution of glycerol oxidation is notably different in PEC and electrochemical scenarios at the same current density, and the parasitic oxygen evolution reaction can be suppressed in the PEC case. This approach raises opportunities to drive complex electrochemical reactions in a more selective manner.</description>
      <author>Anna Balog, Egon Kecsenovity, Gergely F. Samu, Jie He, D&#225;vid Fekete, Csaba Jan&#225;ky</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41929-024-01134-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A non-consumable argon plasma anode for carbon-free electrochemical ironmaking</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.03.011</link>
      <description>Shuwei Feng, Junjie Zhang, Junli Xu, Mouhamadou A. Diop, Aimin Liu, Fengguo Liu, Xianwei Hu, Zhaowen Wang, Miroslav Bo&#269;a, Zhongning Shi, Materials today. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394757862

                Blast furnace ironmaking produces abundant CO2, and molten oxide electrolysis (MOE) attracts great interest in ironmaking due to its carbon-free emissions. However, the anodes are the key limiting factor, making them very challenging due to high temperature and the intensive oxidation atmosphere. In this respect, a non-consumable argon plasma anode for iron electrolysis is proposed as a new technological process. During electrolysis, argon ionizes anodically and forms Ar+, which will jet into the molten oxide electrolyte and react with the O2&#8211; complex anion from the electrolyte. Metallic iron is obtained by cathodic reduction, while oxygen evolution and argon regeneration occur in the electrolyte through 2O2&#8211;(complex) + 4Ar+ = O2 + 4Ar, demonstrating the workability of the argon plasma as a non-consumable anode for molten oxide electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Shuwei Feng, Junjie Zhang, Junli Xu, Mouhamadou A. Diop, Aimin Liu, Fengguo Liu, Xianwei Hu, Zhaowen Wang, Miroslav Bo&#269;a, Zhongning Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mattod.2024.03.011</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Powering the Future by Iron Sulfide Type Material (Fe&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;S&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;y&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt;) Based Electrochemical Materials for Water Splitting and Energy Storage Applications: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402015</link>
      <description>Farhan Ahmad, Wajeeha Qayyum, Urooj Fatima, Shahid Nawaz, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Tak H. Kim, Varsha Srivastava, John Vakros, Zacharias Frontistis, Grzegorz Boczkaj, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394686918

                Water electrolysis is among the recent alternatives for generating clean fuels (hydrogen). It is an efficient way to produce pure hydrogen at a rapid pace with no unwanted by-products. Effective and cheap water-splitting electrocatalysts with enhanced activity, specificity, and stability are currently widely studied. In this regard, noble metal-free transition metal-based catalysts are of high interest. Iron sulfide (FeS) is one of the essential electrocatalysts for water splitting because of its unique structural and electrochemical features. This article discusses the significance of FeS and its nanocomposites as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and overall water splitting. FeS and its nanocomposites have been studied also for energy storage in the form of electrode materials in supercapacitors and lithium- (LIBs) and sodium-ion batteries (SIBs). The structural and electrochemical characteristics of FeS and its nanocomposites, as well as the synthesis processes, are discussed in this work. This discussion correlates these features with the requirements for electrocatalysts in overall water splitting and its associated reactions. As a result, this study provides a road map for researchers seeking economically viable, environmentally friendly, and efficient electrochemical materials in the fields of green energy production and storage.</description>
      <author>Farhan Ahmad, Wajeeha Qayyum, Urooj Fatima, Shahid Nawaz, Aldona Bal&#269;i&#363;nait&#279;, Tak H. Kim, Varsha Srivastava, John Vakros, Zacharias Frontistis, Grzegorz Boczkaj</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402015</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing electrocatalytic water oxidation performances with tungsten-enhanced perovskite cobaltites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.016</link>
      <description>Wenying Yang, Shimin Lai, Kaitao Li, Qirui Ye, Feifei Dong, Zhan Lin, International journal of hydrogen energy. 65(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394702470

                The sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is generally undesirable for advanced green hydrogen production through renewable energy unless the employment of efficient catalysts. Perovskite-type oxide materials have been recognized as promising alternatives to overcome the kinetic limitations of OER. Nonetheless, despite extensive research endeavors, the electrochemical activity and durability of versatile perovskite candidates still fall short of expectations. Herein, a novel perovskite cobaltite BaCo0.6Fe0.2W0.2O3-&#948; (BCFW0.2), enlightened by tungsten incorporation strategy, is proposed as a reliable electrocatalyst for OER. Characterization analyses unravel that the manipulation of tungsten substitution in BCFW0.2 leads to the formation of high-symmetry crystal structure and more reactive oxygen species, which in turn promotes favorable oxygen catalytic behavior. Accordingly, the BCFW0.2 catalyst exhibits significantly lower overpotential of 273 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and remarkably smaller Tafel slope of 42.34 mV dec&#8722;1 relative to its un-doped counterpart, as well as considerable operational durability under various current densities. The mechanism of lattice oxygen activation in BCFW0.2 is also explored. This study paves a constructive avenue for the rational design of high-performance perovskite-based derivative catalysts.</description>
      <author>Wenying Yang, Shimin Lai, Kaitao Li, Qirui Ye, Feifei Dong, Zhan Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.016</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revealing electronic state evolution of Co(II)/Co(III) in CoO (111) plane during OER process through magnetic measurement</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109872</link>
      <description>Yanjie Li, Chaoqun Qu, Siqi Meng, Jianhang Hu, Zhe Gao, Hongxing Xu, Rui Gao, Ming Feng, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394619266

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is one of the most important half-reactions related to metal-air batteries, fuel cells, and water-splitting. Due to the sluggish kinetic and multi-electron transfer, catalysts appear to be particularly important for the OER. Knowing the reaction mechanism is fundamental to developing new catalysts and improving OER efficiency. In this work, phase transition and atomic reconstruction on CoO (111) plane were revealed through ex-situ diffraction methods and X-ray absorption spectroscopy. At the same time, the electronic state evolution of Co(II)/Co(III) during the OER process has also been concluded by analyzing the magnetic properties. This work shows that during the OER process, Co(III) experiences surface electron rearrangement from IS (intermediate-spin state) to LS (low-spin state) and then returns to IS/HS (high-spin state) under high voltage region. This work provides a new view to reveal the reaction mechanism through the magnetic property and it can be extended to more magnetic 3d transition metals for future catalyst design.</description>
      <author>Yanjie Li, Chaoqun Qu, Siqi Meng, Jianhang Hu, Zhe Gao, Hongxing Xu, Rui Gao, Ming Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109872</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mo, N co-doped cobalt hydroxide nanosheets for highly selective Methanol-to-Formate electrocatalytic conversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151087</link>
      <description>Yaoxin Wu, Lili Ban, H. Wang, Qiong Yang, Yaao Li, Ke L&#252;, Yuxiang Li, Peipei Cui, Jinfeng Yang, Dalei Chang, Dezheng Yang, Feng Ye, Zongyuan Wang, Bin Dai, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394575810

                The development of low-cost electrocatalysts to selectively oxidize methanol to formate to replace the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) will be beneficial to reduce the overpotential of electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, we propose a one-step low-temperature strategy for anion and cation co-doping to reconstruct ZIF-67 into two-dimensional Mo, N co-doped Co(OH)2 [N-CoMo(OH)x]. The N-CoMo(OH)x only needs 1.36 V to achieve 10 mA cm&#8722;2 for methanol oxidation reaction (MOR). Meanwhile, N-CoMo(OH)x exhibits good stability at 100 mA cm&#8722;2 with Faraday efficiency of 98.1 %. The Mo6+ and N co-doping synergistically enhance the conductivity and dehydrogenation energy barrier of OCH2 intermediate species, leading to good catalytic performance. This work thus provides a strategy for designing anion and cation co-doped catalysts for methanol upgrading.</description>
      <author>Yaoxin Wu, Lili Ban, H. Wang, Qiong Yang, Yaao Li, Ke L&#252;, Yuxiang Li, Peipei Cui, Jinfeng Yang, Dalei Chang, Dezheng Yang, Feng Ye, Zongyuan Wang, Bin Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151087</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-precious bifunctional high entropy alloy catalyst and layered double hydroxide enhanced gel electrolyte based rechargeable flexible zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151093</link>
      <description>Tingyu Lin, F.Y. Yen, Yu-Chieh Ting, Po&#8208;Wei Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394580153

                Cost-effective highly efficient and stable bifunctional oxygen catalysts are critical for practical applications of rechargeable zinc-air batteries (ZABs). In this study, a non-precious bifunctional FeCoNiCuMo high entropy alloy (HEA) catalyst was developed, exhibiting outstanding dual-functionality toward catalysis of oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reactions, with an ultralow voltage gap (&#916;E10) of 0.67 V. The FeCoNiCuMo HEA based ZAB exhibited a high peak power density of 298 mW cm&#8722;2 at a high current density of 412 mA cm&#8722;2 and an outstanding cycling stability over 1576 cycles (788 h) at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 with a minor voltage gap increase of 6.2 %. Incorporation of CoNi layered double hydroxide nanowire arrays to poly(vinyl alcohol) (PVA) gel electrolytes significantly enhanced the aqueous electrolyte adsorption and water retention capabilities and ionic conductivities of the PVA gel, leading to much improved efficiency and stability of the flexible ZAB (FZAB), with an increase in peak power densities from 72 to 102.9 mW cm&#8722;2 and a prolonged lifespan from 35 to 58 h at 5 mA cm&#8722;2. The FZAB exhibited excellent mechanical stability, with no variations in voltage gaps observed under increasing bending.</description>
      <author>Tingyu Lin, F.Y. Yen, Yu-Chieh Ting, Po&#8208;Wei Chen, Shih&#8208;Yuan Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151093</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isolated Binary Fe&#8211;Ni Metal&#8211;Nitrogen Sites Anchored on Porous Carbon Nanosheets for Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis through High-Temperature Gas-Migration Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17193</link>
      <description>Xinghuan Liu, Xiaodong Yang, Zehua Zhao, Tianwen Fang, Ke Yi, Long Chen, Shiyu Liu, Rongjie Wang, Xin Jia, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394619166

                Atomically dispersed dual-site catalysts can regulate multiple reaction processes and provide synergistic functions based on diverse molecules and their interfaces. However, how to synthesize and stabilize dual-site single-atom catalysts (DACs) is confronted with challenges. Herein, we report a facile high-temperature gas-migration strategy to synthesize Fe-Ni DACs on nitrogen-doped carbon nanosheets (FeNiSAs/NC). FeNiSAs/NC exhibits a high half-wave potential (0.88 V) for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and a low overpotential of 410 mV at 10 mA cm-2 for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As an air electrode for Zn-air batteries (ZABs), it shows better performances in aqueous ZABs and excellent stability and flexibility in solid-state ZABs. The high specific surface area (1687.32 m2/g) of FeNiSAs/NC is conducive to electron transport. Density functional theory (DFT) reveals that the Fe sites are the active center, and Ni sites can significantly optimize the free energy of the oxygen-containing intermediate state on Fe sites, contributing to the improvement of ORR and the corresponding OER activities. This work can provide guidance for the rational design of DACs and understand the structure-activity relationship of SACs with multiple active sites for electrocatalytic energy conversion.</description>
      <author>Xinghuan Liu, Xiaodong Yang, Zehua Zhao, Tianwen Fang, Ke Yi, Long Chen, Shiyu Liu, Rongjie Wang, Xin Jia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c17193</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Performance of High&#8208;Entropy Disordered Rocksalt Oxyfluoride Cathode by Atomic Layer Deposition Coating for Li&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400005</link>
      <description>Bei Zhou, Siyu An, David Kitsche, S&#246;ren L. Dreyer, Kai Wang, Xiaohui Huang, Jonas Thanner, Matteo Bianchini, Torsten Brezesinski, Ben Breitung, Horst Hahn, Qingsong Wang, Small structures. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394574895

                Lithium&#8208;excess cation&#8208;disordered rocksalt materials are a promising class of transition metal&#8208;based cathodes that exhibit high specific capacity and energy density. The exceptional performance is achieved through participation of anionic redox in addition to cationic redox reactions in the electrochemistry. However, anionic redox reactions accompanied by oxygen evolution, accelerated electrolyte breakdown, and structural evolution lead to voltage hysteresis and low initial Coulombic efficiency. Herein, an Al 2 O 3 layer with varying thickness has been coated onto a high&#8208;entropy disordered rocksalt oxyfluoride cathode through atomic layer deposition to enhance battery performance. The results indicate that the utilization of a uniform Al 2 O 3 coating improves the capacity retention and rate capability of the cathode, with the performance being strongly dependent on the layer thickness. Further investigation into cathode&#8211;electrolyte interfacial reactions reveals that the thin protecting Al 2 O 3 coating can reduce the decomposition of electrolyte on the cathode surface but cannot prevent bulk phase degradation during prolonged cycling. These findings highlight the need for optimized coating design on the disordered rocksalt cathode to improve battery performance.</description>
      <author>Bei Zhou, Siyu An, David Kitsche, S&#246;ren L. Dreyer, Kai Wang, Xiaohui Huang, Jonas Thanner, Matteo Bianchini, Torsten Brezesinski, Ben Breitung, Horst Hahn, Qingsong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sstr.202400005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of bay-substituted perylene diimide as bifunctional photocatalyst for enhanced water oxidation and hydrogen peroxide generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114116</link>
      <description>Bo Zhang, Shoufeng Wang, Shihao Min, Kang Li, Longtian Kang, Wenbin Lin, Molecular catalysis. 560(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394589492

                Rational design of semiconductor molecule structure is of significant importance for achieving the multifunctional photocatalysis. Herein, three end/bay-substituted perylenediimide (PDI) molecules, including bis(N-carboxymethyl) perylenediimide (H2PDI), 1,7-dibromo-substituted H2PDI (2Br-H2PDI) and 1,6,7,12-tetraether-substituted H2PDI (4CH3CH2O-H2PDI), are synthesized for photocatalytic oxygen evolution (POE) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). One-dimensional H2PDI nanorods, two-dimensional 2Br-H2PDI nanosheets, and zero-dimensional 4CH3CH2O-H2PDI nanoparticles are obtained. Under visible light, 4CH3CH2O-H2PDI as photocatalyst (5.31 mmol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1) exhibits the 1.8-times and 20-times POE rate of 2Br-H2PDI (2.93 mmol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1) and H2PDI (0.26 mmol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1) with AgNO3 as sacrificial agent. Additionally, the POE rate can be further improved to 9.34 mmol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1 with the Co2+ doping of 4CH3CH2O-H2PDI. With isopropanol as sacrificial agent, the H2O2 evolution rate of 657.4 &#956;M&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1 can be also achieved via photocatalytic ORR with 4CH3CH2O-H2PDI as catalyst, which is &#8764;3 and &#8764;4 times those of 2Br-H2PDI (220.8 &#956;M&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1) and H2PDI (160.0 &#956;M&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1), respectively. Especially, in the O2- or air- saturated aqueous solution without sacrificial agent, the H2O2 rate of 273.1 or 112.7 &#956;M&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1 can be also achieved. This work provides a promising way to design the PDI-based multifunctional photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Bo Zhang, Shoufeng Wang, Shihao Min, Kang Li, Longtian Kang, Wenbin Lin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mcat.2024.114116</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Principles Study of the Structure&#8211;Performance Relation of Pristine Wn+1Cn and Oxygen-Functionalized Wn+1CnO2 MXenes as Cathode Catalysts for Li-O2 Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14080666</link>
      <description>Liangliang Zhu, J. Wang, Jie Liu, R. H. Wang, Ming Chang Lin, Tao Wang, Yuchao Zhen, Jing Xu, Lianming Zhao, Nanomaterials. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394764123

                Li-O2 batteries are considered a highly promising energy storage solution. However, their practical implementation is hindered by the sluggish kinetics of the oxygen reduction (ORR) and oxygen evolution (OER) reactions at cathodes during discharging and charging, respectively. In this work, we investigated the catalytic performance of Wn+1Cn and Wn+1CnO2 MXenes (n = 1, 2, and 3) as cathodes for Li-O2 batteries using first principles calculations. Both Wn+1Cn and Wn+1CnO2 MXenes show high conductivity, and their conductivity is further enhanced with increasing atomic layers, as reflected by the elevated density of states at the Fermi level. The oxygen functionalization can change the electronic properties of WC MXenes from the electrophilic W surface of Wn+1Cn to the nucleophilic O surface of Wn+1CnO2, which is beneficial for the activation of the Li-O bond, and thus promotes the Li+ deintercalation during the charge&#8211;discharge process. On both Wn+1Cn and Wn+1CnO2, the rate-determining step (RDS) of ORR is the formation of the (Li2O)2* product, while the RDS of OER is the LiO2* decomposition. The overpotentials of ORR and OER are positively linearly correlated with the adsorption energy of the RDS LixO2* intermediates. By lowering the energy band center, the oxygen functionalization and increasing atomic layers can effectively reduce the adsorption strength of the LixO2* intermediates, thereby reducing the ORR and OER overpotentials. The W4C3O2 MXene shows immense potential as a cathode catalyst for Li-O2 batteries due to its outstanding conductivity and super-low ORR, OER, and total overpotentials (0.25, 0.38, and 0.63 V).</description>
      <author>Liangliang Zhu, J. Wang, Jie Liu, R. H. Wang, Ming Chang Lin, Tao Wang, Yuchao Zhen, Jing Xu, Lianming Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14080666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Spectroscopic Monitoring of Metal Chalcogenides for Overall Water Splitting: New Views of Active Species and Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202400048</link>
      <description>Yonggui Zhao, Wenchao Wan, Rolf Erni, Long Pan, Greta R. Patzke, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394570456

                Metal&#8208;based chalcogenides exhibit great promise for overall water splitting, yet their intrinsic catalytic reaction mechanisms remain to be fully understood. In this work, we employed operando X&#8208;ray absorption (XAS) and in situ Raman spectroscopy to elucidate the structure&#8208;activity relationships of low&#8208;crystalline cobalt sulfide (L&#8208;CoS) catalysts toward overall water splitting. The operando results for L&#8208;CoS catalyzing the alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) demonstrate that the cobalt centers in the bulk are predominantly coordinated by sulfur atoms, which undergo a kinetic structural rearrangement to generate metallic cobalt in S&#8208;Co&#8208;Co&#8208;S moieties as the true catalytic active species. In comparison, during the acidic HER, L&#8208;CoS undergoes local structural optimization of Co centers, and H2 production proceeds with adsorption/desorption of key intermediates atop the Co&#8208;S&#8208;Co configurations. Further operando characterizations highlight the crucial formation of high&#8208;valent Co4+ species in L&#8208;CoS for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and the formation of such active species was found to be far more facile than in crystalline Co3O4 and Co&#8208;LDH references. These insights offer a clear picture of the complexity of active species and site formation in different media, and demonstrate how their restructuring influences the catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Yonggui Zhao, Wenchao Wan, Rolf Erni, Long Pan, Greta R. Patzke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202400048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics of anion exchange membrane electrolysis: Unravelling loss mechanisms with electrochemical impedance spectroscopy, reference electrodes and distribution of relaxation times</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234455</link>
      <description>Matthias Ranz, Bianca Grabner, Bernhard Schweighofer, Hannes Wegleiter, Alexander Trattner, Journal of power sources. 605(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394734132

                In recent years, alkaline exchange membrane water electrolysis (AEM-WE) has attracted a lot of attention for its potential cost reduction compared to traditional electrolysis systems. Despite this promise, challenges related to efficiency and stability must be effectively addressed to fully realise the potential of AEM-WE. This paper presents a comprehensive investigation of an AEM-WE single-cell including electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) in conjunction with the equivalent circuit model (ECM). For the first time distribution of relaxation times (DRT) analysis is performed on an AEM-WE cell, employing a reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) as a reference electrode. Half-cell EIS measurements and subsequent DRT spectra are presented, clearly indicating anodic and cathodic half-cell reactions. The DRT analysis reveals five distinct loss mechanisms in the AEM-WE system. These include the hydrogen evolution reaction, the oxygen evolution reaction, and ionic transport losses occurring within the catalyst layers. Through a systematic variation of the operating parameters we successfully allocate DRT peaks to their respective physicochemical origins. The findings contribute valuable insights into the electrochemical processes within the AEM-WE single-cell, offering a better understanding of the underlying mechanisms and facilitating the target-oriented development of enhanced membrane electrode assemblies.</description>
      <author>Matthias Ranz, Bianca Grabner, Bernhard Schweighofer, Hannes Wegleiter, Alexander Trattner</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234455</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fe2O3 facilitating deeper transformation of Ni-MOF into active NiOOH for enhanced OER performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solidstatesciences.2024.107535</link>
      <description>T. Zhang, Hongjuan Xu, Ziyang Tang, Hui&#8722;Hui Cui, Jin Wang, Miao Wang, Zhao-Qian Li, Solid state sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394753191

                Due to the large specific surface area and the highly-exposed active metal centers, nickel metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) have recently emerged as one of the excellent functional materials for oxygen evolution reactions (OER). Herein, we have construct uniformly distributed Fe2O3 particles within Ni-MOF nanosheets (Ni-MOF NSs) for enhanced OER performance. This electrocatalyst, prepared by a facile hydrothermal method, provides highly active Fe2O3 particles while preserving the framework structure of Ni-MOF for effective substrates diffusion. The optimal Fe2O3 doped Ni-MOF NSs deliver high stability in alkaline and exhibit striking OER performance with an overpotential of 232 mV at 10 mA cm-2 and a Tafel slope of 49.3 mV dec-1, outperforming the pristine Ni-MOF and most reported non-noble metal based electrocatalysts. The enhance catalytic activity of Fe2O3 doped Ni-MOF NSs is likely due to the introduction of Fe2O3 particles to facilitate the deeper transformation of Ni-MOF into active NiOOH species.</description>
      <author>T. Zhang, Hongjuan Xu, Ziyang Tang, Hui&#8722;Hui Cui, Jin Wang, Miao Wang, Zhao-Qian Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.solidstatesciences.2024.107535</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Operando Spectroscopic Monitoring of Metal Chalcogenides for Overall Water Splitting: New Views of Active Species and Sites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202400048</link>
      <description>Yonggui Zhao, Wenchao Wan, Rolf Erni, Long Pan, Greta R. Patzke, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394578342

                Metal-based chalcogenides exhibit great promise for overall water splitting, yet their intrinsic catalytic reaction mechanisms remain to be fully understood. In this work, we employed operando X-ray absorption (XAS) and in situ Raman spectroscopy to elucidate the structure-activity relationships of low-crystalline cobalt sulfide (L-CoS) catalysts toward overall water splitting. The operando results for L-CoS catalyzing the alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) demonstrate that the cobalt centers in the bulk are predominantly coordinated by sulfur atoms, which undergo a kinetic structural rearrangement to generate metallic cobalt in S-Co-Co-S moieties as the true catalytic active species. In comparison, during the acidic HER, L-CoS undergoes local structural optimization of Co centers, and H2 production proceeds with adsorption/desorption of key intermediates atop the Co-S-Co configurations. Further operando characterizations highlight the crucial formation of high-valent Co4+ species in L-CoS for the alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and the formation of such active species was found to be far more facile than in crystalline Co3O4 and Co-LDH references. These insights offer a clear picture of the complexity of active species and site formation in different media, and demonstrate how their restructuring influences the catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Yonggui Zhao, Wenchao Wan, Rolf Erni, Long Pan, Greta R. Patzke</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202400048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Theoretical designs of &lt;scp&gt;ORR&lt;/scp&gt;/&lt;scp&gt;OER&lt;/scp&gt; single&#8208;atom catalysts &lt;scp&gt;TM&lt;/scp&gt;@&lt;scp&gt;Ti&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;CT&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; (T = O, S, Cl)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.27374</link>
      <description>Pengcheng Shen, J. Li, Zheng Zhang, Hui Liu, Limin Liang, Cong Chen, Y Li, International journal of quantum chemistry. 124(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394756241

                Abstract Driven by the goal of establishing a fossil&#8208;fuel&#8208;free and nuclear&#8208;power&#8208;free economy based on renewable energy, metal&#8208;air batteries are regarded as promising energy conversion and storage devices. Developing efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR)/oxygen evolution reaction (OER) bifunctional electrocatalysts for the air electrode of metal&#8208;air batteries is becoming increasingly important. In this work, 36 transition metal (TM) single&#8208;atom catalysts are designed based on MXenes Ti 2 CT 2 with different surface terminal atoms (T = O, S, Cl), and their ORR/OER catalytic activity and stability are evaluated by the density functional theory. Ni@Ti 2 CO 2 , Pd@Ti 2 CS 2 , and Co@Ti 2 CCl 2 are found to exhibit good catalytic activity with ORR/OER overpotentials of .54 V/.62 V, .59 V/.29 V, .44 V/.40 V. The aggregation behavior of three catalysts is estimated by comparing the average binding energy of one, two, three, and four TM atoms anchored on Ti 2 CT 2 . This work cannot only provide a theoretical guide to develop bifunctional single&#8208;atom catalysts, but also help us understand the effect of terminal atoms on the electronic structures and catalytic activity of TM@Ti 2 CT 2 .</description>
      <author>Pengcheng Shen, J. Li, Zheng Zhang, Hui Liu, Limin Liang, Cong Chen, Y Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/qua.27374</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preparation of V doped Co2N/CoN and its superior HER and OER performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.124701</link>
      <description>Yuming Lu, Weilin Weng, Yunhu Lu, Xiao Pang, Heli Ni, Banghua Peng, Journal of solid state chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394726581

                Hydrogen is increasingly recognized as a critical energy source for the future. Transition metal nitrides hydrogen catalysts have found to narrow the d-band contraction effectively and alter the filling state of the metal, thereby modulating the metal-hydrogen bonding energy and enhancing both electrical conductivity and catalytic activity. In this study, V-doped cobalt nitrides (V&#8211;Co2N/CoN) with two distinct crystalline structures were successfully synthesized through the nitriding of V-doped cobalt bicarbonate (V&#8211;CoCH) as a precursor. The morphology and structure of the resulting materials were carefully optimized by adjusting the V doping amount and nitriding temperature. For hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), the final product V&#8211;Co2N/CoN-1-400 only needs 47 mV and 230 mV overpotential to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and works at 1.69 V to drive the overall water splitting for 10 mA cm&#8722;2, showing good stability performance without fluctuation for about 10 h. This work implies that V-doped cobalt nitrides can lead to enhanced water splitting catalytic activity. Our findings may illustrate the significance of V doping for improving electrocatalytic performance, and demonstrate the potential of CoV bimetallic nitrides as effective electrocatalysts, offering valuable insights for the further development of non-precious metal nitride-based catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yuming Lu, Weilin Weng, Yunhu Lu, Xiao Pang, Heli Ni, Banghua Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jssc.2024.124701</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Polymetal&#8208;Chelated Fabrication of Bimetallic Nanophosphides as Electrocatalysts for Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202301645</link>
      <description>Xuan&#8208;Wen Gao, Jianjia Mu, Ran Wei, Xue Wang, Qinfen Gu, Lukang Zhao, Wen Luo, Small methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394746981

                Abstract Bimetallic phosphides are considered as promising electrocatalysts for zinc&#8211;air batteries toward oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). To address the semi&#8208;conductor inherent low electronic conductivity and catalytic activity, a polymetal&#8208;chelated strategy is employed to in situ fabricate bimetallic nanophosphides within carbon matrix anchoring by chemical bonding. The employment of biomolecule polydopamine (PDA) efficiently anchors various transition metal ions due to its strong chelating capability via inherent functional groups. Furthermore, the chelation of multi&#8208;metal ion is proved to promote the formation of graphitic nitrogen. The bimetallic Fe x Co y P phosphides nanoparticles are intimately encapsulated in carbon matrix through in situ carbonization and phosphatization processes. When utilized in Zinc&#8211;air batteries, Fe 0.20 Co 0.80 P anchored within N, P co&#8208;doped sub&#8208;microsphere (Fe 0.20 Co 0.80 P /PNC) exhibit a maximum power density of 167 mW cm &#8722;2 and cycle life up to 270 cycles, with a round&#8208;trip voltage of 0.955 V. The mechanisms for catalytic activity passivation are ascribed to the etching of nitrogen and oxidation of phosphorus in carbon matrix, as well as the oxidation of the surface phosphide on the sub&#8208;microspheres. This study presents a promising candidate for advancing the further development of energy conversation catalysis.</description>
      <author>Xuan&#8208;Wen Gao, Jianjia Mu, Ran Wei, Xue Wang, Qinfen Gu, Lukang Zhao, Wen Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202301645</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring multi-segment electrolyte design strategies for portable high-energy aqueous batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.111658</link>
      <description>Kaiqiang Zhang, Chao Ma, Zhulin Yuan, Peter C. Kong, Jilei Ye, Yuping Wu, Journal of energy storage. 88(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394779390

                The limited energy density resulting from the suppressed operating voltage of aqueous batteries presents a significant challenge when it comes to practical applications. To address this issue, various strategies have been proposed to expand the electrochemical potential window of aqueous electrolytes, with a primary focus on inhibiting the hydrogen and oxygen evolution. It is crucial to note that these reactions are closely linked to the pH values. Consequently, adopting a pH design that decouples the acidity of anolyte and basicity of catholyte proves to be advantageous in overcoming the thermodynamic limitations associated with water decomposition and achieving a wider electrochemical stability window. Fortunately, this approach of bipolarized pH values optimizes the redox potentials at anode and cathode, resulting in a lower anodic potential and a higher cathodic potential. This optimization leads to an increase in battery's working voltage. Embracing this concept holds great promises for developing portable high-energy aqueous batteries, thus facilitating their practical applications. In this review, we delve into the research surrounding this innovative electrolyte engineering technology. We aim to provide a clear definition, highlight its efficacy, addressing any remaining challenges, propose potential solutions, and present a roadmap for the portable implementation of multi-segment electrolyte technology.</description>
      <author>Kaiqiang Zhang, Chao Ma, Zhulin Yuan, Peter C. Kong, Jilei Ye, Yuping Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.111658</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering the Role of Nickel in Electrochemical Organic Oxidation Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400696</link>
      <description>Suptish Ghosh, Debabrata Bagchi, Indranil Mondal, Tobias Sontheimer, Rajenahally V. Jagadeesh, Prashanth W. Menezes, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394570714

                Abstract Organic oxidation reactions (OORs) powered by renewable energy sources are gaining importance as a favorable alternative to oxygen evolution reaction, with the promise of reducing the cell potential and enhancing the overall viability of the water electrolysis. This comprehensive review delves into the electrochemical oxidation of diverse organic compounds, including alcohols, aldehydes, amines, and urea, as well as biomass&#8208;derived renewable feedstocks such as hydroxymethylfurfural and glycerol. The key focus centers on the role of nickel (Ni)&#8208;based catalysts for these OORs. The unique redox activity and chemical nature of Ni have been proven instrumental for the sustainable and cost&#8208;effective oxidation of various organic molecules more efficiently and selectively. This review article discusses how strategic choices, such as the selection of foreign metals, intercalating species, vacancies, defects, and a secondary element (e.g. chalcogens and non&#8208;metals), contribute to tuning the electrochemical performances of a Ni&#8208;based (pre)catalyst for OORs. Moreover, this review provides insights into the active species in various reaction environments and further explores reaction mechanisms, to apparent phase changes of the catalyst with the most relevant examples. Finally, the review not only elucidates the limitations of the current approaches but also outlines potential avenues for future advancements in OOR.</description>
      <author>Suptish Ghosh, Debabrata Bagchi, Indranil Mondal, Tobias Sontheimer, Rajenahally V. Jagadeesh, Prashanth W. Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400696</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-Catalyzed Growth of Co&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;N and N-Doped Carbon Nanotubes toward Bifunctional Cathode for Highly Safe and Flexible Li&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01271</link>
      <description>Jun Xia, Shuai Yin, Kai Cui, Tian Yang, Yong-Bin Yan, Shichao Zhang, Yalan Xing, Ping Yang, Tianshuai Wang, Guangmin Zhou, ACS nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394752700

                The practical application of high-energy density lithium&#8211;oxygen (Li&#8211;O2) batteries is severely impeded by the notorious cycling stability and safety, which mainly comes from slow kinetics of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at cathodes, causing inferior redox overpotentials and reactive lithium metal in flammable liquid electrolyte. Herein, a bifunctional electrode, a safe gel polymer electrolyte (GPE), and a robust lithium anode are proposed to alleviate above problems. The bifunctional electrode is composed of N-doped carbon nanotubes (N-CNTs) and Co4N by in situ chemical vapor deposition self-catalyzed growth on carbon cloth (N-CNTs@Co4N@CC). The self-supporting, binder-free N-CNTs@Co4N@CC electrode has a strong and stable three-dimensional (3D) interconnected conductive structure, which provides interconnectivity between the active sites and the electrode to promote the transfer of electrons. Furthermore, the N-CNT-intertwined Co4N ensures efficient catalytic activity. Hence, the electrode demonstrates improved electrochemical properties even under a large current density (2000 mA g&#8211;1) and long cycling operation (250 cycles). Moreover, a highly safe and flexible rechargeable cell using the 3D N-CNTs@Co4N@CC electrode, GPE, and robust lithium anode design has been explored. The open circuit voltage is stable at &#8764;3.0 V even after 9800 cycles, which proves the mechanical durability of the integrated GPE cell. The stable cable-type Li&#8211;air battery was demonstrated to stably drive the light-emitting diodes (LEDs), highlighting the reliability for practical use.</description>
      <author>Jun Xia, Shuai Yin, Kai Cui, Tian Yang, Yong-Bin Yan, Shichao Zhang, Yalan Xing, Ping Yang, Tianshuai Wang, Guangmin Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsnano.4c01271</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum-Modified Cobalt Oxide/Cobalt Nanotubes as Multifunctional Electrocatalysts in Alkaline and Acidic Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c06119</link>
      <description>Julia Mayes, Gesilda Noka, I. G. Dillon, Daniel Ma, Kathryn Kingsbury, Gurpreet Singh, Lukasz Sztaberek, Scott C. McGuire, Stanislaus S. Wong, Christopher Koenigsmann, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394622066

                Nanostructure platinum is an effective catalyst that is active toward a broad range of electrochemical processes over a wide range of pH values. However, its high cost and low abundance prevent its widespread use in practical devices. A promising strategy to overcome the limitations of platinum is to combine platinum with less expensive and more abundant transition metals. In this report, we employ an ambient, template-based approach to prepare monodisperse Co nanotubes (NTs) and modify them with platinum via an electroless deposition process. The composition of the resulting Pt modified Co NTs (Pt-Co NTs) can be varied by controlling the Pt ion concentration in the electroless deposition step. The resulting Pt-Co NTs have a hierarchical structure consisting of Pt-Co NTs coated with an amorphous Co-oxide film. The amorphous Co-oxide coating activates the Pt-Co NTs to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) leading to a 9-fold enhancement in the OER activity in an 80% (by mass) Pt-Co NT relative to pure Pt nanowires. The surface oxide coating can be selectively removed by cycling the Pt-Co NTs in an acidic solution. Removing the oxide film activates the Pt-Co NTs toward methanol oxidation (MOR) and oxygen reduction (ORR) reactions. In both cases, the trends in MOR and ORR activity follow a volcano-type dependence as a function of composition. The catalyst with the optimum composition of 60% Pt has a 4-fold increase in the specific activity for MOR and maintains a +20 mV shift in the half-wave potential for ORR relative to that of pure Pt nanowires.</description>
      <author>Julia Mayes, Gesilda Noka, I. G. Dillon, Daniel Ma, Kathryn Kingsbury, Gurpreet Singh, Lukasz Sztaberek, Scott C. McGuire, Stanislaus S. Wong, Christopher Koenigsmann</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c06119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Efficiency Iridium&#8208;Yttrium Alloy Catalyst for Acidic Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304479</link>
      <description>Xiang Xiong, Jialin Tang, Jian Yuan, Weiqing Xue, Haoyuan Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Hongliang Zeng, Yizhou Dai, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Xinyan Li, Qiu Jiang, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394572023

                Abstract Proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis holds great promise in revolutionizing clean energy production by enabling the efficient generation of hydrogen. Nevertheless, a formidable challenge persists in the realm of designing electrocatalysts that are both highly active and acid&#8208;resistant during the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), thereby mitigating the substantial kinetic barrier. In this study, the facile synthesis of iridium&#8208;yttrium (IrY) alloy nanocatalysts via a thermal shock method is introduced, which exhibits exceptional activity in the context of acidic water oxidation. Through the strategic incorporation of dispersed Y into the lattice of Ir metal, the IrY catalyst demonstrates a notably low overpotential of 255 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and showcases remarkable catalytic stability in acidic electrolytes, enduring for over 500 h with a high current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 . Through a comprehensive set of in situ characterizations and analytical methods, the formation of a surface Ir&#8208;based oxide layer, induced by deprotonation and electrochemical oxidation is unveiled, which is notably stabilized by the presence of Y dopants. This stabilization of the active site imparts enhanced resistance to over&#8208;oxidation and dissolution, underpinning the exceptional stability of the catalyst. Theoretical calculations suggest that the incorporation of Y into the catalyst structure has a significant impact on enhancing the reactivity of the oxygen intermediate (O*) at adjacent Ir sites, thus lowering the overpotential and promoting OER activity. The alloying approach presents a straightforward method for achieving atomic&#8208;level modifications in catalyst design and can pave the way for the development of more effective and economically viable OER catalysts and beyond.</description>
      <author>Xiang Xiong, Jialin Tang, Jian Yuan, Weiqing Xue, Haoyuan Wang, Chunxiao Liu, Hongliang Zeng, Yizhou Dai, Hong&#8208;Jie Peng, Tingting Zheng, Chuan Xia, Xinyan Li, Qiu Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202304479</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of 2D/2D BCNS/Ti3C2 heterojunction with boron-doped g-C3N4 and Ti3C2 MXene for enhanced photocatalytic water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114719</link>
      <description>Aiqin Wang, Fang Chen, Mengdie Cai, Jingshuai Chen, Yong Jiang, Qin Cheng, Zhimin Song, Jiaqi Bai, Yuxue Wei, Song Sun, Catalysis today. 435(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394775428

                Graphitic carbon nitride (g-C3N4) has attracted great interest in photocatalytic water splitting. However, the poor photogenerated charge carriers transfer and the insufficient driving force for oxygen evolution reaction limit its practical application. In this work, boron-doped g-C3N4 nanosheets (BCNS) have been synthesized by calcining a mixture of g-C3N4 and NaBH4. The synthesized BCNS were then combined with Ti3C2 MXene using electrostatic self-assembly to construct a 2D/2D BCNS/Ti3C2 heterojunction. The resultant BCNS retained the original framework of g-C3N4, while the optimized band structure of BCNS induced prominently enhanced visible light absorption, accelerated charge carriers separation, and the increased driving force for water oxidation compared to pure g-C3N4. Density functional theory further proved that BCNS can enhance the driving force for photocatalytic O2 evolution. Moreover, the construction of 2D/2D face-to-face BCNS/Ti3C2 heterojunction was carried out to further enhance photocatalytic performance due to the intimate contact interface and the accelerated separation and transfer of photogenerated charge carriers. As a result, the 2D/2D BCNS/Ti3C2 hetrojunction exhibited a dramatically improved photocatalytic water-splitting performance compared to pristine g-C3N4. This integrated engineering strategy, involving non-metal element doping and 2D/2D heterojunction construction, might provide a unique paradigm for the rational design of efficient photocatalysts for photocatalytic water splitting.</description>
      <author>Aiqin Wang, Fang Chen, Mengdie Cai, Jingshuai Chen, Yong Jiang, Qin Cheng, Zhimin Song, Jiaqi Bai, Yuxue Wei, Song Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cattod.2024.114719</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Cross&#8208;Alignments of 2D Semiconductors with Steered Internal Electric Field for Urea Electrooxidation via Balancing Intermediates Adsorption</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401053</link>
      <description>Haiying Du, Huashuai Hu, Xunlu Wang, Nian Ran, Wei Chen, Hai&#8208;Liang Zhu, Yin Zhou, Minghui Yang, Yuandong Wang, Jianjun Li, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394683163

                Single-component electrocatalysts generally lead to unbalanced adsorption of OH- and urea during urea oxidation reaction (UOR), thus obtaining low activity and selectivity especially when oxygen evolution reaction (OER) competes at high potentials (&gt;1.5 V). Herein, a cross-alignment strategy of in situ vertically growing Ni(OH)2 nanosheets on 2D semiconductor g-C3N4 is reported to form a hetero-structured electrocatalyst. Various spectroscopy measurements including in situ experiments indicate the existence of enhanced internal electric field at the interfaces of vertical Ni(OH)2 and g-C3N4 nanosheets, favorable for balancing adsorption of reaction intermediates. This heterojunction electrocatalyst shows high-selectivity UOR compared to pure Ni(OH)2, even at high potentials (&gt;1.5 V) and large current density. The computational results show the vertical heterojunction could steer the internal electric field to increase the adsorption of urea, thus efficiently avoiding poisoning of strongly adsorbed OH- on active sites. A membrane electrode assembly (MEA)-based electrolyzer with the heterojunction anode could operate at an industrial-level current density of 200 mA cm-2. This work paves an avenue for designing high-performance electrocatalysts by vertical cross-alignments of active components.</description>
      <author>Haiying Du, Huashuai Hu, Xunlu Wang, Nian Ran, Wei Chen, Hai&#8208;Liang Zhu, Yin Zhou, Minghui Yang, Yuandong Wang, Jianjun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous enhancement of charge transfer and surface catalysis through a polymetallic oxide cocatalyst on BiVO4 photoanodes for highly efficient and stable water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151220</link>
      <description>Yiming Zhou, Hongxing Li, Ping Guo, Yu Zhang, Peng Zhou, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394725983

                The rate-determining oxygen evolution reaction (OER) always limits the high-efficient conversion of solar energy to green hydrogen fuels through photoelectrocatalytic or photocatalytic water splitting. The high catalytic overpotential and the instability of catalytic center are commonly regarded as the primary factors contributing to the low rate of OER, remaining to be a challenge in the field of water splitting. Herein, a polymetallic oxide cocatalyst (Mo-MnOy/FeCoNiOx) with well-defined electronic and catalytic properties is designed on BiVO4 photoelectrode for highly efficient and stable photoelectrocatalytic water oxidation. The experimental characterization demonstrates that the dual-layer design of Mo-MnOy/FeCoNiOx can significantly optimizes the electronic property of MnOy and FeCoNiOx components, boosting the photogenerated charge transfer between Mo-MnOy/FeCoNiOx cocatalyst and BiVO4 photoelectrode. The density functional theory (DFT) simulation reveals that the Mo sites in Mo-MnOy layer can activate the neighboring surface Mn sites instead of directly serving as the catalytic center, thereby establishing these Mn sites as primary active centers for achieving stable OER. The developed Mo-MnOy/FeCoNiOx/BiVO4 photoelectrode exhibits a current density of 6.18 mA cm&#8722;2 with an excellent stability for 30 h at 1.23 VRHE under 1 sun irradiation, exhibiting the excellent activity and durability. This work sheds light on design of high-performance multiple-component water-oxidation cocatalyst on photoanode.</description>
      <author>Yiming Zhou, Hongxing Li, Ping Guo, Yu Zhang, Peng Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151220</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Electrochemical Rapid Induction of Highly Active &#947;&#8208;NiOOH Species for Industrial Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310064</link>
      <description>Fuli Wang, Jin&#8208;Long Tan, Zhaoxia Jin, C.D. Gu, Qian&#8208;Xi Lv, Yue Dong, Ren&#8208;Qing Lv, Bin Dong, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394750481

                Abstract Limited by the strong oxidation environment and sluggish reconstruction process in oxygen evolution reaction (OER), designing rapid self&#8208;reconstruction with high activity and stability electrocatalysts is crucial to promoting anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolyzer. Herein, trace Fe/S&#8208;modified Ni oxyhydroxide (Fe/S&#8208;NiOOH/NF) nanowires are constructed via a simple in situ electrochemical oxidation strategy based on precipitation&#8208;dissolution equilibrium. In situ characterization techniques reveal that the successful introduction of Fe and S leads to lattice disorder and boosts favorable hydroxyl capture, accelerating the formation of highly active &#947;&#8208;NiOOH. The Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations have also verified that the incorporation of Fe and S optimizes the electrons redistribution and the d&#8208;band center, decreasing the energy barrier of the rate&#8208;determining step ( * O&#8594; * OOH). Benefited from the unique electronic structure and intermediate adsorption, the Fe/S&#8208;NiOOH/NF catalyst only requires the overpotential of 345 mV to reach the industrial current density of 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 for 120 h. Meanwhile, assembled AEM water electrolyzer (Fe/S&#8208;NiOOH//Pt/C&#8208;60 &#176;C) can deliver 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 at a cell voltage of 2.24 V, operating at the average energy efficiency of 71% for 100 h. In summary, this work presents a rapid self&#8208;reconstruction strategy for high&#8208;performance AEM electrocatalysts for future hydrogen economy.</description>
      <author>Fuli Wang, Jin&#8208;Long Tan, Zhaoxia Jin, C.D. Gu, Qian&#8208;Xi Lv, Yue Dong, Ren&#8208;Qing Lv, Bin Dong, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310064</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stable Operation of Paired CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Reduction/Glycerol Oxidation at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05952</link>
      <description>Attila Korm&#225;nyos, Adrienn Szirmai, Bal&#225;zs Endr&#337;di, Csaba Jan&#225;ky, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394786891

                Despite the considerable efforts made by the community, the high operation cell voltage of CO2 electrolyzers is still to be decreased to move toward commercialization. This is mostly due to the high energy need of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which is the most often used anodic pair for CO2 reduction. In this study, OER was replaced by the electrocatalytic oxidation of glycerol using carbon-supported Pt nanoparticles as an anode catalyst. In parallel, the reduction of CO2 to CO was performed at the Ag cathode catalyst using a membraneless microfluidic flow electrolyzer cell. Several parameters were optimized, starting from the catalyst layer composition (ionomer quality and quantity), through operating conditions (glycerol concentration, applied electrolyte flow rate, etc.), to the applied electrochemical protocol. By identifying the optimal conditions, a 75&#8211;85% Faradaic efficiency (FE) toward glycerol oxidation products (oxalate, glycerate, tartronate, lactate, glycolate, and formate) was achieved at 200 mA cm&#8211;2 total current density while the cathodic CO formation proceeded with close to 100% FE. With static protocols (potentio- or galvanostatic), a rapid loss of glycerol oxidation activity was observed during the long-term measurements. The anode catalyst was reactivated by applying a dynamic potential step protocol. This allowed the periodic reduction, hence, refreshing of Pt, ensuring stable, continuous operation for 5 h.</description>
      <author>Attila Korm&#225;nyos, Adrienn Szirmai, Bal&#225;zs Endr&#337;di, Csaba Jan&#225;ky</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05952</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycerol Electrolyzer with Graphite Anode and Cathode Produces Carbonyl Compounds and Hydrogen: Background Electrocatalysis of a &#8220;Nonparticipating&#8221; Current Collector</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00917</link>
      <description>Nicolly C. Yonamine, Cinthia R. Zanata, Mois&#233;s Barbosa de Souza, Pablo S. Fern&#225;ndez, Heberton Wender, Cau&#234; A. Martins, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394564368

                This study unveils a novel role of bare graphite as a catalyst in glycerol electrooxidation and hydrogen evolution reactions, challenging the prevailing notion that current collectors employed in electrolyzers are inert. Half-cell experiments elucidate the feasibility of glycerol oxidation and hydrogen production on bulk graphite electrodes at potentials exceeding 1.7 V. The investigation of varying glycerol concentrations (0.05 to 1.5 mol L-1) highlights a concentration-dependent competition between glycerol electrooxidation and oxygen evolution reactions. Employing an H-type glycerol electrolyzer, polarization curves reveal significant activation polarization attributed to the low electroactivity of the anode. Glycerol electrolysis at different concentrations yields diverse product mixtures, including formate, glycolate, glycerate, and lactate at the anode, with concurrent hydrogen generation at the cathode. The anolyte composition changes with glycerol concentration, resulting in less-oxidized compounds at higher concentrations and more oxidized compounds at lower concentrations. The cell voltage also influences the product formation selectivity, with an increased voltage favoring more oxidized compounds. The glycerol concentration also affects hydrogen production, with lower concentrations yielding higher hydrogen amounts, peaking at 3.5 V for 0.05 mol L-1. This model quantitatively illustrates graphite's contribution to current and product generation in glycerol electrolyzers, emphasizing the significance of background current and products originating from current collectors if in contact with the reactants. These results have an impact on the efficiency of the electrolyzer and raise questions regarding possible extra non-noble "nonparticipating" current collectors that could affect overall performance. This research expands our understanding of electrocatalysis on graphite surfaces with potential applications in optimizing electrolyzer configurations for enhanced efficiency and product selectivity.</description>
      <author>Nicolly C. Yonamine, Cinthia R. Zanata, Mois&#233;s Barbosa de Souza, Pablo S. Fern&#225;ndez, Heberton Wender, Cau&#234; A. Martins</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00917</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Phthalocyanine Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework as an Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00037</link>
      <description>Giddaerappa Kuntoji, Naseem Kousar, Uday Deshpande, Lokesh Koodlur Sannegowda, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394724958

                Water is the most convenient and facile fossil-free source for the production of hydrogen (H2). Electrochemical water splitting is considered a promising and potential approach for accomplishing hydrogen frugality. Although water-splitting reaction is the most versatile and green technique, it accounts for only 4% of the universal H2 production. The main hindrance in large-scale production is the sluggish kinetics of the reaction, which employs costlier and precious catalysts. In addition, the half-cell reactions for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in water splitting require two different types of precious catalysts, which not only increases the cost but also decreases the efficiency due to the enhanced complexity of the system. Hence, designing an efficient, robust, nonprecious, earth-abundant, and low-cost electrocatalyst capable of catalyzing both HER and OER during overall water splitting is an urgent requirement to meet the energy demand for sustainable growth. Here, a highly potential bifunctional electrocatalyst is fabricated using quinone-substituted cobalt(II) phthalocyanine (HQCoPc) with carbon nanoparticles (Ketjen black, KB). The organic hybrid of HQCoPc + KB modified on GCE and Ni foam showed remarkable electrocatalytic performance for HER and OER in acidic and basic conditions, respectively. The HQCoPc + KB composite affords a lower onset of 76 mV for HER and an overpotential of 234 and 360 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8211;2 for HER and OER, respectively, with superior stability for more than 40,000 s. The designed HQCoPc + KB bifunctional electrocatalyst not only offers a better catalyst for addressing a water-splitting reaction but also provides cost-effectiveness and good chemical stability for sustainable energy technology.</description>
      <author>Giddaerappa Kuntoji, Naseem Kousar, Uday Deshpande, Lokesh Koodlur Sannegowda</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00037</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Energy-efficient and advanced electrowinning of metallic manganese within a novel H exchange membrane cell using a Ti/IrO &#8722; RuO &#8722; SiO anode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127489</link>
      <description>Kexuan Lyu, Chengyan Wang, Yongqiang Chen, Chengyan Wang, Separation and purification technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394770667

                Coated Titanium Anodes (CTAs) exhibit significant potential in addressing the high energy consumption challenge inherent in current manganese electrowinning processes. However, the electrodeposition of manganese dioxide (MnO2) at the anode limits the utilization of CTAs in conventional manganese electrolytic cells. Herein, a novel H+ exchange membrane (HEM) electrolytic cell was proposed and applied to manganese electrowinning employing Ti/IrO2 &#8722; RuO2 &#8722; SiO2 anode. The HEM electrolytic cell is a three-chamber electrolytic reactor consisting of cathode chamber, acidification chamber and anode chamber separated by woven terylene diaphragm and HEM. The results indicated that after 24 h of electrowinning, the cathodic current efficiency (CE) of 85.1 % was achieved, along with a specific energy consumption (EC) of 4189 kW&#183;h/t. Compared to conventional industrial electrowinning technology, this represents an increase in CE by more than 15 % and a reduction in EC by over 1400 kW&#183;h/t. The unique structure of the HEM electrolytic cell effectively prevents MnO2 deposition, ensuring the functionality of the CTAs and eliminating the generation of anode mud. Additionally, the H+ from the oxygen evolution reaction at the anode is collected and concentrated in the acidification chamber. This resulted in a spent electrolyte with 15.2 g/L H2SO4, enabling its reuse in extracting manganese ores. Employing the HEM electrolytic cell with a Ti/IrO2 &#8722; RuO2 &#8722; SiO2 anode for manganese electrowinning is therefore considered an energy-efficient and clean approach. It is highly recommended for saving energy and reducing carbon emissions in industrial processes.</description>
      <author>Kexuan Lyu, Chengyan Wang, Yongqiang Chen, Chengyan Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.seppur.2024.127489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-step constructing advanced N-doped carbon@metal nitride as ultra-stable electrocatalysts via urea plasma under room temperature</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109887</link>
      <description>Tao Tang, Chen Li, Sipu Li, Zhong Qiu, Tianqi Yang, Beirong Ye, San-Qiang Shi, Chunyang Wu, Feng Cao, Xinhui Xia, Minghua Chen, Xinqi Liang, Xinping He, Xin Liu, Yongqi Zhang, Chinese Chemical Letters/Chinese chemical letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394787344

                Highly active transition metal nitrides are desirable for electrocatalytic reactions, but their long-term stability is still unsatisfactory and thus limiting commercial applications. Herein, for the first time, we report a unique and universal room-temperature urea plasma method for controllable synthesis of N-doped carbon coated metal (Fe, Co, Ni, etc.) nitrides arrays electrocatalysts. The preformed metal oxides arrays can be successfully converted into metal nitrides arrays with preserved nanostructures and a thin layer of N-doped carbon (N-C) via one-step urea plasma. Typically, as a representative case, N-C@CoN nanowire arrays are illustrated and corresponding formation mechanism by plasma is proposed. Notably, the designed N-C@CoN catalysts deliver excellent electrocatalytic activity and long-term stability both in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and urea oxidation reaction (UOR). For OER, a low overpotential (264 mV at 10 mA/cm2) and high stability (&gt;50 h at 20 mA/cm2) are acquired. For UOR, a current density of 100 mA/cm2 is achieved at only 1.39 V and maintain over 100 h. Theoretical calculations reveal that the synergetic coupling effect of CoN and N-C can significantly facilitate the charge-transfer process, optimize adsorbed intermediates binding strength and further greatly decrease the energy barrier. This strategy provides a novel method for fabrication of N-C@ metal nitrides as highly active and stable catalysts.</description>
      <author>Tao Tang, Chen Li, Sipu Li, Zhong Qiu, Tianqi Yang, Beirong Ye, San-Qiang Shi, Chunyang Wu, Feng Cao, Xinhui Xia, Minghua Chen, Xinqi Liang, Xinping He, Xin Liu, Yongqi Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cclet.2024.109887</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface effect of Fe doped NiSe/Ni3Se2 heterojunction as highly efficient electrocatalysts for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150996</link>
      <description>Ruxin Deng, Huiqin Yao, Yixuan Wang, Chaonan Wang, Siqi Zhang, Shaoshi Guo, Yongliang Li, Shulan Ma, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394585191

                It matters to design and explore transition metal bifunctional electrocatalysts which can efficiently catalyze overall water splitting. Herein, we report a series of Fe doped NiSe/Ni3Se2 (NiSe/Ni3Se2-Fe-X@t, X is Fe dosage, and t is electrodeposition time) heterojunctions assembled on nickel foam (NF) by one-step electrodeposition. Under alkaline medium (1.0 M KOH), the optimized NiSe/Ni3Se2-Fe-5@5min catalyst shows ultra-low overpotentials of 144 and 200 mV respectively for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) to afford the current density of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2, and a small cell voltage of 1.57 V at 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 is needed for overall water splitting with extraordinary high stability (&#8805;120 h). Density functional theory (DFT) calculations demonstrate the heterojunction keeps metallic state, and Fe3+ doping reduces electron density of Ni2+, effectively accelerating Ni &#8594; Fe electron transfer. For HER, Se serves as the active site in the materials with and without Fe, and Gibbs free energy of hydrogen adsorption (&#916;GH*) at Se site decreases from 0.149 eV in NiSe/Ni3Se2 to &#8722;0.051 eV in NiSe/Ni3Se2-Fe, whose the much smaller value near to zero indicates significantly enhanced HER activity. For OER, in NiSe/Ni3Se2, Ni serves as active site, while in NiSe/Ni3Se2-Fe, Fe becomes the active site. In the both materials, rate-determining step (RDS) is the formation of *O&#8594;*OOH intermediates and the much lower energy barrier (1.589 eV) after Fe doping contributes to superior OER activity. The calculated TDOS shows that Fe doping increases carrier density and intrinsic conductivity of the catalyst. This work provides important reference for regulating interface effect of electrocatalysts through elemental doping.</description>
      <author>Ruxin Deng, Huiqin Yao, Yixuan Wang, Chaonan Wang, Siqi Zhang, Shaoshi Guo, Yongliang Li, Shulan Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Efficiency of Water Splitting and Oxygen Reduction Via &lt;scp&gt;Single&#8208;Atom&lt;/scp&gt; Anchoring on Graphyne Support</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12723</link>
      <description>Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Beenish Bashir, Khan Muhammad Ajmal, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394573820

                Single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs) have received significant interest for optimizing metal atom utilization and superior catalytic performance in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In this study, we investigate a range of single&#8208;transition metal (STM 1 = Sc 1 , Ti 1 , V 1 , Cr 1 , Mn 1 , Fe 1 , Co 1 , Ni 1 , Cu 1 , Zr 1 , Nb 1 , Mo 1 , Ru 1 , Rh 1 , Pd 1 , Ag 1 , W 1 , Re 1 , Os 1 , Ir 1 , Pt 1 , and Au 1 ) atoms supported on graphyne (GY) surface for HER/OER and ORR using first&#8208;principle calculations. Ab initio molecular dynamics (AIMD) simulations and phonon dispersion spectra reveal the dynamic and thermal stabilities of the GY surface. The exceptional stability of all supported STM 1 atoms within the H1 cavity of the GY surface exists in an isolated form, facilitating the uniform distribution and proper arrangement of single atoms on GY. In particular, Sc 1 , Co 1 , Fe 1 , and Au 1 /GY demonstrate promising catalytic efficiency in the HER due to idealistic &#916;G H* values via the Volmer&#8208;Heyrovsky pathway. Notably, Sc 1 and Au 1 /GY exhibit superior HER catalytic activity compared to other studied catalysts. Co 1 /GY catalyst exhibits higher selectivity and activity for the OER, with an overpotential (0.46 V) comparable to MoC 2 , IrO 2 , and RuO 2 . Also, Rh 1 and Co 1 /GY SACs exhibited promising electrocatalysts for the ORR, with an overpotential of 0.36 and 0.46 V, respectively. Therefore, Co 1 /GY is a versatile electrocatalyst for metal&#8208;air batteries and water&#8208;splitting. This study further incorporates computational analysis of the kinetic potential energy barriers of Co 1 and Rh 1 in the OER and ORR. A strong correlation is found between the estimated kinetic activation barriers for the thermodynamic outcomes and all proton&#8208;coupled electron transfer steps. We establish a relation for the Gibbs free energy of intermediates to understand the mechanism of SACs supported on STM 1 /GY and introduce a key descriptor. This study highlights GY as a favorable single&#8208;atom support for designing highly active and cost&#8208;effective versatile electrocatalysts for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Shamraiz Hussain Talib, Beenish Bashir, Khan Muhammad Ajmal, Babar Ali, Sharmarke Mohamed, Ahsanulhaq Qurashi, Jun Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12723</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of multi-interface electron transfer on water splitting and an innovative electrolytic cell for synergistic hydrogen production and degradation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.141929</link>
      <description>Xinjing Yuan, Weiyi Hao, Yiran Teng, Hanming Zhang, Cheng Han, X. Zhang, Zhihui Li, Alex O. Ibhadon, Fei Teng, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394610852

                The cleaning and utilization of industry wastewater are still a big challenge. In this work, we mainly investigate the effect of electron transfer among multi-interfaces on water electrolysis reaction. Typically, the CoS2, Co3S4/CoS2 (designated as CS4-2) and Co3S4/Co9S8/CoS2 (designated as CS4-8-2) samples are prepared on a large scale by one-step molten salt method. It is found that because of the different work functions (designated as WF; WF(Co3S4)=4.48eV, WF(CoS2)=4.41eV, WF(Co9S8)=4.18 eV), the effective heterojunctions at the multi-interfaces of CS4-8-2 sample, which obviously improve interface charge transfer. Thus, the CS4-8-2 sample shows an excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity (134 mV/10 mA cm-2, 40 mV dec-1). The larger double-layer capacitance (Cdl=17.1 mF cm-2) of the CS4-8-2 sample indicates more electrochemical active sites, compared to the CoS2 and CS4-2 samples. Density functional theory (DFT) calculation proves that due to interface polarization under electric field, the multi-interfaces effectively promote electron transfer and regulate electron structure, thus promoting the adsorption of OH- and dissociation of H2O. Moreover, an innovative norfloxacin (NFX) electrolytic cell (EC) is developed through introducing NFX into the electrolyte, in which efficient NFX degradation and hydrogen production are synergistically achieved. To reach 50 mA cm-2, the required cell voltage of NFX-EC has decreased by 35.2%, compared to conventional KOH-EC. After 2h running at 1 V, 25.5% NFX was degraded in the NFX EC. This innovative NFX-EC is highly energy-efficient, which is promising for the synergistic cleaning and utilization of industry wastewater.</description>
      <author>Xinjing Yuan, Weiyi Hao, Yiran Teng, Hanming Zhang, Cheng Han, X. Zhang, Zhihui Li, Alex O. Ibhadon, Fei Teng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.141929</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Comparative Study on the Electrocatalytic OER Activity of Mesoporous High-entropy Oxide and Medium-entropy Oxide Nanoparticles through SCS Method</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.04.139</link>
      <description>Arghavan Vojdani Saghir, Samaneh Mollazadeh, Jalil Vahdati Khaki, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394757262

                Developing readily available and cost-effective electrocatalysts as an alternative to the noble metals is a critical issue for renewable hydrogen energy generation. Mesoporous high-entropy oxides (HEOs) are among the most noteworthy candidates in the kinetically challenged process of oxygen evolution reaction (OER); The current study notifies the successful fabrication, and characterization of a series of meso-structured HEOs (5 elements) and MEOs (4 elements) nanopowders with remarkable electrocatalytic performance. Obtained results reveal that the synthesized HEOs and MEOs nanocompounds are meso-structured (with pore size of &#8275;43-67 &#197;) with particle size of &#8275;20-30 nm. Combusted HEOs and MEOs powders have high crystallinity degree (derived from XRD analysis) and homogenous elemental distributions. The electrocatalytic activity of the prepared HEOs and MEOs nanopowders were studied using linear sweep voltammetry (LSV), electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) and cyclic voltammetry (CV) analyses. It was specified that HEO nanoparticles (HEO 0.95 sample) exhibit superior electrocatalytic performance compared to MEOs particles with respect to their overpotential of 310 mV at 10 mA.cm-2 and Tafel slope of 53 mV.dec-1. The drop of the charge transfer resistance (RCT) and increase of the conductivity in HEO 0.95 sample contributes to the improved electrocatalytic OER activity of the HEOs nanopowders. Taking ECSA into account, the improved electrocatalytic activity of meso-structured HEO 0.95 sample relates to the large number of active sites in this sample. The XRD, TEM, and FE-SEM results of HEO 0.95 sample after OER analysis indicated no alteration in phase composition and morphology revealing the reusability of the synthesized nanoparticles. This study also provides an insight into the behavior of Co, Ni, Cu elements as typical electrocatalysts as well as Zn and Mg elements as obscure electrocatalysts for efficient OER electrocatalysis. Furthermore, the impact of adiabatic temperature, crystallinity degree and physicochemical features of meso-structured particles on electrocatalytic performance are explored.</description>
      <author>Arghavan Vojdani Saghir, Samaneh Mollazadeh, Jalil Vahdati Khaki</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.04.139</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Atomic-Level Synthesis to Device-Scale Reactors: A Multiscale Approach to Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00029</link>
      <description>Xiangbowen Du, Menghui Qi, Yong Wang, Accounts of chemical research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394691855

                ConspectusThe development of an advanced energy conversion system for water electrolysis with high efficiency and durability is of great significance for a hydrogen-powered society. This progress relies on the fabrication of electrocatalysts with superior electrochemical performance. Despite decades of advancements in exploring high-performance noble and non-noble metal electrocatalysts, several challenges persist at both the micro- and macrolevels in the field of water electrolysis.At the microlevel, which encompasses electrocatalyst synthesis and characterization, design strategies for high-performance electrocatalysts have primarily focused on interface chemical engineering. However, comprehensive understanding and investigation of interface chemical engineering across various length scales, from micrometers to atomic scales, are still lacking. This deficiency hampers the rational design of catalysts with optimal performance. Under harsh reaction conditions, such as high bias potential and highly acidic or alkaline media, the surface of catalyst materials is susceptible to undergoing "reconstruction", deviating from what is observed through ex situ characterization techniques postsynthesis. Conventional ex situ characterization methods do not provide an accurate depiction of the catalyst's structural evolution during the electrocatalytic reaction, hindering the exploration of the catalytic mechanism.At the macrolevel, pertaining to catalysis-performance evaluation systems and devices, traditional laboratory settings employ a conventional three-electrode or two-electrode system to assess the catalytic performance of electrocatalysts. However, this approach does not accurately simulate hydrogen production under realistic industrial conditions, such as elevated temperatures (60-70 &#176;C), high current densities exceeding 0.5 A cm-2, and flowing electrolytes. To address this limitation, it is crucial to develop testing equipment and methodologies that replicate the actual industrial conditions.In this Account, we propose a multiscale research framework for water electrolysis, spanning from microscale synthesis to macroscale scaled reactor design. Our approach focuses on the design and evaluation of high-performance HER/OER (hydrogen evolution reaction/oxygen evolution reaction) electrocatalysts, incorporating the following strategies: Leveraging principles of interface chemical engineering across various length scales (micrometers, nanometers, and atoms) enables the design of catalyst materials that enhance both activity and durability. This approach provides a comprehensive understanding of the intricate interplay between the catalyst structure and activity, implementing in situ/operando characterization techniques to monitor dynamic interfacial reactions and surface reconstruction processes. This facilitates a profound exploration of catalytic reaction mechanisms, offering insights into the catalyst's structural evolution during the electrocatalytic reaction. We construct a laboratory-scale membrane electrode assembly (MEA) electrochemical reactor capable of operating at high current densities (&gt;1 A cm-2) to evaluate the electrocatalytic performance under simulated industrial conditions. This ensures objective and authentic assessments of the catalyst application potential. Throughout the following sections, we illustrate the application of interface chemical engineering on different length scales in designing diverse electrocatalyst materials. We rely on in situ characterization techniques to gain a profound understanding of the mechanisms behind the HER and OER. Additionally, we describe the development of both acidic and alkaline MEA electrochemical reactors to enhance the precision of electrocatalytic performance evaluation. Finally, we provide a concise overview of the challenges and opportunities in this field.</description>
      <author>Xiangbowen Du, Menghui Qi, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.accounts.4c00029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some caveats about the evolution of the N/O abundance and the star formation history</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.1004.0754</link>
      <description>M. Molla, M. Gavilan, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2010. https://openalex.org/W4394667344

                We carefully analyze how the abundance of Nitrogen over Oxygen evolves when dependent on metallicity stellar yields with a primary component of N proceeding from AGBs stars are used. We show the results obtained with a chemical evolution models grid, calculated with variable star formation efficiencies, which produce different star formation histories. Finally we see how the N/O abundance is related on the evolutionary history.</description>
      <author>M. Molla, M. Gavilan</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2010 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.1004.0754</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatially resolved TALIF investigation of atomic oxygen in the effluent of a CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; microwave discharge</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6595/ad3c36</link>
      <description>Arne Meindl, Ante He&#263;imovi&#263;, U. Fantz, Plasma sources science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394604316

                Abstract A diagnostic setup for one-dimensionally spatially resolved TALIF detection of ground state oxygen atoms (2p 4 3 P 2,1,0 ) is developed. The goal of this study is to investigate the evolution of temperatures and absolute number densities of oxygen atoms along the effluent of a low-pressure CO 2 microwave discharge in order to gain insights into some of the mechanisms governing the post-discharge regime. The plasma source is operated at conditions of 600 W&#8722;1200 W of absorbed power with flow rates of 74 sccm and 370 sccm pure CO2 at pressures between 1.2 mbar and 5 mbar with specific energy inputs up to 111.9 eV/molecule. These operating conditions exhibit high CO 2 conversions (up to 90 %) at low energy efficiencies (2&#8722;7.4 %), due to direct electron impact dissociation driving the conversion process resulting in splitting of CO 2 into CO and metastable oxygen atoms. The TALIF measurements yield spatially resolved translational temperatures between 1000 K&#8722;1600 K for most operating conditions and axial positions along the effluent. Reference measurements with xenon 6p&#8242; [3/2] 2 are used for absolute number density calibration. The resulting axially resolved number density profiles of ground state atomic oxygen increase along the effluent, even at considerable distances of several centimeters from the active discharge, before they reach a maximum between 5&#215;10 20 m &#8722;3 and 2.2&#215;10 21 m &#8722;3 depending on the condition, and decrease after that. This behavior indicates the potential significance of quenching of metastable oxygen atoms within the post-discharge regime of the investigated CO 2 discharges. The measured spatially resolved number density evolutions are qualitatively consistent with quenching via wall collisions being the dominant deactivation mechanism, underlining the importance of particle-wall interactions.</description>
      <author>Arne Meindl, Ante He&#263;imovi&#263;, U. Fantz</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1361-6595/ad3c36</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Life in the last lane: Star formation and chemical evolution in an extremely gas-rich dwarf</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.0711.1588</link>
      <description>Ayesha Begum, Jayaram N. Chengalur, Robert C. Kennicutt, &#1048;. &#1044;. &#1050;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1094;&#1077;&#1074;, M. Boquien, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2007. https://openalex.org/W4394634278

                We present an analysis of HI, H-alpha, and oxygen abundance data for NGC 3741. This galaxy has a very extended gas disk (~8.8 times the Holmberg radius), and a dark to luminous (i.e. stellar) mass ratio of ~149, which makes it one of the ``darkest'' dwarf irregular galaxies known. However its ratio of baryons (i.e. gas + stellar) mass to dark mass is typical of that in galaxies. Our new high-resolution HI images of the galaxy show evidence for a large scale (purely gaseous) spiral arm and central bar. Despite the gaseous spiral feature and the on-going star formation, we find that the global gas density in NGC 3741 is significantly lower than the Toomre instability criterion. We also find that the star formation rate is consistent with that expected from the observed correlations between HI mass and SFR and the global Kennicutt-Schmidt law respectively. We measure the oxygen abundance to be 12+ log(O/H)=7.66$\pm$0.10, which is consistent with that expected from the metallicity-luminosity relation, despite its extreme gas mass ratio. We also examine the issue of chemical evolution of NGC 3741 in the context of closed-box model of chemical evolution. The effective oxygen yield of NGC 3741 is consistent with recent model estimates of closed-box yields, provided one assumes that the gas has been efficiently mixed all the way to edge of the HI disk (i.e. &gt;8 times the optical radius). This seems a priori unlikely. On the other hand, using a sample of galaxies with both interferometric HI maps and chemical abundance measurements, we find that the effective yield is anti-correlated with the total dynamical mass, as expected in leaky box models (slightly abridged).</description>
      <author>Ayesha Begum, Jayaram N. Chengalur, Robert C. Kennicutt, &#1048;. &#1044;. &#1050;&#1072;&#1088;&#1072;&#1095;&#1077;&#1085;&#1094;&#1077;&#1074;, M. Boquien</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.0711.1588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrodynamic simulations of WD-WD mergers and the origin of RCB stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.06864</link>
      <description>Sagiv Shiber, Orsola De Marco, Patrick M. Motl, Bradley Munson, Dominic Marcello, Juhan Frank, Patrick Diehl, Geoffrey C. Clayton, Bennett N. Skinner, Hartmut Kaiser, Gregor Daiss, Dirk Pfl&#252;ger, Jan E. Staff, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394736843

                We study the properties of double white dwarf (DWD) mergers by performing hydrodynamic simulations using the new and improved adaptive mesh refinement code Octo-Tiger. We follow the orbital evolution of DWD systems of mass ratio q=0.7 for tens of orbits until and after the merger to investigate them as a possible origin for R Coronae Borealis (RCB) type stars. We reproduce previous results, finding that during the merger, the Helium WD donor star is tidally disrupted within 20-80 minutes since the beginning of the simulation onto the accretor Carbon-Oxygen WD, creating a high temperature shell around the accretor. We investigate the possible Helium burning in this shell and the merged object's general structure. Specifically, we are interested in the amount of Oxygen-16 dredged-up to the hot shell and the amount of Oxygen-18 produced. This is critical as the discovery of very low Oxygen-16 to Oxygen-18 ratios in RCB stars pointed out the merger scenario as a favorable explanation for their origin. A small amount of hydrogen in the donor may help keep the Oxygen-16 to Oxygen-18 ratios within observational bounds, even if moderate dredge-up from the accretor occurs. In addition, we perform a resolution study to reconcile the difference found in the amount of Oxygen-16 dredge-up between smoothed-particle hydrodynamics and grid-based simulations.</description>
      <author>Sagiv Shiber, Orsola De Marco, Patrick M. Motl, Bradley Munson, Dominic Marcello, Juhan Frank, Patrick Diehl, Geoffrey C. Clayton, Bennett N. Skinner, Hartmut Kaiser, Gregor Daiss, Dirk Pfl&#252;ger, Jan E. Staff</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2404.06864</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predictions for self-pollution in globular cluster stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.astro-ph/0103337</link>
      <description>P. Ventura, F. D&#8217;Antona, I. Mazzitelli, R. Gratton, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2001. https://openalex.org/W4394637193

                Full evolutionary models have been built to follow the phases of asymptotic giant branch evolution with mass loss for metal mass fractions from Z=0.0002 to Z=0.004. For the first time, we find that temperatures close to or even larger than 10^8 K are achieved at low Z; the full CNO cycle operates at the base of the envelope, the Oxygen abundance for the most metal-poor models of 4 and 5 solar masses is drastically reduced, and sodium and aluminum production by by proton capture on neon and magnesium can occur. These results may be relevant for the evolution of primordial massive globular clusters: we suggest that the low-mass stars may have been polluted at the surface by accretion from the gas that was lost from the evolving intermediate-mass stars at early ages.</description>
      <author>P. Ventura, F. D&#8217;Antona, I. Mazzitelli, R. Gratton</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.astro-ph/0103337</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SBS 1150+599A: an extremely oxygen-poor planetary nebula in the Galactic halo?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.astro-ph/0104222</link>
      <description>G. Tovmassian, G. Stasi&#324;ska, V. Chavushyan, S. V. Zharikov, Carlos M. Guti&#233;rrez, Francisco Prada, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2001. https://openalex.org/W4394638932

                We report results of a spectrophotometric study of SBS 1150+599A and discuss the nature of this object based upon our data. Our study shows that SBS 1150+599A is most probably a planetary nebula located in the Galactic halo and not a cataclysmic variable as originally proposed by the authors of the Second Byurakan Survey from low resolution spectroscopy. We have further elaborated on the properties of SBS 1150+599A (now becoming PN G135.9+55.9) with tools used for planetary nebula analysis. Our photoionization models show that, in order to match the observational constraints, the oxygen abundance in the nebula is probably extremely low, around 1/500 solar, which is one order of magnitude lower than the most oxygen-poor planetary nebulae known so far. This finding has strong implications on our understanding of the formation of planetary nebulae and of the evolution of the Galactic halo.</description>
      <author>G. Tovmassian, G. Stasi&#324;ska, V. Chavushyan, S. V. Zharikov, Carlos M. Guti&#233;rrez, Francisco Prada</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2001 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.astro-ph/0104222</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HII galaxies in 4D</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.1402.3151</link>
      <description>E. Telles, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2014. https://openalex.org/W4394643213

                HII galaxies are clumpy and their gas kinematics can be mapped to show the global turbulent motions and the effect of massive star evolution. The distribution of their physical conditions is homogeneous and oxygen abundance is uniform. The presence of nebular HeII 4868 line seems to be higher in a low abundance galaxy, implying a harder ionization power probably due to stars in low metallicity. Innovative methods of data cube analysis, namely PCA tomography (nicknamed 4D), seem promising in revealing additional information not detected with the standard methods. I review some of our own recent work on the 3D spectroscopy of HII galaxies.</description>
      <author>E. Telles</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.1402.3151</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AGB and post-AGB stars</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.astro-ph/0508285</link>
      <description>D. Engels, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2005. https://openalex.org/W4394655984

                Intermediate mass stars (1-8 solar masses) evolve along the Asymptotic Giant Branch after completion of hydrogen and helium core burning. At the tip they lose for several ten to hundred thousand years copious amounts of mass and exhibit various forms of variability, as for example large-amplitude variations with periods of one to five years. In the oxygen-rich circumstellar envelopes powerful OH, H2O and SiO masers may operate. Part of the AGB population is converted to carbon stars. During the latest phases of AGB evolution the mass loss rates approach several 10e-5 solar masses/year, so that the stars become invisible in the optical and in part in the near infrared. On departure from the AGB a fundamental transition in the mass loss process is taking place changing from a spherically symmetric outflow on the AGB to axi-symmetric or point-symmetric geometries. While the mass loss rates decrease to ~10e-8 solar masses/year, the velocities are strongly increasing. Stars are now in their "post-AGB" phase. Mounting evidence is gathered that during the very latest phase of AGB evolution and during the post-AGB phase, evolution proceeds on very short timescales, which in extreme cases is comparable to the working life of an astronomer.</description>
      <author>D. Engels</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2005 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.astro-ph/0508285</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidating the Synergistic Effects of Temperature Rise Inhibitor at the Water Tricalcium Silicate Interface</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07380</link>
      <description>Jiale Huang, Xabier M. Aretxabaleta, Yu Yan, Zhangli Hu, Hegoi Manzano, Jiaping Liu, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394753454

                Organic&#8211;inorganic composites play a crucial role in modulating concrete properties, encompassing interfacial interactions and their synergistic mechanisms. Unraveling these interactions presents a formidable challenge. In this study, molecular dynamics simulations were employed to probe the intricate structure, competition, and equilibrium state of interfacial connections involving a temperature rise inhibitor (TRI), C3S, and water. Computational results reveal that the interplay of different bonding networks significantly influences the equilibrium state of the C3S&#8211;TRI interfacial interactions, marked by dynamic adsorption&#8211;desorption equilibria. The interaction between C3S and TRI manifests in intricate calcium&#8211;oxygen and hydrogen bonding networks, which are both easily disturbed by water molecules. Oxygen sites in water serve as binding sites for calcium atoms in C3S and hydrogen atoms in TRI, thereby attenuating the C3S&#8211;TRI bonding. Simultaneously, hydrogen sites in water engage with oxygen sites in the TRI, diminishing calcium&#8211;oxygen bonding and prompting the detachment of TRI from the C3S surface. Moreover, these hydrogen sites interact with the oxygen sites on the C3S surface, inducing lattice structure alterations and removal of calcium atoms from C3S. As TRI detaches into the liquid phase, it forms complexes with calcium ions, reducing the migration rate of calcium ions within the liquid phase. This study represents the inaugural comprehensive evaluation of the interfacial interaction mechanism between TRI, C3S, and water, offering fundamental insights into the impact of TRI on the evolution of the C3S phase. These findings contribute to a deeper understanding of the complex interplay governing concrete properties, paving the way for enhanced control and optimization in concrete technology.</description>
      <author>Jiale Huang, Xabier M. Aretxabaleta, Yu Yan, Zhangli Hu, Hegoi Manzano, Jiaping Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.3c07380</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diagenetic Genesis and Evolution of Coal-Bearing Tight Sandstone Reservoir in the Yangxia Formation, Northern Kuqa Depression, Tarim Basin</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10100</link>
      <description>Huajun Guo, Wencheng Xia, Xiang Shan, Kelai Xi, Bo Peng, Xianzhang Yang, Zhiwen Zou, Wenfang Yuan, ACS omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394728653

                Coal seams of the Yangxia Formation are widespread in the northern part of the Kuqa Depression in the Tarim Basin. During the thermal evolution of the coal seams, the generated fluids of different periods and natures have a significant impact on tight sandstone reservoirs. To further investigate the diagenetic characteristics and reservoir genesis of the tight sandstones due to the influence of coal seams, an in-depth exploration of the causes of dissolution and cementation in the reservoirs was conducted through thin-section casting, cathode luminescence, scanning electron microscopy, carbon&#8211;oxygen isotopic analyses, and X-ray diffraction of whole rock and authigenic clay minerals, along with burial evolution history and fluid evolution history. It is suggested that two phases of acidic fluids are mainly produced during the thermal evolution process of coal seams, including an early humic acid and a late organic carboxylic acid. The early phase humic acid plays a purifying role in reservoirs with coarse particles, rigidity-rich particles, and good permeability conditions. It selectively dissolves sedimentary calcareous mud and calcite, and the dissolution products are completely migrated. At the same time, it inhibits early carbonate cementation. The late organic carboxylic acid will dissolve potassium feldspar and some volcanic rock debris, and the dissolution products are difficult to migrate under the sealing conditions caused by lithological differences, which often take the cementation form of siliceous overgrowth and kaolinite or illite. In addition to the cementation resulting from the dissolution products of acidic fluids produced by the coal seams, the CO2-rich fluids generated by the coal seam thermal evolution will combine with ions such as Ca2+ from different sources, resulting in two phases of carbonate cementation. Based on the above research, this study summarizes a set of diagenetic evolution models for coal-bearing reservoirs.</description>
      <author>Huajun Guo, Wencheng Xia, Xiang Shan, Kelai Xi, Bo Peng, Xianzhang Yang, Zhiwen Zou, Wenfang Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.3c10100</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHARACTERISTICS AND ELECTROCHEMICAL BEHAVIOR OF OXIDE COATED TITANIUM ANODES</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1993.3.35</link>
      <description>Lan Wang, Shixiong Jin, Yingyong huaxue. 10(3)] 1993. https://openalex.org/W4394704205

                The effects of some oxide intermediate layers on the electrochemical behavior and characteristics of oxide-coated titanium electrodes Ti/PbO2, Ti/Co3O4 and Ti/CuCO2O4 have been investigated.The results showed that the intermediate layers of Co3O4, PdOx, SnO2 and Sb2O3 could markedly decrease the interface resistance of the electrodes. The electrode Ti/PbO2 with intermediate layer of (Sb2O3+PdOx) and the electrode Ti/Co3O4 with intermediate layer of (SnO2+PdOx) showed nearly the same reaction activity for anodic evolution of Cl2 as the industrial electrode consisting of Ti/RuO2+TiO2, but higher oxygen overpotentials than the latter.</description>
      <author>Lan Wang, Shixiong Jin</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 1993 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3724/j.issn.1000-0518.1993.3.35</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing the adsorption of intermediates through modulating Mn d-band centers by the Mn-Ce heterojunction for high-performance lithium-oxygen batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234512</link>
      <description>Mengran Xie, Nan Wang, Shaoze Zhao, Zhongjun Li, Youcai Lu, Qingchao Liu, Journal of power sources. 605(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394790676

                Admitting that rare-earth (RE)-based transition metal oxides (TMO) are emerging as a promising catalyst for lithium-oxygen (Li-O2) batteries, the understanding of their electrocatalytic mechanism and active sites remains ambiguous. In this study, CeO2 nanoparticles modified MnOOH nanowires (CeO2@MnOOH NWs) is prepared by a simple solvothermal method as highly effective cathode catalysts for Li-O2 batteries. The incorporation of CeO2 nanoparticles into MnOOH facilitates a robust interaction between the 3d electronic state of MnOOH and the 4f electronic state of CeO2 at the Fermi level (Ef). The strong electron interaction at the heterogeneous interface between MnOOH and CeO2 promotes internal electron transfer. Compared to pristine MnOOH, the prepared CeO2@MnOOH NWs exhibits enhanced electrocatalytic activity and improved electrocatalytic stability. According to experimental analysis and density functional theory (DFT) results, it is demonstrated that there is a slight negative shift in the d-band center of the Mn site, resulting in faster electron transfer rates and higher conductivity. This acceleration of charge transfer optimizes the adsorption strength of the oxygen-containing intermediate (LiO2), thereby promoting the kinetics of the oxygen reduction/evolution reactions (ORR/OER) and reducting the reaction over-potential. As a result, the electrochemical performances of Li-O2 batteries are greatly enhanced.</description>
      <author>Mengran Xie, Nan Wang, Shaoze Zhao, Zhongjun Li, Youcai Lu, Qingchao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234512</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Superoxide anion radical generation in photosynthetic electron transport chain</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31857/s0320972523080018</link>
      <description>Marina Kozuleva, &#1041;. &#1053;. &#1048;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;, Biohimi&#226;. 88(8)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394749567

                The review analyzes the data available in the literature on the rates, characteristics and mechanisms of oxygen reduction to a superoxide anion radical at the sites of the photosynthetic electron transport chain where this reduction can occur. The existing assumptions about the role of the components of these sites in this process are critically examined, with use of thermodynamic approaches and the results of recent studies. The process of O2 reduction at the acceptor side of PSI, which is considered the main place of this process in the photosynthetic chain, is described in detail. The evolution of the photosynthetic apparatus in the context of controlling the leakage of electrons to O2 is considered. The reasons limiting the application of the results obtained with isolated segments of the photosynthetic chain to estimate the rates of O2 reduction at the corresponding sites in the intact thylakoid membrane are discussed.</description>
      <author>Marina Kozuleva, &#1041;. &#1053;. &#1048;&#1074;&#1072;&#1085;&#1086;&#1074;</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31857/s0320972523080018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing the Corrosion Resistance of A630-420H Steel Exposed to NaCl Solution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.9734/bpi/cicms/v8/11900f</link>
      <description>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, &#193;lvaro Soliz, Luis C&#225;ceres, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Danny Guzm&#225;n, Edelmira D. G&#225;lvez, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394757783

                The deterioration of reinforced concrete structures in marine environments presents multiple problems due to the premature degradation of reinforced steel. The corrosion of reinforcing steel exposed to seawater has received significant attention due to its widespread use in industrial and social infrastructures. This work aimed to study the corrosion of reinforced A630-420H steel when exposed to a 0.5 M NaCl solution. Although this carbon steel is the most widely used material for reinforced concrete structures in Chile, there is limited research on its resistance to corrosion when in contact with saline solutions. The electrochemical reactions and their roles in the corrosion rate were studied using linear sweep voltammetry, weight loss, scanning electron microscopy, and X-ray diffraction techniques. The experimental procedure was designed to examine the kinetics of the partial electrochemical reactions in A630-420H steel immersed in 0.5 M NaCl solution, with a focus on the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and iron oxidation reaction (IOR). This analysis is unique as it used the superposition model based on mixed potential theory to determine the electrochemical and corrosion parameters. The outcomes of this study show that A630-420H steel has a higher corrosion rate than those of the other commercial carbon steels studied. This fact can be attributed to the competition between the cathodic oxygen reduction reaction and hydrogen evolution reaction, which also depends on the environmental conditions, exposure time, stabilization of the corrosion products layer, and presence of chloride ions. Additionally, the results under mechanical stress conditions show a brittle fracture of the corrosion product oriented longitudinally in the direction of the bend section, where the presence of pores and cracks were also observed. The corrosion products after corrosion were mainly composed of magnetite and lepidocrocite oxide phases, which are in concordance with the electrochemical results.</description>
      <author>Felipe M. Galleguillos Madrid, &#193;lvaro Soliz, Luis C&#225;ceres, Sebasti&#225;n Salazar-Avalos, Danny Guzm&#225;n, Edelmira D. G&#225;lvez</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.9734/bpi/cicms/v8/11900f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SN 2020udy: A New Piece of the Homogeneous Bright Group in the Diverse Iax Subclass</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad2618</link>
      <description>Mridweeka Singh, D. K. Sahu, Barnab&#225;s Barna, Anjasha Gangopadhyay, Raya Dastidar, Rishabh Singh Teja, Kuntal Misra, D. Andrew Howell, Xiaofeng Wang, Jun Mo, Shengyu Yan, D. Hiramatsu, C. Pellegrino, G. C. Anupama, Arti Joshi, K. Azalee Bostroem, J. Burke, C. McCully, Rama Subramanian, Gaici Li, Gaobo Xi, X. Allen Li, Zhitong Li, Shubham Srivastav, Hyobin Im, Anirban Dutta, Astrophysical journal/&#152;The &#156;Astrophysical journal. 965(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394571480

                Abstract We present optical observations and analysis of the bright type Iax supernova SN 2020udy hosted by NGC 0812. The evolution of the light curve of SN 2020udy is similar to that of other bright type Iax SNe. Analytical modeling of the quasi-bolometric light curves of SN 2020udy suggests that 0.08 &#177; 0.01 M &#8857; of 56 Ni would have been synthesized during the explosion. The spectral features of SN 2020udy are similar to those of the bright members of type Iax class, showing a weak Si ii line. The late-time spectral sequence is mostly dominated by iron group elements with broad emission lines. Abundance tomography modeling of the spectral time series of SN 2020udy using TARDIS indicates stratification in the outer ejecta; however, to confirm this, spectral modeling at a very early phase is required. After maximum light, uniform mixing of chemical elements is sufficient to explain the spectral evolution. Unlike in the case of normal type Ia SNe, the photospheric approximation remains robust until +100 days, requiring an additional continuum source. Overall, the observational features of SN 2020udy are consistent with the deflagration of a carbon&#8211;oxygen white dwarf.</description>
      <author>Mridweeka Singh, D. K. Sahu, Barnab&#225;s Barna, Anjasha Gangopadhyay, Raya Dastidar, Rishabh Singh Teja, Kuntal Misra, D. Andrew Howell, Xiaofeng Wang, Jun Mo, Shengyu Yan, D. Hiramatsu, C. Pellegrino, G. C. Anupama, Arti Joshi, K. Azalee Bostroem, J. Burke, C. McCully, Rama Subramanian, Gaici Li, Gaobo Xi, X. Allen Li, Zhitong Li, Shubham Srivastav, Hyobin Im, Anirban Dutta</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad2618</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contributions to a More Realistic Characterization of Corrosion Processes on Cut Edges of Coated Metals Using Scanning Microelectrochemical Techniques, Illustrated by the Case of ZnAlMg-Galvanized Steel with Different Coating Densities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071679</link>
      <description>M.F. Bolsanello, A Garcia, Luciana Xavier da Cruz Lima, Bruno Kneipel Neto, Jetson Lemos Ferreira, Jesualdo Luiz Rossi, Isolda Costa, Ricardo M. Souto, Javier Izquierdo, Materials. 17(7)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394576028

                Corrosion processes at cut edges of galvanized steels proceed as highly localized electrochemical reactions between the exposed bulk steel matrix and the protective thin metallic coating of a more electrochemically active material. Scanning microelectrochemical techniques can thus provide the spatially resolved information needed to assess the corrosion initiation and propagation phenomena, yet most methods scan cut edge sections as embedded in insulating resin to achieve a flat surface for scanning purposes. In this work, the galvanized coatings on both sides of the material were concomitantly exposed to simulated acid rain while characterizing the cut edge response using SECM and SVET techniques, thereby maintaining the coupled effects through the exposure of the whole system as rather realistic operation conditions. The cut edges were shown to strongly promote oxygen consumption and subsequent alkalization to pH 10-11 over the iron, while diffusion phenomena eventually yielded the complete depletion of oxygen and pH neutralization of the nearby electrolyte. In addition, the cathodic activation of the exposed iron was intensified with a thinner coating despite the lower presence of sacrificial anode, and preferential sites of the attack in the corners revealed highly localized acidification below pH 4, which sustained hydrogen evolution at spots of the steel-coating interface.</description>
      <author>M.F. Bolsanello, A Garcia, Luciana Xavier da Cruz Lima, Bruno Kneipel Neto, Jetson Lemos Ferreira, Jesualdo Luiz Rossi, Isolda Costa, Ricardo M. Souto, Javier Izquierdo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17071679</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemodynamical gas flow cycles and their influence on the chemical evolution of dwarf irregular galaxies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.astro-ph/0302383</link>
      <description>Andreas Rieschick, G. Hensler, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2003. https://openalex.org/W4394636222

                Here we investigate an exemplary chemodynamical evolutionary simulation of a dwarf irregular galaxy. By means of this model we demonstrate the existence of three gas mixing cycles: 1) An inner "local cycle" mixing the metals produced in stars locally, and 2) an outer "galactic cycle" on which hot gas is driven out of the galaxy by multiple supernovae type II and mixes on a short timescale with the available cold gas. 3) Only a small fraction of the metals leaves the galactic gravitational field and follows the "global cycle" with the intergalactic matter. The large-scale mixing results in a temporary depletion of supernova ejected metals. We will discuss this "delayed recycling" and its influence on the chemical evolution, especially on the nitrogen over oxygen ratio which is increased temporarily. These results presented her are also relevant for less sophisticated analytical approaches and chemical evolutionary models of galaxies which have to parameterize the metal loss through outflow.</description>
      <author>Andreas Rieschick, G. Hensler</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2003 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.astro-ph/0302383</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling sulfate concentrations in the global ocean through Phanerozoic time</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1144/jgs2023-184</link>
      <description>Alexander J. Krause, Graham Shields, Robert J. Newton, Benjamin J. W. Mills, Journal of the Geological Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394577217

                Understanding the long-term variance of seawater sulfate concentrations ([SO 4 2- ] sw ) is critical to understanding the dynamic relationship between the sulfur, carbon, calcium, and oxygen cycles, and their influence on Earth's habitability. Here, we explore how [SO 4 2- ] sw has changed throughout the Phanerozoic, and its impact on other elemental cycles. We do this by utilising the biogeochemical box model GEOCARBSULFOR. The model suggests that [SO 4 2- ] sw rose throughout the Paleozoic, declined during the Mesozoic, and then rose once more in the Cenozoic, generally matching geochemical proxies. Atmospheric oxygen mirrors [SO 4 2- ] sw changes during the Paleozoic and Mesozoic, but intriguingly, decouples during the Cenozoic. We further explored controls on [SO 4 2- ] sw by modifying the modelled gypsum fluxes via the incorporation of evaporite data from the geological record. We find that forcing gypsum burial with the observed evaporite deposition data causes the model to better match proxy records at some times, but worsens predictions at others. Finally, we investigate model reliance on a prescribed record of marine calcium concentrations, finding that it is a dominant control on modelled Phanerozoic [SO 4 2- ] sw , and that removing this control seriously degrades model predictions. We conclude that no model can yet simulate a reasonable evolution of both the calcium and sulfur cycles. Thematic collection: This article is part of the Sulfur in the Earth system collection available at: https://www.lyellcollection.org/topic/collections/sulfur-in-the-earth-system Supplementary material: https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.c.7164928</description>
      <author>Alexander J. Krause, Graham Shields, Robert J. Newton, Benjamin J. W. Mills</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1144/jgs2023-184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Subsolar Metallicity on the Ultra-short-period Planet HIP 65Ab</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ad3071</link>
      <description>Luc Bazinet, Sonia Pelletier, Bj&#246;rn Benneke, Ricardo Salinas, Gregory N. Mace, &#152;The &#156;Astronomical journal. 167(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394608520

                Abstract Studying and understanding the physical and chemical processes that govern hot Jupiters gives us insights on the formation of these giant planets. Having a constraint on the molecular composition of their atmosphere can help us pinpoint their evolution timeline. Namely, the metal enrichment and carbon-to-oxygen ratio can give us information about where in the protoplanetary disk a giant planet may have accreted its envelope, and, subsequently, indicate if it went through migration. Here we present the first analysis of the atmosphere of the hot Jupiter HIP 65Ab. Using near-infrared high-resolution observations from the IGRINS spectrograph, we detect H 2 O and CO absorption in the dayside atmosphere of HIP 65Ab. Using a high-resolution retrieval framework, we find a CO abundance of log(CO) =   &#8722;   3.85   &#8722; 0.36   + 0.33    , which is slightly underabundant with expectation from solar composition models. We also recover a low-water abundance of log(H 2 O) = &#8722;4.42 &#177; 0.18, depleted by 1 order of magnitude relative to a solar-like composition. Upper limits on the abundance of all other relevant major carbon- and oxygen-bearing molecules are also obtained. Overall, our results are consistent with a sub-stellar metallicity but slightly elevated C/O. Such a composition may indicate that HIP 65Ab accreted its envelope from beyond the water snowline and underwent a disk-free migration to its current location. Alternatively, some of the oxygen on HIP 65Ab could be condensed out of the atmosphere, in which case the observed gas-phase abundances would not reflect the true bulk envelope composition.</description>
      <author>Luc Bazinet, Sonia Pelletier, Bj&#246;rn Benneke, Ricardo Salinas, Gregory N. Mace</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-3881/ad3071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Marine redox dynamics and biotic response to the mid-Silurian Ireviken Extinction Event in a mid-shelf setting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1144/jgs2023-155</link>
      <description>Y. Wang, Paul B. Wignall, Yijun Xiong, David K. Loydell, Jeff Peakall, Jaco H. Baas, Benjamin J. W. Mills, Simon W. Poulton, Journal of the Geological Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394571488

                The early Silurian Llandovery&#8211;Wenlock boundary interval was marked by significant marine perturbations and biotic turnover, culminating in the Ireviken Extinction Event (IEE) and the Early Sheinwoodian Carbon Isotope Excursion (ESCIE). Here, we apply multiple independent redox proxies to the early Wenlock Buttington section, which was deposited in a mid-shelf location in the Welsh Basin, UK. To account for regional geochemical variability in marine sediments due to factors such as sediment provenance, we first define oxic baseline values for the Welsh basin, utilizing deeper water, well-oxygenated intervals of late Llandovery age. Our approach documents unstable, oscillating redox conditions on the mid shelf at Buttington. We suggest that these dynamic redox fluctuations are likely to relate to changes in the position of the chemocline or a migrating oxygen minimum zone. Benthic biota such as trilobites, brachiopods, bivalves and gastropods appear to have been relatively unaffected by fluctuating oxic-ferruginous conditions, but were more severely impacted by the development of euxinia, highlighting the inhibiting role of toxic sulfides. By contrast, the redox perturbations appear to have placed extreme stress on graptolites, causing many extinction losses regardless of the specific development of euxinia. Thematic collection: This article is part of the Chemical Evolution of the Mid-Paleozoic Earth System and Biotic Response collection available at: https://www.lyellcollection.org/topic/collections/chemical-evolution-of-the-mid-paleozoic-earth-system Supplementary material: https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.c.7165009</description>
      <author>Y. Wang, Paul B. Wignall, Yijun Xiong, David K. Loydell, Jeff Peakall, Jaco H. Baas, Benjamin J. W. Mills, Simon W. Poulton</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1144/jgs2023-155</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the high-temperature corrosion resistance of HVOF-sprayed NiCoCrAlY coating in marine environment by Pt modification and pre-oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.02.079</link>
      <description>Y.Y. Li, Yixiao Jiang, C. Zhang, H.Z. Ji, S. Li, Na Xu, Bao Zhang, Shenglong Zhu, F.H. Wang, Journal of Materials Science and Technology/Journal of materials science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394616309

                To prolong the service lifetime of hot-section components used in marine environment at elevated temperatures, it is crucial to explore and develop high-temperature corrosion-resistant coatings. High-velocity oxygen fuel (HVOF) sprayed NiCoCrAlY, Pt-modified NiCoCrAlY and pre-oxidized Pt-modified NiCoCrAlY coatings were prepared and investigated. This study is concerned with the performance of three coatings in a simulated marine environment based on the phase composition of corrosion products and microstructure evolution of coating samples combined with first-principles density functional theory. The results show that the NiCoCrAlY coating was subject to accelerated corrosion and extensive aluminum depletion, leading to premature coating failure. The high-temperature corrosion resistance of Pt-modified NiCoCrAlY coating was found to be better than that of NiCoCrAlY coating. In contrast, the pre-oxidized Pt-modified NiCoCrAlY coating offered long-lasting protection and exhibited the best corrosion resistance, which is attributed to the positive synergistic effect between Pt modification and pre-oxidation.</description>
      <author>Y.Y. Li, Yixiao Jiang, C. Zhang, H.Z. Ji, S. Li, Na Xu, Bao Zhang, Shenglong Zhu, F.H. Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jmst.2024.02.079</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hypervalent Iodine(III) Mediated Halogen Bonded Supramolecular Chiral System with Cholesteryl Naphthalimides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401004</link>
      <description>Jie Zhang, Aiyou Hao, Pengyao Xing, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394575146

                Halogen bonding acknowledged as a noteworthy weak interaction, has gained growing recognition in the field of supramolecular chemistry. In this study, we selected structurally rigid diaryliodonium ions (I(III)) with two biaxial &#963;-holes as halogen-bond donors, to bind with three chiral acceptor molecules bearing cholesteryl and naphthalimides with distinct geometries. The abundant carbonyl oxygen atoms in side-arm substituents function as multiple acceptors for halogen bonding. The self-aggregation of chiral acceptor molecules demonstrates adaptiveness to solvent media, evidenced by the inversion of the Cotton effect and the morphological evolution from spherical to rod-like nanoarchitectures in different solvent systems. The distinct geometries of the acceptor molecules conferred various binding modes with I(III). The introduction of I(III) as a halogen-bond donor regulates the aggregation of the donors, achieving amplification of chiroptical signals and inheriting solvent responsiveness from the self-aggregated assembly. This study successfully utilized rational structural design and multimodal control strategies to achieve regulation of supramolecular chirality.</description>
      <author>Jie Zhang, Aiyou Hao, Pengyao Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401004</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Disentangling the Evolution of Electrons and Holes in photoexcited ZnO nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2310.04060</link>
      <description>Christopher J. Milne, Natalia S. Nagornova, Thomas Pope, Huiyuan Chen, Thomas Rossi, Jakub Szlachetko, Wojciech Gawe&#322;da, Alexander Britz, Tim B. van Drie, L. Sala, Simon Ebner, Tetsuo Katayama, Stephen H. Southworth, Gilles Doumy, Anne Marie March, C. Stefan Lehmann, Melanie Mucke, Denys Iablonskyi, Yoshiaki Kumagai, Gregor Knopp, K. Motomura, Tadashi Togashi, Shigeki Owada, Makina Yabashi, Martin Meedom Nielsen, M. Pajek, Kiyoshi Ueda, R. Abela, Thomas J. Penfold, Majed Chergui, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394668459

                The evolution of charge carriers in photoexcited room temperature ZnO nanoparticles in solution is investigated using ultrafast ultraviolet photoluminescence spectroscopy, ultrafast Zn K-edge absorption spectroscopy and ab-initio molecular dynamics (MD) simulations. The photoluminescence is excited at 4.66 eV, well above the band edge, and shows that electron cooling in the conduction band and exciton formation occur in &lt;500 fs, in excellent agreement with theoretical predictions. The X-ray absorption measurements, obtained upon excitation close to the band edge at 3.49 eV, are sensitive to the migration and trapping of holes. They reveal that the 2 ps transient largely reproduces the previously reported transient obtained at 100 ps time delay in synchrotron studies. In addition, the X-ray absorption signal is found to rise in ~1.4 ps, which we attribute to the diffusion of holes through the lattice prior to their trapping at singly-charged oxygen vacancies. Indeed, the MD simulations show that impulsive trapping of holes induces an ultrafast expansion of the cage of Zn atoms in &lt;200 fs, followed by an oscillatory response at a frequency of ~100 cm-1, which corresponds to a phonon mode of the system involving the Zn sub-lattice.</description>
      <author>Christopher J. Milne, Natalia S. Nagornova, Thomas Pope, Huiyuan Chen, Thomas Rossi, Jakub Szlachetko, Wojciech Gawe&#322;da, Alexander Britz, Tim B. van Drie, L. Sala, Simon Ebner, Tetsuo Katayama, Stephen H. Southworth, Gilles Doumy, Anne Marie March, C. Stefan Lehmann, Melanie Mucke, Denys Iablonskyi, Yoshiaki Kumagai, Gregor Knopp, K. Motomura, Tadashi Togashi, Shigeki Owada, Makina Yabashi, Martin Meedom Nielsen, M. Pajek, Kiyoshi Ueda, R. Abela, Thomas J. Penfold, Majed Chergui</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2310.04060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancing strategies on green H2 production via water electrocatalysis: bridging the benchtop research with industrial scale-up</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.87</link>
      <description>Yanzhao Zhang, Dazhi Yao, Jinzhe Liu, Zhiliang Wang, Luyao Wang, Microstructures. 4(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394721521

                Water splitting provides clean hydrogen via different technologies such as alkaline water electrolysis, proton exchange membrane electrolyzers, solid oxide electrolysis cells, and photoelectrolysis, each with advantages and challenges. The focus on alkaline water electrolysis highlights its maturity compared to emerging methods. Non-noble metal catalysts offer increased stability, low cost and operational lifespan. Challenges such as low current density, gas crossover, corrosive electrolytes, and limited efficiency are still to be addressed. These advanced electrocatalysts are summarized for alkaline oxygen and hydrogen evolution reactions. Meanwhile, different factors including product gas bubble management, operation conditions, separator and electrolyte affecting the performance were concluded and discussed. For the promising approach, seawater splitting is still far from large-scale application. Salinity, pH fluctuations, and complex composition are significant obstacles. The review underscores the need for improvements in electrocatalysts to enhance the efficiency, stability, and practicality of water splitting for hydrogen production, ultimately contributing to the growth of the clean hydrogen market and supporting the transition to sustainable energy systems.</description>
      <author>Yanzhao Zhang, Dazhi Yao, Jinzhe Liu, Zhiliang Wang, Luyao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/microstructures.2023.87</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identifying the Active Sites in MoSi&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;@MoO&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunctions for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202301542</link>
      <description>Bo Gao, Qilin Cheng, Xianan Du, Hongyang Zhao, Chunhui Xiao, Jin Wang, Zhongxiao Song, Ho Won Jang, Small methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394726357

                Abstract Developing Two&#8208;dimensional (2D) Mo&#8208;based heterogeneous nanomaterials is of great significance for energy conversion, especially in alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), however, it remains a challenge to identify the active sites at the interface due to the structure complexity. Herein, the real active sites are systematically explored during the HER process in varied Mo&#8208;based 2D materials by theoretical computational and magnetron sputtering approaches first to filtrate the candidates, then successfully combined the MoSi 2 and MoO 3 together through Oxygen doping to construct heterojunctions. Benefiting from the synergistic effects between the MoSi 2 and MoO 3 , the obtained MoSi 2 @MoO 3 exhibits an unprecedented overpotential of 72 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . Density functional theory calculations uncover the different Gibbs free energy of hydrogen adsorption (&#916; G H* ) values achieved at the interfaces with different sites as adsorption sites. The results can facilitate the optimization of heterojunction electrocatalyst design principles for the Mo&#8208;based 2D materials.</description>
      <author>Bo Gao, Qilin Cheng, Xianan Du, Hongyang Zhao, Chunhui Xiao, Jin Wang, Zhongxiao Song, Ho Won Jang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202301542</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermally Induced Structure and Functionality Evolution of a Pt&#8208;based Lean NOx Trap Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400023</link>
      <description>Dezhi Ren, Chengxiong Wang, Dan Yang, Yinglong Wu, Feng Feng, Junliang Du, Fangyong Yu, Zhu Jin-hua, Yue Zhao, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394570470

                Applying a NOx trap catalyst to effectively remove NOx contaminants from the oxygen&#8208;rich exhaust is still very challenging, due to the lack of use guidance based on deactivation mechanisms. The temperature&#8208;dependent Pt sintering rate constant was described using Pt dispersion determined by pulse CO chemisorption. It was found that 700&#8208;850 &#186;C was the determining temperature regions for the significant Pt sintering, according to the sintering kinetics and the evolution of active Pt&#948;+ sites. The weak basicity plays a critical role in trapping NOx at low&#8208;temperature (&#8804; 300 &#186;C), and the NOx trap efficiency decreases because of the loss of catalytic activity and medium basicity caused by forming BaAl2O4 phase. The reduction of NOx towards N2 on the Pt crystallites smaller than 18 nm is structure sensitive and decreases with losing the reducibility of catalysts. The security for long&#8208;time use of a NOx trap catalyst should be exposed to the exhaust gas within 750 &#186;C, and effectively removing NOx contaminants requires it to be worked in the 350&#8208;500 &#186;C regions. These findings can guide engineers and applied chemists how to efficiently use a NOx trap catalyst in the automotive exhaust purification system.</description>
      <author>Dezhi Ren, Chengxiong Wang, Dan Yang, Yinglong Wu, Feng Feng, Junliang Du, Fangyong Yu, Zhu Jin-hua, Yue Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202400023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallicity of the intergalactic medium using pixel statistics: IV. Oxygen</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.0712.1239</link>
      <description>Anthony Aguirre, Corey Dow-Hygelund, Joop Schaye, Tom Theuns, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2007. https://openalex.org/W4394637525

                We have studied the abundance of oxygen in the IGM by analyzing OVI, CIV, SiIV, and HI pixel optical depths derived from a set of high-quality VLT and Keck spectra of 17 QSOs at 2.1 &lt; z &lt; 3.6. Comparing OVI and CIV optical depth ratios to those in realistic, synthetic spectra drawn from a hydrodynamical simulation and comparing to existing constraints on [Si/C] places strong constraints on the ultraviolet background (UVB) model using weak priors on allowed values of [Si/O]: for example, a quasar-only background yields [Si/O] ~ 1.4, highly inconsistent with the [Si/O] ~ 0 expected from nucleosynthetic yields and with observations of metal-poor stars. Assuming a fiducial quasar+galaxy UVB consistent with these constraints yields a primary result that [O/C] = 0.66 +/- 0.06 +/- 0.2; this result pertains to gas with overdensity &gt;~ 0.2. Consistent results are obtained by similarly comparing OVI to HI or OVI to SiIV optical depth ratios to simulation values, and also by directly ionization-correcting OVI optical depths as function of HI optical depths into [O/H] as a function of density. Subdividing the sample reveals no evidence for evolution, but low- and high-density samples are inconsistent, suggesting either density-dependence of [O/C] or -- more likely -- prevalence of collisionally-ionized gas at high density.</description>
      <author>Anthony Aguirre, Corey Dow-Hygelund, Joop Schaye, Tom Theuns</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.0712.1239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulation of Ni/Co Ratio and Gas Transport in High&#8208;Order Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper Perovskite Air Electrodes for Protonic Ceramic Electrochemical Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403493</link>
      <description>Jiaojiao Xia, Mingyang Zhou, Hui Gao, Fan He, Zhiwei Du, Yu Chen, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394596069

                Abstract The delicate design of efficient air electrodes is conducive to improving the reaction kinetics and operational durability of protonic ceramic electrochemical cells (PCECs) at intermediate&#8208;low temperatures. Here, a series of high&#8208;order Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper (RP) perovskite electrodes are developed via the regulation of Ni/Co ratio and porosity for efficient charge/gas transfer. As verified by structural analysis and electrochemical characterizations, the electrode with a composition of Pr 4 Ni 1.8 Co 1.2 O 10&#8208;&#948; (PNCO64) shows the most matchable thermal expansion behavior with electrolytes, and highest electrical conductivity, and best catalytic activity toward oxygen reduction/evolution reactions. The Ni/Co ratio of 6:4 can induce the formation of an optimized amount of Pr 6 O 11 in PNCO64, which is likely the pivotal source of the improved catalytic activity. When implemented on PCECs, the PNCO64 electrodes with the addition of 5% graphite pore&#8208;former achieve a remarkable peak power density (1.18 W cm &#8722;2 ) and a high current density of 2.08 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.3 V at 600 &#176;C. Excellent durability in fuel cell mode (&#8776;85 h) and electrolysis mode (&#8776;92 h) is also accomplished in PCECs at 600 &#176;C.</description>
      <author>Jiaojiao Xia, Mingyang Zhou, Hui Gao, Fan He, Zhiwei Du, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403493</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Active and Stable Cobalt&#8208;Free Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper Nd&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Sr&lt;sub&gt;1.2&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;1&#8208;x&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&#177;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; Air Electrode for Reversible Proton&#8208;Conducting Solid Oxide Cells</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202316485</link>
      <description>Ting Chen, Guangjun Zhang, Kui Liu, Chenxiao Wang, Guozhu Zheng, Zuzhi Huang, Ningning Sun, Li&#8208;Yan Xu, Juan Zhou, Yucun Zhou, Shaorong Wang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394595901

                Abstract Reversible proton&#8208;conducting solid oxide cells (R&#8208;PSOCs) are considered to be one of the most promising devices for efficient power generation and hydrogen production. However, the requirement of high catalytic activity for fast oxygen reduction/evolution reaction (ORR/OER) and durability under high steam concentration of air electrode materials remains the major challenge for the practical application of R&#8208;PSOCs. Here, a series of cobalt&#8208;free Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper perovskite of Nd 0.8 Sr 1.2 Ni 1&#8208;x Fe x O 4&#177;&#948; are reported with mixed conductivity for enhanced ORR/OER kinetics. The R&#8208;PSOCs with an optimal Nd 0.8 Sr 1.2 Ni 0.7 Fe 0.3 O 4&#177;&#948; air electrode show a high peak power density of 1.28 W cm &#8722;2 in the fuel cell mode and a promising current density of 3.24 A cm &#8722;2 at 1.3 V in the electrolysis cell mode at 700 &#176;C. In addition, the R&#8208;PSOCs show favorable stability under the fuel cell, electrolysis, and reversible modes for hundreds of hours. This work demonstrates that the Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper materials can be utilized as suitable air electrodes for R&#8208;PSOCs.</description>
      <author>Ting Chen, Guangjun Zhang, Kui Liu, Chenxiao Wang, Guozhu Zheng, Zuzhi Huang, Ningning Sun, Li&#8208;Yan Xu, Juan Zhou, Yucun Zhou, Shaorong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202316485</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning the A&#8208;site Element in LaCo&lt;sub&gt;0.8&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;0.2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; Perovskite&#8208;based Catalyst for High Temperature N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O Decomposition in Nitric Acid Plant</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202304026</link>
      <description>Peng Zheng, Fei He, Yeke Wu, Jianhui Yang, Fangli Jing, Pascal Granger, ChemistrySelect. 9(14)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394619959

                Abstract The effect of La&#8208;deficiency and Ce/Sr&#8208;substitution in the benchmark LaCo 0.8 Fe 0.2 O 3 has been investigated for the decomposition of N 2 O between 500 and 900 &#176;C. Real inlet gas composition and space velocity reveal that La&#8208;deficiency and Ce/Sr&#8208;substitution can improve the thermal stability of catalyst, while La 1&#8208; x Sr x Co 0.8 Fe 0.2 O 3 with x &#8805;0.1 was highlighted as a promising formula due to the strongest resistance to deactivation and suppressed undesired NO x decomposition at high space velocity. This phenomenon is mainly ascribed to the incorporation of Sr 2+ into the perovskite lattice during the reaction consequently stabilizing the Co 3+ species and creating the oxygen vacancies in La 1&#8208; x Sr x CoO 3&#8208;&#948; . On the contrary, the loss of activity on Ce&#8208;substituted LaCo 0.8 Fe 0.2 O 3 has been preferentially related to the cobalt exsolution to extra framework of perovskite making the catalytic cycle with Co 3+ unfavorable. All these bulk and surface changes are accompanied with opposite evolution of apparent activation energy and pre&#8208;exponential factor which can be discussed based on a redox mechanism.</description>
      <author>Peng Zheng, Fei He, Yeke Wu, Jianhui Yang, Fangli Jing, Pascal Granger</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202304026</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The causal arrows - from genotype, environment and management to plant phenotype - are double headed</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.04.08.588646</link>
      <description>V&#237;ctor O. Sadras, Peter Hayman, bioRxiv (Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394759254

                Unidirectional, cause-and-effect arrows are drawn from genotype (G), environment (E), and agronomic management (M) to the plant phenotype in crop stands. Here we focus on the overlooked bi-directionality of these arrows. The phenotype-to-genotype arrow includes increased mutation rates in stressed phenotypes, relative to basal rates. From a developmental viewpoint, the phenotype modulates gene expression returning multiple cellular phenotypes with a common genome. From a computational viewpoint, the phenotype influences gene expression in a process of downward causation. The phenotype-to-environment arrow is captured in the process of niche construction, which spans from persistent and global (e.g., photosynthetic archaea and cyanobacteria that emerged ~3.4 billion years ago created the oxygen-rich atmosphere that enabled the evolution of aerobic organisms and eukaryotes) to transient and local (e.g., lucerne tap root constructs soil biopores that influence the root phenotype of the following wheat crop). Research on crop rotations illustrates but is divorced of niche construction theory. The phenotype-to-management arrow involves, for example, a diseased crop that triggers fungicide treatments. Making explicit the bi-directionality of the arrows in the G X E X M model allows to connect crop improvement and agronomy with other, theoretically rich scientific fields.</description>
      <author>V&#237;ctor O. Sadras, Peter Hayman</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1101/2024.04.08.588646</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roles of hygrothermal aging temperature and time in degradation of the fracture toughness of highly cross&#8208;linked epoxy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/app.55541</link>
      <description>Kushal Mishra, Aparna Singh, Journal of applied polymer science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394765039

                Abstract The evolution of plane&#8208;strain fracture toughness in highly cross&#8208;linked epoxies was assessed for different hygrothermal aging temperatures (25, 50, and 75&#176;C) and durations (0&#8211;75 days). The absorption of water increased with hygrothermal aging, but at a diminishing rate and without saturating. A fraction of the absorbed water persisted despite prolonged drying. Thermogravimetric analysis revealed that the epoxy&#8208;decomposition temperature decreased with hygrothermal aging. 13 C solid&#8208;state nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy indicated an increase in the de&#8208;shielding of carbon atoms in the vicinity of electronegative elements like oxygen with hygrothermal aging severity, indicating the development of intermolecular hydrogen bonding. X&#8208;ray photoelectron spectroscopy tracked the chemical bonding state of carbon by using a narrow scan on the C1s binding energy region. Upon hygrothermal aging, there was a decrease in C&#63743;C/C&#63742;C groups, indicating main chain scission through hydrolysis. A simultaneous increase in the C&#63743;O species indicates the formation of alcohols as hydrolysis reaction products. In this manner, retained water was involved in hydrogen bonding and chemical reactions with the epoxy. With increasing severity of hygrothermal aging, the fracture toughness decreased. This was consistent with fracture surface micrographs that showed a greater distance amongst crack stretch marks in specimens with less toughness.</description>
      <author>Kushal Mishra, Aparna Singh</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/app.55541</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generation of environmentally persistent free radicals on photoaged tire wear particles and their neurotoxic effects on neurotransmission in Caenorhabditis elegans</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2024.108640</link>
      <description>Yulun Gu, Yongqi Jiang, Xiaoxia Chen, Liangzhong Li, Haibo Chen, Jinyu Chen, Chen Wang, Jun Yu, Chao Chen, Hui Li, Environment international. 186(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394567032

                Tire wear particles (TWP) are a prevalent form of microplastics (MPs) extensively distributed in the environment, raising concerns about their environmental behaviors and risks. However, knowledge regarding the properties and toxicity of these particles at environmentally relevant concentrations, specifically regarding the role of environmentally persistent free radicals (EPFRs) generated during TWP photoaging, remains limited. In this study, the evolution of EPFRs on TWP under different photoaging times and their adverse effects on Caenorhabditis elegans were systematically investigated. The photoaging process primarily resulted in the formation of EPFRs and reactive oxygen species (O2&#8226;-, &#8901;OH, and 1O2), altering the physicochemical properties of TWP. The exposure of nematodes to 100 &#956;g/L of TWP-50 (TWP with a photoaging time of 50 d) led to a significant decrease in locomotory behaviors (e.g., head thrashes, body bends, and wavelength) and neurotransmitter contents (e.g., dopamine, glutamate, and serotonin). Similarly, the expression of neurotransmission-related genes was reduced in nematodes exposed to TWP-50. Furthermore, the addition of free-radical inhibitors significantly suppressed TWP-induced neurotoxicity. Notably, correlation analysis revealed a significantly negative correlation between EPFRs levels and the locomotory behaviors and neurotransmitter contents of nematodes. Thus, it was concluded that EPFRs on photoaged TWP induce neurotoxicity by affecting neurotransmission. These findings elucidate the toxicity effects and mechanisms of EPFRs, emphasizing the importance of considering their contributions when evaluating the environmental risks associated with TWP.</description>
      <author>Yulun Gu, Yongqi Jiang, Xiaoxia Chen, Liangzhong Li, Haibo Chen, Jinyu Chen, Chen Wang, Jun Yu, Chao Chen, Hui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envint.2024.108640</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thermodynamic and kinetic analysis on the biomass syngas fueled chemical looping hydrogen generation process in fixed bed reactor</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131308</link>
      <description>Zixiang Gao, Di Wu, Fan Yin, Libin Sun, Dewang Zeng, Rui Xiao, Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394787383

                Because of its simple structure and easy operation, the fixed bed reactor is widely used in the chemical looping process to assess the performance of oxygen carriers (OC) or to evaluate new chemical looping technologies. However, the systematic investigation of the redox behavior and temperature evolution during the chemical looping hydrogen generation (CLHG) process in the fixed bed reactor under different conditions, which is crucial for process optimization and reactor design, has received less attention. In the present work, the redox characteristics of the CLHG process with biomass syngas as the fuel in a fixed bed reactor were investigated and analyzed from a perspective of thermodynamics and kinetics. Results showed that high redox temperature (&gt;800 &#176;C) favors the fuel conversion due to the improved reaction kinetics and favorable thermodynamics. A space velocity in the range of 0.12-0.5 s-1 and superficial velocity of 0.008-0.075 m/s can provide enough reaction time meanwhile enhance the external diffusion of fuel gas, achieving high reduction degree of OC and further high H2 yield (3.4 mmol/g Fe2O3) and high H2 energy efficiency (45%). Moreover, a violent OC bed temperature rise (100 &#176;C) was observed in the air oxidization stage, which can be mitigated by diluting the Fe2O3 content and decreasing the air flow rate. Finally, the reaction front and flow front moving behavior were discussed in detail for a better understanding of the CLHG process.</description>
      <author>Zixiang Gao, Di Wu, Fan Yin, Libin Sun, Dewang Zeng, Rui Xiao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.energy.2024.131308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Island&#8208;in&#8208;Sea Structured Pt&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;Fe Nanoparticles&#8208;in&#8208;Fe Single Atoms Loaded in Carbon Materials as Superior Electrocatalysts toward Alkaline HER and Acidic ORR</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400240</link>
      <description>Benteng Sun, Hang Lv, Qi Xu, Peiran Tong, Panzhe Qiao, He Tian, Haibing Xia, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394622730

                Abstract In this work, Pt 3 Fe nanoparticles (Pt 3 Fe NPs) with the ordered internal structure and Pt&#8208;rich shells surrounded by plenty of Fe single atoms (Fe SAs) as active species (Pt 3 Fe NP&#8208;in&#8208;Fe SA) loaded in the carbon materials are successfully fabricated, which are abbreviated as island&#8208;in&#8208;sea structured (IISS) Pt 3 Fe NP&#8208;in&#8208;Fe SA catalysts. Moreover, the synergistic effect of O&#8208;bridging between Pt 3 Fe NPs and Fe SAs, and the ordered internal structured Pt 3 Fe NPs with Pt&#8208;rich shells of an optimal thickness contributes to the achievement of the local acidic environments on the surfaces of Pt 3 Fe NPs in the alkaline hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the enhancement of the desorption rate of *OH intermediate in the acidic oxygen reduction reaction (ORR). In addition, the electronic interactions between Pt 3 Fe NPs and dispersed Fe SAs cannot only provide efficient electrons transfer, but also prevent the aggregation and dissolution of Pt 3 Fe NPs. Furthermore, the overpotential and the half wave potential of the as&#8208;prepared IISS Pt 3 Fe NP&#8208;in&#8208;Fe SA catalysts toward the alkaline HER and toward the acidic ORR are 8 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and 0.933 V, respectively, which is 29 lower and 86 mV higher than those (37 mV and 0.847 V) of commercial Pt/C catalysts.</description>
      <author>Benteng Sun, Hang Lv, Qi Xu, Peiran Tong, Panzhe Qiao, He Tian, Haibing Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202400240</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swift heavy ion irradiation-driven energy band engineering and its profound influence on the photoresponse of &lt;b&gt;&#946;&lt;/b&gt;-Ga2O3 ultraviolet photodetectors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0203552</link>
      <description>Huiping Zhu, Yuanjun Tang, Aoxue Zhong, Lei Wang, Fanyu Liu, Peixiong Zhao, Jie Liu, Lei Shu, Zhenping Wu, Bo Li, Applied physics letters. 124(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394764485

                Swift heavy Ta ions with an ultra-high energy of 2896 MeV are utilized for irradiation of &#946;-Ga2O3 photodetectors. Noteworthy variations in device performance under different wavelengths are observed. Under 254 nm light illumination, the photocurrent of the devices exhibit degradation at low ion fluences but gradually recover and even surpass the performance of non-irradiated devices at the irradiation fluence of 1 &#215; 1010 cm&#8722;2. Conversely, under 365 nm light illumination, photocurrent increases at low fluence but slightly decreases at the same high fluence of 1 &#215; 1010 cm&#8722;2. Cathodoluminescence spectra and first-principles calculations elucidate the mechanism underlying the evolution of device performance with irradiation fluence. At low irradiation fluence, the introduction of point defects such as oxygen vacancies and gallium vacancies leads to an expansion of the bandgap, resulting in a decline in photocurrent under 254 nm light illumination. Additionally, deep defect levels are generated by these point defects, promoting an enhancement of photocurrent under 365 nm light illumination. Higher fluences transform these point defects into complex defects such as Ga&#8211;O pair vacancies, resulting in a reduction in the bandgap. Consequently, an increase in photocurrent is observed for devices illuminated with 254 nm light. However, at high irradiation fluences, charge recombination induced by the presence of deep defect levels becomes more significant, leading to a decrease in photocurrent when exposed to 365 nm light. No matter what, at 1 &#215; 1010 cm&#8722;2 fluence, &#946;-Ga2O3 photodetectors still maintain excellent performance, implying their strong radiation resistance and immense potential for application in space environments.</description>
      <author>Huiping Zhu, Yuanjun Tang, Aoxue Zhong, Lei Wang, Fanyu Liu, Peixiong Zhao, Jie Liu, Lei Shu, Zhenping Wu, Bo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0203552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Bipolar Dual&#8208;Active Sites through High&#8208;Entropy&#8208;Induced Electric Dipole Transition for Decoupling Oxygen Redox</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202401018</link>
      <description>Q. Zhang, Zhiyang Zheng, Runhua Gao, Xiao Xiao, Menggai Jiao, Boran Wang, Guangmin Zhou, Hui&#8211;Ming Cheng, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394720272

                Abstract It remains a significant challenge to construct active sites to break the trade&#8208;off between oxidation and reduction processes occurring in battery cathodes with conversion mechanism, especially for the oxygen reduction and evolution reactions (ORR/OER) involved in the Zinc&#8208;air batteries (ZABs). Here, we propose using a high&#8208;entropy&#8208;driven electric dipole transition strategy to activate and stabilize the tetrahedral sites, while enhancing the activity of octahedral sites through orbital hybridization in a FeCoNiMnCrO spinel oxide, thus constructing bipolar dual&#8208;active sites with high&#8208;low valence states, which can effectively decouple ORR/OER. The FeCoNiMnCrO high&#8208;entropy spinel oxide (HESO) with severe lattice distortion, exhibits a strong 1s&#8594;4s electric dipole transition and intense t 2g (Co)/e g (Ni)&#8208;2p(O L ) orbital hybridization that regulates the electronic descriptors, e g and t 2g , which leads to the formation of low&#8208;valence Co tetrahedral sites (Co th ) and high&#8208;valence Ni octahedral sites (Ni oh ), resulting in a higher half&#8208;wave potential of 0.87 V on Co th sites and a lower overpotential of 0.26 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 on Ni oh sites as well as a superior performance of ZABs compared to low/mild entropy spinel oxides (L/MESO). Therefore, entropy engineering presents a distinctive approach for designing catalytic sites by inducing novel electromagnetic properties in materials across various electrocatalytic reactions, particularly for decoupling systems. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Q. Zhang, Zhiyang Zheng, Runhua Gao, Xiao Xiao, Menggai Jiao, Boran Wang, Guangmin Zhou, Hui&#8211;Ming Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202401018</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reply to three reviewers' comments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2023-2684-ac1</link>
      <description>Yele Sun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4394615643

                Abstract. Aerosol particles play crucial roles in both climate dynamics and human health. However, there remains a significant gap in our understanding of aerosol composition and evolution, particularly regarding secondary organic aerosols (SOA), and their interaction with clouds in high-altitude background areas in China. Here we conducted real-time measurements of submicron aerosols (PM1) using aerosol mass spectrometers at a forested mountain site (1128 m a.s.l.) in southeastern China in November 2022. Our results revealed that organic aerosol (OA) constituted a substantial portion of PM1 (41.1 %), with the OA being primarily of secondary origin, as evidenced by a high oxygen-to-carbon (O/C) ratio (0.85&#8211;0.96). Positive matrix factorization resolved two distinct SOA factors: less oxidized oxygenated OA (LO-OOA) and more oxidized OOA (MO-OOA). Interestingly, MO-OOA was scavenged efficiently during cloud events, while cloud evaporation contributed significantly to LO-OOA. The ratio of OA/&#916;CO increased with a decrease in the O/C ratio, suggesting that OA remaining in cloud droplets generally maintained a moderate oxidation state. Furthermore, our results indicated a higher contribution of organic nitrates to total nitrate during cloudy periods (27 %) compared to evaporative periods (3 %). Notably, a substantial contribution of nitrate in PM1 (20.9 %) was observed, particularly during high PM periods, implying that nitrate formed in polluted areas interacted with clouds and significantly impacted the regional background site. Overall, our study underscores the importance of understanding the dynamics of secondary organic aerosols and the impacts of cloud processing in regional mountainous areas in southeastern China.</description>
      <author>Yele Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2023-2684-ac1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical and Cellular Formation of Reactive Oxygen Species from Secondary Organic Aerosols in Epithelial Lining Fluid.</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4394766603</link>
      <description>Manabu Shiraiwa, Ting Fang, Jia Wang, Pascale S. J. Lakey, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang, K C Edwards, Shitij Kapur, Javier Mena, Yicheng Huang, Michelle A. Digman, Scott Weichenthal, Sergey A. Nizkorodov, Michael T. Kleinman, PubMed. None(215)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4394766603

                Oxidative stress mediated by reactive oxygen species (ROS) is a key process for adverse aerosol health effects. Secondary organic aerosols (SOA) account for a major fraction of particulate matter with aerodynamic diameter &#8804;2.5 &#181;m (PM2.5). PM2.5 inhalation and deposition into the respiratory tract causes the formation of ROS by chemical reactions and phagocytosis of macrophages in the epithelial lining fluid (ELF), but their relative contributions are not well quantified and their link to oxidative stress remains uncertain. The specific aims of this project were (1) elucidating the chemical mechanism and quantifying the formation kinetics of ROS in the ELF by SOA; (2) quantifying the relative importance of ROS formation by chemical reactions and macrophages in the ELF.SOA particles were generated using reaction chambers from oxidation of various precursors including isoprene, terpenes, and aromatic compounds with or without nitrogen oxides (NOx). We collected size-segregated PM at two highway sites in Anaheim, CA, and Long Beach, CA, and at an urban site in Irvine, CA, during two wildfire events. The collected particles were extracted into water or surrogate ELF that contained lung antioxidants. ROS generation was quantified using electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy with a spin-trapping technique. PM oxidative potential (OP) was also quantified using the dithiothreitol assay. In addition, kinetic modeling was applied for analysis and interpretation of experimental data. Finally, we quantified cellular superoxide release by RAW264.7 macrophage cells upon exposure to quinones and isoprene SOA using a chemiluminescence assay as calibrated with an EPR spin-probing technique. We also applied cellular imaging techniques to study the cellular mechanism of superoxide release and oxidative damage on cell membranes.Superoxide radicals (&#183;O2-) were formed from aqueous reactions of biogenic SOA generated by hydroxy radical (&#183;OH) photooxidation of isoprene, &#946;-pinene, &#945;-terpineol, and d-limonene. The temporal evolution of &#183;OH and &#183;O2- formation was elucidated by kinetic modeling with a cascade of aqueous reactions, including the decomposition of organic hydroperoxides (ROOH), &#183;OH oxidation of primary or secondary alcohols, and unimolecular decomposition of &#945;-hydroxyperoxyl radicals. Relative yields of various types of ROS reflected the relative abundance of ROOH and alcohols contained in SOA, which generated under high NOx conditions, exhibited lower ROS yields. ROS formation by SOA was also affected by pH. Isoprene SOA had higher &#183;OH and organic radical yields at neutral than at acidic pH. At low pH &#183;O2- was the dominant species generated by all types of SOA. At neutral pH, &#945;-terpineol SOA exhibited a substantial yield of carbon-centered organic radicals (R&#183;), while no radical formation was observed by aromatic SOA.Organic radicals in the ELF were formed by mixtures of Fe2+ and SOA generated from photooxidation of isoprene, &#945;-terpineol, and toluene. The molar yields of organic radicals by SOA were 5-10 times higher in ELF than in water. Fe2+ enhanced organic radical yields by a factor of 20-80. Ascorbate mediated redox cycling of iron ions and sustained organic peroxide decomposition, as supported by kinetic modeling reproducing time- and concentration-dependence of organic radical formation, as well as by additional experiments observing the formation of Fe2+ and ascorbate radicals in mixtures of ascorbate and Fe3+. &#183;OH and superoxide were found to be efficiently scavenged by antioxidants.Wildfire PM mainly generated &#183;OH and R&#183; with minor contributions from superoxide and oxygen-centered organic radicals (RO&#183;). PM OP was high in wildfire PM, exhibiting very weak correlation with radical forms of ROS. These results were in stark contrast with PM collected at highway and urban sites, which generated much higher amounts of radicals dominated by &#183;OH radicals that correlated well with OP. By combining field measurements of size-segregated chemical composition, a human respiratory tract model, and kinetic modeling, we quantified production rates and concentrations of different types of ROS in different regions of the ELF by considering particle-size-dependent respiratory deposition. While hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) and &#183;O2- production were governed by Fe and Cu ions, &#183;OH radicals were mainly generated by organic compounds and Fenton-like reactions of metal ions. We obtained mixed results for correlations between PM OP and ROS formation, providing rationale and limitations of the use of oxidative potential as an indicator for PM toxicity in epidemiological and toxicological studies.Quinones and isoprene SOA activated nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide phosphate (NADPH) oxidase in macrophages, releasing massive amounts of superoxide via respiratory burst and overwhelming the superoxide formation by aqueous chemical reactions in the ELF. The threshold dose for macrophage activation was much smaller for quinones compared with isoprene SOA. The released ROS caused lipid peroxidation to increase cell membrane fluidity, inducing oxidative damage and stress. Further increases of doses led to the activation of antioxidant response elements, reducing the net cellular superoxide production. At very high doses and long exposure times, chemical production became comparably important or dominant if the escalation of oxidative stress led to cell death.The mechanistic understandings and quantitative information on ROS generation by SOA particles provided a basis for further elucidation of adverse aerosol health effects and oxidative stress by PM2.5. For a comprehensive assessment of PM toxicity and health effects via oxidative stress, it is important to consider both chemical reactions and cellular processes for the formation of ROS in the ELF. Chemical composition of PM strongly influences ROS formation; further investigations are required to study ROS formation from various PM sources. Such research will provide critical information to environmental agencies and policymakers for the development of air quality policy and regulation.</description>
      <author>Manabu Shiraiwa, Ting Fang, Jia Wang, Pascale S. J. Lakey, Bing&#8208;Joe Hwang, K C Edwards, Shitij Kapur, Javier Mena, Yicheng Huang, Michelle A. Digman, Scott Weichenthal, Sergey A. Nizkorodov, Michael T. Kleinman</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4394766603</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
