<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 01:08:36 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Sustainable Enabling of Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101150584</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4399347332

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101150584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy Generation and Stabilization in Layered NiFeCo Double Hydroxide Nanosheets for a Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01840</link>
      <description>Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Lemma Teshome Tufa, Mahendra Goddati, Youngseok Lee, Boka Fikadu Banti, Njemuwa Nwaji Njoku, S. J. You, Jaebeom Lee, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399282865

                Oxygen vacancy (Vo) is ubiquitous, playing a critical role in tuning the electronic configuration and optimizing the adsorption of adsorbates in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process. However, fine control over the density and stabilization of Vo is a big challenge in the highly oxidizing environment of OER. Herein, we have fabricated bulk NiFeCo (layered double hydroxide) LDHs via the hydrothermal method and exfoliated them into thin sheets rich with Vo using high-energy Ar-plasma. We doped fluoride to simultaneously modulate the charge distribution of surrounding atoms and stabilize Vo by taking advantage of the extremely high electronegativity and similar ion diameter to oxygen of fluoride. The material exhibited OER activity with a low overpotential of 200 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 34.6 mV dec&#8211;1. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations support the claim that Vo and fluoride substantially increase NiFeCo LDH OER activity by modifying the electronic structures of the catalytically active sites.</description>
      <author>Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Lemma Teshome Tufa, Mahendra Goddati, Youngseok Lee, Boka Fikadu Banti, Njemuwa Nwaji Njoku, S. J. You, Jaebeom Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen evolution reaction through self-reconstruction of 2D nanoarrays on nickel foam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141389</link>
      <description>Xue Li, Dangcheng Su, Jianjun Chen, Bingbing Fan, Rui Zhang, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399285934

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Li, Dangcheng Su, Jianjun Chen, Bingbing Fan, Rui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141389</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Mn3Ce2O5&#8208;Cluster Mimicking the Oxygen&#8208;Evolving Center in Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401031</link>
      <description>Yang Chen, Yao Su, Juanjuan Han, Changhui Chen, Hongjun Fan, Changsheng Zhang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399290354

                The photosynthetic oxygen&#8208;evolving center (OEC) is a unique Mn4CaO5&#8208;cluster that catalyzes water splitting into electrons, protons, and dioxygen. Precisely structural and functional mimicking of the OEC is a long&#8208;standing challenge and pressingly needed for understanding the structure&#8208;function relationship and catalytic mechanism of O&#8208;O bond formation. Herein we report two simple and robust artificial Mn3Ce2O5&#8208;complexes that display a remarkable structural similarity to the OEC in regarding of the ten&#8208;atom core (five metal ions and five oxygen bridges) and the alkyl carboxylate peripheral ligands. This Mn3Ce2O5&#8208;cluster can catalyze the water&#8208;splitting reaction on the surface of ITO electrode. These results clearly show that cerium can structurally and functionally replace both calcium and manganese in the cluster. Mass spectroscopic measurements demonstrate that the oxide bridges in the cluster are exchangeable and can be rapidly replaced by the isotopic oxygen of H218O in acetonitrile solution, which supports that the oxide bridge(s) may serve as the active site for the formation of O&#8208;O bond during the water&#8208;splitting reaction. These results would contribute to our understanding of the structure&#8208;reactivity relationship of both natural and artificial clusters and shed new light on the development of efficient water&#8208;splitting catalysts in artificial photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Yang Chen, Yao Su, Juanjuan Han, Changhui Chen, Hongjun Fan, Changsheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-7</link>
      <description>Guangfu Li, Shichun Mu, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399290556

                The large-scale production of green hydrogen by proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis is currently of considerable interest. However, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) occurring in the anode is a primary source of overpotential due to the sluggish kinetics. To realize fast reaction kinetics, it is essential to obtain a facile electron transfer between electrocatalysts and the oxygen intermediates, which is critically related to reaction mechanism and electrode interface. Meanwhile, developing high-performance electrocatalysts for acidic OER is an outstanding challenge since most metal materials are unstable under the strong acidic and oxidative conditions. Even for the promising electrocatalyst candidates, Ir oxides undergo the continuous Ir dissolution due to surface oxidization during OER [1,2]. It is also difficult to establish the structure&#8211;performance relationship due to the dynamic changes of catalyst surface (named surface reconstruction). Hence, acquiring an enhanced understanding of the electron transfer pathways and reaction interface is crucial for the design of efficient and robust OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Guangfu Li, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Ni decorated MoOx nanorod catalysts for efficient overall urea&#8211;water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0206432</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Li, Wulin Yang, Kun Xiong, J CHEN, Haidong Zhang, Mingbo Yang, Xuewei Gan, Yuan Gao, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399300065

                Substituting slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with thermodynamically favorable urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is considered as one of the feasible strategies for achieving energy-saving hydrogen production. Herein, a uniform layer of NiMoO4 nanorods was grown on nickel foam by a hydrothermal method. Then, a series of Ni-MoOx/NF-X nanorod catalysts comprising Ni/NiO and MoOx (MoO2/MoO3) were prepared through regulating annealing atmosphere and reduction temperature. The optimized Ni-MoOx/NF-3 with a large accessible specific area can act as a bifunctional catalyst for electrocatalytic anodic UOR and cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). At a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2, the introduction of urea can significantly reduce the overpotential of Ni-MoOx/NF-3 by 210 mV compared to OER. In addition, Ni-MoOx/NF-3 has a higher intrinsic activity than other catalysts. It only requires &#8722;0.21 and 1.38 V to reach 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in HER and UOR, respectively. Such an excellent performance can be attributed to the synergistic function between Ni and MoOx. The presence of metallic Ni and reduced MoOx in pairs is beneficial for improving the electrical conductivity and modulating the electronic structure, resulting in enhancing the electrocatalytic performance. When assembling Ni-MoOx/NF-3 into an overall urea&#8211;water splitting system, it can achieve energy-saving hydrogen production and effective removal of urea-rich wastewater.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Li, Wulin Yang, Kun Xiong, J CHEN, Haidong Zhang, Mingbo Yang, Xuewei Gan, Yuan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0206432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Janus dual-atom catalyst for electrocatalytic oxygen reduction and evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00545-1</link>
      <description>Bing Tang, Yanan Zhou, Qianqian Ji, Zechao Zhuang, Lei Zhang, Chao Wang, Haibo Hu, Huijuan Wang, Bingbao Mei, Fei Song, Shuang Yang, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Hao Tan, Dingsheng Wang, Wensheng Yan, Nature synthesis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399300303

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Tang, Yanan Zhou, Qianqian Ji, Zechao Zhuang, Lei Zhang, Chao Wang, Haibo Hu, Huijuan Wang, Bingbao Mei, Fei Song, Shuang Yang, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Hao Tan, Dingsheng Wang, Wensheng Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00545-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Surface Reconstruction of Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-8</link>
      <description>Mengxin Chen, Pengyun Xu, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301995

                Along with the intensified global energy crisis and climate change, it is particularly crucial to accelerate the transformation of the energy structure and gradually increase the percentage of new energy. Currently, electrochemical water splitting is widely regarded as one of the most promising hydrogen production technologies, with considerable implications for tackling the challenge of global warming and achieving the goal of "carbon neutrality". The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a crucial anode reaction for water splitting, metal-air batteries, and renewable fuel cells. However, the OER process contains four proton&#8211;electron transfer steps, resulting in a slow kinetics, which has long been the bottleneck. In general, noble metals and their oxides (RuO2 and IrO2) are considered to be promising catalysts for OER, but the high price and scarce resources restrict their wide-scale application. Hence, it is crucial to develop low-cost, high-activity and stable catalysts for improving the efficiency of water splitting. Recently, significant attention has been dedicated to non-noble transition metal materials as promising alternatives for water splitting. Gaining a comprehensive understanding of the intrinsic catalytic mechanism and identifying the active sites of catalysts will greatly benefit the rational design and effective application of high-efficiency catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mengxin Chen, Pengyun Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-protecting CoFeAl-layered double hydroxides enable stable and efficient brine oxidation at 2 A cm&#8722;2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49195-z</link>
      <description>Wei Liu, Jiage Yu, Tianshui Li, Shihang Li, Biao Ding, Xiaoxiao Guo, Ang Cao, Qihao Sha, Daojin Zhou, Yun Kuang, Xiaoming Sun, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399302363

                Abstract Low-energy consumption seawater electrolysis at high current density is an effective way for hydrogen production, however the continuous feeding of seawater may result in the accumulation of Cl &#8722; , leading to severe anode poisoning and corrosion, thereby compromising the activity and stability. Herein, CoFeAl layered double hydroxide anodes with excellent oxygen evolution reaction activity are synthesized and delivered stable catalytic performance for 350 hours at 2 A cm &#8722;2 in the presence of 6-fold concentrated seawater. Comprehensive analysis reveals that the Al 3+ ions in electrode are etched off by OH &#8722; during oxygen evolution reaction process, resulting in M 3+ vacancies that boost oxygen evolution reaction activity. Additionally, the self-originated Al(OH) n &#8722; is found to adsorb on the anode surface to improve stability. An electrode assembly based on a micropore membrane and CoFeAl layered double hydroxide electrodes operates continuously for 500 hours at 1 A cm &#8722;2 , demonstrating their feasibility in brine electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Wei Liu, Jiage Yu, Tianshui Li, Shihang Li, Biao Ding, Xiaoxiao Guo, Ang Cao, Qihao Sha, Daojin Zhou, Yun Kuang, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49195-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co/Ce-MOF-Derived Oxygen Electrode Bifunctional Catalyst for Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00787</link>
      <description>Kang Wu, Daomiao Wang, Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Qihua Xiong, Shaik Gouse Peera, Chao Liu, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399302485

                Improving the practicality of rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries relies heavily on the development of oxygen electrode catalysts that are low-cost, durable, and highly efficient in performing dual functions. In the present study, a catalyst with atomic Ce and Co distribution on a nitrogen-doped carbon substrate was prepared by doping the rare earth elements Ce and Co into a metal&#8211;organic framework precursor. Rare earth element Ce, known for its unique structure and excellent oxygen affinity, was utilized to regulate the catalytic activity. The catalyst prepared in this study demonstrated an exceptional electrocatalytic performance. At a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2, the catalyst exhibited an overpotential of 340 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which was lower than that of commercial IrO2 (370 mV), while achieving a half-wave potential of 0.79 V for the process of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), exhibiting a similar level of effectiveness as commercially accessible Pt/C catalysts (0.8 V). The catalyst's porous structure, interconnected three-dimensional carbon network, and large specific surface area are the factors contributing to the significant improvement in catalytic performance. Furthermore, in comparison to commercial Pt/C+IrO2, the catalyst exhibited good cycling stability and high efficiency in rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Kang Wu, Daomiao Wang, Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Qihua Xiong, Shaik Gouse Peera, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal-Based Polyoxometalates for Oxygen Electrode Bifunctional Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10060197</link>
      <description>Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Filipe M. B. Gusm&#227;o, Sara Kne&#382;evi&#263;, Nemanja Gavrilov, Anup Paul, Diogo M.F. Santos, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Batteries. 10(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399304301

                Polyoxometalates (POMs) with transition metals (Co, Cu, Fe, Mn, Ni) of Keggin structure and lamellar-stacked multi-layer morphology were synthesized. They were subsequently explored as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen electrodes, i.e., oxygen reduction (ORR) and evolution (OER) reaction, for aqueous rechargeable metal-air batteries in alkaline media. The lowest Tafel slope (85 mV dec&#8722;1) value and the highest OER current density of 93.8 mA cm&#8722;2 were obtained for the Fe-POM electrocatalyst. Similar OER electrochemical catalytic activity was noticed for the Co-POM electrocatalyst. This behavior was confirmed by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy, where Fe-POM gave the lowest charge transfer resistance of 3.35 &#937;, followed by Co-POM with Rct of 15.04 &#937;, during the OER. Additionally, Tafel slope values of 85 and 109 mV dec&#8722;1 were calculated for Fe-POM and Co-POM, respectively, during the ORR. The ORR at Fe-POM proceeded by mixed two- and four-electron pathways, while ORR at Co-POM proceeded exclusively by the four-electron pathway. Finally, capacitance studies were conducted on the synthesized POMs.</description>
      <author>Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Filipe M. B. Gusm&#227;o, Sara Kne&#382;evi&#263;, Nemanja Gavrilov, Anup Paul, Diogo M.F. Santos, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10060197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Trends and Perspectives in Single-Entity Electrochemistry: A Review with Focus on a Water Splitting Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10408347.2024.2358492</link>
      <description>A. Gowrisankar, Byung Kwon Kim, Critical reviews in analytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399304430

                Electrochemical measurements involving single nanoparticles have attracted considerable research attention. In recent years, various studies have been conducted on single-entity electrochemistry (SEE) for the in-depth analyses of catalytic reactions. Although, several electrocatalysts have been developed for H2 energy production, designing innovative electrocatalysts for this purpose remains a challenging task. Stochastic collision electrochemistry is gaining increased attention because it has led to new findings in the SEE field. Importantly, it facilitates establishing structure activity relationships for electrocatalysts by monitoring transient signals. This article reviews the recent achievements related to hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) using different electrocatalysts at the nanoscale level. In particular, it discusses the electrocatalytic activities of noble metal nanoparticles, including Ag, Au, Pt, and Pd nanoparticles, at the single-particle level. Because heterogeneity is a key factor affecting the catalytic activity of nanostructures, our work focuses on the influence of heterogeneities in catalytic materials on the OER and HER activities. These results may help to achieve a better understanding of the fundamental processes involved in the water splitting reaction.</description>
      <author>A. Gowrisankar, Byung Kwon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/10408347.2024.2358492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Active Sites of Nanosheet NiSe/NiSe2 Catalyst by Pulse Electrodeposition on the 3D Microporous Ni-Cu/NF Substrate for both Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad5381</link>
      <description>Nafise Modghan, Mostafa Mirjalili, Mohammad Hadi Moayed, Ghasem Barati Darband, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399305499

                Abstract Establishing proper intrinsic catalysts with nanostructured high active surfaces endows the paramount electrocatalytic activity. A Ni-Se@Cu-Ni/NF catalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER) is prepared via an efficient two-step pulse current (PC) electrodeposition method. The initial 3D film of Cu-Ni is synthesized via the dynamic hydrogen bubble template (DHBT) method to attain further active surface area. Then, Ni-Se film is prepared by direct current (DC) and PC electrodeposition. Morphological, chemical, and electrocatalytic characteristics of the Ni-Se electrodeposited films are evaluated. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and high-resolution transmission electron microscopy results show a NiSe/NiSe2 nanofilm on the 3D microporous nanostructured Cu-Ni substrate which reveals an efficient bifunctional electrocatalytic behavior with overpotentials of 74 and 272 mV in the current density of 10 mA cm-2, and Tafel slopes of 78 and 50 mV dec-1 for HER and OER, respectively. The two-electrode examination with NiSe/NiSe2@Cu-Ni/NF catalyst in overall water splitting indicates a required potential of 1.57 V in the current density of 10 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Nafise Modghan, Mostafa Mirjalili, Mohammad Hadi Moayed, Ghasem Barati Darband</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad5381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pourbaix Machine Learning Framework Identifies Acidic Water Oxidation Catalysts Exhibiting Suppressed Ruthenium Dissolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01353</link>
      <description>Jehad Abed, Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Ming Ronnier Luo, Wajdi Alnoush, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Jian Wang, Jigang Zhou, Daojin Zhou, Khalid Fatih, John R. Kitchin, Drew Higgins, Zachary W. Ulissi, Edward H. Sargent, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399305702

                The demand for green hydrogen has raised concerns over the availability of iridium used in oxygen evolution reaction catalysts. We identify catalysts with the aid of a machine learning-aided computational pipeline trained on more than 36,000 mixed metal oxides. The pipeline accurately predicts Pourbaix decomposition energy (Gpbx) from unrelaxed structures with a mean absolute error of 77 meV per atom, enabling us to screen 2070 new metallic oxides with respect to their prospective stability under acidic conditions. The search identifies Ru0.6Cr0.2Ti0.2O2 as a candidate having the promise of increased durability: experimentally, we find that it provides an overpotential of 267 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 and that it operates at this current density for over 200 h and exhibits a rate of overpotential increase of 25 &#956;V h&#8211;1. Surface density functional theory calculations reveal that Ti increases metal&#8211;oxygen covalency, a potential route to increased stability, while Cr lowers the energy barrier of the HOO* formation rate-determining step, increasing activity compared to RuO2 and reducing overpotential by 40 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 while maintaining stability. In situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy and ex situ ptychography-scanning transmission X-ray microscopy show the evolution of a metastable structure during the reaction, slowing Ru mass dissolution by 20&#215; and suppressing lattice oxygen participation by &gt;60% compared to RuO2.</description>
      <author>Jehad Abed, Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Ming Ronnier Luo, Wajdi Alnoush, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Jian Wang, Jigang Zhou, Daojin Zhou, Khalid Fatih, John R. Kitchin, Drew Higgins, Zachary W. Ulissi, Edward H. Sargent</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green reaction engineering towards an iron-based nanostructured hybrid as an electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01193g</link>
      <description>Anna Dymerska, Ewa Mijowska, F. G. Vagizov, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Rustem Zairov, Ewa Mijowska, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399309285

                Developing robust electrocatalysts based on nonprecious metals with high activity in the sluggish oxygen-evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for achieving large-scale hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Anna Dymerska, Ewa Mijowska, F. G. Vagizov, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Rustem Zairov, Ewa Mijowska</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01193g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Ternary Layered Double Hydroxide Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalyst for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3365/kjmm.2024.62.6.472</link>
      <description>Seungjun Myeong, Song Jin, Chiho Kim, Jooyoung Lee, Jae Won Kim, Minseok Choi, Daehan geumsog jae'lyo haghoeji/Daehan geumsok jaeryo hakoeji. 62(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399313073

                To achieve net zero emissions, green hydrogen should be produced via water electrolysis with renewable energy. To develop efficient anion exchange membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWE), the development of efficient and stable non-precious metal electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential. In this study, a high-performance ternary NiFeCo-layer double hydroxide (LDH) electrocatalyst for AEMWE was easily developed by the co-precipitation method. The introduction of Co has been shown to have an effect on the electronic structure of Ni and Fe, improving their intrinsic OER properties. In addition, the three-dimensional flower-like nanosheet morphology improved mass transfer and achieved excellent current density at high voltages. The ternary NiFeCo-LDH electrocatalyst requires low overpotentials (253 mV at 10 mA cm-2) and Tafel slope (45 mV dec-1) in 1 M KOH. AEMWE using the ternary NiFeCo-LDH electrocatalyst showed excellent electrolysis performance with a high current density of 2.27 A cm-2 at 1.8 V cell. Moreover, an energy conversion efficiency of 86.73 % was achieved during the durability test for 100 hours at a current density of 0.5 A cm-2. The performance of the AEMWE electrolyzer utilizing the ternary NiFeCo-LDH electrocatalyst surpassed that of previously reported AEMWE electrolyzers. This work reports a highly active OER electrocatalyst that could open numerous opportunities for the development of ternary LDH electrocatalysts in AEMWE.</description>
      <author>Seungjun Myeong, Song Jin, Chiho Kim, Jooyoung Lee, Jae Won Kim, Minseok Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3365/kjmm.2024.62.6.472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Titanate&#8211;Phosphorous-Doped g-C3N4 Heterostructure with Impressive Electrocatalytic Activity for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11148-z</link>
      <description>Rekha Muthuvel, Mukul Sethi, L. Cindrella, Journal of electronic materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399322660

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rekha Muthuvel, Mukul Sethi, L. Cindrella</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11148-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple and Scalable Synthetic Route for Tunable Compositions of Multimetallic Oxyfluorides as Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00259</link>
      <description>Alexandre Terry, Samuel Mathiot, Amandine Guiet, &#201;douard Boivin, Zahra Goharibajestani, Vincent Maisonneuve, Annie H&#233;mon&#8208;Ribaud, Romain Moury, Nikolay Kornienko, J&#233;r&#244;me Lhoste, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399323479

                This work suggests a simple and scalable synthetic route to prepare multimetallic oxyfluorides, without requiring high temperature, high pressure, and a specific atmosphere (F2, N2, Ar, vacuum, etc.). For that, tunable compositions of Ni2+&#8211;Co2+&#8211;Fe3+-based oxyfluorides Co(1&#8211;x)/2Nix/2Fe0.5O0.5F1.5 have been prepared by calcination at moderate temperature under ambient air of Co1&#8211;xNixFeF5(H2O)7 precursors, prepared beforehand through coprecipitation at room temperature, across the whole range of the solid solution (0 &#8804; x &#8804; 1). Structural and thermal analyses confirmed the successful substitution for both hydrated fluoride precursors and oxyfluorides. Finally, we evaluated the electrocatalytic performance of the different Ni2+&#8211;Co2+&#8211;Fe3+ oxyfluorides for oxygen evolution reaction. Among these, the trimetallic Co0.25Ni0.25Fe0.5O0.5F1.5 exhibits the lowest overpotential (290 and 370 mV respectively at 10 and 100 mA cm&#8211;2) and the highest specific activity (3.9 A m&#8211;2 at 1.53 V vs RHE). These results highlight the need for compositional tunability to maximize performance.</description>
      <author>Alexandre Terry, Samuel Mathiot, Amandine Guiet, &#201;douard Boivin, Zahra Goharibajestani, Vincent Maisonneuve, Annie H&#233;mon&#8208;Ribaud, Romain Moury, Nikolay Kornienko, J&#233;r&#244;me Lhoste</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Metal&#8208;Support Interaction Modulation between Pt Nanoclusters and Mn&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets through Oxygen Vacancy Control to Achieve High Activities for Acidic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402652</link>
      <description>Dan Hu, Yongjie Wang, Weiheng Chen, Zhongqing Jiang, Binglu Deng, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399330823

                Abstract The optimization of metal&#8208;support interactions is used to fabricate noble metal&#8208;based nanoclusters with high activity for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acid media. Specifically, the oxygen&#8208;defective Mn 3 O 4 nanosheets supported Pt nanoclusters of &#8776;1.71 nm in diameter (Pt/V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs) are synthesized through the controlled solvothermal reaction. The Pt/V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs show a superior activity and excellent stability for the HER in the acidic media. They only require an overpotential of 19 mV to drive &#8722;10 mA cm &#8722;2 and show negligible activity loss at &#8722;10 and &#8722;250 mA cm &#8722;2 for &gt;200 and &gt;60 h, respectively. Their Pt mass activity is 12.4 times higher than that of the Pt/C and even higher than those of many single&#8208;atom based Pt catalysts. DFT calculations show that their high HER activity arises mainly from the strong metal&#8208;support interaction between Pt and Mn 3 O 4 . It can facilitate the charge transfer from Mn 3 O 4 to Pt, optimizing the H adsorption on the catalyst surface and promoting the evolution of H 2 through the Volmer&#8211;Tafel mechanism. The oxygen vacancies in the V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs are found to be inconducive to the high activity of the Pt/V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs, highlighting the great importance to reduce the vacancy levels in V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs.</description>
      <author>Dan Hu, Yongjie Wang, Weiheng Chen, Zhongqing Jiang, Binglu Deng, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402652</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood&#8208;Structured Nanomaterials as Highly Efficient, Self&#8208;Standing Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402511</link>
      <description>Jianlin Huang, Zhikai Shi, Chengwei Mao, Gaixiu Yang, Yan Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399331219

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting (EWS) driven by renewable energy is widely considered an environmentally friendly and sustainable approach for generating hydrogen (H 2 ), an ideal energy carrier for the future. However, the efficiency and economic viability of large&#8208;scale water electrolysis depend on electrocatalysts that can efficiently accelerate the electrochemical reactions taking place at the two electrodes. Wood&#8208;derived nanomaterials are well&#8208;suited for serving as EWS catalysts because of their hierarchically porous structure with high surface area and low tortuosity, compositional tunability, cost&#8208;effectiveness, and self&#8208;standing integral electrode configuration. Here, recent advancements in the design and synthesis of wood&#8208;structured nanomaterials serving as advanced electrocatalysts for water splitting are summarized. First, the design principles and corresponding strategies toward highly effective wood&#8208;structured electrocatalysts (WSECs) are emphasized. Then, a comprehensive overview of current findings on WSECs, encompassing diverse structural designs and functionalities such as supported&#8208;metal nanoparticles (NPs), single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs), metal compounds, and heterostructured electrocatalysts based on engineered wood hosts are presented. Subsequently, the application of these WSECs in various aspects of water splitting, including the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), overall water splitting (OWS), and hybrid water electrolysis (HWE) are explored. Finally, the prospects, challenges, and opportunities associated with the broad application of WSECs are briefly discussed. This review aims to provide a comprehensive understanding of the ongoing developments in water&#8208;splitting catalysts, along with outlining design principles for the future development of WSECs.</description>
      <author>Jianlin Huang, Zhikai Shi, Chengwei Mao, Gaixiu Yang, Yan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Ligands Regulate the Redox Leveling Mechanism of the Oxygen-Evolving Complex of the Photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02926</link>
      <description>Jinchan Liu, Ke Yang, Zhuoran Long, William H. Armstrong, Gary W. Brudvig, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399332391

                Understanding how water ligands regulate the conformational changes and functionality of the oxygen-evolving complex (OEC) in photosystem II (PSII) throughout the catalytic cycle of oxygen evolution remains a highly intriguing and unresolved challenge. In this study, we investigate the effect of water insertion (WI) on the redox state of the OEC by using the molecular dynamics (MD) and quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) hybrid methods. We find that water binding significantly reduces the free energy change for proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) from Mn to Y</description>
      <author>Jinchan Liu, Ke Yang, Zhuoran Long, William H. Armstrong, Gary W. Brudvig, V&#237;ctor S. Batista</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;4&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;Materials Based on Mo and Mn Diatomic Co-Doping Were Used to Study Oxygen Evolution Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12677/japc.2024.132028</link>
      <description>&#39062; &#39038;, Wu li hua xue jin zhan. 13(02)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399349968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#39062; &#39038;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12677/japc.2024.132028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacancy Mediated Electrooxidation of 5&#8208;Hydroxymethyl Furfuryl Using Defect Engineered Layered Double Hydroxide Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400676</link>
      <description>Muhammad Zubair, Pavel M. Usov, Hiroyoshi Ohtsu, Jodie A. Yuwono, Carter S. Gerke, Gregory D. Foley, Haira G. Hackbarth, Richard F. Webster, Yintang Yang, William Hadinata Lie, Zhipeng Ma, Lars Thomsen, Masaki Kawano, Nicholas M. Bedford, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399355849

                Abstract Electrochemical biomass oxidation coupled with hydrogen evolution offers a promising route to generate value&#8208;added chemicals and clean energy. The complex adsorption behavior of 5&#8208;hydroxymethyl furfural (HMF) and hydroxyl ions (OH &#8722; ) on the electrocatalyst surface during HMF electrooxidation reaction (HMFOR) necessitates an in&#8208;depth understanding of active sites available for adsorption. Herein, oxygen vacancy (V O ) defects are introduced in NiFe layered double hydroxide (LDH) using Ce dopants to manipulate electronic structure. Synchrotron&#8208;based HE&#8208;XRD and XAS indicate negligible V O in La&#8208;doped NiFe while Ce doping leads to V O defects due to flexible Ce redox (Ce 3+ &#8596; Ce 4+ ). The V O &#8208;rich Ce&#8208;NiFe exhibits higher Faradic efficiency of &#8776;90% to produce 2,5&#8208;furan dicarboxylic acid (FDCA), far greater than &#8776;60% for NiFe V O in Ce&#8208;NiFe act as alternative active sites for OH &#8722; adsorption, hence reducing adsorption competition for the same metal sites. DFT calculation results corroborate experimental findings by showcasing that the presence of V O in Ce&#8208;NiFe manipulates the adsorption energies and facilitates the chemical adsorption OH &#8722; in V O to improve HMFOR. In situ HE&#8208;XRD derived pair distribution function coupled to RMC simulations confirm OH &#8722; trapping in V O and HMF adsorption on metal centers as evident by interlayer distance evolution. Taken together, this work showcases routes for dual&#8208;site electrocatalyst design for improved biomass electrooxidation.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Zubair, Pavel M. Usov, Hiroyoshi Ohtsu, Jodie A. Yuwono, Carter S. Gerke, Gregory D. Foley, Haira G. Hackbarth, Richard F. Webster, Yintang Yang, William Hadinata Lie, Zhipeng Ma, Lars Thomsen, Masaki Kawano, Nicholas M. Bedford</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400676</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering antibonding orbital occupancy of NiMoO4-supported Ru nanoparticles for enhanced chlorine evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.023</link>
      <description>D. W. Zhang, Haiming Gong, Tao Liu, Yuanyuan Wang, Panyong Kuang, Journal of colloid and interface science. 672(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399357409

                Chlorine evolution reaction (CER) is crucial for industrial-scale production of high-purity Cl2. Despite the development of classical dimensionally stable anodes to enhance CER efficiency, the competitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a barrier to achieving high Cl2 selectivity. Herein, a binder-free electrode, Ru nanoparticles (NPs)-decorated NiMoO4 nanorod arrays (NRAs) supported on Ti foam (Ru-NiMoO4/Ti), was designed for active CER in saturated NaCl solution (pH = 2). The Ru-NiMoO4/Ti electrode exhibits a low overpotential of 20 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 current density, a high Cl2 selectivity exceeding 90 %, and robust durability for 90 h operation. The marked difference in Tafel slopes between CER and OER indicates the high Cl2 selectivity and superior reaction kinetics of Ru-NiMoO4/Ti electrode. Further studies reveal a strong metal-support interaction (SMSI) between Ru and NiMoO4, facilitating electron transfer through the Ru&#8211;O bridge bond and increasing the Ru 3d&#8211;Cl 2p antibonding orbital occupancy, which eventually results in weakened Ru&#8211;Cl bonding, promoted Cl desorption, and enhanced Cl2 evolution. Our findings provide new insights into developing electrodes with enhanced CER performance through antibonding orbital occupancy engineering.</description>
      <author>D. W. Zhang, Haiming Gong, Tao Liu, Yuanyuan Wang, Panyong Kuang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.06.023</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Feasibility of Polaronic OER on the (110) Surface of Rutile TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400523</link>
      <description>Hori Pada Sarker, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Michal Bajdich, ChemPhysChem. 25(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399359402

                Abstract The front cover artwork is provided by Dr. Hori Pada Sarker from Dr. Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen's research group at the SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory. The image shows the generation of photoexcited carriers (electrons and holes) and the subsequent formation of hole polaron in rutile TiO 2 during oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Read the full text of the Research Article at 10.1002/cphc.202400060 .</description>
      <author>Hori Pada Sarker, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Michal Bajdich</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Powered Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion Enabled by a Multifunctional Carbon&#8208;Based Electrocatalyst and a Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401766</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Lei Shi, Huamei Xie, Ruilin Song, Dan Wang, Dong Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399359807

                Abstract Multifunctional electrocatalysts are required for diverse clean energy&#8208;related technologies (e.g., electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) and metal&#8211;air batteries). Herein, a nitrogen and fluorine co&#8208;doped carbon nanotube (NFCNT) is reported to simultaneously achieve multifunctional catalytic activities for CO 2 RR, oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Theoretical calculations reveal that the superior multifunctional catalytic activities of NFCNT are attributed to the synergistic effect of nitrogen and fluorine co&#8208;doping to induce charge redistribution and decrease the energy barrier of rate&#8208;determining step for different electrocatalytic reactions. Furthermore, the rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery (ZAB) with NFCNT electrode delivers a high peak power density of 230 mW cm &#8722;2 and superior durability over 100 cycles, outperforming the ZAB with Pt/C+RuO 2 based electrodes. More importantly, a self&#8208;driven CO 2 electrolysis unit powered by the as&#8208;assembled ZABs is developed, which achieves 80% CO Faraday efficiency and 60% total energy efficiency. This work provides a new insight into the exploration of highly efficient multifunctional carbon&#8208;based electrocatalysts for novel energy&#8208;related applications.</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Lei Shi, Huamei Xie, Ruilin Song, Dan Wang, Dong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanadium&#8208;Doped Heterogeneous Bimetallic Phosphides Derived from Layered Double Hydroxides for Saline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402250</link>
      <description>Yixuan Li, Jiahui Jiang, Qing Wu, Yi Feng, Zhongxu Chen, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Li Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399360497

                Abstract The development of energy&#8208; and time&#8208;saving synthetic methods to prepare bifunctional and high stability catalysts are vital for overall water splitting. Here, V&#8208;doped nickel&#8208;iron hydroxide precursor by etching NiFe foam (NFF) at room temperature with dual chloride solution (&#8220;NaCl&#8208;VCl3&#8221;), is obtained then phosphating to obtain V&#8208;Ni 2 P&#8208;FeP/NFF as efficient bifunctional (oxygen/hydrogen exchange reaction, OER/HER) electrocatalysts, denoted as NFF(V, Na)&#8208;P. The NFF(V, Na)&#8208;P requires only 185 and 117 mV overpotentials to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER and HER. When used as a catalyst for water splitting in a full cell, it can be stably sustained for more than 1000 h in alkaline brine electrolysis at both current densities of 100 and 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . In situ Raman analyses and density functional theory (DFT) show that the V&#8208;doping&#8208;induced surface remodeling generates hydroxyl oxides as the true catalytic active centers, which not only enhances the reaction kinetics, but also reduces the free energy change in the rate&#8208;determining step. This work provides a cost&#8208;effective substrate self&#8208;derivation method to convert commercial NFF into a powerful catalyst for electrolytic brine, offering a unique route to the development of efficient electrocatalysts for saline water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yixuan Li, Jiahui Jiang, Qing Wu, Yi Feng, Zhongxu Chen, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceria&#8208;Optimized Oxygen&#8208;Species Exchange in Hierarchical Bimetallic Hydroxide for Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202406682</link>
      <description>Li Guo, Zhuang Zhang, Zhaori Mu, Pengfei Da, An Li, Wei Shen, Yichao Hou, Pinxian Xi, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399360588

                Abstract The utilization of rare earth elements to regulate the interaction between catalysts and oxygen&#8208;containing species holds promising prospects in the field of oxygen electrocatalysis. Through structural engineering and adsorption regulation, it is possible to achieve high&#8208;performance catalytic sites with a broken activity&#8208;stability tradeoff. Herein, we fabricate a hierarchical CeO 2 /NiCo hydroxide for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This material exhibits superior overpotentials and enhanced stability. Multiple potential&#8208;dependent experiments reveal that CeO 2 promotes oxygen&#8208;species exchange, especially OH &#8722; ions, between catalyst and environment, thereby optimizing the redox transformation of hydroxide and the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates during OER. This is attributed to the reduction in the adsorption energy barrier of Ni to *OH facilitated by CeO 2 , particularly the near&#8208;interfacial Ni sites. The less&#8208;damaging adsorbate evolution mechanism and the CeO 2 hierarchical shell significantly enhance the structural robustness, leading to exceptional stability. Additionally, the observed &#8220;self&#8208;healing&#8221; phenomenon provides further substantiation for the accelerated oxygen exchange. This work provides a neat strategy for the synthesis of ceria&#8208;based complex hollow electrocatalysts, as well as an in&#8208;depth insight into the co&#8208;catalytic role of CeO 2 in terms of oxygen transfer. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Li Guo, Zhuang Zhang, Zhaori Mu, Pengfei Da, An Li, Wei Shen, Yichao Hou, Pinxian Xi, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202406682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block copolymer-mediated synthesis of TiO2/RuO2 nanocomposite for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09702-5</link>
      <description>Binod Raj KC, Dhananjay Kumar, Bishnu Prasad Bastakoti, Journal of materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399362951

                Abstract An amphiphilic block copolymer, poly (styrene-2-polyvinyl pyridine-ethylene oxide), was used as a structure-directing and stabilizing agent to synthesize TiO 2 /RuO 2 nanocomposite. The strong interaction of polymers with metal precursors led to formation of a porous heterointerface of TiO 2 /RuO 2 . It acted as a bridge for electron transport, which can accelerate the water splitting reaction. Scanning electron microscopy, energy-dispersive X -ray spectroscopy, transmission electron microscopy, and X -ray diffraction analysis of TiO 2 /RuO 2 samples revealed successful fabrication of TiO 2 /RuO 2 nanocomposites. The TiO 2 /RuO 2 nanocomposites were used to measure electrochemical water splitting in three-electrode systems in 0.1-M KOH. Electrochemical activities unveil that TiO 2 /RuO 2 -150 nanocomposites displayed superior oxygen evolution reaction activity, having a low overpotential of 260 mV with a Tafel slope of 80 mVdec &#8722;1 . Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Binod Raj KC, Dhananjay Kumar, Bishnu Prasad Bastakoti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09702-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pt Single Atoms on TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Can Catalyze Water Oxidation in Photoelectrochemical Experiments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03319</link>
      <description>Shi Wu, Wu Lu, Nikita Denisov, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Giorgio Zoppellaro, Xiaoyu Yang, Patrik Schmuki, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399380646

                Photoelectrochemical water splitting on n-type semiconductors is highly dependent on catalysis of the rate-determining reaction of O2 evolution. Conventionally, in electrochemistry and photoelectrochemistry O2 evolution is catalyzed by metal oxide catalysts like IrO2 and RuO2, whereas noble metals such as Pt are considered unsuitable for this purpose. However, our study finds that Pt, in its single-atom form, exhibits exceptional cocatalytic properties for photoelectrochemical water oxidation on a TiO2 photoanode, in contrast to Pt in a nanoparticle form. The decoration of Pt single atoms onto TiO2 yields a remarkable current density of 5.89 mA cm&#8211;2 at 1.23 VRHE, surpassing bare TiO2 (or Pt nanoparticle decorated TiO2) by 2.52 times. Notably, this enhancement remains consistent over a wide pH range. By accompanying theoretical work, we assign this significant enhancement to an improved charge transfer and separation efficiency along with accelerated kinetics in the oxygen evolution reaction facilitated by the presence of Pt single atoms on the TiO2 surface.</description>
      <author>Shi Wu, Wu Lu, Nikita Denisov, Zde&#328;&#283;k Ba&#271;ura, Giorgio Zoppellaro, Xiaoyu Yang, Patrik Schmuki</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c03319</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of High Entropy Alloys on a Metal&#8211;Organic Framework Approaching Active Oxygen Reduction Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01278</link>
      <description>Jing Liang, Yanling Ma, Yanjie Li, Wencong Zhang, Hao Hu, Jie Su, Zhenpeng Yao, Wenpei Gao, Wen Shang, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399380880

                High-entropy alloys (HEAs) have garnered considerable attention as promising nanocatalysts for effectively utilizing Pt in catalysis toward oxygen reduction reactions due to their unique properties. Nonetheless, there is a relative dearth of attention regarding the structural evolution of HEAs in response to electrochemical conditions. In this work, we propose a thermal reduction method to synthesize high entropy nanoparticles by leveraging the confinement effect and abundant nitrogen-anchored sites provided by pyrolyzed metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs). Notably, the prepared catalysts exhibit enhanced activity accompanied by structural reconstruction during electrochemical activation, approaching 1 order of magnitude higher mass activity compared to Pt/C in oxygen reduction. Atomic-scale structural characterization reveals that abundant defects and single atoms are formed during the activation process, contributing to a significant boost in the catalytic performance for oxygen reduction reactions. This study provides deep insights into surface reconstruction engineering during electrochemical operations, with practical implications for fuel cell applications.</description>
      <author>Jing Liang, Yanling Ma, Yanjie Li, Wencong Zhang, Hao Hu, Jie Su, Zhenpeng Yao, Wenpei Gao, Wen Shang, Tao Deng, Jianbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01278</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of N and S co-doped lignin-based porous carbon aerogels loaded with FeCo alloys and their application to oxygen evolution and reduction reactions in Zn-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.132961</link>
      <description>Ying Han, Zihao Ma, Xing Wang, Guangwei Sun, International journal of biological macromolecules. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399382547

                Zn-air batteries are a highly promising clean energy sustainable conversion technology, and the design of dual-function electrocatalysts with excellent activity and stability is crucial for their development. In this work, FeCo alloy loaded biomass-based N and S co-doped carbon aerogels (FeCo@NS-LCA) were fabricated from chitosan and lignosulfonate-metal chelates via liquid nitrogen pre-frozen synergistic high-temperature carbonization with application in electrocatalytic reactions. The abundant oxygen-containing functional groups on lignosulfonates have a chelating effect on metal ions, which can avoid the aggregation of metal nanoparticles during carbonation and catalysis, facilitating the construction of a nanoconfinement catalytic system with biomass carbon as the domain-limiting body and FeCo nanoparticles as the active sites. FeCo@NS-LCA exhibited catalytic activity (E1/2 = 0.87 V, JL = 5.7 mA cm&#8722;2) comparable to the commercial Pt/C in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), excellent resistance to methanol toxicity and stability. Meanwhile, the overpotential of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) was 324 mV, close to that of commercial RuO2 catalysts (351 mV). This study utilizes the coordination action of lignosulfonate to provide a novel and environmentally friendly method for the preparation of confined nano-catalysts and provides a new perspective for the high-value utilization of biomass resources.</description>
      <author>Ying Han, Zihao Ma, Xing Wang, Guangwei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijbiomac.2024.132961</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Internal and External Low-Coordination Atoms in Nickel&#8211;Organic Framework Nanoarrays to Promote the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01086</link>
      <description>Shun Wang, Chong Lin, Xuetong Zhang, Yisheng Tan, B.L. Xiao, Yi Zeng, Jingyang Tian, Minghui Cao, Yuanping Jiang, Min Li, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399393923

                Monometallic nickel&#8211;organic frameworks based on a carboxylated ligand [2,6-naphthalenedicarboxylic acid (Ni-NDC)] have abundant and uniformly distributed single-atom Ni sites, enabling superior oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity. In theory, most of the Ni atoms inside Ni-NDC microcrystals are coordinatively saturated except for the surface. Therefore, there are no accessible low-coordination atoms (LCAs) as electrocatalytic sites for the OER. One effective way is to expose more LCAs by preparing self-supporting Ni-NDC nanoarrays (Ni-NDC NAs) with hierarchical secondary structural units. Another effective method is to create more internal LCAs by removing partial ligands or coordination atoms attached to the Ni atoms. Herein, by combining the two strategies, we engineered LCAs in the interior and exterior of Ni-NDC to synergistically accelerate the OER. In brief, ultrathick "brick-like" Ni-NDC NAs were first prepared with dissolution and coordination effects of NDC on self-sacrificial templates of "agaric-like" nickel hydroxide nanoarrays [Ni(OH)2 NAs]. Subsequently, dual-coordinated NDC was partially replaced by monocoordinated 2-naphthoic acid (NA). The Ni-NDC NAs were further tailed into ultrathin "liner leaf-like" nanoneedle arrays (LCAs-Ni-NDC NAs). As a consequence, the LCAs-Ni-NDC NAs have more internal and external LCAs, which can deliver an OER performance that is superior to that of Ni-NDC NAs.</description>
      <author>Shun Wang, Chong Lin, Xuetong Zhang, Yisheng Tan, B.L. Xiao, Yi Zeng, Jingyang Tian, Minghui Cao, Yuanping Jiang, Min Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c01086</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399455932

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399455934

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399455937

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399456113

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "3D flower-like bimetallic Ni&#8211;Co metal&#8211;organic framework as an electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399456174

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra02280g/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Oxidation Kinetics Through Electronic Structure Regulation of MnCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4.5&lt;/sub&gt;@Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; p&#8211;n Junction for Urea&#8208;Assisted Electrocatalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311548</link>
      <description>Sangeeta Adhikari, Stephan N. Steinmann, Maheswari Arunachalam, Soon Hyung Kang, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399462204

                Abstract A promising strategy to boost electrocatalytic performance is via assembly of hetero&#8208;nanostructured electrocatalysts that delivers the essential specific surface area and also active sites by lowering the reaction barrier. However, the challenges associated with the intricate designs and mechanisms remain underexplored. Therefore, the present study constructs a p&#8211;n junction in a free&#8208;standing MnCo 2 O 4.5 @Ni 3 S 2 on Ni&#8208;Foam. The space&#8208;charge region's electrical characteristics is dramatically altered by the formed p&#8211;n junction, which enhances the electron transfer process for urea&#8208;assisted electrocatalytic water splitting (UOR). The optimal MnCo 2 O 4.5 @Ni 3 S 2 electrocatalyst results in greater oxygen evolution reactivity (OER) than pure systems, delivering an overpotential of only 240 mV. Remarkably, upon employing as UOR electrode the required potential decreases to 30 mV. The impressive performance of the designed catalyst is attributed to the enhanced electrical conductivity, greater number of electrochemical active sites, and improved redox activity due to the junction interface formed between p&#8208;MnCo 2 O 4.5 and n&#8208;Ni 3 S 2 . There are strong indications that the in situ formed extreme&#8208;surface NiOOH, starting from Ni 3 S 2, boosts the electrocatalytic activity, i.e., the electrochemical surface reconstruction generates the active species. In conclusion, this work presents a high&#8208;performance p&#8211;n junction design for broad use, together with a viable and affordable UOR electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Sangeeta Adhikari, Stephan N. Steinmann, Maheswari Arunachalam, Soon Hyung Kang, Do&#8208;Heyoung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311548</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the effective ionic radii of trivalent dopants in ceria using a combination of dopants to improve catalytic efficiency for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03360d</link>
      <description>Debarati Das, Jyoti Prakash, Anisha Bandyopadhyay, Annu Balhara, U.K. Goutam, R. Acharya, Santosh K. Gupta, K. Sudarshan, RSC advances. 14(25)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399309847

                Matching effective ionic radii of trivalent dopants with the host through judicious choice of dopants and codopants has emerged as a smarter strategy for improving OER catalytic activity of ceria than individual ion doping.</description>
      <author>Debarati Das, Jyoti Prakash, Anisha Bandyopadhyay, Annu Balhara, U.K. Goutam, R. Acharya, Santosh K. Gupta, K. Sudarshan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03360d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of machine learning to discover new intermetallic catalysts for the hydrogen evolution and the oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00491d</link>
      <description>Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo, Benjamin M. Comer, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Kirsten T. Winther, J. Llorca, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399336542

                The adsorption energies for hydrogen, oxygen, and hydroxyl were calculated by means of density functional theory on the lowest energy surface of 24 pure metals and 332 binary intermetallic compounds...</description>
      <author>Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo, Benjamin M. Comer, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Kirsten T. Winther, J. Llorca</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00491d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Acidic Hydrogen Evolution through Pyrrolic Nitrogen-Doped Reduced Graphene Oxide Triggering Two-Electron Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01187b</link>
      <description>Zhiqiang Hou, Hui Jiang, Yafei Guo, Ke&#8208;Jing Huang, Fei Zhao, Yin Xu, Peng Peng, Shasha Zou, Juan Yan, Junjun Zhang, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399294549

                Developing cost-effective and efficient electrocatalysts is essential for addressing the slow kinetics and high overpotential in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), but significant challenges remain. Here, we fabricated the sandwich-structured...</description>
      <author>Zhiqiang Hou, Hui Jiang, Yafei Guo, Ke&#8208;Jing Huang, Fei Zhao, Yin Xu, Peng Peng, Shasha Zou, Juan Yan, Junjun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01187b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution of In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; by Decorating In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; with Rich Oxygen Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00720</link>
      <description>Changxue Dong, Qiuyan Chen, Xin Deng, Lan Jiang, Tianli Han, Yufeng Zhou, Jinwei Chen, Ruilin Wang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399331742

                The hydrogen (H2) evolution rates of photocatalysts suffer from weak oxidation and reduction ability and low photogenerated charge carrier separation efficiency. Herein, by combining band-gap structure optimization and vacancy modulation through a one-step hydrothermal method, In2O3 containing oxygen vacancy (Ov/In2O3) is simply introduced into In2S3 to promote photocatalytic hydrogen evolution. Specifically, the change in the sulfur source ratio can induce the coexistence of Ov/In2O3 and In2S3 in a high-temperature hydrothermal process. Under light irradiation, In2S3@Ov/In2O3-0.1 nanosheets hold a remarkable average H2 evolution rate up to 4.04 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1, which is 32.14, 11.91, and 2.25-fold better than those of pristine In2S3, In2S3@Ov/In2O3-0.02, and In2S3@Ov/In2O3-0.25 nanosheets, respectively. The ultraviolet&#8211;visible (UV&#8211;vis) diffuse reflectance and photoluminescence (PL) spectra reveal that the formation of Ov/In2O3 in In2S3 optimizes the band-gap structure and accelerates the migration of the photogenerated charge carrier of In2S3@Ov/In2O3-x nanosheets, respectively. Both the enhancement of oxidation and reduction ability and photogenerated charge carrier separation ability are responsible for the remarkable improvement in photocatalytic H2 evolution performance. This work provides a new strategy to prepare a composite of metal sulfide and metal oxide through a one-step hydrothermal method.</description>
      <author>Changxue Dong, Qiuyan Chen, Xin Deng, Lan Jiang, Tianli Han, Yufeng Zhou, Jinwei Chen, Ruilin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00720</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Non-Precious Metal-Based Electrodes for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-2</link>
      <description>Jiakai Bai, Pengxi Li, Dongwei Qiao, Xianming Yuan, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301694

                Owing to the proportional growing demand for clean and affordable energy, the production of hydrogen via electrolysis of water has seen significant advancements. This review summarizes recent progresses achieved in the area of non-precious metal-based electrodes that are being utilized for the electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline water electrolysis. Based on the HER and OER mechanisms, common strategies to improve the electrocatalytic performance are proposed.2.1 Introduction</description>
      <author>Jiakai Bai, Pengxi Li, Dongwei Qiao, Xianming Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the potential of a g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 ternary heterojunction photocatalyst for rechargeable zinc-air battery: Visible-light-driven photo-assisted charging for bifunctional ORR and OER at the air cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234795</link>
      <description>Amornrat Khampuanbut, Soorathep Kheawhom, Wathanyu Kao&#8208;ian, Wanwisa Limphirat, Hiroshi Uyama, Prasit Pattananuwat, Journal of power sources. 612(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399316435

                Advancements in solar-driven energy storage technology have been achieved for rechargeable zinc-air batteries (RZABs), facilitating accelerated kinetic responses in both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, we successfully synthesized a novel g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 ternary heterojunction through a facile hydrothermal process, demonstrating its efficacy as a bifunctional photocatalyst. Upon exposure to LED irradiation, this heterojunction triggers an effective separation of the photogenerated electron-hole pairs, resulting in enhanced oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance by 46.19 % and 65.69 % respectively, compared to non-LED conditions. Interestingly, the reduction in the potential gap under LED irradiation (0.06 V), correlating with a significant 2.71 % increase in round-trip efficiency (RTE), is observed. In addition, the optimized band alignment derived from g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 ternary heterojunction for photo-assisted charging rechargeable zinc-air batteries is proposed. Insightfully, photo-enhanced charging in RZABs mechanism during the charge/discharge process through in-situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) is monitored, confirming the large interaction between O2 adsorption and Bi 6d orbitals of g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 in the presence of LED. In conclusion, our innovative g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 ternary heterojunction underscores the significant role that visible-light-driven photocatalysts can play in enhancing the efficiency of rechargeable zinc-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Amornrat Khampuanbut, Soorathep Kheawhom, Wathanyu Kao&#8208;ian, Wanwisa Limphirat, Hiroshi Uyama, Prasit Pattananuwat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Device Architecture Strategies for Decoupled Water Splitting: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00745</link>
      <description>Asha Mathur, Charles E. Diesendruck, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399281979

                Electrochemical water-splitting processes are a safe, sustainable, and ecofriendly method to generate pure hydrogen, with minimal carbon emission. Typically, water reduction (hydrogen evolution) and oxidation (oxygen evolution) occur simultaneously, although such coupled processes lead to several limitations such as gas crossover, electrocatalyst degradation by reactive oxygen species, and more. This review presents several strategies to design decoupled water splitting devices, separating the two half-reactions spatially and temporally, to address several of these issues. The designs change according to the electrode materials, electrolyte, and decoupling strategy employed (redox mediator). The review describes how the decoupling mechanisms adopted affect different properties and lead to designs with optimal efficiency. It also focuses on their integration with renewable energy, which can be used to power each half-reaction independently. Lastly, the merits and constraints of the decoupled systems in addressing global environmental issues are discussed along with potential questions to further advance this technology-based strategy.</description>
      <author>Asha Mathur, Charles E. Diesendruck</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biochar Made from Luffa Cylindrica and Applied as Bifunctional Electrocatalyst in Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853912</link>
      <description>Natalia Tsoukala, Antonios N. Papadopoulos, Vasiliki Premeti, Alexandros K. Bikogiannakis, Eftychia Martino, Eleana Kordouli, &#922;aterina Govatsi, Ioannis D. Manariotis, Georgios Kyriakou, Dionissios Mantzavinos, Panagiotis Lianos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399343780

                Biochar has been prepared by pyrolysis of Luffa Cylindrica (the vegetable sponge produced by Luffa Aegiptiaca) and activated by mixing with KOH and a second pyrolysis step. Non-activated and activated biochar have both been structurally and then electrochemically characterized to record their differences and assess their suitability as bifunctional oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts in Zn-air batteries. Non activated biochar carries several functional groups; however, the activation procedure led to a material with mainly O and Mg groups. Biochar activation improved its electrocatalytic properties, but both activated and non-activated luffa biochar were functional as bifunctional electrocatalysts to a satisfactory degree. This is justified by the fact that both carried a large percentage of carbon and graphitic carbon. The advantage of the non-activated biochar versus the activated biochar was its variety of functional groups while that of the activated biochar was its large specific surface area.</description>
      <author>Natalia Tsoukala, Antonios N. Papadopoulos, Vasiliki Premeti, Alexandros K. Bikogiannakis, Eftychia Martino, Eleana Kordouli, &#922;aterina Govatsi, Ioannis D. Manariotis, Georgios Kyriakou, Dionissios Mantzavinos, Panagiotis Lianos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuNi Aerogels with Suppressed Water Activation for Efficient Nucleophilic Methanol Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01596</link>
      <description>Qie Fang, S. Ye, Lirong Zheng, Hengjia Wang, Lili Hu, Wenling Gu, Lijin Wang, Le Shi, Chengzhou Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301299

                Suppressing the competitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the critical prerequisite for efficient nucleophile oxidation in electrochemical biomass upgrading coupled with hydrogen production. Herein, Cu91Ni9 aerogels with atomically dispersed Ni are designed as effective nucleophile electrooxidation catalysts with significantly suppressed water activation performance, exhibiting a remarkable 99.3% Faradaic efficiency in the conversion of methanol to formic acid. Experimental and theoretical investigations reveal that the Cu support promotes the formation of Ni&#8211;O&#8211;Cu active pockets, where Ni3+ behaves as the main adsorbed sites and electrophilic lattice oxygen in Ni&#8211;O&#8211;Cu serves as a hydrogen acceptor, thus accelerating the electrochemical catalyst dehydrogenation reaction and the spontaneous nucleophilic dehydrogenation reaction. Furthermore, Cu integration exhibits weaker OER competition by inactivating the deprotonation capacity of OH* to O*, promoting the Faradaic efficiency of formic acid. This work paves the way for the development of advanced catalysts to achieve highly efficient biomass upgrading by modulating the OER activity.</description>
      <author>Qie Fang, S. Ye, Lirong Zheng, Hengjia Wang, Lili Hu, Wenling Gu, Lijin Wang, Le Shi, Chengzhou Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured Mnmoo4 as a Trifunctional Electrocatalyst for Overall Water Splitting and Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853666</link>
      <description>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399337243

                Electrochemical water splitting and CO2 reduction are important processes to produce hydrogen and low&#8211;carbon fuels as renewable energy sources. Here, nanostructured MnMoO4, prepared by the reflux precipitation method, was investigated as a trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions. Using a combination of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results, a direct band gap of 3.05 eV was obtained experimentally for the prepared MnMoO4. An overpotential of 0.36 V at a current density of 5 mA cm-2 and a Tafel slope of 58 mV dec-1 were obtained for the oxygen evolution reaction. At a current density of 3 mA cm-2, overpotentials of 0.39 V and 0.58 V were achieved in the absence and presence of CO2 bubbling into a 0.1 M KOH solution, respectively, emphasizing the poisoning effect of CO2 reduction intermediates for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Based on the obtained results, MnMoO4 could be a promising electrocatalyst for water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions.</description>
      <author>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing the Challenge of Electrochemical Ionomer Oxidation in Future Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00832</link>
      <description>Jihoon Lim, Jeffrey M. Klein, Seung Geol Lee, Eun Joo Park, Sun Young Kang, Sandip Maurya, William E. Mustain, Shannon W. Boettcher, Yu Seung Kim, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399299301

                Hydrogen production through anion-exchange membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWEs) offers cost advantages over proton-exchange membrane counterparts, mainly due to the good oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity of platinum-group-metal-free catalysts in alkaline environments. However, the electrochemical oxidation of ionomers at the OER catalyst interface can decrease the local electrode pH, which limits AEMWE performance. Various strategies at the single-cell-level have been explored to address this issue. This work reviews the current understanding of electrochemical ionomer oxidation and strategies to mitigate it, providing our perspective on each approach. Our analysis highlights the competitive adsorption strategy as particularly promising for mitigating ionomer oxidation. This Perspective also outlines future directions for advancing high-performance alkaline AEMWEs and other energy devices using hydrocarbon ionomers.</description>
      <author>Jihoon Lim, Jeffrey M. Klein, Seung Geol Lee, Eun Joo Park, Sun Young Kang, Sandip Maurya, William E. Mustain, Shannon W. Boettcher, Yu Seung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waxberry-Like Hydrophilic Co-Doped Znfe2o4 as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Water Splittingwaxberry-Like Hydrophilic Co-Doped Znfe2o4 as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853910</link>
      <description>Xiao Lyu, Yongbin Hu, Yun Han, Xuning Li, Yu Q, Bin Wen, Xin Zhao, Qi Dong, Aijun Du, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399347211

                The development of bifunctional electrocatalysts is challenging but desirable for the scale-up applications of water splitting. Nowadays transition metal oxides (TMOs) are considered as the promising electrocatalysts due to their low cost, structural flexibility and stability, however, their electrocatalytic activities are eager to be improved. Here, we synthesized waxberry-like hydrophilic Co-doped ZnFe2O4 electrocatalysts as bifunctional electrocatalysts for water splitting. Due to the enhanced active sites by morphology regulation and metallic doping strategy, the spinel ZFO-Co0.5 electrocatalyst exhibits excellent catalytic activities both on oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). It exhibits a remarkable low OER overpotential of 220 mV and a Tafel slope of 28.2 mV dec-1, surpassing the performance of commercial IrO2 electrocatalyst. Meanwhile, it achieves a low overpotential of 73 mV with the Tafel slope of 87 mV dec -1 for HER. In addition, water-splitting performance of ZFO-Co0.5||ZFO-Co0.5 surpasses that of commercial IrO2||Pt/C. Our work reveals that the hydrophilic morphology regulation combined with metallic doping strategy is a facile and effective approach to synthesize spinel TMOs as excellent bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Xiao Lyu, Yongbin Hu, Yun Han, Xuning Li, Yu Q, Bin Wen, Xin Zhao, Qi Dong, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free-Standing Electrodes and Catalysts for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-3</link>
      <description>Miao He, Fuyue Liu, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301864

                Free-standing electrocatalysts (FSECs) are a series of electrochemically active materials grown directly on a substrate with remarkable conductivity, sufficient porous structure, and high specific surface areas. The catalytic properties of FSECs toward both hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) for alkaline water electrolysis mainly depend on the substrates, active materials, and synthesis methods of FSECs. In this chapter, we first introduce the concepts, advantages, and relative mechanisms of FSECs. Then, the merits and applications of different substrates (such as the nickel foam and carbon fiber paper carbon cloth) for FSECs are summarized and introduced. Importantly, we reviewed the various active materials of FSECs for both HER and OER, including metals or alloys, transitional metal oxides, transitional metal sulfides, transition metal selenides, transition metal phosphides, transition metal carbides and nitrides, transition metal hydroxides/oxyhydroxides, and indicated their advantages and shortcomings. Lastly, some typical synthesis methods of FSECs are summarized and reviewed. This chapter can shed the light on the development of high-performance FSECs.</description>
      <author>Miao He, Fuyue Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-step Fabrication of P-Co5.47N/Co9S8@NPC Heterojunction Derived from Saccharomycetes Cerevisiae as Environment-Friendly Bifunctional High-efficiency Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134411</link>
      <description>Xinli Jing, Changwu Lv, Hongmei Zhang, Chu Chen, Zhaofeng Wu, Colloids and surfaces. A, Physicochemical and engineering aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399303052

                The one-step green preparation of heterojunction-structured bifunctional high-efficiency electrocatalysts provides a simple method for the green, low-cost, convenient and efficient application of hydrogen energy, meanwhile it is still challenging to achieve. In the present work, the phosphorus-doped two-phase heterojunction P-Co5.47N/Co9S8@NPC nanorods was synthesized on carbon cloth (CC) as a high-quality bifunctional electrode through simple one-step chemical vapor deposition (CVD) method. Saccharomycetes cerevisiae were used for the non-toxic phosphorus doping and formation of a carbon nanolayer wrapping Co5.47N/Co9S8 nanorods. Compared with the single-phase electrocatalyst Co9S8@NPC NSs/CC, P-Co5.47N/Co9S8@NPC NSs/CC exhibited more excellent electrocatalytic performance which required overpotentials of 69 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), 182.5 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), 1.45 V for over water splitting (OWS) at 10 mA cm-2 in KOH solution. The designed P-Co5.47N/Co9S8@NPC NSs/CC presented multiple advantages of nanorod structure, doped structure, abundant heterointerfaces, as well as dual-phase synergy, which triggered outstanding electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Xinli Jing, Changwu Lv, Hongmei Zhang, Chu Chen, Zhaofeng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Oxygen Vacancies in Phase Transition and the Optical Absorption Properties within Nanocrystalline ZrO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110967</link>
      <description>Jing Ouyang, Youming Peng, Wenting Zhou, Xianfeng Liang, G. Wang, Zeming Qi, Bo Yuan, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399304013

                Zirconia (ZrO2) nanoparticles were synthesized using a solvothermal method under varying synthesis conditions, namely acidic, neutral, and alkaline. X-ray diffraction (XRD) and field emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM) were leveraged to investigate the phase evolution and topographical features in detail. The resulting crystal phase structures and grain sizes exhibited substantial variation based on these conditions. Notably, the acidic condition fostered a monoclinic phase in ZrO2, while the alkaline condition yielded a combination of tetragonal and monoclinic phases. In contrast, ZrO2 obtained under neutral conditions demonstrated a refinement in grain sizes, constrained within a 1 nm scale upon an 800 &#176;C thermal treatment. This was accompanied by an important transformation from a monoclinic phase to tetragonal phase in the ZrO2. Furthermore, a rigorous examination of XPS data and a UV-visible spectrometer (UV-vis) analysis revealed the significant role of oxygen vacancies in phase stabilization. The notable emergence of new energy bands in ZrO2, in stark contrast to the intrinsic bands observed in a pure monoclinic sample, are attributed to these oxygen vacancies. This research offers valuable insights into the novel energy bands, phase stability, and optical absorption properties influenced by oxygen vacancies in ZrO2. Moreover, it proposes an innovative energy level model for zirconia, underpinning its applicability in diverse technological areas.</description>
      <author>Jing Ouyang, Youming Peng, Wenting Zhou, Xianfeng Liang, G. Wang, Zeming Qi, Bo Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the physiology of high-altitude flight and altitudinal migration in birds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/icb/icae062</link>
      <description>Catherine M. Ivy, Jessie L. Williamson, Integrative and comparative biology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399322452

                Abstract Many bird species fly at high altitudes for short periods and/or shift seasonally in altitude during migration, but little is known about the physiology of these behaviors. Transient high-altitude flight, or short-term flight at extreme altitudes, is a strategy used by lowland-native birds, often in the absence of topographic barriers. Altitudinal migration, or seasonal roundtrip movement in altitude between the breeding and non-breeding seasons, is a form of migration that occurs as a regular part of the annual cycle and results in periods of seasonal residency at high altitudes. Despite their nuanced differences, these two behaviors share a common challenge: Exposure to reduced oxygen environments during at least part of the migratory journey. In this perspective piece, we compare what is known about the physiology of oxygen transport during transient high-altitude flight and altitudinal migration by highlighting case studies and recent conceptual advances from work on captive and wild birds. We aim to open avenues for integrative research on the ecology, evolution, and physiology of high-flying and mountain-climbing birds.</description>
      <author>Catherine M. Ivy, Jessie L. Williamson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/icb/icae062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zircon compositional systematics from Devonian oxidized I-type granitoids: examination of porphyry Cu fertility indices in the New Brunswick Appalachians, Canada</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/feart.2024.1363029</link>
      <description>Fazilat Yousefi, David R. Lentz, Christopher R.M. McFarlane, James A. Walker, Kathleen G. Thorne, Frontiers in earth science. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301948

                Zircon is a common, widely distributed accessory mineral in most igneous rocks and its refractory nature records magmatic evolution in terms of oxygen and U-Th-Pb isotopes, and trace-element contents all of which reflect the intrinsic physio-chemical evolution of the magmatic systems in which it crystallized. Zircon compositions can be used as an indicator of relative fertility of hypabyssal intrusions in terms Cu &#177; Mo &#177; Au porphyry mineralization. To further characterize syn- to post-collisional adakitic Devonian oxidized I-type granitoids in the New Brunswick (specifically, those with Cu &#177; Mo &#177; Au porphyry-style mineralization), LA-ICP-MS analyses (guided by &#181;XRF-EDS mapping and SEM-BSE imaging of polished thin sections) of zircons from 13 granitoids was conducted. The zircons studied were similar in terms of their textures (homogenous cores, patchy zoning, oscillatory zoning, and some unzoned zircon); however, they have a wide range of trace- and minor-element (Hf, HREE, Y, Th, U) compositions. Specifically, Zr/Hf ranges between 24&#8211;60, whereas Th/U ranges between 0.15 and 5.37. The presence of inherited zircon affects the concentrations of Th and U, as well as other key elements. Estimated crystallization temperatures of granitoids, ranging from 737 to 899&#176;C, were calculated via Ti-in-zircon geothermometry assuming reduced TiO 2 and SiO 2 activities. The calculated log f O 2 values for zircons from some of these granitoids indicate a highly oxidized magmatic signature. Zr/Hf, Eu/Eu &#8270; , and (Eu/Eu &#8270; )/Y in zircon, as well as zircon (Ce/Nd)/Y are some of the best indicators of porphyry fertility. The Ce/Ce * in zircon exhibit a large range (1.1&#8211;590), with higher Ce/Ce * reflecting more metallogenically favourable oxidizing conditions. If Eu/Eu &#8270; in zircon is &#8805;0.4 (relatively oxidized conditions), it indicates a high potential for an ore-forming porphyry Cu mineralizing system. Lower Eu contents reflect relatively reducing conditions, as Eu anomalies vary with oxygen fugacity as well, and the relative abundance of Eu 2+ is higher, but does not substitute into the zircon lattice. The evidence extracted from analyzing the zircon composition within New Brunswick&#8217;s I-type granitoids indicates the fertility of these hypabyssal intrusions.</description>
      <author>Fazilat Yousefi, David R. Lentz, Christopher R.M. McFarlane, James A. Walker, Kathleen G. Thorne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/feart.2024.1363029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu doping in TM ordered and disordered layered oxides for Sodium-Ion Batteries: Electrochemical Properties, structure evolution and Cu-Ion migration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152788</link>
      <description>Jun Yan, Yin-Hui Peng, Yunbo Li, Hongyan Zhou, Jingjie Feng, Qinghua Fan, Quan Kuang, Youzhong Dong, Xiao&#8208;Bao Yang, Yanming Zhao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399302942

                The ordered/disordered distribution of transition metal (TM) plays a significant role in determining electrochemical properties including lattice oxygen redox, ion kinetics and structure evolution. From a novel perspective, this work demonstrates how the TM distributions influence the doping effect by means of introducing Cu element into ordered/disordered O3-Nax(NiySb1-y)O2. What's more, the irreversible Cu migration from TM sites to Na layers upon electrochemical process is found. This migration which would deteriorate electrochemical stability only occurs in honeycomb-ordered compounds, instead of in disordered one. Theoretical calculations reveal that the TM disordered distribution promotes the formation of antibonding orbitals between Cu 3d and O 2p, thereby increasing the barrier of Cu migration to maintain well Na diffusion kinetics. Our discovery rolls out a new guidance for designing advanced cathode materials for sodium-ion batteries and speeds up the research on transition metal migration.</description>
      <author>Jun Yan, Yin-Hui Peng, Yunbo Li, Hongyan Zhou, Jingjie Feng, Qinghua Fan, Quan Kuang, Youzhong Dong, Xiao&#8208;Bao Yang, Yanming Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photodynamic Therapy for Atherosclerosis: Past, Present, and Future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics16060729</link>
      <description>Yanqing Lin, Ruosen Xie, Yu Chen, Pharmaceutics. 16(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399288196

                This review paper examines the evolution of photodynamic therapy (PDT) as a novel, minimally invasive strategy for treating atherosclerosis, a leading global health concern. Atherosclerosis is characterized by the accumulation of lipids and inflammation within arterial walls, leading to significant morbidity and mortality through cardiovascular diseases such as myocardial infarction and stroke. Traditional therapeutic approaches have primarily focused on modulating risk factors such as hypertension and hyperlipidemia, with emerging evidence highlighting the pivotal role of inflammation. PDT, leveraging a photosensitizer, specific-wavelength light, and oxygen, offers targeted treatment by inducing cell death in diseased tissues while sparing healthy ones. This specificity, combined with advancements in nanoparticle technology for improved delivery, positions PDT as a promising alternative to traditional interventions. The review explores the mechanistic basis of PDT, its efficacy in preclinical studies, and the potential for enhancing plaque stability and reducing macrophage density within plaques. It also addresses the need for further research to optimize treatment parameters, mitigate adverse effects, and validate long-term outcomes. By detailing past developments, current progress, and future directions, this paper aims to highlight PDT&#8217;s potential in revolutionizing atherosclerosis treatment, bridging the gap from experimental research to clinical application.</description>
      <author>Yanqing Lin, Ruosen Xie, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics16060729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environment-Driven Variability in Absolute Band Edge Positions and Work Functions of Reduced Ceria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05053</link>
      <description>Xingfan Zhang, Christopher S. Blackman, Robert G. Palgrave, Sobia Ashraf, Avishek Dey, Matthew O. Blunt, Xu Zhang, Taifeng Liu, Shijia Sun, Lei Zhu, Jingcheng Guan, You L&#252;, Thomas W. Keal, John Buckeridge, C. Richard A. Catlow, Alexey A. Sokol, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399367657

                The absolute band edge positions and work function (&#934;) are the key electronic properties of metal oxides that determine their performance in electronic devices and photocatalysis. However, experimental measurements of these properties often show notable variations, and the mechanisms underlying these discrepancies remain inadequately understood. In this work, we focus on ceria (CeO2), a material renowned for its outstanding oxygen storage capacity, and combine theoretical and experimental techniques to demonstrate environmental modifications of its ionization potential (IP) and &#934;. Under O-deficient conditions, reduced ceria exhibits a decreased IP and &#934; with significant sensitivity to defect distributions. In contrast, the IP and &#934; are elevated in O-rich conditions due to the formation of surface peroxide species. Surface adsorbates and impurities can further augment these variabilities under realistic conditions. We rationalize the shifts in energy levels by separating the individual contributions from bulk and surface factors, using hybrid quantum mechanical/molecular mechanical (QM/MM) embedded-cluster and periodic density functional theory (DFT) calculations supported by interatomic-potential-based electrostatic analyses. Our results highlight the critical role of on-site electrostatic potentials in determining the absolute energy levels in metal oxides, implying a dynamic evolution of band edges under catalytic conditions.</description>
      <author>Xingfan Zhang, Christopher S. Blackman, Robert G. Palgrave, Sobia Ashraf, Avishek Dey, Matthew O. Blunt, Xu Zhang, Taifeng Liu, Shijia Sun, Lei Zhu, Jingcheng Guan, You L&#252;, Thomas W. Keal, John Buckeridge, C. Richard A. Catlow, Alexey A. Sokol</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration Construction of Hybrid Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reductions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404773</link>
      <description>Lei Huang, Huiting Niu, Bao Yu Xia, Fumin Li, Shahid Zaman, Bao Yu Xia, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399286686

                Abstract There has been notable progress in the development of efficient oxygen reduction electrocatalysts, which are crucial components of fuel cells. However, these superior activities are limited by imbalanced mass transport and cannot be fully reflected in actual fuel cell applications. Herein, we present the design concepts and development tracks of platinum&#8208;nanocarbon hybrid catalysts, aiming to enhance both cathodic electrocatalysts and hydrogen reactors. This review commences with an introduction to Pt/C catalysts, highlighting the diverse architectures developed to date, with particular emphasis on heteroatom modification and microstructure construction of functionalized nanocarbons based on integrated design concepts. This discussion encompasses the structural evolution, property enhancement, and catalytic mechanisms of Pt/C&#8208;based catalysts, including rational preparation recipes, superior activity, strong stability, robust metal&#8208;support interactions, adsorption regulation, synergistic pathways, confinement strategies, ionomer optimization, mass transport permission, multidimensional construction, and reactor upgrading. Furthermore, this review explores the low&#8208;barrier or barrier&#8208;free mass exchange interfaces and channels achieved through the impressive multidimensional construction of platinum&#8208;nanocarbon integrated catalysts, with the goal of optimizing fuel cell efficiency. In conclusion, this review outlines the challenges associated with platinum&#8208;nanocarbon integrated catalysts and provides perspectives on the future development trends of fuel cells and beyond. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Lei Huang, Huiting Niu, Bao Yu Xia, Fumin Li, Shahid Zaman, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ visualizing reveals potential drive of lattice expansion on defective support toward efficient removal of nitrogen oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2311180121</link>
      <description>Zhineng Hao, Guoquan Liu, Pengfei Wang, Weiyu Zhang, Wenming Sun, Lirong Zheng, Shaojun Guo, Sihui Zhan, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399281694

                As a sustainable and promising approach of removing of nitrogen oxides (NO x ), catalytic reduction of NO x with H 2 is highly desirable with a precise understanding to the structure&#8211;activity relationship of supported catalysts. In particular, the dynamic evolution of support at microscopic scale may play a critical role in heterogeneous catalysis, however, identifying the in situ structural change of support under working condition with atomic precision and revealing its role in catalysis is still a grand challenge. Herein, we visually capture the surface lattice expansion of WO 3&#8722;x support in Pt&#8211;WO 3&#8722;x catalyst induced by NO in the exemplified reduction of NO with H 2 using in situ transmission electron microscopy and first reveal its important role in enhancing catalysis. We find that NO can adsorb on the oxygen vacancy sites of WO 3&#8722;x and favorably induce the reversible stretching of W&#8211;O&#8211;W bonds during the reaction, which can reduce the adsorption energy of NO on Pt 4 centers and the energy barrier of the rate-determining step. The comprehensive studies reveal that lattice expansion of WO 3&#8722;x support can tune the catalytic performance of Pt&#8211;WO 3&#8722;x catalyst, leading to 20% catalytic activity enhancement for the exemplified reduction of NO with H 2 . This work reveals that the lattice expansion of defective support can tune and optimize the catalytic performance at the atomic scale.</description>
      <author>Zhineng Hao, Guoquan Liu, Pengfei Wang, Weiyu Zhang, Wenming Sun, Lirong Zheng, Shaojun Guo, Sihui Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2311180121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemically regulating COD/TN ratio of aged landfill leachate via rapid chlorine-mediated ammonia oxidation with RuO2-IrO2/Ti anode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113255</link>
      <description>Haoran Sun, Chen Wang, Hongtao Liu, Yucheng Liu, Yufan Chen, Lizhang Wang, Journal of environmental chemical engineering. 12(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399327555

                Electrochemical oxidation process was employed to regulate the ratio of chemical oxygen demand to total nitrogen (COD/TN ratio) of aged landfill leachate, aiming to meet the requirement of biological treatment. The results indicate that the ammonia nitrogen can be rapidly removed through electrogenerated chlorine radicals over a typical chlorine evolution RuO2-IrO2/Ti anode. The increased input current and decreased flow rate are beneficial to COD/TN ratio improvement, and COD/TN ratio can be increased to more than 16 at 1000 mA (input current) and 0.3 L/h (flow rate). According to the obtained experimental data, we present a strategy for COD/TN ratio increase: (i) determining the COD/TN ratio balance coefficient (B) of aged landfill leachate, and selecting the anode with COD/TN ratio adjustment coefficient (TN) &gt; B, where TN represents the ability to regulate COD/TN ratio, and B represents the specific TN to keep the same COD/TN ratio; (ii) performing the wastewater treatment experiments at different control parameters during electrochemical process; (iii) calculating the k of control parameter sensitivity curves to achieve different tolerance abilities, and further preferentially regulating the reaction process to high average current efficiency (ACE) of ammonia nitrogen and low ACE of COD. This work validates that the electrochemical process can increase the COD/TN ratio together with enhancing the biodegradability of such refractory wastewater, and also provides an effective tool for regulation of the COD/TN ratio via complete ammonia oxidation.</description>
      <author>Haoran Sun, Chen Wang, Hongtao Liu, Yucheng Liu, Yufan Chen, Lizhang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jece.2024.113255</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulsatile extractions of Lower Cretaceous silicic volcanic plumbing system beneath the Baiyunzhang and Lianhuashan Basins, eastern Guangdong: silicic magma evolution and related mineralization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1144/jgs2024-049</link>
      <description>Jianqiang He, Yan Xia, Xisheng Xu, Hongyang Shi, Jiangjiang Gu, Journal of the Geological Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399299701

                Highly differentiated magmas are closely related to the formation of tin deposits. The Lianhuashan Basin and Baiyunzhang Basin, surrounded by multiple coeval tin deposits, developed various types of volcanic and subvolcanic rocks. The diagenetic connections between different types of rocks within the two basins will provide new insight on the silicic magma systems evolution and the impact of highly differentiated magmas on tin mineralization. Both basins have consistent zircon U-Pb ages (143 &#8764; 138 Ma) and similar whole-rock Nd isotopes ( &#949; Nd ( t ) = -5.7 &#8764; -3.4) and zircon Hf-O isotopes ranges ( &#949; Hf ( t ) = -9.0 &#8764; -2.5; &#948; 18 O = 5.1 &#8764; 7.9), suggesting both basins originate from the same deep-level magma reservoir, followed by different degrees of crystal differentiation and several episodes of crystal-melt separation in their respective shallow-level magma reservoirs. The multiple pulses of magma extraction eventually produced different volcanic rocks, granite porphyry and rhyolite porphyry, while the remaining crystal mush consolidated in situ to form quartz monzonite porphyry. Further studies show that the tectonic regime changed from a compressive to an extensional environment at &#8764;140 Ma. Consequently, mantle-derived magmas with low oxygen fugacity injected shallow magma reservoirs that able to evolve to a high degree of differentiation through multiple recharge, thus favoring the formation of the Sn deposit. Supplementary material: https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.c.7258282</description>
      <author>Jianqiang He, Yan Xia, Xisheng Xu, Hongyang Shi, Jiangjiang Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1144/jgs2024-049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlating substrates reactivity at electrified interfaces with electrolyte structure in synthetically relevant organic solvent/water mixtures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-g1jhk-v2</link>
      <description>Florian Dorchies, Alessandra Serva, Astrid Sidos, Laurent J. Michot, Micha&#235;l Deschamps, Mathieu Salanne, Alexis Grimaud, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301085

                Optimizing electrosynthetic reactions requires fine tuning of a vast chemical space, including charge transfer at electrocatalyst/electrode surfaces, engineering of mass transport limitations and complex interactions of reactants and products with their environment. Hybrid electrolytes, in which supporting salt ions and substrates are dissolved in a binary mixture of organic solvent and water, represent a new piece to this complex puzzle, as they offer a unique opportunity to harvest water as the oxygen or proton source in electrosynthesis. In this work, we demonstrate that modulating water-organic solvent interactions drastically impacts the solvation properties of hybrid electrolytes. Combining various spectroscopies with synchrotron small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS) and classical molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, we show that the size and composition of aqueous domains forming in hybrid electrolytes can be controlled. We demonstrate that water is more reactive for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in aqueous domains than when strongly interacting with solvent molecules, which originates from a change in reaction kinetics rather than from a thermodynamic effect. We examplify novel opportunities arising from this new knowledge for optimizing electrosynthetic reactions in hybrid electrolytes. For reactions proceeding first via the activation of water, fine tuning of aqueous domains impact the kinetics and potentially the selectivity of the reaction. Instead, for organic substrates reacting prior to water, aqueous domains have no impact on reaction kinetics, while selectivity may be affected. We believe that such fine comprehension of solvation properties of hybrid electrolytes can be transposed to numerous electrosynthetic reactions.</description>
      <author>Florian Dorchies, Alessandra Serva, Astrid Sidos, Laurent J. Michot, Micha&#235;l Deschamps, Mathieu Salanne, Alexis Grimaud</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-g1jhk-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Duplication and neofunctionalization of a horizontally transferred xyloglucanase as a facet of the Red Queen coevolutionary dynamic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2218927121</link>
      <description>Victoria Attah, David S. Milner, Yufeng Fang, Yan Xia, Guy Leonard, Joseph Heitman, Nicholas J. Talbot, Thomas A. Richards, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399281648

                Oomycete protists share phenotypic similarities with fungi, including the ability to cause plant diseases, but branch in a distant region of the tree of life. It has been suggested that multiple horizontal gene transfers (HGTs) from fungi-to-oomycetes contributed to the evolution of plant-pathogenic traits. These HGTs are predicted to include secreted proteins that degrade plant cell walls, a barrier to pathogen invasion and a rich source of carbohydrates. Using a combination of phylogenomics and functional assays, we investigate the diversification of a horizontally transferred xyloglucanase gene family in the model oomycete species Phytophthora sojae . Our analyses detect 11 xyloglucanase paralogs retained in P. sojae . Using heterologous expression in yeast, we show consistent evidence that eight of these paralogs have xyloglucanase function, including variants with distinct protein characteristics, such as a long-disordered C-terminal extension that can increase xyloglucanase activity. The functional variants analyzed subtend a phylogenetic node close to the fungi-to-oomycete transfer, suggesting the horizontally transferred gene was a bona fide xyloglucanase. Expression of three xyloglucanase paralogs in Nicotiana benthamiana triggers high-reactive oxygen species (ROS) generation, while others inhibit ROS responses to bacterial immunogens, demonstrating that the paralogs differentially stimulate pattern-triggered immunity. Mass spectrometry of detectable enzymatic products demonstrates that some paralogs catalyze the production of variant breakdown profiles, suggesting that secretion of variant xyloglucanases increases efficiency of xyloglucan breakdown as well as diversifying the damage-associated molecular patterns released. We suggest that this pattern of neofunctionalization and the variant host responses represent an aspect of the Red Queen host&#8211;pathogen coevolutionary dynamic.</description>
      <author>Victoria Attah, David S. Milner, Yufeng Fang, Yan Xia, Guy Leonard, Joseph Heitman, Nicholas J. Talbot, Thomas A. Richards</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2218927121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Male with Acute Dermonecrosis over the Right Flank</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4103/idoj.idoj_776_23</link>
      <description>Vijayasankar Palaniappan, Anusuya Sadhasivamohan, Kaliaperumal Karthikeyan, Indian dermatology online journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399320463

                A 42-year-old farmer presented with an acute onset painful red raised lesion over the right side of his abdomen. While working in the paddy fields, the patient experienced a spider bite 3 days before the onset of this complaint. Initially, he had pain for a day, followed by redness and blister formation that eventually ruptured. He did not have any systemic complaints. On cutaneous examination, he had a single necrotic boggy plaque over the right flank. A linear streak of erythema was noted emanating from the superior aspect of the ovoid lesion [Figure 1a]. Dermoscopy showed a central bluish-black crust outlined by an irregular non-homogeneous reddish blue area in an erythematous background [Figure 2]. There was no regional lymphadenopathy.Figure 1: (a) A single oval erythematous boggy plaque of size 9 cm &#215; 7 cm with a central necrosis over the right flank, with a linear streak of erythema emanating from the superior aspect of the ovoid lesion; (b-f) Follow-up on day 5, day 10, day 16, day 30, and day 52Figure 2: A central bluish-black crust outlined by an irregular non-homogeneous reddish blue area in an erythematous backgroundThe vital parameters, hemogram, liver function tests, renal function tests, bleeding time, and clotting time were found to be normal. What is the diagnosis? Answer: Cutaneous loxoscelism with dermonecrosis Discussion The diagnosis of cutaneous arachnidism (loxoscelism) with dermonecrosis was made based on the positive history of spider bite, clinical presentation, and dermoscopy. The patient was managed with topical collagenase ointment, oral acetaminophen, a prophylactic antibiotic with intravenous ceftazidime twice daily, and oral prednisolone 0.4 mg/kg/day for 7 days. The patient was periodically followed up [Figures 1b-f]. The lesion healed with a hypertrophic scar. Necrotic arachnidism is a cutaneous reaction to toxins released from the venoms of spider bites. Loxoscelism is a term used for spider bites associated with loxosceles species.[1] Cutaneous loxoscelism is the most common presentation of loxoscelism. Systemic involvement with fever, myalgia, and hemolytic anemia can rarely occur.[1] The differences between cutaneous and systemic loxoscelism are mentioned in Table 1.[2] The toxins responsible for cutaneous loxoscelism are enzymes sphingomyelinase-D, phospholipase-D, alkaline phosphatase, hyaluronidase, esterase, and proteases.Table 1: Differences between cutaneous and systemic loxoscelism.Clinically cutaneous loxoscelism presents as a painful localized bluish-gray halo surrounding the bite site. This is followed by a vesicle or cyanotic pustule with surrounding erythema, edema, and purpura. Later, a central ischemic pallor with a dry, crusted, necrotic lesion with surrounding erythema, vesiculation, and pustulation is noted. The lesion spreads rapidly and extensively, with the eschar shedding and leaving erosions and ulcers. The affected site may take up to 6 months to heal with or without scarring. The pathognomic lesional description is a classical red, white, and blue sign. The red depicts erythema, followed by a palisaded white ring of vasoconstriction due to the toxin, and a central blue necrotic zone.[1] The most common affected sites are the proximal part of the lower extremity and the distal part of the upper extremity. Lymphedema can occur as a complication to loxoscelism.[3] The conditions that mimic cutaneous loxoscelism are arthropod bites, erysipelas, ecthyma, cellulitis, urticaria and angioedema, burns, vasculitis, pyoderma gangrenosum, cutaneous diphtheroid, anthrax, and cutaneous malignancies.[4,5] There are no standard guidelines for the management of cutaneous loxoscelism. Spider bites generally require rest to the involved part, analgesia, sterile dressing, and periodic follow-up. Cutaneous loxoscelism with dermonecrosis may require systemic steroids, prophylactic antibiotics, vasodilators, dapsone, tetracycline, heparin, and hyperbaric oxygen therapy.[4,6] Systemic involvement, which develops anytime within 12&#8211;36 hours after the bite, requires vigorous hemodynamic management.[2] Antivenin provides beneficial effects like prevention of necrosis, edema, and ecchymoses when administered as early as possible.[7] A high index of suspicion should be kept in mind to diagnose this entity in patients presenting with acute onset ulceration. A proper history taking and clinical examination holds the key to clinching the diagnosis. The aim of reporting this case is to emphasize the clinical evolution of cutaneous loxoscelism, which may pose a diagnostic dilemma. Declaration of patient consent The authors certify that they have obtained all appropriate patient consent forms. In the form the patient(s) has/have given his/her/their consent for his/her/their images and other clinical information to be reported in the journal. The patients understand that their names and initials will not be published and due efforts will be made to conceal their identity, but anonymity cannot be guaranteed. Financial support and sponsorship Nil. Conflicts of interest There are no conflicts of interest.</description>
      <author>Vijayasankar Palaniappan, Anusuya Sadhasivamohan, Kaliaperumal Karthikeyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4103/idoj.idoj_776_23</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
