<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 01:04:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Phosphorus-Doped Porous Carbon with Exceptional Electrocatalytic Performance for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4815163</link>
      <description>Shuhao Chen, Juan Meng, Anzheng Zhang, Rui Xu, Hongyu Zhang, Jie Jiang, Yue Zhou, Zhou Yang, Hengfei Qin, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396578284

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shuhao Chen, Juan Meng, Anzheng Zhang, Rui Xu, Hongyu Zhang, Jie Jiang, Yue Zhou, Zhou Yang, Hengfei Qin</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4815163</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Defects Containing TiN Films for the Hydrogen Evolution Reaction: A Robust Thin-Film Electrocatalyst with Outstanding Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14090770</link>
      <description>Ayoub Laghrissi, M. Es&#8208;Souni, Nanomaterials. 14(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396579097

                Density functional theory (DFT) calculations of hydrogen adsorption on titanium nitride had previously shown that hydrogen may adsorb on both titanium and nitrogen sites with a moderate adsorption energy. Further, the diffusion barrier was also found to be low. These findings may qualify TiN, a versatile multifunctional material with electronic conductivity, as an electrode material for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). This was the main impetus of this study, which aims to experimentally and theoretically investigate the electrocatalytic properties of TiN layers that were processed on a Ti substrate using reactive ion sputtering. The properties are discussed, focusing on the role of oxygen defects introduced during the sputtering process on the HER. Based on DFT calculations, it is shown that these oxygen defects alter the electronic environment of the Ti atoms, which entails a low hydrogen adsorption energy in the range of &#8722;0.1 eV; this leads to HER performances that match those of Pt-NPs in acidic media. When a few nanometer-thick layers of Pd-NPs are sputtered on top of the TiN layer, the performance is drastically reduced. This is interpreted in terms of oxygen defects being scavenged by the Pd-NPs near the surface, which is thought to reduce the hydrogen adsorption sites.</description>
      <author>Ayoub Laghrissi, M. Es&#8208;Souni</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14090770</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt&#8211;Nickel Vanadate Nanonest Colonies Deposited Carbon Fabric as a Bifunctional Electrode for Li-Ion Batteries and Oxygen-Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s42765-024-00419-3</link>
      <description>S. Chandra Sekhar, Bhimanaboina Ramulu, Shaik Junied Arbaz, Manchi Nagaraju, Yun Suk Huh, Advanced Fiber Materials/Advanced fiber materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396579243

                No abstract</description>
      <author>S. Chandra Sekhar, Bhimanaboina Ramulu, Shaik Junied Arbaz, Manchi Nagaraju, Yun Suk Huh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s42765-024-00419-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1D@2D Hierarchical NiCo&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@MIL-53(Fe) Nanostructures Synergistically Enhance Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00801</link>
      <description>Zeng Guo Wang, Xiaoxia Li, Zhixia Ding, Feng Mao, Jingjie Wu, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang, Energy &amp; fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396585577

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zeng Guo Wang, Xiaoxia Li, Zhixia Ding, Feng Mao, Jingjie Wu, Peng Fei Liu, Hua Gui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.4c00801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Radical Coupling on Short-Range Ordered Ru Atom Arrays Enables Exceptional Activity and Stability for Acidic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13248</link>
      <description>Jiangwei Chang, Yuanyuan Shi, Han Wu, Jingkun Yu, Junjie Wen, Siyang Wang, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Zhiyong Tang, Siyu Lu, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592376

                The discovery of efficient and stable electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in acid is vital for the commercialization of the proton-exchange membrane water electrolyzer. In this work, we demonstrate that short-range Ru atom arrays with near-ideal Ru&#8211;Ru interatomic distances and a unique Ru&#8211;O hybridization state can trigger direct O*&#8211;O* radical coupling to form an intermediate O*&#8211;O*-Ru configuration during acidic OER without generating OOH* species. Further, the Ru atom arrays suppress the participation of lattice oxygen in the OER and the dissolution of active Ru. Benefiting from these advantages, the as-designed Ru array-Co3O4 electrocatalyst breaks the activity/stability trade-off that plagues RuO2-based electrocatalysts, delivering an excellent OER overpotential of only 160 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and outstanding durability during 1500 h operation, representing one of the best acid-stable OER electrocatalysts reported to date. 18O-labeled operando spectroscopic measurements together with theoretical investigations revealed that the short-range Ru atom arrays switched on an oxide path mechanism (OPM) during the OER. Our work not only guides the design of improved acidic OER catalysts but also encourages the pursuit of short-range metal atom array-based electrocatalysts for other electrocatalytic reactions.</description>
      <author>Jiangwei Chang, Yuanyuan Shi, Han Wu, Jingkun Yu, Junjie Wen, Siyang Wang, Geoffrey I. N. Waterhouse, Zhiyong Tang, Siyu Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13248</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanadium Dissolution Eliminate the Lattice Distortion of Co-O Octahedron during Oxygen Evolution for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4286568/v1</link>
      <description>Honggang Fu, Liang Zhang, Di Shen, Yao Wei, Fanfei Sun, Ying Xie, Lei Wang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592957

                Abstract The electrocatalysts for high-energy consumed anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) especially in water splitting are generally prone to reconfiguration, so the dynamic structural evolution mechanisms should be deeply investigated. Herein, coral-like nanoarray assembled by nanosheets were synthesized via the layered effect of cobalt (Co) and the one-dimensional guiding effect of vanadium (V). The unique structure facilitates the full contact between active sites and electrolyte to enhance the electrocatalytic activity. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and OER activity can be respectively promoted through modulating the electronic structure with nitrogen and phosphate anions. Thus, the assembled anion exchange membrane electrolyzer exhibits a direct current energy consumption of 4.31 kWh Nm&#8211;3@250 mA cm&#8211;2 at 70&#176;C. It only required 1.88 V voltage to achieve a current density of 500 mA cm&#8211;2 with excellent stability over 200 h. Operando synchrotron radiation and Bode phase angle analyses reveal that the dissolution of vanadium species makes the distorted Co-O octahedral to regular octahedral structure during OER, accompanying by a decrease of band gap and a shortening of the Co-Co bond length. Such a structural evolution plays as the key active site for the formation of oxygen-containing intermediates, thereby accelerating the reaction kinetics.</description>
      <author>Honggang Fu, Liang Zhang, Di Shen, Yao Wei, Fanfei Sun, Ying Xie, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4286568/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur and Phosphorus Co-Doped CoFeLDH/MXene Nanoarray Electrocatalyst for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01159</link>
      <description>Wei Zuo, Xin Lan, Gang Liu, Cuicui Yang, Ping Lan, Bo Peng, Pengru Liu, Ke Li, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396597822

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Zuo, Xin Lan, Gang Liu, Cuicui Yang, Ping Lan, Bo Peng, Pengru Liu, Ke Li</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01159</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selenium-Enriched Hollow NiCo2O4/NiO Heterostructured Nanocages as Efficient Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01144a</link>
      <description>Vaibhav Namdev Kale, T. Maiyalagan, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396605164

                Finding clean, sustainable, and environmentally friendly technologies is especially crucial in addressing both energy and environmental challenges. Intending to accelerate the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and to decrease the obstacle...</description>
      <author>Vaibhav Namdev Kale, T. Maiyalagan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01144a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Localized oxygen evolution and transport analysis in PEM water electrolysis on local static pressure, temperature and current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.273</link>
      <description>Myungkeun Gong, Youngseung Na, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396605953

                With the escalating severity of the global climate crisis and the strengthening global demand for carbon neutrality, hydrogen produced from renewable energy offers a pathway towards achieving carbon neutrality. To reduce the cost of eco-friendly hydrogen production, we need to increase the current density in proton exchange membrane water electrolysis for green hydrogen production, a promising technology. One problem arising from an increase in current density is that it leads to a significant generation of oxygen, resulting in mass transfer losses. However, there have been few studies on oxygen transport near the anode catalyst layer, with most studies only measuring current density. In this study, local static pressure and temperature were measured in real-time to elucidate the relationship between voltage and current. At 2.1 V (corrected voltage = 2.03 V), the static pressure amplitude is approximately &#8722;5 to 5 kPa. At 2.55 V (correction voltage = 2.41 V), it decreased by about 50 % to about &#8722;2.5 to 2.5 kPa, and the frequency became faster. With increasing voltage, the decrease in static pressure amplitude and the increase in frequency occur because oxygen rapidly increases in the catalyst layer, resulting in a reduction in residence time. At 1.65 V (corrected voltage = 1.63 V), there is little change in local static pressure, indicating the dominance of the liquid single phase. At 3.6 V (corrected voltage = 3.05 V), there is little change in local static pressure. This is due to the rapid detachment of oxygen bubbles, leading to the dominance of the gas single phase. This elucidates how oxygen bubbles are influenced by fluctuations in local static pressure, leading to the conclusion that efficient design patterns for future anode flow fields can be achieved.</description>
      <author>Myungkeun Gong, Youngseung Na</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.273</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the interdependence of calcium and chloride activation of O2 evolution in photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01094-6</link>
      <description>Alice Haddy, Shilpa Beravolu, John W. Johnston, H. Kern, M. E. McDaniel, Brandon M. Ore, Rick R. Reed, Henry Tai, Photosynthesis research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396608313

                Abstract Calcium and chloride are activators of oxygen evolution in photosystem II (PSII), the light-absorbing water oxidase of higher plants, algae, and cyanobacteria. Calcium is an essential part of the catalytic Mn 4 CaO 5 cluster that carries out water oxidation and chloride has two nearby binding sites, one of which is associated with a major water channel. The co-activation of oxygen evolution by the two ions is examined in higher plant PSII lacking the extrinsic PsbP and PsbQ subunits using a bisubstrate enzyme kinetics approach. Analysis of three different preparations at pH 6.3 indicates that the Michaelis constant, K M , for each ion is less than the dissociation constant, K S , and that the affinity of PSII for Ca 2+ is about ten-fold greater than for Cl &#8722; , in agreement with previous studies. Results are consistent with a sequential binding model in which either ion can bind first and each promotes the activation by the second ion. At pH 5.5, similar results are found, except with a higher affinity for Cl &#8722; and lower affinity for Ca 2+ . Observation of the slow-decaying Tyr Z radical, Y Z &#8226;, at 77 K and the coupled S 2 Y Z &#8226; radical at 10 K, which are both associated with Ca 2+ depletion, shows that Cl &#8722; is necessary for their observation. Given the order of electron and proton transfer events, this indicates that chloride is required to reach the S 3 state preceding Ca 2+ loss and possibly for stabilization of Y Z &#8226; after it forms. Interdependence through hydrogen bonding is considered in the context of the water environment that intervenes between Cl &#8722; at the Cl&#8722;1 site and the Ca 2+ /Tyr Z region.</description>
      <author>Alice Haddy, Shilpa Beravolu, John W. Johnston, H. Kern, M. E. McDaniel, Brandon M. Ore, Rick R. Reed, Henry Tai</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11120-024-01094-6</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Water Hardness and Complexing Agents on Electrochemical Hydrogen Peroxide Generation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400491</link>
      <description>Marius Simon Enstrup, Jochen Steinmann, Freyja Galina Daragan, Babak Dangpiaei, Ulrich Kunz, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396611714

                Recently, many studies have been published regarding electrochemical oxygen reduction reaction for generating hydrogen peroxide (H2O2) using gas diffusion electrodes (GDEs) for various applications. Sodium salts solved in deionized water were usually used as supporting electrolytes. In technical applications, however, tap water&#8208;based electrolytes with hardeners are particularly relevant and have only been considered in a few studies to date. In this work, we investigated the influence of hardeners on H2O2&#8208;generation at 150 mA cm&#8209;2 and were able to show that scaling occurs predominantly on the GDE surface and not in its pore structure. With the novel method in electrochemical synthesis by using complexing agents to bind hardeners, we were able to significantly reduce the scaling. Even after 10 h of operation, the reactor still achieves a faradaic efficiency (FE) of above 70 % (&gt; 67 mg h&#8208;1 cm&#8208;2), comparable to the experiments without hardeners and complexing agents in the electrolyte. Furthermore, we demonstrate that the complexing agents are not electrochemically converted at the carbon&#8208;based GDE and behave inertly. If the cell is operated with complexing agents and rinsed with acidic liquid (anolyte) between batches, scaling can be completely avoided.</description>
      <author>Marius Simon Enstrup, Jochen Steinmann, Freyja Galina Daragan, Babak Dangpiaei, Ulrich Kunz</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400491</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the electrocatalytic activity and stability of Ni/NiO toward oxygen evolution reaction by coupling FeOOH nanosheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01114g</link>
      <description>Yajing Wang, Quanxi Zhu, Peng Zhang, Songli Liu, Jiankang Wang, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396619003

                The unsatisfactory performance of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and complex preparation method are the main challenges, hindering the OER electrocatalyst&#8217;s industrial application in electrochemical water splitting for hydrogen production. Herein,...</description>
      <author>Yajing Wang, Quanxi Zhu, Peng Zhang, Songli Liu, Jiankang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01114g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering MOF-derived hollow metal oxides toward enhanced electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119772</link>
      <description>Xuelin Dong, Erhu Yan, Yubing Lv, Ying Zhou, Xianxu Chu, Applied catalysis. A, General. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396621326

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuelin Dong, Erhu Yan, Yubing Lv, Ying Zhou, Xianxu Chu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apcata.2024.119772</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Applied electric field induced the change of spin-electron of the Fe3GeTe2 to improve its oxygen evolution reaction performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118310</link>
      <description>Liwei Guo, Rui Wang, Qiuhong Li, Jingguo Hu, Jing Pan, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396621839

                Utilizing density functional theory (DFT) calculations, we investigate the influence of the external electric field on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of monolayer Fe3GeTe2. Monolayer Fe3GeTe2 has ferromagnetic metal properties and displays excellent electrocatalytic activity. The magnetism mainly comes from FeI atoms, owing to the strong Fe-Te orbitals hybridization, and FeI atoms have great effect on the active site Te atoms. The electric field induces the change of spin-electron and promotes charge redistribution in the Fe3GeTe2, resulting in the changes of the magnetic moment and magnetic anisotropic energy (MAE). Simultaneously, the applied electric field shifts the energy band and decreases the work function which facilitates carrier migration to the surface. Therefore, the OER overpotential is reduced and the catalytic performance is improved. These valuable findings can serve as vital references for the design of 2D magnetic electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Liwei Guo, Rui Wang, Qiuhong Li, Jingguo Hu, Jing Pan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118310</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Floret Assembly of NiCo2O4@Tailored Nanostructured Carbon Support for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112075</link>
      <description>Muhammad Rahees Puthalath, Aruna K. Kunhiraman, A. Thangaraj, R. Ajay Rakkesh, Sujay Chakravarty, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396622953

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a bottleneck in overall water splitting due to the involvement of the four-electron process and requires a high overpotential. This hinders the stability and durability of electrocatalysts over a longer period. Herein, we report flower-like NiCo2O4 decorated on carbon nanostructures synthesized using a one-pot wet chemical method as an OER electrocatalyst in an alkaline medium. The catalytic activities were characterized by various electrochemical measurements including linear sweep voltammetry (LSV), cyclic voltammetry (CV), electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), and turnover frequency (TOF). 90% NiCo2O4@rGO/f-MWCNT demonstrated a higher OER activity compared to stand-alone NiCo2O4, 90% NiCo2O4@rGO, 90% NiCo2O4@f-MWCNT and 80% NiCo2O4@rGO/f-MWCNT.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Rahees Puthalath, Aruna K. Kunhiraman, A. Thangaraj, R. Ajay Rakkesh, Sujay Chakravarty</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112075</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of oxygen vacancies rich CeO2-xNx/GCN hybrid nanostructure with great active interfaces for electrochemical detection of antiviral levofloxacin in pharmaceutical samples</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142481</link>
      <description>Chellakannu Rajkumar, Wan-Young Chung, Journal of cleaner production. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396625100

                COVID-19 is an emerging viral infectious disease. Severe respiratory problems are considered an important syndrome of COVID-19 in humans. Levofloxacin (LEV), a promising fluoroquinolone antibacterial agent/therapeutic agent for influenza virus (H1N1)-induced pneumonia drug. These have been used as a potent antidote for acute respiratory tract infections. Owing to its excellent pharmacokinetic properties such as potential antiviral and scavenging activity, LEV has been used in controlling and treating COVID-19 during infectious emergencies. Even taking over the dosage of LEV and disposing of the embryonic toxic nature of LEV residues in the pharmaceutical research industry can cause adverse effects on the public health and environment. For this purpose, the development of great analytical tools is important to the detection of antiviral LEV for human health safety and environmental protection. In this work, we report a nitrogen (N) doped strategy to construct the enriched oxygen vacancies (OVs) on CeO2-xNx/GCN-2 hybrid nanostructure as an efficient electrocatalyst for the ultrasensitive detection of antiviral LEV. The effect of the N doping into the CeO2 (CeO2-xNx) lattice with increasing the large amount of OVs and boosted their redox properties (Ce4+&#8594;Ce3+), thus provided that a great electrochemically active site. Although the abundant OVs were conformed on the CeO2-xNx/GCN-2 from the peak-area ratio of Ce3+/Ce4+ and O2/O1 by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) assay. Owing to the strong electronic coupling between the OV-rich CeO2-xNx and the conductive GCN surface, thus CeO2-xNx/GCN-2 heterojunction achieved superior analytical performance for LEV oxidation with a good linear range from 0.01 &#956;M to 710 &#956;M, and detection limits of 5.6 nM (S/N = 3), and sensitivity 24.711&#956;A &#956;M&#8722;1 cm&#8722;2 at a very low working potential (0.7 V). The proposed hybrid sensor also exploited to the analysis of the pharmaceutical industry wastewater, pharmaceutical tablet and human urine samples with a satisfactory recovery rate.</description>
      <author>Chellakannu Rajkumar, Wan-Young Chung</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jclepro.2024.142481</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coupling interface constructions of flower-like structure MoSe2&#8211;NiWSe2 for efficient oxygen evolution reaction and urea oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102071</link>
      <description>Kankan Liu, Yimiao Yu, Jing Cheng, Yutong Wang, Fengbo Guo, Shijun Lei, Meng Li, Yun Ye, Ruina Shi, Wei Song, Materials today chemistry. 38(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396631423

                Because of its low thermodynamic voltage, the electrocatalytic urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is an effective way to replace the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and address the issue of urea-rich water pollution. Herein, we have synthesized MoSe2&#8211;NiWSe2 with spherical nanoflower structure consisting of MoSe2 nanosheets and NiWSe2 nanosheets crisscrossed longitudinally and transversely. The results show that the prepared MoSe2&#8211;NiWSe2 has a significant competitive advantage in the UOR and OER. With 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a mere 200 mV overpotential was required, indicating high OER catalytic activity. MoSe2&#8211;NiWSe2-driven UOR might operate at a comparatively low potential of 1.36 V (10 mA cm&#8722;2). The overpotential did not significantly alter after 40 h of continuous operation, suggesting it possesses high UOR stability. A built-in electric field that aids in controlling the adsorption and oriented distribution of urea molecules and thus promotes the oxidative properties of water and urea forms at the interface of MoSe2 and NiWSe2, where the difference in electronegativity between the elements Mo and Ni induces self-driven charge transfer and interfacial coupling effects. This work offers a method for creating catalysts that produce more oxygen and clean up urea-rich water contamination.</description>
      <author>Kankan Liu, Yimiao Yu, Jing Cheng, Yutong Wang, Fengbo Guo, Shijun Lei, Meng Li, Yun Ye, Ruina Shi, Wei Song</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102071</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on oxygen evolution reaction efficiency demonstrated by Ce-E (E = S, Se and te) electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.343</link>
      <description>Kiran Shoukat, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Syed Hamad Bukhari, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Ifra Bashir, Asma A. Alothman, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Suleyman I. Allakhverdiev, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396631840

                The strategy of generating sustainable energy with hydrogen fuel is highly significant and promising. Hydrogen fuel being non-toxic proves beneficial for the environment and can be produced in a variety of ways, as industrial water splitting into oxygen and hydrogen is a crucial future plan. This study aims to investigate cerium-based chalcogens (CeS, CeSe, and CeTe), as a catalyst to broaden the family of highly effective OER electrocatalysts based on transition metal chalcogenides. CeTe on NF was found to exhibit lowest onset potential with an overpotential of 333 mV at 10 mAcm&#8722;2 and a 51 mVdec&#8722;1 Tafel value among CeE (E = S, Se) chalcogenides with comparable stoichiometry. Using different analyses, it was determined that CeTe had a large surface area of 83.7 m2g-1, a cubic structure, and a highly crystalline nanoflakes morphology. High electrochemical surface area of 562 cm2, small resistance as Rs of 1.12 &#937;, and Rct 729 m&#937;, along with high TOF value of 0.174 s&#8722;1, 0.059 s&#8722;1, 0.009 s&#8722;1 for CeTe as compared to CeSe and CeS have supported by CV results. In particular, CeTe showed exceptional catalytic efficiency and was highly active and durable in oxygen evolution reactions.</description>
      <author>Kiran Shoukat, Muhammad Moazzam Khan, Syed Hamad Bukhari, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Ifra Bashir, Asma A. Alothman, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Suleyman I. Allakhverdiev</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.343</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selectivity of Mn rich Ru Mn O phases in parallel oxygen and chlorine evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144346</link>
      <description>Catalina Astudillo, Kate&#345;ina Minhov&#225; Macounov&#225;, Roman Nebel, Jan Pl&#353;ek, Petr Krtil, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396640999

                Single phase Mn rich Mn1-x RuxO2 conforming a highly disordered &#947; MnO2 with pyrolusite-like blocks dominating in the structure were prepared for low Ru content (0.15 &#8805; x &#8805; 0.30). All synthesized materials were electrochemically active in oxygen and chlorine evolution reactions in acidic conditions while varying the content of chlorides. The total activity increased with increasing Ru content in the structure as well as increasing concentration of chlorides in the solution. The selectivity towards oxygen evolution reaction was predominant for all chloride concentrations (from 0.02 to 0.3M), and its value was not dependent on the total Ru content in the material structure. The reaction mechanism with respect to chlorine evolution reaction was discussed on the basis of the determined order of reactions, which apparently increased with increasing Ru content.</description>
      <author>Catalina Astudillo, Kate&#345;ina Minhov&#225; Macounov&#225;, Roman Nebel, Jan Pl&#353;ek, Petr Krtil</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144346</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Double oxygen evolution co-catalysts modified BiVO4 to boost photoelectrochemical water oxidation performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174725</link>
      <description>Yaoguang Hu, Ziyang Tao, Jiawei Yang, Qiang Zhang, Jin&#8208;Ping Li, Guang Liu, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396643328

                Improving the kinetics of oxygen evolution is crucial for enhancing the performance of photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting. Herein, this study utilizes a chemical self-growth method to grow NiFe tannic acid complex (NFTA) and Co(OH)2 on the surface of BiVO4 photoanode (BiVO4/NFTA/Co). As a result, the synergistic effects of NFTA and Co(OH)2 layers promote the efficiency and stability of BiVO4 photoanode towards PEC water oxidation. The photocurrent density of the obtained BiVO4/NFTA/Co photoanode reaches 4.97 mA cm-2, which is significantly greater than those of BiVO4/NFTA (4.36 mA cm-2), BiVO4/Co (2.51 mA cm-2), BiVO4 (1.34 mA cm-2), respectively. Detailed analysis confirms that NFTA could provide an efficient way to hasten the transfer of photo-generated holes on the photoanode surface and diminish the surface charge transfer resistance. In other hand, Co(OH)2 could be served as a cocatalyst to accelerate charge transfer for efficient oxygen evolution reaction as well as a protective layer to maintain the long-term stability of NFTA on the surface of BiVO4 during water oxidation. Such double oxygen evolution co-catalysts decoration strategy paves an effective pathway to enhance the PEC water oxidation performance of BiVO4 photoanode.</description>
      <author>Yaoguang Hu, Ziyang Tao, Jiawei Yang, Qiang Zhang, Jin&#8208;Ping Li, Guang Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174725</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iron Triad-Based Bimetallic M&#8211;N&#8211;C Nanomaterials as Highly Active Bifunctional Oxygen Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00366</link>
      <description>Mahboob Alam, Kefeng Ping, Mati Danilson, Valdek Mikli, Maike K&#228;&#228;rik, Jaan Leis, Jaan Aruv&#228;li, P&#228;&#228;rn Paiste, Mihkel R&#228;hn, V&#228;in&#246; Sammelselg, Kaido Tammeveski, Steffen Haller, Ulrike I. Kramm, Pavel Starkov, Nade&#382;da Kongi, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396575612

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mahboob Alam, Kefeng Ping, Mati Danilson, Valdek Mikli, Maike K&#228;&#228;rik, Jaan Leis, Jaan Aruv&#228;li, P&#228;&#228;rn Paiste, Mihkel R&#228;hn, V&#228;in&#246; Sammelselg, Kaido Tammeveski, Steffen Haller, Ulrike I. Kramm, Pavel Starkov, Nade&#382;da Kongi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00366</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of a CoFe2O4-MnO Electrocatalyst for an Improved Oxygen Evolution Process in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11099-5</link>
      <description>Nargis Bano, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Nosheen Blouch, Nasreen Bibi, M. A. Shah, Ali Junaid, Asad Syed, Ali H Bakhali, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq, Journal of electronic materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396577717

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Nargis Bano, Syed Imran Abbas Shah, Nosheen Blouch, Nasreen Bibi, M. A. Shah, Ali Junaid, Asad Syed, Ali H Bakhali, Muhammad Fahad Ehsan, Muhammad Naeem Ashiq</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11099-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoM-ZSM5 (M = Zn and Ni) Zeolites for an Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12050907</link>
      <description>Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Srna Stojanovi&#263;, Katarina Rondovi&#263;, Ljiljana Damjanovi&#263;-Vasili&#263;, Vladislav Rac, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Processes. 12(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396578492

                An ion-exchange procedure of synthetic zeolite ZSM-5 (Si/Al = 15) was used to prepare three cobalt ZSM-5 zeolites (CoM-ZSM5 (M = Zn and Ni)) that were examined for OERs in alkaline media. The structural, morphological, and surface properties of the prepared materials were studied by X-ray powder diffraction, Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, scanning electron microscopy with energy dispersive spectroscopy, and low-temperature nitrogen adsorption. All three electrocatalysts showed OER activity where CoNi-ZSM5 presented the highest current density (9.5 mA cm&#8722;2 at 2 V), the lowest Tafel slope (134 mV dec&#8722;1), and the lowest resistances of the charge transfer reaction (31.5 &#937;). Overpotential (&#951;onset) at an onset potential of 410 mV for both CoNi-ZSM5 and Co-ZSM5 and 440 mV for CoZn-ZSM5 electrodes was observed. Co-ZSM5 showed somewhat lower OER catalytic activity than CoNi-ZSM5, while CoZn-ZSM5 demonstrated the lowest OER catalytic activity. The Rct of CoZn-ZSM5 is significantly higher than the Rct of CoNi-ZSM5, which could lead to their different OER activities. Good OER stability and low price are the main advantages of the synthesized CoM-ZSM5 samples in this study.</description>
      <author>Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Srna Stojanovi&#263;, Katarina Rondovi&#263;, Ljiljana Damjanovi&#263;-Vasili&#263;, Vladislav Rac, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pr12050907</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Heterointerface MnO2/RuO2 with rich oxygen vacancies for enhanced oxygen evolution in acidic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00827h</link>
      <description>Z. Guan, Chen Qian, Lie Lin, Chenghui Xia, Lei Cao, Bo Dong, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396585916

                The design and synthesis of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts that operate efficiently and stably under acidic conditions are important for the preparation of green hydrogen energy. The low intrinsic...</description>
      <author>Z. Guan, Chen Qian, Lie Lin, Chenghui Xia, Lei Cao, Bo Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00827h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exquisite regulated CeO2/Co (OH)2 electrocatalysts for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00636d</link>
      <description>Xiaowei Li, Quanquan Shi, Jingjia Li, Chun Li, Qingyi Qian, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396594360

                The development of advanced transition metals catalysts for the efficient electrocatalytic oxygen evolution have been widely studied, which have the potential to replace precious metal and achieve widespread commercial application....</description>
      <author>Xiaowei Li, Quanquan Shi, Jingjia Li, Chun Li, Qingyi Qian</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00636d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite CoSn(OH)6 nanocubes with tuned d-band states towards enhanced oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00975d</link>
      <description>Mingwei Sun, Baopeng Yang, Jiaxing Yan, Yulong Zhou, Zhencong Huang, Ning Zhang, Rong Mo, Renzhi Ma, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396594415

                The CoSn(OH)6 perovskite hydroxide is a structure stable and inexpensive electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reactions (OER). However, OER activity for CoSn(OH)6 is still unfavorable due to its limited active sites....</description>
      <author>Mingwei Sun, Baopeng Yang, Jiaxing Yan, Yulong Zhou, Zhencong Huang, Ning Zhang, Rong Mo, Renzhi Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr00975d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Crystalline metal phosphide-coated amorphous iron oxide-hydroxide (FeOOH) with oxygen vacancies as highly active and stable oxygen evolution catalyst in alkaline seawater at high current density&#8221; [J. Coll. Interf. Sci. 667 (2024) 362&#8211;370]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.203</link>
      <description>Wei Yan, Zhuang Shi, Feng Hao, Jinshi Yu, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen, Journal of colloid and interface science. 669(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396614604

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Yan, Zhuang Shi, Feng Hao, Jinshi Yu, Wenmiao Chen, Yanli Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.04.203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction of Hydrothermally Synthesized NiFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1166/sam.2024.4691</link>
      <description>S. M. Bodhale, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, Abhijit Gurav, A.D. Teli, N.N. Kengar, A. R. Vedante, Pravin Jadhav, M.M. Abdullah, Hasan B. Albargi, Jari S. Algethami, Preeti Singh, C.M. Kanamadi, Science of advanced materials. 16(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396631293

                In this study, nickel ferrite (NiFe 2 O 4 ) nanoparticles were synthesized using the hydrothermal method at various pH values. The objective was to investigate the influence of pH variation on particle size and electrocatalytic activity. The formation of cubic phase nanoparticles was confirmed through X-ray diffraction (XRD) analysis. To characterize the electrochemical properties, the nickel ferrite nanoparticles were coated onto a stainless steel substrate using the doctor blade technique. The microstructural analysis was conducted using scanning electron microscopy (SEM). The samples were further analyzed using linear sweep voltammetry (LSV) and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS). The average crystallite size, determined from the XRD pattern, was approximately 40 nm. SEM images revealed a conversion from nanoplates to a granular morphology. The synthesized electrode exhibited an overpotential of 392 mV at 10 mA/cm 2 and demonstrated good stability for 5 hours. These findings highlight the excellent electrocatalytic activity of nickel ferrite nanoparticles for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>S. M. Bodhale, Guruprasad A. Bhinge, Abhijit Gurav, A.D. Teli, N.N. Kengar, A. R. Vedante, Pravin Jadhav, M.M. Abdullah, Hasan B. Albargi, Jari S. Algethami, Preeti Singh, C.M. Kanamadi</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1166/sam.2024.4691</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating the electronic state of SnO2@NiFe-LDH heterojunction: Activating lattice oxygen for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131762</link>
      <description>Chaojie Yin, Fanghe Zhou, Chunliang Ding, Shengde Jin, Rui Zhu, J. Wu, Wenhao Li, Yang Chang Wu, Jia Lin, Xiaoxun Ma, Jie Deng, Zhongjun Zhao, Fuel. 370(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396633891

                In Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), catalysts with lattice oxygen, utilizing the Lattice Oxygen Mechanism (LOM), directly participate in oxygen evolution, effectively reducing activation energy. NiFe-Layered Double Hydroxides (NiFe-LDHs), rich in surface hydroxyls, are potential for LOM. However, their stability is challenged in alkaline conditions due to metal cation dissolution from the lattice, limiting catalytic efficiency. In this work, we modify NiFe-LDH by combining hydrothermal and electrodeposition techniques, coupling NiFe-LDH with the metal oxide SnO2. This process creates a heterojunction enriched with oxygen vacancies through interfacial and defect engineering. In 1 M KOH solution, this modified catalyst exhibits an OER overpotential of just 209 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2. Furthermore, when the current density is increased to 100 mA cm&#8722;2, the overpotential only increases by a modest 46 mV. Subsequent DFT investigations reveal that in the heterostructured system, there is an enhanced overlap between the O 2p and metal 3d orbitals, which optimizes the covalency of the metal&#8211;oxygen bond and promotes the participation of lattice oxygen in the reduction reaction. The heterojunction, in concert with oxygen vacancies, aligns the energy bands of oxygen and metal closer to the Fermi level, resulting in improved continuity of electronic orbitals near the Fermi level. This synergistic arrangement significantly reduces the energy barrier for the rate-determining step of the OER, substantiating the improved performance and activation of lattice oxygen.</description>
      <author>Chaojie Yin, Fanghe Zhou, Chunliang Ding, Shengde Jin, Rui Zhu, J. Wu, Wenhao Li, Yang Chang Wu, Jia Lin, Xiaoxun Ma, Jie Deng, Zhongjun Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131762</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IrO2 nanoparticles supported on submicrometer-sized TiO2 as an efficient and stable coating for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144392</link>
      <description>Bao Liu, G.H. Li, Xing-Min Cai, Yajun Wang, Yanan Zeng, Qijun Ren, Junguo Li, Electrochimica acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396634429

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bao Liu, G.H. Li, Xing-Min Cai, Yajun Wang, Yanan Zeng, Qijun Ren, Junguo Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144392</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anion Structure Regulation of Cobalt Silicate Hydroxide Endowing Boosted Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401394</link>
      <description>Yang Wang, Longmei Li, Sheng-Guo Wang, Xueliang Dong, Chongtao Ding, Yang Mu, Miao Cui, Tao Hu, Changgong Meng, Yifu Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396659240

                Abstract Transition metal silicates (TMSs) are attempted for the electrocatalyst of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) due to their special layered structure in recent years. However, defects such as low theoretical activity and conductivity limit their application. Researchers always prefer to composite TMSs with other functional materials to make up for their deficiency, but rarely focus on the effect of intrinsic structure adjustment on their catalytic activity, especially anion structure regulation. Herein, applying the method of interference hydrolysis and vacancy reserve, new silicate vacancies (anionic regulation) are introduced in cobalt silicate hydroxide (CoSi), named SV&#8208;CoSi, to enlarge the number and enhance the activity of catalytic sites. The overpotential of SV&#8208;CoSi declines to 301 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 compared to 438 mV of CoSi. Source of such improvement is verified to be not only the increase of active sites, but also the positive effect on the intrinsic activity due to the enhancement of cobalt&#8208;oxygen covalence with the variation of anion structure by density functional theory (DFT) method. This work demonstrates that the feasible intrinsic anion structure regulation can improve OER performance of TMSs and provides an effective idea for the development of non&#8208;noble metal catalyst for OER.</description>
      <author>Yang Wang, Longmei Li, Sheng-Guo Wang, Xueliang Dong, Chongtao Ding, Yang Mu, Miao Cui, Tao Hu, Changgong Meng, Yifu Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solidophobic Surface for Electrochemical Extraction of High-Valued Mg(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Coupled with H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Production from Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01484</link>
      <description>Yi Li, Chen Xu, Yingjie Wen, Haocheng Chen, Sixie Zhang, Hao Yang, Wenbo Li, Lihui Zhou, Bo Xu, Wenwen Xu, Wenjie Guan, Sheng Dai, Zhiyi Lu, Nano letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396660312

                A significant challenge in direct seawater electrolysis is the rapid deactivation of the cathode due to the large scaling of Mg(OH)2. Herein, we synthesized a Pt-coated highly disordered NiCu alloy (Pt-NiCu alloy) electrode with superior solidophobic behavior, enabling stable hydrogen generation (100 mA cm&#8211;2, &gt;1000 h durability) and simultaneous production of Mg(OH)2 (&gt;99.0% purity) in electrolyte enriched with Mg2+ and Ca2+. The unconventional solidophobic property primarily stems from the high surface energy of the NiCu alloy substrate, which facilitates the adsorption of surface water and thereby compels the bulk formation of Mg(OH)2 via homogeneous nucleation. The discovery of this solidophobic electrode will revolutionarily simplify the existing techniques for seawater electrolysis and increase the economic viability for seawater electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Yi Li, Chen Xu, Yingjie Wen, Haocheng Chen, Sixie Zhang, Hao Yang, Wenbo Li, Lihui Zhou, Bo Xu, Wenwen Xu, Wenjie Guan, Sheng Dai, Zhiyi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.nanolett.4c01484</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; and CoSe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles Incorporated Nitrogen-Doped Carbon as Efficient Trifunctional Electrocatalyst for Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries and Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02766</link>
      <description>Lubing Li, Jia-Tong Qu, Lei Zhang, Liting Wei, Jinzhan Su, Liejin Guo, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396674690

                The development of affordable, highly active, and stable trifunctional electrocatalysts is imperative for sustainable energy applications such as overall water splitting and rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery. Herein, we report a composite electrocatalyst with RuSe2 and CoSe2 hybrid nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen-doped carbon (RuSe2CoSe2/NC) synthesized through a carbonization&#8211;adsorption&#8211;selenylation strategy. This electrocatalyst is a trifunctional electrocatalyst with excellent hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) activities. An in-depth study of the effect of Se on the electrocatalytic process was conducted. Notably, the incorporation of Se moderately adjusted electronic structure of Ru and Co, enhancing all three types of catalytic performance (HER, &#951;10 = 31 mV; OER, &#951;10 = 248 mV; ORR, E1/2 = 0.834 V) under alkaline condition with accelerated kinetics and improved stability. Density functional theory (DFT) calculation reveals that the (210) crystal facet of RuSe2 is the dominant HER active site as it exhibited the lowest &#916;GH* value. The in situ Raman spectra unravel the evolution process of the local electronic environment of Co&#8211;Se and Ru&#8211;Se bonds, which synergistically promotes the formation of CoOOH as the active intermediate during the OER. The superior catalytic efficiency and remarkable durability of RuSe2CoSe2/NC as an electrode for water splitting and zinc&#8211;air battery devices demonstrate its great potential for energy storage and conversion devices.</description>
      <author>Lubing Li, Jia-Tong Qu, Lei Zhang, Liting Wei, Jinzhan Su, Liejin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High&#8208;Energy Facet Engineering for Electrocatalytic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401546</link>
      <description>Rui Wu, Jong&#8208;Min Lee, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396675515

                Abstract The design of high&#8208;energy facets in electrocatalysts has attracted significant attention due to their potential to enhance electrocatalytic activity. In this review, the significance of high&#8208;energy facets in various electrochemical reactions are highlighted, including oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), nitrogen reduction reaction (NRR), and carbon dioxide reduction reaction (CRR). Their importance in various electrochemical reactions and present strategies for constructing high&#8208;energy facets are discussed, including alloying, heterostructure formation, selective etching, capping agents, and coupling with substrates. These strategies enable control over crystallographic orientation and surface morphology, fine&#8208;tuning electrocatalytic properties. This study also addresses future directions and challenges, emphasizing the need to better understand fundamental mechanisms. Overall, high&#8208;energy facets offer exciting opportunities for advancing electrocatalysis.</description>
      <author>Rui Wu, Jong&#8208;Min Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401546</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grain boundary defect engineering in rutile iridium oxide boosts efficient and stable acidic water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400651</link>
      <description>Ning Zhang, Yunyun Fan, Depeng Wang, Yan Yu, Jianwei Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Di Bao, Haixia Zhong, Xinbo Zhang, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396675555

                PEMWE is considered a promising technology for coupling with renewable energy sources to achieve clean hydrogen production. However, constrained by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic OER and the acidic abominable environment render the grand challenges in developing the active and stable OER electrocatalyst, leading to low efficiency of PEMWE. Herein, we develop the rutile&#8208;type IrO2 nanoparticles with abundant grain boundaries and the continuous nanostructure through the joule heating and sacrificial template method. DFT calculations verified that grain boundaries can modulate the electronic structure of Ir sites and optimize the adsorption of oxygen intermediates, resulting in the accelerated kinetics. The 350&#8208;IrO2 affords a rapid OER process with 20 times higher mass activity (0.61 A mgIr&#8208;1) than the commercial IrO2 at 1.50 V vs. RHE. Benefiting from the reduced overpotential and the preservation of the stable rutile structure, 350&#8208;IrO2 exhibits the stability of 200 h test at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 with only trace decay of 11.8 mV. Moreover, the assembled PEMWE with anode 350&#8208;IrO2 catalyst outputs the current density up to 2 A cm&#8208;2 with only 1.84 V applied voltage, long&#8208;term operation for 100 h without obvious performance degradation at 1 A cm&#8208;2.</description>
      <author>Ning Zhang, Yunyun Fan, Depeng Wang, Yan Yu, Jianwei Liu, Jianrong Zeng, Di Bao, Haixia Zhong, Xinbo Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202400651</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dual Doping of B and Fe Activated Lattice Oxygen Participation for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity in Alkaline Freshwater and Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402264</link>
      <description>Yanhong Pan, Zhichong Wang, Kaixuan Wang, Qing Ye, B. G. Shen, Fuwei Yang, Yongliang Cheng, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396677401

                Abstract The exploitation of highly activity oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is critical for the application of electrocatalytic water splitting. Triggering the lattice oxygen mechanism (LOM) is expected to provide a promising pathway to overcome the sluggish OER kinetics, however, effectively enhancing the involvement of lattice oxygen remains challenging. In this study, the fabrication of B, Fe co&#8208;doped CoP (B, Fe&#9472;CoP) nanofibers is reported, which serve as highly efficient OER electrocatalyst through phosphorization and boronation treatment of Fe&#8208;doped Co 3 O 4 nanofibers. Experimental results combined with theoretical calculations reveal that simultaneous incorporation of both B and Fe can more effectively trigger the participation of lattice oxygen in CoFe oxyhydroxides reconstructed from B, Fe&#9472;CoP nanofibers compared to incorporating only B or Fe. Therefore, the optimized B, Fe&#9472;CoP nanofibers exhibit superb OER activity with low overpotentials of 361 and 376 mV at 1000 mA cm &#8722;2 in alkaline freshwater and alkaline natural seawater, respectively. The present work provides significant guidelines and innovative design concepts for the development of OER electrocatalysts following the LOM pathway.</description>
      <author>Yanhong Pan, Zhichong Wang, Kaixuan Wang, Qing Ye, B. G. Shen, Fuwei Yang, Yongliang Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402264</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Lattice Oxygen Participation of NiFe Stack Anode for Sustainable Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4818766</link>
      <description>Sinwoo Kang, Dong-yeol Lee, Yeongin Kim, Sooan Bae, Jae Kwang Lee, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691473

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sinwoo Kang, Dong-yeol Lee, Yeongin Kim, Sooan Bae, Jae Kwang Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4818766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Isomerization Engineering of Oxygen&#8208;Enriched Carbon Quantum Dots for Efficient Electrochemical Hydrogen Peroxide Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401253</link>
      <description>Xie Le-ping, Caihong Liang, Yao Wu, Kang Wang, Wei Hou, Hongwei Guo, Zeming Wang, Yeng Ming Lam, Zheng Liu, Liang Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691493

                Abstract Hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) has emerged as a kind of multi&#8208;functional green oxidants with extensive industrial utility. Oxidized carbon materials exhibit promises as electrocatalysts in the two&#8208;electron (2e &#8722; ) oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) for H 2 O 2 production. However, the precise identification and fabrication of active sites that selectively yield H 2 O 2 present a serious challenge. Herein, a structural engineering strategy is employed to synthesize oxygen&#8208;doped carbon quantum dots (o&#8208;CQD) for the 2e &#8722; ORR. The surface electronic structure of the o&#8208;CQDs is systematically modulated by varying isomerization precursors, thereby demonstrating excellent electrocatalyst performance. Notably, o&#8208;CQD&#8208;3 emerges as the most promising candidate, showcasing a remarkable H 2 O 2 selectivity of 96.2% (n = 2.07) at 0.68 V versus RHE, coupled with a low Tafel diagram of 66.95 mV dec &#8722;1 . In the flow cell configuration, o&#8208;CQD&#8208;3 achieves a H 2 O 2 productivity of 338.7 mmol g catalyst &#8722;1 h &#8722;1 , maintaining consistent production stability over an impressive 120&#8208;hour duration. Utilizing in situ technology and density functional theory calculations, it is unveil that edge sites of o&#8208;CQD&#8208;3 are facilely functionalized by C&#8208;O&#8208;C groups under alkaline ORR conditions. This isomerization engineering approach advances the forefront of sustainable catalysis and provides a profound insight into the carbon&#8208;based catalyst design for environmental&#8208;friendly chemical synthesis processes.</description>
      <author>Xie Le-ping, Caihong Liang, Yao Wu, Kang Wang, Wei Hou, Hongwei Guo, Zeming Wang, Yeng Ming Lam, Zheng Liu, Liang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The current state of transition metal-based electrocatalysts (oxides, alloys, POMs, and MOFs) for oxygen reduction, oxygen evolution, and hydrogen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1373522</link>
      <description>H. M. Ara&#250;jo, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Sandra Gago, Diogo M.F. Santos, Frontiers in energy research. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396695394

                Climate change is showing its impacts now more than ever. The intense use of fossil fuels and the resulting CO 2 emissions are mainly to blame, accentuating the need to develop further the available energy conversion and storage technologies, which are regarded as effective solutions to maximize the use of intermittent renewable energy sources and reduce global CO 2 emissions. This work comprehensively overviews the most recent progress and trends in the use of transition metal-based electrocatalysts for three crucial reactions in electrochemical energy conversion and storage, namely, the oxygen evolution (OER), oxygen reduction (ORR), and hydrogen evolution (HER) reactions. By analyzing the state-of-the-art polyoxometalates (POMs) and metal-organic frameworks (MOFs), the performance of these two promising types of materials for OER, ORR, and HER is compared to that of more traditional transition metal oxides and alloy-based electrocatalysts. Both catalytic activity and stability are highly influenced by the adsorption energies of the intermediate species formed in each reaction, which are very sensitive to changes in the microstructure and chemical microenvironment. POMs and MOFs allow these aspects to be easily modified to fine-tune the catalytic performances. Therefore, their chemical tunability and versatility make it possible to tailor such properties to obtain higher electrocatalytic activities, or even to obtain derived materials with more compelling properties towards these reactions.</description>
      <author>H. M. Ara&#250;jo, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Sandra Gago, Diogo M.F. Santos</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fenrg.2024.1373522</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen evolution reaction performance of Ruddlesden&#8211;Popper perovskite oxide through heteroatom incorporation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151912</link>
      <description>Shu&#8208;Fang Li, Baoqin Zhang, Zhen&#8208;Bo Wang, Dong Yan, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396696534

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shu&#8208;Fang Li, Baoqin Zhang, Zhen&#8208;Bo Wang, Dong Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.151912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>N/P-doped NiFeV oxide nanosheets with oxygen vacancies as an efficient electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00943f</link>
      <description>Jingyuan Zhang, Zhenqiang Ma, Lanqi Wang, Ni Hui, Juanjuan Yu, Bin Zhao, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396696656

                An N/P-doped NiFeV oxide nanosheet catalyst (N/P-NiFeVO) is constructed by plasma treatment as an efficient electrocatalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction.</description>
      <author>Jingyuan Zhang, Zhenqiang Ma, Lanqi Wang, Ni Hui, Juanjuan Yu, Bin Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00943f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Evolution and Reverse Evolution of Graphene Vacancy Defects in the Oxygen Plasma Environment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4819861</link>
      <description>Shu Xiao, Yinong Chen, Shuyu Fan, Yi Wu, Jian Wu, Guangze Tang, Xinyu Meng, Fenghua Su, Xuepeng Wu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713726

                The phenomenon of friction increase in graphene coatings during prolonged treatment in an oxygen plasma environment has been widely recognized. In this study, we report a newly discovered oxidation state that leads to decreased friction during oxygen plasma treatment of vacancy graphene and propose a simple, clean, and efficient method for the controlled oxidation. Through density-functional theory calculations, we suggest the possibility of evolution from vacancies to oligo-oxygen and poly-oxygen structures during the oxygen plasma treatment, confirming sequential friction decrease and increase. Furthermore, molecular dynamics simulations indicate that the oligo-oxygen structure exhibits excellent in-plane stiffness in addition to low surface friction, making it an ideal friction interface. Notably, conditional friction can induce the reverse evolution of the poly-oxygen structures back to the oligo-oxygen structures. Experimental results demonstrate that the friction of oligo-oxygen and poly-oxygen structures decreased by 30.6% and increased by 130.1%, respectively, compared to the initial graphene vacancy structures. Moreover, the induced friction by 0.1 N in the presence of hydrogen makes the friction performance of the induced poly-oxygen structures, especially in the initial friction phase, almost comparable to that of the oligo-oxygen structures. These findings reveal the structural evolution and reverse evolution laws of graphene coatings in high-energy oxygen plasma environments, which are of great significance for the lubrication of moving component devices in the oxygen plasma environment, including in the plasma industry and space.</description>
      <author>Shu Xiao, Yinong Chen, Shuyu Fan, Yi Wu, Jian Wu, Guangze Tang, Xinyu Meng, Fenghua Su, Xuepeng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4819861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ruthenium-doped bimetallic organic framework self-supported electrodes as efficient electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.318</link>
      <description>Li Jing, Ya nan Wang, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Bo Liu, Chunbo Liu, Xianyu Chu, Guangbo Che, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396716177

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Li Jing, Ya nan Wang, Wei Jiang, Yuanyuan Wu, Bo Liu, Chunbo Liu, Xianyu Chu, Guangbo Che</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten doping-Induced electronic structure modulation in NiFe-based metal-organic frameworks for enhanced oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.355</link>
      <description>Dazhi Shen, Wenchang Ke, Gulimire Balati, Yunhua Li, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396716607

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Dazhi Shen, Wenchang Ke, Gulimire Balati, Yunhua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.355</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic Structure Tailoring of Cuco2o4 for Boosting Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820433</link>
      <description>Qi Dong, Bin Wen, Xin Zhao, Peiyi Wang, Xiao Lyu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713715

                Electronic structure tuning in metal oxides is a facile and effective strategy on boosting their catalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance. Here, we demonstrate the electronic structure tuning of CuCo2O4 by phosphorus (P) doping via in-situ diffusion method. The results found that due to more electrons transferred from P to the neighboring Co3+, the tuned Co was served as OER active sites, which contributes to an extraordinary OER performance. The synthesized P3.85-CCO/NF exhibits an overpotential of 250 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm-2, and a Tafel slope of 27 mV dec-1, which performs an enhanced OER activity than that of IrO2/NF. Moreover, the P3.85-CCO/NF presents stable electrochemical performances upon long-time running for 30 h. Thus, the electronic structure tuning strategy by in-situ P diffusion method emerges as an effective approach on enhancing the catalytic OER performance for metal oxide electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Qi Dong, Bin Wen, Xin Zhao, Peiyi Wang, Xiao Lyu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820433</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chemical etching to boost medium-entropy metal oxide for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118318</link>
      <description>Shaofu Kuang, Honglin Zhang, Liwen Zhou, Zugao Pi, Hua Lin, Ming Nie, Junhui Sun, Qing Li, Journal of electroanalytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396621685

                It is crucial to improve the catalytic activity of medium-entropy materials by adjusting the surface electronic structure of medium-entropy materials. In this research, we utilize a chemical etching method for synthesizing a medium-entropy metal oxide E-FeCoNiZn with abundant defects. Owing to the etching of Zn, a special form of electron-transfer by means of electron-accepting-donating is introduced, which greatly optimizes OER activity. The E-FeCoNiZn displays a superior OER activity with a low overpotential of 259 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a small Tafel slope of 37.1 mV dec-1 in 1 M KOH solution, outperforming the performance of FeCoNiZn and Ni-foam, while maintaining excellent stability over 48 h. Theoretical calculations demonstrate that the introduction of defects regulates the surface electronic structure of the E-FeCoNiZn via modifying the number of electrons transferred and then optimize the OER activity. This work provides a new strategy for designing medium-entropy materials possessing high catalytic activity.</description>
      <author>Shaofu Kuang, Honglin Zhang, Liwen Zhou, Zugao Pi, Hua Lin, Ming Nie, Junhui Sun, Qing Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jelechem.2024.118318</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intercalated and Surface-Adsorbed Phosphate Anions in NiFe Layered Double-Hydroxide Catalysts Synergistically Enhancing Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01200</link>
      <description>Shiqing Ding, Zheng Bo, Xiao&#8208;Feng Wang, Yue Zhou, Zhongben Pan, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Guangxiang Liu, Leiming Lang, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396633214

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER), a crucial semireaction in water electrolysis and rechargeable metal-air batteries, is vital for carbon neutrality. Hindered by a slow proton-coupled electron transfer, an efficient catalyst activating the formation of an O-H bond is essential. Here, we proposed a straightforward one-step hydrothermal procedure for fabricating PO</description>
      <author>Shiqing Ding, Zheng Bo, Xiao&#8208;Feng Wang, Yue Zhou, Zhongben Pan, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Guangxiang Liu, Leiming Lang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01200</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Instability of Cobalt-Substituted Polyoxometalates during the Oxygen Evolution Reaction: An &lt;i&gt;Operando&lt;/i&gt; X-ray Absorption Spectroscopy Study</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01265</link>
      <description>Benjamin Rotonnelli, Benedikt Lassalle&#8208;Kaiser, Antoine Bonnefont, S&#233;verine Renaudineau, Delphine Garnier, Anna Proust, Fabrice Bournel, Jean&#8208;Jacques Gallet, Tristan Asset, Elena R. Savinova, Journal of physical chemistry. C./Journal of physical chemistry. C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396669935

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Benjamin Rotonnelli, Benedikt Lassalle&#8208;Kaiser, Antoine Bonnefont, S&#233;verine Renaudineau, Delphine Garnier, Anna Proust, Fabrice Bournel, Jean&#8208;Jacques Gallet, Tristan Asset, Elena R. Savinova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c01265</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facet Dependence of the Oxygen Evolution Reaction on Co&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;, CoFe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;, and Fe&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Epitaxial Film Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13595</link>
      <description>Earl Matthew Davis, Arno Bergmann, Helmut Kuhlenbeck, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721089

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Earl Matthew Davis, Arno Bergmann, Helmut Kuhlenbeck, Beatriz Rold&#225;n Cuenya</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.3c13595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure and Texture Evolution in Cold-Rolled and Annealed Oxygen-Free Copper Sheets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102202</link>
      <description>Jing Qin, Xun Li, Dongsheng Wang, Chen Zhou, Tao Hu, Jingwen Wang, Youwen Yang, Yujun Hu, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396721951

                Commercial oxygen-free copper sheets were cold-rolled with reduction rates ranging from 20% to 87% and annealed at 400, 500 and 600 &#176;C. The microstructure and texture evolution during the cold-rolling and annealing processes were studied using optical microscopy (OM), scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and electron back-scattered diffraction (EBSD). The results show that the deformation textures of {123}&lt;634&gt; (S), {112}&lt;111&gt; (Copper) and {110}&lt;112&gt; (Brass) were continuously enhanced with the increase in cold-rolling reduction. The orientations along the &#945;-oriented fiber converged towards Brass, and the orientation density of &#946; fiber obviously increased when the rolling reduction exceeded 60%. The recrystallization texture was significantly affected by the cold-rolling reduction. After 60% cold-rolling reduction, Copper and S texture components gradually decreased, and the {011}&lt;511&gt; recrystallization texture component formed with the increase in annealing temperature. After 87% cold-rolling reduction, a strong Cube texture formed, and other textures were inhibited with the increase in annealing temperature. The strong Brass and S deformation texture was conducive to the formation of a strong Cube annealing texture. The density of the annealing twin boundary decreased with the increase in annealing temperature, and more annealing twin boundaries formed in the oxygen-free copper sheets with the increase in cold-rolling reduction.</description>
      <author>Jing Qin, Xun Li, Dongsheng Wang, Chen Zhou, Tao Hu, Jingwen Wang, Youwen Yang, Yujun Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SAGAbg. I. A Near-unity Mass-loading Factor in Low-mass Galaxies via Their Low-redshift Evolution in Stellar Mass, Oxygen Abundance, and Star Formation Rate</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad3042</link>
      <description>Erin Kado-Fong, Marla Geha, Yao-Yuan Mao, Mithi A. C. de los Reyes, Risa H. Wechsler, Y. Asali, Nitya Kallivayalil, Ethan O. Nadler, Erik Tollerud, Benjamin J. Weiner, Astrophysical journal/&#152;The &#156;Astrophysical journal. 966(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396579115

                Abstract Measuring the relation between star formation and galactic winds is observationally difficult. In this work we make an indirect measurement of the mass-loading factor (the ratio between the mass outflow rate and star formation rate) in low-mass galaxies using a differential approach to modeling the low-redshift evolution of the star-forming main sequence and mass&#8211;metallicity relation. We use Satellites Around Galactic Analogs (SAGA) background galaxies, i.e., spectra observed by the SAGA Survey that are not associated with the main SAGA host galaxies, to construct a sample of 11,925 spectroscopically confirmed low-mass galaxies from 0.01 &#8818; z &#8804; 0.21 and measure auroral line metallicities for 120 galaxies. The crux of the method is to use the lowest-redshift galaxies as the boundary condition of our model, and to infer a mass-loading factor for the sample by comparing the expected evolution of the low-redshift reference sample in stellar mass, gas-phase metallicity, and star formation rate against the observed properties of the sample at higher redshift. We infer a mass-loading factor of    &#951;   m   =   0.92   &#8722; 0.74   + 1.76    , which is in line with direct measurements of the mass-loading factor from the literature despite the drastically different sets of assumptions needed for each approach. While our estimate of the mass-loading factor is in good agreement with recent galaxy simulations that focus on resolving the dynamics of the interstellar medium, it is smaller by over an order of magnitude than the mass-loading factor produced by many contemporary cosmological simulations.</description>
      <author>Erin Kado-Fong, Marla Geha, Yao-Yuan Mao, Mithi A. C. de los Reyes, Risa H. Wechsler, Y. Asali, Nitya Kallivayalil, Ethan O. Nadler, Erik Tollerud, Benjamin J. Weiner</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad3042</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Light Absorption and Photo&#8208;Generated Charge Separation Efficiency for Boosting Photocatalytic H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Evolution through TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Quantum Dots with N&#8208;Doping and Concomitant Oxygen Vacancy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311861</link>
      <description>Ziwei Pan, Zhu Xi, Yuxin Liu, Long Yang, Mingyang Jiao, Shichang Kang, Junhai Luo, Xiangkai Fu, Wenqiang Lu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396676929

                Low-range light absorption and rapid recombination of photo-generated charge carriers have prevented the occurrence of effective and applicable photocatalysis for decades. Quantum dots (QDs) offer a solution due to their size-controlled photon properties and charge separation capabilities. Herein, well-dispersed interstitial nitrogen-doped TiO</description>
      <author>Ziwei Pan, Zhu Xi, Yuxin Liu, Long Yang, Mingyang Jiao, Shichang Kang, Junhai Luo, Xiangkai Fu, Wenqiang Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311861</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anchored Ru Clusters on lignin/algae carbon aerogel as efficient bifunctional catalysts for water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00409d</link>
      <description>Pengfei Li, Zhenping Cheng, Weidong Chai, Yao Ya, Ning Zhang, Yi Hong, Yanping Wang, Yi Luo, Liang Zhou, Lulu Zhou, Jianming Zhang, Z Wang, Tian-shun Dong, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396663512

                As a dual-functional catalyst for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER), Ru clusters have great potential, but there are certain difficulties in their stability on the substrate...</description>
      <author>Pengfei Li, Zhenping Cheng, Weidong Chai, Yao Ya, Ning Zhang, Yi Hong, Yanping Wang, Yi Luo, Liang Zhou, Lulu Zhou, Jianming Zhang, Z Wang, Tian-shun Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00409d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metallic Ru&#8208;Ru Interaction in Ruthenium Oxide Enabling Durable Proton Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404213</link>
      <description>Guoqiang Zhao, Wei Guo, Mengtian Shan, Yanyan Fang, Gongming Wang, Mingxi Gao, Yongfeng Liu, Mingxi Gao, Wenping Sun, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396583076

                Developing efficient and robust electrocatalysts toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is critical for proton exchange membrane water electrolysis (PEMWE). RuO</description>
      <author>Guoqiang Zhao, Wei Guo, Mengtian Shan, Yanyan Fang, Gongming Wang, Mingxi Gao, Yongfeng Liu, Mingxi Gao, Wenping Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404213</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Symmetric Catalyst Design Employing Ir Nanoparticles on Black WO&lt;sub&gt;3&#8208;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Nanofiber Support for Boosting Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401858</link>
      <description>Yeo&#8208;Jin Rho, Changsoo Lee, Min-Joong Kim, Won&#8208;Hee Ryu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396588990

                The efficient evolution of gaseous hydrogen and oxygen from water is required to realize sustainable energy conversion systems. To address the sluggish kinetics of the multielectron transfer reaction, bifunctional catalyst materials for both the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) should be developed. Herein, a tailored combination of atomically minimized iridium catalysts and highly conductive black WO</description>
      <author>Yeo&#8208;Jin Rho, Changsoo Lee, Min-Joong Kim, Won&#8208;Hee Ryu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401858</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Non-noble metal coordinated hypercrosslinked polymers based on porphyrin for efficient electrocatalytic OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01234h</link>
      <description>Xin&#8208;Ming Hu, Penglei Cui, Hong Zhang, Zhongli He, New journal of chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396711175

                The electrochemical catalysts for Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with abundant reserves, high catalytic activity, and robust stability are highly crucial for efficient electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, we designed and synthesized...</description>
      <author>Xin&#8208;Ming Hu, Penglei Cui, Hong Zhang, Zhongli He</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj01234h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong and Hierarchical Ni(OH)2/Ni/rGO Composites as Multifunctional Catalysts for Excellent Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14050309</link>
      <description>Lixin Wang, Ailing Song, Yonglai Lu, Manman Duanmu, Zhipeng Ma, Xiujuan Qin, Guangjie Shao, Catalysts. 14(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691959

                The lack of efficient and non-precious metal catalysts poses a challenge for electrochemical water splitting in hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions. Here, we report on the preparation of growing Ni(OH)2 nanosheets in situ on a Ni and graphene hybrid using supergravity electrodeposition and the hydrothermal method. The obtained catalyst displays outstanding performance with small overpotentials of 161.7 and 41 mV to acquire current densities of 100 and 10 mA cm&#8722;2 on hydrogen evolution reaction, overpotentials of 407 and 331 mV to afford 100 and 50 mA cm&#8722;2 on oxygen evolution reaction, and 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 at a cell voltage of 1.43 V for water splitting in 1 M KOH. The electrochemical activity of the catalyst is higher than most of the earth-abundant materials reported to date, which is mainly due to its special hierarchical structure, large surface area, and good electrical conductivity. This study provides new tactics for enhancing the catalytic performance of water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Lixin Wang, Ailing Song, Yonglai Lu, Manman Duanmu, Zhipeng Ma, Xiujuan Qin, Guangjie Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14050309</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F-regulated Ni2P-F3 nanosheets as efficient electrocatalysts for full-water-splitting and urea oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00615a</link>
      <description>Xiaoduan Sun, Shenhua Song, Guoying Yan, Yingchun Liu, Haojie Ding, Xiaojie Zhang, Yuanping Feng, Dalton transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396680349

                Heteroatomic anion doping represents a powerful approach for manipulating the electronic configuration of the active metal locus in electrocatalysts, resulting in enhanced multifunctional electrocatalytic properties in hydrogen/oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER). Here, fluorine-tailored Ni</description>
      <author>Xiaoduan Sun, Shenhua Song, Guoying Yan, Yingchun Liu, Haojie Ding, Xiaojie Zhang, Yuanping Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00615a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three&#8208;dimensional interconnected graphene network&#8208;based high&#8208;performance air electrode for rechargeable zinc&#8210;air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/sus2.201</link>
      <description>Jiajia An, Yu Meng, Hong&#8208;Bo Zhang, Yuanzhi Zhu, Xiaohua Yu, Ju Rong, Peng&#8208;Xiang Hou, Chang Liu, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Li, SusMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396732299

                Abstract Although zinc&#8210;air batteries (ZABs) are regarded as one of the most prospective energy storage devices, their practical application has been restricted by poor air electrode performance. Herein, we developed a free&#8208;standing air electrode that is fabricated on the basis of a multifunctional three&#8208;dimensional interconnected graphene network. Specifically, a three&#8208;dimensional interconnected graphene network with fast mass and electron transport ability, prepared by catalyzing growth of graphene foam on nickel foam and then filling reduced graphene oxide into the pores of graphene foam, is used to anchor iron phthalocyanine molecules with atomic Fe&#8210;N 4 sites for boosting the oxygen reduction during discharging and nanosized FeNi hydroxides for accelerating the oxygen evolution during charging. As a result, the obtained air electrode exhibited an ultra&#8208;small electrocatalytic overpotential of 0.603 V for oxygen reactions, a high peak power density of 220.2 mW cm &#8210;2 , and a small and stable charge&#8210;discharge voltage gap of 0.70 V at 10 mA cm &#8210;2 after 1136 cycles. Furthermore, in situ Raman spectroscopy together with theoretical calculations confirmed that phase transformation of FeNi hydroxides takes place from &#945;&#8208;Ni(OH) x to &#946;&#8208;Ni(OH) x to &#947;&#8208;Ni (3+&#948;)+ OOH for the oxygen evolution reaction and Ni is the active center while Fe enhances the activity of Ni active sites.</description>
      <author>Jiajia An, Yu Meng, Hong&#8208;Bo Zhang, Yuanzhi Zhu, Xiaohua Yu, Ju Rong, Peng&#8208;Xiang Hou, Chang Liu, Hui&#8208;Ming Cheng, Jin&#8208;Cheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/sus2.201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stacked High&#8208;Entropy Hydroxides Promote Charge Transfer Kinetics for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403948</link>
      <description>Lei Wang, Zehua Gao, Kai Su, Nhat Truong Nguyen, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Junxiang Chen, Lei Wang, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592408

                Abstract Although various kinds of cocatalyst are developed and decorated on the bismuth vanadate (BiVO 4 ) photoanode, its photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting performance is limited owing to severe charge recombination and sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Herein, a high&#8208;entropy hydroxide electrocatalyst (FeCoNiMoCrOOH) is constructed as a co&#8208;catalyst deposited on BiVO 4 with a good PEC activity and stability in potassium borate buffer, addressing substantial charge recombination and poor surface oxygen evolution reaction of the material. FeCoNiMoCrOOH synthesized by a simple electrodeposition stacking strategy, delivers an overpotential of 172 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 with a stability of 600 h under alkaline conditions, representing one of the best performances on high&#8208;entropy&#8208;based catalysts. The FeCoNiMoCrOOH/BiVO 4 photoanode shows a photocurrent density of 5.23 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V RHE with 100 h durability in potassium borate buffer. Experimental investigations and theoretical calculations demonstrate that the synergistic effect of Mo and Cr in FeCoNi catalyst effectively decreases the dissolution Fe, Co, and Ni after long&#8208;term operation, increases the charge transfer kinetics, and promotes OER and PEC performances, therefore enhancing the photocorrosion resistance of BiVO 4 . This work provides a new avenue to design high entropy&#8208;based electrocatalysts boosting solar water splitting activity and stability.</description>
      <author>Lei Wang, Zehua Gao, Kai Su, Nhat Truong Nguyen, Rui&#8208;Ting Gao, Junxiang Chen, Lei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202403948</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering the Neglected: Counter Electrode Optimization as a Key Driver for Improved Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4816853</link>
      <description>Hannah Rabl, Stephen Nagaraju Myakala, Pablo Rony Alberto Ayala Leiva, Jakob Blaschke, Stefan Pfaffel, Dorottya Varga, Alexey Cherevan, Do&#287;ukan Hazar Apayd&#305;n, Dominik Eder, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396629818

                This study introduces an innovative approach to enhance cathodic CO2 reduction on the working side by focusing on the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) on the counter side. Maintaining an inert atmosphere on the counter side led to a significant improvement in CO faradaic efficiency from 65% to 95%. BiVO4 on FTO proved to be resistant to oxygen poisoning when used as photoanode. Additionally, investigations into the stability of [AgSePh]&#8734; reveal insights into its behaviour under elevated potential and surrounding electrolyte, suggesting weakening Ag-Se bonds and the release of benzeneselenol upon charge accumulation within the first 2 hours before producing CO in a stable manner for 16 hours. Overall, this research significantly contributes to electrocatalytic CO2 reduction, offering innovative pathways for catalyst development and optimization.</description>
      <author>Hannah Rabl, Stephen Nagaraju Myakala, Pablo Rony Alberto Ayala Leiva, Jakob Blaschke, Stefan Pfaffel, Dorottya Varga, Alexey Cherevan, Do&#287;ukan Hazar Apayd&#305;n, Dominik Eder</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4816853</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrolysis &#8211; Alkaline electrolyzer with anion-exchange membrane | Alkaline anion exchange membrane electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00241-3</link>
      <description>S. Ramakrishnan, Mohamed Mamlouk, Elsevier eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713567

                This chapter examines alkaline anion exchange membrane (AAEM) electrolysis, exploring both its advantages and challenges. A comprehensive overview of the fundamentals of water electrolyzers is provided. This is followed by a detailed discussion on the advantages and challenges faced by AEM electrolyzers in comparison to alkaline water electrolyzers (AWE) and proton exchange membrane electrolyzers (PEMWE). AEM chemistry and degradation mechanism was reviewed. The hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysis is discussed in terms of the activity descriptors, mechanism, and performance across a wide range of pH levels. Conclusion and recommendation were made on the advancement required in AEM water electrolyzers performance, durability and scale up challenges to enable rapid deployment and competitive green hydrogen production to meet global NetZero hydrogen ambitions.</description>
      <author>S. Ramakrishnan, Mohamed Mamlouk</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/b978-0-323-96022-9.00241-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ exploration of oxygen electrocatalysis using core-shell nanostructure-enhanced Raman spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.03.006</link>
      <description>Zhengxin Qian, Ji&#8208;Shuang Zeng, Shuang Zhao, Qing&#8208;Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Qingchi Xu, Hua Zhang, Jian-Feng Li, Nano materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396589595

                Advancements in fuel cells and water electrolyzers have significantly bolstered the utilization of hydrogen energy. Notably, the oxidation and reduction processes of oxygen at the electrode&#8212;termed oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR)&#8212;manifest sluggish reaction kinetics, thus requiring noble metals as catalysts, which considerably impedes system efficiency and cost. The imperative for enhancing reaction rates and diminishing overpotential necessitates the development of effective catalysts, which strongly depends on the mechanistic understanding of these reactions at the molecular level. Therefore, this review summarizes our recent efforts in utilizing in situ enhanced Raman spectroscopy, especially the borrowing surface-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SERS) strategy, shell-isolated nanoparticle-enhanced Raman spectroscopy (SHINERS), and the SHINERS-satellite strategy, to capture oxygen intermediate species as a bridge to investigate the molecular mechanisms of OER and ORR. Combining in situ SERS with other characterization techniques and theoretical simulation, the structural evolution of active sites and intermediates, including &#8727;OOH, &#8727;OH, &#8727;OO, etc., during OER/ORR has been monitored under reaction conditions, and the reaction mechanisms together with structure-activity correlations have been identified at the molecular level. These findings may provide a pivotal scientific foundation towards the discovery of better materials for electrochemical hydrogen energy.</description>
      <author>Zhengxin Qian, Ji&#8208;Shuang Zeng, Shuang Zhao, Qing&#8208;Na Zheng, Jing&#8208;Hua Tian, Qingchi Xu, Hua Zhang, Jian-Feng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoms.2024.03.006</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructure and electrochemical properties of Ti/Mn2O3-Co3O4 coating anodes for electrolytic manganese</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2024.130855</link>
      <description>Tao Lin, Chuanbin Li, Hongbin Zhao, Xiaotian Yuan, Yanxi Yin, Surface &amp; coatings technology/Surface and coatings technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396621305

                The Ti/Mn2O3-Co3O4 coating anodes synthesized via thermal decomposition, and their phase and morphology were characterized using X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), Field-Emission Scanning Electron Microscope (FE-SEM), and X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS). Electrochemical tests, including cyclic voltammetry (CV), linear sweep voltammetry (LSV), and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS), were conducted in a MnSO4 solution. Results indicated that the Ti/Mn2O3-Co3O4 anode with 10 mol% Co showed the best performance with a significantly higher voltammetric charge and a lower overpotential for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) compared to Ti/Mn2O3 coating anode. The Co-Mn synergy enhanced oxygen adsorption on the anode surface, thereby improving OER electrochemical performance of Ti/Mn2O3-Co3O4 coating anodes. In addition, the Ti/Mn2O3-Co3O4 coating anode had a voltammetric charge 21 times higher than Pb-Ag alloy anodes.</description>
      <author>Tao Lin, Chuanbin Li, Hongbin Zhao, Xiaotian Yuan, Yanxi Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfcoat.2024.130855</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient Hydrogen Evolution Electrocatalyst: MoN/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;N/NF Coupled with Methanol Oxidation Reaction for Formate Production in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4682</link>
      <description>Yang Zhou, Kun Zhao, Chenhao Shi, Haojie Ma, Dingwang Yuan, Zhiguo Yi, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396571474

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting for hydrogen production is promising, but its practical application is limited by the sluggish kinetics of the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and the less valuable oxygen by-product. Hence, replacing OER with a thermodynamically favorable methanol oxidation reaction (MOR) and coupling with value-added formate generation on the anode is an energy-saving and effective scheme. In this work, we report a self-supporting bifunctional electrocatalyst MoN/Ni3N/NF, which exhibits excellent hydrogen evolution reaction catalytic activity and stability, requiring overpotentials of only 18 and 68 mV to reach current densities of &#8722;10 and &#8722;100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. Moreover, the catalyst&#8217;s performance minimally deteriorates after long-standing chronopotentiometry measurements (&#8722;100 mA cm&#8722;2@150h). When MOR is used instead of OER, the required potential drops by 200 mV to 1.38 V at a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 and MoN/Ni3N/NF also demonstrates splendid catalytic stability towards OER and MOR. Finally, a two-electrode system employing MoN/Ni3N/NF as a bifunctional electrocatalyst only requires a cell voltage of 1.40, 1.68 V to achieve current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. The coupled electrolyzer also exhibits high faradaic efficiency for producing cathodic H2 (100%) and anodic formate (90%).</description>
      <author>Yang Zhou, Kun Zhao, Chenhao Shi, Haojie Ma, Dingwang Yuan, Zhiguo Yi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad4682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electro-catalytic activity of TNTs/SnO2-Sb electrode through the effect mechanism of TNTs architecture</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5813(23)60390-1</link>
      <description>Lisha Yang, GUO Yanming, Journal of fuel chemistry &amp; technology. 52(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396626888

                The TiO2 nanotubes arrays/SnO2-Sb (TNTs/SnO2-Sb) electrode is successfully fabricated using the solvothermal synthesis technique. Various architectures of TNTs are constructed by varying the anodization voltage and time, aiming to investigate their impact on the structural and electrochemical properties of the SnO2-Sb electrode. The anodization voltage is identified as the primary influencing factor on the morphology and surface hydrophilia of TNTs arrays, which is evidenced by scanning electron microscopy (SEM) and contact angle testing. In contrast, the effect of anodization time is relatively small. SEM, X-ray diffraction (XRD), linear sweep voltammograms (LSV), and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) results indicate that the morphology and crystal size of the catalytic coating, as well as the oxygen evolution potential of the electrode, are influenced by the pore size of TNTs arrays. The influencing mechanism of enhanced electrochemical activity by adjusting the architecture of TNTs arrays is investigated using X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS), electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR), and hydroxyl radicals (&#183;OH) generation test. The results reveal a higher concentration of oxygen vacancies on the sample with a compact and smaller particle coating, indicating the presence of more adsorbed oxygen species. Consequently, this enhances the generation capacity of active radicals for organic matter degradation. The electrode featuring TNTs arrays with a length of 950 nm and a pore diameter of 100 nm exhibits the most effective remediation of phenol-containing wastewater, achieving approximately 92% &#177; 4.6% removal after a duration of 2 h.</description>
      <author>Lisha Yang, GUO Yanming</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/s1872-5813(23)60390-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shape&#8211;Preserved CoFeNi&#8211;MOF/NF Exhibiting Superior Performance for Overall Water Splitting across Alkaline and Neutral Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102195</link>
      <description>Yu Liu, Panpan Li, Zegao Wang, Liangjuan Gao, Materials. 17(10)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396691543

                This study reported a multi&#8211;functional Co0.45Fe0.45Ni0.9&#8211;MOF/NF catalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and overall water splitting, which was synthesized via a novel shape&#8211;preserving two&#8211;step hydrothermal method. The resulting bowknot flake structure on NF enhanced the exposure of active sites, fostering a superior electrocatalytic surface, and the synergistic effect between Co, Fe, and Ni enhanced the catalytic activity of the active site. In an alkaline environment, the catalyst exhibited impressive overpotentials of 244 mV and 287 mV at current densities of 50 mA cm&#8722;2 and 100 mA cm&#8722;2, respectively. Transitioning to a neutral environment, an overpotential of 505 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 was achieved with the same catalyst, showing a superior property compared to similar catalysts. Furthermore, it was demonstrated that Co0.45Fe0.45Ni0.9&#8211;MOF/NF shows versatility as a bifunctional catalyst, excelling in both OER and HER, as well as overall water splitting. The innovative shape&#8211;preserving synthesis method presented in this study offers a facile method to develop an efficient electrocatalyst for OER under both alkaline and neutral conditions, which makes it a promising catalyst for hydrogen production by water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yu Liu, Panpan Li, Zegao Wang, Liangjuan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/ma17102195</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Visible Light Triggered Overall Water Splitting over Plasmonic Au/SrTiO3:Al Photocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cptc.202400107</link>
      <description>Bin Zeng, Zhou Qing, Na Ta, Shengyang Wang, Can Li, Rengui Li, ChemPhotoChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396641847

                The surface plasmon resonance (SPR) effect has garnered extensive attention in semiconductor photocatalysis for solar energy conversion, thanks to its remarkable optical properties. However, the majority SPR&#8208;induced photocatalytic systems have been limited to achieving hydrogen evolution or oxygen evolution half reactions, and attaining overall water splitting on a SPR&#8208;induced photocatalyst under visible light remains a formidable challenging. In this study, we employed a plasmonic photocatalyst Au/SrTiO3, and further enhanced its performance by doping aluminum (Al) into the SrTiO3 lattice (denoted as Au/SrTiO3:Al). By constructing reduction cocatalyst (RhCrOx) and oxidation cocatalyst (CoOOH), the Au/SrTiO3:Al photocatalyst successfully realizes photocatalytic overall water splitting with a stoichiometric ratio of H2 and O2 under visible light (&#955; &#8805; 440 nm). We revealed that the introduction of Al species effectively modified the electronic structure of SrTiO3, thereby enhancing the hydrogen evolution reaction in Au/SrTiO3:Al. Simultaneously, the RhCrOx and CoOOH cocatalysts synergistically capitalized on the short&#8208;lived hot electrons and holes generated by the plasmonic Au/SrTiO3:Al photocatalyst, enabling to realize photocatalytic overall water splitting. This work offers a promising avenue for the rational design of plasmon&#8208;induced overall water splitting photocatalysts through the integration of suitable cocatalysts and surface/interface engineering strategies.</description>
      <author>Bin Zeng, Zhou Qing, Na Ta, Shengyang Wang, Can Li, Rengui Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cptc.202400107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Structural Rigidity of Ultrahigh&#8208;Ni Oxide Through Al and Nb Dual&#8208;Bulk&#8208;Doping for High&#8208;Voltage Lithium&#8208;Ion Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400224</link>
      <description>Zhi&#8208;Chao Liu, Fang Wang, Weina Wang, Sheng Liu, Xueping Gao, Small methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396622147

                Abstract The pursuit of high energy densities propels the design of next&#8208;generation nickel&#8208;based layered oxide cathodes. The utilization of low&#8208;cobalt, ultrahigh&#8208;nickel layered oxide cathodes, and the extension of operating voltages promise enhanced energy density. However, stability and safety face challenges associated with nickel content, including structural degradation, lattice oxygen evolution, and thermal instability. In this study, a promising strategy of Al and Nb dual&#8208;bulk&#8208;doping is presented in high&#8208;Ni cathode materials of LiNi 0.96 Co 0.04 O 2 (NC) to stabilize the bulk structure, suppress oxygen release, and attain superior electrochemical performance at high voltages. The introduction of Al and Nb effectively raises the migration energy of Ni 2+ into Li sites and stabilizes lattice oxygen through strengthened Al&#9472;O and Nb&#9472;O bonds. Furthermore, the substitution of high&#8208;valence Nb ions reduces the charge depletion of lattice oxygen and induces an ordered microstructure. The Al and Nb dual&#8208;bulk&#8208;doping strategy mitigates strain and stress associated with the H2&#8596;H3 phase transition, reducing the generation and propagation of microcracks. The resulting Li(Ni 0.96 Co 0.04 ) 0.985 Al 0.01 Nb 0.005 O 2 (NCAN) cathode exhibits superior cycling stability, with a capacity retention of 77.8% after 300 cycles, even when operating at a high&#8208;voltage of 4.4 V, outperforming the NC (48.5%). This work provides a promising perspective for developing high&#8208;voltage and high&#8208;Ni cathode materials.</description>
      <author>Zhi&#8208;Chao Liu, Fang Wang, Weina Wang, Sheng Liu, Xueping Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400224</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of Ni&#8208;Polyaniline/Graphene Oxide Composite Electrode with High Capacitance and Water Splitting Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202300795</link>
      <description>Tatiana N. Myasoedova, Olga Nedoedkova, Rajathsing Kalusulingam, Yury Popov, A.S. Mikheykin, Alexey Konstantinov, Zhengyou Li, &#1058;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1080;&#1093;&#1072;&#1081;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1042;. &#1040;. &#1064;&#1084;&#1072;&#1090;&#1082;&#1086;, G. &#201;. Yalovega, ChemPhysChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396583805

                The Ni-PANI@GO composite electrode was fabricated via cost effective electrodeposition technique. According to the XRD, FTIR, Raman, SEM, and XPS analyses revealed that the nickel doped PANI@GO composite has been fabricated on the surface of the nickel foam. Addition of nickel significantly enhanced interaction between graphene with PANI leading to higher degree of polyaniline doping though imine groups. Electrochemical investigation revelated the significant performance of the Ni-PANI@GO composite electrode, boosting an impressive capacitance of 4480 F/g at 40 A/g, surpassing previous Ni-foam-based binder-free electrodes. Notably, Ni-PANI@GO electrode displayed excellent catalytic activity in both oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), generating a considerable volume of the gas bubbles at relatively modest overpotentials of 279 mV and 244 mV respectively. This event allows for the achievement of 20 mA&#183;cm-2 current density. Furthermore, in the laboratory-scale water electrolyzer, a low cell voltage of 1.72 V was achieved, facilitating a water-splitting current density of 20 mA&#183;cm-2. This study underscores the premising potential for the real-world device's application of the versatile Ni-PANI@GO composite electrode.</description>
      <author>Tatiana N. Myasoedova, Olga Nedoedkova, Rajathsing Kalusulingam, Yury Popov, A.S. Mikheykin, Alexey Konstantinov, Zhengyou Li, &#1058;. &#1040;. &#1052;&#1080;&#1093;&#1072;&#1081;&#1083;&#1086;&#1074;&#1072;, &#1042;. &#1040;. &#1064;&#1084;&#1072;&#1090;&#1082;&#1086;, G. &#201;. Yalovega</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202300795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electric Field Redistribution Triggered Surface Adsorption and Mass Transfer to Boost Electrocatalytic Glycerol Upgrading Coupled with Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400851</link>
      <description>Zhefei Zhao, Xinyi Shen, Xingyu Luo, Minhao Chen, M. Zhang, Ruipeng Yu, Renxi Jin, Huajun Zheng, Advanced energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396685384

                Abstract Electrocatalytic glycerol oxidation reaction (GOR) stands out as an economical and prospective technology to replace oxygen evolution reaction for co&#8208;producing high&#8208;valued chemicals and hydrogen (H 2 ). Regulating the adsorption of glycerol (GLY) and hydroxyl (OH) species is of great significance for improving the GOR performance. Herein, a hierarchical p&#8211;n heterojunction by combining Co&#8208;metal organic framework (MOF) nanosheets with CuO nanorod arrays (CuO@Co&#8208;MOF) is developed to realize the optimization on GOR. Specifically, CuO@Co&#8208;MOF electrode exhibits superior performance with a conversion of 98.4%, formic acid (FA) selectivity of 87.3%, and Faradaic efficiency (FE) of 98.9%. The flow&#8208;cell system with the bifunctional CuO@Co&#8208;MOF electrode for pairing GOR with the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) reveals better energy conversion efficiency. Experimental results and theoretical calculations unravel the redistributed electric field by introducing Co&#8208;containing species that contribute to the improved performance, which not only enhances the OH adsorption but also modulates the excessive GLY adsorption of CuO, thus reducing reaction energy barriers of FA desorption. Simultaneously, finite element analysis reveals that the novelty hierarchical structure can increase the concentration of OH &#8722; and facilitate the mass transfer of OH &#8722; in the solution.</description>
      <author>Zhefei Zhao, Xinyi Shen, Xingyu Luo, Minhao Chen, M. Zhang, Ruipeng Yu, Renxi Jin, Huajun Zheng</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202400851</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WC nanoparticles and NiFe alloy co-encapsulated in N-doped carbon nanocage for exceptional OER and ORR bifunctional electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160201</link>
      <description>Eun-Su Jang, Jangwoo Cho, Ji Hoon Kim, Jooheon Kim, Applied surface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396622337

                Developing earth-abundant electrocatalysts with optimized intrinsic active sites is crucial for enhancing bifunctional oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance. In this study, we fabricated a hollow structured carbon framework utilizing NiFe Prussian Blue analogs (PBAs) as templates, while polypyrrole (PPy) and phosphotungstic acid (PW12). Pyrrole monomer underwent polymerization on the nanocubic PBA surface in the presence of PW12 (PBA@PPy-PW12). Subsequent carbothermal reduction created an N-doped carbon shell with embedded NiFe alloy and tungsten carbide (WC) nanoparticles. The polymeric PPy-PW12 nature can not only prevent the aggregation of PBA and WC structures but also enhance electrical conductivity by connecting neighboring nanospheres. Moreover, the introduction of WC can significantly enhance the bifunctional electrocatalytic activity of the carbon-based catalyst, which is attributed to synergism between the WC and NiFe materials within the NC layer. Consequently, NiFe/W0.3C@NC exhibited outstanding OER (overpotential = 290 mV for 10 mA/cm2; Tafel slope = 57 mV/dec) and ORR (half wave potential = 0.81 V; Tafel slope = 61 mV/dec) performances. This work presents a promising avenue for developing high-performance electrocatalysts for energy conversion systems that showcase remarkable efficiency, stability, and potential practicability.</description>
      <author>Eun-Su Jang, Jangwoo Cho, Ji Hoon Kim, Jooheon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.160201</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Net &lt;scp&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/scp&gt; exchange rates under dark and light conditions across different stem compartments</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19782</link>
      <description>Sara Natale, Lucas Le&#243;n Peralta Ogorek, Ludovico Caracciolo, Tomas Morosinotto, Herbert van Amerongen, Valentino Casolo, Ole Pedersen, Andrea Nardini, New phytologist. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396643438

                Summary Woody plants display some photosynthetic activity in stems, but the biological role of stem photosynthesis and the specific contributions of bark and wood to carbon uptake and oxygen evolution remain poorly understood. We aimed to elucidate the functional characteristics of chloroplasts in stems of different ages in Fraxinus ornus . Our investigation employed diverse experimental approaches, including microsensor technology to assess oxygen production rates in whole stem, bark, and wood separately. Additionally, we utilized fluorescence lifetime imaging microscopy (FLIM) to characterize the relative abundance of photosystems I and II (PSI : PSII chlorophyll ratio) in bark and wood. Our findings revealed light&#8208;induced increases in O 2 production in whole stem, bark, and wood. We present the radial profile of O 2 production in F. ornus stems, demonstrating the capability of stem chloroplasts to perform light&#8208;dependent electron transport. Younger stems exhibited higher light&#8208;induced O 2 production and dark respiration rates than older ones. While bark emerged as the primary contributor to net O 2 production under light conditions, our data underscored that wood chloroplasts are also photosynthetically active. The FLIM analysis unveiled a lower PSI abundance in wood than in bark, suggesting stem chloroplasts are not only active but also acclimate to the spectral composition of light reaching inner compartments.</description>
      <author>Sara Natale, Lucas Le&#243;n Peralta Ogorek, Ludovico Caracciolo, Tomas Morosinotto, Herbert van Amerongen, Valentino Casolo, Ole Pedersen, Andrea Nardini</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19782</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A photothermal assisted zinc-air battery cathode based on pyroelectric and photocatalytic effect</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.013</link>
      <description>Song Lin Li, Hongsheng Jia, Zhimeng Zhang, Mei Han, E Yuanlong, Chunbo Liu, Qingshuang Wang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396634086

                Zinc&#8211;air battery as one of the new generations of battery system, its theoretical specific energy is as high as 1086 Wh kg&#8722;1, specific capacity up to 820 mAh/g, and zinc has the advantages of environmental friendliness, resource abundance, low cost and good safety, so it has attracted much attention. However, due to its slow reaction kinetic process, zinc&#8211;air battery will produce a large charging overpotential usually up to 2 V, it is far beyond the theoretical voltage of 1.65 V, so reducing the overpotential of zinc&#8211;air batteries is extremely necessary, and the most common way to solve this problem is to use excellent catalyst cathode to improve the oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution kinetics of zinc&#8211;air batteries. So we developed a new photothermal assisted zinc&#8211;air battery system with Hollow carbon nanosphere@poly (vinylidene fluoride-trifluoroethylene-chlorofluoroethylene)@CdS (HCN@PVTC@CdS) photocathode, the pyroelectric and photocatalysis effect can effectively promote the reaction kinetics and reduce the reaction overpotential. With the pyroelectric and photocatalysis synergistic effect, the zinc&#8211;air has displayed a high discharge potential of 1.33 V and a low charging potential of 1.5 V with good cycle stability. This multi-assist technology with built-in electric and light fields paves the way for the development of high-performance zinc&#8211;air batteries and other energy storage systems.</description>
      <author>Song Lin Li, Hongsheng Jia, Zhimeng Zhang, Mei Han, E Yuanlong, Chunbo Liu, Qingshuang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.013</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different M-doped Ni3S2/FeS (M=Co, Cr, Cu, Zn) hybrid nanosheet arrays for overall urea splitting and seawater oxidation reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104432</link>
      <description>Yanhong Wang, Shijie Liu, Xiaoqiang Du, Xiaoshuang Zhang, Surfaces and interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396656784

                Hydrogen production by electrolysis of water is gradually becoming the main way to obtain green energy, but due to the scarcity of fresh water resources in the world, so the study of urea and seawater electrolysis has become an important work. In this experiment, different metal ions M (M=Co, Cr, Cu, Zn) doped Ni3S2/FeS were investigated as catalysts with good catalytic activity in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) as well as in urea oxidation reaction (UOR) in urea electrolyte, and Co-Ni3S2/FeS and Cr-Ni3S2/FeS, which performed well in HER and UOR, were assembled into an electrolytic cell for the overall urea decomposition (1.50 V @ 10 mA cm&#8722;2). Density Functional Theory (DFT) calculations demonstrated that Co-Ni3S2 possesses a lower free energy for H, while FeS possesses a higher density of states (DOS) near the Fermi energy level, and such a composite structure promotes significantly the catalytic activity of HER. The catalytic effect of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) was further investigated in the seawater electrolyte, and the results showed that the performance of Co-Ni3S2/FeS catalyst was better, and certain ions in seawater affected durability of the catalyst. The electronic structure of the catalyst was investigated through the characterization of the catalyst and combined with the special morphology jointly promote the catalytic reaction in electrolysis experiments, which provides a candidate catalyst for electrolysis of urea and seawater oxidation reaction.</description>
      <author>Yanhong Wang, Shijie Liu, Xiaoqiang Du, Xiaoshuang Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.surfin.2024.104432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of MOF-derived hollow sugar gourd-like Ni-Co-S@NiMoO4&#8226;xH2O nanocage arrays for efficient solar-powered overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115540</link>
      <description>Zhongtang Gao, Tengfei Zhang, Dianguo Xu, Ping Liu, Huan Liu, Huanhuan Li, Yanyan Liu, Feng Ye, Gang Wang, Journal of catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396708238

                In situ growth of nanoarrays on conductive substrates is an efficient strategy for designing electrocatalysts. However, preparing array with excellent catalytic activities for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) remains a challenge. Here, we construct a novel hollow sugar gourd-like Ni-Co-S@NiMoO4&#183;xH2O/NF nanocage array through MOF derivation strategy for stable solar-driven overall water splitting. Due to the hollow core&#8211;shell structure and multi-component advantages, the Ni-Co-S@NiMoO4&#183;xH2O/NF presents high density of active sites and fast charge transfer rate. Therefore, Ni-Co-S@NiMoO4&#183;xH2O/NF exhibits attractive electrocatalytic activity in alkaline electrolytes for HER (90 mV@10 mA cm&#8722;2) and OER (208 mV@10 mA cm&#8722;2, 245 mV@100 mA cm&#8722;2). The corresponding two-electrode electrolytic cell demonstrates small cell voltage (1.515 V @ 10 mA cm&#8722;2) and shows durability over 50 h at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, exhibiting excellent overall water splitting performance. It is worth noting that the solar-assisted electrolysis cell reaches a high solar-to-hydrogen (STH) conversion rate of 19.4 %. The construction of this unique hollow structure gives a fascinating method for improving the HER and OER performance of transition metal sulfide electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Zhongtang Gao, Tengfei Zhang, Dianguo Xu, Ping Liu, Huan Liu, Huanhuan Li, Yanyan Liu, Feng Ye, Gang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcat.2024.115540</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Bifunctional Electrocatalyst of Flower-Like Cr-Doped CoP/Fe2P Microsphere for Efficient Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad477f</link>
      <description>Yu Yan, Dongxiao Li, Zenghui Guo, Hao Ren, Yubiao Huang, Biao Yan, Ruihuan Zhao, Xin Yao, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396601563

                Abstract Developing efficient, low-price non-noble metal-based electrocatalysts for overall water splitting in alkaline medium remains a formidable challenge. In our work, Cr-doped CoP/Fe2P (Cr-CoP/Fe2P) flower-like microsphere was synthesized through a simple hydrothermal and phosphating process. The resulting Cr-CoP/Fe2P electrocatalyst shows significantly enhanced oxygen evolution reaction performance (262 mV @ 10 mA cm-2) and has a satisfactory hydrogen evolution reaction performance (114 mV @ 10 mA cm-2), coupled with favorable stability in an alkaline medium. Furthermore, when assembling Cr-CoP/Fe2P into an electrolytic cell, the two-electrode system can provide a current density of 10 mA cm-2 at a voltage of 1.61 V. At high current density, the performance of the electrolytic cell composed of Cr-CoP/Fe2P is superior to that of noble metal catalyst electrode pair. Electronic structure analysis and various characterizations confirm that Cr doping and the formation of CoP/Fe2P heterogeneous interfaces redistribute the electron densities of the active sites, enlarge the specific surface area, and enhance the aerophobicity of the catalysts, thereby improving the electrocatalytic property. This work provides a referable method for engineering highly efficient and stable non-noble polymetallic phosphides, which serve as bifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yu Yan, Dongxiao Li, Zenghui Guo, Hao Ren, Yubiao Huang, Biao Yan, Ruihuan Zhao, Xin Yao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad477f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating Alcohol Adsorption Modes for Boosting Electrooxidation-Assisted Hydrogen Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01078</link>
      <description>Peipei Zhu, Yongli Shen, Zhi&#8208;Ming Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Shenglin Xiong, Xuguang An, Shenglin Xiong, Changhua An, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581872

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) suffers from sluggish kinetics and results in the increasing cost of hydrogen production. The exploration of an appropriate anode organic reaction occurring at low potential represents a feasible strategy to accelerate the implementation of water splitting in practice. Herein, we develop a ligand-confining thermolysis strategy to fabricate a Ru single-atom catalyst (Ru-SA/NSC) on N,S-codoped carbon. The adsorption mode effects of substrate alcohols on the electrocatalytic oxidation of Ru-SA/NSC are unraveled through modulation of substituent groups. The horizontal adsorption through the O atom on Ru-SA/NSC significantly facilitates the benzyl alcohol oxidation, delivering ultralow potential of 0.97 V vs reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE) at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 with high yield (&#8764;96%), selectivity (&#8764;99%), and Faraday efficiency (&#8764;100%) to produce aldehydes. The vertical adsorption through the N atom in pyridine methanol over Ru-SA/NSC has no response to the reaction. Furthermore, in the coupling device of alcohol oxidation and hydrogen evolution reaction, hydrogen production with a low potential of 1.21 V at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 is achieved, surpassing that of benchmark Pt/C||IrO2 (1.56 V) and the state-of-the-art reports. This study provides insights into the design of nanocatalysts toward the rational conversion of organic molecules to value-added chemicals and concurrently produces clean energy carriers.</description>
      <author>Peipei Zhu, Yongli Shen, Zhi&#8208;Ming Zhang, Dingsheng Wang, Shenglin Xiong, Xuguang An, Shenglin Xiong, Changhua An</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01078</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work function-tunable graphene/WO3 heterojunctions for high-performance photoelectrochemical cell: UV-treatment effect and defective graphene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234650</link>
      <description>Ayoung Cho, Jin Hong Kim, Sung R. Choi, Jun-Young Park, Yoon-Uk Heo, Jung Sang Cho, Taekjib Choi, Journal of power sources. 608(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396652575

                Designing hybrid photoelectrodes with graphene capable of efficient charge-carrier transfer and excellent chemical stability is an effective strategy for developing high-performance photoelectrochemical (PEC) cells. However, it remains unclear how the PEC properties are enhanced and how to control the junction properties in graphene/metal oxide heterojunction-based photoelectrodes. Here, we develop a deterministic junction to enhance PEC performance in graphene/tungsten trioxide (WO3)-based photoelectrodes by tuning the work function of graphene. It reveals that the band structure of graphene/WO3 heterojunctions can be modified by ultraviolet (UV) treatment on WO3 thin films. This modification is supported by the observation that a single-layer graphene/UV-treated WO3 photoelectrode exhibits significantly enhanced PEC activities toward the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) (evidenced by features like a threefold increase in photocurrent, an onset potential shift, and improved stability), whereas the single-layer graphene/untreated WO3 electrode demonstrates improved properties for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). Additionally, defects in the graphene layer formed during PEC water splitting contribute to high catalytic activities of the graphene/WO3 photoelectrode due to a decrease in the Gibbs free energy for OER and HER. These results emphasize that band structure engineering via work function tuning in graphene/WO3 heterostructures can provide multiple benefits for high PEC performance and long-term stability.</description>
      <author>Ayoung Cho, Jin Hong Kim, Sung R. Choi, Jun-Young Park, Yoon-Uk Heo, Jung Sang Cho, Taekjib Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-Metal-Oxygen Moieties Enriched Surface Reconstruction in Cofe Electrocatalysts for Stabilizing High-Valence Co Sites Enable Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820462</link>
      <description>Yingwei Li, Wang Meng'en, Jie Tian, Xudong Song, Baojun Ma, Wei Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396713732

                Despite the potential of heterostructure construction and surface reconstruction strategies to significantly enhance the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance of transition metal compounds, integrating these approaches into a single material system remains a significant challenge. In this work, we report an efficient CoFe-LDH catalyst with multi-metal nitrides on the surface through simple and tunable N2-plasma treatment. Structural and chemical state characterization indicates a high concentration of defective sites in PL CoFe-LDH, which facilitates the exposure of a greater number of active N-Fe-O and N-Co-O centers. During the initial stage of the OER process, there is a rapid phase transition of Fe and Co, leading to the formation of metal (oxy)hydroxides. Meanwhile, Co3+ species gradually accumulate on the surfaces, which is responsible for the excellent OER catalytic activity. Then, the neighboring N atoms function as electron reservoirs, donating electrons to the Co sites to prevent overoxidation and dissolution of Co in the electrolyte, thus significantly enhancing the stability of the OER. The catalysts enable the achievement of ultralow OER overpotential, measuring 161.1 and 205.5 mV at current densities of 10 mA cm-2 and 200 mA cm-2, respectively, while exhibiting exceptional stability.</description>
      <author>Yingwei Li, Wang Meng'en, Jie Tian, Xudong Song, Baojun Ma, Wei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4820462</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A highly-stable and low-energy-barrier photoelectrocatalyst (NiFe-LDH@Ti-MOF) for water splitting at high current densities via breaking the atomic structure symmetry</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.05.005</link>
      <description>Azam Pirkarami, Arash Javanmard, Ebrahim Ghasemi, Journal of industrial and engineering chemistry/Journal of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry - Korean Society of Industrial and Engineering Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396678627

                There is a flurry of interest in enhancing the stability and efficiency of photoelectrocatalysts in water splitting at high current densities. In the present study, nickel&#8211;iron layered double hydroxide (NiFe-LDH) was decorated with MIP-177-LT (Ti-metal organic framework (MOF)) to fabricate a heteroatom electrocatalyst (NiFe-LDH@Ti-MOF). The overpotentials of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) turned out to be very low: 199 and 232 mV at current densities of 200 and 600 mA cm&#8722;2, in that order. Then, current densities of 1,000 mA cm&#8722;2 were applied to the modified electrode over a long period of 800 h, and this generated a higher stability than that of the commercial IrO2. Further, its mass activity proved &#8764;2 and 7 times as high as those of IrO2 and NiFe-LDH, in that order. Furthermore, for water splitting, the produced photoelectrocatalyst obtained a current density of 1,000 mA cm&#8722;2 using only 1.6 V, and this performance remained changeless for 800 h, which can be considered the most superb performance ever reported. The experimental characterization revealed that during the process of doping Ti-MOF on NiFe-LDH, symmetry breaking takes place in the atomic structure of the LDH surface, which increases the active sites in the photoelectrocatalyst. The presence of oxygen in the Ti-MOF active sites improves the efficiency of OER at high current densities and also contributes to the higher stability of multiple heteroatomic interfaces for water splitting. The propounded strategy enables the generation of oxygen and hydrogen from water splitting at high current densities on an industrial scale by changing the symmetry of the atomic structure of heteroatomic photocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Azam Pirkarami, Arash Javanmard, Ebrahim Ghasemi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jiec.2024.05.005</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MIL-101(Fe)-derivatized cathode as an efficient oxygen electrocatalyst for rechargeable Zn-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.111828</link>
      <description>Liping Hao, Tao Yu, Rui Guo, Chunming Liu, Junhua You, Hangzhou Zhang, Journal of energy storage. 90(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396631414

                The exploration of multifunctional electrocatalysts with cost-effective and high kinetic activity for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is crucial for the development of advanced energy conversion and storage equipment. Herein, a novel hierarchical mesoporous/macropores MIL-101(Fe) derivative carbon catalyst material was prepared by a simple molten ZnCl2-assisted synthesis route. Specifically, 1H-benzotriazole (BTA) organic ligands were intentionally introduced as nitrogen sources in order to induce the formation of charge-rich regions through an electronegative nitrogen doping control strategy, and most importantly, the lone pair electron-rich nature of element N could facilitate the separation and anchoring of iron species enchanted the utilization rate of active sites. Because of these properties, the as-prepared catalyst (denoted as FeSACs/NxC) possesses unrivalled bifunction electrocatalytic activity and durability for the ORR and OER. The FeSACs/N1.25C as working electrode exhibits a quite satisfactory electrochemical performance for the ORR (half-wave potential of 0.82 V) and OER (a small overpotential of 302 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2) in the classic three-electrode configuration. Moreover, the FeSACs/N1.25C-based air cathode imparts encouraging performance in a rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery prototype with an open-circuit voltage of 1.45 V, a specific capacity of 792.16 mAh g&#8722;1, an energy density of 871.38 Wh kg&#8722;1, and excellent stability for 120 h. This work has opened the way for the development of low-cost, fast kinetic and stable non-noble metal multifunctional catalysts.</description>
      <author>Liping Hao, Tao Yu, Rui Guo, Chunming Liu, Junhua You, Hangzhou Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.est.2024.111828</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of an Internal Charge Field: CoS&lt;sub&gt;1.097&lt;/sub&gt;/Ni&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Heterojunction Promotes Efficient Urea Oxidation Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402776</link>
      <description>Mingliang Du, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396702405

                Abstract Urea oxidation reaction (UOR) features a lower overpotential compared to the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) during electrolysis, facilitating the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) at the cathode. The distribution of charge plays a pivotal role in promoting the adsorption and cleavage of chemical groups in urea molecules, which can be modulated by introducing a heterostructure. Herein, a CoS 1.097 /Ni 3 S 2 heterojunction grown on nickel foam is designed, serving simultaneously for UOR and HER. Based on density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the spontaneous charge transfer at the CoS 1.097 /Ni 3 S 2 heterointerface induces the formation of localized electrophilic/nucleophilic regions, intelligently adsorbing electron&#8208;donating/electron&#8208;withdrawing groups in urea molecules, activating chemical bonds, thereby triggering urea decomposition. CoS 1.097 /Ni 3 S 2 exhibits excellent catalytic activity for urea, requiring only a potential of 1.22 V (with an overpotential of 0.85 V) to achieve a current density of 100 mA cm &#8722;2 in UOR, and potentials of 1.27 and 1.57 V to reach current densities of 10 and 100 mA cm &#8722;2 , respectively, in a UOR//HER electrolysis cell, maintaining good stability at high current density for 60 h. Tests in real urine have demonstrated performance similar to that in urea electrolyte. This work represents nearly the best catalytic performance of transition metal&#8208;based materials in UOR applications, promising for both efficient hydrogen production and urea decomposition.</description>
      <author>Mingliang Du, Yujin Ji, Youyong Li, Shengzhong Liu, Junqing Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202402776</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of BaMnO3 nanoparticles embedded on rGO nanosheets via facile hydrothermal route to improve water oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.320</link>
      <description>Mehrun Nisa, Haifa A. Alyousef, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, B. M. Alotaibi, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Gul N. Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, A.M.A. Henaish, International journal of hydrogen energy. 68(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592358

                In light of environmental problems such as the depletion of hydrocarbon resources and global warming, the use of environment-friendly power production has become crucial nowadays. Hydrogen can serve as a globally friendly energy source because the byproduct of hydrogen combustion is only water. By a hydrothermal approach, we synthesized barium manganese oxide (BaMnO3) embedded on reduced graphene oxide (rGO) as a competent electrocatalyst for OER. We utilized X-ray diffraction (XRD), scanning electron microscope (SEM), energy dispersive x-rays (EDX), Brunauer Emmette Teller (BET) and Raman to determine the crystal structure, morphology, elemental composition, surface area and lattice phenomena of the fabricated rGO/BaMnO3 nanocomposite. The BaMnO3 agglomerated nanoparticles were incorporated into the mesoporous hollow carbon nanosheets to form amorphous textured embedded rGO/BaMnO3. This enhanced the intrinsic reactivity of rGO/BaMnO3 nanocomposite for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in addition to increasing the effective surface area of the electrolyte. The electrochemical outcomes demonstrate that synthesized nanocomposite exhibited an impressive Tafel slope (36 mV dec&#8722;1), lowest overpotential (202 mV) and remarkable stability over 35 h. Therefore, the fabricated nanocomposite displayed exceptional efficiency in OER process as well as for numerous other future applications.</description>
      <author>Mehrun Nisa, Haifa A. Alyousef, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, B. M. Alotaibi, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Gul N. Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, A.M.A. Henaish</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.320</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Selective Facet Engineering of Ni&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;5&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticle for Maximization of Electrocatalytic Oxidative Reaction of Biomass Chemicals</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00269</link>
      <description>Souradip Ganguly, Jyotishman Kaishyop, Tuhin Suvra Khan, S.K. Tarik Aziz, Arnab Dutta, Chanchal Loha, Sirshendu Ghosh, ACS sustainable chemistry &amp; engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396592375

                Electrocatalytic hydrogen generation is a prime research topic for the large-scale production of hydrogen fuel. High energy demanding oxygen evolution process impedes the production of H2 at low potentials. Conversion of biomass to value-added chemicals or fuels is appraised as an upcycling process, which is advantageous for resource management. Coupling of hydrogen generation at the cathode with oxidative conversion of biomass to market-demanded chemicals at the anode is a sustainable approach to increase energy efficiency in hybrid electrolysis. For that purpose, Ni-based anode electrocatalysts are in the forefront for ease of formation of hypervalent NiIII species, at a mild anodic potential, which act as an oxidant to propagate the oxidation and dehydrogenation reactions. Herein, we synthesized Ni12P5 nanohexagon via kinetic stabilization of high index {425&#175;} facets and compared the electrocatalytic activity toward various biomass-derived platform chemicals oxidation with the thermodynamically stable Ni12P5 nanosphere. The Ni12P5 nanohexagon outperforms the current state-of-the-art catalysts regarding mass activity, product conversion, and Faradaic yield. Ease of formation of active species, faster charge transfer, and enhanced adsorption of substrates over {425&#175;} facets resulted in this superior activity. This shape-directing effects on Ni12P5 ensured potential advantage of 150 mV in hybrid electrolysis over water splitting reaction when ethanol was used as a substrate in a two-electrode electrolyzer cell.</description>
      <author>Souradip Ganguly, Jyotishman Kaishyop, Tuhin Suvra Khan, S.K. Tarik Aziz, Arnab Dutta, Chanchal Loha, Sirshendu Ghosh</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c00269</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Induced Diffusion Effect Realizes Heterogeneous Separation/Aggregation for In Situ Fabrication of Heterostructure with Enhanced Catalytic Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405339</link>
      <description>Hang Li, Xinyu Ding, Mengfei Su, Chunyan Zhang, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu, Advanced functional materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396688368

                Abstract Space charge transfer, which can be provided by heterogeneous structure, is the key to efficient electrocatalytic processes. However, difficulty in controlling the relative atomic diffusion rates due to different atomic radii and affinity makes heterogeneous nanostructures difficult to be accurately designed. Herein, an induced diffusion strategy based on affinity differences between elements is proposed to direct the separation/aggregation of different components in the precursor. The key to strategy in this study is the different affinity of Cu and Co to S/P in the precursor of CuCo Prussian blue analogue (PBA). By controlling the molar ratio of S and P during the phosphorization/vulcanization process, induced diffusion can be achieved and leads to directional separation/aggregation of Cu and Co species. As a result, a heterogeneous yolk&#8208;shell Cu 2 S@CoP 2 &#8208;C&#8208;N&#8208;S structure is successfully synthesized with a reticular CoP2&#8208;C&#8208;N&#8208;Cu&#8208;S as the shell and a Cu 2 S nanocrystal as the core. The space charge effect of the semiconductor heterojunction resulting from component separation/aggregation significantly promotes oxygen evolution reaction, resulting in an ultralow overpotential of 180 mV at 10 mA&#183;cm &#8722;2 . This work not only provides a simple method for efficient separation of key components in gas&#8208;solid systems but also provides a method for fine&#8208;tuning the active site in an active&#8208;site&#8208;engineering approach.</description>
      <author>Hang Li, Xinyu Ding, Mengfei Su, Chunyan Zhang, Feng Gao, Qingyi Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202405339</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Nano&#8208;Interlayer Inhibiting Interfacial Degradation toward High&#8208;Voltage PEO&#8208;Based All&#8208;Solid&#8208;State Lithium Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310547</link>
      <description>Pengfei Zhai, Shuangquan Qu, Niaz Ahmad, Ze Hua, Ruiwen Shao, Wen Yang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396705586

                Abstract The interfacial instability between PEO&#8208;based solid electrolyte (SPE) and high&#8208;voltage cathode materials inhibits the longevity of high&#8208;energy&#8208;density all&#8208;solid&#8208;state polymer lithium metal batteries (ASSPLBs). Herein, for the first time it is demonstrated, that contact loss caused by gas generation from interfacial side reactions between the high&#8208;voltage cathode and solid polymer electrolyte (SPE) can also arise in ASSPLBs. To alleviate the interfacial side reactions, a LiNb 0.6 Ti 0.5 O 3 (LNTO) layer is well coated on LiNi 0.83 Co 0.07 Mn 0.1 O 2 (NCM83), denoted as (CNCM83). The LNTO layer with low electronic conductivity reduces the decomposition drive force of SPE. Furthermore, Ti and Nb in the LNTO layer spontaneously migrate inside the NCM83 surface to form a strong Ti/Nb&#9472;O bond, stalling oxygen evolution in high&#8208;voltage cathodes. The interfacial degradation phenomena, including SPE decomposition, detrimental phase transition and intragranular cracks of NCM83, and void formation between cathode and SPE, are effectively mitigated by the LNTO layer. Therefore, the growth rate of interfacial resistance (R CEI ) decreases from 37.6 &#937; h &#8722;0.5 for bare NCM83 to 2.4 &#937; h &#8722;0.5 for CNCM83 at 4.2 V. Moreover, 4.2 V PEO&#8208;based ASSPLBs achieve impressive cyclability with high capacity retention of 135 mAh g &#8722;1 (75%) even after 300 cycles at 0.5 C.</description>
      <author>Pengfei Zhai, Shuangquan Qu, Niaz Ahmad, Ze Hua, Ruiwen Shao, Wen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202310547</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the electric, dielectric and optical properties of template-free hydrothermally synthesized CuO nanostructures via Co doping</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.051</link>
      <description>M.P. Monis, H. A. A. Saadallah, Yuda Prima Hardianto, Mohamed Khairy, N. M. A. Hadia, A.M. Abdel Hakeem, E.M.M. Ibrahim, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396694255

                Facile template-free hydrothermal method was utilized for preparing CuO nanostructures (NSs) doped with Co element (Cu1-xCoxO (x=0.0, 0.02, 0.04, 0.06 and 0.08)). A single-phase monoclinic crystal with changing in morphology from rod- to sphere-like nanoparticles was observed. . The temperature dependency of DC electrical conductivity revealed that the shallow and deep donor levels are responsible for the DC conduction in low and high temperature ranges, respectively. The Ac electrical conductivity, dielectric constant and dielectric loss were also measured as functions in frequency and temperature. The frequency dependence of the AC conductivity was well represented by the Jonscher's universal power law. The AC conduction was governed by the Correlated Barrier Hopping model where the inter-well and intra-well hopping mechanisms contribute to the electrical conduction in the low and high frequency ranges, respectively. The activation energies and the barrier height decreased while the dielectric constant and dielectric loss increased with increasing the Co content. The relaxation and deformational polarizations predominate and the overall behavior of dielectric constant fits well with the Koops' model. The Cole-Cole plots indicated a decrease in the sample resistance with increasing temperatures and Co concentrations. UV-vis absorption spectra exhibited two peaks at wavelengths 252 and 323 nm. The optical energy gap was calculated using Tauc's equation and decrease from 2.24 to 2.1 eV with increasing the Co concentrations. The effect of Co-doping on CuO was explored for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and found a decrease in the overvoltage (&#956;) about 50 mV at 0.08 ratios, which declares that the doping of Co element enhances the electrical conductivity and feasibility for further electrocatalytic improvement.</description>
      <author>M.P. Monis, H. A. A. Saadallah, Yuda Prima Hardianto, Mohamed Khairy, N. M. A. Hadia, A.M. Abdel Hakeem, E.M.M. Ibrahim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dealloying of Mg-based alloys for production of self-supporting metallic nanostructures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intermet.2024.108308</link>
      <description>Jian&#8208;Bin Lin, Weitao Zheng, Wenxue Ke, Xin He, Pei Liang, Chengkai Zhang, Intermetallics. 170(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396650185

                Dealloying is a proficient technique in the fabrication of nanostructured metals, particularly nanoporous materials, with promising potential for diverse applications. However, the development of robust and self-standing nanostructured metal foils through dealloying presents significant challenges. By generating an alloy layer on the surface of the metal foil, nanostructures can be generated on the metal foil surface through subsequent dealloying. This approach utilizes the inherent flexibility and ductility of the metal foil to ensure self-support. It also allows for the tailoring of the structure and composition of the dealloyed nanostructured metal by manipulation of the phase constitution in the surface alloy layer. In this study, we report a strategy for generating alloy layers on metal foil surfaces through the thermal evaporation of magnesium (Mg) followed by annealing. Upon dealloying the surface alloy layer, we successfully obtain self-supported nanostructured metal foils. Employing copper (Cu) as an example, we demonstrate that Mg can form a Mg&#8211;Cu alloy layer on the surface of a Cu foil, where the control over the alloy layer's phase composition and thickness is achieved by adjusting the annealing duration. Furthermore, we investigated the feasibility of this method on nickel (Ni) substrates, including Ni foils and Ni foams. Moreover, by further functionalizing the resulting nanostructured Ni foil, we transformed it into Ni(OH)2/Ni foil and explored its performance in the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The resulting catalyst achieved a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at a potential of only 349 mV in a 1 M KOH solution, exhibiting a Tafel slope of 84.52 mV dec&#8722;1. Following 10 h of stability testing, the catalyst exhibited negligible degradation in performance. This study provides a convenient and versatile pathway for preparing self-supported nanostructured metals.</description>
      <author>Jian&#8208;Bin Lin, Weitao Zheng, Wenxue Ke, Xin He, Pei Liang, Chengkai Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.intermet.2024.108308</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Functional consequences of modification of the photosystem I/photosystem II ratio in the cyanobacterium &lt;i&gt;Synechocystis&lt;/i&gt; sp. PCC 6803</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1128/jb.00454-23</link>
      <description>Vicki Moore, Wim F. J. Vermaas, Journal of bacteriology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396581225

                ABSTRACT The stoichiometry of photosystem II (PSII) and photosystem I (PSI) varies between photoautotrophic organisms. The cyanobacterium Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803 maintains two- to fivefold more PSI than PSII reaction center complexes, and we sought to modify this stoichiometry by changing the promoter region of the psaAB operon. We thus generated mutants with varied psaAB expression, ranging from ~3% to almost 200% of the wild-type transcript level, but all showing a reduction in PSI levels, relative to wild type, suggesting a role of the psaAB promoter region in translational regulation. Mutants with 25%&#8211;70% of wild-type PSI levels were photoautotrophic, with whole-chain oxygen evolution rates on a per-cell basis comparable to that of wild type. In contrast, mutant strains with &lt;10% of the wild-type level of PSI were obligate photoheterotrophs. Variable fluorescence yields of all mutants were much higher than those of wild type, indicating that the PSI content is localized differently than in wild type, with less transfer of PSII-absorbed energy to PSI. Strains with less PSI saturate at a higher light intensity, enhancing productivity at higher light intensities. This is similar to what is found in mutants with reduced antennae. With 3-(3,4-dichlorophenyl)-1,1-dimethylurea present, P700 + re-reduction kinetics in the mutants were slower than in wild type, consistent with the notion that there is less cyclic electron transport if less PSI is present. Overall, strains with a reduction in PSI content displayed surprisingly vigorous growth and linear electron transport. IMPORTANCE Consequences of reduction in photosystem I content were investigated in the cyanobacterium Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803 where photosystem I far exceeds the number of photosystem II complexes. Strains with less photosystem I displayed less cyclic electron transport, grew more slowly at lower light intensity and needed more light for saturation but were surprisingly normal in their whole-chain electron transport rates, implying that a significant fraction of photosystem I is dispensable for linear electron transport in cyanobacteria. These strains with reduced photosystem I levels may have biotechnological relevance as they grow well at higher light intensities.</description>
      <author>Vicki Moore, Wim F. J. Vermaas</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1128/jb.00454-23</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of solution pH on the dynamics of oxygen bubbles on the surface of TiO2-NTAs electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.293</link>
      <description>Qiang Xu, Jiayang Chi, Tengfei Nie, Yonglu She, Xinyi Luo, Liejin Guo, International journal of hydrogen energy. 69(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396650718

                The rise of concentration resistance caused by bubble growth is a key factor affecting the photoelectrochemical water splitting efficiency. In this research, we employed an electrochemical workstation, a synchronized measuring system, and a CCD camera to investigate the in-situ evolution of oxygen bubbles on the surfaces of TiO2-NTAs and C/TiO2-NTAs electrodes. The connection among the critical nucleation, growth and departure behavior of a single bubble on the photoanode surface and photocurrent curves at different solution pH (1&#8211;13) has been investigated. For TiO2-NTAs, it was found that strong alkalinity significantly reduces the voltage required for critical bubble nucleation. The photocurrent rises approximately 1.5 times when the control voltage is 0.10 V (vs. Ag/AgCl) by pH increasing from 1 to 13 and while the bubble evolution cycles decline by approximately 3.2 times. The photocurrent rises by 10.4 times compared with pH = 9 and by 7.3 times compared with pH = 13 when the control voltage is 0.71 V (vs. RHE), respectively. We also found that the oxygen bubble evolution of C/TiO2-NTAs is similar to TiO2-NTAs. When pH = 3&#8211;13, the average photocurrent of C/TiO2-NTAs electrode is higher than that of TiO2-NTAs, and the average bubble evolution cycles are lower than those of TiO2-NTAs at the same pH. According to the results, carbon films can rise the absorption capacity of TiO2-NTAs and significantly improve the effectiveness of photogenerated holes and electrons departure. Meanwhile, based on the oxygen bubble force balance model on the photoanode surface, the concentration Marangoni force rises with the increase of pH, which leads to the growth of bubble departure diameter. The outcomes demonstrate that oxygen bubbles on the photoanode surface can be successfully eliminated in strongly alkaline settings.</description>
      <author>Qiang Xu, Jiayang Chi, Tengfei Nie, Yonglu She, Xinyi Luo, Liejin Guo</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.04.293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Implications of Thermal Hydrodynamic Atmospheric Escape on the
  TRAPPIST-1 Planets</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.02401</link>
      <description>Megan T. Gialluca, R. Barnes, Victoria Meadows, Rodolfo Garc&#237;a, Jessica Birky, Eric Agol, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396715330

                JWST observations of the 7-planet TRAPPIST-1 system will provide an excellent opportunity to test outcomes of stellar-driven evolution of terrestrial planetary atmospheres, including atmospheric escape, ocean loss and abiotic oxygen production. While most previous studies use a single luminosity evolution for the host star, we incorporate observational uncertainties in stellar mass, luminosity evolution, system age, and planetary parameters to statistically explore the plausible range of planetary atmospheric escape outcomes. We present probabilistic distributions of total water loss and oxygen production as a function of initial water content, for planets with initially pure water atmospheres and no interior-atmosphere exchange. We find that the interior planets are desiccated for initial water contents below 50 Earth oceans. For TRAPPIST-1e, f, g, and h, we report maximum water loss ranges of 8.0$^{+1.3}_{-0.9}$, 4.8$^{+0.6}_{-0.4}$, 3.4$^{+0.3}_{-0.3}$, and 0.8$^{+0.2}_{-0.1}$ Earth oceans, respectively, with corresponding maximum oxygen retention of 1290$^{+75}_{-75}$, 800$^{+40}_{-40}$, 560$^{+30}_{-25}$, and 90$^{+10}_{-10}$ bars. We explore statistical constraints on initial water content imposed by current water content, which could inform evolutionary history and planet formation. If TRAPPIST-1b is airless while TRAPPIST-1c possesses a tenuous oxygen atmosphere, as initial JWST observations suggest, then our models predict an initial surface water content of 8.2$^{+1.5}_{-1.0}$ Earth oceans for these worlds, leading to the outer planets retaining $&gt;$1.5 Earth oceans after entering the habitable zone. Even if TRAPPIST-1c is airless, surface water on the outer planets would not be precluded.</description>
      <author>Megan T. Gialluca, R. Barnes, Victoria Meadows, Rodolfo Garc&#237;a, Jessica Birky, Eric Agol</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.02401</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Catalytic and Oxygen Release Capability in LaFe&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ni&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; to Intensify Chemical Looping Reactions at Medium Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01386</link>
      <description>Rongjiang Zhang, Gen Liu, Chunyong Huo, Lijun Jia, Bo Zhang, Bolun Yang, Xiaoyong Tian, Zhiqiang Wu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396645619

                Perovskite oxygen carriers in a methane chemical looping partial oxidation process enable high reactivity over 850 &#176;C. Lowering the reaction temperature helps to circumvent energy dissipation and couple the above-mentioned process with energy-efficient systems. This paper demonstrates the attractive oxygen-donating capacity of Fe&#8211;Ni-based perovskite oxygen carriers for methane partial oxidation. The aforesaid process exhibits more than 70% methane conversion and 6.71 mmol&#183;g&#8211;1 unit syngas yield at 700 &#176;C, using LaFe0.5Ni0.5O3. This impressive high reactivity mainly originates from the lowered lattice oxygen bonding strength and the spontaneously constructed active Ni-rich surface of perovskite oxides by Ni doping. In addition to the outward migration of lattice oxygen, active metal elements, such as Ni, continuously segregate to the surface with the reduction of perovskite oxides, promoting methane partial oxidation. We speculate that the chemical looping reaction pathway consists of consecutive competitive reactions based on analysis of the real-time product distribution and the dynamic evolution of oxygen carriers. Highly selective syngas production can be achieved on LaFe0.5Ni0.5O3 by reducing reaction temperatures or increasing space velocity to balance methane dissociation and lattice oxygen release kinetics. Irreversible Ni segregation and phase-separation-induced inert La2O3 on the surface of perovskite oxides during redox cycles are responsible for the cyclic performance degradation of oxygen carriers. This work offers intriguing references to design perovskite oxygen carriers for intensifying the medium-temperature chemical looping partial oxidation process.</description>
      <author>Rongjiang Zhang, Gen Liu, Chunyong Huo, Lijun Jia, Bo Zhang, Bolun Yang, Xiaoyong Tian, Zhiqiang Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01386</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advancements in marine micropaleontological and paleoceanographic research from India</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s43538-024-00307-9</link>
      <description>Arun D. Singh, Pothuri Divakar Naidu, Proceedings of the Indian National Science Academy. Part A, Physical Sciences. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396652208

                The article presents an overview of the research contributions in the field of Marine Micropaleontology and Paleoceanography, made by the Indian scientists during the last five years. Keeping pace with recent development in analytical techniques, significant contributions have been made in diversified research aspects: paleoceanographic proxy development, Asian monsoon variability and dynamics, Neogene-Quaternary evolution of the Indian Ocean in relation to the global climate change, carbonate cycle and ocean acidification, development of oxygen minimum zone and its variability through time. Although, the major emphasis is given to the Indian Ocean paleoceanographic studies, a few Indian research groups are also actively engaged in understanding ocean-climate evolution of the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans, inter-basinal connections and their implications on global ocean deep circulation and climate on tectonic to millennial time scales.</description>
      <author>Arun D. Singh, Pothuri Divakar Naidu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s43538-024-00307-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black TiO2 and Oxygen Vacancies: Unraveling the Role in the Thermal Anatase-to-Rutile Transformation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/applnano5020007</link>
      <description>Mattia Allieta, Mauro Coduri, Alberto Naldoni, Applied nano. 5(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396613998

                Understanding the role of oxygen vacancies in the phase transformation of metal oxide nanomaterials is fundamental to design more efficient opto-electronic devices for a variety of applications, including sensing, spintronics, photocatalysis, and photo-electrochemistry. However, the structural mechanisms behind the phase transformation in reducible oxides remain poorly described. Here, we compare P25 and black TiO2 during the thermal anatase-to-rutile transformation using in situ synchrotron powder diffraction. The precise measurement of the phase fractions, unit cell parameters, and Ti-O bond sheds light on the phase transformation dynamics. Notably, we observe distinct temperature-dependent shifts in the relative phase fractions of anatase and rutile in both materials highlighting the role of the oxygen vacancy in promoting the phase transformation. We employ bond valence concepts for structural modeling, revealing unique trends in temperature evolution of Ti-O distances of black rutile, confirming that this TiO2 phase is preferentially reduced over anatase. These findings not only enhance our understanding of phase transitions in TiO2 but also open new ways for the design of advanced photocatalytic materials through targeted phase control.</description>
      <author>Mattia Allieta, Mauro Coduri, Alberto Naldoni</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/applnano5020007</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buoyancy control and air breathing in royal knifefish (&lt;i&gt;Chitala blanci&lt;/i&gt;) and a new hypothesis for the early evolution of vertebrate air&#8208;breathing behaviors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.25460</link>
      <description>Elska B Kaczmarek, Elizabeth L. Brainerd, &#152;The &#156;anatomical record. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396704495

                Abstract We present the first description of inspiration&#8208;first air breaths in royal knifefish, Chitala blanci , a ray&#8208;finned fish known to use four&#8208;stroke air breaths. Four&#8208;stroke breaths are used by nearly all ray&#8208;finned fish species that use their gas bladder to breathe air and are the ancestral breath type of ray&#8208;finned fishes. Interestingly, one such species, Amia calva , is known to perform two distinct breath types. Amia use four&#8208;stroke breaths when they need more oxygen and performs inspiration&#8208;first breaths to restore buoyancy. We observed that C. blanci also performs inspiration&#8208;first breaths and tested whether the two breath types are performed for the same functions in C. blanci as they are in Amia . We recorded the frequency of each breath type when exposed to aquatic hypoxia and two conditions of oxygen availability. We found that C. blanci performed more four&#8208;stroke breaths (81% &#177; 15% of total breaths) than inspiration&#8208;first breaths when exposed to aerial normoxia but performed more inspiration&#8208;first breaths (72% &#177; 40%) than four&#8208;stroke breaths when exposed to aerial hyperoxia. These patterns match those described for Amia and indicate that C. blanci performs four&#8208;stroke breaths in response to oxygen depletion and performs inspiration&#8208;first breaths to maintain buoyancy. Few studies have examined the role of air&#8208;breathing in buoyancy regulation. Decreasing buoyancy, rather than oxygen availability, to stimulate air breaths may reveal that inspiration&#8208;first breaths are more common among fishes than we are aware. We consider this possibility and present a new hypothesis for the origin and early evolution of air breathing in vertebrates.</description>
      <author>Elska B Kaczmarek, Elizabeth L. Brainerd</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ar.25460</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spin-selective evolution of the Zhang-Rice state in binary transition metal oxide MnO(001) film</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.195111</link>
      <description>Asish K. Kundu, P. M. Sheverdyaeva, Paolo Moras, Krishnakumar S. R. Menon, Subhasish Mandal, C. Carbone, Physical review. B./Physical review. B. 109(19)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396625669

                The Zhang-Rice (ZR) state is a strongly hybridized bound state formed by transition-metal and oxygen atoms. The spin fluctuations within the ZR state are known to play an important role in high-${T}_{\mathrm{c}}$ superconductivity in cuprates. Here, we employ a combination of angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES), x-ray photoemission spectroscopy (XPS), and ab initio embedded dynamical mean-field theory (eDMFT) to investigate the influence of magnetic ordering on the spectral characteristics of the valence band and Mn $2p$ core-level in MnO (001) ultrathin films. Our results demonstrate that a complex spin-selective evolution of Mn $3d\ensuremath{-}\mathrm{O}\phantom{\rule{4pt}{0ex}}2p$ hybridization develops due to the long-range antiferromagnetic (AFM) ordering. This hybridization significantly alters the spectral shape and weight of the ZR state. Specifically, in the AFM phase, we observed the sharpening of the ZR state and band folding with the periodicity of the AFM unit cell of MnO(001). We also demonstrated a strong connection between the spectral evolution of the ZR state and the non-local screening channels of the photoexcited core holes. Further, our detailed temperature-dependent study reveals the presence of short-range antiferromagnetic correlations that exist at much higher temperatures than Neel temperature $({T}_{\mathrm{N}})$ and shows the evolution of the ZR state across the magnetic transitions and its implication to the core-hole screening in $3d$ binary transition metal oxides.</description>
      <author>Asish K. Kundu, P. M. Sheverdyaeva, Paolo Moras, Krishnakumar S. R. Menon, Subhasish Mandal, C. Carbone</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1103/physrevb.109.195111</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Observation of the Interface Reaction Dynamics of the Ndcefeb Phase Via In-Situ Annealing &amp;amp; Quenching Stem</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4816937</link>
      <description>Xiangyu Zhu, Qingxiao Wang, Yan Li, Byung Oh Jung, Myungshin Choi, Sunyong Song, Seok Namkung, Nam Lyong Kang, Hyungsoon Shin, Minho Joo, Xianming Dai, Moon Kim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396647807

                Although the Rare Earth (RE)2Fe14B type magnets were invented in the 1980s and are widely used worldwide. Yet, the phase formation and dissolution mechanisms are still not crystal clear. The reaction dynamics between rare earth elements (REE) and Iron enriched matrix is essential to understand the formation of hard magnetic REE-Fe-B phase or, conversely, phase dissociation and performance degeneration. The development of reaction mechanism is fundamentally important for process engineering and performance manipulation. This work investigates the interface reaction dynamics between REE and Iron enriched matrix via in-situ scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM). The Focused ion beam (FIB) procedure and in-situ STEM experiments are specifically designed to achieve both oxygen-involved and oxygen-free reaction mechanisms within one specimen. The reaction dynamics at high temperatures are frozen to room temperature (RT) by rapid quenching, preserving the solid-liquid interface dynamics between Fe23B6 and liquid phases. Serial atomic resolution STEM images depict lattice evolution while REE atoms embed into the Fe23B6 lattice. The presented work also demonstrates that combining advanced FIB procedure with in-situ annealing &amp; quenching STEM is a powerful tool for investigating high-temperature reaction mechanisms and interface phenomena of the complex system.</description>
      <author>Xiangyu Zhu, Qingxiao Wang, Yan Li, Byung Oh Jung, Myungshin Choi, Sunyong Song, Seok Namkung, Nam Lyong Kang, Hyungsoon Shin, Minho Joo, Xianming Dai, Moon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4816937</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space confined growth of RuO2/Ru carbon nanorods for highly efficient electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113258</link>
      <description>Ruilin He, Piaoping Yang, Maoyuan Zhang, Jingchuan Wang, Yawei Hao, Lijun Yang, Vacuum. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396621741

                Exploring efficient and robust electrocatalysts with low cost for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) is critical for practical application of electrochemical water splitting. Ru-based platinum group electrocatalysts shows great potential in HER, however, Ru suffer from sluggish kinetics of water dissociation for electrochemical reduction of water to hydrogen in alkaline environments. Here, oxygen atoms are introduced into Ru by simple secondary heat treatment to form Ru-O-C bonds to weak the strength of Ru-H bond. The overpotential of the catalyst is only 19 mV at 10 mA cm-2 and the stability is greatly improved. Theoretical calculations reveal that the Ru-O-C structure formed in RuO2 facilitates the dissociation of H-OH, which is the rate-determining step in alkaline electrolytes, leading to significant improvement in HER activity.</description>
      <author>Ruilin He, Piaoping Yang, Maoyuan Zhang, Jingchuan Wang, Yawei Hao, Lijun Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.vacuum.2024.113258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graphite-N reinforced sludge biochar electrode: A experimental and DFT theoretical analysis of efficient evolution and in-situ utilization of H2O2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2024.124107</link>
      <description>Chenxi Li, Xiaojie Qiu, Huilin Wan, Zehao Ma, Ruotong Jin, Yan Zhao, Environmental pollution. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396745336

                Rational reuse of municipal sludge to produce electro-Fenton electrode can not only save resources, but also produce superior peroxide and degradation pollutants simultaneously. Herein, a novel electro-Fenton electrode derived from sludge biochar loaded on Ni foam (SBC@Ni) was constructed via high temperature pyrolysis and chemical coating for efficient H2O2 evolution and pollutant degradation. Systematic experiments and density functional theory calculations (DFT calculation) explained that the production of graphite C and graphite N during high-temperature pyrolysis of municipal sludge can greatly enhance the oxygen reduction reaction of SBC@Ni electrode and promote the evolution of H2O2. And the hybrid heterojunctions, such as FeP, also played a key role in electrocatalytic processes. Notably, the electrode still exhibited excellent performance after 1000 linear scans and 12 hours of continuous current stimulation, which demonstrated the excellent stability of the electrode. Moreover, SBC@Ni electrode can not only effectively oxidize 4-chlorophenol through the electro-Fenton effect, but also fully mineralize organic matter, indicating promising environmental application. The free radical quenching experiment also revealed that the &#183;OH is the main active species for 4-CP degradation in SBC@Ni electro-Fenton system.</description>
      <author>Chenxi Li, Xiaojie Qiu, Huilin Wan, Zehao Ma, Ruotong Jin, Yan Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2024.124107</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sedimentary Environment, Tectonic Setting, and Uranium Mineralization Implications of the Yimin Formation, Kelulun Depression, Hailar Basin, China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12050763</link>
      <description>Fanyu Meng, Fengjun Nie, Fei Xia, Zhaobin Yan, D. H. Sun, Wenbo Zhou, Xin Zhang, Qing Wang, Journal of marine science and engineering. 12(5)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396578871

                The sandstone-type uranium deposit of the Kelulun Depression is the first industrially valuable uranium deposit discovered in the Hailar Basin. This study performed a systematic examination of 17 sandstone samples from the Yimin Formation in the Kelulun Depression based on various analytical techniques. The findings of the current study were synthesized with previous research to investigate the impact of the redox conditions and the tectonic background of the source area, as well as the paleoclimatic evolution of the Yimin Formation on uranium mineralization. The elemental Mo, U/Th, V/Cr, Ni/Co, and V/(V+Ni) ratios indicate that the paleowater was in an oxygen-rich environment during the deposition of the Yimin Formation. Additionally, the C-value, Sr/Cu, Al2O3/MgO, and Rb/Sr ratios indicate that the Yimin Formation was formed in a paleoclimate characterized by arid-to-semi-arid conditions. The geochemical characteristics of the observed elements indicated that the sediment source of the Yimin Formation was mainly felsic rocks from the upper continental crust, the weathering of the rock was weak, and the tectonic background was a passive continental margin. Coffinite is distributed in the form of cementation and stellates within or around pyrite crystals, and uranium-titanium oxide is mostly distributed in an irregular granular distribution in the biotite cleavage fractures of the study area. In summary, the findings of this study reveal that the tectonic settings, provenance, uranium source, paleoclimate, and oxygen-rich paleowater of the Yimin Formation have important geological significance for the large-scale uranium mineralization of the Kelulun Depression.</description>
      <author>Fanyu Meng, Fengjun Nie, Fei Xia, Zhaobin Yan, D. H. Sun, Wenbo Zhou, Xin Zhang, Qing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/jmse12050763</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Vertical Plasma Motion on the Evolution of Predawn Equatorial Plasma Bubbles on the Dayside</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1029/2024gl109241</link>
      <description>H. Kil, J. D. Huba, L. J. Paxton, Geophysical research letters. 51(9)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396591110

                Abstract This study investigates the impact of vertical ionospheric drift during daytime on the evolution of predawn equatorial plasma bubbles by conducting model simulations using &#8220;Sami3 is Another Model of the Ionosphere.&#8221; The upward drift of the ionosphere transports bubbles to higher altitudes, where their lifetime is set by the atomic oxygen photoionization rate. While the bubbles generated at predawn persist into dayside, the bubbles generated shortly after sunset diminish before sunrise. Therefore, post&#8208;sunset bubbles do not contribute to daytime electron density irregularities. Bubbles maintain their field&#8208;aligned characteristics throughout the daytime regardless of the vertical ionospheric drift. This property allows bubbles to exist near the magnetic equator despite poleward plasma transport by the fountain process. The shift of irregularity concentration to higher latitudes over time in satellite observations is explained by the combined effect of transport of bubbles to higher altitudes and rapid refilling of depletions near the magnetic equator.</description>
      <author>H. Kil, J. D. Huba, L. J. Paxton</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1029/2024gl109241</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross-scale deciphering thermal failure process of Ni-rich layered cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109685</link>
      <description>Ding Yang, Yan Li, Ruoyu Xu, Xiaopeng Han, Kai Huang, Xiaoxing Ke, Bo Wang, Manling Sui, Pengfei Yan, Nano energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396644926

                Ni-rich LiNixCoyMn1-x-yO2 (NCM) layered oxides are low-cost high-energy density cathode materials, but plagued by its poor thermal stability incurred safety concerns. The thermal failure process of the layered cathode is accompanied by heat generation and oxygen release, which drives the battery into thermal runaway (TR). Aiming to fully understand the TR process and the structure evolution, this work applies diverse characterization techniques onto a polycrystalline Ni-rich layered cathode (LiNi0.83Mn0.05Co0.12O2 (PCN83)) to comprehensively investigate its thermal failure process at multiple scales. From macro level, we validate that it is the cathode thermal failure that drives the battery from the heat accumulation stage into TR in adiabatic conditions. From micro level, transmission electron microscopy (TEM) verifies that the thermal failure of PCN83 starts from 150 &#176;C, which is much lower than the TR temperature measured from macro level tests. We reveal that the PCN83 cathode experiences sequential phase transitions before the TR, where the phase transition mechanism is illustrated from the atomic scale and the pore evolution process is unraveled. In situ heating TEM further reveals that thermal failure is preferentially initiated from grain boundaries and defect regions. These findings provide an in-depth understanding of the whole thermal failure process of NMC-based layered cathode materials and sheds new lights on the rational design of Ni-rich cathode materials with improved thermal safety.</description>
      <author>Ding Yang, Yan Li, Ruoyu Xu, Xiaopeng Han, Kai Huang, Xiaoxing Ke, Bo Wang, Manling Sui, Pengfei Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.109685</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrosion Kinetics of T91 Steel under Low Oxygen Conditions (10-7wt% O) in Lead-Bismuth Eutectic at 500 &#186;C</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109106</link>
      <description>Shujian Tian, Zhizhong Jiang, Ge Zhu, Lin Luo, Jing Liu, Materials today communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396640774

                Among the advanced reactor designs of the fourth generation, the Lead-cooled Fast Reactor (LFR) stands out as one of six distinct types. The corrosion caused by the liquid Lead-Bismuth Eutectic (LBE) on structural materials is recognized as a significant obstacle hindering the development of LFR. The corrosion kinetics of T91 steel in static LBE with 10-7 wt% oxygen at 500 &#186;C is analyzed in this study. The formed oxide scale consists of an outer (Fe, Cr)3O4 layer with a Fe-Cr spinel structure and an inner internal oxidation zone (IOZ). The thickness evolution of the oxide layers follows a parabolic rule, with rate constants determined for different layers. The dissolution rate of metals into the LBE decreases over time, indicating diminishing the concentration gradient of Fe across the oxide layer-LBE interface. The observed deviations from expected norms may be attributed to dynamic flow conditions and non-isothermal loop experiments, which accelerate Fe diffusion into LBE.</description>
      <author>Shujian Tian, Zhizhong Jiang, Ge Zhu, Lin Luo, Jing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtcomm.2024.109106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mechanism of stress evolution in environmental barrier coatings considering the presence of crack channels</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.072</link>
      <description>Jinkang Du, Guoqiang Yu, Beichen Xue, &#21843;&#26230; &#26085;&#39640;, Jiaming Li, Xiguang Gao, Yang Song, Fang Wang, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396706248

                The roles of crack channel transitions and thermally grown oxides (TGO) in the failure of environmental barrier coatings (EBCs) should be clarified. Hence, in this study, the laws of penetration and delamination crack evolution were investigated using a virtual crack extension method for multilayer materials to gain insights into the transformation conditions with a framework for a coupled thermal/mechanical/chemical numerical model of TGO containing channel cracks developed based on this law. The framework integrates diffusion, TGO growth, and phase transformation of the oxides. A theoretical model for high-temperature gas corrosion of EBCs coupled with deformation, mass diffusion, and chemical reactions was proposed, with the results indicating that the cracks transitioned from vertical to exfoliation cracks in the ytterbium dibasic silicate (YbDS) layer. The coupling effect of cracks and stresses led to non-uniform growth of the TGO by affecting the oxygen diffusion and inflow rates. The y-direction stresses at the YbDS/TGO interface near the crack channel changed from compressive to tensile stresses after cooling, making the first location to undergo delamination failure. The proposed model can provide better guidance for designing EBCs systems and supporting the life prediction of EBCs in service environments.</description>
      <author>Jinkang Du, Guoqiang Yu, Beichen Xue, &#21843;&#26230; &#26085;&#39640;, Jiaming Li, Xiguang Gao, Yang Song, Fang Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spectroscopy and Photochemistry of [Al, N, C, O, H]: Connectivity to Aluminium&#8208;Bearing Species in the Universe</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401397</link>
      <description>Lina Wang, Xin Jiang, Beibei Sun, Tarek Trabelsi, Joseph S. Francisco, Xiaoqing Zeng, Mingfei Zhou, Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396669343

                Aluminium is one of the most abundant metals in the universe and impacts the evolution of various astrophysical environments. Currently detected Al&#8208;bearing molecules represent only a small fraction of the aluminium budget, suggesting that aluminium may reside in other species. AlO and AlOH molecules are abundant in the oxygen&#8208;rich supergiant stars such as VY Canis Majoris, a stellar molecular factory with 60+ molecules including the prebiotic NC&#8208;bearing species. Additional Al&#8208;bearing molecules with N, C, O, and H may form in O&#8208;rich environments with radiation&#8208;accelerated chemistry. Here, we present spectroscopic identification of novel aluminium&#8208;bearing molecules composed of [Al, N, C, O, H] and [Al, N, C, O] from the reactions of Al atoms and HNCO in solid argon matrix, which are potential Al&#8208;bearing molecules in space. Photoinduced transformations among six [Al, N, C, O, H] isomers and three [Al, N, C, O] isomers, along with their dissociation reactions forming the known interstellar species, have been disclosed. These results provide new insight into the chemical network of astronomically detected Al&#8208;bearing species in space.</description>
      <author>Lina Wang, Xin Jiang, Beibei Sun, Tarek Trabelsi, Joseph S. Francisco, Xiaoqing Zeng, Mingfei Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.202401397</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel ultra-low NOx coal combustion technologies based on local microenvironment targeted regulation. Part 1. Selective oxygenation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.combustflame.2024.113486</link>
      <description>Xiuchao Yang, Jiaxun Liu, Guoqing Chen, Zining Zhou, Xinyu Zhong, Jianguo Liu, Xiumin Jiang, Combustion and flame. 265(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396650281

                Developing a novel high-efficiency coal combustion technology with ultra-low NOx emission is urgently needed to sustain the good ecological environment. Here, the targeted regulation of local microenvironment around fuel-N, such as functional groups, radicals, molecular configurations, and reaction atmosphere, is realized by the selective oxidation. The molecular configurations, including pore networks and microcrystalline structure in coal, are well characterized through synchrotron radiation-induced SAXS (small angle X-ray scattering) and WAXS (wide angle X-ray scattering) simultaneously. Furthermore, by combining density functional theory (DFT) and experiments, the effects of the local microenvironment on the nitrogen transformation and NO evolution during the thermal conversion are focused on. The results indicate that for the PPA oxidation, the H radicals attack the adjacent carbon to pyrrole/pyridine nitrogen, promoting the conversion of fuel-N to HCN. On the other hand, for the H2O2 oxidation, disrupting the &#960; bond electron cloud by the CO and C = O on the ortho carbon of pyrrole/pyridine dominates the NH3 generation. Additionally, the increased La (average graphene layer extent), a3 (average interlayer spacing), &#963;3 (standard deviation of interlayer spacing) and &#963;1 (standard deviation of the first-neighbor distribution) induce massive smaller pores, promoting the generation of abundant reaction defects inside the particles. Importantly, the intensified adsorption on abundant active sites lead to the decreased HCN and increased NH3 evolution, which is adverse for the interaction between homogeneous and heterogeneous NO reduction. Interestingly, the PAA selective oxidation can reduce NO emission by 31.72 % - 34.30 % during the air combustion, which is far better than the H2O2 oxidation. Overall, the attack of free radicals on nitrogen-containing heterocycles promotes the conversion of fuel-N to HCN, the adsorption of which on char surfaces can further enhance the heterogeneous reduction in a lean oxygen atmosphere. The work here provides a novel route for developing high-efficiency and low-NOx combustion technologies.</description>
      <author>Xiuchao Yang, Jiaxun Liu, Guoqing Chen, Zining Zhou, Xinyu Zhong, Jianguo Liu, Xiumin Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.combustflame.2024.113486</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycogen synthesis prevents metabolic imbalance and disruption of photosynthetic electron transport from photosystem &lt;scp&gt;II&lt;/scp&gt; during transition to photomixotrophy in &lt;i&gt;Synechocystis&lt;/i&gt; sp. &lt;scp&gt;PCC&lt;/scp&gt; 6803</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19793</link>
      <description>Pablo Ortega&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Lauri Nikkanen, Laura T. Wey, Francisco J. Florencio, Yagut Allahverdiyeva, Sandra D&#237;az&#8208;Troya, New phytologist. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396662875

                Summary Some cyanobacteria can grow photoautotrophically or photomixotrophically by using simultaneously CO 2 and glucose. The switch between these trophic modes and the role of glycogen, their main carbon storage macromolecule, was investigated. We analysed the effect of glucose addition on the physiology, metabolic and photosynthetic state of Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803 and mutants lacking phosphoglucomutase and ADP&#8208;glucose pyrophosphorylase, with limitations in glycogen synthesis. Glycogen acted as a metabolic buffer: glucose addition increased growth and glycogen reserves in the wild&#8208;type (WT), but arrested growth in the glycogen synthesis mutants. Already 30 min after glucose addition, metabolites from the Calvin&#8211;Benson&#8211;Bassham cycle and the oxidative pentose phosphate shunt increased threefold more in the glycogen synthesis mutants than the WT. These alterations substantially affected the photosynthetic performance of the glycogen synthesis mutants, as O 2 evolution and CO 2 uptake were both impaired. We conclude that glycogen synthesis is essential during transitions to photomixotrophy to avoid metabolic imbalance that induces inhibition of electron transfer from PSII and subsequently accumulation of reactive oxygen species, loss of PSII core proteins, and cell death. Our study lays foundations for optimising photomixotrophy&#8208;based biotechnologies through understanding the coordination of the crosstalk between photosynthetic electron transport and metabolism.</description>
      <author>Pablo Ortega&#8208;Mart&#237;nez, Lauri Nikkanen, Laura T. Wey, Francisco J. Florencio, Yagut Allahverdiyeva, Sandra D&#237;az&#8208;Troya</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1111/nph.19793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of lapped sequence on corrosion behavior and mechanism of pure titanium/galvanized steel joint using cold metal transfer joining technology</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpvp.2024.105203</link>
      <description>Jinghuan Chang, Jian&#8208;Feng Wen, Rui Cao, Yingjie Yan, Ran Sui, S.T. Tu, International journal of pressure vessels and piping. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396642626

                Titanium/steel joints are widely used in petrochemical, nuclear and aerospace industries. The lapped sequence of dissimilar metal lapped joints can considerably affect their mechanical and corrosion properties. In the study, the microstructure and corrosion behavior of pure titanium/galvanized steel dissimilar cold metal transfer welding joints with different lapped sequences were investigated using microscopic examination, immersion and electrochemical corrosion tests. Pure titanium/galvanized steel joints can be defined as Ti/steel joint (the Ti sheet on top of the steel sheet) or steel/Ti joint (the steel sheet on top of the Ti sheet). The results showed that the corrosion resistance of the Ti/steel joint was poorer than that of the steel/Ti joint in artificial seawater solution because of the formation of larger intermetallics in the weld metal of the Ti/steel joint. Galvanic corrosion occurred in both the Ti/steel and steel/Ti joints. The interface between the galvanized steel base metal and weld metal was the weakest zone in both joints. Moreover, the corrosion mechanisms of the Ti/steel and steel/Ti joints were similar, the reactions were the reduction of oxygen and the evolution of H2 at the cathode. Anodic reactions included the oxidation of metal ions, the formation of TiO2 oxide film and the oxidation of the intermetallics. These findings could contribute to a better understanding of the corrosion behavior of titanium/steel lapped joints under artificial seawater conditions.</description>
      <author>Jinghuan Chang, Jian&#8208;Feng Wen, Rui Cao, Yingjie Yan, Ran Sui, S.T. Tu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijpvp.2024.105203</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of Redox Patterns at the Transcriptional and Systemic Levels in Newly Diagnosed Acute Leukemia</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29328/journal.jhcr.1001029</link>
      <description>Alina Ag&#252;ero, M&#243;naco Mar&#237;a Eugenia, Lazarte Sandra, A. Ledesma, Alvarez Carmona A, Ter&#225;n Magdalena Mar&#237;a, Iss&#233; Blanca Alicia, Medina Marcela, Haro Cecilia, Journal of hematology and clinical research. 8(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396704095

                Background: Acute leukemia is the result of clonal transformation and proliferation of a hematopoietic progenitor giving rise to poorly differentiated neoplastic cells. Reactive oxygen species play a role in maintaining the quiescence, self-renewal, and long-term survival of hematopoietic stem cells, but it is unclear how they would affect disease onset and progression. The aim is to evaluate, at the transcriptional and systemic level, the oxidative-inflammatory status in newly diagnosis acute leukemia patients. Methods: Seventy acute leukemia patients [26 acute lymphoblastic leukemia (ALL), 13 Acute Promyelocytic Leukemia (APL), and 31 Acute Myeloid Leukemia (AML)] and forty-one healthy controls were analyzed. Malondialdehyde and catalase activity were evaluated. Gene expression of NRF2, SOD, PRDX2, CAT, IL-6, and TNF-&#945; was analyzed by real-time PCR. Results: Malondialdehyde concentration was similar in all groups studied. Catalase activity was significantly higher in AML and APL patients compared to controls, while ALL showed similar activity to the healthy group. NRF2, CAT, and PRDX2 expression levels were similar between groups, SOD expression was downregulated in all acute leukemia patients. TNF-&#945; expression was lower in AML groups than in healthy individuals, and IL-6 mRNA expression was downregulated in ALL and APL. Conclusion: This is the first report that correlates transcriptional and systemic parameters associated with the oxidative inflammatory status in newly diagnosed acute leukemia. Some of the parameters evaluated could be used as biomarkers in the selection of an effective therapeutic strategy and will open new directions for the follow-up and evolution of this disease.</description>
      <author>Alina Ag&#252;ero, M&#243;naco Mar&#237;a Eugenia, Lazarte Sandra, A. Ledesma, Alvarez Carmona A, Ter&#225;n Magdalena Mar&#237;a, Iss&#233; Blanca Alicia, Medina Marcela, Haro Cecilia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29328/journal.jhcr.1001029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Densely Populated Macrocyclic Dicobalt Sites in Ladder Polymers for Ultralow Overpotential Oxygen Reduction Catalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4329137/v1</link>
      <description>Xikui Liu, Xikui Liu, Zhen Zhang, Zhen Zhang, Zhenyu Xing, Zhenyu Xing, Luo Xianglin, Xingguang Lu&#959;, Chong Cheng, Chong Cheng, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396602422

                Abstract Dual-atom catalysts (DACs) with synergetic dinuclear active sites, have the potential to break the linear scaling relationship of the well-established single-atom catalysts for oxygen reduction reaction (ORR); however, the design of DACs with rationalized local microenvironment for high activity and selectivity remains a blind area and is great challenge. Herein, we reported a design of bisalphen ladder polymer with well-defined densely populated binuclear cobalt sites that in suit growth on Ketjenblack substrates (CoCo-BiSalphen@KB). The strong electron coupling effect between the fully-conjugated ladder structure with carbon substrates induces the low-to-high spin transition for the 3d electron of Co(II), activating O-O bond through the side-on overlapping and enhancing the electron transfer between the cobalt center and reactants/intermediates. In situ techniques and density functional theory calculations revealed the dynamic evolution of Co2N4O2 active sites and reaction intermediates. In alkaline conditions, the catalyst presented impressive ORR activity featuring an ultrahigh onset potential of 1.10 V and a remarkable half-wave potential of 1.00 V, insignificant decay after 30,000 cycles, which pushes the overpotential boundaries of ORR electrocatalysis to an unprecedented low level. This work provides a new platform for designing high-efficiency dual atom catalysts with well-defined coordination and electronic structures in energy conversion technologies.</description>
      <author>Xikui Liu, Xikui Liu, Zhen Zhang, Zhen Zhang, Zhenyu Xing, Zhenyu Xing, Luo Xianglin, Xingguang Lu&#959;, Chong Cheng, Chong Cheng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4329137/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simulations predict preferred Mg2+ coordination in a nonenzymatic primer extension reaction center</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpj.2024.04.032</link>
      <description>Shriyaa Mittal, Collin Nisler, Jack W. Szostak, Biophysical journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396621480

                The mechanism by which genetic information was copied prior to the evolution of ribozymes is of great interest because of its importance to the origin of life. The most effective known process for the nonenzymatic copying of an RNA template is primer extension by a two-step pathway in which 2-aminoimidazole activated nucleotides first react with each other to form an imidazolium-bridged intermediate that subsequently reacts with the primer. Reaction kinetics, structure-activity relationships, and X-ray crystallography have provided insight into the overall reaction mechanism, but many puzzles remain. In particular, high concentrations of Mg2+ are required for efficient primer extension, but the mechanism by which Mg2+ accelerates primer extension remains unknown. By analogy with the mechanism of DNA and RNA polymerases, a role for Mg2+ in facilitating the deprotonation of the primer 3&#8242;-hydroxyl is often assumed, but no catalytic metal ion is seen in crystal structures of the primer extension complex. To explore the potential effects of Mg2+ binding in the reaction center, we performed atomistic molecular dynamics simulations of a series of modeled complexes in which a Mg2+ ion was placed in the reaction center with inner sphere coordination to different sets of functional groups. Our simulations suggest that coordination of a Mg2+ ion to both O3&#8242; of the terminal primer nucleotide and the pro-Sp non-bridging oxygen of the reactive phosphate of an imidazolium-bridged dinucleotide would help to preorganize the structure of the primer/template substrate complex to favor the primer-extension reaction. Our results suggest that the catalytic metal ion may play an important role in overcoming electrostatic repulsion between a deprotonated O3&#8242; and the reactive phosphate of the bridged dinucleotide, and lead to testable predictions of the mode of Mg2+ binding that is most relevant to catalysis of primer extension.</description>
      <author>Shriyaa Mittal, Collin Nisler, Jack W. Szostak</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.bpj.2024.04.032</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the expression of the unspecific peroxygenase in Komagataella phaffii through a combination strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s00253-024-13166-7</link>
      <description>Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Applied microbiology and biotechnology. 108(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396676995

                The unspecific peroxygenase (UPO) from Cyclocybe aegerita (AaeUPO) can selectively oxidize C-H bonds using hydrogen peroxide as an oxygen donor without cofactors, which has drawn significant industrial attention. Many studies have made efforts to enhance the overall activity of AaeUPO expressed in Komagataella phaffii by employing strategies such as enzyme-directed evolution, utilizing appropriate promoters, and screening secretion peptides. Building upon these previous studies, the objective of this study was to further enhance the expression of a mutant of AaeUPO with improved activity (PaDa-I) by increasing the gene copy number, co-expressing chaperones, and optimizing culture conditions. Our results demonstrated that a strain carrying approximately three copies of expression cassettes and co-expressing the protein disulfide isomerase showed an approximately 10.7-fold increase in volumetric enzyme activity, using the 2,2'-azino-bis(3-ethylbenzothiazoline-6-sulfonic acid) as the substrate. After optimizing the culture conditions, the volumetric enzyme activity of this strain further increased by approximately 48.7%, reaching 117.3 U/mL. Additionally, the purified catalytic domain of PaDa-I displayed regioselective hydroxylation of R-2-phenoxypropionic acid. The results of this study may facilitate the industrial application of UPOs. KEY POINTS: &#8226; The secretion of the catalytic domain of PaDa-I can be significantly enhanced through increasing gene copy numbers and co-expressing of protein disulfide isomerase. &#8226; After optimizing the culture conditions, the volumetric enzyme activity can reach 117.3 U/mL, using the 2,2'-azino-bis(3-ethylbenzothiazoline-6-sulfonic acid) as the substrate. &#8226; The R-2-phenoxypropionic acid can undergo the specific hydroxylation reaction catalyzed by catalytic domain of PaDa-I, resulting in the formation of R-2-(4-hydroxyphenoxy)propionic acid.</description>
      <author>Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue, Ya&#8208;Ping Xue</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s00253-024-13166-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification and characterization of the CRK gene family in the wheat genome and analysis of their expression profile in response to high temperature-induced male sterility</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.17370</link>
      <description>Hongzhan Liu, Xiaoyi Li, Zujun Yin, Junmin Hu, Liuyong Xie, Huanhuan Wu, Seung Hoon Han, Bing Li, Huifang Zhang, Chaoqiong Li, Lili Li, Fuli Zhang, Guangxuan Tan, PeerJ. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396704694

                Cysteine-rich receptor-like kinases (CRKs) play many important roles during plant development, including defense responses under both biotic and abiotic stress, reactive oxygen species (ROS) homeostasis, callose deposition and programmed cell death (PCD). However, there are few studies on the involvement of the CRK family in male sterility due to heat stress in wheat ( Triticum aestivum L.). In this study, a genome-wide characterization of the CRK family was performed to investigate the structural and functional attributes of the wheat CRKs in anther sterility caused by heat stress. A total of 95 CRK genes were unevenly distributed on 18 chromosomes, with the most genes distributed on chromosome 2B. Paralogous homologous genes with Ka/Ks ratios less than 1 may have undergone strong purifying selection during evolution and are more functionally conserved. The collinearity analysis results of CRK genes showed that wheat and Arabidopsis ( A. thaliana ), foxtail millet, Brachypodium distachyon ( B. distachyon ), and rice have three, 12, 15, and 11 pairs of orthologous genes, respectively. In addition, the results of the network interactions of genes and miRNAs showed that five miRNAs were in the hub of the interactions map, namely tae-miR9657b-5p, tae-miR9780, tae-miR9676-5p, tae-miR164, and tae-miR531. Furthermore, qRT-PCR validation of the six TaCRK genes showed that they play key roles in the development of the mononuclear stage anthers, as all six genes were expressed at highly significant levels in heat-stressed male sterile mononuclear stage anthers compared to normal anthers. We hypothesized that the TaCRK gene is significant in the process of high-temperature-induced sterility in wheat based on the combination of anther phenotypes, paraffin sections, and qRT-PCR data. These results improve our understanding of their relationship.</description>
      <author>Hongzhan Liu, Xiaoyi Li, Zujun Yin, Junmin Hu, Liuyong Xie, Huanhuan Wu, Seung Hoon Han, Bing Li, Huifang Zhang, Chaoqiong Li, Lili Li, Fuli Zhang, Guangxuan Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7717/peerj.17370</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maturation from oceanic arcs to continental crust: Insights from Paleozoic magmatism in West Junggar, NW China</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2024.104795</link>
      <description>Jiyuan Yin, Wenjiao Xiao, Tao Wang, Mike Fowler, Andrew C. Kerr, Min Sun, Rob Strachan, He Huang, Ji&#8217;en Zhang, Wen Chen, Zaili Tao, Earth-science reviews. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396622775

                Understanding the processes involved in the transformation of juvenile basaltic oceanic arc crust into mature continental crust remains a key challenge in Earth sciences. In this contribution, we present a comprehensive synthesis of in situ zircon UPb age and HfO isotope data for Paleozoic intrusions within the West Junggar oceanic arc, NW China. Our study reveals four distinct pulses of magmatic activity: Early Cambrian to Early Ordovician (515 to 486 Ma); Late Ordovician to Middle Devonian (445 to 392 Ma); Early Carboniferous (343 to 310 Ma) and Late Carboniferous to Middle Permian (309 to 259 Ma). These pulses have varied spatial and temporal distributions. All magmatic rocks display consistently high zircon Hf and whole-rock Nd isotope values, but substantial variations in zircon O isotopes. There are two groups of intrusions: those with high zircon &#948;18O (&gt;6.5&#8240;) and those with mantle-like zircon &#948;18O (ca. 5.5&#8240;). The high zircon &#948;18O intrusions are predominantly concentrated in the southern West Junggar and their Hf and Nd isotopes indicate the involvement of supracrustal material and juvenile basaltic crust in their petrogenesis. Binary mixing calculations indicate a contribution from the supracrustal rocks ranging from 10% to 50%. The intrusions with mantle-like zircon &#948;18O are found primarily in northern West Junggar with a small amount occurring in southern West Junggar. The intrusions record a variety of magma sources and processes as demonstrated by HfO isotope and geochemical data. These data indicate partial melting of metasomatized depleted mantle, mixing of depleted mantle and juvenile crust, and partial melting of trapped juvenile oceanic crust or mafic lower crust. Hf model ages reveal significant crustal growth in the West Junggar, characterized by three distinct episodes of crust formation occurring at approximately 656&#8211;684 Ma, 524&#8211;536 Ma, and 441&#8211;471 Ma, involving periodic remelting of igneous material derived from a depleted mantle source. This newly-formed crust maintains a mantle-like oxygen isotope composition despite being repeatedly sampled by magmas for up to 0.26 Ga. Since the timing of crustal growth occurred independently of the major magmatic pulses, the latter reflect primarily reworking and remelting processes. Two significant episodes of magmatic activity, the late Silurian to early Devonian and the late Carboniferous to early Permian, preserve a signature of ocean ridge subduction. High-temperature magmatism during these periods promoted extensive melting of the mafic lower crust, oceanic crust, and supracrustal rocks, leading to the compositional transformation from basaltic to felsic continental crust. This comprehensive compilation provides valuable insights into granite petrogenesis, crustal evolution, and the diverse processes involved in the maturation of oceanic arc crust and its contribution to continental crust formation and evolution.</description>
      <author>Jiyuan Yin, Wenjiao Xiao, Tao Wang, Mike Fowler, Andrew C. Kerr, Min Sun, Rob Strachan, He Huang, Ji&#8217;en Zhang, Wen Chen, Zaili Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2024.104795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The NIRVANDELS Survey: the stellar and gas-phase mass-metallicity
  relations of star-forming galaxies at z = 3.5</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.00774</link>
      <description>T. M. Stanton, F. Cullen, R. J. McLure, Alice E. Shapley, K. Z. Arellano-C&#243;rdova, R. Begley, R. Amor&#237;n, L. Barrufet, A. Calabr&#242;, A. C. Carnall, M. Cirasuolo, J. S. Dunlop, C. T. Donnan, M. L. Hamadouche, Feng-Shan Liu, D. J. McLeod, L. Pentericci, L. Pozzetti, Ryan L. Sanders, D. Scholte, Michael W. Topping, arXiv (Cornell University). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396653729

                We present determinations of the gas-phase and stellar metallicities of a sample of 65 star-forming galaxies at $z \simeq 3.5$ using rest-frame far-ultraviolet (FUV) spectroscopy from the VANDELS survey in combination with follow-up rest-frame optical spectroscopy from VLT/KMOS and Keck/MOSFIRE. We infer gas-phase oxygen abundances ($Z_{\mathrm{g}}$; tracing O/H) via strong optical nebular lines and stellar iron abundances ($Z_{\star}$; tracing Fe/H) from full spectral fitting to the FUV continuum. Our sample spans the stellar mass range $8.5 &lt; \mathrm{log}(M_{\star}/\mathrm{M}_{\odot}) &lt; 10.5$ and shows clear evidence for both a stellar and gas-phase mass-metallicity relation (MZR). We find that our O and Fe abundance estimates both exhibit a similar mass-dependence, such that $\mathrm{Fe/H}\propto M_{\star}^{0.30\pm0.11}$ and $\mathrm{O/H}\propto M_{\star}^{0.32\pm0.09}$. At fixed $M_{\star}$ we find that, relative to their solar values, O abundances are systematically larger than Fe abundances (i.e., $\alpha$-enhancement).We estimate an average enhancement of $\mathrm{(O/Fe)} = 2.65 \pm 0.16 \times \mathrm{(O/Fe)_\odot}$ which appears to be independent of $M_{\star}$. We employ analytic chemical evolution models to place a novel constraint on the strength of galactic-level outflows via the mass-outflow factor ($\eta$). We show that outflow efficiencies that scale as $\eta \propto M_{\star}^{-0.32}$ can simultaneously explain the functional form of of the stellar and gas-phase MZR, as well as the degree of $\alpha$-enhancement at fixed Fe/H. Our results add further evidence to support a picture in which $\alpha$-enhanced abundance ratios are ubiquitous in high-redshift star-forming galaxies, as expected for young systems whose interstellar medium is primarily enriched by core-collapse supernovae.</description>
      <author>T. M. Stanton, F. Cullen, R. J. McLure, Alice E. Shapley, K. Z. Arellano-C&#243;rdova, R. Begley, R. Amor&#237;n, L. Barrufet, A. Calabr&#242;, A. C. Carnall, M. Cirasuolo, J. S. Dunlop, C. T. Donnan, M. L. Hamadouche, Feng-Shan Liu, D. J. McLeod, L. Pentericci, L. Pozzetti, Ryan L. Sanders, D. Scholte, Michael W. Topping</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.48550/arxiv.2405.00774</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Resolved properties of a luminous hinge clump in the compact group of galaxies NGC 6845</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202348869</link>
      <description>D. Olave-Rojas, J. A. Hern&#225;ndez-Jim&#233;nez, S. Torres-Flores, Marcelo D. Mora, V. Firpo, Astronomy &amp; astrophysics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396573645

                Compact groups of galaxies are unique places where galaxy-galaxy interactions play a mayor role on the evolution of its members. These strong gravitational encounters can induce star formation bursts. We study the properties of one of the most luminous so-called hinge clumps that is located in the compact group of galaxies NGC\,6845. Using integral field spectroscopy from GMOS/Gemini complemented with archival MUSE data, we obtained oxygen abundances, ages, star formation rates, and velocity fields, and we also modeled a single stellar population to understand the star formation history of the hinge clump in NGC\,6845. We found that the hinge clump sits in a tailthat has a star formation rate of 3.4 M$_ odot $ yr$^ $, which is comparable with a few other extreme cases, for instance, the star clusters in the Antennae galaxy and other reported hinge clumps in the literature. This clump represents sim 15&lt;!PCT!&gt; of total star formation rate of NGC\,6845A. Large-scale modeling of the observed velocity field of NGC\,6845A rules out the scenario according to which this hinge clump was a satellite galaxy. Its kinematics is compatible with that of the galactic disk of NGC\,6845A. Its abundance with a mean value of 0.4Zodot is also consistent with the metallicity gradient of the galaxy. Our analysis suggest that the hinge clump is formed by multiple stellar populations and not by a single burst. This causes the wide age range. We found that the central clump is encompassed by a ring-like structure, which might suggest a second generation of star formation. In addition, the analysis of the diagnostic diagram indicates that this central region might also be ionized by shocks from stellar and supernova winds. Finally, the derived star formation rate density Sigma = 9.7 M$_ odot $ yr$^ $ kpc$^ $ of the central clump places it in starburst regime, where gas inflows should provide gas to maintain the star formation. This work shows a resolved example of an extreme localized starburst in a compact group of galaxies.</description>
      <author>D. Olave-Rojas, J. A. Hern&#225;ndez-Jim&#233;nez, S. Torres-Flores, Marcelo D. Mora, V. Firpo</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1051/0004-6361/202348869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microbial nitrogen transformation processes across environments: more than just a cycle</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tim.2024.04.006</link>
      <description>Jennifer B. Glass, Kathrin Rousk, Trends in microbiology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4396709074

                Nitrogen (N) is unique amongst the bioessential elements in that its major reservoir is in the atmosphere, as triple-bonded N2, which comprises 78% of the atmosphere. Breaking the extremely strong triple bond of N2 is challenging; in nature, only the microbial nitrogenase enzyme is known to be capable of this reaction, and nitrogenase is by far the dominant source of N2 fixation on the modern Earth. Abiotic N2 fixation is found only in extremely high energy situations, namely lightning bolts, and industrial N2 fixation for fertilizer production. Indeed, N is one of the elemental cycles most influenced by human activities; in a little over a century, humans have more than doubled fixed N2 in the environment due to industrial N2 fixation via the Haber&#8211;Bosch process. Excess fertilizer use and subsequent runoff contributes to eutrophication of waterways and emissions of greenhouse gases, namely nitrous oxide. While humans have radically changed the N cycle in the Anthropocene, it was single-celled microorganisms that established the nitrogen cycle and its enzymatic processes over Earth's history [1.St&#252;eken E.E. et al.The evolution of Earth's biogeochemical nitrogen cycle.Earth Sci. Rev. 2016; 160: 220-239Crossref Scopus (0) Google Scholar]. Once fixed into 'reactive' N (the term for all forms of N in the environment except N2), N cycles through dozens of inorganic and organic nitrogenous forms on the Earth's surface [2.Zhang X. et al.Global nitrogen cycle: critical enzymes, organisms, and processes for nitrogen budgets and dynamics.Chem. Rev. 2020; 120: 5308-5351Crossref PubMed Scopus (167) Google Scholar]. With every passing year, it becomes clearer that the so-called N cycle, often drawn as a circle, is instead a tangled web. While relatively stable chemical species like nitrate and ammonium are often the focus of attention, highly reactive intermediates &#8211; such as nitric oxide, hydroxylamine, and even hydrazine (rocket fuel) &#8211; are increasingly recognized as the linchpins in the N web but often experience cryptic cycling due to their reactivity. Even more complexity is introduced when one considers the fact that the N web is woven by biotic&#8211;abiotic couplings, such as chemodenitrification, in which products of microbial metabolism react with ferrous iron to produce gaseous N. Biotic transformations in the N cycle are primarily catalyzed by metalloenzymes, many of which contain iron, molybdenum, and/or copper cofactors [3.Lycus P. et al.Structural biology of proteins involved in nitrogen cycling.Curr. Opin. Chem. Biol. 2023; 74102278Crossref Scopus (0) Google Scholar]. For instance, alternative forms of nitrogenase (vanadium&#8211;iron or iron&#8211;iron) have been detected, but they are rare in natural environments. Intriguingly, molybdenum&#8211;iron nitrogenase is by far the dominant form, even in environments in which vanadium is present at higher concentrations than molybdenum [4.Warren M.J. et al.Molybdenum-based diazotrophy in a sphagnum peatland in northern Minnesota.Appl. Environ. Microbiol. 2017; 83e01174&#8211;17Crossref Scopus (43) Google Scholar]. In some environments, such as the low-chlorophyll, high-nitrate regions of the oceans, scarcity of trace metals, particularly iron, limits photosynthesis and nitrate assimilation by phytoplankton. Scientific disciplines separate the N cycle/web into soil, freshwater, marine, and anthropogenic compartments; microbial life, of course, ignores all such designations and N freely flows across such artificial boundaries. While challenging, enhanced communication across disciplinary spheres is vital for expediting scientific discoveries and applications. Towards that end, Trends in Microbiology has joined forces with iScience to present a special issue on 'Nitrogen Cycling Across Environments' that explores microbial N processes across aquatic and terrestrial environments, with a focus on lessons that can be gained from cross-communication across the fields. The N cycle is replete with examples of how processes discovered in one environment have informed another. This is particularly common in the study of wastewater engineering, in which a large priority is conversion of reactive N from human and animal waste to N gas while minimizing greenhouse gas emissions, also known as biological N removal [5.Winkler M.K. Straka L. New directions in biological nitrogen removal and recovery from wastewater.Curr. Opin. Biotechnol. 2019; 57: 50-55Crossref PubMed Scopus (184) Google Scholar]. Anaerobic oxidation of ammonium (anammox) was first characterized in samples of wastewater sludge but has since been discovered in soil as well. More recently, the pathway of complete nitrification, thus far restricted to terrestrial environments, was discovered in other samples from engineered, aquatic systems. Crosstalk between fields can also bring new ideas about potential interactions between species in the N cycle. Interactions between diazotrophic bacteria and photosynthetic eukaryotes in root nodules (e.g., in legumes and alder trees) have long been studied in soils but remained relatively unknown in the ocean until the discovery of UCYN-A unicellular cyanobacteria in symbiosis with haptophyte algae. Likewise, while non-cyanobacterial diazotrophs have long been known to be key for terrestrial N2 fixation, they were only relatively recently discovered in the ocean. The role of viruses in the nitrogen cycle remains understudied across ecosystems. Many technological challenges hinder progress, such as challenges cultivating and genetic systems for environmentally key species and applying limited rate measurements across scales. Methods for microbial cultivation and pathway characterization are increasingly complex, which poses problems for widespread access to study of the cycle. This special issue tackles these questions and more. Three of the articles focus on the entry of N into the cycle via N2 fixation catalyzed by nitrogenase. Chakraborty et al. discuss engineering N2-fixing bacteria to increase N yield to crops, Zehr and Capone highlight recent developments and challenges in marine N2 fixation research, and Rucker and Ka&#231;ar describe interconnections between metal cycles and N cycles. Bowen et al. highlight salt marshes as an interface between terrestrial and marine realms, both subject to anthropogenic disturbances, which remove excess N prior to its entry into marine habitats. Deutsch and colleagues tackle the temperature dependence of biological N2 fixation and uncover a relationship that is similar across terrestrial and marine environments. Beeckman et al. critically examine the role of nitrification inhibitors that are used to relieve the deleterious effects associated with excess nitrification, providing insights into their applicability in the field. Sagha&#239; and Hallin review ammonifiers in terrestrial and aquatic environments. The article looks at enzymes involved in the reduction of nitrate and nitrite to ammonia with a particular focus on the widely used marker, NrfA. The special issue also highlights two recently published articles on the influence of tillage practices on the rhizosphere [6.Behr J.H. et al.Long-term conservation tillage with reduced nitrogen fertilization intensity can improve winter wheat health via positive plant&#8211;microorganism feedback in the rhizosphere.FEMS Microb. Ecol. 2024; 100fiae003Crossref Scopus (1) Google Scholar] and the identification of Methylomirabilis bacterium capable of methane-dependent complete denitrification [7.Yao X. et al.Methane-dependent complete denitrification by a single Methylomirabilis bacterium.Nat. Microbiol. 2024; 9: 464-476Crossref PubMed Scopus (5) Google Scholar]. Finally, our Microbe of the Month for this special issue is the diazotrophic Gram-negative bacterium, Bradyrhizobium japonicum (diazoefficiens), covered by Ong and O'Brian. We would also like to draw your attention to the articles published in iScience that are part of this interdisciplinary collection (https://www.cell.com/cp/collections-microbial-nitrogen-transformation). Christensen and Rousk review global sources of N2O emissions, identifying those which are influenced by anthropogenic activities, and highlighting agricultural systems with the potential for mitigation. Derikvand and colleagues focus on the microbial ecology of engineered aquaponic systems, investigating microbial community dynamics and ammonia removal in response to ammonia-oxidizing inocula and changing pH. While dozens of microbial reactions in the N cycle have been discovered, many more exergonic and disproportionation reactions, and the enzymes that catalyze them, await unearthing [8.Kuypers M.M.M. et al.The microbial nitrogen-cycling network.Nat. Rev. Microbiol. 2018; 16: 263-276Crossref PubMed Scopus (2225) Google Scholar]. Crystal structures of membrane proteins such as ammonia monooxygenase have been notoriously difficult to solve but are essential for mechanistic understanding of nitrogen cycle processes [9.Bradely B.T. et al.Integrated structural biology and molecular ecology of N-cycling enzymes from ammonia-oxidizing archaea.Environ. Microbiol. 2017; 5: 484-491Google Scholar]. Forms of oxygen-resistant enzymes previously thought to be extremely oxygen sensitive have also been discovered, such as the atypical form of nitrous oxide reductase, and surely many more remain to be found [10.Simon J. Klotz M.G. Diversity and evolution of bioenergetic systems involved in microbial nitrogen compound transformations.BBA-Bioenergetics. 2013; 2: 114-135Crossref Scopus (259) Google Scholar]. As we venture even further into the Anthropocene, the importance of studying N cycling across environments subject to global climate change becomes ever more important. Nitrogen is a bioessential element with an almost limitless supply from the atmosphere, yet conversion to reactive N currently relies on fossil fuels and results in eutrophication and greenhouse emissions. Harnessing insights from microbes that drive the N cycle to tackle these environmental challenges will be increasingly key going forward [11.Stein L.Y. Klotz M.G. The nitrogen cycle.Curr. Biol. 2016; 26: R94-R98Abstract Full Text Full Text PDF PubMed Scopus (327) Google Scholar].</description>
      <author>Jennifer B. Glass, Kathrin Rousk</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tim.2024.04.006</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
