<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 00:42:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Rational Design of Organic Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen and Oxygen Electrocatalytic Applications</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202402184</link>
      <description>Ruiqi Cheng, Xiaoyun He, Kaiqi Li, Biao Ran, Xinlong Zhang, Yonghong Qin, Guanjie He, Huanxin Li, Chaopeng Fu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392577718

                Abstract Efficient electrocatalysts are pivotal for advancing green energy conversion technologies. Organic electrocatalysts, as cost&#8208;effective alternatives to noble&#8208;metal benchmarks, have garnered attention. However, the understanding of the relationships between their properties and electrocatalytic activities remains ambiguous. Plenty of research articles regarding low&#8208;cost organic electrocatalysts started to gain momentum in 2010 and have been flourishing recently though, a review article for both entry&#8208;level and experienced researchers in this field is still lacking. This review underscores the urgent need to elucidate the structure&#8208;activity relationship and design suitable electrode structures, leveraging the unique features of organic electrocatalysts like controllability and compatibility for real&#8208;world applications. Organic electrocatalysts are classified into four groups: small molecules, oligomers, polymers, and frameworks, with specific structural and physicochemical properties serving as activity indicators. To unlock the full potential of organic electrocatalysts, five strategies are discussed: integrated structures, surface property modulation, membrane technologies, electrolyte affinity regulation, and addition of anti&#8208;corrosion species, all aimed at enhancing charge efficiency, mass transfer, and long&#8208;term stability during electrocatalytic reactions. The review offers a comprehensive overview of the current state of organic electrocatalysts and their practical applications, bridging the understanding gap and paving the way for future developments of more efficient green energy conversion technologies. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Ruiqi Cheng, Xiaoyun He, Kaiqi Li, Biao Ran, Xinlong Zhang, Yonghong Qin, Guanjie He, Huanxin Li, Chaopeng Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202402184</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesoporous Single Atom-Cluster Fe&#8211;N/C Oxygen Evolution Electrocatalysts Synthesized with Bottlebrush Block Copolymer-Templated Rapid Thermal Annealing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c18693</link>
      <description>Dipankar Saha, Hsin-Jung Yu, Jiacheng Wang, Prateek, Xiaobo Chen, Chaoyun Tang, Claire Senger, James Nicolas Pagaduan, Reika Katsumata, Kenneth R. Carter, Guangwen Zhou, Peng Bai, Nianqiang Wu, James J. Watkins, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392580330

                Current electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are either expensive (such as IrO2, RuO2) or/and exhibit high overpotential as well as sluggish kinetics. This article reports mesoporous earth-abundant iron (Fe)&#8211;nitrogen (N) doped carbon electrocatalysts with iron clusters and closely surrounding Fe&#8211;N4 active sites. Unique to this work is that the mechanically stable mesoporous carbon-matrix structure (79 nm in pore size) with well-dispersed nitrogen-coordinated Fe single atom-cluster is synthesized via rapid thermal annealing (RTA) within only minutes using a self-assembled bottlebrush block copolymer (BBCP) melamine&#8211;formaldehyde resin composite template. The resulting porous structure and domain size can be tuned with the degree of polymerization of the BBCP backbone, which increases the electrochemically active surface area and improves electron transfer and mass transport for an effective OER process. The optimized electrocatalyst shows a required potential of 1.48 V (versus RHE) to obtain the current density of 10 mA/cm2 in 1 M KOH aqueous electrolyte and a small Tafel slope of 55 mV/decade at a given overpotential of 250 mV, which is significantly lower than recently reported earth-abundant electrocatalysts. Importantly, the Fe single-atom nitrogen coordination environment facilitates the surface reconstruction into a highly active oxyhydroxide under OER conditions, as revealed by X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and in situ Raman spectroscopy, while the atomic clusters boost the single atoms reactive sites to prevent demetalation during the OER process. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations support that the iron nitrogen environment and reconstructed oxyhydroxides are electrocatalytically active sites as the kinetics barrier is largely reduced. This work has opened a new avenue for simple, rapid synthesis of inexpensive, earth-abundant, tailorable, mechanically stable, mesoporous carbon-coordinated single-atom electrocatalysts that can be used for renewable energy production.</description>
      <author>Dipankar Saha, Hsin-Jung Yu, Jiacheng Wang, Prateek, Xiaobo Chen, Chaoyun Tang, Claire Senger, James Nicolas Pagaduan, Reika Katsumata, Kenneth R. Carter, Guangwen Zhou, Peng Bai, Nianqiang Wu, James J. Watkins</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.3c18693</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen defect based Cobalt-doped-NiMoO4 Hierarchical hollow nanosheet-based-nanosphere for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00659c</link>
      <description>Zhuoxun Yin, Min Zhou, Xinping Li, Xiangcun Liu, Xinzhi Ma, Yang Zhou, Aleksandra B. Djuri&#353;i&#263;, Jinlong Li, Lina Liu, Jun Lv, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392587160

                Hollow structures with hierarchical architecture and multi-composition have attracted extensive interest because of their fascinating physicochemical properties as well as wide applications. to improve the efficiency of overall water splitting,...</description>
      <author>Zhuoxun Yin, Min Zhou, Xinping Li, Xiangcun Liu, Xinzhi Ma, Yang Zhou, Aleksandra B. Djuri&#353;i&#263;, Jinlong Li, Lina Liu, Jun Lv</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00659c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Synthesis of CuP2 and Cu3P and Their Performance as Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen Evolution, Oxygen Evolution, and Oxygen Reduction Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/solids5010010</link>
      <description>Xiao Ma, Xueni Huang, Abdessadek Lachgar, Solids. 5(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392587799

                Copper phosphides are promising materials for energy conversion applications because of their unique electronic structure and controllable composition. Two stoichiometric copper phosphides, CuP2 and Cu3P, were prepared by direct wet-chemical synthesis using red phosphorus. They were characterized by powder X-ray diffraction, scanning and transmission electron microscopy, and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. The precursor selection, reaction temperature, time and solvent composition were also studied. CuP2 is the thermodynamically more stable product, but Cu3P is more commonly obtained. This work demonstrated that higher temperature helps in CuP2 formation. More importantly, using more trioctylphosphine oxide helps control the morphology leading to crystal growth along the crystallographic a-axis. CuP2 and Cu3P were tested for hydrogen evolution, oxygen evolution, and oxygen reduction reactions. CuP2 works better for HER in acidic conditions and OER in general, and Cu3P showed better activity than CuP2 for HER and ORR in an alkaline medium. This study has led to a simple approach to the synthesis of CuP2 nanowires.</description>
      <author>Xiao Ma, Xueni Huang, Abdessadek Lachgar</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/solids5010010</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Lewis acid-induced self-healing of loose FeOOH for alkaline oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150253</link>
      <description>Ning Yu, Jing Lv, Zhanhu Guo, Xin-Jie Tian, Yusheng Zhang, Wenjing Li, Yulu Zhou, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392593905

                The fast leaching of the Fe catalytic center and low conductivity of FeOOH have hindered the optimal stability and activity of Fe-based electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions (OER). Here, Zn2+ is introduced into FeOOH with a looser nanosheet structure by regulating electric double layer (EDL) repulsion during electrodeposition. Meanwhile, as strong Lewis acids, Zn2+ in ZnxFeOOH could act as an electron acceptor, accepting electrons from FeOOH. The doping of Zn2+ shortens the bond length of Fe-O and enhances the covalency of Fe-O to improve electron transport rate and stability. The faster catalytic kinetics also been obtained by facilitating O* to form OOH* intermediates. At 100 mA cm&#8722;2, Zn0.5FeOOH requires overpotential of only 250 mV and maintains initial activity in 1 M KOH after 120 h. Notably, Zn-induced self-healing is achieved when the leaching and redeposition of Fe reach dynamic equilibrium. In 1 M KOH seawater, Zn0.5FeOOH requires overpotentials of 286 mV to produce current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2. At 2.0 V, Zn0.5FeOOH can achieve 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 in anion exchange membrane (AEM) water electrolyzer at room temperature. This work provides an effective Zn-induced strategy for designing efficient and stable OER catalysts for industrial development.</description>
      <author>Ning Yu, Jing Lv, Zhanhu Guo, Xin-Jie Tian, Yusheng Zhang, Wenjing Li, Yulu Zhou, Yong&#8208;Ming Chai, Bin Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.150253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Platinum Oxide Formation under Oxygen Evolution Reaction Conditions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3400440/v1</link>
      <description>Leon Jacobse, R. Schuster, Mona Kohantorabi, Silvan Dolling, Johannes Pfrommer, Xin Deng, Tim Weber, Olof Gutowski, Ann Christin Dippel, Olaf Brummel, Yaroslava Lykhach, Heshmat Noei, Herbert Over, J&#246;rg Libuda, Vedran Vonk, Andreas Stierle, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392593961

                Abstract Electrocatalyst degradation, often caused by oxidative processes, forms a large barrier for the wide-spread application of electrolysers and fuel cells, which are crucial for a sustainable energy society. A detailed understanding of the catalyst surface structure under oxygen evolution reaction (OER) conditions is, therefore, required to design more stable catalysts. Here, we study the oxidation of a Pt(111) model electrode under operando conditions combining High-Energy Surface X-ray Diffraction (HE-SXRD) with a Rotating Disk Electrode (RDE) in a unique experimental setup. This novel approach allows us to follow the atomic structure of the electrode/electrolyte interface under oxygen evolution reaction conditions under hitherto unexplored potential regimes. We find that the Pt(111) surface gets electro-oxidized in a layer-by-layer fashion, which is the best scenario in terms of electrode stability. From ex situ X-ray Reflectivity (XRR) and X-ray Photoelectron Spectroscopy (XPS) measurements we find that a sub-nm thick, PtO 2 oxide film is forming, which deactivates the surface and leads to surface roughening after subsequent dissolution. Our results provide important insight for the operation of fuel cells and electrolysers under intermittent conditions of renewable energies.</description>
      <author>Leon Jacobse, R. Schuster, Mona Kohantorabi, Silvan Dolling, Johannes Pfrommer, Xin Deng, Tim Weber, Olof Gutowski, Ann Christin Dippel, Olaf Brummel, Yaroslava Lykhach, Heshmat Noei, Herbert Over, J&#246;rg Libuda, Vedran Vonk, Andreas Stierle</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-3400440/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmenting the Electrocatalytic Activities of Metal&#8211;N-Heterocyclic Carbene Complexes as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions by Carbon Composite Strategy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04793</link>
      <description>Monica Vijayakumar, Gautam Achar, Zhoveta Yhobu, Jan Grzegorz Ma&#322;ecki, D. H. Nagaraju, Rangappa S. Keri, Srinivasa Budagumpi, Energy &amp; Fuels. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392598576

                The pursuit of efficient transformation of green energy sources through water electrolysis necessitates the expansion of reasonable, earth-abundant, and robust bifunctional electrocatalysts for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this connection, N-heterocyclic carbenes (NHCs) coordinated metal complexes have become one of the most stimulating and ubiquitous classes of organometallics due to their ease of preparation and modularity in stereoelectronic possessions. Here, we report a series of metal NHC complexes synthesized by the reaction of an NHC precursor with an appropriate metal source and thoroughly characterized using spectral and analytical techniques. Both metal&#8211;NHC complexes and their carbon composites using multiwalled carbon nanotubes (MWCNT) and graphene plates (GP) were tested for their electrochemical HER and OER performances in acidic and basic electrolytes, respectively. The MWCNT and GP composites displayed improved HER activity compared with the bare complexes. Furthermore, a two-fold improved OER performance of the carbon composites was evident compared with the activity of the bare metal&#8211;NHC complexes to achieve the overpotential (&#951;10). Furthermore, the electrochemical impedance spectroscopic technique was used to bring out the key information required to justify the activity trend in HER and OER reactions and the nature of the electrode&#8211;electrolyte interaction of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Monica Vijayakumar, Gautam Achar, Zhoveta Yhobu, Jan Grzegorz Ma&#322;ecki, D. H. Nagaraju, Rangappa S. Keri, Srinivasa Budagumpi</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.energyfuels.3c04793</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-Doped Ni&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Co&lt;sub&gt;0.5&lt;/sub&gt;Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Porous Single-Crystalline Nanosheets for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c06069</link>
      <description>Zhenyu Wang, Minghao Zhang, Xiaoyuan Liu, Hang Gao, Caixia Song, Debao Wang, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392603750

                Developing a highly efficient catalyst for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is of great significance for its application in electrocatalytic water splitting. Herein, a solid&#8211;solid transformation strategy has been developed to construct sulfur-doped Ni0.5Co0.5Fe2O4 spinel porous single-crystal nanosheet arrays on nickel foam (S-NCFO/NF). The single-crystalline nanosheet self-assembled nanostructures can provide fast charge transfer channels. With the effect of S-doping, a distorted/incomplete octahedral structure nanosheet can be formed. The unique porous S-NCFO nanosheets can provide a large number of active sites and sufficiently contact the electrolyte to adsorb OH&#8211; and desorb O2. By virtue of the porous single-crystal nanosheet, sulfur-doped spinel structure, and the unique self-assembled nanosheet configurations, the S-NCFO/NF electrode exhibits enhanced OER performance with low overpotentials at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 of 300 mV in 1 M KOH and 317 mV in 1 M KOH + 0.5 M NaCl. The synthesis strategy provides insight for the preparation and application of self-assembled nanostructures in electrocatalytic seawater splitting.</description>
      <author>Zhenyu Wang, Minghao Zhang, Xiaoyuan Liu, Hang Gao, Caixia Song, Debao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.3c06069</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancement of oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline water electrolysis by Lorentz forces generated by an external magnetic field</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.199</link>
      <description>Wilton Foga&#231;a, Hayata Ikeda, Ryuta Misumi, Yoshiyuki Kuroda, Shigenori Mitsushima, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 61(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392612847

                The effects of vertical Lorentz forces generated by an external magnetic field applied perpendicular to the inherent electric field on the oxygen evolution reaction conducted on a Ni wire are investigated using cyclic voltammetry, impedance measurements, and particle image velocimetry (PIV). Both downward and upward Lorentz forces provide smaller overpotentials than that generated in their absence. Based on a dual-bubble layer model for reactant transfer, we find that the diffusion resistance of the hydroxide ions and increased ohmic resistance (after iR correction) induced by the layer of bubbles attached to the electrode surface are most effectively alleviated by the downward Lorentz force, while the charge-transfer resistance is retained. Furthermore, the generated bubbles have smaller average diameters. By using PIV measurements, we find that stronger shear stresses induced by the faster flow of the electrolyte in the vicinity of the working electrode facilitate the detachment of bubbles from the electrode surface.</description>
      <author>Wilton Foga&#231;a, Hayata Ikeda, Ryuta Misumi, Yoshiyuki Kuroda, Shigenori Mitsushima</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.02.199</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessment of photosynthetic activity in dense microalgae cultures using oxygen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2024.108510</link>
      <description>Antoni Mateu Vera-Vives, Tim Michelberger, Tomas Morosinotto, Giorgio Perin, Plant Physiology and Biochemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392613222

                Microalgae are photosynthetic microorganisms playing a pivotal role in primary production in aquatic ecosystems, sustaining the entry of carbon in the biosphere. Microalgae have also been recognized as sustainable source of biomass to complement crops. For this objective they are cultivated in photobioreactors or ponds at high cell density to maximize biomass productivity and lower the cost of downstream processes. Photosynthesis depends on light availability, that is often not constant over time. In nature, sunlight fluctuates over diurnal cycles and weather conditions. In high-density microalgae cultures of photobioreactors outdoors, on top of natural variations, microalgae are subjected to further complexity in light exposure. Because of the high-density cells experience self-shading effects that heavily limit light availability in most of the mass culture volume. This limitation strongly affects biomass productivity of industrial microalgae cultivation plants with important implication on economic feasibility. Understanding how photosynthesis responds to cell density is informative to assess functionality in the inhomogeneous light environment of industrial photobioreactors. In this work we exploited a high-sensitivity Clark electrode to measure microalgae photosynthesis and compare cultures with different densities, using Nannochloropsis as model organism. We observed that cell density has a substantial impact on photosynthetic activity, and demonstrated the reduction of the cell's light-absorption capacity by genetic modification is a valuable strategy to increase photosynthetic functionality on a chlorophyll-basis of dense microalgae cultures.</description>
      <author>Antoni Mateu Vera-Vives, Tim Michelberger, Tomas Morosinotto, Giorgio Perin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.plaphy.2024.108510</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-efficiency oxygen evolution electrocatalyst based on a Co3[Co (CN)6]2@NiFe LDH composite material</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00908h</link>
      <description>Jiaan Yu, Ruru Fu, Shanhai Ge, Yang Liu, Yun Zhao, Caihong Feng, Qingze Jiao, Hansheng Li, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392621570

                Due to the slow kinetics and large overpotential of oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in electrochemical water splitting. It is important to develop efficient and low-cost electrocatalysts for OER. In this...</description>
      <author>Jiaan Yu, Ruru Fu, Shanhai Ge, Yang Liu, Yun Zhao, Caihong Feng, Qingze Jiao, Hansheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj00908h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of defective mesoporous cerium oxide nanostructure for promoting an efficient and stable electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100169</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Mondal, Muthuraja Velpandian, Himadri Tanaya Das, Apurba Sinhamahapatra, Suddhasatwa Basu, Mohd Afzal, Next Materials. 3(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392621869

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Mondal, Muthuraja Velpandian, Himadri Tanaya Das, Apurba Sinhamahapatra, Suddhasatwa Basu, Mohd Afzal</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nxmate.2024.100169</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improved Oxygen Evolution Reaction Kinetics with Titanium Incorporated Nickel Ferrite for Efficient Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05761</link>
      <description>Ki-Yong Yoon, Kyung&#8208;Bok Lee, Jaehoon Jeong, Myung&#8208;Jun Kwak, Dohyung Kim, Hyunchul Roh, Ji-Hoon Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Hosik Lee, Juchan Yang, ACS Catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392622761

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ki-Yong Yoon, Kyung&#8208;Bok Lee, Jaehoon Jeong, Myung&#8208;Jun Kwak, Dohyung Kim, Hyunchul Roh, Ji-Hoon Lee, Sung Mook Choi, Hosik Lee, Juchan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.3c05761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of porous flower-like Ru-doped CoNiFe layered double hydroxide for supercapacitors and oxygen evolution reaction catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.044</link>
      <description>Qian Ding, Jingbo Yin, Yueyue Huang, Chaofan Wang, Hubin Luo, Shiguo Sun, Yongqian Xu, Hongjuan Li, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392626543

                In recent years, ternary layered double hydroxide (LDH) has become a research hotspot for electrode materials and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalyst due to the enhanced synergistic effect between individual elements. However, the application of LDH is greatly limited by its low electrical conductivity and the disadvantage that nanosheets tend to accumulate and mask the active sites. Herein, a novel Ru-doped CoNiFe &#8722; LDH was prepared via a facile hydrothermal method. According to the density functional theory (DFT) calculations, the doping of Ru element could improve electron state density and band gaps of LDH and consequently boosted the electrochemical reaction kinetics as well as electrical conductivity. Furthermore, introduction of Ru atom induced the formation of porous flower-like structures in nanosheets. Compared to CoNiFe &#8722; LDH (28.9 m2/g), Ru-doped CoNiFe &#8722; LDH performed larger specific surface area of 53.1 m2/g, resulting in more electrochemically active sites. In these case, Ru-doped CoNiFe &#8722; LDH demonstrated better energy storage performance of 176.0 mAh/g at 1 A/g compared to original CoNiFe &#8722; LDH (78.9 mAh/g at 1 A/g). Besides, the assembled Ru-doped CoNiFe &#8722; LDH//activated carbon (AC) device delivered a maximum energy density of 36.4 W h kg&#8722;1 at the power density of 740.3 W kg&#8722;1 and an outstanding cycle life (78.7 % after 10,000 cycles). Meanwhile, Ru-doped CoNiFe &#8722; LDH exhibited lower overpotential (339 mV at 50 mA cm&#8722;2) and Tafel slope (93.2 mV dec&#8722;1). Therefore, this work provided novel and valuable insights into the rational doping of Ru elements for the controlled synthesis of supercapacitor electrode materials and OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Qian Ding, Jingbo Yin, Yueyue Huang, Chaofan Wang, Hubin Luo, Shiguo Sun, Yongqian Xu, Hongjuan Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.044</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tungsten Doped Fecop2 Nanoparticles Embedded into Carbon for Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4752172</link>
      <description>Xinyao Quan, Jiajia Ma, Qian-Shuo Shao, Hao-Cong Li, Lingxiang Sun, Gui Li Huang, Yan Su, Hong Zhang, Yuning Wang, Xiaoqing Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392626811

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Xinyao Quan, Jiajia Ma, Qian-Shuo Shao, Hao-Cong Li, Lingxiang Sun, Gui Li Huang, Yan Su, Hong Zhang, Yuning Wang, Xiaoqing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4752172</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Supported Fe&#8208;Based Nanostructured Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting and Selective Oxidation Reactions: Past, Present, and Future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303730</link>
      <description>Mayur A. Gaikwad, Vishal Burungale, D.B. Malavekar, Uma V. Ghorpade, Umesh P. Suryawanshi, Sae Jang, Xiaofeng Guo, Seung Wook Shin, Jun&#8208;Seok Ha, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, Jihun Kim, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392632371

                Abstract Electrochemical water splitting plays a vital role in facilitating the transition towards a sustainable energy future by enabling renewable hydrogen (H 2 ) production, energy storage, and emission&#8208;free transportation. Developing earth&#8208;abundant electrocatalysts with outstanding overall water&#8208;splitting performance, excellent catalytic activity, and robust long&#8208;term stability is highly important in the practical application of water electrolysis. Self&#8208;supported electrocatalysts have emerged as the most appealing candidate for practical H 2 production due to their increased active site loading, rapid mass and charge transfer, and strong interaction with the underneath conducting support. Additionally, these electrocatalysts also provide enhanced reaction kinetics and stability. Here, a comprehensive review of recent progress in developing self&#8208;supported Fe&#8208;based electrocatalysts for water splitting and selective oxidation reactions is presented with examples of oxyhydroxides, layered double hydroxides, oxides, chalcogenides, phosphides, nitrides, and other Fe&#8208;containing electrocatalysts. A comprehensive historical development in the synthesis of self&#8208;supported Fe&#8208;based electrocatalysts is provided, with an emphasis on the various deposition methods and the choice of self&#8208;supported conducting substrates considering large&#8208;scale commercial applications. An overview of mechanistic understanding and approaches for enhanced H 2 production are also presented. Finally, the challenges and opportunities associated with developing Fe&#8208;based electrocatalysts for practical applications in water splitting and alternative oxidation reactions are discussed.</description>
      <author>Mayur A. Gaikwad, Vishal Burungale, D.B. Malavekar, Uma V. Ghorpade, Umesh P. Suryawanshi, Sae Jang, Xiaofeng Guo, Seung Wook Shin, Jun&#8208;Seok Ha, Mahesh P. Suryawanshi, Jihun Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202303730</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ru Species Anchored on Defective Cobalt Iron Oxide for Biomass Electro-Oxidation Coupled with Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4754289</link>
      <description>Shasha Cui, Guangjin Wang, Fen Wang, Ting&#8208;Ting Li, Zhijuan Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392634950

                Download This Paper Open PDF in Browser Add Paper to My Library Share: Permalink Using these links will ensure access to this page indefinitely Copy URL Copy DOI</description>
      <author>Shasha Cui, Guangjin Wang, Fen Wang, Ting&#8208;Ting Li, Zhijuan Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4754289</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>&lt;i&gt;In Situ&lt;/i&gt;-Generated Hollow CoFe-LDH/Co-MOF Heterostructure Nanorod Arrays for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00021</link>
      <description>Guoying Yang, Yonghua Song, Song&#8208;De Han, Zhen&#8208;Zhen Xue, De&#8208;Xuan Liu, Ani Wang, Guo&#8208;Ming Wang, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392637087

                Assembling a heterostructure is an effective strategy for enhancing the electrocatalytic activity of hybrid materials. Herein, CoFe-layered double hydroxide and Co-metal&#8211;organic framework (CoFe-LDH/Co-MOF) hollow heterostructure nanorod arrays are synthesized. First, [Co(DIPL)(H3BTC)(H2O)2]n [named as Co-MOF, DIPL = 2,6-di(pyrid-4-yl)-4-phenylpyridine, H3BTC = 1,3,5-benzenetricarboxylic acid] crystalline materials with a uniform hollow structure were prepared on the nickel foam. The CoFe-LDH/Co-MOF composite perfectly inherits the original hollow nanorod array morphology after the subsequent electrodeposition process. Optimized CoFe-LDH/Co-MOF hollow heterostructure nanorod arrays display excellent performance in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with ultralow overpotentials of 215 mV to deliver current densities of 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and maintain the electrocatalytic activity for a duration as long as 220 h, ranking it one of the non-noble metal-based electrocatalysts for OER. Density functional theory calculations validate the reduction in free energy for the rate-determining step by the synergistic effect of Co-MOF and CoFe-LDH, with the increased charge density and noticeable electron transfer at the Co&#8211;O site, which highlights the capability of Co-MOF to finely adjust the electronic structure and facilitate the creation of active sites. This work establishes an experimental and theoretical basis for promoting efficient water splitting through the design of heterostructures in catalysts.</description>
      <author>Guoying Yang, Yonghua Song, Song&#8208;De Han, Zhen&#8208;Zhen Xue, De&#8208;Xuan Liu, Ani Wang, Guo&#8208;Ming Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00021</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Regulating atomic Fe/Cu dual sites with unsymmetrical Fe-N6 and Cu-N1S2 coordination for promoting bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis in advanced zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103342</link>
      <description>Jing Peng, Bihua Hu, Zhitong Li, Xiongwei Zhong, Junwei Shi, Shuyu Cui, Xingzhu Wang, Baomin Xu, Energy Storage Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392639396

                Dual-metal single-atom catalysts with heteronuclear active sites exhibit superior oxygen catalysis performance than their single-atom counterparts, facilitating the practical applications in advanced electrochemical energy devices. Herein, a Fe-Cu dual-metal single-atom catalyst with Fe-N6 and Cu-N1S2 coordination environment (FeCu-DSAs/NSC) is reported. Due to the synergism of bimetallic active sites and asymmetric heteroatom coordination, the resultant FeCu-DSAs/NSC displays better bifunctional catalytic performance (a small potential gap between the E&#951;10 and E1/2, &#916;E=0.647 V) when compared with the counterparts (Pt/C+IrO2 and Cu-ISAs/NSC), as well as surpassing most of bifunctional metal atom-based catalysts reported to date. As expected, FeCu-DSAs/NSC based rechargeable zinc-air battery shows remarkable superiority than commercial Pt/C+IrO2 benchmark, resulting in a high peak power density (230.66 mW cm&#8722;2), open-circuit voltage (1.464 V) and long-term cycling stability (up to 350 h at 10 mA cm&#8722;2).</description>
      <author>Jing Peng, Bihua Hu, Zhitong Li, Xiongwei Zhong, Junwei Shi, Shuyu Cui, Xingzhu Wang, Baomin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103342</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-doped Yttrium Ruthenate Pyrochlore catalyst for Efficient Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution in Acidic Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174072</link>
      <description>Rei&#8208;Cheng Yang, Hao Qi, Jianan Zhao, Cong Liu, Shujie Xue, Fengjuan Miao, Wenbing Tang, Qinghong Huang, Jing Wang, Yuping Wu, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392639957

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rei&#8208;Cheng Yang, Hao Qi, Jianan Zhao, Cong Liu, Shujie Xue, Fengjuan Miao, Wenbing Tang, Qinghong Huang, Jing Wang, Yuping Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.174072</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tm-Doping Modulated P-D Orbital Coupling to Enhance the Oxygen Evolution Performance of Ni3s2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4755085</link>
      <description>Jing Pan, Qiuhong Li, Minghao Zhang, Rui Wang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392641110

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Pan, Qiuhong Li, Minghao Zhang, Rui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4755085</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NH4Cl-assisted synthesis of TaON nanoparticle applied to photocatalytic hydrogen and oxygen evolution from water</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.051</link>
      <description>Yanhua Xu, Kaiwei Liu, Jifang Zhang, Boyang Zhang, Jiaming Zhang, Shaoyong Ke, Haifeng Wang, Guijun Ma, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392642667

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanhua Xu, Kaiwei Liu, Jifang Zhang, Boyang Zhang, Jiaming Zhang, Shaoyong Ke, Haifeng Wang, Guijun Ma</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Engineered Titanium with Nanoceria to Enhance Soft Tissue Integration Via Reactive Oxygen Species Modulation and Nanotopographical Sensing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02119</link>
      <description>Hye-Won Shim, Amal George Kurian, Jiwon Lee, Sang Cheol Lee, Hae&#8208;Won Kim, Rajendra K. Singh, Jung Hwan Lee, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392650694

                The design of implantable biomaterials involves precise tuning of surface features because the early cellular fate on such engineered surfaces is highly influenced by many physicochemical factors [roughness, hydrophilicity, reactive oxygen species (ROS) responsiveness, etc.]. Herein, to enhance soft tissue integration for successful implantation, Ti substrates decorated with uniform layers of nanoceria (Ce), called Ti@Ce, were optimally developed by a simple and cost-effective in situ immersion coating technique. The characterization of Ti@Ce shows a uniform Ce distribution with enhanced roughness (&#8764;3-fold increase) and hydrophilicity (&#8764;4-fold increase) and adopted ROS-scavenging capacity by nanoceria coating. When human gingival fibroblasts were seeded on Ti@Ce under oxidative stress conditions, Ti@Ce supported cellular adhesion, spreading, and survivability by its cellular ROS-scavenging capacity. Mechanistically, the unique nanocoating resulted in higher expression of amphiphysin (a nanotopology sensor), paxillin (a focal adhesion protein), and cell adhesive proteins (collagen-1 and fibronectin). Ti@Ce also led to global chromatin condensation by decreasing histone 3 acetylation as an early differentiation feature. Transcriptome analysis by RNA sequencing confirmed the chromatin remodeling, antiapoptosis, antioxidant, cell adhesion, and TGF-&#946; signaling-related gene signatures in Ti@Ce. As key fibroblast transcription (co)factors, Ti@Ce promotes serum response factor and MRTF-&#945; nucleus localization. Considering all of this, it is proposed that the surface engineering approach using Ce could improve the biological properties of Ti implants, supporting their functioning at soft tissue interfaces and utilization as a bioactive implant for clinical conditions such as peri-implantitis.</description>
      <author>Hye-Won Shim, Amal George Kurian, Jiwon Lee, Sang Cheol Lee, Hae&#8208;Won Kim, Rajendra K. Singh, Jung Hwan Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c02119</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Efficient Alkaline Hydrogen Evolution Reaction of CoFe&#8208;Layered Double Hydroxides Nanosheets via Co&#8208;Coordination Mechanism of W&#8208;Doping and Oxygen Defect Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311221</link>
      <description>Shaohong Wang, Jing Wu, Yin Xu, Dandan Liang, Da Li, Gang Chen, Guohong Liu, Yujie Feng, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392658994

                Abstract While surface defects and heteroatom doping exhibit promising potential in augmenting the electrocatalytic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), their performance remains unable to rival that of the costly Pt&#8208;based catalysts. Yet, the concurrent modification of catalysts by integrating both approaches stands as a promising strategy to effectively address the aforementioned limitation. In this work, tungsten dopants are introduced into self&#8208;supported CoFe&#8208;layered double hydroxides (LDH) on nickel foam using a hydrothermal method, and oxygen vacancies (Ov) are further introduced through calcination. The analysis results demonstrated that tungsten doping reduces the Ov formation energy of CoFeW&#8208;LDH. The Ov acted as oxophilic sites, facilitating water adsorption and dissociation, and reducing the barrier for cleaving HO&#9472;H bonds from 0.64 to 0.14 eV. Additionally, Ov regulated the electronic structure of CoFeW&#8208;LDH to endow optimized hydrogen binding ability on tungsten atoms, thereby accelerating alkaline Volmer and Heyrovsky reaction kinetics. Specifically, the abundance of Ov induced a transition of tungsten from a six&#8208;coordinated to highly active four&#8208;coordinated structure, which becomes the active site for HER. Consequently, an ultra&#8208;low overpotential of 41 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and a low Tafel slope of 35 mV dec &#8722;1 are achieved. These findings offer crucial insights for the design of efficient HER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Shaohong Wang, Jing Wu, Yin Xu, Dandan Liang, Da Li, Gang Chen, Guohong Liu, Yujie Feng</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311221</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Effect of Electrocatalyst for Enhanced Oxygen Reduction Reaction: Low Pt-Loaded CuPt Alloy Nanoparticles Supported on N-Doped Hierarchical Porous Carbon</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00297</link>
      <description>Min Li, Feng Liu, Yongming Zhang, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392659004

                It is challenging to synthesize oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysts that are highly efficient, affordable, and stable for use in proton exchange membrane fuel cells. To address this challenge, we developed a low platinum-loading (only 6.68% wt) ORR catalyst (PtCu1-NC), comprising CuPt nanoparticles (average size: 1.51 nm) supported on the N-doped carbon substrates. PtCu1-NC possesses a high specific surface area of 662 m2 g&#8211;1 and a hierarchical porous structure, facilitating efficient mass transfer. The synergistic effect from introduced copper and the electron effect from nitrogen modify the electronic structure of platinum, effectively accelerating the ORR reaction and enhancing stability. Density functional theory calculations demonstrate the catalytic mechanism and further verify the synergistic effect. Electrochemical assessments indicate that PtCu1-NC exhibits specific activity and mass activity 5.3 and 5.6 times higher, respectively, than commercial Pt/C. The half-wave potential is 27 mV more positive than that of commercial Pt/C. The electrochemical active surface area value is 104.3 m2 g&#8211;1, surpassing that of Pt/C. Approximately 78% of current is retained after 10,000 s chronoamperometry measurement. These results highlight the effectiveness of alloying in improving the catalyst performance.</description>
      <author>Min Li, Feng Liu, Yongming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c00297</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite for Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution at Elevated Temperatures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301534</link>
      <description>Fatma Abdelghafar, Xiaomin Xu, San Ping Jiang, Zongping Shao, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392697241

                The development of advanced electrolysis technologies such as anion exchange membrane water electrolyzer (AEMWE) is central to the vision of a sustainable energy future. Key to the realization of such AEMWE technology lies in the exploration of low&#8208;cost and high&#8208;efficient catalysts for facilitating the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Despite tremendous efforts in the fundamental research, most of today&#8217;s OER works are conducted under room temperature, which deviates significantly with AEMWE&#8217;s operating temperature (50&#8211;80 &#176;C). To bridge this gap, it is highly desirable to obtain insights into the OER catalytic behavior at elevated temperatures. Herein, using the well&#8208;known perovskite catalyst Ba0.5Sr0.5Co0.8Fe0.2O3&#8722;&#948; (BSCF) as a proof of concept, the effect of temperature on the variation in OER catalytic activity and stability is evaluated. It is found that the BSCF&#8217;s activity increases with increasing temperature due to enhanced lattice oxygen participation promoting the lattice oxygen&#8208;mediated OER process. Further, surface amorphization and cation leaching of BSCF become more pronounced as temperature increases, causing a somewhat attenuated OER stability. These new understandings of the fundamental OER catalysis over perovskite materials at industrial&#8208;relevant temperature conditions are expected to have strong implications for the research of OER catalysts to be deployed in practical water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Fatma Abdelghafar, Xiaomin Xu, San Ping Jiang, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202301534</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Fundamental Understanding and Electrocatalysts Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400239</link>
      <description>Jiao Li, Weiming Tian, Qi Li, Shenlong Zhao, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392813847

                Water electrolysis driven by &#8220;green electricity&#8220; is an ideal technology to realize energy conversion and store renewable energy into hydrogen. With the development of proton exchange membrane (PEM), water electrolysis in acidic media suitable for many situations with an outstanding advantage of high gas purity has attracted significant attention. Compared with hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in water electrolysis, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a kinetic sluggish process that needs a higher overpotential. Especially in acidic media, OER process poses higher requirements for the electrocatalysts, such as high efficiency, high stability and low costs. This review focuses on the acidic OER electrocatalysis, reaction mechanisms, and critical parameters used to evaluate performance. Especially the modification strategies applied in the design and construction of new&#8208;type electrocatalysts are also summarized. The characteristics of traditional noble metal&#8208;based electrocatalysts and the noble metal&#8208;free electrocatalysts developed in recent decades are compared and discussed. Finally, the current challenges for the most promising acidic OER electrocatalysts are presented, together with a perspective for future water electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Jiao Li, Weiming Tian, Qi Li, Shenlong Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202400239</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent progress of electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215758</link>
      <description>Yuping Chen, Chunyan Shang, Xin Xiao, Weihua Guo, Qiang Xu, Coordination Chemistry Reviews. 508(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392743186

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yuping Chen, Chunyan Shang, Xin Xiao, Weihua Guo, Qiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ccr.2024.215758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface-Functionalized Ni nanostructures for Oxygen Evolution Reaction, a different synthetic approach.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.135</link>
      <description>Aureliano Macili, Laia Franc&#225;s, Jordi Garc&#305;&#769;a-Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392704432

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aureliano Macili, Laia Franc&#225;s, Jordi Garc&#305;&#769;a-Ant&#243;n, Xavier Sala</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.135</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxide management in Ruthenium oxide catalysts for efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction in acid.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.202</link>
      <description>Amit Kumar Das, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer, Xia Lu, Anku Guha, Viktoria Holovanova, No host. None(None)] 2023. https://openalex.org/W4392704834

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Amit Kumar Das, F. Pelayo Garc&#305;&#769;a de Arquer, Xia Lu, Anku Guha, Viktoria Holovanova</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.29363/nanoge.matsus.2024.202</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Core-shell cobalt iron oxide nanoparticles for the electrocatalysis of the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://openalex.org/W4392769583</link>
      <description>Lisa Royer, No host. None(None)] 2022. https://openalex.org/W4392769583

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lisa Royer</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://openalex.org/W4392769583</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen doped leather waste-derived carbon materials as electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112295</link>
      <description>Afshin Abbasi, Musammir Khan, Fawad Ahmad, Muhammad Imran Khan, Abdallah Shanableh, R. P. S. Rajput, Suryyia Manzoor, Shabnam Shahida, Rafael Luque, Sameh M. Osman, Mushtaq Hussain Lashari, Inorganic Chemistry Communications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392715055

                Nitrogen doped leather waste-derived carbon materials have been employed as eletrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction. Low current densities and complex synthesis routes of other carbon-based materials limit their practical applicability. We present herein a simple and cost-competitive design of a metal free nitrogen-doped carbon matrix (NCM). At 10 mA cm&#8722;2 of current density, the assembled NCM showed a low over potential of 330 mV. NCM provided 73 mV dec-1 of slope value according to Tafel analysis, with NCM slope value improved as compared to previously described electrocatalysts inclusive of graphene (113 mV dec&#8722;1) and carbon nanosheets (101 mV dec&#8722;1), under similar reaction conditions. Linear sweep voltamogram, stability test and electrochemical impedance spectra confirmed the potential of NCM in OER as a heterogeneous electrocatalyst.</description>
      <author>Afshin Abbasi, Musammir Khan, Fawad Ahmad, Muhammad Imran Khan, Abdallah Shanableh, R. P. S. Rajput, Suryyia Manzoor, Shabnam Shahida, Rafael Luque, Sameh M. Osman, Mushtaq Hussain Lashari</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.inoche.2024.112295</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interface oxidation induced amorphous/crystalline 1D hollandite Rb0.17IrO2 for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159881</link>
      <description>Danni Li, Anhui Zhou, Xiang Shao, Lin Zhu, Youwei Du, Limei Cao, Chenglong Ma, Jie Yang, Applied Surface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392660887

                Recently, surface reconstruction derived from Ir-based derivatives could achieve satisfactory oxygen evolution performance. Herein, ultra-long nanowire hollandite structured Rb0.17IrO2 was synthesized and a nano-amorphous layer with a thickness of &#8764;1.5 nm was achieved by interfacial oxidation treatment. The prepared catalyst exhibits outstanding water oxidation activity with an oxygen evolution reaction (OER) current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 at 330 mV for robust continuous operation in acidic media. Through the spectroscopic and density functional theory (DFT) theoretical calculations, we demonstrate that the nano-amorphous layers induced by interfacial oxidation on the one-dimensional (1D)-nanowire surface have enhanced O-2p centers and increased Ir-O hybridization compared to the bulk Rb0.17IrO2 phase, which essentially balances the adsorption energy of the intermediates. Effectively incorporating surface reconstruction behavior could significantly improve catalyst activity. This work effectively combines 1D Ir-based materials and surface reconstruction, which provides a strategy for the subsequent full utilization of Ir-based materials applied on OER process.</description>
      <author>Danni Li, Anhui Zhou, Xiang Shao, Lin Zhu, Youwei Du, Limei Cao, Chenglong Ma, Jie Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.apsusc.2024.159881</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Modulation of Oxygen Vacancies on 2D Metal Hydroxide Organic Frameworks for High&#8208;Efficiency Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311713</link>
      <description>Kai Ge, Yi Zhao, Yunxia Hu, Zhuozhi Wang, Jingjing Wang, Mei&#8208;Sang Yang, Canfei He, Yongfang Yang, Lei Zhu, Boxiong Shen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392732464

                Abstract The discovery of non&#8208;precious catalysts for replacing the precious metal of ruthenium in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) represents a key step in reducing the cost of green hydrogen production. The 2D d &#8208;MHOFs, a new 2D materials with controllable oxygen vacancies formed by controlling the degree of coordination bridging between metal hydroxyl oxide and BDC ligands are synthesized at room temperature, exhibit excellent OER properties with low overpotentials of 207 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 . High&#8208;resolution transmission electron microscopy images and density functional theory calculations demonstrate that the introduction of oxygen vacancy sites leads to a lattice distortion and charge redistribution in the catalysts, enhancing the OER activity of 2D d &#8208;MHOFs comprehensively. Synchrotron radiation and in situ Raman/Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy indicate that part of oxygen defect sites on the surface of 2D d &#8208;MHOFs are prone to transition to highly active metal hydroxyl oxides during the OER process. This work provides a mild strategy for scalable preparation of 2D d &#8208;MHOFs nanosheets with controllable oxygen defects, reveals the relationship between oxygen vacancies and OER performance, and offers a profound insight into the basic process of structural transformation in the OER process.</description>
      <author>Kai Ge, Yi Zhao, Yunxia Hu, Zhuozhi Wang, Jingjing Wang, Mei&#8208;Sang Yang, Canfei He, Yongfang Yang, Lei Zhu, Boxiong Shen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202311713</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating space charge of FeP/CoP p-n heterojunction for boosting oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.060</link>
      <description>Shaqi Fu, Peng Cheng, Yuancong Luo, Lingli Cheng, Xuechun Yang, Z. Jiao, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392636984

                Surface reconstruction of electrocatalysts is an effective strategy to modulate the space charge distribution to enhance the electrocatalytic activity. The p-n heterostructured FeP/CoP-2D octagonal nanoplates were successfully constructed by cation-exchange method. The space charge effect caused by the p-n heterojunction accelerated the electron transfer, optimized the electronic structure, and improved the activity of the active sites during the oxygen evolution reaction process. As a result, FeP/CoP-2D required only 247 mV overpotential to achieve a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2 with a Tafel slope as low as 68 mV dec-1. Density-functional theory calculations confirmed that the construction of p-n heterojunctions can enhance the adsorption of *OH in the active centers and optimize the Gibbs free energy of the OER reaction. This study provides an effective and feasible strategy for constructing p-n heterojunctions to modulate the space charge state for optimizing the OER performance of electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Shaqi Fu, Peng Cheng, Yuancong Luo, Lingli Cheng, Xuechun Yang, Z. Jiao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.03.060</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical FeO H @Ni3B hybrid for efficient alkaline oxygen evolution at high current density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.061</link>
      <description>Fuxi Liu, Qing Liang, Zhenyu Li, Meiqi Liu, Nailin Yue, Zizhun Wang, Xu Zou, Wei Zhang, Journal of Energy Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392714501

                Electrocatalysts with high activity and long-term durability are vital toward large-scale hydrogen production from electrocatalytic water splitting. Here, the self-supported electrode (FeOxHy@Ni3B/NF) with hierarchical heterostructure was simply prepared by using Ni3B chunks grown on nickel foam as substrate to in situ form vertical FeOxHy nanosheets. Such hybrid shows efficient oxygen evolution reaction activity with overpotentials as low as 267 and 249 mV at 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 M KOH solution and 30 wt% KOH solution, respectively. Meanwhile, it also exhibits excellent catalytic stability, sustaining catalysis at 500 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 M KOH solution for 200 h, and even for 200 h at 1000 mA cm&#8722;2 in 30 wt% KOH solution. Further experimental results reveal that the FeOxHy@Ni3B/NF is endowed with superhydrophilic and superaerophobic surface properties, which not only provide more mass transport channels, as well as facilitated the diffusion of reaction intermediates and gas bubbles. Also, it holds faster reaction kinetics, more accessible active sites and accelerated electron transfer rates due to strong synergistic interactions at the heterogeneous interface.</description>
      <author>Fuxi Liu, Qing Liang, Zhenyu Li, Meiqi Liu, Nailin Yue, Zizhun Wang, Xu Zou, Wei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jechem.2024.02.061</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFeLDH/Mo4/3B2-xTz/NF composite electrodes to enhance oxygen evolution performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00834k</link>
      <description>Lulu Xu, Ping Yang, Rongbin Ye, Xin Wu, Yong Tao, Journal of materials chemistry. A, Materials for energy and sustainability. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392723773

                A NiFeLDH /Mo4/3B2-xTz/NF (foam nickel) composite electrode was prepared by electrodepositing a layer of NiFe-layered hydroxides (NiFeLDH) on the Mo4/3B2-xTz /NF which was obtained by NF being soaked in two-dimensional...</description>
      <author>Lulu Xu, Ping Yang, Rongbin Ye, Xin Wu, Yong Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta00834k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A series of Isostructural Metal-Organic Frameworks for Enhanced Electro-catalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00210e</link>
      <description>Pampa Jhariat, Abdul Kareem, Priyanka Kumari, Shafeeq Sarfudeen, Pravati Panda, Sellappan Senthilkumar, Tamas Panda, Dalton Transactions. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392741361

                Three new isostructural MOFs (ZnTIA, CoTIA and CdTIA) were synthesized by the solvothermal synthesis of organic linker 5-triazole isophthalic acid (5-TIA) with the transition metals Zn(II), Co(II) and Cd(II) salts...</description>
      <author>Pampa Jhariat, Abdul Kareem, Priyanka Kumari, Shafeeq Sarfudeen, Pravati Panda, Sellappan Senthilkumar, Tamas Panda</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4dt00210e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intermetallic Cobalt Indium Nanoparticles as Oxygen Evolution Reaction Precatalyst: A Non&#8208;Leaching p&#8208;Block Element</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309749</link>
      <description>J. Niklas Hausmann, Marten L. P. Ashton, Stefan Mebs, Carsten Walter, S&#246;ren Selve, Michael Haumann, Tobias Sontheimer, Holger Dau, Matthias Drie&#223;, Prashanth W. Menezes, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392782764

                Abstract Merely all transition&#8208;metal&#8208;based materials reconstruct into similar oxyhydroxides during the electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER), severely limiting the options for a tailored OER catalyst design. In such reconstructions, initial constituent p&#8208;block elements take a sacrificial role and leach into the electrolyte as oxyanions, thereby losing the ability to tune the catalyst's properties systematically. From a thermodynamic point of view, indium is expected to behave differently and should remain in the solid phase under alkaline OER conditions. However, the structural behavior of transition metal indium phases during the OER remains unexplored. Herein, are synthesized intermetallic cobalt indium (CoIn 3 ) nanoparticles and revealed by in situ X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy and scanning transmission microscopy that they undergo phase segregation to cobalt oxyhydroxide and indium hydroxide. The obtained cobalt oxyhydroxide outperforms a metallic&#8208;cobalt&#8208;derived one due to more accessible active sites. The observed phase segregation shows that indium behaves distinctively differently from most p&#8208;block elements and remains at the electrode surface, where it can form lasting interfaces with the active metal oxo phases.</description>
      <author>J. Niklas Hausmann, Marten L. P. Ashton, Stefan Mebs, Carsten Walter, S&#246;ren Selve, Michael Haumann, Tobias Sontheimer, Holger Dau, Matthias Drie&#223;, Prashanth W. Menezes</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202309749</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A review on synthesis and modification of cobalt-molybdenum based sulfides as hydrogen and oxygen evolution catalysts for water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cinorg.2024.100043</link>
      <description>Jie Zhang, Chunlin Hu, Peng Deng, Yan-Hong Yin, Chemistry of Inorganic Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392660622

                Hydrogen energy as the alternative to fossil fuel received wide attention. Among different methods of hydrogen production, water electrolysis is the cleanest and most promising method. However, its development is greatly limited by hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) reaction and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) reaction. Therefore, it is very necessary to develop low-cost, high activity, and good stability of non-precious metal catalyst to replace the precious metal catalyst (Pt, RuO2), and to further reduce overpotential and power consumption. To date, great efforts have been made to develop transition metal compounds with electrocatalytic performance, such as sulfides, oxides, and carbides materials. Especially, transition metal sulfides play a very important role as catalysts and have attracted wide attention for their structural adjustability, high abundance, and mild preparation process. In this introduction, we focus on the role of transition metal sulfides in catalysts for water electrolysis, especially in a few most studied sulfides such as cobalt/molybdenum based sulfides and the recently reported homogeneous cobalt-molybdenum based sulfides, in which cobalt acts as a key element. Composition, morphology, and size are the most important factors that influence the intrinsic activity, electrical conductivity, and electronic structure of these transition metal sulfides. Besides, the effect of carbon nanomaterials as carrier materials is also discussed. The aim of this review is to emphasize the great potentials of cobalt and molybdenum based sulfides with high performance, and to help improve the performance of existing sulfides and explore new modification methods.</description>
      <author>Jie Zhang, Chunlin Hu, Peng Deng, Yan-Hong Yin</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cinorg.2024.100043</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical cobalt-molybdenum layered double hydroxide arrays power efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6529-1</link>
      <description>Xinyi Zhu, Jiahui Lyu, Shanshan Wang, Xingchuan Li, Xiaoy&#252; Wei, Cheng Chen, Wanida Koo&#8208;Amornpattana, Francis Verpoort, Jianxin Wu, Zongkui Kou, Nano Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392804986

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xinyi Zhu, Jiahui Lyu, Shanshan Wang, Xingchuan Li, Xiaoy&#252; Wei, Cheng Chen, Wanida Koo&#8208;Amornpattana, Francis Verpoort, Jianxin Wu, Zongkui Kou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6529-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel-cobalt alloy oxide nanoparticles wrapped by carbon black for efficient oxygen evolution electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131462</link>
      <description>Bosheng Zhang, Panchao Zhao, Junqiu Guo, Hemu Pi, Fuel. 367(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4392791612

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bosheng Zhang, Panchao Zhao, Junqiu Guo, Hemu Pi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.131462</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
