<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 01:07:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Sustainable Enabling of Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalyst for Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3030/101150584</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4399347332

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3030/101150584</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced electrochemical efficiency of the open porous sandrose structured electrocatalyst for sustainable hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.422</link>
      <description>Chandrasekaran Pitchai, Mahalakshmi Vedanarayanan, Chih&#8208;Ming Chen, Mathur Gopalakrishnan Sethuraman, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399205918

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Chandrasekaran Pitchai, Mahalakshmi Vedanarayanan, Chih&#8208;Ming Chen, Mathur Gopalakrishnan Sethuraman</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.422</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFeCo Alloy Nanoparticles Composited with Phosphorus-doped Vacancies-abundant Carbon Substrates as Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175050</link>
      <description>Hu-Jun Qian, Zi&#8208;Jie Long, Shuqin Huang, Zhihao Zhang, Jintang Li, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399207582

                Transition metal alloy nanoparticles are cost-effective electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reactions. Preparing alloy catalysts with flexible controllability, high activity, and long-term stability is a challenge. By adjusting the proportion of metal atoms and engineering vacancies through their composite with a carbon substrate, we can enhance electron transfer and modulate the adsorption capacity of reaction intermediates. Herein, we synthesized a hybrid catalyst using Prussian blue analogs (PBAs) as the precursor, doped with Fe and Ni atoms, and subjected them to a defective engineering and phosphatization process. As an efficient alkaline OER electrocatalyst, the formation of the alloy increases the number of active sites, while the defect-rich phosphorus-doped carbon substrate improves internal electron transfer and mass transfer channels. The synthesized NiFeCoPC-1.5 electrocatalyst exhibits excellent catalytic activity with an overpotential of 211 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and a Tafel slope of 59 mV dec&#8722;1, and demonstrates good stability up to 1000 CV cycles. This work will expand the application of alloy nanoparticles in oxygen evolution electrodes.</description>
      <author>Hu-Jun Qian, Zi&#8208;Jie Long, Shuqin Huang, Zhihao Zhang, Jintang Li</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175050</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-doped cerium-iron phosphide as an ultra-efficient Ru-free electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175051</link>
      <description>Sivalingam Gopi, Kyusik Yun, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399208937

                Designing nonprecious metal-based heteroatom-doped electrocatalysts with low overpotential for efficient hydrogen production via oxygen evolution reactions presents significant challenges. We fabricated and carbonized an N-doped bimetallic phosphide (CeFeP) in this study. Scanning electron microscopy and transmission electron microscopy analyses revealed the formation of a uniform spherical nanoparticle morphology, while structural changes were evidenced in the carbonization step at temperatures of 300 and 700 &#8451; by XRD analysis. The synthesized materials were then coated onto carbon paper electrodes in a basic medium, and their performance in the oxygen evolution reaction was evaluated. The results show that the N-doped bimetallic phosphide material carbonized at 700 &#8451; has enhanced catalytic activity, as indicated by its low overpotential of 155 mV and Tafel slope of 57 mV/dec, respectively, for a standard current density of 10 mA/cm2. The catalytic performance of the N-doped CeFeP sample was significantly higher than that of undoped CeFeP and the single metal phosphide, thereby indicating it has significant potential for practical applications.</description>
      <author>Sivalingam Gopi, Kyusik Yun</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175051</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloride&#8208; and Hydrosulfide&#8208;Bound 2Fe Complexes as Models of the Oxygen&#8208;Stable State of [FeFe] Hydrogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408142</link>
      <description>Ming-Hsi Chiang, Yu&#8208;Chiao Liu, Kai&#8208;Ti Chu, Hongru Wang, Gene&#8208;Hsiang Lee, Mei&#8208;Chun Tseng, C.C. Wang, Yih&#8208;Chern Horng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399210237

                [FeFe] hydrogenases demonstrate remarkable catalytic efficiency in hydrogen evolution and oxidation processes. However, susceptibility of enzymes to oxygen&#8208;induced degradation impedes their practical deployment in hydrogen&#8208;production devices and fuel cells. Recent investigations into the oxygen&#8208;stable (Hinact) state of the H&#8208;cluster revealed its inherent capacity to resist oxygen degradation. Herein, we present findings on Cl&#8208;/SH&#8208;bound [2Fe&#8208;2S] complexes, bearing relevance to the oxygen&#8208;stable state within a biological context. A characteristic attribute of these complexes is the terminal Cl&#8722;/SH&#8722; ligation to the iron bearing the CO bridge. Structural analysis of the t&#8208;Cl demonstrates a striking resemblance to the Hinact state of DdHydAB and CbA5H. The t&#8208;Cl/t&#8208;SH exhibit reversible oxidation, with both redox species, electronically, being the first biomimetic analogs to the Htrans and Hinact states. These complexes exhibit notable resistance against oxygen&#8208;induced decomposition, supporting the potential oxygen&#8208;resistant nature of the Htrans and Hinact states. The swift reductive release of the Cl&#8208;/SH&#8208; demonstrates its labile and kinetically controlled binding. The findings garnered from these investigations offer valuable insights into properties of the enzymatic O2&#8208;stable state, and key factors governing deactivation and reactivation conversion. This work contributes to advancement of bio&#8208;inspired molecular catalysts and integration of enzymes and artificial catalysts into H2&#8208;evolution devices and fuel&#8208;cell applications.</description>
      <author>Ming-Hsi Chiang, Yu&#8208;Chiao Liu, Kai&#8208;Ti Chu, Hongru Wang, Gene&#8208;Hsiang Lee, Mei&#8208;Chun Tseng, C.C. Wang, Yih&#8208;Chern Horng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202408142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Ni-doped Co3O4 oxygen evolution catalysts for anion exchange membrane water electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.365</link>
      <description>Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, N. Krishna Chandar, Nisha Devi, Hai Lin, Cheng-Che Huang, Xin-Yu Jiang, Yuan-Yao Li, G. Arthanareeswaran, Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, Neeraj K. Jaiswal, Yong&#8208;Song Chen, International journal of hydrogen energy. 72(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399212076

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, N. Krishna Chandar, Nisha Devi, Hai Lin, Cheng-Che Huang, Xin-Yu Jiang, Yuan-Yao Li, G. Arthanareeswaran, Ramesh Aravind Murugesan, Neeraj K. Jaiswal, Yong&#8208;Song Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.365</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The rational design of bifunctional MOF-ZnFe2O4 hollow sphere-based nanocomposites for ultra-efficient electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction and high-performance symmetric supercapacitor electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175048</link>
      <description>Dong&#8208;Eun Lee, Mohtaram Danish, Ahmad Husain, Wan&#8208;Kuen Jo, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399220781

                Supercapacitors have emerged as versatile energy storage devices, valued for their rapid charge-discharge capabilities and long cycle life. Concurrently, efficient electrocatalysts are essential for promoting the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in sustainable energy applications. Inevitably, this study explores the integration of a Cobalt-Nickel (Co/Ni) based metal-organic framework [CoNi((&#956;3-tp)2(&#956;2-py)2 or CNTP] with ZnFe2O4 hollow spheres (ZHS) to create innovative CNTP/ZHS nanocomposites tailored for supercapacitor and electrocatalytic OER applications. Different weight percentages of CNTP/ZHS nanocomposites were synthesized through a facile and scalable method, and their electrochemical performance was rigorously assessed. Electrochemical characterization revealed that a 40 weight percentage CNTP/ZHS (40-CNTP/ZHS) electrode demonstrated a very high specific capacitance of 1519.2 Fg-1 at 1 Ag-1 and retained 92.6% of its specific capacitance after 10000 cycles. Moreover, it delivered remarkably high specific capacitance (447.2 Fg-1) and energy density (62.1 WhKg-1) along with outstanding cyclic stability (97.5% after 5000 galvanostatic charge-discharge cycles). It also exhibited excellent OER activity, with a very low overpotential (207 mV to attain a current density of 10 mAcm-2), a small Tafel slope (66.5 mVdec-1), and high stability over 2000 cyclic voltammetry cycles. These characteristics underscore the significant potential of renewable energy technologies, particularly for water electrolysis and sustainable energy conversion.1</description>
      <author>Dong&#8208;Eun Lee, Mohtaram Danish, Ahmad Husain, Wan&#8208;Kuen Jo</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175048</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of CuO/MnAl2O4 nanocomposite as electrocatalysts for robust oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112121</link>
      <description>Muhammad Sadiq, B.M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Khalid I. Hussein, Md. Rezaul Karim, Journal of physics and chemistry of solids. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399222190

                The primary focus of current research is the development of an affordable, effective and reliable electrocatalyst for electrochemical water splitting to generate clean energy. In this context, designing and manipulating the valence states of transition metals is a promising method for developing effective electrocatalysts for the splitting of water. Because increased valence metal sites can accelerate the reaction rates for oxygen evolution process (OER). Herein, the physiochemical features of CuO are modulated by the inclusion of spinel MnAl2O4 with high-valence metal sites and a porous framework comprised of linked tiny nanoparticles. nanocomposite CuO/MnAl2O4 were fabricated through a sonication procedure in 1.0 M KOH for OER. The electrocatalytic measurement of CuO/MnAl2O4 showed outstanding oxygen activity for OER with reduced overpotential of 196 mV at current density (Cd:10 mA cm&#8722;2) and Tafel value (34 mV dec-1) and lower onset potential of 1.28V than pristine CuO. Also, the Nyquist plot illustrates the improved conductivity by illustrating a minor charge transfer resistance (Rct) value (0.13 &#937;), moreover, nanocomposite shows stability for 50 hours at 65% of its current density.</description>
      <author>Muhammad Sadiq, B.M. Alotaibi, Albandari W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, Khalid I. Hussein, Md. Rezaul Karim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpcs.2024.112121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Core-shell Structured NiMoO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;@CoFe-LDH Nanorods: Performance of Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Overall Water-splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.15541/jim20240098</link>
      <description>Yue QuanXin, GUO Ruihua, Ruifen Wang, Shengli An, ZHANG Guofang, Guan LiLi, Wuji cailiao xuebao. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399229005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yue QuanXin, GUO Ruihua, Ruifen Wang, Shengli An, ZHANG Guofang, Guan LiLi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.15541/jim20240098</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MOF-Derived LDHs: Unveiling Their Potential in Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100128</link>
      <description>Mohammad Etesami, Shiva Rezaei Motlagh, Ramin Khezri, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Myong Yong Choi, Kasidit Nootong, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Soorathep Kheawhom, EnergyChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239615

                This review explores the potential of metal-organic frameworks (MOFs) to drive sustainable clean energy solutions and their crucial role in transitioning towards a decarbonized global economy. The paper underscores the remarkable versatility and modifiability of MOFs. Central to this discourse is the conversion of MOFs into layered double hydroxides (LDHs), with a detailed exposition of the synthesis methodologies and their consequential effects on catalytic efficacy. A meticulous evaluation of MOF-derived LDHs is presented, particularly in the context of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), encapsulating cutting-edge progress and probing the feasibility of integrating these materials into next-generation energy technologies. Diverging from existing literature, this research provides an in-depth exploration of MOF-to-LDH conversion, a promising area in OER catalysis. In addition, structural engineering techniques to optimize the performance of MOF-derived LDHs in electrochemical devices are explored, highlighting the potential of MOFs as future electrocatalysts and guiding future research directions.</description>
      <author>Mohammad Etesami, Shiva Rezaei Motlagh, Ramin Khezri, Mohan Gopalakrishnan, Jayaraman Theerthagiri, Myong Yong Choi, Kasidit Nootong, Anongnat Somwangthanaroj, Soorathep Kheawhom</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.enchem.2024.100128</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous MnRuOx Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405641</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Li Gao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239788

                Compared to Ir, Ru&#8208;based catalysts often exhibited higher activity but suffered significant and rapid activity loss during the challenging oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in a corrosive acidic environment. Herein, we developed a hybrid MnRuOx catalyst in which the RuO2 microcrystalline regions serve as a supporting framework, and the amorphous MnRuOx phase fills the microcrystalline interstices. In particular, the MnRuOx&#8208;300 catalyst from an annealing temperature of 300oC contains an optimal amorphous/crystalline heterostructure, providing substantial defects and active sites, facilitating efficient adsorption and conversion of OH&#8208;. In addition, the heterostructure leads to a relative increase of the d&#8208;band center close to the Fermin level, thus accelerating electron transfer with reduced charge transfer resistance at the active interface between crystalline and amorphous phases during the OER. The catalyst was further thoroughly evaluated under various operating conditions and demonstrated exceptional activity and stability for the OER, representing a promising solution to replace Ir in water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Li Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202405641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient oxygen evolution activity for heterojunctions CoFe-PBA using a bimetallic probe (Mo/Cu) at room temperature: Construction of multilayered activated structural bodies and cationic vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00863d</link>
      <description>Lihai Wei, Zhihao Liu, Xiaodong Wu, Huabo Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang, Green chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399243418

                The development of efficient and stable active agents is key to accelerating the four-electron process of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Prussian blue (PBA) has greatly limited its application in...</description>
      <author>Lihai Wei, Zhihao Liu, Xiaodong Wu, Huabo Huang, Qianqian Jiang, Jianguo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4gc00863d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrated iron phosphides and cobalt oxide electrocatalyst for enhanced hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions: A study on activity and stability factors</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.449</link>
      <description>Asma A. Alothman, Jafar Hussain Shah, Mehar Un Nisa, S. Noor Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Muhammad Usman, Muhammad Adnan, International journal of hydrogen energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399256266

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Asma A. Alothman, Jafar Hussain Shah, Mehar Un Nisa, S. Noor Mohammad, Abdul Ghafoor Abid, Muhammad Usman, Muhammad Adnan</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.05.449</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances on defect modulated electrocatalysts for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01805b</link>
      <description>Qianyun He, Lei Han, Chao Lin, Kai Tao, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399259171

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for applications such as water splitting and rechargeable metal-air batteries. Recent research has focused on improving the activity and stability of OER electrocatalysts...</description>
      <author>Qianyun He, Lei Han, Chao Lin, Kai Tao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01805b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Augmented Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution by &lt;i&gt;d&lt;/i&gt;&#8208;&lt;i&gt;p&lt;/i&gt; Orbital Electron Coupling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404772</link>
      <description>Ning Sun, Zhichuan Zheng, Zhuangzhuang Lai, Junjie Wang, Peng Du, Tianping Ying, Hai Feng Wang, Jianchun Xu, Runze Yu, Kaiming Bi, Ming Lei, Kuo-Si Huang, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399259276

                While high-entropy alloys (HEAs), high-entropy oxides (HEOs), and high-entropy hydroxides (HEHs), have been advanced as a novel frontier in electrocatalytic oxygen evolution, their inherent activity deficiency poses a major challenge. To achieve the unlimited goal to tailor the structure-activity relationship in multicomponent systems, entropy-driven composition engineering presents substantial potential, by fabricating high-entropy anion-regulated transition metal compounds as sophisticated oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts. Herein, we developed a versatile two-dimensional high-entropy metal phosphorus trisulfides (HEPS</description>
      <author>Ning Sun, Zhichuan Zheng, Zhuangzhuang Lai, Junjie Wang, Peng Du, Tianping Ying, Hai Feng Wang, Jianchun Xu, Runze Yu, Kaiming Bi, Ming Lei, Kuo-Si Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404772</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Microalgae-Membrane Photobioreactor System for Onboard Oxygen Production in an Aircraft</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-26-0402</link>
      <description>S. Chalathadka Subrahmanya, Naveen Kumar, J.K. Ranjan, Shivaprasad Kotnadh, SAE technical papers on CD-ROM/SAE technical paper series. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399266140

                &lt;div class="section abstract"&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;The purpose of the Air Generation System is to provide a constant supply of conditioned fresh air to meet the necessary oxygen availability and to prevent CO2 concentrations for the occupants in an aircraft. The engine bleed energy or electrical load energy consumed towards this circumstance accounts to be approximately 5% of total fuel burn and in turn, contributes to the global emissions of greenhouse gases.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;This paper studies the improvement areas of the present conventional system such as fuel burn consumption associated with an aircraft ECS depending on the amount of bleed, ram air usage and electric power consumption. Improved systems for sustainability and hybridization in environmental control systems are desirable in aircraft.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;This paper explains how a new design of the sustainable hybrid module assists the conventional system, by using a proposed modular MPBR. The MPBR system generates oxygen-enriched air, which is mixed with the traditional fresh air generated from conventional air generation systems.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;MPBR system revitalizes the existing air and establishes more air recirculation when compared to a conventional system. It will reduce the demand for fresh air from the engine bleed in case of engine bleed aircraft or reduce the electrical load in case of more electric aircraft, which hereby improves engine efficiency.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;The proposed system can also be used for redundant life support purposes during an emergency.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class="htmlview paragraph"&gt;VOCs related to fuel consumption, maintenance, and global emissions of greenhouse gases can be addressed with the proposed solution. It applies to most of the aircraft variants and enhances sustainability, hybridization, reliability, and cost-effective features which would be of value and interest in a business case for the Suppliers, Manufacturers, and Customers side.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <author>S. Chalathadka Subrahmanya, Naveen Kumar, J.K. Ranjan, Shivaprasad Kotnadh</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4271/2024-26-0402</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ semi-etching of bimetallic LDH nanosheet arrays into FeNi-LDH/MOF to boost oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152721</link>
      <description>Hanli Qin, Chenglong Jia, Quanfa Zhou, Zhenyuan Ji, Hanyong Peng, Xiaoping Shen, Hu Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, Juan Yang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399275113

                The inherent sluggish kinetics of water oxidation is the core issue for electrochemical hydrogen production from water splitting. Metal organic frameworks (MOFs) with tunable porous structures, abundant coordination metal centers and large specific surface area are expected as efficient electrocatalysts. In this paper, FeNi-LDH/MOF composite nanostructures were successfully constructed on carbon cloth (CC) through partially converting iron-nickel layered double hydroxide (FeNi-LDH) into FeNi-MOF (NiFe(CN)5NO) by an in-situ semi-etching method. The MOF nanocrystals in this material are in-situ decorated on the surface of FeNi-LDH nanosheets, providing abundant open active sites and mass transfer channels for electrocatalysis. Thanks to the synergistic effect of the LDH and MOF, as well as the exceptional hierarchical architecture, the FeNi-LDH/MOF/CC as a self-supported electrode exhibits distinguished electrocatalytic OER performance, with a low overpotential of 263 mV@100 mA cm&#8722;2 and a small Tafel slope of 50.2 mV dec-1 in 1.0 M KOH. In addition, the catalyst exhibits good durability with almost constant current density during 24 h OER test. This work provides an effective way to design high-performance MOFs-based composite electrocatalytic materials.</description>
      <author>Hanli Qin, Chenglong Jia, Quanfa Zhou, Zhenyuan Ji, Hanyong Peng, Xiaoping Shen, Hu Zhou, Guoxing Zhu, Juan Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152721</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrangea shaped bimetallic NiRu MOFs directly catalyzing highly-efficient alkaline freshwater/seawater overall splitting based on electronic structure and oxygen vacancy modulation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132025</link>
      <description>Junfeng Qin, Shijie Hu, Xiaohua Zhang, Maochun Hong, Cuicui Du, Jinhua Chen, Fuel. 371(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399201488

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junfeng Qin, Shijie Hu, Xiaohua Zhang, Maochun Hong, Cuicui Du, Jinhua Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.fuel.2024.132025</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional MoC/NiC@N-doped reduced graphene oxide nano electrocatalyst for simultaneous production of hydrogen and oxygen through efficient overall electrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2024.100489</link>
      <description>Abdullah Al Mahmud, Mohammad R. Thalji, Ganesh Dhakal, Yuvaraj Haldorai, Woo Kyoung Kim, Jae&#8211;Jin Shim, Materials today nano. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399219030

                Recently, hydrogen has been an important green energy source for fuel cell-operated vehicles, buildings, power plants, and portable electronics. This study focuses on developing inexpensive, non-noble bifunctional transition metal nano electrocatalysts for producing green hydrogen and industrially important oxygen simultaneously by water splitting. A nanocomposite consisting of two single-metal carbides, MoC and NiC, and nitrogen-doped reduced graphene oxide (N-rGO) was prepared for the first time as an electrocatalyst and used in water splitting. The overpotential of MoC/NiC@N-doped rGO was 185 mV for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and 298 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). The Tafel slopes for HER and OER were relatively modest, 78 and 80 mV dec&#8722;1, respectively. The nanocomposite had a 6.8% lower overpotential than RuO2 for OER. A symmetric two-electrode setup was prepared to split water through HER/OER to produce hydrogen and water simultaneously. In this apparatus, the nanocomposite electrocatalyst exhibited a high performance, raising the current density to 10 mA cm&#8722;2 and lowering the cell voltage by 2.5% below the standard material. The nanocomposite showed excellent stability for 55 h for overall water splitting. The highly performing MoC/NiC@N-doped rGO nanocomposite may open the horizon for developing efficient, inexpensive, non-noble bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Abdullah Al Mahmud, Mohammad R. Thalji, Ganesh Dhakal, Yuvaraj Haldorai, Woo Kyoung Kim, Jae&#8211;Jin Shim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtnano.2024.100489</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating built-in electric field via Bi-VO4-Fe interfacial bridges to enhance charge separation for efficient photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.218</link>
      <description>Yingying Wang, Jie Huang, Yuxuan Chen, Hao Yang, Kai&#8208;Hang Ye, Yongchao Huang, Journal of colloid and interface science. 672(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399242567

                Photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting on semiconductor electrodes is considered to be one of the important ways to produce clean and sustainable hydrogen fuel, which is a great help in solving energy and environmental problems. Bismuth vanadate (BiVO4) as a promising photoanode for photoelectrochemical water splitting still suffers from poor charge separation efficiency and photo-induced self-corrosion. Herein, we develop heterojunction-rich photoanodes composed of BiVO4 and iron vanadate (FeVO4), coated with nickel iron oxide (NiFeOx/FeVO4/BiVO4). The formation of the interface between BiVO4 and FeVO4 (Bi-VO4-Fe bridges) enhances the interfacial interaction, resulting in improved performance. Meanwhile, high-conductivity FeVO4 and NiFeOx oxygen evolution co-catalysts effectively enhance bulk electron/hole separation, interface water's kinetics and photostability. Concurrently, the optimized NiFeOx/FeVO4/BiVO4 possesses a remarkable photocurrent density of 5.59 mA/cm2 at 1.23 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (vs RHE) under AM 1.5G (Air Mass 1.5 Global) simulated sunlight, accompanied by superior stability without any decreased of its photocurrent density after 14 h. This work not only reveals the crucial role of built-in electric field in BiVO4-based photoanode during PEC water splitting, but also provides a new guide to the design of efficient photoanode for PEC.</description>
      <author>Yingying Wang, Jie Huang, Yuxuan Chen, Hao Yang, Kai&#8208;Hang Ye, Yongchao Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.218</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cauliflower-like Ni3S2 foam for ultrastable oxygen evolution electrocatalysis in alkaline seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6744-9</link>
      <description>Qing Dai, Xiuli He, Yongchao Yao, Kai Dong, Xuwei Liu, X.H. Guo, Jie Chen, Xiaoya Fan, Dongning Zheng, Yonglan Luo, Shengjun Sun, Luming Li, W. K. Chu, Amr Farouk, Mohamed S. Hamdy, Xuping Sun, Bo Tang, Nano research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399246793

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qing Dai, Xiuli He, Yongchao Yao, Kai Dong, Xuwei Liu, X.H. Guo, Jie Chen, Xiaoya Fan, Dongning Zheng, Yonglan Luo, Shengjun Sun, Luming Li, W. K. Chu, Amr Farouk, Mohamed S. Hamdy, Xuping Sun, Bo Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12274-024-6744-9</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen Vacancy Generation and Stabilization in Layered NiFeCo Double Hydroxide Nanosheets for a Highly Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01840</link>
      <description>Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Lemma Teshome Tufa, Mahendra Goddati, Youngseok Lee, Boka Fikadu Banti, Njemuwa Nwaji Njoku, S. J. You, Jaebeom Lee, ACS applied nano materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399282865

                Oxygen vacancy (Vo) is ubiquitous, playing a critical role in tuning the electronic configuration and optimizing the adsorption of adsorbates in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) process. However, fine control over the density and stabilization of Vo is a big challenge in the highly oxidizing environment of OER. Herein, we have fabricated bulk NiFeCo (layered double hydroxide) LDHs via the hydrothermal method and exfoliated them into thin sheets rich with Vo using high-energy Ar-plasma. We doped fluoride to simultaneously modulate the charge distribution of surrounding atoms and stabilize Vo by taking advantage of the extremely high electronegativity and similar ion diameter to oxygen of fluoride. The material exhibited OER activity with a low overpotential of 200 mV at 10 mA cm&#8211;2 and a Tafel slope of 34.6 mV dec&#8211;1. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations support the claim that Vo and fluoride substantially increase NiFeCo LDH OER activity by modifying the electronic structures of the catalytically active sites.</description>
      <author>Birhanu Bayissa Gicha, Lemma Teshome Tufa, Mahendra Goddati, Youngseok Lee, Boka Fikadu Banti, Njemuwa Nwaji Njoku, S. J. You, Jaebeom Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c01840</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing oxygen evolution reaction through self-reconstruction of 2D nanoarrays on nickel foam</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141389</link>
      <description>Xue Li, Dangcheng Su, Jianjun Chen, Bingbing Fan, Rui Zhang, Chemical physics letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399285934

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xue Li, Dangcheng Su, Jianjun Chen, Bingbing Fan, Rui Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cplett.2024.141389</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthetic Mn3Ce2O5&#8208;Cluster Mimicking the Oxygen&#8208;Evolving Center in Photosynthesis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401031</link>
      <description>Yang Chen, Yao Su, Juanjuan Han, Changhui Chen, Hongjun Fan, Changsheng Zhang, ChemSusChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399290354

                The photosynthetic oxygen&#8208;evolving center (OEC) is a unique Mn4CaO5&#8208;cluster that catalyzes water splitting into electrons, protons, and dioxygen. Precisely structural and functional mimicking of the OEC is a long&#8208;standing challenge and pressingly needed for understanding the structure&#8208;function relationship and catalytic mechanism of O&#8208;O bond formation. Herein we report two simple and robust artificial Mn3Ce2O5&#8208;complexes that display a remarkable structural similarity to the OEC in regarding of the ten&#8208;atom core (five metal ions and five oxygen bridges) and the alkyl carboxylate peripheral ligands. This Mn3Ce2O5&#8208;cluster can catalyze the water&#8208;splitting reaction on the surface of ITO electrode. These results clearly show that cerium can structurally and functionally replace both calcium and manganese in the cluster. Mass spectroscopic measurements demonstrate that the oxide bridges in the cluster are exchangeable and can be rapidly replaced by the isotopic oxygen of H218O in acetonitrile solution, which supports that the oxide bridge(s) may serve as the active site for the formation of O&#8208;O bond during the water&#8208;splitting reaction. These results would contribute to our understanding of the structure&#8208;reactivity relationship of both natural and artificial clusters and shed new light on the development of efficient water&#8208;splitting catalysts in artificial photosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Yang Chen, Yao Su, Juanjuan Han, Changhui Chen, Hongjun Fan, Changsheng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cssc.202401031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Acid Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-7</link>
      <description>Guangfu Li, Shichun Mu, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399290556

                The large-scale production of green hydrogen by proton exchange membrane (PEM) water electrolysis is currently of considerable interest. However, oxygen evolution reaction (OER) occurring in the anode is a primary source of overpotential due to the sluggish kinetics. To realize fast reaction kinetics, it is essential to obtain a facile electron transfer between electrocatalysts and the oxygen intermediates, which is critically related to reaction mechanism and electrode interface. Meanwhile, developing high-performance electrocatalysts for acidic OER is an outstanding challenge since most metal materials are unstable under the strong acidic and oxidative conditions. Even for the promising electrocatalyst candidates, Ir oxides undergo the continuous Ir dissolution due to surface oxidization during OER [1,2]. It is also difficult to establish the structure&#8211;performance relationship due to the dynamic changes of catalyst surface (named surface reconstruction). Hence, acquiring an enhanced understanding of the electron transfer pathways and reaction interface is crucial for the design of efficient and robust OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Guangfu Li, Shichun Mu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synthesis of Ni decorated MoOx nanorod catalysts for efficient overall urea&#8211;water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0206432</link>
      <description>Zhiwei Li, Wulin Yang, Kun Xiong, J CHEN, Haidong Zhang, Mingbo Yang, Xuewei Gan, Yuan Gao, Journal of chemical physics online/&#152;The &#156;Journal of chemical physics/Journal of chemical physics. 160(21)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399300065

                Substituting slow oxygen evolution reaction (OER) with thermodynamically favorable urea oxidation reaction (UOR) is considered as one of the feasible strategies for achieving energy-saving hydrogen production. Herein, a uniform layer of NiMoO4 nanorods was grown on nickel foam by a hydrothermal method. Then, a series of Ni-MoOx/NF-X nanorod catalysts comprising Ni/NiO and MoOx (MoO2/MoO3) were prepared through regulating annealing atmosphere and reduction temperature. The optimized Ni-MoOx/NF-3 with a large accessible specific area can act as a bifunctional catalyst for electrocatalytic anodic UOR and cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). At a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2, the introduction of urea can significantly reduce the overpotential of Ni-MoOx/NF-3 by 210 mV compared to OER. In addition, Ni-MoOx/NF-3 has a higher intrinsic activity than other catalysts. It only requires &#8722;0.21 and 1.38 V to reach 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in HER and UOR, respectively. Such an excellent performance can be attributed to the synergistic function between Ni and MoOx. The presence of metallic Ni and reduced MoOx in pairs is beneficial for improving the electrical conductivity and modulating the electronic structure, resulting in enhancing the electrocatalytic performance. When assembling Ni-MoOx/NF-3 into an overall urea&#8211;water splitting system, it can achieve energy-saving hydrogen production and effective removal of urea-rich wastewater.</description>
      <author>Zhiwei Li, Wulin Yang, Kun Xiong, J CHEN, Haidong Zhang, Mingbo Yang, Xuewei Gan, Yuan Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0206432</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Janus dual-atom catalyst for electrocatalytic oxygen reduction and evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00545-1</link>
      <description>Bing Tang, Yanan Zhou, Qianqian Ji, Zechao Zhuang, Lei Zhang, Chao Wang, Haibo Hu, Huijuan Wang, Bingbao Mei, Fei Song, Shuang Yang, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Hao Tan, Dingsheng Wang, Wensheng Yan, Nature synthesis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399300303

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Tang, Yanan Zhou, Qianqian Ji, Zechao Zhuang, Lei Zhang, Chao Wang, Haibo Hu, Huijuan Wang, Bingbao Mei, Fei Song, Shuang Yang, Bert M. Weckhuysen, Hao Tan, Dingsheng Wang, Wensheng Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s44160-024-00545-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Surface Reconstruction of Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-8</link>
      <description>Mengxin Chen, Pengyun Xu, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301995

                Along with the intensified global energy crisis and climate change, it is particularly crucial to accelerate the transformation of the energy structure and gradually increase the percentage of new energy. Currently, electrochemical water splitting is widely regarded as one of the most promising hydrogen production technologies, with considerable implications for tackling the challenge of global warming and achieving the goal of "carbon neutrality". The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a crucial anode reaction for water splitting, metal-air batteries, and renewable fuel cells. However, the OER process contains four proton&#8211;electron transfer steps, resulting in a slow kinetics, which has long been the bottleneck. In general, noble metals and their oxides (RuO2 and IrO2) are considered to be promising catalysts for OER, but the high price and scarce resources restrict their wide-scale application. Hence, it is crucial to develop low-cost, high-activity and stable catalysts for improving the efficiency of water splitting. Recently, significant attention has been dedicated to non-noble transition metal materials as promising alternatives for water splitting. Gaining a comprehensive understanding of the intrinsic catalytic mechanism and identifying the active sites of catalysts will greatly benefit the rational design and effective application of high-efficiency catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mengxin Chen, Pengyun Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-8</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self-protecting CoFeAl-layered double hydroxides enable stable and efficient brine oxidation at 2 A cm&#8722;2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49195-z</link>
      <description>Wei Liu, Jiage Yu, Tianshui Li, Shihang Li, Biao Ding, Xiaoxiao Guo, Ang Cao, Qihao Sha, Daojin Zhou, Yun Kuang, Xiaoming Sun, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399302363

                Abstract Low-energy consumption seawater electrolysis at high current density is an effective way for hydrogen production, however the continuous feeding of seawater may result in the accumulation of Cl &#8722; , leading to severe anode poisoning and corrosion, thereby compromising the activity and stability. Herein, CoFeAl layered double hydroxide anodes with excellent oxygen evolution reaction activity are synthesized and delivered stable catalytic performance for 350 hours at 2 A cm &#8722;2 in the presence of 6-fold concentrated seawater. Comprehensive analysis reveals that the Al 3+ ions in electrode are etched off by OH &#8722; during oxygen evolution reaction process, resulting in M 3+ vacancies that boost oxygen evolution reaction activity. Additionally, the self-originated Al(OH) n &#8722; is found to adsorb on the anode surface to improve stability. An electrode assembly based on a micropore membrane and CoFeAl layered double hydroxide electrodes operates continuously for 500 hours at 1 A cm &#8722;2 , demonstrating their feasibility in brine electrolysis.</description>
      <author>Wei Liu, Jiage Yu, Tianshui Li, Shihang Li, Biao Ding, Xiaoxiao Guo, Ang Cao, Qihao Sha, Daojin Zhou, Yun Kuang, Xiaoming Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49195-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co/Ce-MOF-Derived Oxygen Electrode Bifunctional Catalyst for Rechargeable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00787</link>
      <description>Kang Wu, Daomiao Wang, Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Qihua Xiong, Shaik Gouse Peera, Chao Liu, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399302485

                Improving the practicality of rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries relies heavily on the development of oxygen electrode catalysts that are low-cost, durable, and highly efficient in performing dual functions. In the present study, a catalyst with atomic Ce and Co distribution on a nitrogen-doped carbon substrate was prepared by doping the rare earth elements Ce and Co into a metal&#8211;organic framework precursor. Rare earth element Ce, known for its unique structure and excellent oxygen affinity, was utilized to regulate the catalytic activity. The catalyst prepared in this study demonstrated an exceptional electrocatalytic performance. At a current density of 10 mA cm&#8211;2, the catalyst exhibited an overpotential of 340 mV for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), which was lower than that of commercial IrO2 (370 mV), while achieving a half-wave potential of 0.79 V for the process of oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), exhibiting a similar level of effectiveness as commercially accessible Pt/C catalysts (0.8 V). The catalyst's porous structure, interconnected three-dimensional carbon network, and large specific surface area are the factors contributing to the significant improvement in catalytic performance. Furthermore, in comparison to commercial Pt/C+IrO2, the catalyst exhibited good cycling stability and high efficiency in rechargeable zinc&#8211;air batteries.</description>
      <author>Kang Wu, Daomiao Wang, Qiming Fu, Tongtong Xu, Qihua Xiong, Shaik Gouse Peera, Chao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00787</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Transition Metal-Based Polyoxometalates for Oxygen Electrode Bifunctional Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10060197</link>
      <description>Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Filipe M. B. Gusm&#227;o, Sara Kne&#382;evi&#263;, Nemanja Gavrilov, Anup Paul, Diogo M.F. Santos, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;, Batteries. 10(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399304301

                Polyoxometalates (POMs) with transition metals (Co, Cu, Fe, Mn, Ni) of Keggin structure and lamellar-stacked multi-layer morphology were synthesized. They were subsequently explored as bifunctional electrocatalysts for oxygen electrodes, i.e., oxygen reduction (ORR) and evolution (OER) reaction, for aqueous rechargeable metal-air batteries in alkaline media. The lowest Tafel slope (85 mV dec&#8722;1) value and the highest OER current density of 93.8 mA cm&#8722;2 were obtained for the Fe-POM electrocatalyst. Similar OER electrochemical catalytic activity was noticed for the Co-POM electrocatalyst. This behavior was confirmed by electrochemical impedance spectroscopy, where Fe-POM gave the lowest charge transfer resistance of 3.35 &#937;, followed by Co-POM with Rct of 15.04 &#937;, during the OER. Additionally, Tafel slope values of 85 and 109 mV dec&#8722;1 were calculated for Fe-POM and Co-POM, respectively, during the ORR. The ORR at Fe-POM proceeded by mixed two- and four-electron pathways, while ORR at Co-POM proceeded exclusively by the four-electron pathway. Finally, capacitance studies were conducted on the synthesized POMs.</description>
      <author>Jadranka Miliki&#263;, Filipe M. B. Gusm&#227;o, Sara Kne&#382;evi&#263;, Nemanja Gavrilov, Anup Paul, Diogo M.F. Santos, Biljana &#352;ljuki&#263;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/batteries10060197</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Trends and Perspectives in Single-Entity Electrochemistry: A Review with Focus on a Water Splitting Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1080/10408347.2024.2358492</link>
      <description>A. Gowrisankar, Byung Kwon Kim, Critical reviews in analytical chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399304430

                Electrochemical measurements involving single nanoparticles have attracted considerable research attention. In recent years, various studies have been conducted on single-entity electrochemistry (SEE) for the in-depth analyses of catalytic reactions. Although, several electrocatalysts have been developed for H2 energy production, designing innovative electrocatalysts for this purpose remains a challenging task. Stochastic collision electrochemistry is gaining increased attention because it has led to new findings in the SEE field. Importantly, it facilitates establishing structure activity relationships for electrocatalysts by monitoring transient signals. This article reviews the recent achievements related to hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) using different electrocatalysts at the nanoscale level. In particular, it discusses the electrocatalytic activities of noble metal nanoparticles, including Ag, Au, Pt, and Pd nanoparticles, at the single-particle level. Because heterogeneity is a key factor affecting the catalytic activity of nanostructures, our work focuses on the influence of heterogeneities in catalytic materials on the OER and HER activities. These results may help to achieve a better understanding of the fundamental processes involved in the water splitting reaction.</description>
      <author>A. Gowrisankar, Byung Kwon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1080/10408347.2024.2358492</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring the Active Sites of Nanosheet NiSe/NiSe2 Catalyst by Pulse Electrodeposition on the 3D Microporous Ni-Cu/NF Substrate for both Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad5381</link>
      <description>Nafise Modghan, Mostafa Mirjalili, Mohammad Hadi Moayed, Ghasem Barati Darband, Journal of the Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399305499

                Abstract Establishing proper intrinsic catalysts with nanostructured high active surfaces endows the paramount electrocatalytic activity. A Ni-Se@Cu-Ni/NF catalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER and OER) is prepared via an efficient two-step pulse current (PC) electrodeposition method. The initial 3D film of Cu-Ni is synthesized via the dynamic hydrogen bubble template (DHBT) method to attain further active surface area. Then, Ni-Se film is prepared by direct current (DC) and PC electrodeposition. Morphological, chemical, and electrocatalytic characteristics of the Ni-Se electrodeposited films are evaluated. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy and high-resolution transmission electron microscopy results show a NiSe/NiSe2 nanofilm on the 3D microporous nanostructured Cu-Ni substrate which reveals an efficient bifunctional electrocatalytic behavior with overpotentials of 74 and 272 mV in the current density of 10 mA cm-2, and Tafel slopes of 78 and 50 mV dec-1 for HER and OER, respectively. The two-electrode examination with NiSe/NiSe2@Cu-Ni/NF catalyst in overall water splitting indicates a required potential of 1.57 V in the current density of 10 mA cm-2.</description>
      <author>Nafise Modghan, Mostafa Mirjalili, Mohammad Hadi Moayed, Ghasem Barati Darband</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad5381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pourbaix Machine Learning Framework Identifies Acidic Water Oxidation Catalysts Exhibiting Suppressed Ruthenium Dissolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01353</link>
      <description>Jehad Abed, Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Ming Ronnier Luo, Wajdi Alnoush, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Jian Wang, Jigang Zhou, Daojin Zhou, Khalid Fatih, John R. Kitchin, Drew Higgins, Zachary W. Ulissi, Edward H. Sargent, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399305702

                The demand for green hydrogen has raised concerns over the availability of iridium used in oxygen evolution reaction catalysts. We identify catalysts with the aid of a machine learning-aided computational pipeline trained on more than 36,000 mixed metal oxides. The pipeline accurately predicts Pourbaix decomposition energy (Gpbx) from unrelaxed structures with a mean absolute error of 77 meV per atom, enabling us to screen 2070 new metallic oxides with respect to their prospective stability under acidic conditions. The search identifies Ru0.6Cr0.2Ti0.2O2 as a candidate having the promise of increased durability: experimentally, we find that it provides an overpotential of 267 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 and that it operates at this current density for over 200 h and exhibits a rate of overpotential increase of 25 &#956;V h&#8211;1. Surface density functional theory calculations reveal that Ti increases metal&#8211;oxygen covalency, a potential route to increased stability, while Cr lowers the energy barrier of the HOO* formation rate-determining step, increasing activity compared to RuO2 and reducing overpotential by 40 mV at 100 mA cm&#8211;2 while maintaining stability. In situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy and ex situ ptychography-scanning transmission X-ray microscopy show the evolution of a metastable structure during the reaction, slowing Ru mass dissolution by 20&#215; and suppressing lattice oxygen participation by &gt;60% compared to RuO2.</description>
      <author>Jehad Abed, Javier Heras&#8208;Domingo, Rohan Yuri Sanspeur, Ming Ronnier Luo, Wajdi Alnoush, D&#233;bora Motta Meira, Hsiao&#8208;Tsu Wang, Jian Wang, Jigang Zhou, Daojin Zhou, Khalid Fatih, John R. Kitchin, Drew Higgins, Zachary W. Ulissi, Edward H. Sargent</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c01353</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green reaction engineering towards an iron-based nanostructured hybrid as an electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01193g</link>
      <description>Anna Dymerska, Ewa Mijowska, F. G. Vagizov, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Rustem Zairov, Ewa Mijowska, Journal of materials chemistry. A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399309285

                Developing robust electrocatalysts based on nonprecious metals with high activity in the sluggish oxygen-evolution reaction (OER) is crucial for achieving large-scale hydrogen production.</description>
      <author>Anna Dymerska, Ewa Mijowska, F. G. Vagizov, Almaz L. Zinnatullin, Rustem Zairov, Ewa Mijowska</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta01193g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Development of Ternary Layered Double Hydroxide Oxygen Evolution Reaction Electrocatalyst for Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3365/kjmm.2024.62.6.472</link>
      <description>Seungjun Myeong, Song Jin, Chiho Kim, Jooyoung Lee, Jae Won Kim, Minseok Choi, Daehan geumsog jae'lyo haghoeji/Daehan geumsok jaeryo hakoeji. 62(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399313073

                To achieve net zero emissions, green hydrogen should be produced via water electrolysis with renewable energy. To develop efficient anion exchange membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWE), the development of efficient and stable non-precious metal electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is essential. In this study, a high-performance ternary NiFeCo-layer double hydroxide (LDH) electrocatalyst for AEMWE was easily developed by the co-precipitation method. The introduction of Co has been shown to have an effect on the electronic structure of Ni and Fe, improving their intrinsic OER properties. In addition, the three-dimensional flower-like nanosheet morphology improved mass transfer and achieved excellent current density at high voltages. The ternary NiFeCo-LDH electrocatalyst requires low overpotentials (253 mV at 10 mA cm-2) and Tafel slope (45 mV dec-1) in 1 M KOH. AEMWE using the ternary NiFeCo-LDH electrocatalyst showed excellent electrolysis performance with a high current density of 2.27 A cm-2 at 1.8 V cell. Moreover, an energy conversion efficiency of 86.73 % was achieved during the durability test for 100 hours at a current density of 0.5 A cm-2. The performance of the AEMWE electrolyzer utilizing the ternary NiFeCo-LDH electrocatalyst surpassed that of previously reported AEMWE electrolyzers. This work reports a highly active OER electrocatalyst that could open numerous opportunities for the development of ternary LDH electrocatalysts in AEMWE.</description>
      <author>Seungjun Myeong, Song Jin, Chiho Kim, Jooyoung Lee, Jae Won Kim, Minseok Choi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3365/kjmm.2024.62.6.472</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt Titanate&#8211;Phosphorous-Doped g-C3N4 Heterostructure with Impressive Electrocatalytic Activity for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11148-z</link>
      <description>Rekha Muthuvel, Mukul Sethi, L. Cindrella, Journal of electronic materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399322660

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Rekha Muthuvel, Mukul Sethi, L. Cindrella</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s11664-024-11148-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Simple and Scalable Synthetic Route for Tunable Compositions of Multimetallic Oxyfluorides as Oxygen Evolution Reaction Catalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00259</link>
      <description>Alexandre Terry, Samuel Mathiot, Amandine Guiet, &#201;douard Boivin, Zahra Goharibajestani, Vincent Maisonneuve, Annie H&#233;mon&#8208;Ribaud, Romain Moury, Nikolay Kornienko, J&#233;r&#244;me Lhoste, ACS applied energy materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399323479

                This work suggests a simple and scalable synthetic route to prepare multimetallic oxyfluorides, without requiring high temperature, high pressure, and a specific atmosphere (F2, N2, Ar, vacuum, etc.). For that, tunable compositions of Ni2+&#8211;Co2+&#8211;Fe3+-based oxyfluorides Co(1&#8211;x)/2Nix/2Fe0.5O0.5F1.5 have been prepared by calcination at moderate temperature under ambient air of Co1&#8211;xNixFeF5(H2O)7 precursors, prepared beforehand through coprecipitation at room temperature, across the whole range of the solid solution (0 &#8804; x &#8804; 1). Structural and thermal analyses confirmed the successful substitution for both hydrated fluoride precursors and oxyfluorides. Finally, we evaluated the electrocatalytic performance of the different Ni2+&#8211;Co2+&#8211;Fe3+ oxyfluorides for oxygen evolution reaction. Among these, the trimetallic Co0.25Ni0.25Fe0.5O0.5F1.5 exhibits the lowest overpotential (290 and 370 mV respectively at 10 and 100 mA cm&#8211;2) and the highest specific activity (3.9 A m&#8211;2 at 1.53 V vs RHE). These results highlight the need for compositional tunability to maximize performance.</description>
      <author>Alexandre Terry, Samuel Mathiot, Amandine Guiet, &#201;douard Boivin, Zahra Goharibajestani, Vincent Maisonneuve, Annie H&#233;mon&#8208;Ribaud, Romain Moury, Nikolay Kornienko, J&#233;r&#244;me Lhoste</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00259</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong Metal&#8208;Support Interaction Modulation between Pt Nanoclusters and Mn&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Nanosheets through Oxygen Vacancy Control to Achieve High Activities for Acidic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402652</link>
      <description>Dan Hu, Yongjie Wang, Weiheng Chen, Zhongqing Jiang, Binglu Deng, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399330823

                Abstract The optimization of metal&#8208;support interactions is used to fabricate noble metal&#8208;based nanoclusters with high activity for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in acid media. Specifically, the oxygen&#8208;defective Mn 3 O 4 nanosheets supported Pt nanoclusters of &#8776;1.71 nm in diameter (Pt/V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs) are synthesized through the controlled solvothermal reaction. The Pt/V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs show a superior activity and excellent stability for the HER in the acidic media. They only require an overpotential of 19 mV to drive &#8722;10 mA cm &#8722;2 and show negligible activity loss at &#8722;10 and &#8722;250 mA cm &#8722;2 for &gt;200 and &gt;60 h, respectively. Their Pt mass activity is 12.4 times higher than that of the Pt/C and even higher than those of many single&#8208;atom based Pt catalysts. DFT calculations show that their high HER activity arises mainly from the strong metal&#8208;support interaction between Pt and Mn 3 O 4 . It can facilitate the charge transfer from Mn 3 O 4 to Pt, optimizing the H adsorption on the catalyst surface and promoting the evolution of H 2 through the Volmer&#8211;Tafel mechanism. The oxygen vacancies in the V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs are found to be inconducive to the high activity of the Pt/V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs, highlighting the great importance to reduce the vacancy levels in V&#183;&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 NSs.</description>
      <author>Dan Hu, Yongjie Wang, Weiheng Chen, Zhongqing Jiang, Binglu Deng, Zhong&#8208;Jie Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402652</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood&#8208;Structured Nanomaterials as Highly Efficient, Self&#8208;Standing Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402511</link>
      <description>Jianlin Huang, Zhikai Shi, Chengwei Mao, Gaixiu Yang, Yan Chen, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399331219

                Abstract Electrocatalytic water splitting (EWS) driven by renewable energy is widely considered an environmentally friendly and sustainable approach for generating hydrogen (H 2 ), an ideal energy carrier for the future. However, the efficiency and economic viability of large&#8208;scale water electrolysis depend on electrocatalysts that can efficiently accelerate the electrochemical reactions taking place at the two electrodes. Wood&#8208;derived nanomaterials are well&#8208;suited for serving as EWS catalysts because of their hierarchically porous structure with high surface area and low tortuosity, compositional tunability, cost&#8208;effectiveness, and self&#8208;standing integral electrode configuration. Here, recent advancements in the design and synthesis of wood&#8208;structured nanomaterials serving as advanced electrocatalysts for water splitting are summarized. First, the design principles and corresponding strategies toward highly effective wood&#8208;structured electrocatalysts (WSECs) are emphasized. Then, a comprehensive overview of current findings on WSECs, encompassing diverse structural designs and functionalities such as supported&#8208;metal nanoparticles (NPs), single&#8208;atom catalysts (SACs), metal compounds, and heterostructured electrocatalysts based on engineered wood hosts are presented. Subsequently, the application of these WSECs in various aspects of water splitting, including the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), oxygen evolution reaction (OER), overall water splitting (OWS), and hybrid water electrolysis (HWE) are explored. Finally, the prospects, challenges, and opportunities associated with the broad application of WSECs are briefly discussed. This review aims to provide a comprehensive understanding of the ongoing developments in water&#8208;splitting catalysts, along with outlining design principles for the future development of WSECs.</description>
      <author>Jianlin Huang, Zhikai Shi, Chengwei Mao, Gaixiu Yang, Yan Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Ligands Regulate the Redox Leveling Mechanism of the Oxygen-Evolving Complex of the Photosystem II</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02926</link>
      <description>Jinchan Liu, Ke Yang, Zhuoran Long, William H. Armstrong, Gary W. Brudvig, V&#237;ctor S. Batista, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399332391

                Understanding how water ligands regulate the conformational changes and functionality of the oxygen-evolving complex (OEC) in photosystem II (PSII) throughout the catalytic cycle of oxygen evolution remains a highly intriguing and unresolved challenge. In this study, we investigate the effect of water insertion (WI) on the redox state of the OEC by using the molecular dynamics (MD) and quantum mechanics/molecular mechanics (QM/MM) hybrid methods. We find that water binding significantly reduces the free energy change for proton-coupled electron transfer (PCET) from Mn to Y</description>
      <author>Jinchan Liu, Ke Yang, Zhuoran Long, William H. Armstrong, Gary W. Brudvig, V&#237;ctor S. Batista</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c02926</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiFe&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;2&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;O&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;4&amp;lt;/sub&amp;gt;Materials Based on Mo and Mn Diatomic Co-Doping Were Used to Study Oxygen Evolution Performance</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.12677/japc.2024.132028</link>
      <description>&#39062; &#39038;, Wu li hua xue jin zhan. 13(02)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399349968

                No abstract</description>
      <author>&#39062; &#39038;</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.12677/japc.2024.132028</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Prediction of Feasibility of Polaronic OER on the (110) Surface of Rutile TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400523</link>
      <description>Hori Pada Sarker, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Michal Bajdich, ChemPhysChem. 25(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399359402

                Abstract The front cover artwork is provided by Dr. Hori Pada Sarker from Dr. Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen's research group at the SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory. The image shows the generation of photoexcited carriers (electrons and holes) and the subsequent formation of hole polaron in rutile TiO 2 during oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Read the full text of the Research Article at 10.1002/cphc.202400060 .</description>
      <author>Hori Pada Sarker, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Michal Bajdich</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cphc.202400523</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self&#8208;Powered Electrochemical CO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Conversion Enabled by a Multifunctional Carbon&#8208;Based Electrocatalyst and a Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401766</link>
      <description>Jingrui Han, Lei Shi, Huamei Xie, Ruilin Song, Dan Wang, Dong Liu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399359807

                Abstract Multifunctional electrocatalysts are required for diverse clean energy&#8208;related technologies (e.g., electrochemical CO 2 reduction reaction (CO 2 RR) and metal&#8211;air batteries). Herein, a nitrogen and fluorine co&#8208;doped carbon nanotube (NFCNT) is reported to simultaneously achieve multifunctional catalytic activities for CO 2 RR, oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Theoretical calculations reveal that the superior multifunctional catalytic activities of NFCNT are attributed to the synergistic effect of nitrogen and fluorine co&#8208;doping to induce charge redistribution and decrease the energy barrier of rate&#8208;determining step for different electrocatalytic reactions. Furthermore, the rechargeable Zn&#8211;air battery (ZAB) with NFCNT electrode delivers a high peak power density of 230 mW cm &#8722;2 and superior durability over 100 cycles, outperforming the ZAB with Pt/C+RuO 2 based electrodes. More importantly, a self&#8208;driven CO 2 electrolysis unit powered by the as&#8208;assembled ZABs is developed, which achieves 80% CO Faraday efficiency and 60% total energy efficiency. This work provides a new insight into the exploration of highly efficient multifunctional carbon&#8208;based electrocatalysts for novel energy&#8208;related applications.</description>
      <author>Jingrui Han, Lei Shi, Huamei Xie, Ruilin Song, Dan Wang, Dong Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202401766</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vanadium&#8208;Doped Heterogeneous Bimetallic Phosphides Derived from Layered Double Hydroxides for Saline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402250</link>
      <description>Yixuan Li, Jiahui Jiang, Qing Wu, Yi Feng, Zhongxu Chen, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Li Zhang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399360497

                Abstract The development of energy&#8208; and time&#8208;saving synthetic methods to prepare bifunctional and high stability catalysts are vital for overall water splitting. Here, V&#8208;doped nickel&#8208;iron hydroxide precursor by etching NiFe foam (NFF) at room temperature with dual chloride solution (&#8220;NaCl&#8208;VCl3&#8221;), is obtained then phosphating to obtain V&#8208;Ni 2 P&#8208;FeP/NFF as efficient bifunctional (oxygen/hydrogen exchange reaction, OER/HER) electrocatalysts, denoted as NFF(V, Na)&#8208;P. The NFF(V, Na)&#8208;P requires only 185 and 117 mV overpotentials to reach 10 mA cm &#8722;2 for OER and HER. When used as a catalyst for water splitting in a full cell, it can be stably sustained for more than 1000 h in alkaline brine electrolysis at both current densities of 100 and 500 mA cm &#8722;2 . In situ Raman analyses and density functional theory (DFT) show that the V&#8208;doping&#8208;induced surface remodeling generates hydroxyl oxides as the true catalytic active centers, which not only enhances the reaction kinetics, but also reduces the free energy change in the rate&#8208;determining step. This work provides a cost&#8208;effective substrate self&#8208;derivation method to convert commercial NFF into a powerful catalyst for electrolytic brine, offering a unique route to the development of efficient electrocatalysts for saline water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yixuan Li, Jiahui Jiang, Qing Wu, Yi Feng, Zhongxu Chen, Guan&#8208;Cheng Xu, Li Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202402250</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ceria&#8208;Optimized Oxygen&#8208;Species Exchange in Hierarchical Bimetallic Hydroxide for Electrocatalytic Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202406682</link>
      <description>Li Guo, Zhuang Zhang, Zhaori Mu, Pengfei Da, An Li, Wei Shen, Yichao Hou, Pinxian Xi, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399360588

                Abstract The utilization of rare earth elements to regulate the interaction between catalysts and oxygen&#8208;containing species holds promising prospects in the field of oxygen electrocatalysis. Through structural engineering and adsorption regulation, it is possible to achieve high&#8208;performance catalytic sites with a broken activity&#8208;stability tradeoff. Herein, we fabricate a hierarchical CeO 2 /NiCo hydroxide for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction (OER). This material exhibits superior overpotentials and enhanced stability. Multiple potential&#8208;dependent experiments reveal that CeO 2 promotes oxygen&#8208;species exchange, especially OH &#8722; ions, between catalyst and environment, thereby optimizing the redox transformation of hydroxide and the adsorption of oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates during OER. This is attributed to the reduction in the adsorption energy barrier of Ni to *OH facilitated by CeO 2 , particularly the near&#8208;interfacial Ni sites. The less&#8208;damaging adsorbate evolution mechanism and the CeO 2 hierarchical shell significantly enhance the structural robustness, leading to exceptional stability. Additionally, the observed &#8220;self&#8208;healing&#8221; phenomenon provides further substantiation for the accelerated oxygen exchange. This work provides a neat strategy for the synthesis of ceria&#8208;based complex hollow electrocatalysts, as well as an in&#8208;depth insight into the co&#8208;catalytic role of CeO 2 in terms of oxygen transfer. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Li Guo, Zhuang Zhang, Zhaori Mu, Pengfei Da, An Li, Wei Shen, Yichao Hou, Pinxian Xi, Chun&#8208;Hua Yan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202406682</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block copolymer-mediated synthesis of TiO2/RuO2 nanocomposite for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09702-5</link>
      <description>Binod Raj KC, Dhananjay Kumar, Bishnu Prasad Bastakoti, Journal of materials science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399362951

                Abstract An amphiphilic block copolymer, poly (styrene-2-polyvinyl pyridine-ethylene oxide), was used as a structure-directing and stabilizing agent to synthesize TiO 2 /RuO 2 nanocomposite. The strong interaction of polymers with metal precursors led to formation of a porous heterointerface of TiO 2 /RuO 2 . It acted as a bridge for electron transport, which can accelerate the water splitting reaction. Scanning electron microscopy, energy-dispersive X -ray spectroscopy, transmission electron microscopy, and X -ray diffraction analysis of TiO 2 /RuO 2 samples revealed successful fabrication of TiO 2 /RuO 2 nanocomposites. The TiO 2 /RuO 2 nanocomposites were used to measure electrochemical water splitting in three-electrode systems in 0.1-M KOH. Electrochemical activities unveil that TiO 2 /RuO 2 -150 nanocomposites displayed superior oxygen evolution reaction activity, having a low overpotential of 260 mV with a Tafel slope of 80 mVdec &#8722;1 . Graphical abstract</description>
      <author>Binod Raj KC, Dhananjay Kumar, Bishnu Prasad Bastakoti</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s10853-024-09702-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous MnRuOx Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405641</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Li Gao, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399241187

                Compared to Ir, Ru&#8208;based catalysts often exhibited higher activity but suffered significant and rapid activity loss during the challenging oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in a corrosive acidic environment. Herein, we developed a hybrid MnRuOx catalyst in which the RuO2 microcrystalline regions serve as a supporting framework, and the amorphous MnRuOx phase fills the microcrystalline interstices. In particular, the MnRuOx&#8208;300 catalyst from an annealing temperature of 300oC contains an optimal amorphous/crystalline heterostructure, providing substantial defects and active sites, facilitating efficient adsorption and conversion of OH&#8208;. In addition, the heterostructure leads to a relative increase of the d&#8208;band center close to the Fermin level, thus accelerating electron transfer with reduced charge transfer resistance at the active interface between crystalline and amorphous phases during the OER. The catalyst was further thoroughly evaluated under various operating conditions and demonstrated exceptional activity and stability for the OER, representing a promising solution to replace Ir in water electrolyzers.</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Li Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202405641</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal vacancies and self-reconstruction of high entropy metal borates to boost the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152758</link>
      <description>Mengyuan Zhang, Kai Luo, Yaning Fan, Xiaoyan L&#252;, Jian Ye, Ning Liu, Jie Dong, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399275414

                Exploring highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction (OER) electrocatalysts is important for industrial water electrolysis. Herein, a new high entropy material was reported, i.e., an amorphous high entropy metal borate (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx was synthesized by a new simple solvothermal method. The key of this new synthesis method was to obtain (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx with a high specific surface area (446 m2/g) and porous structure, being expected to promote OER reaction. (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx provided a low overpotential of 236 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, a reduced Tafel slope of 64 mV dec&#8211;1, and good stability. The outstanding OER performance of (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx was attributed to the high entropy structure, generation of metal vacancies, and self-reconstruction during OER. The Cr vacancies generated during the OER process have been demonstrated by Cr 2P XPS and EPR experiments. Various in situ and Ex-situ analyses such as In situ Raman, XPS, and TEM were used to investigate the self-reconstruction of the (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx during the OER. The resulting metal (oxy)hydroxide was believed to be the true active center for OER. The DFT calculation showed the high entropy structure can reduce the adsorption and conversion energy barriers of oxygen-containing intermediates, matching well with the catalytic performance results. This study provided a new simple strategy to construct high entropy metal borate (CrMnCoNiFe)0.2BOx and would inspire the design of high-performance OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Mengyuan Zhang, Kai Luo, Yaning Fan, Xiaoyan L&#252;, Jian Ye, Ning Liu, Jie Dong, Qiang Niu, Junjun Zhang, Pengfei Zhang, Sheng Dai</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152758</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulating the effective ionic radii of trivalent dopants in ceria using a combination of dopants to improve catalytic efficiency for the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03360d</link>
      <description>Debarati Das, Jyoti Prakash, Anisha Bandyopadhyay, Annu Balhara, U.K. Goutam, R. Acharya, Santosh K. Gupta, K. Sudarshan, RSC advances. 14(25)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399309847

                Matching effective ionic radii of trivalent dopants with the host through judicious choice of dopants and codopants has emerged as a smarter strategy for improving OER catalytic activity of ceria than individual ion doping.</description>
      <author>Debarati Das, Jyoti Prakash, Anisha Bandyopadhyay, Annu Balhara, U.K. Goutam, R. Acharya, Santosh K. Gupta, K. Sudarshan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ra03360d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineering in Composition and Valence Band Center of Y&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;(Y&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;Ru&lt;sub&gt;1&#8211;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&#8722;&#948;&lt;/sub&gt; Pyrochlore Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04292</link>
      <description>Barnali Ghosh, Cheng Zhang, Stefanie Frick, En Ju Cho, Toby J. Woods, Ying Yang, Nicola H. Perry, Andreas Klein, Hong Yang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399209196

                Oxygen evolution reaction (OER) takes place in various types of electrochemical devices that are pivotal for the conversion and storage of renewable energy. This paper describes a strategy in the design of solid-state structures of OER electrocatalysts through controlling the cation substitution on the active metal site and consequently valence band center position of site-mixed Y</description>
      <author>Barnali Ghosh, Cheng Zhang, Stefanie Frick, En Ju Cho, Toby J. Woods, Ying Yang, Nicola H. Perry, Andreas Klein, Hong Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application of machine learning to discover new intermetallic catalysts for the hydrogen evolution and the oxygen reduction reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00491d</link>
      <description>Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo, Benjamin M. Comer, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Kirsten T. Winther, J. Llorca, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399336542

                The adsorption energies for hydrogen, oxygen, and hydroxyl were calculated by means of density functional theory on the lowest energy surface of 24 pure metals and 332 binary intermetallic compounds...</description>
      <author>Carmen Mart&#237;nez-Alonso, Valent&#237;n Vassilev-Galindo, Benjamin M. Comer, Frank Abild&#8208;Pedersen, Kirsten T. Winther, J. Llorca</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00491d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Acidic Hydrogen Evolution through Pyrrolic Nitrogen-Doped Reduced Graphene Oxide Triggering Two-Electron Oxygen Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01187b</link>
      <description>Zhiqiang Hou, Hui Jiang, Yafei Guo, Ke&#8208;Jing Huang, Fei Zhao, Yin Xu, Peng Peng, Shasha Zou, Juan Yan, Junjun Zhang, Inorganic chemistry frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399294549

                Developing cost-effective and efficient electrocatalysts is essential for addressing the slow kinetics and high overpotential in the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), but significant challenges remain. Here, we fabricated the sandwich-structured...</description>
      <author>Zhiqiang Hou, Hui Jiang, Yafei Guo, Ke&#8208;Jing Huang, Fei Zhao, Yin Xu, Peng Peng, Shasha Zou, Juan Yan, Junjun Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01187b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution of In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; by Decorating In&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; with Rich Oxygen Vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00720</link>
      <description>Changxue Dong, Qiuyan Chen, Xin Deng, Lan Jiang, Tianli Han, Yufeng Zhou, Jinwei Chen, Ruilin Wang, Inorganic chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399331742

                The hydrogen (H2) evolution rates of photocatalysts suffer from weak oxidation and reduction ability and low photogenerated charge carrier separation efficiency. Herein, by combining band-gap structure optimization and vacancy modulation through a one-step hydrothermal method, In2O3 containing oxygen vacancy (Ov/In2O3) is simply introduced into In2S3 to promote photocatalytic hydrogen evolution. Specifically, the change in the sulfur source ratio can induce the coexistence of Ov/In2O3 and In2S3 in a high-temperature hydrothermal process. Under light irradiation, In2S3@Ov/In2O3-0.1 nanosheets hold a remarkable average H2 evolution rate up to 4.04 mmol g&#8211;1 h&#8211;1, which is 32.14, 11.91, and 2.25-fold better than those of pristine In2S3, In2S3@Ov/In2O3-0.02, and In2S3@Ov/In2O3-0.25 nanosheets, respectively. The ultraviolet&#8211;visible (UV&#8211;vis) diffuse reflectance and photoluminescence (PL) spectra reveal that the formation of Ov/In2O3 in In2S3 optimizes the band-gap structure and accelerates the migration of the photogenerated charge carrier of In2S3@Ov/In2O3-x nanosheets, respectively. Both the enhancement of oxidation and reduction ability and photogenerated charge carrier separation ability are responsible for the remarkable improvement in photocatalytic H2 evolution performance. This work provides a new strategy to prepare a composite of metal sulfide and metal oxide through a one-step hydrothermal method.</description>
      <author>Changxue Dong, Qiuyan Chen, Xin Deng, Lan Jiang, Tianli Han, Yufeng Zhou, Jinwei Chen, Ruilin Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c00720</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous cobalt-nickel borides boost electrocatalytic ethanol oxidation coupled with energy-saving hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00277f</link>
      <description>Anqi Hong, Xiangbowen Du, Kun Qian, Fang Zheng, Dongli Yu, Jing Sui, Wei Tong, Renhong Li, Catalysis science &amp; technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399265708

                The thermodynamically more advantageous ethanol oxidation (EOR) can replace anodic oxygen evolution (OER) in electrolysis, offering a practical way to produce energy-efficient hydrogen and simultaneously upgrade biomass. Here, we design...</description>
      <author>Anqi Hong, Xiangbowen Du, Kun Qian, Fang Zheng, Dongli Yu, Jing Sui, Wei Tong, Renhong Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00277f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Advances in Non-Precious Metal-Based Electrodes for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-2</link>
      <description>Jiakai Bai, Pengxi Li, Dongwei Qiao, Xianming Yuan, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301694

                Owing to the proportional growing demand for clean and affordable energy, the production of hydrogen via electrolysis of water has seen significant advancements. This review summarizes recent progresses achieved in the area of non-precious metal-based electrodes that are being utilized for the electrochemical hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) in alkaline water electrolysis. Based on the HER and OER mechanisms, common strategies to improve the electrocatalytic performance are proposed.2.1 Introduction</description>
      <author>Jiakai Bai, Pengxi Li, Dongwei Qiao, Xianming Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the potential of a g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 ternary heterojunction photocatalyst for rechargeable zinc-air battery: Visible-light-driven photo-assisted charging for bifunctional ORR and OER at the air cathode</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234795</link>
      <description>Amornrat Khampuanbut, Soorathep Kheawhom, Wathanyu Kao&#8208;ian, Wanwisa Limphirat, Hiroshi Uyama, Prasit Pattananuwat, Journal of power sources. 612(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399316435

                Advancements in solar-driven energy storage technology have been achieved for rechargeable zinc-air batteries (RZABs), facilitating accelerated kinetic responses in both the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER). In this study, we successfully synthesized a novel g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 ternary heterojunction through a facile hydrothermal process, demonstrating its efficacy as a bifunctional photocatalyst. Upon exposure to LED irradiation, this heterojunction triggers an effective separation of the photogenerated electron-hole pairs, resulting in enhanced oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance by 46.19 % and 65.69 % respectively, compared to non-LED conditions. Interestingly, the reduction in the potential gap under LED irradiation (0.06 V), correlating with a significant 2.71 % increase in round-trip efficiency (RTE), is observed. In addition, the optimized band alignment derived from g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 ternary heterojunction for photo-assisted charging rechargeable zinc-air batteries is proposed. Insightfully, photo-enhanced charging in RZABs mechanism during the charge/discharge process through in-situ X-ray absorption spectroscopy (XAS) is monitored, confirming the large interaction between O2 adsorption and Bi 6d orbitals of g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 in the presence of LED. In conclusion, our innovative g-C3N4/BiOBr/Bi2O2CO3 ternary heterojunction underscores the significant role that visible-light-driven photocatalysts can play in enhancing the efficiency of rechargeable zinc-air batteries.</description>
      <author>Amornrat Khampuanbut, Soorathep Kheawhom, Wathanyu Kao&#8208;ian, Wanwisa Limphirat, Hiroshi Uyama, Prasit Pattananuwat</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jpowsour.2024.234795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Device Architecture Strategies for Decoupled Water Splitting: A Review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00745</link>
      <description>Asha Mathur, Charles E. Diesendruck, ACS materials letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399281979

                Electrochemical water-splitting processes are a safe, sustainable, and ecofriendly method to generate pure hydrogen, with minimal carbon emission. Typically, water reduction (hydrogen evolution) and oxidation (oxygen evolution) occur simultaneously, although such coupled processes lead to several limitations such as gas crossover, electrocatalyst degradation by reactive oxygen species, and more. This review presents several strategies to design decoupled water splitting devices, separating the two half-reactions spatially and temporally, to address several of these issues. The designs change according to the electrode materials, electrolyte, and decoupling strategy employed (redox mediator). The review describes how the decoupling mechanisms adopted affect different properties and lead to designs with optimal efficiency. It also focuses on their integration with renewable energy, which can be used to power each half-reaction independently. Lastly, the merits and constraints of the decoupled systems in addressing global environmental issues are discussed along with potential questions to further advance this technology-based strategy.</description>
      <author>Asha Mathur, Charles E. Diesendruck</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsmaterialslett.4c00745</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic Pore Structure and Active Site Modulation in Co&#8211;N&#8211;C Catalysts Enabling Stable Zinc&#8211;Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01761</link>
      <description>Xin Li, Xiaowei Lv, Panpan Sun, Xiaohua Sun, ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399238599

                Development of cheap, highly active, and durable nonprecious metal-based oxygen electrocatalysts is essential for metal-air battery technology, but achieving the balance of oxygen evolution reaction (OER)/oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) bifunctional performance and long-term durability is still a great challenge. Using a typical Co-N-C catalyst as a model, herein, we introduced ammonium chloride into nitrogen-doped carbon materials containing metal elements during the pyrolysis process (Co-N-C/AC), which not only increases the active area but also realizes the accurate customization of the active site (pyridine nitrogen and cobalt oxide species) so as to achieve the balance of the OER/ORR bifunctional sites. The synthesized Co-N-C/AC bifunctional catalyst with a three-dimensional porous structure exhibits a smaller potential gap of 0.72 V. The peak power density of the aqueous cell at a current density of 308 mA cm</description>
      <author>Xin Li, Xiaowei Lv, Panpan Sun, Xiaohua Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c01761</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biochar Made from Luffa Cylindrica and Applied as Bifunctional Electrocatalyst in Zn-Air Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853912</link>
      <description>Natalia Tsoukala, Antonios N. Papadopoulos, Vasiliki Premeti, Alexandros K. Bikogiannakis, Eftychia Martino, Eleana Kordouli, &#922;aterina Govatsi, Ioannis D. Manariotis, Georgios Kyriakou, Dionissios Mantzavinos, Panagiotis Lianos, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399343780

                Biochar has been prepared by pyrolysis of Luffa Cylindrica (the vegetable sponge produced by Luffa Aegiptiaca) and activated by mixing with KOH and a second pyrolysis step. Non-activated and activated biochar have both been structurally and then electrochemically characterized to record their differences and assess their suitability as bifunctional oxygen reduction and oxygen evolution reaction electrocatalysts in Zn-air batteries. Non activated biochar carries several functional groups; however, the activation procedure led to a material with mainly O and Mg groups. Biochar activation improved its electrocatalytic properties, but both activated and non-activated luffa biochar were functional as bifunctional electrocatalysts to a satisfactory degree. This is justified by the fact that both carried a large percentage of carbon and graphitic carbon. The advantage of the non-activated biochar versus the activated biochar was its variety of functional groups while that of the activated biochar was its large specific surface area.</description>
      <author>Natalia Tsoukala, Antonios N. Papadopoulos, Vasiliki Premeti, Alexandros K. Bikogiannakis, Eftychia Martino, Eleana Kordouli, &#922;aterina Govatsi, Ioannis D. Manariotis, Georgios Kyriakou, Dionissios Mantzavinos, Panagiotis Lianos</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853912</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CuNi Aerogels with Suppressed Water Activation for Efficient Nucleophilic Methanol Electrooxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01596</link>
      <description>Qie Fang, S. Ye, Lirong Zheng, Hengjia Wang, Lili Hu, Wenling Gu, Lijin Wang, Le Shi, Chengzhou Zhu, ACS catalysis. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301299

                Suppressing the competitive oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the critical prerequisite for efficient nucleophile oxidation in electrochemical biomass upgrading coupled with hydrogen production. Herein, Cu91Ni9 aerogels with atomically dispersed Ni are designed as effective nucleophile electrooxidation catalysts with significantly suppressed water activation performance, exhibiting a remarkable 99.3% Faradaic efficiency in the conversion of methanol to formic acid. Experimental and theoretical investigations reveal that the Cu support promotes the formation of Ni&#8211;O&#8211;Cu active pockets, where Ni3+ behaves as the main adsorbed sites and electrophilic lattice oxygen in Ni&#8211;O&#8211;Cu serves as a hydrogen acceptor, thus accelerating the electrochemical catalyst dehydrogenation reaction and the spontaneous nucleophilic dehydrogenation reaction. Furthermore, Cu integration exhibits weaker OER competition by inactivating the deprotonation capacity of OH* to O*, promoting the Faradaic efficiency of formic acid. This work paves the way for the development of advanced catalysts to achieve highly efficient biomass upgrading by modulating the OER activity.</description>
      <author>Qie Fang, S. Ye, Lirong Zheng, Hengjia Wang, Lili Hu, Wenling Gu, Lijin Wang, Le Shi, Chengzhou Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acscatal.4c01596</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modulation in work function of CoTe as bifunctional electrocatalyst for rechargeable zinc air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.232</link>
      <description>Tiantian Xiong, Xianwei Li, Zeyu Ma, Kaiyi Liu, Yalong Li, Chen Li, Fang Luo, Zehui Yang, Journal of colloid and interface science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399258693

                The sluggish kinetics and inferior stability of oxygen electrocatalyst in rechargeable zinc air battery (ZAB) hamper its industrialization. In this work, we activate cobalt telluride (CoTe) by introduction of metallic cobalt (Co) to modulate the work function to facilitate the electron transfer from Co to CoTe during oxygen catalysis; additionally, the three-dimensional porous carbon nanosheets (3DPC) are invited to reduce the resistance towards electrolyte/oxygen diffusion. Thereby, Co-CoTe@3DPC only demands 280 mV overpotential to reach 10 mA cm&#8722;2 under alkaline oxygen evolution reaction (OER) condition, relatively lower than commercial iridium oxides (IrO2); besides the operando electrochemical impedance spectroscopy (EIS) indicates a better resistance towards surface reconstruction than Co@3DPC leading to a superior stability. A Pt-like oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) performance, half-wave potential associated with kinetic current density, is achieved for Co-CoTe@3DPC. A maximum power density of 203 mW cm&#8722;2 is achieved and sustains for 800 h. Furthermore, the all-solid-state ZAB offers 97 mW cm&#8722;2. Theoretical calculation suggests that the incorporation of metallic Co to CoTe maintains the superb ORR activity and promotes the OER catalysis.</description>
      <author>Tiantian Xiong, Xianwei Li, Zeyu Ma, Kaiyi Liu, Yalong Li, Chen Li, Fang Luo, Zehui Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.05.232</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanostructured Mnmoo4 as a Trifunctional Electrocatalyst for Overall Water Splitting and Co2 Reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853666</link>
      <description>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399337243

                Electrochemical water splitting and CO2 reduction are important processes to produce hydrogen and low&#8211;carbon fuels as renewable energy sources. Here, nanostructured MnMoO4, prepared by the reflux precipitation method, was investigated as a trifunctional electrocatalyst for overall water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions. Using a combination of diffuse reflectance spectroscopy and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy results, a direct band gap of 3.05 eV was obtained experimentally for the prepared MnMoO4. An overpotential of 0.36 V at a current density of 5 mA cm-2 and a Tafel slope of 58 mV dec-1 were obtained for the oxygen evolution reaction. At a current density of 3 mA cm-2, overpotentials of 0.39 V and 0.58 V were achieved in the absence and presence of CO2 bubbling into a 0.1 M KOH solution, respectively, emphasizing the poisoning effect of CO2 reduction intermediates for the hydrogen evolution reaction. Based on the obtained results, MnMoO4 could be a promising electrocatalyst for water splitting and CO2 reduction reactions.</description>
      <author>Neda Sadat Barekati, Eshagh Irandoost, Hossein Farsi, Elahe Dana, Safiye Kolangikhah, Shokufeh Moghiminia, Alireza Farrokhi</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853666</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Addressing the Challenge of Electrochemical Ionomer Oxidation in Future Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolyzers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00832</link>
      <description>Jihoon Lim, Jeffrey M. Klein, Seung Geol Lee, Eun Joo Park, Sun Young Kang, Sandip Maurya, William E. Mustain, Shannon W. Boettcher, Yu Seung Kim, ACS energy letters. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399299301

                Hydrogen production through anion-exchange membrane water electrolyzers (AEMWEs) offers cost advantages over proton-exchange membrane counterparts, mainly due to the good oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity of platinum-group-metal-free catalysts in alkaline environments. However, the electrochemical oxidation of ionomers at the OER catalyst interface can decrease the local electrode pH, which limits AEMWE performance. Various strategies at the single-cell-level have been explored to address this issue. This work reviews the current understanding of electrochemical ionomer oxidation and strategies to mitigate it, providing our perspective on each approach. Our analysis highlights the competitive adsorption strategy as particularly promising for mitigating ionomer oxidation. This Perspective also outlines future directions for advancing high-performance alkaline AEMWEs and other energy devices using hydrocarbon ionomers.</description>
      <author>Jihoon Lim, Jeffrey M. Klein, Seung Geol Lee, Eun Joo Park, Sun Young Kang, Sandip Maurya, William E. Mustain, Shannon W. Boettcher, Yu Seung Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsenergylett.4c00832</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring tin sulfide electrocatalyst with petroleum coke derived reduced graphene oxide for overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100689</link>
      <description>Chandan Kumar&#8208;Sinha, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Pinky Saharan, Ashish Gupta, J.B. Singh, Mandeep Singh, Sanjay R. Dhakate, FlatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399208222

                Metal chalcogenides like Tin sulfide (SnS2) presents as viable alternative electrocatalysts for alkaline water splitting (AWS) due to their huge abundance, stability, and environment friendly nature. However, insufficient exposed active sites and poor conductivity severely impede its large-scale applications. In this work, an in-situ hybridization of hexagonal SnS2 with intercalation of reduced graphene oxide nanosheets (TS-rGOx) overcomes the problem of SnS2 stacking. It further enhances the interlayer spacing thereby boosting the number of active sites. The resulting TS-rGOx exhibited excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) activities demanding low overpotential of 313 mV and 196.2 mV at 20 mA/cm2 with long term durability upto 60 h, which can be attributed to enhanced interlayer spacing of SnS2, abundant active sites and higher conductivity resulting from the in-situ hybridization and intercalation of rGO nanosheets. This work opens a prospect towards the design and application of efficient SnS2 based heterostructured electrocatalyst for AWS.</description>
      <author>Chandan Kumar&#8208;Sinha, Thangjam Ibomcha Singh, Pinky Saharan, Ashish Gupta, J.B. Singh, Mandeep Singh, Sanjay R. Dhakate</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.flatc.2024.100689</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexible bifunctional electrocatalyst (Ni@(Ni,Fe)Se2/Ni@CC) by adjusting d-band center for high-efficiency HER and overall water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphma.2024.05.003</link>
      <description>Wenbo Liao, Baojie Zhang, Lan Mu, Ning Zhao, Gang Zhao, Junjie Huang, Xijin Xu, ChemPhysMater. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399206547

                Nickel foam is widely used as a collector for electrocatalysts because of its excellent electrical conductivity; however, it is prone to react with elements such as oxygen, sulfur, and phosphorus during the growth of electrode materials, which makes it brittle and fragile, thus limiting its large-scale application. In this study, bifunctional electrocatalysts with flexible multilevel Ni-based nanoclusters Ni@(Ni,Fe)Se2/Ni@CC were synthesized on carbon cloth(CC) by hydrothermal and electrodeposition methods; these flexible electrocatalysts are convenient for subsequent industrial applications. At a current density of 10 mA cm&#8722;2, the overpotentials of the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and oxygen evolution reaction (OER) reached 98 and 224 mV, respectively, exceeding the catalytic effects of most metal-based collectors. The overall water-splitting potential of the catalyst was only 1.56 V at 10 mA cm&#8722;2, and the performance was maintained after a 24 h stability test. Ni@(Ni,Fe)Se2/Ni@CC significantly improved the activity in alkaline environments by modulating the center of the d-band, thereby increasing the adsorption capacity of the catalyst for H ions. In this study, we improved the intrinsic activity and charge transfer of transition metal electrocatalysts by modifying the carbon cloth and constructing multilevel Ni-based nanoclusters, which provided some insights into the rational design of flexible bifunctional electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Wenbo Liao, Baojie Zhang, Lan Mu, Ning Zhao, Gang Zhao, Junjie Huang, Xijin Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chphma.2024.05.003</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waxberry-Like Hydrophilic Co-Doped Znfe2o4 as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Water Splittingwaxberry-Like Hydrophilic Co-Doped Znfe2o4 as Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853910</link>
      <description>Xiao Lyu, Yongbin Hu, Yun Han, Xuning Li, Yu Q, Bin Wen, Xin Zhao, Qi Dong, Aijun Du, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399347211

                The development of bifunctional electrocatalysts is challenging but desirable for the scale-up applications of water splitting. Nowadays transition metal oxides (TMOs) are considered as the promising electrocatalysts due to their low cost, structural flexibility and stability, however, their electrocatalytic activities are eager to be improved. Here, we synthesized waxberry-like hydrophilic Co-doped ZnFe2O4 electrocatalysts as bifunctional electrocatalysts for water splitting. Due to the enhanced active sites by morphology regulation and metallic doping strategy, the spinel ZFO-Co0.5 electrocatalyst exhibits excellent catalytic activities both on oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). It exhibits a remarkable low OER overpotential of 220 mV and a Tafel slope of 28.2 mV dec-1, surpassing the performance of commercial IrO2 electrocatalyst. Meanwhile, it achieves a low overpotential of 73 mV with the Tafel slope of 87 mV dec -1 for HER. In addition, water-splitting performance of ZFO-Co0.5||ZFO-Co0.5 surpasses that of commercial IrO2||Pt/C. Our work reveals that the hydrophilic morphology regulation combined with metallic doping strategy is a facile and effective approach to synthesize spinel TMOs as excellent bifunctional electrocatalyst for water splitting.</description>
      <author>Xiao Lyu, Yongbin Hu, Yun Han, Xuning Li, Yu Q, Bin Wen, Xin Zhao, Qi Dong, Aijun Du</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4853910</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facile fabrication of SnO2/MnTe nanocomposite as an efficient electrocatalyst for OER in basic media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175036</link>
      <description>Rabab Zahra, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, B.M. Alotaibi, Haifa A. Alyousef, Nuha Al-Harbi, A. Dahshan, Khursheed Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Journal of alloys and compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399209327

                There is a strong demand for developing an extremely effective and robust electrocatalyst to facilitate oxygen evolution reaction in water electrolysis applications. Herein, we successfully produced SnO2/MnTe using an efficient ultrasonication technique that is cost-effective and readily accessible along with improved catalytic behavior. The physical properties of fabricated catalysts are examined to analyze textural, structural and morphological characteristics. The SnO2/MnTe nanocomposite exhibited the low overpotential (181 mV) at 10 mA cm-2 and smaller Tafel slope of 33 mV dec-1 in alkaline (1.0 M KOH) medium. Moreover, the material also showed prolonged and excellent stability over 50 h following 5000 stability cycles. Electrochemical impedance spectroscopy studies demonstrated that charge transfer kinetics at the catalyst-electrolyte interface could be achievable, with lower Rct values (0.8&#937;) directing it to increase electrochemical behavior. The acquired outcomes obtained from electrochemical activity demonstrate the potential of SnO2/MnTe as a highly promising electrocatalyst for future electrochemical energy generation.</description>
      <author>Rabab Zahra, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, B.M. Alotaibi, Haifa A. Alyousef, Nuha Al-Harbi, A. Dahshan, Khursheed Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175036</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free-Standing Electrodes and Catalysts for Alkaline Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-3</link>
      <description>Miao He, Fuyue Liu, CRC Press eBooks. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301864

                Free-standing electrocatalysts (FSECs) are a series of electrochemically active materials grown directly on a substrate with remarkable conductivity, sufficient porous structure, and high specific surface areas. The catalytic properties of FSECs toward both hydrogen and oxygen evolution reactions (HER/OER) for alkaline water electrolysis mainly depend on the substrates, active materials, and synthesis methods of FSECs. In this chapter, we first introduce the concepts, advantages, and relative mechanisms of FSECs. Then, the merits and applications of different substrates (such as the nickel foam and carbon fiber paper carbon cloth) for FSECs are summarized and introduced. Importantly, we reviewed the various active materials of FSECs for both HER and OER, including metals or alloys, transitional metal oxides, transitional metal sulfides, transition metal selenides, transition metal phosphides, transition metal carbides and nitrides, transition metal hydroxides/oxyhydroxides, and indicated their advantages and shortcomings. Lastly, some typical synthesis methods of FSECs are summarized and reviewed. This chapter can shed the light on the development of high-performance FSECs.</description>
      <author>Miao He, Fuyue Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1201/9781003368939-3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-step Fabrication of P-Co5.47N/Co9S8@NPC Heterojunction Derived from Saccharomycetes Cerevisiae as Environment-Friendly Bifunctional High-efficiency Electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134411</link>
      <description>Xinli Jing, Changwu Lv, Hongmei Zhang, Chu Chen, Zhaofeng Wu, Colloids and surfaces. A, Physicochemical and engineering aspects. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399303052

                The one-step green preparation of heterojunction-structured bifunctional high-efficiency electrocatalysts provides a simple method for the green, low-cost, convenient and efficient application of hydrogen energy, meanwhile it is still challenging to achieve. In the present work, the phosphorus-doped two-phase heterojunction P-Co5.47N/Co9S8@NPC nanorods was synthesized on carbon cloth (CC) as a high-quality bifunctional electrode through simple one-step chemical vapor deposition (CVD) method. Saccharomycetes cerevisiae were used for the non-toxic phosphorus doping and formation of a carbon nanolayer wrapping Co5.47N/Co9S8 nanorods. Compared with the single-phase electrocatalyst Co9S8@NPC NSs/CC, P-Co5.47N/Co9S8@NPC NSs/CC exhibited more excellent electrocatalytic performance which required overpotentials of 69 mV for hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), 182.5 mV for oxygen evolution reaction (OER), 1.45 V for over water splitting (OWS) at 10 mA cm-2 in KOH solution. The designed P-Co5.47N/Co9S8@NPC NSs/CC presented multiple advantages of nanorod structure, doped structure, abundant heterointerfaces, as well as dual-phase synergy, which triggered outstanding electrocatalytic performance.</description>
      <author>Xinli Jing, Changwu Lv, Hongmei Zhang, Chu Chen, Zhaofeng Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134411</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A dual spin-controlled chiral two-/three-dimensional perovskite artificial leaf for efficient overall photoelectrochemical water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49216-x</link>
      <description>Hyungsoo Lee, Chan Uk Lee, Juwon Yun, Chang-Seop Jeong, Wooyong Jeong, Jaehyun Son, Young Sun Park, Subin Moon, Soobin Lee, Junhwan Kim, Jooho Moon, Nature communications. 15(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399263634

                The oxygen evolution reaction, which involves high overpotential and slow charge-transport kinetics, plays a critical role in determining the efficiency of solar-driven water splitting. The chiral-induced spin selectivity phenomenon has been utilized to reduce by-product production and hinder charge recombination. To fully exploit the spin polarization effect, we herein propose a dual spin-controlled perovskite photoelectrode. The three-dimensional (3D) perovskite serves as a light absorber while the two-dimensional (2D) chiral perovskite functions as a spin polarizer to align the spin states of charge carriers. Compared to other investigated chiral organic cations, R-/S-naphthyl ethylamine enable strong spin-orbital coupling due to strengthened &#960;-&#960; stacking interactions. The resulting naphthyl ethylamine-based chiral 2D/3D perovskite photoelectrodes achieved a high spin polarizability of 75%. Moreover, spin relaxation was prevented by employing a chiral spin-selective L-NiFeOOH catalyst, which enables the secondary spin alignment to promote the generation of triplet oxygen. This dual spin-controlled 2D/3D perovskite photoanode achieves a 13.17% of applied-bias photon-to-current efficiency. Here, after connecting the perovskite photocathode with L-NiFeOOH/S-naphthyl ethylamine 2D/3D photoanode in series, the resulting co-planar water-splitting device exhibited a solar-to-hydrogen efficiency of 12.55%.</description>
      <author>Hyungsoo Lee, Chan Uk Lee, Juwon Yun, Chang-Seop Jeong, Wooyong Jeong, Jaehyun Son, Young Sun Park, Subin Moon, Soobin Lee, Junhwan Kim, Jooho Moon</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-49216-x</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sulfur doped Zinc Oxide-Nikel Oxide as Efficient Bifunctional Electrocatalyst for overall Water splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4441679/v1</link>
      <description>Saeed Farahany, Salma Aslam Arain, Yong Wang, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399216497

                Abstract A mixed Sulfur-doped zinc oxide-nickel oxide nanocomposite electrocatalyst for oxygen evolution reaction (OER) was prepared. By hydrothermal method, we prepared a high-efficiency OER electrocatalyst doped with zinc oxide and nickel oxide. By applying different characterizations, the material was proven to be a new phase of (S-doped-ZnO-NiO). S-doped ZnO-NiO, ZnO-NiO did not show excellent performance. At 10 mA cm&#8722; 2, the generation potential of OER is 1.45 V and that of HER is -0.04 V. This unique morphology results in better OER performance of 240 mV at 10 mA cm&#8722; 2 in the KOH electrolyte, and similarly, the S-doped ZnO-NiO shows us excellent long-term stability in alkaline media with a small Tafel slope (77 mV dec&#8722; 1). S-doped ZnO-NiO hybrid catalysts offer great potential for electrochemical devices due to their low cost and high activity. we have successfully constructed an electrocatalyst with the dual functions of HER and OER, which can achieve efficient water splitting.</description>
      <author>Saeed Farahany, Salma Aslam Arain, Yong Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4441679/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advancements in water splitting for sustainable energy generation: A review</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.24294/can.v7i1.5834</link>
      <description>Razu Shahazi, Amirul Islam Saddam, S.K. Majumdar, Md. Rakibul Islam, Mohammed M. Rahman, M. M. Alam, Ajoy Kumer, Giti Paimard, Characterization and application of nanomaterials. 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399244269

                Water splitting, the process of converting water into hydrogen and oxygen gases, has garnered significant attention as a promising avenue for sustainable energy production. One area of focus has been the development of efficient and cost-effective catalysts for water splitting. Researchers have explored catalysts based on abundant and inexpensive materials such as nickel, iron, and cobalt, which have demonstrated improved performance and stability. These catalysts show promise for large-scale implementation and offer potential for reducing the reliance on expensive and scarce materials. Another avenue of research involves photoelectrochemical (PEC) cells, which utilize solar energy to drive the water-splitting reaction. Scientists have been working on designing novel materials, including metal oxides and semiconductors, to enhance light absorption and charge separation properties. These advancements in PEC technology aim to maximize the conversion of sunlight into chemical energy. Inspired by natural photosynthesis, artificial photosynthesis approaches have also gained traction. By integrating light-absorbing materials, catalysts, and membranes, these systems aim to mimic the complex processes of natural photosynthesis and produce hydrogen fuel from water. The development of efficient and stable artificial photosynthesis systems holds promise for sustainable and clean energy production. Tandem cells, which combine multiple light-absorbing materials with different bandgaps, have emerged as a strategy to enhance the efficiency of water-splitting systems. By capturing a broader range of the solar spectrum, tandem cells optimize light absorption and improve overall system performance. Lastly, advancements in electrocatalysis have played a critical role in water splitting. Researchers have focused on developing advanced electrocatalysts with high activity, selectivity, and stability for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and hydrogen evolution reaction (HER). These electrocatalysts contribute to overall water-splitting efficiency and pave the way for practical implementation.</description>
      <author>Razu Shahazi, Amirul Islam Saddam, S.K. Majumdar, Md. Rakibul Islam, Mohammed M. Rahman, M. M. Alam, Ajoy Kumer, Giti Paimard</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.24294/can.v7i1.5834</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CNT/Nafion functionalized Ti/SnO2-Sb/&#946;-PbO2-CNT/Nafion composite electrode toward highly active and robust degradation of octadecylamine and 4-dodecylmorpholine in real high-salinity system</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152716</link>
      <description>Miao Liu, Siyuan Zhang, Li Ma, Zhenlun Song, Xiushen Ye, Huifang Zhang, Haining Liu, Ying Wang, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399207089

                The efficient removal of recalcitrant organics in high-salinity systems, specifically brine, poses a significant challenge for electrochemically advanced oxidation processes in terms of both activity and stability. Herein, a composite electrode comprising of CNT/Nafion functionalized Ti/SnO2-Sb/&#946;-PbO2-CNT/Nafion was developed for efficient and stable removal of octadecylamine (ODA) and 4-dodecylmorpholine (DMP) in a real high-salinity environment. The degradation efficiencies of ODA and DMP on the composite electrode can reach 100 % within 60 min, respectively. The total organic carbon (TOC) removal efficiency of ODA and DMP was significantly improved to 78 % and 66 % with remarkably low energy consumption (0.414 and 1.402 kWh/g TOC), respectively. The electrochemical characterizations demonstrate that the composite electrode exhibits improved electrochemical activity (oxygen evolution potentials = 1.791 V) and electrode surface area (ECSA = 20 cm2), while maintaining reduced charge transfer resistance (Rct = 18.21 &#937;/cm2) and enhanced corrosion-resistant capacity (corrosion potential = 1.115 V). Based on recycling and accelerated lifespan testing, the composite electrode demonstrates exceptional stability and recyclability. Additionally revealed was the linked stability mechanism. The electrocatalytic degradation of ODA and DMP begins with the removal of amino and morpholine rings, and then the decomposition of the carbon chains. Gas chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC&#8211;MS) and theoretical calculations were used to identify intermediate products generated during the degradation of ODA and DMP, and possible degradation pathways were provided in high-salinity systems, respectively. This work offered a fresh perspective on electrocatalytic oxidation for a real high-salinity system that is more efficient and stable.</description>
      <author>Miao Liu, Siyuan Zhang, Li Ma, Zhenlun Song, Xiushen Ye, Huifang Zhang, Haining Liu, Ying Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152716</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chloride&#8208; and Hydrosulfide&#8208;Bound 2Fe Complexes as Models of the Oxygen&#8208;Stable State of [FeFe] Hydrogenase</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408142</link>
      <description>Ming-Hsi Chiang, Yu&#8208;Chiao Liu, Kai&#8208;Ti Chu, Hongru Wang, Gene&#8208;Hsiang Lee, Mei&#8208;Chun Tseng, C.C. Wang, Yih&#8208;Chern Horng, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399240729

                [FeFe] hydrogenases demonstrate remarkable catalytic efficiency in hydrogen evolution and oxidation processes. However, susceptibility of enzymes to oxygen&#8208;induced degradation impedes their practical deployment in hydrogen&#8208;production devices and fuel cells. Recent investigations into the oxygen&#8208;stable (Hinact) state of the H&#8208;cluster revealed its inherent capacity to resist oxygen degradation. Herein, we present findings on Cl&#8208;/SH&#8208;bound [2Fe&#8208;2S] complexes, bearing relevance to the oxygen&#8208;stable state within a biological context. A characteristic attribute of these complexes is the terminal Cl&#8722;/SH&#8722; ligation to the iron bearing the CO bridge. Structural analysis of the t&#8208;Cl demonstrates a striking resemblance to the Hinact state of DdHydAB and CbA5H. The t&#8208;Cl/t&#8208;SH exhibit reversible oxidation, with both redox species, electronically, being the first biomimetic analogs to the Htrans and Hinact states. These complexes exhibit notable resistance against oxygen&#8208;induced decomposition, supporting the potential oxygen&#8208;resistant nature of the Htrans and Hinact states. The swift reductive release of the Cl&#8208;/SH&#8208; demonstrates its labile and kinetically controlled binding. The findings garnered from these investigations offer valuable insights into properties of the enzymatic O2&#8208;stable state, and key factors governing deactivation and reactivation conversion. This work contributes to advancement of bio&#8208;inspired molecular catalysts and integration of enzymes and artificial catalysts into H2&#8208;evolution devices and fuel&#8208;cell applications.</description>
      <author>Ming-Hsi Chiang, Yu&#8208;Chiao Liu, Kai&#8208;Ti Chu, Hongru Wang, Gene&#8208;Hsiang Lee, Mei&#8208;Chun Tseng, C.C. Wang, Yih&#8208;Chern Horng</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202408142</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Lower Eyelid in Basal Cell Carcinoma Case with Adjunctive Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy: A Case Report</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.35790/msj.v7i1.54895</link>
      <description>Yulius A. M. Chietra, Mendy Hatibie, Ramli Dali, Medical Scope Journal (MSJ). 7(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399265467

                Abstract: Basal cell carcinomas (BCCs) are the most common cancers in humans, caused by exposure to ultraviolet light and are associated with PTCH1 gene mutation. Its incidence rate significantly increases per year especially in elderly people. Several modalities are available for BCC treatment but surgery is still considered as the gold standard. Oxygen is mandatory for almost all wound healing processes, and oxygen substitution can be delivered in the form of hyperbaric oxygen (HBO) therapy. We presented a 70 years old woman with a major complaint of a tumor located in the left infrapalpebral region, below the left lower lash line with 5 years of evolution. Patient had clinical presentation of solid nodular basal cell carcinoma which was the most common clinical subtype. Patient was diagnosed as having BCC based on history taking, clinical findings, and histopathological examination. Surgical wide excision, skin flap, and HBO as the adjunctive therapy were performed on this patient. With these techniques, healing time was reduced, complications rates were low, and cosmetic outcome was much better. In conclusion, closing defects of BCC case with surgical wide excision and flap yields a remarkable outcome and an adjunctive HBO therapy after surgery optimizes the oxygenation, thus, the healing potential of tissue prior to surgery, and accelerates wound healing post operatively. A good result with short healing duration was observed. Keywords: basal cell carcinoma; hyperbaric oxygen therapy; flap; wound healing</description>
      <author>Yulius A. M. Chietra, Mendy Hatibie, Ramli Dali</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.35790/msj.v7i1.54895</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Role of Oxygen Vacancies in Phase Transition and the Optical Absorption Properties within Nanocrystalline ZrO2</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110967</link>
      <description>Jing Ouyang, Youming Peng, Wenting Zhou, Xianfeng Liang, G. Wang, Zeming Qi, Bo Yuan, Nanomaterials. 14(11)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399304013

                Zirconia (ZrO2) nanoparticles were synthesized using a solvothermal method under varying synthesis conditions, namely acidic, neutral, and alkaline. X-ray diffraction (XRD) and field emission scanning electron microscopy (FESEM) were leveraged to investigate the phase evolution and topographical features in detail. The resulting crystal phase structures and grain sizes exhibited substantial variation based on these conditions. Notably, the acidic condition fostered a monoclinic phase in ZrO2, while the alkaline condition yielded a combination of tetragonal and monoclinic phases. In contrast, ZrO2 obtained under neutral conditions demonstrated a refinement in grain sizes, constrained within a 1 nm scale upon an 800 &#176;C thermal treatment. This was accompanied by an important transformation from a monoclinic phase to tetragonal phase in the ZrO2. Furthermore, a rigorous examination of XPS data and a UV-visible spectrometer (UV-vis) analysis revealed the significant role of oxygen vacancies in phase stabilization. The notable emergence of new energy bands in ZrO2, in stark contrast to the intrinsic bands observed in a pure monoclinic sample, are attributed to these oxygen vacancies. This research offers valuable insights into the novel energy bands, phase stability, and optical absorption properties influenced by oxygen vacancies in ZrO2. Moreover, it proposes an innovative energy level model for zirconia, underpinning its applicability in diverse technological areas.</description>
      <author>Jing Ouyang, Youming Peng, Wenting Zhou, Xianfeng Liang, G. Wang, Zeming Qi, Bo Yuan</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/nano14110967</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On the physiology of high-altitude flight and altitudinal migration in birds</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1093/icb/icae062</link>
      <description>Catherine M. Ivy, Jessie L. Williamson, Integrative and comparative biology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399322452

                Abstract Many bird species fly at high altitudes for short periods and/or shift seasonally in altitude during migration, but little is known about the physiology of these behaviors. Transient high-altitude flight, or short-term flight at extreme altitudes, is a strategy used by lowland-native birds, often in the absence of topographic barriers. Altitudinal migration, or seasonal roundtrip movement in altitude between the breeding and non-breeding seasons, is a form of migration that occurs as a regular part of the annual cycle and results in periods of seasonal residency at high altitudes. Despite their nuanced differences, these two behaviors share a common challenge: Exposure to reduced oxygen environments during at least part of the migratory journey. In this perspective piece, we compare what is known about the physiology of oxygen transport during transient high-altitude flight and altitudinal migration by highlighting case studies and recent conceptual advances from work on captive and wild birds. We aim to open avenues for integrative research on the ecology, evolution, and physiology of high-flying and mountain-climbing birds.</description>
      <author>Catherine M. Ivy, Jessie L. Williamson</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1093/icb/icae062</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elaborate construction of honeycomb-like porous carbon with embedment of N-doped carbon nanotubes as efficient electrocatalyst for zinc-air battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119299</link>
      <description>Ao Xie, Xuefeng Tai, Yujing Guo, Jinyuan Miao, D. Liu, Rufei Zhang, Linting Cheng, Zemin Zhao, Yang Tang, Xiaojin Yang, Junqing Pan, Pingyu Wan, Carbon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399202916

                Devising the synthesis strategy and uncovering the evolution mechanism of carbon-based materials are critical to the development of efficient oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) electrocatalysts for renewable energy storage systems. This study reports a hierarchical ORR electrocatalyst, Co@N-CNTs/3DHC, which features ultrafine cobalt nanoparticles embedded in nitrogen-doped carbon nanotubes (Co@N-CNTs) and Co@N-CNTs firmly anchored in the nano-chambers of a three-dimensional honeycomb-like porous carbon (3DHC). The synthesis strategy of Co@N-CNTs/3DHC involves the initial construction of a precursor, followed by controllable pyrolysis step. Based on detailed analysis of both evolved gases and carbonized products of precursors, the evolution mechanism of Co@N-CNTs/3DHC is specifically proposed. Prompted by the electron reconfiguration, extensive reaction interface and fast mass-transfer pathway, the as-synthesized hierarchical Co@N-CNTs/3DHC displays superior ORR activity in alkaline media (0.88 V of half-wave potential) compared to commercial Pt/C. Impressively, zinc-air battery equipped with Co@N-CNTs/3DHC cathode presents outstanding discharge voltage and exceptional stability. This work highlights a unique perspective on the synthesis strategy and growth mechanism of Co@N-CNTs@3DHC toward creation of hierarchical 3D carbon-based composite for advanced electrochemical energy devices.</description>
      <author>Ao Xie, Xuefeng Tai, Yujing Guo, Jinyuan Miao, D. Liu, Rufei Zhang, Linting Cheng, Zemin Zhao, Yang Tang, Xiaojin Yang, Junqing Pan, Pingyu Wan</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.carbon.2024.119299</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barcoding, structural, and genetic variation of morphologically adopted polychaetes (Annelida: Paronidae, Lumberineridae, Spionidae) using mitochondrial COI gene sequences from the Bay of Bengal shelf including Oxygen Minimum Zone</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsma.2024.103613</link>
      <description>Seerangan Manokaran, Chinnamani PrasannaKumar, Kapuli Gani Mohamed Thameemul Ansari, Thadickal V. Joydas, Karuppasamy P. Manikandan, K.M. Aarif, S. Raja, P. Ramasamy, T. Sudhagar, Regional studies in marine science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399206627

                The structural and genetic variation of morphologically adapted polychaetes from the Bay of Bengal continental shelf (North Indian Ocean) including Oxygen Minimum Zone (OMZ) are described. The density and biomass of polychaetes such as Aricidea curviseta (Paronidae), Lumberineris aberrans (Lumberineridae), Prionospio malmgreni, Paraprionospio pinnata, and Prinospio sexoculata (Spionidae) were significantly differed (P&lt;0.05) in depths (Non-Oxygen Minimum Zone - NOMZ and OMZ), transects and cruises. The response and morphometric measures of branchiae structures were inconsistent between OMZ and NOMZ depths. The species Aricidea curviseta (OR450003 - OR450005), Paraprionospio pinnata (OR436939, OR436941, OR436952 and OR436953), and Prionospio malmgreni (OR436956, OR436957, OR436945, OR436946, OR436947) were barcoded for the first time. The Maximum likelihood tree analysis indicated low ranges of similarity indices among the NOMZ (0.255 - 0.446%) and OMZ (0.257 - 0.443) depths. The total number of mutations and polymorphic sites were 395 and 268, with low haplotypes (12) and nucleotide diversity (among depths: 0.228 - 0.246, and regions: 0.826 - 0.100). The groups of haplotypes were also independent of the geographical locations. The AMOVA revealed that the variation among populations was low (regions: -5%, and depths: -1.86%) and within populations were high (regions:105.45% and depths: 101.86%, respectively). The nMDS indicated that the oxygen factor significantly separated the distribution of density and biomass of polychaetes within transects (density: biomass: F=3.57) and cruises (biomass: F=2.41, P&lt;0.05). Generally, 70-80% of the total variation was described in four pCCAs by salinity (PSU), pressure, Co, Cu, Fe, Mn, Ni, Pb, Zn, Hg (ppm), and clay (%) with NOMZ and OMZ depths, different cruises, transects and or the interaction between this three. OMZs might not influence the genetic variations. Several additional studies, such as physiological, metabolic, enzymatic, and biochemical, are also be essential for understanding the ecology and evolution of organisms in this habitat.</description>
      <author>Seerangan Manokaran, Chinnamani PrasannaKumar, Kapuli Gani Mohamed Thameemul Ansari, Thadickal V. Joydas, Karuppasamy P. Manikandan, K.M. Aarif, S. Raja, P. Ramasamy, T. Sudhagar</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.rsma.2024.103613</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>High-temperature Oxidation mechanism and microstructure evolution of Cr-Mn-Si alloyed steel oxidized by Fe2O3 contained in mold flux</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.438</link>
      <description>Fengkang Wang, Wanlin Wang, Jie Du, Gao Qing, Il Sohn, Jie Zeng, Ceramics international. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399242141

                The high-temperature oxidation behavior of Cr-Mn-Si alloyed steel by Fe2O3 contained mold flux in high temperatures, and its effect on microstructure evolution were investigated in detail by TEM, EBSD, CLSM, SEM, and XPS. A novel oxidation mechanism was firstly revealed that the Fe2O3 in mold flux melts during high temperatures plays a role of oxidizing alloyed steels by the released free oxygen ions (O2&#8722;) from the transformation of Fe2O3 (Fe3+) to FeO (Fe2+). The formed oxidized dots within the oxide layer changed from SiO2 and MnSiO3 to MnCr2O4 spinel phases by increasing the content of Fe2O3 in the mold flux. Notably, the amorphous SiO2 was discovered in the core region of MnSiO3 phase due to its selective oxidative behavior in high temperatures. This research provides conclusive evidence that the small size MnSiO3 oxides can be acted as a nucleation core for the refinement of austenite grains through in-situ observation.</description>
      <author>Fengkang Wang, Wanlin Wang, Jie Du, Gao Qing, Il Sohn, Jie Zeng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ceramint.2024.05.438</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zircon compositional systematics from Devonian oxidized I-type granitoids: examination of porphyry Cu fertility indices in the New Brunswick Appalachians, Canada</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/feart.2024.1363029</link>
      <description>Fazilat Yousefi, David R. Lentz, Christopher R.M. McFarlane, James A. Walker, Kathleen G. Thorne, Frontiers in earth science. 12(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301948

                Zircon is a common, widely distributed accessory mineral in most igneous rocks and its refractory nature records magmatic evolution in terms of oxygen and U-Th-Pb isotopes, and trace-element contents all of which reflect the intrinsic physio-chemical evolution of the magmatic systems in which it crystallized. Zircon compositions can be used as an indicator of relative fertility of hypabyssal intrusions in terms Cu &#177; Mo &#177; Au porphyry mineralization. To further characterize syn- to post-collisional adakitic Devonian oxidized I-type granitoids in the New Brunswick (specifically, those with Cu &#177; Mo &#177; Au porphyry-style mineralization), LA-ICP-MS analyses (guided by &#181;XRF-EDS mapping and SEM-BSE imaging of polished thin sections) of zircons from 13 granitoids was conducted. The zircons studied were similar in terms of their textures (homogenous cores, patchy zoning, oscillatory zoning, and some unzoned zircon); however, they have a wide range of trace- and minor-element (Hf, HREE, Y, Th, U) compositions. Specifically, Zr/Hf ranges between 24&#8211;60, whereas Th/U ranges between 0.15 and 5.37. The presence of inherited zircon affects the concentrations of Th and U, as well as other key elements. Estimated crystallization temperatures of granitoids, ranging from 737 to 899&#176;C, were calculated via Ti-in-zircon geothermometry assuming reduced TiO 2 and SiO 2 activities. The calculated log f O 2 values for zircons from some of these granitoids indicate a highly oxidized magmatic signature. Zr/Hf, Eu/Eu &#8270; , and (Eu/Eu &#8270; )/Y in zircon, as well as zircon (Ce/Nd)/Y are some of the best indicators of porphyry fertility. The Ce/Ce * in zircon exhibit a large range (1.1&#8211;590), with higher Ce/Ce * reflecting more metallogenically favourable oxidizing conditions. If Eu/Eu &#8270; in zircon is &#8805;0.4 (relatively oxidized conditions), it indicates a high potential for an ore-forming porphyry Cu mineralizing system. Lower Eu contents reflect relatively reducing conditions, as Eu anomalies vary with oxygen fugacity as well, and the relative abundance of Eu 2+ is higher, but does not substitute into the zircon lattice. The evidence extracted from analyzing the zircon composition within New Brunswick&#8217;s I-type granitoids indicates the fertility of these hypabyssal intrusions.</description>
      <author>Fazilat Yousefi, David R. Lentz, Christopher R.M. McFarlane, James A. Walker, Kathleen G. Thorne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/feart.2024.1363029</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cu doping in TM ordered and disordered layered oxides for Sodium-Ion Batteries: Electrochemical Properties, structure evolution and Cu-Ion migration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152788</link>
      <description>Jun Yan, Yin-Hui Peng, Yunbo Li, Hongyan Zhou, Jingjie Feng, Qinghua Fan, Quan Kuang, Youzhong Dong, Xiao&#8208;Bao Yang, Yanming Zhao, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399302942

                The ordered/disordered distribution of transition metal (TM) plays a significant role in determining electrochemical properties including lattice oxygen redox, ion kinetics and structure evolution. From a novel perspective, this work demonstrates how the TM distributions influence the doping effect by means of introducing Cu element into ordered/disordered O3-Nax(NiySb1-y)O2. What's more, the irreversible Cu migration from TM sites to Na layers upon electrochemical process is found. This migration which would deteriorate electrochemical stability only occurs in honeycomb-ordered compounds, instead of in disordered one. Theoretical calculations reveal that the TM disordered distribution promotes the formation of antibonding orbitals between Cu 3d and O 2p, thereby increasing the barrier of Cu migration to maintain well Na diffusion kinetics. Our discovery rolls out a new guidance for designing advanced cathode materials for sodium-ion batteries and speeds up the research on transition metal migration.</description>
      <author>Jun Yan, Yin-Hui Peng, Yunbo Li, Hongyan Zhou, Jingjie Feng, Qinghua Fan, Quan Kuang, Youzhong Dong, Xiao&#8208;Bao Yang, Yanming Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152788</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directional Growth and Density Modulation of Single&#8208;Atom Platinum for Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406650</link>
      <description>Xinyang Liu, Yuxuan Zhou, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Zhijun Wang, Liangyong Jia, Mengyuan Li, K&#232; Yang, Jinchen Fan, Weiwei Yang, Guisheng Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399240926

                Dispersion of single atoms (SAs) in the host is important for optimizing catalytic activity. Herein, we propose a novel strategy to tune oxygen vacancies in CeO2&#8208;X directionally anchoring the single atom platinum (PtSA), which is uniformly dispersed on the rGO. The catalyst's performance for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) can be enhanced by controlling different densities of CeO2&#8208;X in rGO. The PtSA performs best optimally densified and loaded on homogeneous and moderately densified CeO2&#8208;X/rGO (PtSA&#8208;M&#8208;CeO2&#8208;X/rGO). It exhibited high activity in HER with an overpotential of 25 mV at 0.5 M H2SO4 and 33 mV at 1 KOH than that of almost reported electrocatalysts. Furthermore, it exhibited stability for 90 hours at &#8722;100 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 KOH and &#8722;150 mA cm&#8722;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 conditions, respectively. Through comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations, the suitable dispersion density of PtSA on the defects of CeO2&#8208;X with more active sites gives the potential for practical applications. This research paves the way for developing single&#8208;atom catalysts with exceptional catalytic activity and stability, holding promise in advanced green energy conversion through defects engineering.</description>
      <author>Xinyang Liu, Yuxuan Zhou, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Zhijun Wang, Liangyong Jia, Mengyuan Li, K&#232; Yang, Jinchen Fan, Weiwei Yang, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202406650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photodynamic Therapy for Atherosclerosis: Past, Present, and Future</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics16060729</link>
      <description>Yanqing Lin, Ruosen Xie, Yu Chen, Pharmaceutics. 16(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399288196

                This review paper examines the evolution of photodynamic therapy (PDT) as a novel, minimally invasive strategy for treating atherosclerosis, a leading global health concern. Atherosclerosis is characterized by the accumulation of lipids and inflammation within arterial walls, leading to significant morbidity and mortality through cardiovascular diseases such as myocardial infarction and stroke. Traditional therapeutic approaches have primarily focused on modulating risk factors such as hypertension and hyperlipidemia, with emerging evidence highlighting the pivotal role of inflammation. PDT, leveraging a photosensitizer, specific-wavelength light, and oxygen, offers targeted treatment by inducing cell death in diseased tissues while sparing healthy ones. This specificity, combined with advancements in nanoparticle technology for improved delivery, positions PDT as a promising alternative to traditional interventions. The review explores the mechanistic basis of PDT, its efficacy in preclinical studies, and the potential for enhancing plaque stability and reducing macrophage density within plaques. It also addresses the need for further research to optimize treatment parameters, mitigate adverse effects, and validate long-term outcomes. By detailing past developments, current progress, and future directions, this paper aims to highlight PDT&#8217;s potential in revolutionizing atherosclerosis treatment, bridging the gap from experimental research to clinical application.</description>
      <author>Yanqing Lin, Ruosen Xie, Yu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/pharmaceutics16060729</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Directional Growth and Density Modulation of Single&#8208;Atom Platinum for Efficient Electrocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406650</link>
      <description>Xinyang Liu, Yuxuan Zhou, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Zhijun Wang, Liangyong Jia, Mengyuan Li, K&#232; Yang, Jinchen Fan, Weiwei Yang, Guisheng Li, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399239500

                Dispersion of single atoms (SAs) in the host is important for optimizing catalytic activity. Herein, we propose a novel strategy to tune oxygen vacancies in CeO2&#8208;X directionally anchoring the single atom platinum (PtSA), which is uniformly dispersed on the rGO. The catalyst's performance for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) can be enhanced by controlling different densities of CeO2&#8208;X in rGO. The PtSA performs best optimally densified and loaded on homogeneous and moderately densified CeO2&#8208;X/rGO (PtSA&#8208;M&#8208;CeO2&#8208;X/rGO). It exhibited high activity in HER with an overpotential of 25 mV at 0.5 M H2SO4 and 33 mV at 1 KOH than that of almost reported electrocatalysts. Furthermore, it exhibited stability for 90 hours at &#8722;100 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1 KOH and &#8722;150 mA cm&#8722;2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 conditions, respectively. Through comprehensive experiments and theoretical calculations, the suitable dispersion density of PtSA on the defects of CeO2&#8208;X with more active sites gives the potential for practical applications. This research paves the way for developing single&#8208;atom catalysts with exceptional catalytic activity and stability, holding promise in advanced green energy conversion through defects engineering.</description>
      <author>Xinyang Liu, Yuxuan Zhou, Jingkai Lin, Xiao Xiao, Zhijun Wang, Liangyong Jia, Mengyuan Li, K&#232; Yang, Jinchen Fan, Weiwei Yang, Guisheng Li</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202406650</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Environment-Driven Variability in Absolute Band Edge Positions and Work Functions of Reduced Ceria</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05053</link>
      <description>Xingfan Zhang, Christopher S. Blackman, Robert G. Palgrave, Sobia Ashraf, Avishek Dey, Matthew O. Blunt, Xu Zhang, Taifeng Liu, Shijia Sun, Lei Zhu, Jingcheng Guan, You L&#252;, Thomas W. Keal, John Buckeridge, C. Richard A. Catlow, Alexey A. Sokol, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399367657

                The absolute band edge positions and work function (&#934;) are the key electronic properties of metal oxides that determine their performance in electronic devices and photocatalysis. However, experimental measurements of these properties often show notable variations, and the mechanisms underlying these discrepancies remain inadequately understood. In this work, we focus on ceria (CeO2), a material renowned for its outstanding oxygen storage capacity, and combine theoretical and experimental techniques to demonstrate environmental modifications of its ionization potential (IP) and &#934;. Under O-deficient conditions, reduced ceria exhibits a decreased IP and &#934; with significant sensitivity to defect distributions. In contrast, the IP and &#934; are elevated in O-rich conditions due to the formation of surface peroxide species. Surface adsorbates and impurities can further augment these variabilities under realistic conditions. We rationalize the shifts in energy levels by separating the individual contributions from bulk and surface factors, using hybrid quantum mechanical/molecular mechanical (QM/MM) embedded-cluster and periodic density functional theory (DFT) calculations supported by interatomic-potential-based electrostatic analyses. Our results highlight the critical role of on-site electrostatic potentials in determining the absolute energy levels in metal oxides, implying a dynamic evolution of band edges under catalytic conditions.</description>
      <author>Xingfan Zhang, Christopher S. Blackman, Robert G. Palgrave, Sobia Ashraf, Avishek Dey, Matthew O. Blunt, Xu Zhang, Taifeng Liu, Shijia Sun, Lei Zhu, Jingcheng Guan, You L&#252;, Thomas W. Keal, John Buckeridge, C. Richard A. Catlow, Alexey A. Sokol</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05053</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genetic isolation and metabolic complexity of an Antarctic subglacial microbiome</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4392950/v1</link>
      <description>Ok-Sun Kim, Ki-Hwan Hwang, Hanbyul Lee, Soyeon Kim, Ahnna Cho, Christina Davis, Brent C. Christner, John C. Priscu, Kyung Mo Kim, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399247798

                Abstract Microbes inhabiting and evolving in aquatic ecosystems at the base of polar ice sheets subsist under energy-limited conditions while in relative isolation from surface gene pools and their common ancestral populations of origin. Samples recently obtained from the base of West Antarctic Ice Sheet (WAIS) allowed us to examine evolutionary relationships of and identify metabolic pathways in microbial genomes recovered from the Mercer Subglacial Lake (SLM) ecosystem. We obtained 1,374 single-cell amplified genomes from individual bacterial and archaeal cells that were isolated from samples of SLM&#8217;s water column and sediments. Genome-based taxonomic classification coherently identified nearly all of the subglacial microorganisms as new species or novel taxonomic groups, and phylogenomic analyses showed evidence for genetically isolation of the microbial populations from marine and surface biomes. Comparative genomic analysis revealed a lake ecosystem exhibiting a range of metabolisms to oxidize various organic and inorganic compounds via aerobic or anerobic respiration. Network construction identified two distinct organotrophic and chemolithotrophic metabolic guilds that may operate alternatively depending on oxygen availability. Our SAG data imply substantial metabolic flexibility in the microbial assemblage characterized, reveal key energy generating strategies in the subglacial ecosystem, and provide a framework to assess microbial evolution beneath WAIS.</description>
      <author>Ok-Sun Kim, Ki-Hwan Hwang, Hanbyul Lee, Soyeon Kim, Ahnna Cho, Christina Davis, Brent C. Christner, John C. Priscu, Kyung Mo Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4392950/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integration Construction of Hybrid Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Reductions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404773</link>
      <description>Lei Huang, Huiting Niu, Bao Yu Xia, Fumin Li, Shahid Zaman, Bao Yu Xia, Advanced materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399286686

                Abstract There has been notable progress in the development of efficient oxygen reduction electrocatalysts, which are crucial components of fuel cells. However, these superior activities are limited by imbalanced mass transport and cannot be fully reflected in actual fuel cell applications. Herein, we present the design concepts and development tracks of platinum&#8208;nanocarbon hybrid catalysts, aiming to enhance both cathodic electrocatalysts and hydrogen reactors. This review commences with an introduction to Pt/C catalysts, highlighting the diverse architectures developed to date, with particular emphasis on heteroatom modification and microstructure construction of functionalized nanocarbons based on integrated design concepts. This discussion encompasses the structural evolution, property enhancement, and catalytic mechanisms of Pt/C&#8208;based catalysts, including rational preparation recipes, superior activity, strong stability, robust metal&#8208;support interactions, adsorption regulation, synergistic pathways, confinement strategies, ionomer optimization, mass transport permission, multidimensional construction, and reactor upgrading. Furthermore, this review explores the low&#8208;barrier or barrier&#8208;free mass exchange interfaces and channels achieved through the impressive multidimensional construction of platinum&#8208;nanocarbon integrated catalysts, with the goal of optimizing fuel cell efficiency. In conclusion, this review outlines the challenges associated with platinum&#8208;nanocarbon integrated catalysts and provides perspectives on the future development trends of fuel cells and beyond. This article is protected by copyright. All rights reserved</description>
      <author>Lei Huang, Huiting Niu, Bao Yu Xia, Fumin Li, Shahid Zaman, Bao Yu Xia</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202404773</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In situ visualizing reveals potential drive of lattice expansion on defective support toward efficient removal of nitrogen oxides</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2311180121</link>
      <description>Zhineng Hao, Guoquan Liu, Pengfei Wang, Weiyu Zhang, Wenming Sun, Lirong Zheng, Shaojun Guo, Sihui Zhan, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399281694

                As a sustainable and promising approach of removing of nitrogen oxides (NO x ), catalytic reduction of NO x with H 2 is highly desirable with a precise understanding to the structure&#8211;activity relationship of supported catalysts. In particular, the dynamic evolution of support at microscopic scale may play a critical role in heterogeneous catalysis, however, identifying the in situ structural change of support under working condition with atomic precision and revealing its role in catalysis is still a grand challenge. Herein, we visually capture the surface lattice expansion of WO 3&#8722;x support in Pt&#8211;WO 3&#8722;x catalyst induced by NO in the exemplified reduction of NO with H 2 using in situ transmission electron microscopy and first reveal its important role in enhancing catalysis. We find that NO can adsorb on the oxygen vacancy sites of WO 3&#8722;x and favorably induce the reversible stretching of W&#8211;O&#8211;W bonds during the reaction, which can reduce the adsorption energy of NO on Pt 4 centers and the energy barrier of the rate-determining step. The comprehensive studies reveal that lattice expansion of WO 3&#8722;x support can tune the catalytic performance of Pt&#8211;WO 3&#8722;x catalyst, leading to 20% catalytic activity enhancement for the exemplified reduction of NO with H 2 . This work reveals that the lattice expansion of defective support can tune and optimize the catalytic performance at the atomic scale.</description>
      <author>Zhineng Hao, Guoquan Liu, Pengfei Wang, Weiyu Zhang, Wenming Sun, Lirong Zheng, Shaojun Guo, Sihui Zhan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2311180121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pulsatile extractions of Lower Cretaceous silicic volcanic plumbing system beneath the Baiyunzhang and Lianhuashan Basins, eastern Guangdong: silicic magma evolution and related mineralization</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1144/jgs2024-049</link>
      <description>Jianqiang He, Yan Xia, Xisheng Xu, Hongyang Shi, Jiangjiang Gu, Journal of the Geological Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399299701

                Highly differentiated magmas are closely related to the formation of tin deposits. The Lianhuashan Basin and Baiyunzhang Basin, surrounded by multiple coeval tin deposits, developed various types of volcanic and subvolcanic rocks. The diagenetic connections between different types of rocks within the two basins will provide new insight on the silicic magma systems evolution and the impact of highly differentiated magmas on tin mineralization. Both basins have consistent zircon U-Pb ages (143 &#8764; 138 Ma) and similar whole-rock Nd isotopes ( &#949; Nd ( t ) = -5.7 &#8764; -3.4) and zircon Hf-O isotopes ranges ( &#949; Hf ( t ) = -9.0 &#8764; -2.5; &#948; 18 O = 5.1 &#8764; 7.9), suggesting both basins originate from the same deep-level magma reservoir, followed by different degrees of crystal differentiation and several episodes of crystal-melt separation in their respective shallow-level magma reservoirs. The multiple pulses of magma extraction eventually produced different volcanic rocks, granite porphyry and rhyolite porphyry, while the remaining crystal mush consolidated in situ to form quartz monzonite porphyry. Further studies show that the tectonic regime changed from a compressive to an extensional environment at &#8764;140 Ma. Consequently, mantle-derived magmas with low oxygen fugacity injected shallow magma reservoirs that able to evolve to a high degree of differentiation through multiple recharge, thus favoring the formation of the Sn deposit. Supplementary material: https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.c.7258282</description>
      <author>Jianqiang He, Yan Xia, Xisheng Xu, Hongyang Shi, Jiangjiang Gu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1144/jgs2024-049</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Correlating substrates reactivity at electrified interfaces with electrolyte structure in synthetically relevant organic solvent/water mixtures</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-g1jhk-v2</link>
      <description>Florian Dorchies, Alessandra Serva, Astrid Sidos, Laurent J. Michot, Micha&#235;l Deschamps, Mathieu Salanne, Alexis Grimaud, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399301085

                Optimizing electrosynthetic reactions requires fine tuning of a vast chemical space, including charge transfer at electrocatalyst/electrode surfaces, engineering of mass transport limitations and complex interactions of reactants and products with their environment. Hybrid electrolytes, in which supporting salt ions and substrates are dissolved in a binary mixture of organic solvent and water, represent a new piece to this complex puzzle, as they offer a unique opportunity to harvest water as the oxygen or proton source in electrosynthesis. In this work, we demonstrate that modulating water-organic solvent interactions drastically impacts the solvation properties of hybrid electrolytes. Combining various spectroscopies with synchrotron small-angle X-ray scattering (SAXS) and classical molecular dynamics (MD) simulations, we show that the size and composition of aqueous domains forming in hybrid electrolytes can be controlled. We demonstrate that water is more reactive for the hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) in aqueous domains than when strongly interacting with solvent molecules, which originates from a change in reaction kinetics rather than from a thermodynamic effect. We examplify novel opportunities arising from this new knowledge for optimizing electrosynthetic reactions in hybrid electrolytes. For reactions proceeding first via the activation of water, fine tuning of aqueous domains impact the kinetics and potentially the selectivity of the reaction. Instead, for organic substrates reacting prior to water, aqueous domains have no impact on reaction kinetics, while selectivity may be affected. We believe that such fine comprehension of solvation properties of hybrid electrolytes can be transposed to numerous electrosynthetic reactions.</description>
      <author>Florian Dorchies, Alessandra Serva, Astrid Sidos, Laurent J. Michot, Micha&#235;l Deschamps, Mathieu Salanne, Alexis Grimaud</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.26434/chemrxiv-2024-g1jhk-v2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni and Co Catalysts on Interactive Oxide Support for Anion Exchange Membrane Electrolysis Cell (AEMEC)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12060153</link>
      <description>Katerina Maksimova-Dimitrova, Boryana Mladenova, G. Borisov, E. Slavcheva, Inorganics. 12(6)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399215326

                The work presents novel composite catalytic materials&#8212;Ni and Co deposited on Magneli phase titania&#8212;and describes their complex characterization and integration into membrane electrode assemblies to produce hydrogen by electrochemical water splitting in cells with anion exchange membranes (AEMEC). Chemical composition, surface structure, and morphology were characterized by XRD and SEM analysis. The activity in the evolution of the partial electrode reactions of hydrogen (HER) and oxygen (OER) was assessed in an aqueous alkaline electrolyte (25 wt.% KOH) using linear sweep voltammetry. The interactive role of the support was investigated and discussed. Among the tested samples, the sample with 30 wt.% Co (Co30/MPT) demonstrated superior performance in the OER. The reaction started at 1.65 V, and at 1.8 V, the current density reached 75 mA cm&#8722;2. The HER is most efficient on the sample containing 40 wt.% Ni (Ni40/MPT), where the current density reaches 95 mA at a potential of &#8722;0.5 V. The change in catalytic efficiency compared to that of the unsupported Ni and Co is due to synergism resulting from electronic interactions between the transition metal having a hyper-d-electron character and hypo-d-electron support. The pre-selected catalysts were integrated in membrane electrode assembly (MEA) using commercial and laboratory-prepared anion-conductive membranes and tested in a custom-made AEMEC. The performance was compared to that of MEA with a commercial carbon-supported Pt catalyst. It was found that the MEA with newly prepared catalysts demonstrated better performance in long-term operation (50 mA cm&#8722;2 at 1.8 V in a 60 h durability test), which, combined with the higher cost efficiency, gave credence to considering this combination of materials as promising for AEMEC applications.</description>
      <author>Katerina Maksimova-Dimitrova, Boryana Mladenova, G. Borisov, E. Slavcheva</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/inorganics12060153</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A high-precision interpretable framework for marine dissolved oxygen concentration inversion</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1396277</link>
      <description>Xin Li, Zhenyi Liu, Zhifeng Yang, Meng Fan, Tao Song, Frontiers in marine science. 11(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399246492

                Variations in Marine Dissolved Oxygen Concentrations (MDOC) play a critical role in the study of marine ecosystems and global climate evolution. Although artificial intelligence methods, represented by deep learning, can enhance the precision of MDOC inversion, the uninterpretability of the operational mechanism involved in the &#8220;black-box&#8221; often make the process difficult to interpret. To address this issue, this paper proposes a high-precision interpretable framework (CDRP) for intelligent MDOC inversion, including Causal Discovery, Drift Detection, RuleFit Model, and Post Hoc Analysis. The entire process of the proposed framework is fully interpretable: (i) The causal relationships between various elements are further clarified. (ii) During the phase of concept drift analysis, the potential factors contributing to changes in marine data are extracted. (iii) The operational rules of RuleFit ensure computational transparency. (iv) Post hoc analysis provides a quantitative interpretation from both global and local perspectives. Furthermore, we have derived quantitative conclusions about the impacts of various marine elements, and our analysis maintains consistency with conclusions in marine literature on MDOC. Meanwhile, CDRP also ensures the precision of MDOC inversion: (i) PCMCI causal discovery eliminates the interference of weakly associated elements. (ii) Concept drift detection takes more representative key frames. (iii) RuleFit achieves higher precision than other models. Experiments demonstrate that CDRP has reached the optimal level in single point buoy data inversion task. Overall, CDRP can enhance the interpretability of the intelligent MDOC inversion process while ensuring high precision.</description>
      <author>Xin Li, Zhenyi Liu, Zhifeng Yang, Meng Fan, Tao Song</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3389/fmars.2024.1396277</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phase-field simulation of high-temperature corrosion of binary Zr-2.5Sn alloys</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.73.20240393</link>
      <description>Liu Xu-Xi, Gao Shi-Sen, La Yong-Xiao, Wenbo Liu, Wuli xuebao. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399236229

                Due to the small neutron absorption cross section and excellent thermal creep performance, zirconium alloy is one of the most important cladding materials for fuel rods in commercial fission reactors. However, quantitative analysis of the effects of temperature and grain boundaries on the corrosion microstructure evolution of zirconium alloys is still needed. It is of great significance to establish a phase field simulation for the corrosion process of polycrystalline zirconium alloy and systematically investigate the thermodynamic impact. In this study, the phase field model of the corrosion process in zirconium alloys was developed by incorporating corrosion electrochemistry to calculate the interfacial energy at the metal-oxide and oxide-fluid boundaries. Then model was then employed to investigate the uniform corrosion behavior on the surface of Zr-2.5Sn alloy, which demonstrated that the corrosion kinetics curve followed a cubic rule. Subsequently, the influence of temperature on the corrosion thickening curve of zirconium alloys was examined, and good agreement between simulation and experimental results was achieved. It was observed that during early stages of oxide layer formation, there is a high growth rate with minimal temperature dependence; however, as the oxide layer thickness increases, temperature becomes a significant factor affecting its growth rate, with higher temperatures resulting in faster corrosion rates. Furthermore, an investigation into the effect of polycrystalline zirconium alloy matrices on corrosion rates revealed that grain boundaries accelerate oxide layer thickening due to enhanced oxygen diffusion rates. Along these grain boundaries towards the metal matrix at metal-oxide interfaces, regions with higher O&lt;sup&gt;2-&lt;/sup&gt; concentrations form an O&lt;sup&gt;2-&lt;/sup&gt; band which primarily influences oxidation-corrosion rates during initial oxidation stages.</description>
      <author>Liu Xu-Xi, Gao Shi-Sen, La Yong-Xiao, Wenbo Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.7498/aps.73.20240393</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Duplication and neofunctionalization of a horizontally transferred xyloglucanase as a facet of the Red Queen coevolutionary dynamic</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2218927121</link>
      <description>Victoria Attah, David S. Milner, Yufeng Fang, Yan Xia, Guy Leonard, Joseph Heitman, Nicholas J. Talbot, Thomas A. Richards, Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America. 121(24)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399281648

                Oomycete protists share phenotypic similarities with fungi, including the ability to cause plant diseases, but branch in a distant region of the tree of life. It has been suggested that multiple horizontal gene transfers (HGTs) from fungi-to-oomycetes contributed to the evolution of plant-pathogenic traits. These HGTs are predicted to include secreted proteins that degrade plant cell walls, a barrier to pathogen invasion and a rich source of carbohydrates. Using a combination of phylogenomics and functional assays, we investigate the diversification of a horizontally transferred xyloglucanase gene family in the model oomycete species Phytophthora sojae . Our analyses detect 11 xyloglucanase paralogs retained in P. sojae . Using heterologous expression in yeast, we show consistent evidence that eight of these paralogs have xyloglucanase function, including variants with distinct protein characteristics, such as a long-disordered C-terminal extension that can increase xyloglucanase activity. The functional variants analyzed subtend a phylogenetic node close to the fungi-to-oomycete transfer, suggesting the horizontally transferred gene was a bona fide xyloglucanase. Expression of three xyloglucanase paralogs in Nicotiana benthamiana triggers high-reactive oxygen species (ROS) generation, while others inhibit ROS responses to bacterial immunogens, demonstrating that the paralogs differentially stimulate pattern-triggered immunity. Mass spectrometry of detectable enzymatic products demonstrates that some paralogs catalyze the production of variant breakdown profiles, suggesting that secretion of variant xyloglucanases increases efficiency of xyloglucan breakdown as well as diversifying the damage-associated molecular patterns released. We suggest that this pattern of neofunctionalization and the variant host responses represent an aspect of the Red Queen host&#8211;pathogen coevolutionary dynamic.</description>
      <author>Victoria Attah, David S. Milner, Yufeng Fang, Yan Xia, Guy Leonard, Joseph Heitman, Nicholas J. Talbot, Thomas A. Richards</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1073/pnas.2218927121</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efficient and durable iridium-doped SnO2 anode for reactive chlorine species-mediated urine wastewater treatment</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152698</link>
      <description>Sukhwa Hong, Gil-Bok Choi, Nhat-Long Phan, Hyungcheol Shin, Jonghun Lim, Chemical engineering journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399240365

                The prevalence of nitrogen pollutants in urine wastewater has become a pressing environmental issue. Among various methods for addressing this concern, electrochemical oxidation processes that generate reactive chlorine species (RCS) from chloride ions commonly found in urine wastewater stand out as a promising approach. Despite the exploration of diverse anode materials, existing options still suffer from low selectivity in RCS generation, poor stability, and considerable energy consumption. In this study, we synthesized iridium-doped tin oxide (Ir-SnO2) as an efficient, durable, and energy-conserving anode and systematically evaluated its electrochemical activity for RCS-mediated removal of nitrogen pollutants in urine wastewater. The Ir-SnO2 anode outperformed counterparts such as IrO2, SnO2, and Sb-SnO2, demonstrating its superior electrochemical performance characterized by high current density, low charge transfer resistance, and substantial active surface area. It also achieved exceptional current efficiency of 91.7 % and energy efficiency of 7.79 mmol/Wh for RCS generation at 30 mA cm&#8722;2 in diluted 0.1 M chloride solution. Computational analysis from Density Functional Theory (DFT) additionally supported experimental results, revealing that Ir doping to SnO2 enhances chlorine adsorption through electronic structure modification, significantly lowering the overpotential and improving electrocatalytic activity for chlorine evolution reactions. In the electrolysis of synthetic urine wastewater at 30 mA cm&#8722;2 for 5 h, the Ir-SnO2 anode demonstrated remarkable efficacy in degrading ammonia nitrogen (NH3-N), total nitrogen (TN), and chemical oxygen demand (COD) with efficiencies of 100 %, 97.8 %, and 89.1 %, respectively. These results were comparable to those achieved by IrO2 (dimensional stable anode, DSA) and exceeded the performance of the boron-doped diamond (BDD) anode. Furthermore, Ir-SnO2 exhibited the lowest energy consumption compared to benchmark DSA and BDD anodes in the treatment of urine wastewater. In stability assessments, furthermore, the Ir-SnO2 electrode maintained stable anodic cell potential for 100 h of continuous electrolysis in a 0.1 M NaCl electrolyte at 30 mA cm&#8722;2 and remained functional over five cycles without any signs of deactivation. This study provides valuable insights into the development of a suitable anode for energy-efficient urine wastewater treatment.</description>
      <author>Sukhwa Hong, Gil-Bok Choi, Nhat-Long Phan, Hyungcheol Shin, Jonghun Lim</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.152698</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Male with Acute Dermonecrosis over the Right Flank</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.4103/idoj.idoj_776_23</link>
      <description>Vijayasankar Palaniappan, Anusuya Sadhasivamohan, Kaliaperumal Karthikeyan, Indian dermatology online journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4399320463

                A 42-year-old farmer presented with an acute onset painful red raised lesion over the right side of his abdomen. While working in the paddy fields, the patient experienced a spider bite 3 days before the onset of this complaint. Initially, he had pain for a day, followed by redness and blister formation that eventually ruptured. He did not have any systemic complaints. On cutaneous examination, he had a single necrotic boggy plaque over the right flank. A linear streak of erythema was noted emanating from the superior aspect of the ovoid lesion [Figure 1a]. Dermoscopy showed a central bluish-black crust outlined by an irregular non-homogeneous reddish blue area in an erythematous background [Figure 2]. There was no regional lymphadenopathy.Figure 1: (a) A single oval erythematous boggy plaque of size 9 cm &#215; 7 cm with a central necrosis over the right flank, with a linear streak of erythema emanating from the superior aspect of the ovoid lesion; (b-f) Follow-up on day 5, day 10, day 16, day 30, and day 52Figure 2: A central bluish-black crust outlined by an irregular non-homogeneous reddish blue area in an erythematous backgroundThe vital parameters, hemogram, liver function tests, renal function tests, bleeding time, and clotting time were found to be normal. What is the diagnosis? Answer: Cutaneous loxoscelism with dermonecrosis Discussion The diagnosis of cutaneous arachnidism (loxoscelism) with dermonecrosis was made based on the positive history of spider bite, clinical presentation, and dermoscopy. The patient was managed with topical collagenase ointment, oral acetaminophen, a prophylactic antibiotic with intravenous ceftazidime twice daily, and oral prednisolone 0.4 mg/kg/day for 7 days. The patient was periodically followed up [Figures 1b-f]. The lesion healed with a hypertrophic scar. Necrotic arachnidism is a cutaneous reaction to toxins released from the venoms of spider bites. Loxoscelism is a term used for spider bites associated with loxosceles species.[1] Cutaneous loxoscelism is the most common presentation of loxoscelism. Systemic involvement with fever, myalgia, and hemolytic anemia can rarely occur.[1] The differences between cutaneous and systemic loxoscelism are mentioned in Table 1.[2] The toxins responsible for cutaneous loxoscelism are enzymes sphingomyelinase-D, phospholipase-D, alkaline phosphatase, hyaluronidase, esterase, and proteases.Table 1: Differences between cutaneous and systemic loxoscelism.Clinically cutaneous loxoscelism presents as a painful localized bluish-gray halo surrounding the bite site. This is followed by a vesicle or cyanotic pustule with surrounding erythema, edema, and purpura. Later, a central ischemic pallor with a dry, crusted, necrotic lesion with surrounding erythema, vesiculation, and pustulation is noted. The lesion spreads rapidly and extensively, with the eschar shedding and leaving erosions and ulcers. The affected site may take up to 6 months to heal with or without scarring. The pathognomic lesional description is a classical red, white, and blue sign. The red depicts erythema, followed by a palisaded white ring of vasoconstriction due to the toxin, and a central blue necrotic zone.[1] The most common affected sites are the proximal part of the lower extremity and the distal part of the upper extremity. Lymphedema can occur as a complication to loxoscelism.[3] The conditions that mimic cutaneous loxoscelism are arthropod bites, erysipelas, ecthyma, cellulitis, urticaria and angioedema, burns, vasculitis, pyoderma gangrenosum, cutaneous diphtheroid, anthrax, and cutaneous malignancies.[4,5] There are no standard guidelines for the management of cutaneous loxoscelism. Spider bites generally require rest to the involved part, analgesia, sterile dressing, and periodic follow-up. Cutaneous loxoscelism with dermonecrosis may require systemic steroids, prophylactic antibiotics, vasodilators, dapsone, tetracycline, heparin, and hyperbaric oxygen therapy.[4,6] Systemic involvement, which develops anytime within 12&#8211;36 hours after the bite, requires vigorous hemodynamic management.[2] Antivenin provides beneficial effects like prevention of necrosis, edema, and ecchymoses when administered as early as possible.[7] A high index of suspicion should be kept in mind to diagnose this entity in patients presenting with acute onset ulceration. A proper history taking and clinical examination holds the key to clinching the diagnosis. The aim of reporting this case is to emphasize the clinical evolution of cutaneous loxoscelism, which may pose a diagnostic dilemma. Declaration of patient consent The authors certify that they have obtained all appropriate patient consent forms. In the form the patient(s) has/have given his/her/their consent for his/her/their images and other clinical information to be reported in the journal. The patients understand that their names and initials will not be published and due efforts will be made to conceal their identity, but anonymity cannot be guaranteed. Financial support and sponsorship Nil. Conflicts of interest There are no conflicts of interest.</description>
      <author>Vijayasankar Palaniappan, Anusuya Sadhasivamohan, Kaliaperumal Karthikeyan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.4103/idoj.idoj_776_23</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
