<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>water splitting</title>
    <link>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jkitchin/literature-alerts/main/rss/rss/water-splitting.xml</link>
    <description>water splitting papers</description>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 01:13:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator>
    <docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs>
    <item>
      <title>Synergizing ruthenium oxide with bimetallic Co2CrO4 for highly efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.260</link>
      <description>Mengyue Qi, Xinyu Zheng, Huamei Tong, Haibo Liu, Di Li, Zaoxue Yan, Deli Jiang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. 677(None)] 2025. https://openalex.org/W4401375873

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mengyue Qi, Xinyu Zheng, Huamei Tong, Haibo Liu, Di Li, Zaoxue Yan, Deli Jiang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.07.260</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt-iron Co-doped ammonium phosphomolybdate for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution in acidic electrolyte</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.292</link>
      <description>L. Y. Xin, Li Luo, Tian Gan, Xianhe Liu, Ze-Da Meng, Mengjiao Zhu, Shou&#8208;Qing Liu, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401203924

                No abstract</description>
      <author>L. Y. Xin, Li Luo, Tian Gan, Xianhe Liu, Ze-Da Meng, Mengjiao Zhu, Shou&#8208;Qing Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.292</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing post-treatment strategies for enhanced oxygen reduction/evolution activity in Co&#8211;N&#8211;C electrocatalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.388</link>
      <description>Gulnara Yusibova, Kefeng Ping, Maike K&#228;&#228;rik, Jaan Leis, Jaan Aruv&#228;li, Kri&#353;j&#257;nis &#352;mits, Tanel K&#228;&#228;mbre, Vambola Kisand, Yevgen Karpichev, Kaido Tammeveski, Nade&#382;da Kongi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401208758

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Gulnara Yusibova, Kefeng Ping, Maike K&#228;&#228;rik, Jaan Leis, Jaan Aruv&#228;li, Kri&#353;j&#257;nis &#352;mits, Tanel K&#228;&#228;mbre, Vambola Kisand, Yevgen Karpichev, Kaido Tammeveski, Nade&#382;da Kongi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.388</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZIF-67 Nanostructures Anchored on 3D Graphene Sheets: A Non-noble Electrocatalyst for Efficient Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01181</link>
      <description>Duk&#8208;Hyun Choe, Komal Patil, Sun-Woo Kim, Seyeon Cho, Yujin Cho, Jincheol Kim, Dong Han Seo, Jongsung Park, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401212933

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Duk&#8208;Hyun Choe, Komal Patil, Sun-Woo Kim, Seyeon Cho, Yujin Cho, Jincheol Kim, Dong Han Seo, Jongsung Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c01181</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural optimization: Ternary FeNiZn sulfide nanoparticles anchored on nanosheets to strengthen oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.414</link>
      <description>Jun Yu, Xiaofeng Wang, Yangping Zhang, Tianpeng Liu, Zhengying Wu, Shudi Yu, Yukou Du, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401217392

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jun Yu, Xiaofeng Wang, Yangping Zhang, Tianpeng Liu, Zhengying Wu, Shudi Yu, Yukou Du</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.414</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ingenious Regulation and Activation of Sites in the 2h-Mos2basal Planes by Oxygen Incorporation for Enhanced Photocatalytic Hydrogen Evolution of CDS</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4912824</link>
      <description>Guixin Zeng, Honghai Miao, Jiangbo Wu, Jianjian Yi, Xingwang Zhu, Haiping Qi, Zhao Mo, Jinyuan Liu, Baibiao Huang, Hongxiang Xu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401219512

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Guixin Zeng, Honghai Miao, Jiangbo Wu, Jianjian Yi, Xingwang Zhu, Haiping Qi, Zhao Mo, Jinyuan Liu, Baibiao Huang, Hongxiang Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4912824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One-pot modulated construction of Ni-MOF/NiFe2O4 heterostructured catalyst for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02915-2</link>
      <description>Xingyu Guo, Zhiqiang Yang, Jing Zhao, Rui Liu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401229023

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xingyu Guo, Zhiqiang Yang, Jing Zhao, Rui Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02915-2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic oxygen evolution activity of nickel-doped manganese oxide nanorods in acid</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03221g</link>
      <description>Chao Wang, B. Xin, Yong Wang, Yvpei Li, Pengfei Xing, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401229672

                Active and stable electrocatalysts based on earth-abundant elements for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) are crucial for the hydrogen production using proton-exchange membrane water electrolyzers. Here, nickel-doped manganese oxide nanorods...</description>
      <author>Chao Wang, B. Xin, Yong Wang, Yvpei Li, Pengfei Xing</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj03221g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copper-doped nickel&#8211;iron metal/metal oxide electrode with improved performance by promoting synergistic effects in the oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102225</link>
      <description>Xiaoyu Gong, Jiawei Ge, Junlei Qi, Honghe Ding, Leijie Zhang, Peiyu Ma, Zuohuan Chen, Nian Zhang, Jilong Xu, Lijuan Zhu, Jing L&#252;, Guiqiang Li, Junjie Ge, Yifan Ye, Materials Today Chemistry. 40(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401230203

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiaoyu Gong, Jiawei Ge, Junlei Qi, Honghe Ding, Leijie Zhang, Peiyu Ma, Zuohuan Chen, Nian Zhang, Jilong Xu, Lijuan Zhu, Jing L&#252;, Guiqiang Li, Junjie Ge, Yifan Ye</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.mtchem.2024.102225</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of strain and dopants on breaking the activity-stability trade-off of RuO2 acidic oxygen evolution electrocatalysts</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4721957/v1</link>
      <description>Hyoyoung Lee, Haibo Liu, Yixuan Wang, Hao Li, Min Gyu Kim, Mingbo Wu, Research Square (Research Square). None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401232471

                Abstract Ruthenium dioxide (RuO&#8322;) electrocatalysts for acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) suffer from mediocre activity and rather instability induced by high Ru-O covalency. Here, the tensile strained Sr0.1Ta0.1Ru0.8O2-x (TS-Sr0.1Ta0.1Ru0.8O2-x) nanocatalysts were synthesized via a molten salt-assisted quenching strategy. The TS spacially elongates the Ru-O bond and reduces covalency, thereby inhibiting the lattice oxygen participation and structural decomposition. The synergistic electronic modulations among Sr-Ru-Ta groups both optimize deprotonation on oxygen sites and intermediates absorption on Ru sites, lowering the OER energy barrier. Those result in a well-balanced activity-stability profile, confirmed by comprehensive experimental and theoretical analyses. Our TS-Sr0.1Ta0.1Ru0.8O2-x electrode demonstrated an overpotential of 166 mV at 10 mA cm-2 in 0.5 M H2SO4 and an order of magnitude higher S-number, indicating exceptional stability compared to bare Sr0.1Ta0.1Ru0.8O2-x. It exhibited degradation rates of 0.02 mV/h at 10 mA cm-2 over 1000 h and 0.25 mV/h at 200 mA cm-2 over 200 h. This study elucidates the effectiveness of tensile strain and strategic doping in enhancing the activity and stability of Ru-based catalysts for acidic OER.</description>
      <author>Hyoyoung Lee, Haibo Liu, Yixuan Wang, Hao Li, Min Gyu Kim, Mingbo Wu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21203/rs.3.rs-4721957/v1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal V doping optimizes the binding affinity of CuCoO2 with OH- contributes to efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175795</link>
      <description>Shiyu Ma, Jilin Bai, Wei Wang, Chao Jiang, Qian Shen, Lifeng Liu, Xiujian Zhao, Dehua Xiong, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401240700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiyu Ma, Jilin Bai, Wei Wang, Chao Jiang, Qian Shen, Lifeng Liu, Xiujian Zhao, Dehua Xiong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175795</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Direct Identification of O&#9472;O Bond Formation Through Three&#8208;Step Oxidation During Water Splitting by Operando Soft X&#8208;ray Absorption Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202401236</link>
      <description>Yucheng Huang, Yujie Wu, Ying&#8211;Rui Lu, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Hong&#8208;Ji Lin, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Chi&#8208;Liang Chen, Chao Jing, Jing Zhou, Linjuan Zhang, Yanyong Wang, Wu&#8208;Ching Chou, Shuangyin Wang, Zhiwei Hu, Chung&#8208;Li Dong, Advanced Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401241330

                Abstract Anionic redox allows the direct formation of O&#9472;O bonds from lattice oxygens and provides higher catalytic in the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) than does the conventional metal ion mechanism. While previous theories have predicted and experiments have suggested the possible O&#9472;O bond, it has not yet been directly observed in the OER process. In this study, operando soft X&#8208;ray absorption spectroscopy (sXAS) at the O K&#8208;edge and the operando Raman spectra is performed on layered double CoFe hydroxides (LDHs) after intercalation with [Cr(C 2 O 4 ) 3 ] 3&#8722; , and revealed a three&#8208;step oxidation process, staring from Co 2+ to Co 3+ , further to Co 4+ (3d6L), and ultimately leading to the formation of O&#9472;O bonds and O 2 evolution above a threshold voltage (1.4 V). In contrast, a gradual oxidation of Fe is observed in CoFe LDHs. The OER activity exhibits a significant enhancement, with the overpotential decreasing from 300 to 248 mV at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , following the intercalation of [Cr(C 2 O 4 ) 3 ] 3&#8722; into CoFe LDHs, underscoring a crucial role of anionic redox in facilitating water splitting.</description>
      <author>Yucheng Huang, Yujie Wu, Ying&#8211;Rui Lu, Jeng&#8208;Lung Chen, Hong&#8208;Ji Lin, Chien&#8208;Te Chen, Chi&#8208;Liang Chen, Chao Jing, Jing Zhou, Linjuan Zhang, Yanyong Wang, Wu&#8208;Ching Chou, Shuangyin Wang, Zhiwei Hu, Chung&#8208;Li Dong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/advs.202401236</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Interfacial Engineering of Mn Porphyrin/Au Electrodes for Identifying MnO&lt;sub&gt;&lt;i&gt;x&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/sub&gt; as the Active Species under Oxygen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01420</link>
      <description>Yongman Kim, Yong-Chan Jeong, D. Na, Young Jae Kim, Jeong Young Park, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401243424

                Understanding the influence of surface structural features at a molecular level is beneficial in guiding an electrode's mechanistic proposals for electrocatalytic reactions. The relationship between structural stability and catalytic activity significantly impacts reaction performance, even though atomistic knowledge of active sites remains a topic of discussion. In this context, this work presents scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) results for the highly ordered arrangement of manganese porphyrin molecules on a Au(111) surface; STM allows us to monitor active sites at a molecular level to focus on long-standing issues with the electrocatalytic process, especially the exact nature of the real active sites at the interfaces. After water oxidation, manganese porphyrin rapidly decomposes into active catalytic species as bright protrusions. These newly formed active species drastically lost catalytic activity, up to 82%, through only acid treatment, one of the oxide removal methods, not by deionized water and acetone treatments. STM results of the obviated active species on the Au surface by an acidic solution support the forfeited catalytic activity. In addition, it shows a 67% decrement in catalytic activity by adsorption of phosphonic acid, one of the oxide's preferred adsorption materials, compared to the pristine one. Based on these observations, we confirm that the newly formed active species, as water oxidation catalysts, mostly consist of manganese oxides. Notable findings of our work provide molecular evidence for the active sites of Au and modified Au electrodes that spur the future development of water oxidation catalysts.</description>
      <author>Yongman Kim, Yong-Chan Jeong, D. Na, Young Jae Kim, Jeong Young Park</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c01420</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Catalytic Activity and Selectivity of Manganese Dioxide-Modified Nickel&#8211;Iron-Based Hydroxide Electrodes for Initiating the Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Natural Seawater</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080502</link>
      <description>Fangfang Liu, Miaomiao Fan, Haofeng Yan, Sheng Wang, Jimei Song, Hui Wang, Jianwei Ren, Catalysts. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401243930

                Transition metal oxides, particularly NiFe(OH)2, are recognized for their high oxygen evolution reaction (OER) activity and structural stability. However, their performance in natural seawater electrolysis remains insufficiently studied. Manganese dioxide (MnO2), which is known for its multiple crystal phases and high OER selectivity, can be incorporated to enhance the catalytic properties. In this study, the OER catalytic performance of carbon cloth-supported manganese dioxide-modified nickel&#8211;iron bimetallic hydroxide (MnO2-NiFe-LDH/CC) electrodes was explored in both alkaline and natural seawater. Electrochemical tests demonstrated that the MnO2-NiFe-LDH/CC electrode achieved overpotentials of 284 mV and 363 mV at current densities of 10 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2 and 100 mA&#183;cm&#8722;2, respectively, with a Tafel slope of 68.6 mV&#183;dec&#8722;1 in alkaline seawater. Most importantly, the prepared MnO2-NiFe-LDH/CC electrode maintained stable OER performance over 120 h of testing. In natural seawater, the MnO2-NiFe-LDH/CC electrode outperformed the NiFe-LDH/CC electrode by exhibiting an oxygen evolution selectivity of 61.1%. This study highlights the potential of MnO2-modified nickel&#8211;iron-based materials for efficient and stable OER in seawater electrolysis, which offers a promising approach for sustainable hydrogen production in coastal desert regions.</description>
      <author>Fangfang Liu, Miaomiao Fan, Haofeng Yan, Sheng Wang, Jimei Song, Hui Wang, Jianwei Ren</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080502</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering of active site coupling to facilitate interatomic charge transfer for bifunctional oxygen electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134986</link>
      <description>Qiaoling Xu, Lei Zhang, Hongyue Zhao, Xinyu Yin, Anqi Wang, Xiaowei Li, Guangzhi Hu, Colloids and Surfaces A Physicochemical and Engineering Aspects. 701(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401248419

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Qiaoling Xu, Lei Zhang, Hongyue Zhao, Xinyu Yin, Anqi Wang, Xiaowei Li, Guangzhi Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.colsurfa.2024.134986</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Electrocatalytic Performance of Double-Shell Structured Nixfe2-Xp/Nife2o4 for Oxygen Evolution Reaction and Anion Exchange Membrane Water Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4913996</link>
      <description>Junseong Kim, Kyeongseok Min, Hyunjin Lee, Hyeonseok Kwon, Sang Eun Shim, Sung&#8208;Hyeon Baeck, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401250208

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Junseong Kim, Kyeongseok Min, Hyunjin Lee, Hyeonseok Kwon, Sang Eun Shim, Sung&#8208;Hyeon Baeck</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4913996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic Field Assisted Oxygen Evolution Reaction: Beyond Spin Effects</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.31635/renewables.024.202400067</link>
      <description>Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Jing Fu, Renewables. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401250803

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shi&#8208;Yi Lin, Jing Fu</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.31635/renewables.024.202400067</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing the Oxygen Evolution Reaction activity of CuCo based Hydroxides with V2CTx MXene</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02700k</link>
      <description>Bastian Schmiedecke, Bing Wu, Thorsten Schultz, Aline Alencar Emerenciano, N. L. Sharma, Danielle Douglas-Henry, Apostolos Koutsioukis, Mehmet Turan Goerueryilmaz, Valeria Nicolosi, Tristan Petit, Norbert Koch, Zden&#283;k Sofer, Michelle P. Browne, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401252416

                The oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is a key reaction in the production of green hydrogen by water electrolysis. In alkaline media, the current state of the art catalysts used for...</description>
      <author>Bastian Schmiedecke, Bing Wu, Thorsten Schultz, Aline Alencar Emerenciano, N. L. Sharma, Danielle Douglas-Henry, Apostolos Koutsioukis, Mehmet Turan Goerueryilmaz, Valeria Nicolosi, Tristan Petit, Norbert Koch, Zden&#283;k Sofer, Michelle P. Browne</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02700k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lithium Orbital Hybridization Chemistry to Stimulate Oxygen Redox with Reversible Phase Evolution in Sodium-Layered Oxide Cathodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04814</link>
      <description>Haojie Dong, Haoliang Liu, Yu&#8208;Guo Guo, Yi&#8208;Hu Feng, Xu Zhu, Shaowen Xu, Fengxiang Sui, Lianzheng Yu, Mengting Liu, Jin&#8208;Zhi Guo, Ya&#8208;Xia Yin, Bing Xiao, Xing&#8208;Long Wu, Yu&#8208;Guo Guo, Pengfei Wang, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401255814

                Searching for high energy-density electrode materials for sodium ion batteries has revealed Na-deficient intercalation compounds with lattice oxygen redox as promising high-capacity cathodes. However, anionic redox reactions commonly encountered poor electrochemical reversibility and unfavorable structural transformations during dynamic (de)sodiation processes. To address this issue, we employed lithium orbital hybridization chemistry to create Na-O-Li configuration in a prototype P2-layered Na</description>
      <author>Haojie Dong, Haoliang Liu, Yu&#8208;Guo Guo, Yi&#8208;Hu Feng, Xu Zhu, Shaowen Xu, Fengxiang Sui, Lianzheng Yu, Mengting Liu, Jin&#8208;Zhi Guo, Ya&#8208;Xia Yin, Bing Xiao, Xing&#8208;Long Wu, Yu&#8208;Guo Guo, Pengfei Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c04814</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Role of Fe and Cr doped ZnO nanoparticles for electrocatalytic oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.437</link>
      <description>Naresh Bodicherla, T.V.M. Sreekanth, K. Prasad, Dongseob Kim, Jonghoon Kim, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401258823

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Naresh Bodicherla, T.V.M. Sreekanth, K. Prasad, Dongseob Kim, Jonghoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.437</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Co&#8211;FeOOH thin nanosheets derived from 2D ZIF-L for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.440</link>
      <description>Tingting Zheng, Xiao Yuan, Yulin Min, Tianchen Cui, Yiting Peng, Qiaoxia Li, Shaowei Chen, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401265502

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Tingting Zheng, Xiao Yuan, Yulin Min, Tianchen Cui, Yiting Peng, Qiaoxia Li, Shaowei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.440</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Surface Reconstruction of Te-Doped NiFe Layered Double Hydroxide for Robust Oxygen Evolution at High Current Density</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03672</link>
      <description>Yanyan Li, Haoran Guo, Jiayang Zhao, Kanglei Pang, Rui Song, ACS Sustainable Chemistry &amp; Engineering. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401266450

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yanyan Li, Haoran Guo, Jiayang Zhao, Kanglei Pang, Rui Song</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acssuschemeng.4c03672</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hierarchical Porous Carbon Supported Co&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;P&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; Nanoparticles for Oxygen Evolution and Oxygen Reduction in a Rechargeable Zn&#8211;Air Battery</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02599</link>
      <description>Bin Zhang, Xu Dong, Suer Guo, Meng Chen, Xingge He, Xin Chen, Mingxing Zhang, Jingui Duan, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401266868

                The oxygen reduction/evolution reaction (ORR/OER) represents a pivotal process in metal-air batteries; however, it is constrained by the limitations of slow kinetics. Nevertheless, the creation of long-lasting and bifunctional catalysts represents a significant challenge. This study presents a series of hierarchical porous carbon-supported cobalt pyrophosphate (Co</description>
      <author>Bin Zhang, Xu Dong, Suer Guo, Meng Chen, Xingge He, Xin Chen, Mingxing Zhang, Jingui Duan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02599</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synergistic promotion of the oxygen evolution reaction by Co and Fe dual-doping of NiS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01329h</link>
      <description>Wenjuan Xu, Y.H. Wang, Jiangyan Dang, Xiaoying Zhang, Wenliang Li, Jingping Zhang, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401275179

                Bimetallic doped Co,Fe&#8211;NiS2 nanosheet arrays are a promising non-precious metal electrocatalyst for the oxygen reduction reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Wenjuan Xu, Y.H. Wang, Jiangyan Dang, Xiaoying Zhang, Wenliang Li, Jingping Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01329h</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Cation Intercalation Facilitating Chemical Oxidation of Water and Surface Stabilization During the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12813</link>
      <description>Huiyan Zeng, Zhongfei Liu, Jun Qi, Jiajun Chen, Yanquan Zeng, Chonghui Yang, Zhenzhong Li, Chao Wang, Long Gu, Yanyan Zhang, Shu Miao, Chunzhen Yang, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401276935

                A comprehensive understanding of the dynamic processes at the catalyst/electrolyte interfaces is crucial for the development of advanced electrocatalysts for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, the chemical processes related to surface corrosion and catalyst degradation have not been well understood so far. In this study, we employ LiCoO 2 as a model catalyst and observe distinct OER activities and surface stabilities in different alkaline solutions. Operando X&#8208;ray diffraction (XRD) and online mass spectroscopy (OMS) measurements prove the selective intercalation of alkali cations into the layered structure of LiCoO 2 during OER. It is proposed that the dynamic cation intercalations facilitate the chemical oxidation process between highly oxidative Co species and adsorbed water molecules, triggering the so&#8208;called electrochemical&#8208;chemical reaction mechanism (EC&#8208;mechanism). The results of this study emphasize the influence of cations on OER and provide insights into new strategies for achieving both high activity and stability in high&#8208;performance OER catalysts.</description>
      <author>Huiyan Zeng, Zhongfei Liu, Jun Qi, Jiajun Chen, Yanquan Zeng, Chonghui Yang, Zhenzhong Li, Chao Wang, Long Gu, Yanyan Zhang, Shu Miao, Chunzhen Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12813</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Electrochemical Oxygen Evolution with Nickel Oxide Nanoparticle-Modified Glassy Carbon Electrodes in Alkaline Solutions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c04700</link>
      <description>Abdulrahman I. Alharthi, Omar A. Hazazi, Badreah A. Al Jahdaly, Mohammed A. Kassem, Mohamed I. Awad, ACS Omega. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401282919

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Abdulrahman I. Alharthi, Omar A. Hazazi, Badreah A. Al Jahdaly, Mohammed A. Kassem, Mohamed I. Awad</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsomega.4c04700</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabrication of cobalt phosphide/nitride/carbon nanotube composite: An efficient bifunctional catalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.394</link>
      <description>Zhaoyu Cai, Li Xu, Yifan Zhou, Longqing Gao, Xiaowei An, Xuli Ma, Yufei Ma, Jie Liu, Xiumin Li, Keyong Tang, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401283306

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaoyu Cai, Li Xu, Yifan Zhou, Longqing Gao, Xiaowei An, Xuli Ma, Yufei Ma, Jie Liu, Xiumin Li, Keyong Tang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.394</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Fast&#8208;Discharging Performance and Cyclability in Oxygen&#8208;Redox&#8208;Based P3&#8208;Type Na&#8208;Layered Cathode via Vacancies in TM layers</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402412</link>
      <description>Sangyeop Lee, Heejun Kweon, Sangyeop Lee, Min&#8208;kyung Cho, Hobin Ahn, Jinho Ahn, Bonyoung Ku, Myungeun Choi, Hun&#8208;Gi Jung, Dong Ok Shin, Jongsoon Kim, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401288212

                Abstract Oxygen redox in layered oxide cathodes for Na&#8208;ion batteries is considered a promising approach for improving the energy density. However, oxygen&#8208;redox&#8208;based cathodes suffer from sluggish kinetics and undesirable structural change during charge/discharge, leading to poor electrochemical performances. Herein, introducing vacancies (&#9633;) in the transition metal layers enables the enhanced oxygen redox&#8208;based electrochemical performances in the P3&#8208;type Mn&#8208;based layered oxide cathode is demonstrated. The vacancies can play a role of the local distortion buffers, resulting in the enhanced oxygen redox kinetics and the suppressed structural deformation such as P3&#8208;O3(II) phase transition. The oxygen&#8208;redox&#8208;based P3&#8208;type Na 0.56 [Ni 0.1 Mn 0.81 &#9633; 0.09 ]O 2 exhibits the large discharge capacity of &#8776;140.95 mAh g &#8722;1 at 26 mA g &#8722;1 with a high average discharge voltage of &#8776;3.54 V (vs Na + /Na). Even at 650 mA g &#8722;1 , its discharge capacity and average operation voltages delivered &#8776;122.06 mAh g &#8722;1 and &#8776;3.22 V, respectively. Especially, the small gap of average discharge voltage indicates both improves power&#8208;capability and enhanced kinetics of oxygen redox in P3&#8208;type Na 0.56 [Ni 0.1 Mn 0.81 &#9633; 0.09 ]O 2 . Moreover, the vacancy buffer in the transition metal layers results in the stable cycle&#8208;performance of P3&#8208;type Na 0.56 [Ni 0.1 Mn 0.81 &#9633; 0.09 ]O 2 with the capacity retention of &#8776;80.80% for 100 cycles, due to the suppressed P3&#8208;O3(II) phase transition.</description>
      <author>Sangyeop Lee, Heejun Kweon, Sangyeop Lee, Min&#8208;kyung Cho, Hobin Ahn, Jinho Ahn, Bonyoung Ku, Myungeun Choi, Hun&#8208;Gi Jung, Dong Ok Shin, Jongsoon Kim</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402412</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Synthesis of High&#8208;Entropy (Oxy)Hydroxides Via Electrochemical Reconfiguration As Catalysts For Efficient Water Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404379</link>
      <description>Weilin Shen, Yan Du, Huibin Liu, Chi&#8208;Wing Tsang, Xiao Chen, Changhai Liang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401290098

                Abstract Surface reconstruction plays a pivotal role in enhancing the activity of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER), particularly in terms of the structural transformation from metal oxides to (oxy)hydroxides. Herein, a novel (oxy)hydroxide (FeCoNiCuMoOOH) with high entropy is developed by the electrochemical reconstitution of corresponding oxide (FeCoNiCuMoO x ). Significantly, the FeCoNiCuMoOOH exhibits much higher OER electrocatalytic activity and durability with an overpotential as low as 201 mV at a current density of 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , and with a Tafel slope of 39.4 mV dec &#8722;1 . The FeCoNiCuMoOOH/NF presents high stability when testing under a constant current at 100 mA cm &#8722;2 within 1000 h. The surface reconstruction is a process of dissolution&#8208;reprecipitation of Cu and Mo species and co&#8208;hydroxylation of five metal species, which ultimately leads to the formation of FeCoNiCuMoOOH from FeCoNiCuMoOx. This study holds great significance in the realm of designing high&#8208;entropy (oxy)hydroxides catalysts with exceptional activity and stability for OER.</description>
      <author>Weilin Shen, Yan Du, Huibin Liu, Chi&#8208;Wing Tsang, Xiao Chen, Changhai Liang</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404379</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Constructing Co&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;(SO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt;)&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; Clusters within Metal&#8211;Organic Frameworks for Efficient Oxygen Electrocatalysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408094</link>
      <description>Zuozhong Liang, Guojun Zhou, Huang Tan, Yonghong Mou, Jieling Zhang, Hongbo Guo, Shujiao Yang, Haitao Lei, Haoquan Zheng, Wei Zhang, Haiping Lin, Rui Cao, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401290707

                Abstract Multinuclear metal clusters are ideal candidates to catalyze small molecule activation reactions involving the transfer of multiple electrons. However, synthesizing active metal clusters is a big challenge. Herein, on constructing an unparalleled Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 cluster within porphyrin&#8208;based metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) and the electrocatalytic features of such Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 clusters for the oxygen evolution reaction (OER) and oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) is reported. The reaction of Co II sulfate and metal complexes of tetrakis(4&#8208;pyridyl)porphyrin under solvothermal conditions afforded Co 4 &#8208;M&#8208;MOFs (M&#9552;Co, Cu, and Zn). Crystallographic studies revealed that these Co 4 &#8208;M&#8208;MOFs have the same framework structure, having the Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 clusters connected by metalloporphyrin units through Co&#9472;N pyridyl bonds. In the Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 cluster, the four Co II ions are chemically and symmetrically equivalent and are each coordinated with four sulfate O atoms to give a distorted cube&#8208;like structure. Electrocatalytic studies showed that these Co 4 &#8208;M&#8208;MOFs are all active for electrocatalytic OER and ORR. Importantly, by regulating the activity of the metalloporphyrin units, it is confirmed that the Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 cluster is active for oxygen electrocatalysis. With the use of Co porphyrins as connecting units, Co 4 &#8208;Co&#8208;MOF displays the highest electrocatalytic activity in this series of MOFs by showing a 10 mA cm &#8722;2 OER current density at 357 mV overpotential and an ORR half&#8208;wave potential at 0.83 V versus reversible hydrogen electrode (RHE). Theoretical studies revealed the synergistic effect of two proximal Co atoms in the Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 cluster in OER by facilitating the formation of O&#9472;O bonds. This work is of fundamental significance to present the construction of Co 4 (SO 4 ) 4 clusters in framework structures for oxygen electrocatalysis and to demonstrate the cooperation between two proximal Co atoms in such clusters during the O&#9472;O bond formation process.</description>
      <author>Zuozhong Liang, Guojun Zhou, Huang Tan, Yonghong Mou, Jieling Zhang, Hongbo Guo, Shujiao Yang, Haitao Lei, Haoquan Zheng, Wei Zhang, Haiping Lin, Rui Cao</author>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408094</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In-situ grown ternary metal hydroxides@3D oriented crumpled V2C MXene sheets for improved Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e35643</link>
      <description>Anum Iqbal, Hamzeh Sabouni, Nasser M. Hamdan, Heliyon. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401296732

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anum Iqbal, Hamzeh Sabouni, Nasser M. Hamdan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2024.e35643</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Is Pt dissolution a concern from the counter electrode in electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction?</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144824</link>
      <description>Xiang Lyu, Jun Yang, Alexey Serov, Electrochimica Acta. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401305159

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xiang Lyu, Jun Yang, Alexey Serov</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.electacta.2024.144824</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bifunctional Oxygen&#8208;Defect Bismuth Catalyst toward Concerted Production of H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; with over 150% Cell Faradaic Efficiency in Continuously Flowing Paired&#8208;Electrosynthesis System</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408341</link>
      <description>Qiqi Zhang, Changsheng Cao, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjie Xu, Xintao Wu, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu, Advanced Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401308478

                Abstract The electrosynthesis of hydrogen peroxide (H 2 O 2 ) from O 2 or H 2 O via the two&#8208;electron (2e &#8722; ) oxygen reduction (2e &#8722; ORR) or water oxidation (2e &#8722; WOR) reaction provides a green and sustainable alternative to the traditional anthraquinone process. Herein, a paired&#8208;electrosynthesis tactic is reported for concerted H 2 O 2 production at a high rate by coupling the 2e &#8722; ORR and 2e &#8722; WOR, in which the bifunctional oxygen&#8208;vacancy&#8208;enriched Bi 2 O 3 nanorods (O v &#8208;Bi 2 O 3 &#8208;EO), obtained through electrochemically oxidative reconstruction of Bi&#8208;based metal&#8211;organic framework (Bi&#8208;MOF) nanorod precursor, are used as both efficient anodic and cathodic electrocatalysts, achieving concurrent H 2 O 2 production at both electrodes with high Faradaic efficiencies. Specifically, the coupled 2e &#8722; ORR//2e &#8722; WOR electrolysis system based on such distinctive oxygen&#8208;defect Bi catalyst displays excellent performance for the paired&#8208;electrosynthesis of H 2 O 2 , delivering a remarkable cell Faradaic efficiency of 154.8% and an ultrahigh H 2 O 2 production rate of 4.3 mmol h &#8722;1 cm &#8722;2 . Experiments combined with theoretical analysis reveal the crucial role of oxygen vacancies in optimizing the adsorption of intermediates associated with the selective two&#8208;electron reaction pathways, thereby improving the activity and selectivity of the 2e &#8722; reaction processes at both electrodes. This work establishes a new paradigm for developing advanced electrocatalysts and designing novel paired&#8208;electrolysis systems for scalable and sustainable H 2 O 2 electrosynthesis.</description>
      <author>Qiqi Zhang, Changsheng Cao, Shenghua Zhou, Wei Wang, Xin Chen, Rongjie Xu, Xintao Wu, Qi&#8208;Long Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.202408341</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NiCo-LDH sheets and Ag3PO4 nanoparticles decorated on graphitic carbon nitride for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175860</link>
      <description>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Younghwan Im, Misook Kang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401311945

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Kotesh Kumar Mandari, Younghwan Im, Misook Kang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175860</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Amorphous/Crystalline Ni-Fe Based Electrodes with Rich Oxygen Vacancies Enable Highly Active Oxygen Evolution in Seawater Electrolysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916694</link>
      <description>Jingcheng Zhang, Xiulin Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401323219

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingcheng Zhang, Xiulin Ji, Chenhui Han, Li Zheng, Shanshan Jiang, Jie Yu, Daifen Chen, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4916694</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Progress and challenges in engineering the atomic structure of oxygen electrocatalysts for zinc-air batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154561</link>
      <description>Jinyeong Choi, Hyeokjun Jang, Jihan Park, Duho Han, Abhishek Lahiri, Pilgun Oh, Joohyuk Park, Minjoon Park, Chemical Engineering Journal. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326374

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jinyeong Choi, Hyeokjun Jang, Jihan Park, Duho Han, Abhishek Lahiri, Pilgun Oh, Joohyuk Park, Minjoon Park</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154561</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-Dimensional &#960;&#8211;d-Conjugated Cobalt-Based Metal&#8211;Organic Framework for Efficient Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02588</link>
      <description>Jing Wang, Zhe Chuan Feng, Yantao Wang, Junfeng Huang, Cailing Xu, Hua Li, ACS Applied Nano Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326994

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jing Wang, Zhe Chuan Feng, Yantao Wang, Junfeng Huang, Cailing Xu, Hua Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsanm.4c02588</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbon cloth supporting (CrMnFeCoCu)3O4 high entropy oxide as electrocatalyst for efficient oxygen evolution reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175874</link>
      <description>Xuanmeng He, Zeqin Zhang, Xianwei Jiang, Haibo Liu, Tengfei Xing, Xinzhen Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401327382

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Xuanmeng He, Zeqin Zhang, Xianwei Jiang, Haibo Liu, Tengfei Xing, Xinzhen Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175874</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electronic structure regulation of Fe-doped Ni2P nanocrystals towards durable electrocatalytic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02845-z</link>
      <description>Ya Liu, Xing Cao, Jia Li, Meisheng Han, Gaowei Zhang, Yubin Zhao, Huanhui Chen, Liang Yu, Junrong Zeng, Zhenbo Chen, Ya Liu, Lijuan Song, Yejun Qiu, Rare Metals. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401329786

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Ya Liu, Xing Cao, Jia Li, Meisheng Han, Gaowei Zhang, Yubin Zhao, Huanhui Chen, Liang Yu, Junrong Zeng, Zhenbo Chen, Ya Liu, Lijuan Song, Yejun Qiu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12598-024-02845-z</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Improving the electrocatalytic efficiency of hydrothermally developed ZnMnO3 with rGO for oxygen evolution reaction activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.372</link>
      <description>Mukhtiar Hussain, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, B.M. Alotaibi, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Imran Saleem, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401331983

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukhtiar Hussain, Albandari.W. Alrowaily, Haifa A. Alyousef, B.M. Alotaibi, Mohammed F. Alotiby, Muhammad Jahangir Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, Muhammad Imran Saleem</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.372</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Ozone Pollutant Elimination in N&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Electrolysis to Produce Nitrate with Reduced Reaction Steps</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405918</link>
      <description>Yaodong Yu, Jiao Liu, Mingzi Sun, Jiani Han, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Bolong Huang, Jianping Lai, Sheng Wang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337627

                Abstract The synthesis of nitrate by the electrochemical N 2 oxidation reaction (NOR) is currently one of the most promising routes. However, the traditional generation of nitrate depends on the oxidation reaction between N 2 and H 2 O (or &#183;OH), which involves complex reaction steps and intermediates, showing strong competition from oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Here, an effective NOR method is proposed to directly oxidize N 2 by using O 3 as a reactive oxygen source to reduce the reaction step. Electrochemical tests demonstrate that the nitrate yield of Pd&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 /CNT electrocatalyst reaches the milligram level, which is the highest yield reported so far for electrocatalytic NOR. Quantitative characterization is employed to establish a comprehensive set of benchmarks to confirm the intrinsic nature of nitrogen activation and test the O 3 &#8208;mediated reaction mechanism. Density functional theory (DFT) calculations show that the heterostructure Pd&#8208;Mn 3 O 4 leads to a strong adsorption preference for N 2 and O 3 , which greatly reduces the activation energy barrier for N 2 . This accelerates the synthesis of nitrate based on the direct formation mechanism, which reduces energy barriers and the reaction steps, thus increasing the performance of electrocatalytic nitrate production. The techno&#8208;economic analysis underscores the promising feasibility and sustainable economic value of the presented method.</description>
      <author>Yaodong Yu, Jiao Liu, Mingzi Sun, Jiani Han, Jing&#8208;Qi Chi, Bolong Huang, Jianping Lai, Sheng Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202405918</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontispiz: Amorphous MnRuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202483361</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li, Angewandte Chemie. 136(33)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401340700

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202483361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frontispiece: Amorphous MnRuO&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; Containing Microcrystalline for Enhanced Acidic Oxygen&#8208;Evolution Activity and Stability</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202483361</link>
      <description>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. 63(33)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401341005

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Jingjing Zhang, Liangliang Xu, Xiaoxuan Yang, Song Guo, Yifei Zhang, Yang Zhao, Gang Wu, Gao Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202483361</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review on chemisorbed oxyanions on electrocatalysts for efficient oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110089</link>
      <description>Han-Ming Zhang, Nano Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401344088

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Han-Ming Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.nanoen.2024.110089</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strong electronic coupling between Ni-based MOF and Ni2P enables high-efficiency oxygen evolution reaction for various application scenarios</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154483</link>
      <description>Yirong Wang, Xuan Yu, Zhonghong Xia, Xuanrong Li, Ya Gao, Jing Zhang, Wuliang Feng, Xingli Zou, Yufeng Zhao, Chemical Engineering Journal. 497(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401344671

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yirong Wang, Xuan Yu, Zhonghong Xia, Xuanrong Li, Ya Gao, Jing Zhang, Wuliang Feng, Xingli Zou, Yufeng Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.cej.2024.154483</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Activating lattice oxygen in local amorphous S-modified NiFe-LDH ultrathin nanosheets toward superior alkaline/natural seawater oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.031</link>
      <description>Shiwei Song, Yanhui Wang, Pengfei Tian, Jianbing Zang, Journal of Colloid and Interface Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351466

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Shiwei Song, Yanhui Wang, Pengfei Tian, Jianbing Zang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jcis.2024.08.031</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydrothermally Synthesized rGO/MnO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanohybrids as Superior Bifunctional Electrocatalysts for Oxygen and Hydrogen Evolution Reactions</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02192</link>
      <description>Simiyon Denisdon, P. Senthil Kumar, B. Chitra, R. Gayathri, Langmuir. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352112

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Simiyon Denisdon, P. Senthil Kumar, B. Chitra, R. Gayathri</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.langmuir.4c02192</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Water-Lotus-like Iridium&#8211;Cobalt Carbonate Hydroxides on Plasma-Treated Carbon Fibers for Enhanced Electrocatalytic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02591</link>
      <description>Yingpeng Xie, Jinfeng Qiu, Guangliang Chen, Yingchun Guo, Peisong Tang, Bin He, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401352734

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yingpeng Xie, Jinfeng Qiu, Guangliang Chen, Yingchun Guo, Peisong Tang, Bin He</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02591</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two-dimensional (2D) Oxysulfide nanosheets with sulfur-rich vacancy as an visible-light-driven difunctional photocatalyst for hydrogen and oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175898</link>
      <description>Hui Liang, Han Sun, Shuyu Jiang, Shu Cui, Fujiao Song, Lan Fan, Jia Gao, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354256

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hui Liang, Han Sun, Shuyu Jiang, Shu Cui, Fujiao Song, Lan Fan, Jia Gao</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175898</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ni/Ni-MoS2/Ni-MoS2-Fe3O4 multilayer electrode for oxygen evolution reaction in alkaline medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175901</link>
      <description>Wei Jiang, Junjie Li, Yuanlong Chen, Fankai Zhu, Jing Wang, Journal of Alloys and Compounds. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354375

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wei Jiang, Junjie Li, Yuanlong Chen, Fankai Zhu, Jing Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jallcom.2024.175901</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nickel&#8217;s Effect on Iron Oxide for Oxygen-Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04258</link>
      <description>Zahra Zand, Fatemeh Jafari, Maryam Gharedaghloo, Subhajit Nandy, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour, The Journal of Physical Chemistry C. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358416

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zahra Zand, Fatemeh Jafari, Maryam Gharedaghloo, Subhajit Nandy, Keun Hwa Chae, Mohammad Mahdi Najafpour</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.jpcc.4c04258</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring In Situ Kinetics of Oxygen Vacancy-Rich B/P-Incorporated Cobalt Oxide Nanowires for the Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00816</link>
      <description>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Maulik Patel, Henry Charlton, Rinkoo Bhabal, R. Fernandes, Rupali Patel, N. Patel, ACS Applied Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358503

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Aniruddha Bhide, Suraj Gupta, Maulik Patel, Henry Charlton, Rinkoo Bhabal, R. Fernandes, Rupali Patel, N. Patel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsaem.4c00816</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Production of oxygen via water oxidation using PANI@CuMn2O4 nanocomposite electrocatalyst for OER</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129803</link>
      <description>Hala M. Abo-Dief, Materials Chemistry and Physics. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401360175

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hala M. Abo-Dief</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.matchemphys.2024.129803</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Catalytic Performances of Metal-doped Ta2O5 Catalysts for Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction with Computations</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03554b</link>
      <description>Congcong Han, Tao Wang, Chemical Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401361496

                The design of stable and active alternative catalysts to iridium oxide for the anodic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) has been a long pursuit in acidic water splitting. Tantalum pentoxide (Ta2O5)...</description>
      <author>Congcong Han, Tao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4sc03554b</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j</link>
      <description>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401365414

                We firstly investigate the electrochemical dealloying effect and mechanism of a high-chromium alloy in alkaline NaNO3 solution under oxygen evolution potential. The electrochemical treatment can form dealloyed layers with Cr-enriched...</description>
      <author>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373364

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core&#8208;shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores&#8217; local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells&#8217; surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nimn2o4 Nanoflower Grown on Activated Carbon Derived from Tamarind Seed as Electrocatalysts for Oxygen Evolution Reactions and Energy Storage by Three-Electrode Measurements</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917324</link>
      <description>Anas Ramadan, Hamouda Adam Hamouda, N Al-Subaie, Yousif Shoaib Mohammed, Murtada Mohamed Edris, Nijuan Liu, Ruibin Guo, Anwar I. Alduma, Hebing Pei, Zunli Mo, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373593

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Anas Ramadan, Hamouda Adam Hamouda, N Al-Subaie, Yousif Shoaib Mohammed, Murtada Mohamed Edris, Nijuan Liu, Ruibin Guo, Anwar I. Alduma, Hebing Pei, Zunli Mo</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917324</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reconstruction of Ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic Cobalt&#8208;based Electrocatalysts under Gradient Magnetic Fields for Enhanced Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</link>
      <description>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376553

                The rational manipulation of the surface reconstruction of catalysts is a key factor in achieving highly efficient water oxidation, but it is a challenge due to the complex reaction conditions. Herein, we introduce a novel in situ reconstruction strategy under a gradient magnetic field to form highly catalytically active species on the surface of ferromagnetic/non&#8208;magnetic CoFe2O4@CoBDC core&#8208;shell structure for electrochemical oxygen evolution reaction (OER). We demonstrate that the Kelvin force from the cores&#8217; local gradient magnetic field modulates the shells&#8217; surface reconstruction, leading to a higher proportion of Co2+ as active sites. These Co sites with optimized electronic configuration exhibit more favorable adsorption energy for oxygen&#8208;containing intermediates and lower the activation energy of the overall catalytic reaction. As a result, a significant enhancement in OER performance is achieved with a large current density increment about 128% at 1.63 V and an overpotential reduction by 28 mV at 10 mA cm&#8208;2 after reconstruction. Interestingly, after removing the external magnetic field, the activity could persist for over 100 h. This work showcases the directional surface reconstruction of catalysts under a gradient magnetic field for enhanced water oxidation.</description>
      <author>Song Ma, Kaixi Wang, Moniba Rafique, Jiecai Han, Qiang Fu, Sida Jiang, Xianjie Wang, Tai Yao, Ping Xu, Bo Song</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202412821</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k</link>
      <description>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376763

                Trade-off between activity and durability of acidic oxygen evolution reaction (OER) catalysts is of key concern in the field of electrocatalysis. RuO2 delivers good activity but displays poor stability due...</description>
      <author>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances in Spin&#8208;Modulated Electrocatalysis of Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401073</link>
      <description>Tabassum Taspya, Rowshan Yeasmin Snigdha, Md. Mominul Islam, ChemistrySelect. 9(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401379797

                Abstract Electrochemical splitting of water for hydrogen generation has emerged as a potential strategy for transitioning towards renewable energy sources and mitigating the environmental impact of fossil fuel dependence. However, the efficiency of water splitting is mainly hindered by oxygen evolution reaction (OER) at the anode side, which involves kinetically sluggish four proton&#8208;coupled electron&#8208;transfer steps. Recent studies on OER demonstrate that a spin&#8208;dependent mechanism governs the reaction kinetics, wherein the electronic exchange interactions in the catalytic activity of transition metals can provide a spin&#8208;selective channel to filter out electron spins with the right orientation during the formation of O 2 . Maximizing efficiency and stability of such catalysts require optimization the geometric and electrical structures of transition metal systems. In addition, it is vital to understand the OER mechanism with spin considerations to be familiar with the connection between spin, charge, orbital, and lattice characteristics. This review focuses on current developments in understanding and the use of the spin&#8208;related effect in the OER mechanism.</description>
      <author>Tabassum Taspya, Rowshan Yeasmin Snigdha, Md. Mominul Islam</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401073</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381907

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381929

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381979

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381996

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382194

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382308

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Lihua Ning, Chunmei Yang, Guannan Jiang, Chenglin Wang, Shuaishuai Wang, Jing Wang, Huanxi Zheng, Xin Liu, Jiyu Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382356

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review3</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382382

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v1/review3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382447

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Decision letter for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v2/decision1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382481

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v2/decision1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Electrochemical Dealloying High-chromium Alloy Under Oxygen Evolution Potential"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review2</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382599

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta04441j/v1/review2</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Synergistic Effect of Two-Dimensional Heterostructure NiFeP@FeOOH as Stable Electrocatalyst for Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080511</link>
      <description>Qinglong Hou, Zhigang Jiang, Chen Wang, Shuhan Yang, Haizhen Liu, Bo Xing, Honghui Cheng, Kuikui Wang, Catalysts. 14(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401388575

                Introducing multiple active sites and constructing a heterostructure are efficient strategies to develop high-performance electrocatalysts. Herein, two-dimensional heterostructure NiFeP@FeOOH nanosheets supported by nickel foam (NF) are prepared by a hydrothermal&#8211;phosphorization&#8211;electrodeposition process. The synthesis of self-supporting heterostructure NiFeP@FeOOH nanosheets on NF increases the specific surface region, while bimetallic phosphide realizes rapid charge transfer, improving the electron transfer rate. The introduction of FeOOH and the construction of a heterostructure result in a synergistic effect among the components, and the surface-active sites are abundant. In situ Raman spectroscopy showed that the excellent oxygen evolution reaction (OER) performance was due to reconstruction-induced hydroxyl oxide, which achieved a multi-active site reaction. The NiFeP@FeOOH/NF electrocatalytic activity was then significantly improved. The findings indicate that in a 1.0 M KOH alkaline solution, NiFeP@FeOOH/NF showed an OER overpotential of 235 mV at 100 mA cm&#8722;2, a Tafel slope of 46.46 mV dec&#8722;1, and it worked stably at 50 mA cm&#8722;2 for 80 h. This research proves that constructing heterostructure and introducing FeOOH are of great significance to the study of the properties of OER electrocatalysts.</description>
      <author>Qinglong Hou, Zhigang Jiang, Chen Wang, Shuhan Yang, Haizhen Liu, Bo Xing, Honghui Cheng, Kuikui Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/catal14080511</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrocatalytic Activity of Sr-Doped Lanthanum Cobaltate for Oxygen Evolution Reaction in Alkaline Medium</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700253</link>
      <description>Basant Lal, Pankaj Chauhan, Russian Journal of Electrochemistry. 60(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401393531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Basant Lal, Pankaj Chauhan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1134/s1023193524700253</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ultrafast Joule heating-induced formation of amorphous CoFeNi phosphate for efficient and stable oxygen evolution reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03130j</link>
      <description>Junhao Ma, Chonghan Xia, Teddy Salim, Yee Yan Tay, Lydia Helena Wong, Kwan Wee Tan, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401395320

                A facile, rapid Joule heating protocol for forming amorphous-structured transition metal phosphate electrocatalysts with low overpotentials, fast kinetics, and long-term stability for oxygen evolution reaction (OER).</description>
      <author>Junhao Ma, Chonghan Xia, Teddy Salim, Yee Yan Tay, Lydia Helena Wong, Kwan Wee Tan</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta03130j</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Local Hydroxide Ion Enrichment at Inner Surface of Lacunaris Perovskite Nanotubes Facilitates Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02783c</link>
      <description>Lin-Bo Liu, Shuo Liu, Yufeng Tang, Yifei Sun, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing-Li Luo, Subiao Liu, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401395881

                Numerous strategies have been devised to optimize the intrinsic activity of perovskite oxides for oxygen evolution reaction (OER). However, conventional synthetic routes typically yield limited active sites and low mass...</description>
      <author>Lin-Bo Liu, Shuo Liu, Yufeng Tang, Yifei Sun, Xian&#8208;Zhu Fu, Jing-Li Luo, Subiao Liu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr02783c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Magnetic field-enhanced photoelectrochemical water splitting of Co3O4/TiO2 for efficient oxygen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3029-5</link>
      <description>Zhaohui Zhou, Yi L&#252;, Yixuan Liu, Shang Cao, Ge Tian, Zhi-Yi Hu, Ling Shen, Si-Ming Wu, Jie Ying, Wei Geng, Xiaoyu Yang, Science China Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401396775

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Zhaohui Zhou, Yi L&#252;, Yixuan Liu, Shang Cao, Ge Tian, Zhi-Yi Hu, Ling Shen, Si-Ming Wu, Jie Ying, Wei Geng, Xiaoyu Yang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40843-024-3029-5</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Corrigendum to &#8220;Effect of Sm dopant on electrocatalytic activity of AgNbO3 perovskite fabricated by sonication method for Oxygen Evaluation Reaction (OER)&#8221; [Int J Hydrogen Energy, 69, 5 June (2024), Pages 974&#8211;981]</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.454</link>
      <description>Mukhtiar Hussain, Meznah M. Alanazi, Saeed D. Alahmari, Muhammad Abdullah, Khurshid Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Gul N. Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi, International Journal of Hydrogen Energy. 82(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401406087

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Mukhtiar Hussain, Meznah M. Alanazi, Saeed D. Alahmari, Muhammad Abdullah, Khurshid Ahmad, A.M.A. Henaish, Gul N. Khan, Abdullah G. Al&#8208;Sehemi</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhydene.2024.07.454</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Construction of Co-Ni3b/Gdy Heterostructured Electrocatalyst for Boosting Oxygen Evolution in Alkaline Media</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917532</link>
      <description>Fuxiang Jing, Shixin Zhang, Honglei Shao, S Zhang, Pengfei Shi, Zhaomei Sun, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401407957

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Fuxiang Jing, Shixin Zhang, Honglei Shao, S Zhang, Pengfei Shi, Zhaomei Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4917532</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics Of Oxygen Evolution in a Thermally Stratified Reservoir Under Climate Warming</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4914468</link>
      <description>Bing Ma, Fei Dong, Wenqi Peng, Xiaobo Liu, Aiping Huang, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401241824

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Bing Ma, Fei Dong, Wenqi Peng, Xiaobo Liu, Aiping Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4914468</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting the Oxygen Evolution Reaction via the Reconstruction of M(OH)x/Fe3O4 Catalyst</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01574f</link>
      <description>Xiaoqu Wang, Limin Wang, Yongchun Liu, Raj Kumar, Jia Li, Qiulan Huang, Dujuan Huang, Youjun Fan, Du&#8208;Hong Chen, Wei Chen, Inorganic Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401375578

                For large-scale hydrogen production from electrocatalysis of water, the Ni- and/or Fe-based catalysts were commonly used but limited by the ultrahigh overpotential and poor stability at high current density (&gt;500...</description>
      <author>Xiaoqu Wang, Limin Wang, Yongchun Liu, Raj Kumar, Jia Li, Qiulan Huang, Dujuan Huang, Youjun Fan, Du&#8208;Hong Chen, Wei Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qi01574f</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RuO2/CoMo2Ox Catalyst with Low Ruthenium Loading for Long-Term Acidic Oxygen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12209-024-00405-1</link>
      <description>Sheng Wang, Xiongwei Zhong, Zhikun Liu, Kang-Lin Peng, Transactions of Tianjin University. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401207527

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Sheng Wang, Xiongwei Zhong, Zhikun Liu, Kang-Lin Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12209-024-00405-1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerated Proton Transfer in Asymmetric Active Units for Sustainable Acidic Oxygen Evolution Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05070</link>
      <description>Liming Deng, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Shuyi Liu, Sheng Zhao, Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Ai&#8208;Yin Wang, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Jian Peng, Rongpeng Ma, Lifang Jiao, Feng Hu, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng, Journal of the American Chemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401392192

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Liming Deng, Sung&#8208;Fu Hung, Shuyi Liu, Sheng Zhao, Zih&#8208;Yi Lin, Chenchen Zhang, Ying Zhang, Ai&#8208;Yin Wang, Han&#8208;Yi Chen, Jian Peng, Rongpeng Ma, Lifang Jiao, Feng Hu, Linlin Li, Shengjie Peng</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/jacs.4c05070</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review1</link>
      <description>, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401381838

                No abstract</description>
      <author/>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/review1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Author response for "Oxygen spillover from RuO2 to MoO3 enhances activity and durability of RuO2 for acidic oxygen evolution"</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/response1</link>
      <description>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401382190

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Wangyan Gou, Shishi Zhang, Yichen Wang, Xiaohe Tan, Liling Liao, Zening Qi, Min Xie, Yuanyuan Ma, Yaqiong Su, Yongquan Qu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee02549k/v2/response1</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Znal2se4/Xse2 (X= Ti, Zr, Hf) Heterostructures for the Efficient Photocatalytic Hydrogen and Oxygen Evolutions with Z-Schemes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4918293</link>
      <description>Hao Sun, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, Xiaohu Li, Yuliang Liu, Wenkai Zhao, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351494

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Hao Sun, Chuan&#8208;Lu Yang, Xiaohu Li, Yuliang Liu, Wenkai Zhao</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.2139/ssrn.4918293</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surface Defects, Ni3+ Species, Charge Transfer Resistance, and Surface Area dictate the Oxygen Evolution Reaction Activity of Mesoporous NiCo2O4 Thin Films</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400242</link>
      <description>Erik Dubai, Qingyang Wu, Stefan Lauterbach, Jan P. Hofmann, Marcus Einert, ChemNanoMat. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401393340

                NiCo2O4 has been proven to show high electrocatalytic activity, however facile and inexpensive techniques for preparation of this compound as mesostructured thin film is lacking. In this study, the sol&#8208;gel synthesis of nanocrystalline mesoporous spinel NiCo2O4 thin films by dip&#8208;coating and soft&#8208;templating using the evaporation&#8208;induced self&#8208;assembly approach is reported. The morphology and crystallographic structure were thoroughly probed by various physicochemical characterization techniques collectively validating the development of uniform mesoporous NiCo2O4 architectures crystallizing exclusively in the cubic spinel phase after calcination in air. The surface area of the thin films depended on the calcination temperature. XPS investigations showed that the amount of Ni3+ and defective oxygen species increased for decreasing calcination temperatures. The overall electrochemical surface area, Ni3+ content, charge transfer resistance, and amount of defective oxygen sites were found to collectively control the oxygen evolution reaction performance. After an optimized annealing procedure at 300&#176;C and chronopotentiometric analysis at 10 mA/cm2 for 1.5 h, a low overpotential of 330 mV vs. RHE at 10 mA/cm2 in alkaline solution was achieved. The results highlight the necessity of precise selection of the appropriate calcination temperature and electrochemical pre&#8208;treatment conditions for adjusting the concentration of electrocatalytically active reaction sites of sol&#8208;gel&#8208;derived NiCo2O4 thin films.</description>
      <author>Erik Dubai, Qingyang Wu, Stefan Lauterbach, Jan P. Hofmann, Marcus Einert</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cnma.202400242</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lattice-compatible piezoelectric modification for suppressing lattice oxygen evolution of Ni-rich cathode materials at high cut-off voltage</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103678</link>
      <description>Yizhen Huang, Dan Su, Lu Zheng, Guangchang Yang, Shuo Li, Juantao Jiang, Qichang Pan, Sijiang Hu, Yaohao Li, Qingyu Li, Xiaohui Zhang, Fenghua Zheng, Xing Ou, Energy storage materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401273531

                No abstract</description>
      <author>Yizhen Huang, Dan Su, Lu Zheng, Guangchang Yang, Shuo Li, Juantao Jiang, Qichang Pan, Sijiang Hu, Yaohao Li, Qingyu Li, Xiaohui Zhang, Fenghua Zheng, Xing Ou</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ensm.2024.103678</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of Oxygen Content of Graphene Oxide for Humidity Sensing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163741</link>
      <description>Shouxin Zhang, Guocheng Zhang, Fuke Wang, Hong Chi, Molecules. 29(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401390527

                Graphene oxide (GO) has shown significant potential in humidity sensing. It is well accepted that the oxygen-containing functional groups in GO significantly influence its humidity sensing performance. However, the relationship between the content of these groups and the humidity sensing capability of GO-based sensors remains unclear. In the present work, we investigate the role of oxygen-containing functional groups in the humidity sensing performance by oxidizing graphite with mesh numbers 80&#8211;120, 325, and 8000 using the Hummers method, resulting in GO-80, GO-325, and GO-8000. Infrared spectroscopy (IR) and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) were used to identify the types and quantification of oxygen-containing functional groups. Molecular dynamics simulation is used to simulate the adsorption energy, intercalation dynamics, and hydrogen bonding of water molecules. Electrochemical tests were used to compare the adsorption/desorption time and response sensitivity of graphene oxide to humidity. It is proposed that hydroxyl and carboxyl groups are the main contributing groups to humidity sensing. GO-8000 shows a relatively fast response time, but the large number of carboxyl groups will hinder intercalation of water molecules, thus exhibiting lower sensitivity. This research provides a reference for the future development of graphene-based sensors, catalysts, and environmental materials.</description>
      <author>Shouxin Zhang, Guocheng Zhang, Fuke Wang, Hong Chi</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163741</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oxidation Evolution and Activity Origin of N-Doped Carbon in the Oxygen Reduction Reaction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s12209-024-00406-0</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Wu, Chuanqi Cheng, Shanshan Lu, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi, Transactions of Tianjin University. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401213777

                Abstract N-doped carbon materials, with their applications as electrocatalysts for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR), have been extensively studied. However, a negletcted fact is that the operating potential of the ORR is higher than the theoretical oxidation potential of carbon, possibly leading to the oxidation of carbon materials. Consequently, the influence of the structural oxidation evolution on ORR performance and the real active sites are not clear. In this study, we discover a two-step oxidation process of N-doped carbon during the ORR. The first oxidation process is caused by the applied potential and bubbling oxygen during the ORR, leading to the oxidative dissolution of N and the formation of abundant oxygen-containing functional groups. This oxidation process also converts the reaction path from the four-electron (4e) ORR to the two-electron (2e) ORR. Subsequently, the enhanced 2e ORR generates oxidative H 2 O 2 , which initiates the second stage of oxidation to some newly formed oxygen-containing functional groups, such as quinones to dicarboxyls, further diversifying the oxygen-containing functional groups and making carboxyl groups as the dominant species. We also reveal the synergistic effect of multiple oxygen-containing functional groups by providing additional opportunities to access active sites with optimized adsorption of OOH*, thus leading to high efficiency and durability in electrocatalytic H 2 O 2 production.</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Wu, Chuanqi Cheng, Shanshan Lu, Bin Zhang, Yanmei Shi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s12209-024-00406-0</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of fuel dosage in self-propagation combustion: Evolution of BiOCl to BiOCl/Bi24O31Cl10 heterojunction enriched with oxygen vacancies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj02709d</link>
      <description>Lei Han, Wenjun Zhang, Meng Chen, New Journal of Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401225223

                BiOCl has garnered considerable attention recently. However, its relatively wide bandgap and poor separation efficiency of charge carriers limit its application in the visible light range. Introducing oxygen vacancies (OVs)...</description>
      <author>Lei Han, Wenjun Zhang, Meng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nj02709d</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microstructural evolution of the inner oxide layer of a Si-modified austenitic stainless steel exposed to oxygen-saturated lead-bismuth eutectic (LBE): toward the origin of LBE penetration</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112350</link>
      <description>Ang Xie, Shenghu Chen, Lichang Yin, Neng He, Chunlin Chen, Lijian Rong, Corrosion Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401376089

                Microstructural evolution of inner oxide layer of a Si-modified austenitic stainless steel exposed to oxygen-saturated static lead-bismuth eutectic (LBE) at 550 &#176;C up to 3000 h has been investigated. A dual-phase separated structure consisting of Fe-Cr spinel and (Fe, Cr)1-xNix phase is formed in inner oxide layer, attributed to partitioning of Ni and Cr associated with Fe-Cr spinel formation. SiO2 is preferentially formed preceding the Fe-Cr spinel at internal oxidation frontier, leading to dispersed SiO2 nanoparticles within Fe-Cr spinel. The mechanism of LBE penetration into inner oxide layer is further developed based on preferable dissolution process of (Fe, Cr)1-xNix phase.</description>
      <author>Ang Xie, Shenghu Chen, Lichang Yin, Neng He, Chunlin Chen, Lijian Rong</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.corsci.2024.112350</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A novel structure Ti/Fe&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;/Cu&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;S/Co(OH)&lt;sub&gt;x&lt;/sub&gt; enhances the photoelectrochemical water splitting performance of iron oxide</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2023.68</link>
      <description>Hao-Yan Shi, Yanxin Chen, Ming-Hao Ji, Qian-Qian Zhou, K. Li, Sheng Wang, Rui Chen, Xiu&#8208;Mei Lin, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu, Chemical Synthesis. 4(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401402237

                The slow oxygen evolution kinetics of iron oxide nanorod arrays have limited their applications in photocatalytic water splitting. Herein, we introduce p-type semiconductor cuprous oxide and further cover cobalt hydroxide ultrathin nanosheets on the surface of both by electrochemical deposition; these methods obviously enhanced the photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting performance of iron oxide nanorods on titanium sheet substrate. The photocurrent of this heterostructure reached 4.8 mA/cm2 at 1.23 V (vs. reversible hydrogen electrode) in a 1 M KOH aqueous solution under AM 1.5G illumination, which is much higher than the currently reported photocatalytic water splitting performance of iron oxide nanoarrays. The construction of Fe2O3/Cu2S p-n heterojunction accelerates the separation of photogenerated carriers in the main body of Fe2O3 nanorod arrays; as an excellent oxygen evolution catalyst (OEC), the introduction of Co(OH)x accelerates the kinetic process of interfacial water oxidation leading to the rapid depletion of photogenerated holes, which further improves the charge separation on the photoanode surface. Thus, the synergistic effect between Fe2O3/Cu2S p-n heterojunctions and oxygen evolution catalysts enhanced the iron oxide nanorod array photoanodes.</description>
      <author>Hao-Yan Shi, Yanxin Chen, Ming-Hao Ji, Qian-Qian Zhou, K. Li, Sheng Wang, Rui Chen, Xiu&#8208;Mei Lin, Can&#8208;Zhong Lu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.20517/cs.2023.68</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Structural Tuning of BiVO4/MnFe-MOF Photoanodes Boosts Hole Extraction for Photoelectrochemical Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00836g</link>
      <description>Chenchen Feng, L.L. Liu, Houyu Fu, Faqi Zhan, Henan Jia, Xiang Cheng, Fucheng Yu, Qi Zhou, Zheng Bian, Beibei Zhang, Catalysis Science &amp; Technology. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401373580

                To achieve extremely effective photoelectrochemical (PEC) water splitting, it is imperative to suppress charge recombination at the interfaces between the oxygen evolution cocatalyst (OEC) and BiVO4. In view of this,...</description>
      <author>Chenchen Feng, L.L. Liu, Houyu Fu, Faqi Zhan, Henan Jia, Xiang Cheng, Fucheng Yu, Qi Zhou, Zheng Bian, Beibei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4cy00836g</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rational design of nanoscale stabilized oxide catalysts for OER with OC22</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01390e</link>
      <description>Richard Tran, Liqiang Huang, Yuan Zi, Lars C. Grabow, Benjamin M. Comer, Xuqing Wu, Stefan J. Raaijman, Nishant K. Sinha, Sajanikumari Sadasivan, Shibin Thundiyil, Kuldeep Mamtani, Ganesh Iyer, Lars C. Grabow, Ligang Lu, Jiefu Chen, Nanoscale. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401379356

                The efficiency of H 2 production via water electrolysis is typically limited to the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER). As such, significant emphasis has been placed upon improving the rate of...</description>
      <author>Richard Tran, Liqiang Huang, Yuan Zi, Lars C. Grabow, Benjamin M. Comer, Xuqing Wu, Stefan J. Raaijman, Nishant K. Sinha, Sajanikumari Sadasivan, Shibin Thundiyil, Kuldeep Mamtani, Ganesh Iyer, Lars C. Grabow, Ligang Lu, Jiefu Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4nr01390e</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Alkaline Water Splitting Efficiency: NiOOH-MnOOH Heterojunctions via In Situ Anodic Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00512k</link>
      <description>Yuru Zhou, Jing Hu, You&#8208;Nian Liu, Wen Fan, panpan tao, Jing Wang, Haitao Huang, Xun Cao, Haijin Li, Siwei Li, Materials Chemistry Frontiers. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401357428

                Designing noble metal-free electrocatalysts remains a challenge for oxygen evolution reactions (OER) in alkaline solutions. In this study, we present a facile electrodeposition approach coupled with an in-situ anodic oxidation...</description>
      <author>Yuru Zhou, Jing Hu, You&#8208;Nian Liu, Wen Fan, panpan tao, Jing Wang, Haitao Huang, Xun Cao, Haijin Li, Siwei Li</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4qm00512k</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Suppressing Product Crossover and C-C Bond Cleavage in a Glycerol Membrane Electrode Assembly Reformer</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee01824a</link>
      <description>Chencheng Dai, Qian Wu, Tianze Wu, Shouxin Zhang, Libo Sun, Xiaogang Wang, Adrian C. Fisher, Zhichuan J. Xu, Energy &amp; Environmental Science. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401234420

                Generating hydrogen through water electrolysis is impeded by high costs and substantial energy consumption mainly due to high equilibrium potential and sluggish kinetics of the oxygen evolution reaction (OER). Glycerol...</description>
      <author>Chencheng Dai, Qian Wu, Tianze Wu, Shouxin Zhang, Libo Sun, Xiaogang Wang, Adrian C. Fisher, Zhichuan J. Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ee01824a</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Probing Electrocatalytic Synergy in Graphene/MoS&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;/Nickel Networks for Water Splitting through a Combined Experimental and Theoretical Lens</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08869</link>
      <description>Dipankar Saha, Ayush Bhardwaj, Jiacheng Wang, Varun Pande, Robert Hengstebeck, Peng Bai, James J. Watkins, ACS Applied Materials &amp; Interfaces. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401256725

                The development of low-cost and active electrocatalysts signifies an important effort toward accelerating economical water electrolysis and overcoming the sluggish hydrogen or oxygen evolution reaction (HER or OER) kinetics. Herein, we report a scalable and rapid synthesis of inexpensive Ni and MoS</description>
      <author>Dipankar Saha, Ayush Bhardwaj, Jiacheng Wang, Varun Pande, Robert Hengstebeck, Peng Bai, James J. Watkins</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acsami.4c08869</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tuning Iron Active Sites of FeOOH via Al&lt;sup&gt;3+&lt;/sup&gt; and Heteroatom Doping&#8208;Induced Asymmetric Oxygen Vacancy Electronic Structure for Efficient Alkaline Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404552</link>
      <description>Jiaqi Lv, Ying&#8208;Fei Chang, Xinyu Chen, Jinyu Guo, Jing Sun, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Hong&#8208;Ying Zang, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358383

                Oxygen evolution reaction is the essential anodic reaction for water splitting. Designing tunable electronic structures to overcome its slow kinetics is an effective strategy. Herein, the molecular ammonium iron sulfate dodecahydrate is employed as the precursor to synthesize the C, N, S triatomic co-doped Fe(Al)OOH on Ni foam (C,N,S-Fe(Al)OOH-NF) with asymmetric electronic structure. Both in situ oxygen vacancies and their special electronic configuration enable the electron transfer between the d-p orbitals and get the increase of OER activity. Density functional theory calculation further indicates the effect of electronic structure on catalytic activity and stability at the oxygen vacancies. In alkaline solution, the catalyst C,N,S-Fe(Al)OOH-NF shows good catalytic activity and stability for water splitting. For OER, the overpotential of 10 mA cm</description>
      <author>Jiaqi Lv, Ying&#8208;Fei Chang, Xinyu Chen, Jinyu Guo, Jing Sun, Zhong&#8208;Min Su, Hong&#8208;Ying Zang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202404552</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Perovskite oxides as electrocatalysts for water electrolysis: From crystalline to amorphous</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.595</link>
      <description>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Hao Ming Chen, Zongping Shao, Carbon Energy. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401254700

                Abstract Crystalline perovskite oxides are regarded as promising electrocatalysts for water electrolysis, particularly for anodic oxygen evolution reactions, owing to their low cost and high intrinsic activity. Perovskite oxides with noncrystalline or amorphous characteristics also exhibit promising electrocatalytic performance toward electrochemical water splitting. In this review, a fundamental understanding of the characteristics and advantages of crystalline, noncrystalline, and amorphous perovskite oxides is presented. Subsequently, recent progress in the development of advanced electrocatalysts for water electrolysis by engineering and breaking the crystallinity of perovskite oxides is reviewed, with a special focus on the underlying structure&#8211;activity relationships. Finally, the remaining challenges and unsolved issues are presented, and an outlook is briefly proposed for the future exploration of next&#8208;generation water&#8208;splitting electrocatalysts based on perovskite oxides.</description>
      <author>Hainan Sun, Xiaomin Xu, Hao Ming Chen, Zongping Shao</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cey2.595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rod&#8208;Shaped Au@Ce Nano&#8208;Platforms for Enhancing Photodynamic Tumor Collaborative Therapy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400945</link>
      <description>Yuxiang Sun, Ziqi Cao, Xiaoli Zhang, Xingchen Zhu, Zhenyang Xu, Huaichun Zhou, Xiaoer Wei, Wenxian Du, Li Xu, Small Methods. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401308457

                Abstract Tumor photodynamic therapy (PDT) relies on intratumoral free radicals, while the limited oxygen source and the depletion of tissue oxygen may exacerbate the hypoxia. As the treatment progresses, there will eventually be a problem of insufficient free radicals. Here, it is found that Au@CeO 2 nano&#8208;rods (Au@Ce NRs), assembled by gold nano&#8208;rods (Au NRs) and ceria nanoparticles (CeO 2 NPs), can efficaciously absorb near&#8208;infrared light (NIR) to promote the release of oxygen and free radicals. Au@Ce NRs exhibit a higher proportion of Ce 3+ (Ce 2 O 3 ) after oxygen release, while Ce 3+ is subsequently oxidized to Ce 4+ (CeO 2 ) by trace H 2 O 2 . Interestingly, Au@Ce NRs re&#8208;oxidized by trace H 2 O 2 can re&#8208;releasing oxygen and free radicals again upon NIR treatment, achieving oxygenation/oxygen evolution, similar to charging/discharging. This loop maximizes the conversion of limited oxygen source into highly cytotoxic free radicals. As a result, when B16&#8208;F10 cells are treated by NIR/Au@Ce NRs, more tumor cells undergo apoptosis, consistent with the higher level of free radicals. Importantly, NIR/Au@Ce NRs successfully suppresses tumor growth and promotes the generation of epidermal collagen fibers in the transplanted tumor model. Therefore, the rod&#8208;shaped Au@Ce NRs provide an ideal platform for maximizing the utilization of intratumoral oxygen sources and improving the treatment of melanoma.</description>
      <author>Yuxiang Sun, Ziqi Cao, Xiaoli Zhang, Xingchen Zhu, Zhenyang Xu, Huaichun Zhou, Xiaoer Wei, Wenxian Du, Li Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smtd.202400945</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Light and Electrode Polarization on BiVO&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; and TiO&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Photoanodes for Glycerol Oxidation.</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6bc3</link>
      <description>Mart&#237; Molera, M. Sarret, Cristian F&#225;brega, Teresa Andreu, Journal of The Electrochemical Society. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401351802

                Abstract In recent years, there has been a growing interest in the photoelectrochemical oxidation of glycerol to produce high-value products. Most studies have focused solely on the photocatalytic properties of the electrodes, overlooking their electrocatalytic properties and the different products obtained under dark conditions. Our work aims to address this gap by comparing the electrocatalytic activity under dark and light conditions to determine whether light influences the reactivity of the electrodes or if it just reduces the overpotential of the reaction. To achieve this, we employed two model semiconductors, TiO2 and BiVO4. We have analyzed their polarization curves under both dark and light conditions and evaluated the competence of glycerol oxidation reaction with the oxygen evolution reaction. Furthermore, we conducted long-term (photo)electrolysis revealing the beneficial role of light on the electrolytic process, as it enables the obtention of C3 products on illuminated TiO2 photoanodes at low electrode polarization, comparable to the performance of BiVO4.</description>
      <author>Mart&#237; Molera, M. Sarret, Cristian F&#225;brega, Teresa Andreu</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1149/1945-7111/ad6bc3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the Power of &lt;scp&gt;PM6&lt;/scp&gt;:&lt;scp&gt;Y6&lt;/scp&gt; Semitransparent Photoanodes by Computational Balancement of Photon Absorption in Photoanode/Photovoltaic Organic Tandems: &amp;gt;7 &lt;scp&gt;mA&lt;/scp&gt; cm&lt;sup&gt;&#8722;2&lt;/sup&gt; Solar Synthetic Fuels Production at Bias&#8208;Free Potentials</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12809</link>
      <description>Francisco Bernal&#8208;Texca, Emmanouela Andrioti, Jordi Martorell, Carles Ros, Energy &amp; environment materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401230065

                This study first demonstrates the potential of organic photoabsorbing blends in overcoming a critical limitation of metal oxide photoanodes in tandem modules: insufficient photogenerated current. Various organic blends, including PTB7&#8208;Th:FOIC, PTB7&#8208;Th:O6T&#8208;4F, PM6:Y6, and PM6:FM, were systematically tested. When coupled with electron transport layer (ETL) contacts, these blends exhibit exceptional charge separation and extraction, with PM6:Y6 achieving saturation photocurrents up to 16.8 mA cm &#8722;2 at 1.23 V RHE (oxygen evolution thermodynamic potential). For the first time, a tandem structure utilizing organic photoanodes has been computationally designed and fabricated and the implementation of a double PM6:Y6 photoanode/photovoltaic structure resulted in photogenerated currents exceeding 7 mA cm &#8722;2 at 0 V RHE (hydrogen evolution thermodynamic potential) and anodic current onset potentials as low as &#8722;0.5 V RHE . The herein&#8208;presented organic&#8208;based approach paves the way for further exploration of different blend combinations to target specific oxidative reactions by selecting precise donor/acceptor candidates among the multiple existing ones.</description>
      <author>Francisco Bernal&#8208;Texca, Emmanouela Andrioti, Jordi Martorell, Carles Ros</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/eem2.12809</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nitrogen-Tungsten Oxide Nanostructures on Nickel Foam as High Efficient Electrocatalysts for Benzyl Alcohol Oxidation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163734</link>
      <description>Yizhen Zhu, Xiangyu Chen, Yuanyao Zhang, Zhifei Zhu, Handan Chen, Kejie Chai, Weiming Xu, Molecules. 29(16)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401394143

                Electrocatalytic alcohol oxidation (EAO) is an attractive alternative to the sluggish oxygen evolution reaction in electrochemical hydrogen evolution cells. However, the development of high-performance bifunctional electrocatalysts is a major challenge. Herein, we developed a nitrogen-doped bimetallic oxide electrocatalyst (WO-N/NF) by a one-step hydrothermal method for the selective electrooxidation of benzyl alcohol to benzoic acid in alkaline electrolytes. The WO-N/NF electrode features block-shaped particles on a rough, inhomogeneous surface with cracks and lumpy nodules, increasing active sites and enhancing electrolyte diffusion. The electrode demonstrates exceptional activity, stability, and selectivity, achieving efficient benzoic acid production while reducing the electrolysis voltage. A low onset potential of 1.38 V (vs. RHE) is achieved to reach a current density of 100 mA cm&#8722;2 in 1.0 M KOH electrolyte with only 0.2 mmol of metal precursors, which is 396 mV lower than that of water oxidation. The analysis reveals a yield, conversion, and selectivity of 98.41%, 99.66%, and 99.74%, respectively, with a Faradaic efficiency of 98.77%. This work provides insight into the rational design of a highly active and selective catalyst for electrocatalytic alcohol oxidation.</description>
      <author>Yizhen Zhu, Xiangyu Chen, Yuanyao Zhang, Zhifei Zhu, Handan Chen, Kejie Chai, Weiming Xu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/molecules29163734</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Defect Engineering of Nickel-Based Compounds for Energy-Saving H2 Production</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153801</link>
      <description>Yi Zeng, Xueqiang Qi, Shun Lu, Mohamed N. Khalil, Xiuxiu Dong, Haoqi Wang, Energies. 17(15)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401252488

                The urea oxidation reaction (UOR), requiring less energy to produce hydrogen, is considered as a potential alternative to the traditional oxygen evolution reaction. Consequently, developing highly efficient UOR catalysts to facilitate H2 production has garnered widespread attention. A promising approach to enhancing the effectiveness of these electrocatalysts is defect engineering. By introducing structural defects, defect engineering can expose more active sites and optimize their electronic structure, thereby improving their activity. This work offers a comprehensive overview of recent progress in defect engineering of nickel-based electrocatalysts for the UOR. It summarizes various strategies for generating defects, including the creation of vacancies, doping, the incorporation of single atoms, amorphization, and achieving high refractivity. Furthermore, we discuss the advanced characterization techniques commonly used to identify the presence of defects in these electrocatalysts, as well as to determine their detailed structures. Finally, we outline the prospects and challenges associated with the systematic design and fabrication of novel UOR electrocatalysts with tunable defects, aiming to further enhance their efficiency and stability.</description>
      <author>Yi Zeng, Xueqiang Qi, Shun Lu, Mohamed N. Khalil, Xiuxiu Dong, Haoqi Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/en17153801</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metal&#8211;Organic Framework with Dual Excitation Pathways as Efficient Bifunctional Catalyst for Photo&#8208;assisted Li&#8211;O&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Batteries</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403683</link>
      <description>Yinglei Tao, Xiaoli Fan, Xingyu Yu, Ke Gong, Yujiao Xia, Hao Gong, Haixia Chen, Xianli Huang, Aidi Zhang, Tao Wang, Jianping He, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401384592

                Abstract Li&#8211;O 2 batteries (LOBs) have sparked significant interest due to their fascinating high theoretical energy density. However, the large overpotential for the formation and oxidation of Li 2 O 2 during charge and discharge process seriously hinders the further development and application of LOBs. In this work, metal&#8211;organic frameworks (MOFs) with different metal clusters (Fe, Ti, Zr) are successfully synthesized, and they are employed as the photoelectrodes for the photo&#8208;assisted LOBs. The special dual excitation pathways of Fe&#8208;MOF under illumination and the superior separation efficiency of photocarriers, which significantly enhance the activation of O 2 /Li 2 O 2 , improving the catalytic activity of oxygen reduction reaction and oxygen evolution reaction. Moreover, compared to traditional inorganic semiconductor crystals, Fe&#8208;MOF exhibits large specific surface area and excellent O 2 adsorption ability. Therefore, the LOB with Fe&#8208;MOF as the cathode exhibits large specific capacity, ultralow charge/discharge overpotential of 0.22 V at 0.05 mA cm &#8722;2 and excellent stability of 195 cycles under illumination. This study provides an environmentally friendly and highly efficient photocatalyst for LOBs, and a new strategy for designing photoelectrodes.</description>
      <author>Yinglei Tao, Xiaoli Fan, Xingyu Yu, Ke Gong, Yujiao Xia, Hao Gong, Haixia Chen, Xianli Huang, Aidi Zhang, Tao Wang, Jianping He</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403683</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electrosynthesis of Amides through Cu- and Co-Incorporated Nickel Hydroxide-Catalyzed Oxidation of Primary Amines Coupled with Hydrogen Evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02797</link>
      <description>Manman Song, Minghui Feng, Zheng Chen, Shanshan Lv, Yan Zhou, Zheng Chen, Inorganic Chemistry. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401212320

                The electrocatalytic oxidation of organic molecules coupled with hydrogen evolution reaction can reduce overpotential and can be connected in series with nonelectrochemical processes to achieve the preparation of more high-value compounds. Herein, Cu- and Co-incorporated nickel hydroxide (CuCo&#8211;Ni(OH)2) was synthesized and applied to the anodic benzylamine oxidation reaction, which is 280 mV lower than the corresponding oxygen evolution reaction to reach the current density of 50 mA cm&#8211;2. When the electrocatalytic oxidation of benzylamine and hydrogen evolution reaction are coupled to form an electrolytic cell, the potential to reach 10 mA cm&#8211;2 is reduced by 197 mV compared to the overall water splitting. The benzylamine is converted to benzamide with 99.3% conversion and 90.2% faraday efficiency under 1.45 V constant voltage electrolysis, and the catalytic performance remains at a high level after 4 cycles. The characterization and density functional theory calculations show that Cu and Co share the transfer charge from Ni, making it easy for CuCo&#8211;Ni(OH)2 to deprotonate Ni&#8211;O* sites. The formed Ni&#8211;O* sites exhibit lower energy barriers in the proton transfer of benzylamine to benzonitrile and hydration intermediates, resulting in a better catalytic performance of CuCo&#8211;Ni(OH)2 than Ni(OH)2 in the electrocatalytic oxidation of benzylamine to benzamide.</description>
      <author>Manman Song, Minghui Feng, Zheng Chen, Shanshan Lv, Yan Zhou, Zheng Chen</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1021/acs.inorgchem.4c02797</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A quantitative description of light-limited cyanobacterial growth using flux balance analysis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012280</link>
      <description>Rune H&#246;per, Daria Komkova, Tom&#225;&#353; Zav&#345;el, Ralf Steuer, PLoS Computational Biology. 20(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401328669

                The metabolism of phototrophic cyanobacteria is an integral part of global biogeochemical cycles, and the capability of cyanobacteria to assimilate atmospheric CO 2 into organic carbon has manifold potential applications for a sustainable biotechnology. To elucidate the properties of cyanobacterial metabolism and growth, computational reconstructions of genome-scale metabolic networks play an increasingly important role. Here, we present an updated reconstruction of the metabolic network of the cyanobacterium Synechocystis sp. PCC 6803 and its quantitative evaluation using flux balance analysis (FBA). To overcome limitations of conventional FBA, and to allow for the integration of experimental analyses, we develop a novel approach to describe light absorption and light utilization within the framework of FBA. Our approach incorporates photoinhibition and a variable quantum yield into the constraint-based description of light-limited phototrophic growth. We show that the resulting model is capable of predicting quantitative properties of cyanobacterial growth, including photosynthetic oxygen evolution and the ATP/NADPH ratio required for growth and cellular maintenance. Our approach retains the computational and conceptual simplicity of FBA and is readily applicable to other phototrophic microorganisms.</description>
      <author>Rune H&#246;per, Daria Komkova, Tom&#225;&#353; Zav&#345;el, Ralf Steuer</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pcbi.1012280</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noble Metal&#8208;Free High Entropy Perovskite Oxide with High Cationic Dispersion Enhanced Oxygen Redox Reactivity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401836</link>
      <description>Arindam Chatterjee, Dipsikha Ganguly, S. Ramaprabhu, Subramshu S. Bhattacharya, ChemistrySelect. 9(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401363653

                Abstract High entropy perovskite oxide (HEPO) materials have received significant interest as efficient electrocatalysts owing to their chemical and structural stability, effective interaction of multiple metal active sites with the reaction intermediate species resulting in enhanced catalytic activity. The effect of high&#8208;entropy strategy could achieve the regulation of the structural durability by tailoring the composition. Herein, we design a novel transition metal and rare&#8208;earth metal based high entropy perovskite oxide (Co 0.11 Mn 0.11 Ni 0.11 Fe 0.14 La 0.13 Nd 0.13 Gd 0.13 Pr 0.13 )O 3, showing superior catalytic activity in the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) and also promising electrocatalyst in oxygen evolution reaction (OER). High degree of cationic dispersion in the lattice and multiple electrocatalytic active sites enhance the oxygen ion migration at the surface and facilitate electron transfer, manifesting good ORR performance. Notably, the as&#8208;prepared high entropy material exhibits onset and half&#8208;wave potential of 1.02 V and 0.89 V versus RHE, respectively, exceeding the performance of the benchmarked Pt/C catalyst in the ORR process with reasonable redox kinetics. Moreover, the material also presents faster kinetics with reasonably low overpotential and excellent electrochemical stability in the OER process as well. This study shows the viability of designing non&#8208;precious high entropy materials as highly efficient oxide electrocatalyst by utilizing its broad compositional space.</description>
      <author>Arindam Chatterjee, Dipsikha Ganguly, S. Ramaprabhu, Subramshu S. Bhattacharya</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202401836</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hollow Fe&#8208;Doped Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;&#8211;NiS@Ni(OH)&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Nanorod Array with Regulated Heterostructural Interface and Band Structure for Expediting Alkaline Electrocatalytic Overall Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409849</link>
      <description>Ruidong Shi, Yuanting Li, Xiaoxin Xu, Xue Wang, Gongbing Zhou, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401260932

                Abstract Aiming to efficiently expedite alkaline overall water splitting (OWS) by addressing challenges such as sluggish kinetics and limited stability, a hollow Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 &#8208;NiS@Ni(OH) 2 nanorod array with surface nanosheets is devised, featuring a high&#8208;index Fe&#8208;doped Ni(OH) 2 (101)&#8208;NiS(211) heterostructural interface and an upshifted d &#8208;band center. This nanoarchitecture intensifies the adsorption and interaction of H 2 O and OH &#8722; reactants on the electrocatalyst surface, suitably bonds the * H intermediate in hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and accelerates electron movement of * H, minimizes the energy requirement of the rate&#8208;limiting phase ( * OH &#8594; * O) in oxygen evolution reaction (OER) by facilitating O&#9472;H cleavage of * OH and optimally adsorbs * O, amplifies the exposure of surface&#8208;active centers, and ultimately reduces the apparent activation energy. Consequently, the overpotentials are as low as 66.4 mV (HER) and 254.9 mV (OER) at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 , alongside high turnover frequencies of 142 s &#8722;1 (H 2 ) and 279 s &#8722;1 (O 2 ) at 100 and 300 mV, respectively, markedly outperforming direct&#8208;electrodeposited analogues. When functioning as a bifunctional electrode in OWS, this material merely requires 1.57 V at 10 mA cm &#8722;2 and sustains an operation for 168 h, approaching Pt/C||RuO 2 benchmark.</description>
      <author>Ruidong Shi, Yuanting Li, Xiaoxin Xu, Xue Wang, Gongbing Zhou</author>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202409849</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Produksi Hidrogen Dari Air Laut Menggunakan Metode Elektrolisis Berbantuan Elektrokatalis</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.14710/jebt.2024.23562</link>
      <description>Febiana Natasha, Ezra Solafide Hutajulu, Hilfi Pardi, Jurnal Energi Baru dan Terbarukan. 5(2)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401279225

                Hidrogen berpotensi sebagai sumber energi bersih yang ideal untuk menurunkan emisi karbondioksida di masa depan. Hal ini dikarenakan hidrogen memiliki kepadatan energi yang tinggi sekitar 142.351 MJ/kg dan bebas dari gas beracun. Oleh karena itu, diperkirakan permintaan hidrogen akan meningkat sekitar 18% pada tahun 2050 untuk memenuhi kebutuhan energi pengganti bahan bakar fosil. Tujuan penelitian, yakni untuk merangkum reaksi-reaksi redoks pada elektroda dalam metode elektrolisis udara laut, menampilkan berbagai elektrokatalis dalam memproduksi hidrogen dari udara laut, dan elektrolisis sebagai media pendukung berlangsungnya proses produksi hidrogen air laut. Hasil yang ditampilkan adalah adanya 3 reaksi redoks dalam elektrolisis udara laut yang terdiri atas Oxygen Evolution Reaction (OER), Chlorine Evolution Reaction (CER), dan Hydrogen Evolution Reaction (HER). Adapun elektrokatalis yang efisien dalam mendukung reaksi HER sebanyak 25 buah. Selain itu, terdapat 4 elektrolit yang mendukung kinerja dari reaksi elektrolisis udara laut dalam memproduksi hidrogen adalah H 2 SO 4 , NaCl, KOH dan NaOH. Oleh karena itu, pengembangan hidrogen dari air laut secara lebih lanjut patut dikembangkan guna mewujudkan Net Zero Emission.</description>
      <author>Febiana Natasha, Ezra Solafide Hutajulu, Hilfi Pardi</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.14710/jebt.2024.23562</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pushing the Operation Current Density of Alkaline Water Oxidation above 1 A cm&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; via Electrocatalyst Engineering</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402034</link>
      <description>Wen&#8208;Yan Zhang, Kunyan Wang, Lei Tan, Faiza Meharban, Sheng Wang, Xiaopeng Li, Chao Lin, Wei Luo, Advanced Energy Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401358181

                Abstract Rapid cost reduction of green hydrogen is essential for the large&#8208;scale deployment of hydrogen&#8208;based energy system. A major component in achieving this is the development of advanced water electrolyzers. Sluggish oxygen evolution reaction (OER) is the bottleneck for water electrolysis, and tremendous efforts have been devoted to develop electrocatalysts that accelerate the OER kinetics. Recent advances have highlighted the potential of precious metal&#8208;free OER electrocatalyst capable of stable operation at current densities above 1 A cm 2 . This brings an opportunity of constructing new&#8208;generation electrolyzer with lower cost and higher productivity. However, achieving such high operating current densities presents new challenges. This review summarize the recent progress of high&#8208;performance OER catalysts, and identifies key factors that can be leveraged to enhance catalyst activity. These factors include interface/surface engineering, amorphous and crystal phase coupling, hierarchical structure design, structural reconstruction and phase conversion, high entropy catalyst, and defect engineering. Additionally, the pressing challenges that have been largely ignored in previous research is addressed, such as sustaining long&#8208;term stability under crucial conditions, disadvantages of immobilized powder electrocatalysts, electrode scale design, the necessity of designing innovative electrolyzer cell designs and advance characterization techniques.</description>
      <author>Wen&#8208;Yan Zhang, Kunyan Wang, Lei Tan, Faiza Meharban, Sheng Wang, Xiaopeng Li, Chao Lin, Wei Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/aenm.202402034</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inter-atomic Electronic Interactions Enables by Rh Single Atoms/CuCo2S4@MoS2 Core-Shell Heterostructure for High-efficiency Solar-assisted Water Splitting</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02881c</link>
      <description>Xinfeng Zhu, Kaixuan Dong, Dinh Chuong Nguyen, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee, Journal of Materials Chemistry A. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401242535

                In this work, we developed an electrocatalyst based on the Rh single atoms confined CuCo2S4@MoS2 core&#8211;shell heterostructure, namely Rh SAs/CuCo2S4@MoS2, for the cathodic hydrogen evolution reaction (HER) and anodic oxygen...</description>
      <author>Xinfeng Zhu, Kaixuan Dong, Dinh Chuong Nguyen, Sampath Prabhakaran, Do Hwan Kim, Duy Thanh Tran, Nam Hoon Kim, Joong Hee Lee</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1039/d4ta02881c</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A coefficient identification problem for a system of advection-diffusion-reaction equations in water quality modeling</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1515/jiip-2024-0030</link>
      <description>&#208;inh Nho H&#224;o, Nguy&#7877;n Trung Th&#224;nh, Nguyen Van Duc, Nguyen Van Thang, Journal of Inverse and Ill-Posed Problems. 0(0)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401289540

                Abstract The inverse problem of reconstructing two space-varying coefficients in a system of one-dimensional (1-d) time-dependent advection-diffusion-reaction (ADR) equations is considered. The ADR system can be used as a water quality model which describes the evolution of the biochemical oxygen demand (BOD) and dissolved oxygen (DO) in a river or stream. The coefficients to be reconstructed represents the effect of the deoxygenation and superficial reaeration processes on the DO and BOD concentration in water. H&#246;lder stability estimates for the coefficients of interest are established using the Carleman estimate technique.</description>
      <author>&#208;inh Nho H&#224;o, Nguy&#7877;n Trung Th&#224;nh, Nguyen Van Duc, Nguyen Van Thang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1515/jiip-2024-0030</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Influence of the Fire Point on the Thermal Dynamic Disaster in the Goaf</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7080270</link>
      <description>Xiaokun Chen, Chao Song, Zhipeng Zhang, Fire. 7(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401326784

                A thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf is one of the most serious coal mine disasters formed by coal spontaneous combustion and gas interweaving. However, the influence of the high-temperature hidden fire source formed in the goaf on the evolution law of thermal dynamic disasters is not clear, and effective prevention and control measures cannot be taken. Therefore, this paper uses the experimental platform of thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf to study the influence of different fire point positions on the development of thermal dynamic disaster in the goaf through a similar simulation experiment of thermal dynamic disaster evolution in the goaf and analyzes the corresponding relationship between temperature and CO concentration in the upper corner. The results show that under different locations of heat source, the high-temperature heat source of coal spontaneous combustion migrates to the air leakage side with sufficient oxygen supply, and an oxygen-poor circle is formed near the ignition point. Under the action of air leakage flow, CH4 accumulates in the deep part of the goaf on the return air side. Due to the increase in coal, part of CH4 is produced, which leads to the increase in concentration of CH4 at the ignition point. Under the action of different heat sources, the changing trend of concentration of CO and temperature in the return air corner is the same, but the temperature change in the return air corner shows a lag compared with the change in the concentration of CO, so concentration monitoring of CO can reflect the evolution process of the fire field in the goaf more quickly than temperature monitoring.</description>
      <author>Xiaokun Chen, Chao Song, Zhipeng Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3390/fire7080270</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced vanadium redox reaction catalytic properties enabled by tunning oxygen vacancy in rutile tio&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; coated graphite felt electrodes</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2814/1/012022</link>
      <description>Yancai Liu, Xiaobo Duan, Haonan Wang, Jiaao Yu, Jian Zhu, Birou Lu, Ming Zhu, Bin Zheng, Lei Zhang, Journal of Physics Conference Series. 2814(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333780

                Abstract Catalyzing vanadium redox reactions in VRFBs with transition metal oxides is an effective and affordable approach. In this study, the surface electron distribution of TiO 2 was regulated by introducing oxygen vacancies into its lattice, enabling the electrode to exhibit outstanding catalytic efficacy in VO 2 + /VO 2+ and V 3+ /V 2+ redox transformations and suppress the detrimental side reaction (HER and OER) simultaneously. Benefiting from the enhanced catalytic activity and selectivity, the 1000-TiO 2 -GF electrode sustained a stable operation for 100 cycles at 120 mA cm &#8722;2 with no discernible efficiency degradation. The DFT results indicate that oxygen vacancy in TiO 2 provides more extra electrons to its neighboring titanium, further strengthening the interaction between the electron-rich titanium and oxygen in VO 2 + /VO 2+ , thus enhancing its catalytic performance. The enhanced catalytic activity for V 3+ /V 2+ on oxygen vacancy-rich TiO 2 coating can be attributed to the effective suppression of hydrogen evolution reaction, which can occupy active sites exclusively and produce detrimental H 2 bubbles. This insight provides valuable guidance for the innovative design of catalysts in vanadium redox flow batteries.</description>
      <author>Yancai Liu, Xiaobo Duan, Haonan Wang, Jiaao Yu, Jian Zhu, Birou Lu, Ming Zhu, Bin Zheng, Lei Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-6596/2814/1/012022</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study on the Pyrolysis and Incineration of Lewisite by Thermodynamic Equilibrium Calculation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202400055</link>
      <description>X.K. Liu, Yuanpeng Zhang, Lin Yang, Weiwei Song, Haitao Wang, ChemistrySelect. 9(30)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401379683

                Abstract Lewisite is a representative chemical warfare agent that contains arsenic. Thermal decomposition is an essential method for Lewisite destruction, and appropriate destruction conditions can enhance the environmental friendliness of this method by minimizing the hazards of destruction products. In this study, the variation of Lewisite during pyrolysis and incineration was calculated, with particular emphasis on the evolution behaviors of arsenic and chloride with temperature, pressure, and molar ratio. The main products identified during pyrolysis were HCl(g), C, As, and AsCl 3 (g). Under anoxic conditions, AsCl 3 (g) and As were the dominant species. In oxygen&#8208;enriched conditions, arsenic existed primarily as AsCl 3 (g), As 2 O 5 , As 2 O 4 , and AsOCl. Below 600 &#176;C, arsenic predominantly existed in high valence forms such as As 2 O 5 . Above 600 &#176;C, the binding capacity of chlorine and arsenic was stronger than that of oxygen, resulting in an AsCl 3 (g) molar fraction exceeding 75 % at 1200 &#176;C. The primary chlorides in oxygen&#8208;enriched conditions were Cl 2 (g), HCl(g), AsCl 3 (g), and Cl(g). Lower incineration temperatures (around 500 &#176;C), sufficient oxygen conditions (molar ratio above 4 : 1), and positive pressures were conducive to reducing the toxicity of destruction products. The results are in good agreement with the experimental data.</description>
      <author>X.K. Liu, Yuanpeng Zhang, Lin Yang, Weiwei Song, Haitao Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/slct.202400055</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the mechanisms of Devonian oceanic anoxia: impact of ocean dynamics, palaeogeography and orbital forcing</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1983</link>
      <description>Justin G&#233;rard, Lo&#239;c Sablon, Jarno J. C. Huygh, Anne&#8208;Christine Da Silva, Alexandre Pohl, Christian V&#233;rard, Michel Crucifix, No host. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401225082

                Abstract. The Devonian is a warmer-than-present geological period spanning from 419 to 359 million years ago (Ma) characterized by multiple identified ocean anoxic/hypoxic events. Despite decades of extensive investigation, no consensus has been reached regarding the drivers of these anoxic events. While growing geological evidence has demonstrated a temporal correlation between astronomical forcing and anoxia during this period, underlying physical mechanisms remain unknown, hence questioning causality. Here, we perform multiple sensitivity experiments, using an Earth system model of intermediate complexity (cGENIE), to isolate the influences of specific Devonian climate and palaeogeography components on ocean oxygen levels, contributing to the better understanding of the intricate interplay of factors preconditioning the ocean to anoxia. We quantify the impact of continental configuration, ocean-atmosphere biogeochemistry (global mean oceanic PO4 concentration and atmospheric pO2), climatic forcing (pCO2) and astronomical forcing on background oceanic circulation and oxygenation during the Devonian. Our results indicate that continental configuration is crucial for Devonian ocean anoxia, significantly influencing ocean circulation and oxygen levels while consistently modulating the effects of other Devonian climate components such as oceanic PO4 concentration, atmospheric pO2 and pCO2, and orbital forcing. The evolution of continental configuration provides a plausible explanation for the increased frequency of ocean anoxic events identified during the Middle and Late Devonian periods, as it contributed to the expansion of oxygen-depleted zones. Our simulations also show that both the decreased atmospheric pO2 and increased oceanic PO2 concentration exacerbate ocean anoxia, consistent with established knowledge. The variation of pCO2 reveals a wide range of ocean dynamics patterns, including stable oscillations, multiple convection cells, multistability and hysteresis; all leading to significant variations of the ocean oxygen levels, therefore strongly impacting the preconditioning of the ocean to anoxia. Furthermore, multistability and important hysteresis (particularly slow ocean time response) offer different mechanisms to account for the prolonged duration of some ocean anoxic events. Finally, we found that astronomical forcing substantially impacts ocean anoxia by altering ocean circulation and oxygen solubility, with obliquity consistently emerging as the primary orbital parameter driving ocean oxygen variations.</description>
      <author>Justin G&#233;rard, Lo&#239;c Sablon, Jarno J. C. Huygh, Anne&#8208;Christine Da Silva, Alexandre Pohl, Christian V&#233;rard, Michel Crucifix</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.5194/egusphere-2024-1983</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piezo&#8208;catalysis Mechanism Elucidation by Tracking Oxygen Reduction to Hydrogen Peroxide with In&#8208;situ EPR Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410381</link>
      <description>Jie He, Zhi Li, Pengju Feng, Gang Lu, Tengda Ding, Li Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Mingshan Zhu, Angewandte Chemie. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401225169

                For piezoelectric catalysis, the catalytic mechanism is a topic of great controversy, with debates centered around whether it belongs to the energy band theory of photocatalysis or the screening charge effect of electrochemical catalysis. Due to the formation of different intermediate active&#8208;species during two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) via electro&#8208; and photo&#8208;catalysis, the key to solving this problem is precisely monitoring the active species involved in ORR during electro&#8208;, photo&#8208;, and piezo&#8208;catalysis under identical condition. Here, a semiconductor material, BiOBr with abundant oxygen vacancies (BOB&#8208;OV) was found remarkable catalytic activity in H2O2 production by all three catalytic methods. By employing in&#8208;situ electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy, the H2O2 evolution pathway through piezo&#8208;catalysis over BOB&#8208;OV was monitored, which showed a similar reaction pathway to that observed in photo&#8208;catalytic process. This finding represents solid evidence supporting the notion that piezo&#8208;catalytic mechanism of ORR is more inclined towards photo&#8208;catalysis rather than electro&#8208;catalysis. Significantly, this exploratory conclusion provides insight to deepen our understanding of piezo&#8208;catalysis.</description>
      <author>Jie He, Zhi Li, Pengju Feng, Gang Lu, Tengda Ding, Li Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Mingshan Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/ange.202410381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Piezo&#8208;catalysis Mechanism Elucidation by Tracking Oxygen Reduction to Hydrogen Peroxide with In&#8208;situ EPR Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410381</link>
      <description>Jie He, Zhi Li, Pengju Feng, Gang L&#252;, Tengda Ding, Li Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Zhu Mingshan, Angewandte Chemie International Edition. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401225016

                For piezoelectric catalysis, the catalytic mechanism is a topic of great controversy, with debates centered around whether it belongs to the energy band theory of photocatalysis or the screening charge effect of electrochemical catalysis. Due to the formation of different intermediate active&#8208;species during two&#8208;electron oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) via electro&#8208; and photo&#8208;catalysis, the key to solving this problem is precisely monitoring the active species involved in ORR during electro&#8208;, photo&#8208;, and piezo&#8208;catalysis under identical condition. Here, a semiconductor material, BiOBr with abundant oxygen vacancies (BOB&#8208;OV) was found remarkable catalytic activity in H2O2 production by all three catalytic methods. By employing in&#8208;situ electron paramagnetic resonance (EPR) spectroscopy, the H2O2 evolution pathway through piezo&#8208;catalysis over BOB&#8208;OV was monitored, which showed a similar reaction pathway to that observed in photo&#8208;catalytic process. This finding represents solid evidence supporting the notion that piezo&#8208;catalytic mechanism of ORR is more inclined towards photo&#8208;catalysis rather than electro&#8208;catalysis. Significantly, this exploratory conclusion provides insight to deepen our understanding of piezo&#8208;catalysis.</description>
      <author>Jie He, Zhi Li, Pengju Feng, Gang L&#252;, Tengda Ding, Li Chen, Xiaoguang Duan, Zhu Mingshan</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/anie.202410381</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advances and Challenges in Analytical Strategies for Fruity Thiol Profiling in Beer: From Sensitivity Optimization to Ecologically Responsible Methodologies</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.61935/acetr.3.1.2024.p204</link>
      <description>H.L. Liu, Jianghua Zhao, Delin Han, F. Deng, Advances in Computer and Engineering Technology Research. 1(3)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401378525

                The fruity thiols in beer, such as 3SH, 3SHA, 4MMP, and 3S4MP, constitute significant components of its volatile profile, playing a pivotal role in shaping the overall flavor alongside hydrocarbons and oxygen-containing compounds. This paper, drawing extensively on relevant literature, presents a comprehensive summary of the composition, aroma contribution, challenges in thiol detection, and advancements in analytical methods and technologies for these compounds. It outlines the limitations and attempted improvements of direct measurement approaches, the innovations and evolution of derivatization methods, and the integration of various specific sample preparation techniques (e.g., SPE, SPME, LLE, and derivatization) with modern, advanced detection equipment, accompanied by an evaluation of the precision and inclusivity of these methods. Concluding the discussion, the article offers a perspective on the future refinement of thiol determination in the brewing industry. This review aims to serve the objective of more precise beer flavor modulation.</description>
      <author>H.L. Liu, Jianghua Zhao, Delin Han, F. Deng</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.61935/acetr.3.1.2024.p204</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inhibiting Voltage Decay in Li-Rich Layered Oxide Cathode: From O3-Type to O2-Type Structural Design</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01473-7</link>
      <description>Guo&#8208;Hua Zhang, Xiaohui Wen, Yuheng Gao, Renyuan Zhang, Zhimei Huang, Nano-Micro Letters. 16(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401233024

                Abstract Li-rich layered oxide (LRLO) cathodes have been regarded as promising candidates for next-generation Li-ion batteries due to their exceptionally high energy density, which combines cationic and anionic redox activities. However, continuous voltage decay during cycling remains the primary obstacle for practical applications, which has yet to be fundamentally addressed. It is widely acknowledged that voltage decay originates from the irreversible migration of transition metal ions, which usually further exacerbates structural evolution and aggravates the irreversible oxygen redox reactions. Recently, constructing O2-type structure has been considered one of the most promising approaches for inhibiting voltage decay. In this review, the relationship between voltage decay and structural evolution is systematically elucidated. Strategies to suppress voltage decay are systematically summarized. Additionally, the design of O2-type structure and the corresponding mechanism of suppressing voltage decay are comprehensively discussed. Unfortunately, the reported O2-type LRLO cathodes still exhibit partially disordered structure with extended cycles. Herein, the factors that may cause the irreversible transition metal migrations in O2-type LRLO materials are also explored, while the perspectives and challenges for designing high-performance O2-type LRLO cathodes without voltage decay are proposed.</description>
      <author>Guo&#8208;Hua Zhang, Xiaohui Wen, Yuheng Gao, Renyuan Zhang, Zhimei Huang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1007/s40820-024-01473-7</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quality of Life and Exercise Capacity in Early Stage and Subclinical Hypertrophic Cardiomyopathy: A Secondary Analysis of the VANISH Trial</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1161/circheartfailure.124.011663</link>
      <description>Catherine G. Ireland, Danielle S. Burstein, Sharlene M. Day, Anna Axelsson Raja, Mark W. Russell, Kenneth Zahka, Alexandre C. Pereira, Charles E. Canter, Richard G. Bach, Matthew T. Wheeler, Joseph W. Rossano, Anjali Tiku Owens, Henning Bundgaard, Luisa Mestroni, Matthew R.G. Taylor, Amit R. Patel, Ivan Wilmot, Jonathan H. Soslow, Jason R. Becker, Ilya Giverts, E. John Orav, Brian Claggett, Kimberly Y. Lin, Carolyn Y. Ho, Circulation Heart Failure. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401223998

                BACKGROUND: The health-related quality of life (HRQOL) and cardiopulmonary exercise testing (CPET) performance of individuals with subclinical and early stage hypertrophic cardiomyopathy (HCM) have not been systematically studied. Improved understanding will inform the natural history of HCM and factors influencing well-being. METHODS: VANISH trial (Valsartan for Attenuating Disease Evolution in Early Sarcomeric HCM) participants with early stage sarcomeric HCM (primary analysis cohort) and subclinical HCM (sarcomere variant without left ventricular hypertrophy comprising the exploratory cohort) who completed baseline and year 2 HRQOL assessment via the pediatric quality of life inventory and CPET were studied. Metrics correlating with baseline HRQOL and CPET performance were identified. The impact of valsartan treatment on these measures was analyzed in the early stage cohort. RESULTS: Two hundred participants were included: 166 with early stage HCM (mean age, 23&#177;10 years; 40% female; 97% White; and 92% New York Heart Association class I) and 34 subclinical sarcomere variant carriers (mean age, 16&#177;5 years; 50% female; and 100% White). Baseline HRQOL was good in both cohorts, although slightly better in subclinical HCM (composite pediatric quality of life score 84.6&#177;10.6 versus 90.2&#177;9.8; P =0.005). Both cohorts demonstrated mildly reduced functional status (mean percent predicted peak oxygen uptake 73&#177;16 versus 78&#177;12 mL/kg per minute; P =0.18). Percent predicted peak oxygen uptake and peak oxygen pulse correlated with HRQOL. Valsartan improved physical HRQOL in early stage HCM (adjusted mean change in pediatric quality of life score +4.1 versus placebo; P =0.01) but did not significantly impact CPET performance. CONCLUSIONS: Functional capacity can be impaired in young, healthy people with early stage HCM, despite New York Heart Association class I status and good HRQOL. Peak oxygen uptake was similarly decreased in subclinical HCM despite normal left ventricular wall thickness and excellent HRQOL. Valsartan improved physical pediatric quality of life scores but did not significantly impact CPET performance. Further studies are needed for validation and to understand how to improve patient experience. REGISTRATION: URL: https://www.clinicaltrials.gov ; Unique identifier: NCT01912534.</description>
      <author>Catherine G. Ireland, Danielle S. Burstein, Sharlene M. Day, Anna Axelsson Raja, Mark W. Russell, Kenneth Zahka, Alexandre C. Pereira, Charles E. Canter, Richard G. Bach, Matthew T. Wheeler, Joseph W. Rossano, Anjali Tiku Owens, Henning Bundgaard, Luisa Mestroni, Matthew R.G. Taylor, Amit R. Patel, Ivan Wilmot, Jonathan H. Soslow, Jason R. Becker, Ilya Giverts, E. John Orav, Brian Claggett, Kimberly Y. Lin, Carolyn Y. Ho</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1161/circheartfailure.124.011663</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S-scheme carbon doped-TiO2/ZnIn2S4 heterojunction for enhanced photocatalytic degradation of microcystin-LR and hydrogen evolution</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.142996</link>
      <description>Li Wang, Lin Ding, Xibao Li, Zhenzhou Wang, Xiwei Xu, Xubiao Luo, Xubiao Luo, Chemosphere. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401270799

                Photocatalytic degradation of pollutants coupled with hydrogen (H2) evolution has emerged as a promising solution for environmental and energy crises. However, the fast recombination of photoexcited electrons and holes limits photocatalytic activities. Herein, an S-scheme heterojunction carbon doped-TiO2 /ZnIn2S4 (C-TiO2/ZnIn2S4) was designed by substituting oxygen sites within C-TiO2 by ZnIn2S4. Under visible light irradiation, the optimal C-TiO2/ZnIn2S4 exhibits a higher degradation efficiency (88.6%) of microcystin-LR (MC-LR), compared to pristine C-TiO2 (72.9%) and ZnIn2S4 (66.8%). Furthermore, the H2 yield of the C-TiO2/ZnIn2S4 reaches 1526.9 &#956;mol&#183;g&#8722;1&#183;h&#8722;1, which is 3.83 times and 2.87 times that of the C-TiO2 and ZnIn2S4, respectively. Experimental and theoretical investigations reveal that an internal electric field (IEF) informed in the C-TiO2/ZnIn2S4 heterojunction, accelerates the separation of photogenerated charge pairs, thereby enhancing photocatalytic efficiency of MC-LR degradation and H2 production. This work highlights a new perspective on the development of high-performance photocatalysts for wastewater treatment and H2 generation.</description>
      <author>Li Wang, Lin Ding, Xibao Li, Zhenzhou Wang, Xiwei Xu, Xubiao Luo, Xubiao Luo</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.chemosphere.2024.142996</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mineral chemistry, petrography and crystallization conditions of the Middle Eocene Kaz&#305;kbeli Pluton (Eastern Pontides, NE T&#252;rkiye)</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.19111/bulletinofmre.1529525</link>
      <description>Zikrullah Samet G&#252;lo&#287;lu, Abdullah Kaygusuz, Emre Ayd&#305;n&#231;ak&#305;r, Cem Y&#252;cel, Bulletin Of The Mineral Research and Exploration. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401401513

                The Eastern Pontides host a diverse suite of plutonic rocks spanning a wide range of ages and compositions. Among these, the Middle Eocene Kaz&#305;kbeli pluton, located in the K&#252;rt&#252;n district of G&#252;m&#252;&#351;hane, stands out due to its distinctive petrological characteristics. This study aims to unravel the petrological implications of petrographic and mineral chemical data to constrain the physicayd&#305;n&#231;ak&#305;rochemical conditions (temperature, pressure, oxygen fugacity) under which the Kaz&#305;kbeli magma crystallized and was emplaced. By integrating mineral chemical data, we seek to quantify emplacement pressure, crystallization temperature, and oxygen fugacity. A comprehensive understanding of the genetic relationships and physicochemical properties of the Kaz&#305;kbeli pluton rocks, as determined through geological, petrographic and mineral chemistry, is crucial for elucidating the geological evolution of the Eastern Pontides. The Kaz&#305;kbeli Pluton exhibits a predominant NE-SW orientation and encompasses an area of roughly 46 km&#178;. Modal mineralogical analysis reveals a compositional spectrum ranging from gabbroic diorite to monzogranite, with granodiorite and tonalite being the most prominent rock types. Textural variations encompass fine- to medium-grained, porphyritic, poikilitic, and occasionally graphic textures. The primary mineral assemblage of the pluton comprises plagioclase, orthoclase, quartz, amphibole, biotite, and Fe-Ti oxides. Accessory minerals include zircon, apatite, sphene, and allanite. Plagioclases are labradorite to oligoclase (An26 to An66) in composition. K-feldspar minerals exhibited an orthoclase composition (Or80 to Or97). All amphiboles belong to the calcic amphibole field and exhibit a magnesio-hornblende (Mg#=0.63-0.73) composition. Biotites crystallized as solidified melt products with compositions between annite and phlogopite endmembers, plotting close to the magnesium-rich (Mg#=0.52-0.58) end of the phlogopite solid solution series. Calculated crystallization temperatures derived from amphibole and biotite data range from 712&#176;C to 824&#176;C. Pressure estimations calculated using amphibole-plagioclase, amphibole and biotite suggest a range of 0.04 to 2.06 kbar. Oxygen fugacity (&#402;O2) values calculated using amphibole and biotite fall between -12.5 and -16.1. Amphibole-based water content estimations indicate a range of 3.7% to 5.7% for the pluton. Biotite compositions within the studied Kaz&#305;kbeli pluton rocks exhibit characteristics suggestive of a potential mantle origin. Geobarometric calculations based on mineral chemistry data with geological and petrographic features indicate the emplacement of the Kaz&#305;kbeli Pluton at relatively shallow depths within the crust (~1 to 8 km).</description>
      <author>Zikrullah Samet G&#252;lo&#287;lu, Abdullah Kaygusuz, Emre Ayd&#305;n&#231;ak&#305;r, Cem Y&#252;cel</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.19111/bulletinofmre.1529525</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nanoceramic particle reinforced high alloying Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1177/14644207241269595</link>
      <description>Hailong Cong, Xianping Zhang, ZeFan Cheng, Hai Chao Li, Pei Wang, Wanting Sun, Proceedings of the Institution of Mechanical Engineers Part L Journal of Materials Design and Applications. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401277442

                In the metal matrix composites (MMCs) reinforced with nanoparticles, the enhancement of composite performance is often closely associated with the types of nanoparticles. It is vital to explore the influences and differences of various nanoparticles on the microstructure evolution and mechanical properties of highly alloyed aluminum-based composites. This study is the first to employ hot pressing for preparing Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composite materials reinforced with SiC and Al 2 O 3 nano-ceramic particles, respectively. By employing hot extrusion and T6 heat treatment techniques, a systematic investigation was conducted on the effects of the addition of nano-ceramic particles on the microstructure evolution and mechanical properties of the Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composites, and a comparative analysis was performed on the two types of composite materials. The experimental results demonstrated that the Mg atoms in the &#945;-Al matrix were consumed by the addition of SiC/Al 2 O 3 nano-ceramic particles, and thereby the grain size primary &#951;&#8217; (MgZn 2 ) strengthening phase was refined, leading to an enhanced overall mechanical performance of the Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composite. In particular, the Mg 2 Si phase was generated by the addition of SiC nanoceramic particles, through the interfacial reactions, and thus with the synergistic effects of precipitation strengthening and Orowan strengthening, the ultimate compressive strength and compressibility of Al-Zn-Mg-Cu composite can be increased to 844 MPa and 27.5%, respectively. On the other hand, the addition of Al 2 O 3 nanoceramic particles can bring about the formation of an oxygen-rich phase and refined precipitates at grain boundaries. Accordingly, the elongation is increased to 43.5% while a high ultimate compressive strength in the composites can be maintained. It is anticipated that nanoceramic particle-reinforced Al-based metal composites have significant potential for achieving both high strength and exceptional ductility for the application in the industry field.</description>
      <author>Hailong Cong, Xianping Zhang, ZeFan Cheng, Hai Chao Li, Pei Wang, Wanting Sun</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1177/14644207241269595</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kinetics&#8208;Matched Electrode Design for Zn&#8208;Metal Free Zinc Ion Batteries with High Energy Density and Stabilities</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407120</link>
      <description>Jiahe Zhang, Chengqian Zhang, Shi Cai Cui, Xiaojun Zhang, Ke Wang, Yihe Zhang, Advanced Functional Materials. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401223909

                Abstract The metal&#8208;free rocking chair type Zn&#8208;ion batteries (ZIBs) provide a promising approach toward the promotion of the Zn&#8208;based batteries by circumventing the challenges including dendrite growth, hydrogen evolution reaction (HER), and surface corrosion. In order to sufficiently exploit the available capacity of this metal&#8208;free batteries, it is necessary to effectively enhance the sluggish reaction kinetics of divalent zinc ions. Equally important is to achieve a balance in the kinetics between cathode and anode. Here, hetero&#8208;valent doping and oxygen vacancy engineering are employed to effectively enhance the reaction dynamics of V 2 O 5 cathodes and MoO 3 anodes. Moreover, to the best of the knowledge, for the first time, the strategy of kinetics matching between the two electrodes is applied to the construction of rocking&#8208;chair zinc ion batteries, enabling the cathode and anode to share similar zinc ion migration rates, and achieving a high energy density of up to 58.7 Wh kg &#8722;1 (based on the total electrode mass) as well as excellent cycling stability (90% after 500 cycles). This work demonstrates the importance of kinetics matching in zinc&#8208;ion full&#8208;cell performance and pave a benefitable avenue to for the pursuit of advanced multi&#8208;valent metal&#8208;ion batteries.</description>
      <author>Jiahe Zhang, Chengqian Zhang, Shi Cai Cui, Xiaojun Zhang, Ke Wang, Yihe Zhang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/adfm.202407120</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wettability step electrode to generate millimeter-scale gas&#8211;liquid interface for drag reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0220158</link>
      <description>Mengzhuo Zhang, Haibao Hu, Liuzhen Ren, Jun Wen, Luo Xie, Physics of Fluids. 36(8)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401337021

                Superhydrophobic surfaces can seal the gas&#8211;liquid interface (GLI) under water to produce the drag reduction effect. Enhancing the stability and slip length of the GLI is an important issue in this context. Herein, we fabricate wettability step electrodes (WSEs) by creating an array of millimeter-scale circular superhydrophobic regions on a hydrophilic graphite plate by using an economical and efficient mask spraying method. When the WSE was electrified as an anode, the oxygen produced by the electrolytic reaction was preferentially precipitated in the superhydrophobic regions and ultimately formed an array of millimeter-scale GLIs. The evolution process of this GLI can be divided into a spreading stage and a growth stage. The results of experiments revealed that the spreading duration of the GLI increased with the diameter of the superhydrophobic regions (D) and decreased with the spacing between adjacent superhydrophobic regions (L). During the growth stage, the height of the GLI decreased with the ratio D/(L + D) and increased over the duration of electrification according to a 1/3 power-law relationship. Finally, we measured the slip characteristic on a single millimeter-scale GLI by particle image velocimetry. The result showed that the effective slip length of the GLI with a streamwise length of 2 mm can exceed 100 &#956;m, thus confirming the potential of the millimeter-scale GLI for drag reduction.</description>
      <author>Mengzhuo Zhang, Haibao Hu, Liuzhen Ren, Jun Wen, Luo Xie</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0220158</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S&#8208;scheme MnO2/Co3O4 sugar&#8208;gourd nanohybrids with abundant oxygen vacancies for efficient visible&#8208;light&#8208;driven CO2 reduction</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401057</link>
      <description>Linfeng Jin, Hao Yu, Chenhui Wang, Changfa Guo, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Yijun Zhong, Yong Hu, ChemCatChem. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401399360

                Converting CO2 to carbon&#8208;based fuels using solar energy via photocatalysis is a promising approach to boost carbon neutrality. However, the solar&#8208;to&#8208;chemical conversion efficiency is hampered by interconnected multiple factors including insufficient light absorption, low separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers as well as complex and sluggish surface reaction kinetics. Herein, we incorporate MnO2 nanowires and Co3O4 hollow polyhedrons with abundant oxygen vacancies (Vo) into MnO2/Co3O4 sugar&#8208;gourd nanohybrids for boosting CO2 photoreduction. The MnO2/Co3O4 nanohybrids not only display strong absorption in the visible&#8211;near infrared region, but also facilitate the separation of photogenerated carriers in terms of S&#8208;scheme transfer pathway, supplying abundant electrons for CO2 reduction reaction. Furthermore, the presence of VO enhances the separation efficiency of photogenerated carriers and promotes the chemical adsorption to CO2 molecules. In addition, the interfacial electronic interaction between MnO2 and Co3O4 also contributes to the chemical adsorption and activation to CO2. Owing to the synergy of S&#8208;scheme transfer pathway and VO, the MnO2/Co3O4 hybrids exhibit greatly enhanced photocatalytic activity towards CO2 reduction under the irradiation of visible light in comparison with bare MnO2 and Co3O4, delivering a CO evolution rate of 15.9 umol g&#8722;1 h&#8722;1 with a 100% selectivity.</description>
      <author>Linfeng Jin, Hao Yu, Chenhui Wang, Changfa Guo, Saikh Mohammad Wabaidur, Yijun Zhong, Yong Hu</author>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/cctc.202401057</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Situ Defect Engineering of Fe&#8208;MIL for Self&#8208;Enhanced Peroxidase&#8208;Like Activity</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403354</link>
      <description>Yujia Cai, Yu Wu, Yinjun Tang, Weiqing Xu, Yifei Chen, Rina Su, Yuexi Fan, Wenxuan Jiang, Yating Wen, Wenling Gu, Hongcheng Sun, Chengzhou Zhu, Small. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333995

                Abstract Defect engineering is an effective strategy to enhance the enzyme&#8208;like activity of nanozymes. However, previous efforts have primarily focused on introducing defects via de novo synthesis and post&#8208;synthetic treatment, overlooking the dynamic evolution of defects during the catalytic process involving highly reactive oxygen species. Herein, a defect&#8208;engineered metal&#8211;organic framework (MOF) nanozyme with mixed linkers is reported. Over twofold peroxidase (POD)&#8208;like activity enhancement compared with unmodified nanozyme highlights the critical role of in situ defect formation in enhancing the catalytic performance of nanozyme. Experimental results reveal that highly active hydroxyl radical (&#8226;OH) generated in the catalytic process etches the 2,5&#8208;dihydroxyterephthalic acid ligands, contributing to electronic structure modulation of metal sites and enlarged pore sizes in the framework. The self&#8208;enhanced POD&#8208;like activity induced by in situ defect engineering promotes the generation of &#8226;OH, holding promise in colorimetric sensing for detecting dichlorvos. Utilizing smartphone photography for RGB value extraction, the resultant sensing platform achieves the detection for dichlorvos ranging from 5 to 300 ng mL &#8722;1 with a low detection limit of 2.06 ng mL &#8722;1 . This pioneering work in creating in situ defects in MOFs to improve catalytic activity offers a novel perspective on traditional defect engineering.</description>
      <author>Yujia Cai, Yu Wu, Yinjun Tang, Weiqing Xu, Yifei Chen, Rina Su, Yuexi Fan, Wenxuan Jiang, Yating Wen, Wenling Gu, Hongcheng Sun, Chengzhou Zhu</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.202403354</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excited&#8208;State Dynamics and Optical Properties of Silica Under Ultrafast Laser Irradiation</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.1002/apxr.202400106</link>
      <description>Arshak A. Tsaturyan, Elena P. Silaeva, Razvan Stoian, Jean&#8208;Philippe Colombier, Advanced Physics Research. None(None)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401354141

                Abstract Excited by intense infrared ultrafast light pulses, a wide bandgap material undergoes nonlinear ionization, generating a high density of free electrons in conduction states. As a result, the electronic band structure is critically modified and the bandgap shrinks. This induces rapid changes in optical properties, dramatically affecting the absorption spectrum during light coupling to the dielectric surface or during nonlinear propagation inside the bulk. This study analyzes the structural behavior and the modification of the optical properties of laser&#8208;excited silica glass at the molecular cluster level through first&#8208;principles simulations. Employing density functional theory and the GW approximations for band structure under nonequilibrium conditions, alongside the Bethe&#8211;Salpeter equation, the dynamics of the optical properties of fused silica are comprehensively explored. The behavior of excited fused silica in a wide photon energy range (from a few to 20 eV) is thus predicted. Laser&#8208;induced electron excitation triggers a redistribution of charges between oxygen and silicon atoms, accompanied by a significant increase in electronic pressure, local atomic structure rearrangement, and material expansion. Molecular dynamics simulations offer a temporal perspective on the excited state dynamics, unveiling the intricate interplay between electronic and atomic effects on bandgap evolution. The analysis sheds light on excitonic resonances, intraband and interband transitions in fused silica under ultrafast laser irradiation, providing valuable insights into its excited state behavior and optical properties.</description>
      <author>Arshak A. Tsaturyan, Elena P. Silaeva, Razvan Stoian, Jean&#8208;Philippe Colombier</author>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.1002/apxr.202400106</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rotation and Abundances of the Benchmark Brown Dwarf HD 33632 Ab from Keck/KPIC High-resolution Spectroscopy</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad58d3</link>
      <description>Chih-Chun Hsu, Jason Wang, Jerry W. Xuan, Jean-Baptiste Ruffio, Evan Morris, Daniel Echeverri, Yinzi Xin, Joshua Liberman, Luke Finnerty, Katelyn Horstman, Ben Sappey, Gregory Doppmann, Dimitri Mawet, Nemanja Jovanovi&#263;, Michael P. Fitzgerald, Jacques-Robert Delorme, J. Kent Wallace, Ashley Baker, Randall Bartos, Geoffrey A. Blake, Benjamin Calvin, Sylvain Cetre, Ronald L&#243;pez, Jacklyn Pezzato, Tobias Schofield, Andrew Skemer, Ji Wang, The Astrophysical Journal. 971(1)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401275175

                Abstract We present the projected rotational velocity and molecular abundances for HD 33632 Ab obtained via Keck Planet Imager and Characterizer (KPIC) high-resolution spectroscopy. HD 33632 Ab is a nearby benchmark brown dwarf companion at a separation of &#8764;20 au that straddles the L&#8211;T transition. Using a forward-modeling framework with on-axis host star spectra, which provides self-consistent substellar atmospheric and retrieval models for HD 33632 Ab, we derive a projected rotational velocity of 53 &#177; 3 km s &#8722;1 and carbon monoxide and water mass fractions of logCO = &#8722;2.3 &#177; 0.3 and logH 2 O = &#8722;2.7 &#177; 0.2, respectively. The inferred carbon-to-oxygen ratio (C/O = 0.58 &#177; 0.14), molecular abundances, and metallicity ([C/H] = 0.0 &#177; 0.2 dex) of HD 33632 Ab are consistent with its host star. Although detectable methane opacities are expected in L&#8211;T transition objects, we did not recover methane in our KPIC spectra, partly due to the high v sin i and to disequilibrium chemistry at the pressures to which we are sensitive. We parameterize the spin as the ratio of rotation to the breakup velocity, and compare HD 33632 Ab to a compilation of &gt;200 very low-mass objects ( M &#8818; 0.1 M &#8857; ) that have spin measurements in the literature. There appears to be no clear trend for the isolated low-mass field objects versus mass, but a tentative trend is identified for low-mass companions and directly imaged exoplanets, similar to previous findings. A larger sample of close-in gas giant exoplanets and brown dwarfs will critically examine our understanding of their formation and evolution through rotation and chemical abundance measurements.</description>
      <author>Chih-Chun Hsu, Jason Wang, Jerry W. Xuan, Jean-Baptiste Ruffio, Evan Morris, Daniel Echeverri, Yinzi Xin, Joshua Liberman, Luke Finnerty, Katelyn Horstman, Ben Sappey, Gregory Doppmann, Dimitri Mawet, Nemanja Jovanovi&#263;, Michael P. Fitzgerald, Jacques-Robert Delorme, J. Kent Wallace, Ashley Baker, Randall Bartos, Geoffrey A. Blake, Benjamin Calvin, Sylvain Cetre, Ronald L&#243;pez, Jacklyn Pezzato, Tobias Schofield, Andrew Skemer, Ji Wang</author>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ad58d3</guid>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Influence of Controlled Condition Ice Encasement of Creeping Bentgrass and Annual Bluegrass on Plant Recovery, Gas Evolution, and Metabolites</title>
      <link>https://doi.org/10.21273/jashs05394-24</link>
      <description>Megan Gendjar, Devendra Prasad Chalise, Randolph M. Beaudry, Emily Merewitz, Journal of the American Society for Horticultural Science. 149(4)] 2024. https://openalex.org/W4401333606

                Two cool-season putting green turfgrass species, annual bluegrass and creeping bentgrass, are differential in ice encasement tolerance. Physiological mechanisms associated with creeping bentgrass ice encasement tolerance and annual bluegrass susceptibility are not understood. The objectives were to evaluate oxygen, ethylene, and CO 2 content within the upper soil space of the plants while frozen and immediately after ice melt after 0, 5, 10, 20, and 28 days of ice encasement (2.54 cm of ice) in growth chamber conditions. Following ice melt, plant samples were separated into leaf, crown, and root tissues and used to evaluate carbohydrate and amino acid content. Annual bluegrass exhibited higher damage (slower recovery rates) on most sampling days compared with creeping bentgrass. The organs that were most damaged and exhibited a differential principal component analysis snapshot, were the leaf and crown tissues. Creeping bentgrass may preserve leaf and crown tissues for postwinter recovery whereas significant metabolic changes occur in annual bluegrass leaves and crowns. Creeping bentgrass retained total amino acids in leaves following ice encasement whereas total leaf amino acid levels declined in annual bluegrass. Specific carbohydrates and amino acids such as the ability to maintain high levels of fructose, asparagine, and proline may be important indicators of the tolerance to ice encasement stress. On the basis of more prominent carbohydrate and amino acid loss in leaves and crowns and higher levels of CO 2 evolution, annual bluegrass may exhibit a higher metabolism and/or tissue damage during ice encasement compared with creeping bentgrass, which could reduce spring recuperative potential.</description>
      <author>Megan Gendjar, Devendra Prasad Chalise, Randolph M. Beaudry, Emily Merewitz</author>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://doi.org/10.21273/jashs05394-24</guid>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
